<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">10074110</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>1999</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>06</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0022-538X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>73</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>1999</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of virology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Virol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Bacterial lipopolysaccharide inhibits dengue virus infection of primary human monocytes/macrophages by blockade of virus entry via a CD14-dependent mechanism.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2650</StartPage><EndPage>2657</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2650-7</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>Monocytes/macrophages (MO/Mphi) are the major target cells for both dengue virus (DV) and bacterial lipopolysaccharide (LPS), and the aim of this study was to define their interactions. We had found that LPS markedly suppressed DV infection of primary human MO/Mphi when it was added to cultures prior to or together with, but not after, viral adsorption. The inhibitory effect of LPS was direct and specific and was not mediated by LPS-induced secretion of cytokines and chemokines such as tumor necrosis factor alpha, interleukin-1beta (IL-1beta), IL-6, IL-8, IL-12, alpha interferon, MIP-1alpha, and RANTES. In fact, productive DV infection was not blocked but was just postponed by LPS, with a time lag equal to one viral replication cycle. Time course studies demonstrated that LPS was only effective in suppressing DV infection of MO/Mphi that had not been previously exposed to the virus. At various time points after viral adsorption, the level of unbound viruses that remained free in the culture supernatants of LPS-pretreated cultures was much higher than that of untreated controls. These observations suggest that the LPS-induced suppression of DV replication was at the level of virus attachment and/or entry. Blockade of the major LPS receptor, CD14, with monoclonal antibodies MY4 or MoS39 failed to inhibit DV infection but could totally abrogate the inhibitory effect of LPS. Moreover, human serum could significantly enhance the LPS-induced DV suppression in a CD14-dependent manner, indicating that the "binding" of LPS to CD14 was critical for the induction of virus inhibition. Taken together, our results suggest that LPS blocked DV entry into human MO/Mphi via its receptor CD14 and that a CD14-associated cell surface structure may be essential for the initiation of a DV infection.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Y C</ForeName><Initials>YC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Hematology, Department of Medical Research, Veterans General Hospital-Taipei and National Yang-Ming University, Taipei, Taiwan, Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>S Y</ForeName><Initials>SY</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>King</LastName><ForeName>C C</ForeName><Initials>CC</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Virol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0113724</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0022-538X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D018950">Lipopolysaccharide Receptors</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D008070">Lipopolysaccharides</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002478" MajorTopicYN="N">Cells, Cultured</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003715" MajorTopicYN="N">Dengue</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="Y">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="N">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003716" MajorTopicYN="N">Dengue Virus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018950" MajorTopicYN="N">Lipopolysaccharide Receptors</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="Y">drug effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008070" MajorTopicYN="N">Lipopolysaccharides</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="Y">pharmacology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008264" MajorTopicYN="N">Macrophages</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000382" MajorTopicYN="N">microbiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="Y">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009000" MajorTopicYN="N">Monocytes</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000382" MajorTopicYN="N">microbiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="Y">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014779" MajorTopicYN="N">Virus Replication</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="N">drug effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>1999</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>1999</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>1999</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10074110</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC104020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JVI.73.4.2650-2657.1999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Anderson R, Wang S, Osiowy C, Issekutz A C. Activation of endothelial cells via antibody-enhanced dengue virus infection of peripheral blood monocytes. J Virol. 1997;71:4226&#x2013;4232.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC191637</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9151809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bagasra O, Wright S D, Seshamma T, Oakes J W, Pomerantz R J. CD14 is involved in control of human immunodeficiency virus type 1 expression in latently infected cells by lipopolysaccharide. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 1992;89:6285&#x2013;6289.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC49485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1378624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergelson J M, Cunningham J A, Droguett G, Kurt-Jones E A, Krithivas A, Hong J S, Horwitz M S, Crowell R L, Finberg R W. Isolation of a common receptor for coxsackie B viruses and adenoviruses 2 and 5. Science. 1997;275:1320&#x2013;1323.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9036860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernstein M S, Tong-Starksen S E, Locksley R M. Activation of human monocyte-derived macrophages with lipopolysaccharide decreases human immunodeficiency virus replication in vitro at the level of gene expression. J Clin Invest. 1991;88:540&#x2013;545.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC295381</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1907615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biswas P, Poli G, Kinter A L, Justement J S, Stanley S K, Maury W J, Bressler P J M, Orenstein J M, Fauci A S. Interferon &#x3b3; modulates the expression of human immunodeficiency virus in persistently infected promonocytic cells by redirecting the production of virions to intracytoplasmic vacuoles. J Exp Med. 1992;176:739&#x2013;750.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2119360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1512539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang D-M, Shaio M-F. Production of interleukin-1 (IL-1) and IL-1 inhibitor by human monocytes exposed to dengue virus. J Infect Dis. 1994;170:811&#x2013;817.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7930722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen L, Haziot A, Shen D R, Lin X-Y, Sia C, Harper R, Silver J, Goyert S M. CD14-independent responses to LPS require a serum factor that is absent from neonates. J Immunol. 1995;155:5337&#x2013;5342.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7594548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daughaday C C, Brandt W E, McCown J M, Russell P K. Evidence for two mechanisms of dengue virus infection of adherent human monocytes: trypsin-sensitive virus receptors and trypsin-resistant immune complex receptors. Infect Immun. 1981;32:469&#x2013;473.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC351468</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7251133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dudding L R, Garnett H M. Interaction of strain AD169 and a clinical isolate of cytomegalovirus with peripheral monocytes: the effect of lipopolysaccharide stimulation. J Infect Dis. 1987;155:891&#x2013;896.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3031171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frey E A, Miller D S, Jahr T G, Sundan A, Bazil V, Espevik T, Finlay B B, Wright S D. Soluble CD14 participates in the response of cells to lipopolysaccharide. J Exp Med. 1992;176:1665&#x2013;1671.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2119444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1281215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallay P, Jongeneel C V, Barras C, Burnier M, Baumgartner J-D, Glauser M P, Heumann D. Short time exposure to lipopolysaccharide is sufficient to activate human monocytes. J Immunol. 1993;150:5086&#x2013;5093.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7684419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gessani S, Testa U, Varano B, Marzio P D, Borghi P, Conti L, Barberi T, Tritarelli E, Martucci R, Seripa D, Peschle C, Belardelli F. Enhanced production of LPS-induced cytokines during differentiation of human monocytes to macrophages: role of LPS receptors. J Immunol. 1993;151:3758&#x2013;3766.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7690813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hailman E, Lichenstein H S, Wurfel M M, Miller D S, Johnson D A, Kelley M, Busse L A, Zukowski M M, Wright S D. Lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-binding protein accelerates the binding of LPS to CD14. J Exp Med. 1994;179:269&#x2013;277.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2191344</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7505800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halstead S B, O&#x2019;Rourke E J, Allison A C. Dengue viruses and mononuclear phagocytes. II. Identity of blood and tissue leukocytes supporting in vitro infection. J Exp Med. 1977;146:218&#x2013;229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2180735</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">195000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halstead S B. Pathogenesis of dengue: challenges to molecular biology. Science. 1988;239:476&#x2013;481.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3277268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haziot A, Chen S, Ferrero E, Low M G, Silber R, Goyert S M. The monocyte differentiation antigen, CD14, is anchored to the cell membrane by a phosphatidylinositol linkage. J Immunol. 1988;141:547&#x2013;552.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3385210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heumann D, Gallay P, Barras C, Zaech P, Ulevitch R J, Tobias P S, Glauser M-P, Baumgartner J D. Control of lipopolysaccharide (LPS) binding and LPS-induced tumor necrosis factor secretion in human peripheral blood monocytes. J Immunol. 1992;148:3505&#x2013;3512.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1375247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson K M. Emerging viruses in context: an overview of viral hemorrhagic fevers. In: Morse S S, editor. Emerging viruses&#x2014;1993. New York, N.Y: Oxford University Press, Inc.; 1993. pp. 46&#x2013;57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kornbluth R S, Oh P S, Munis J R, Cleveland P H, Richman D D. Interferons and bacterial lipopolysaccharide protect macrophages from productive infection by human immunodeficiency virus in vitro. J Exp Med. 1989;169:1137&#x2013;1151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2189273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2466937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krakauer T, Peters C J. Lipopolysaccharide inhibits the production of lymphocytic choriomeningitis virus in a human monocytic cell line. J Gen Virol. 1993;74:1653&#x2013;1656.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8345356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurane I, Ennis F A. Immunity and immunopathology in dengue virus infections. Semin Immunol. 1992;4:121&#x2013;127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1617166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kusunoki T, Hailman E, Juan T S-C, Lichenstein H S, Wright S D. Molecules from Staphylococcus aureus that bind CD14 and stimulate innate immune responses. J Exp Med. 1995;182:1673&#x2013;1682.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2192236</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7500012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee J D, Kato K, Tobias P S, Kirkland T N, Ulevitch R J. Transfection of CD14 into 70Z/3 cells dramatically enhances the sensitivity to complexes of lipopolysaccharide (LPS) and LPS binding protein. J Exp Med. 1992;175:1697&#x2013;1705.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2119268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1375269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee J D, Kravchenko V, Kirkland T N, Han J, Mackman N, Moriarty A, Leturcq D, Tobias P S, Ulevitch R J. GPI-anchored or integral membrane forms of CD14 mediate identical cellular responses to endotoxin. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 1993;90:9930&#x2013;9934.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC47686</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7694296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monath T P. Dengue: the risk to developed and developing countries. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 1994;91:2395&#x2013;2400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC43378</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8146129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morrison D C, Ryan J L. Endotoxins and disease mechanisms. Annu Rev Med. 1987;38:417&#x2013;432.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3555304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nain M, Hinder F, Gong J-H, Schmidt A, Bender A, Sprenger H, Gemsa D. Tumor necrosis factor-&#x3b1; production of influenza A virus-infected macrophages and potentiating effect of lipopolysaccharides. J Immunol. 1990;145:1921&#x2013;1928.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2391423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panuska J R, Merolla R, Rebert N A, Hoffmann S P, Tsivitse P, Cirino N M, Silverman R H, Rankin J A. Respiratory syncytial virus induces interleukin-10 by human alveolar macrophages. J Clin Invest. 1995;96:2445&#x2013;2453.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC185897</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7593633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pomerantz R J, Feinberg M B, Trono D, Baltimore D. Lipopolysaccharide is a potent monocyte/macrophage-specific stimulator of human immunodeficiency virus type 1 expression. J Exp Med. 1990;172:253&#x2013;261.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2188186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2193097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pugin J, Heumann D, Tomasz A, Kravchenko V V, Akamatsu Y, Nishijima M, Glauser M P, Tobias P S, Ulevitch R J. CD14 is a pattern recognition receptor. Immunity. 1994;1:509&#x2013;516.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7534618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pugin J, Schurer-Maly C C, Leturcq D, Moriarty A, Ulevitch R J, Tobias P S. Lipopolysaccharide (LPS) activation of human endothelial and epithelial cells is mediated by LPS binding protein and soluble CD14. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 1993;90:2744&#x2013;2748.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC46172</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7681988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rietschel E T, Kirikae T, Schade F U, Mamat U, Schmidt G, Loppnow H, Ulmer A J, Zahringer U, Seydel U, Padova F D, Schreier M, Brade H. Bacterial endotoxin: molecular relationships of structure to activity and function. FASEB J. 1994;8:217&#x2013;225.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8119492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schumann R R, Leong S R, Flaggs G W, Gray P W, Wright S D, Mathison J C, Tobias P S, Ulevitch R J. Structure and function of lipopolysaccharide binding protein. Science. 1990;249:1429&#x2013;1431.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2402637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaio M-F, Cheng S-N, Yuh Y-S, Yang K D. Cytotoxic factors released by dengue virus-infected human blood monocytes. J Med Virol. 1995;46:216&#x2013;223.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7561793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tobias P S, Mathison J, Mintz D, Lee J-D, Kravchenko V, Kato K, Pugin J, Ulevitch R J. Participation of lipopolysaccharide-binding protein in lipopolysaccharide-dependent macrophage activation. Am J Respir Cell Mol Biol. 1992;7:239&#x2013;245.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1381594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ulevitch R J, Tobias P S. Receptor-dependent mechanisms of cell stimulation by bacterial endotoxin. Annu Rev Immunol. 1995;13:437&#x2013;457.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7542010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vasselon T, Pironkova R, Detmers P A. Sensitive responses of leukocytes to lipopolysaccharide require a protein distinct from CD14 at the cell surface. J Immunol. 1997;159:4498&#x2013;4505.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9379050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verani A, Scarlatti G, Comar M, Tresoldi E, Polo S, Giacca M, Lusso P, Siccardi A G, Vercelli D. C-C chemokines released by lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-stimulated human macrophages suppress HIV-1 infection in both macrophages and T cells. J Exp Med. 1997;185:805&#x2013;816.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2196157</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9120386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viriyakosol S, Kirkland T N. A region of human CD14 required for lipopolysaccharide binding. J Biol Chem. 1995;270:361&#x2013;368.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7529231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S-Y, Chen L-Y, Hsu M-L, Tzeng C-H, Ho C-H, Ho C-K. Effect of lymphocytes on the production of granulomonopoietic enhancing factor by fully mature macrophages. Stem Cells. 1995;13:435&#x2013;444.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7549903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wimmer E, editor. Cellular receptors for animal viruses. Cold Spring Harbor, N.Y: Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory Press; 1994.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wright S D, Ramos R A, Tobias P S, Ulevitch R J, Mathison J C. CD14, a receptor for complexes of lipopolysaccharide (LPS) and LPS binding protein. Science. 1990;249:1431&#x2013;1433.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1698311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>