<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">10970375</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2000</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0095-1137</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>38</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2000</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of clinical microbiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Clin Microbiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Quantitative competitive reverse transcription-PCR for quantification of dengue virus RNA.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>3306</StartPage><EndPage>3310</EndPage><MedlinePgn>3306-10</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>A quantitative competitive reverse transcription-PCR assay was developed to quantify dengue virus RNA in this study. The main features include a primer pair targeting a highly conserved region in the capsid and the addition of competing RNA that contains an internal deletion to provide a stringent internal control for quantification. It can be utilized to quantify RNA isolated from the four dengue virus serotypes but not RNA isolated from other flaviviruses, including Japanese encephalitis virus and hepatitis C virus, both prevalent in Asia. It can also be used to quantify dengue virus RNA isolated from the plasma of infected individuals. The sensitivity of the assay was estimated to be 10 to 50 copies of RNA per reaction, and twofold differences in virus titer are distinguishable. This assay is a convenient, sensitive, and accurate method for quantification and can be used to further understanding of the pathogenesis of dengue virus infection.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>W K</ForeName><Initials>WK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Microbiology, Taipei, Taiwan. wwang60@yahoo.com</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>C N</ForeName><Initials>CN</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kao</LastName><ForeName>C L</ForeName><Initials>CL</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lin</LastName><ForeName>Y L</ForeName><Initials>YL</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>King</LastName><ForeName>C C</ForeName><Initials>CC</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Clin Microbiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7505564</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0095-1137</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D003470">Culture Media</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D012367">RNA, Viral</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003470" MajorTopicYN="N">Culture Media</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003715" MajorTopicYN="N">Dengue</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="Y">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003716" MajorTopicYN="N">Dengue Virus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000145" MajorTopicYN="N">classification</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="Y">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012367" MajorTopicYN="N">RNA, Viral</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="Y">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020133" MajorTopicYN="Y">Reverse Transcriptase Polymerase Chain Reaction</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012680" MajorTopicYN="N">Sensitivity and Specificity</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012703" MajorTopicYN="N">Serotyping</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2000</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2001</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2000</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10970375</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC87378</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JCM.38.9.3306-3310.2000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control. Dengue surveillance&#x2014;United States 1986&#x2013;1992. Morbid Mortal Weekly Rep. 1994;43(SS-2):7&#x2013;19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang G-J J, Trent D W, Vorndam A V, Vergne E, Kinney R M, Mitchell C J. An integrated target sequence and signal amplification assay, reverse transcriptase&#x2013;PCR&#x2013;enzyme-linked-immunosorbent assay, to detect and characterize flaviviruses. J Clin Microbiol. 1994;32:477&#x2013;483.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC263058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7512096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deubel V, Kinney R M, Trent D W. Nucleotide sequence and deduced amino sequence of the structural proteins of dengue type 2 virus, jamaica genotype. Virology. 1986;155:365&#x2013;377.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3024394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deubel V. The contribution of molecular techniques to the diagnosis of dengue infection. In: Gubler D J, Kuno G, editors. Dengue and dengue hemorrhagic fever. London, United Kingdom: CAB International; 1997. pp. 335&#x2013;366.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freeman W M, Walker S J, Vrana K E. Quantitative RT-PCR: pitfalls and potential. BioTechniques. 1999;26:112&#x2013;125.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9894600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green S, Vaughn D W, Kalayanarooj S, Nimmannitya S, Suntayakorn S, Nisalak A, Lew R, Innis B L, Kurane I, Rothman A L, Ennis F A. Early immune activation in acute dengue illness is related to development of plasma leakage and disease severity. J Infect Dis. 1999;179:755&#x2013;762.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10068569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gubler D J, Kuno G, Sather G E, Waterman S H. A case of natural concurrent human infection with two dengue viruses. Am J Trop Med Hyg. 1985;34:170&#x2013;173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3970307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gubler D J. Dengue and dengue hemorrhagic fever. Clin Microbiol Rev. 1998;11:480&#x2013;496.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC88892</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9665979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris E, Roberts G, Smith L, Selle J, Kramer L D, Valle S, Sandoval E, Balmaseda A. Typing of dengue viruses in clinical specimens and mosquitoes by single-tube multiplex reverse transcriptase PCR. J Clin Microbiol. 1998;36:2634&#x2013;2639.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC105176</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9705406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Houng H S H, Hritz D, Kanesa-thasan N. Quantitative detection of dengue 2 virus using fluorogenic RT-PCR based on 3&#x2032;-noncoding sequence. J Virol Methods. 2000;86:1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10713370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Innis B L. Dengue and dengue hemorrhagic fever. In: Porterfield J S, editor. Exotic viral infections&#x2014;1995. London, United Kingdom: Chapman &amp; Hall; 1995. pp. 103&#x2013;146.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuno G, Chang G-J J, Tsuchiya R, Karabatsos N, Cropp C B. Phylogeny of the genus Flavivirus. J Virol. 1998;72:73&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC109351</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9420202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laille M, Deubel V, Sainte-Marie F F. Demonstration of concurrent dengue 1 and dengue 3 infection in six patients by the polymerase chain reaction. J Med Virol. 1991;34:51&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1885943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lanciotti R S, Calisher C H, Gubler D J, Chang G-J, Vorndam A V. Rapid detection and typing of dengue viruses from clinical samples by using reverse transcriptase-polymerase chain reaction. J Clin Microbiol. 1992;30:545&#x2013;551.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC265106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1372617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lau J Y N, Davis G L, Kniffen J, Qian K P, Urdea M S, Chan C S, Mizokami M, Neuwald P D, Wilber J C. Significance of serum hepatitis C virus RNA levels in chronic hepatitis C. Lancet. 1993;341:1501&#x2013;1504.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8099380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laue T, Emmerich P, Schmitz H. Detection of dengue virus RNA in patients after primary or secondary dengue infection by using the TaqMan automated amplification system. J Clin Microbiol. 1999;37:2543&#x2013;2547.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC85278</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10405398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin Y-L, Liao C-L, Chen L-K, Yeh C-T, Liu C-I, Ma S-H, Huang Y-Y, Huang Y-L, Kao C-L, King C-C. Study of dengue virus infection in SCID mice engrafted with human K562 cells. J Virol. 1998;72:9729&#x2013;9737.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC110483</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9811707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lorono-Pino M A, Cropp C B, Farfan J A, Vorndam A V, Rodriguez-Angulo E M, Rosado-Paredes E P, Flores-Flores L F, Beaty B J, Gubler D J. Common occurrence of concurrent infections by multiple dengue virus serotypes. Am J Trop Med Hyg. 1999;61:725&#x2013;730.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10586902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mellors J W, Rinaldo C R, Gupta P, White R M, Todd J A, Kinsley L A. Prognosis in HIV-1 infection predicted by the quantity of virus in plasma. Science. 1996;272:1167&#x2013;1170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8638160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monath T P, Heinz F X. Flaviviruses. In: Fields B N, Knipe D M, Howley P M, et al., editors. Fields virology. Philadelphia, Pa: Lippincott-Raven Publishers; 1996. pp. 961&#x2013;1034.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monath T P. Dengue, the risk to developed and developing countries. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 1994;91:2395&#x2013;2400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC43378</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8146129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piatak M, Luk K C, Williams B, Lifson J D. Quantitative competitive polymerase chain reaction for accurate quantitation of HIV DNA and RNA species. BioTechniques. 1993;14:70&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8424881</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piatak M, Saag M S, Yang L C, Clark S J, Kappes J C, Luk K C, Hahn B H, Shaw G M, Lifson J D. High levels of HIV-1 in plasma during all stages of infection determined by competitive PCR. Science. 1993;259:1749&#x2013;1754.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8096089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shiratori Y, Kato N, Yokosuka O, Hashimoto E, Hayashi N, Nakamura A, Asada M, Kuroda H, Ohkubo H, Arakawa Y, Iwama A, Omata M. Quantitative assays for hepatitis C virus in serum as predictors of the long-term response to interferon. J Hepatol. 1997;27:437&#x2013;444.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9314119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souaze F, Ntodou-Thome A, Tran C Y, Rostene W, Forgez P. Quantitative RT-PCR: limits and accuracy. BioTechniques. 1996;21:280&#x2013;285.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8862813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudiro T M, Ishiko H, Green S, Vaughn D W, Nisalak A, Kalayanarooj S, Rothman A L, Raengsakulrach B, Janus J, Kurane I, Ennis F A. Rapid diagnosis of dengue viremia by reverse transcriptase-polymerase chain reaction using 3&#x2032;-noncoding region universal primers. Am J Trop Med Hyg. 1997;56:424&#x2013;429.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9158052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaughn D W, Green S, Kalayanarooj S, Innis B L, Nimmannitya S, Suntayakorn S, Rothman A L, Ennis F A, Nisalak A. Dengue in the early febrile phase: viremia and antibody responses. J Infect Dis. 1997;176:322&#x2013;330.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9237696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaughn D W, Green S, Kalayanarooj S, Innis B L, Nimmannitya S, Suntayakorn S, Endy T P, Raengsakulrach B, Rothman A L, Ennis F A, Nisalak A. Dengue viremia titer, antibody response pattern, and virus serotype correlate with disease severity. J Infect Dis. 2000;181:2&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10608744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vorndam V, Kuno G. Laboratory diagnosis of dengue virus infections. In: Gubler D J, Kuno G, editors. Dengue and dengue hemorrhagic fever. London, United Kingdom: CAB International; 1997. pp. 313&#x2013;334.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Dengue hemorrhagic fever, diagnosis, treatment and control. Geneva, Switzerland: World Health Organization; 1986.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>