<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">11907199</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2002</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>19</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2019</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0022-538X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>76</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2002</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of virology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Virol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Antiviral effects of an iminosugar derivative on flavivirus infections.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>3596</StartPage><EndPage>3604</EndPage><MedlinePgn>3596-604</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>Endoplasmic reticulum (ER) alpha-glucosidase inhibitors, which block the trimming step of N-linked glycosylation, have been shown to eliminate the production of several ER-budding viruses. Here we investigated the effects of one such inhibitor, N-nonyl-deoxynojirimycin (NN-DNJ), a 9-carbon alkyl iminosugar derivative, on infection by Japanese encephalitis virus (JEV) and dengue virus serotype 2 (DEN-2). In the presence of NN-DNJ, JEV and DEN-2 infections were suppressed in a dose-dependent manner. This inhibitory effect appeared to influence DEN-2 infection more than JEV infection, since lower concentrations of NN-DNJ substantially blocked DEN-2 replication. Secretion of the flaviviral glycoproteins E and NS1 was greatly reduced, and levels of DEN-2 viral RNA replication measured by fluorogenic reverse transcription-PCR were also decreased, by NN-DNJ. Notably, the viral glycoproteins, prM, E, and NS1 were found to associate transiently with the ER chaperone calnexin, and this interaction was affected by NN-DNJ, suggesting a potential role of calnexin in the folding of flaviviral glycoproteins. Additionally, in a mouse model of lethal challenge by JEV infection, oral delivery of NN-DNJ reduced the mortality rate. These findings show that NN-DNJ has an antiviral effect on flavivirus infection, likely through interference with virus replication at the posttranslational modification level, occurring mainly in the ER.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Shu-Fen</ForeName><Initials>SF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate Institute of Life Sciences, National Defense Medical Center and Institute of Biomedical Sciences, Academia Sinica, Taipei, Taiwan, Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Chyan-Jang</ForeName><Initials>CJ</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liao</LastName><ForeName>Ching-Len</ForeName><Initials>CL</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dwek</LastName><ForeName>Raymond A</ForeName><Initials>RA</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zitzmann</LastName><ForeName>Nicole</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lin</LastName><ForeName>Yi-Ling</ForeName><Initials>YL</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Virol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0113724</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0022-538X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000998">Antiviral Agents</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D065089">Glycoside Hydrolase Inhibitors</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C112150">N-nonyl-1-deoxynojirimycin</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>19130-96-2</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D017485">1-Deoxynojirimycin</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017485" MajorTopicYN="N">1-Deoxynojirimycin</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000031" MajorTopicYN="Y">analogs &amp; derivatives</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="Y">pharmacology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000998" MajorTopicYN="N">Antiviral Agents</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="Y">pharmacology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002460" MajorTopicYN="N">Cell Line</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006224" MajorTopicYN="N">Cricetinae</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003715" MajorTopicYN="N">Dengue</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="N">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003716" MajorTopicYN="N">Dengue Virus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="Y">drug effects</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004664" MajorTopicYN="N">Encephalitis Virus, Japanese</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="Y">drug effects</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004672" MajorTopicYN="N">Encephalitis, Japanese</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="Y">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="N">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D065089" MajorTopicYN="N">Glycoside Hydrolase Inhibitors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051379" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008813" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice, Inbred ICR</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2002</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2002</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2002</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11907199</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC136089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/jvi.76.8.3596-3604.2002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Allison, S. L., J. Schalich, K. Stiasny, C. W. Mandl, C. Kunz, and F. X. Heinz. 1995. Oligomeric rearrangement of tick-borne encephalitis virus envelope proteins induced by an acidic pH. J. Virol. 69:695-700.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC188630</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7529335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alper, J. 2001. Saving lives with sugar. Science 291:2339..</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11269309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alper, J. 2001. Searching for medicine's sweet spot. Science 291:2338-2343.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11269308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Block, T. M., X. Lu, A. S. Mehta, B. S. Blumberg, B. Tennant, M. Ebling, B. Korba, D. M. Lansky, G. S. Jacob, and R. A. Dwek. 1998. Treatment of chronic hepadnavirus infection in a woodchuck animal model with an inhibitor of protein folding and trafficking. Nat. Med. 4:610-614.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9585237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Block, T. M., X. Lu, F. M. Platt, G. R. Foster, W. H. Gerlich, B. S. Blumberg, and R. A. Dwek. 1994. Secretion of human hepatitis B virus is inhibited by the imino sugar N-butyldeoxynojirimycin. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA 91:2235-2239.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC43345</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8134380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Branza-Nichita, N., D. Durantel, S. Carrouee-Durantel, R. A. Dwek, and N. Zitzmann. 2001. Antiviral effect of N-butyldeoxynojirimycin against bovine viral diarrhea virus correlates with misfolding of E2 envelope proteins and impairment of their association into E1-E2 heterodimers. J. Virol. 75:3527-3536.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC114844</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11264342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chambers, T. J., C. S. Hahn, R. Galler, and C. M. Rice. 1990. Flavivirus genome organization, expression, and replication. Annu. Rev. Microbiol. 44:649-688.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2174669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, L. K., C. L. Liao, C. G. Lin, S. C. Lai, C. I. Liu, S. H. Ma, Y. Y. Huang, and Y. L. Lin. 1996. Persistence of Japanese encephalitis virus is associated with abnormal expression of the nonstructural protein NS1 in host cells. Virology 217:220-229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8599206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, L. K., Y. L. Lin, C. L. Liao, C. G. Lin, Y. L. Huang, C. T. Yeh, S. C. Lai, J. T. Jan, and C. Chin. 1996. Generation and characterization of organ-tropism mutants of Japanese encephalitis virus in vivo and in vitro. Virology 223:79-88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8806542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Courageot, M. P., M. P. Frenkiel, C. D. Dos Santos, V. Deubel, and P. Despres. 2000. Alpha-glucosidase inhibitors reduce dengue virus production by affecting the initial steps of virion morphogenesis in the endoplasmic reticulum. J. Virol. 74:564-572.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC111573</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10590151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durantel, D., N. Branza-Nichita, S. Carrouee-Durantel, T. D. Butters, R. A. Dwek, and N. Zitzmann. 2001. Study of the mechanism of antiviral action of iminosugar derivatives against bovine viral diarrhea virus. J. Virol. 75:8987-8998.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC114467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11533162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fischer, P. B., M. Collin, G. B. Karlsson, W. James, T. D. Butters, S. J. Davis, S. Gordon, R. A. Dwek, and F. M. Platt. 1995. The alpha-glucosidase inhibitor N-butyldeoxynojirimycin inhibits human immunodeficiency virus entry at the level of post-CD4 binding. J. Virol. 69:5791-5797.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC189444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7543588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fischer, P. B., G. B. Karlsson, T. D. Butters, R. A. Dwek, and F. M. Platt. 1996. N-Butyldeoxynojirimycin-mediated inhibition of human immunodeficiency virus entry correlates with changes in antibody recognition of the V1/V2 region of gp120. J. Virol. 70:7143-7152.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC190767</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8794361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gelman, M. S., W. Chang, D. Y. Thomas, J. J. Bergeron, and J. M. Prives. 1995. Role of the endoplasmic reticulum chaperone calnexin in subunit folding and assembly of nicotinic acetylcholine receptors. J. Biol. Chem. 270:15085-15092.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7797492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gruters, R. A., J. J. Neefjes, M. Tersmette, R. E. de Goede, A. Tulp, H. G. Huisman, F. Miedema, and H. L. Ploegh. 1987. Interference with HIV-induced syncytium formation and viral infectivity by inhibitors of trimming glucosidase. Nature 330:74-77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2959866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gubler, D. J. 1998. Dengue and dengue hemorrhagic fever. Clin. Microbiol. Rev. 11:480-496.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC88892</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9665979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hammond, C., I. Braakman, and A. Helenius. 1994. Role of N-linked oligosaccharide recognition, glucose trimming, and calnexin in glycoprotein folding and quality control. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA 91:913-917.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC521423</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8302866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hebert, D. N., B. Foellmer, and A. Helenius. 1995. Glucose trimming and reglucosylation determine glycoprotein association with calnexin in the endoplasmic reticulum. Cell 81:425-433.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7736594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hebert, D. N., J. F. Simons, J. R. Peterson, and A. Helenius. 1995. Calnexin, calreticulin, and Bip/Kar2p in protein folding. Cold Spring Harbor Symp. Quant. Biol. 60:405-415.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8824414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helenius, A., and M. Aebi. 2001. Intracellular functions of N-linked glycans. Science 291:2364-2369.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11269317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Houng, H. H., D. Hritz, and N. Kanesa-thasan. 2000. Quantitative detection of dengue 2 virus using fluorogenic RT-PCR based on 3&#x2032;-noncoding sequence. J. Virol. Methods 86:1-11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10713370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacob, G. S. 1995. Glycosylation inhibitors in biology and medicine. Curr. Opin. Struct. Biol. 5:605-611.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8574695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karlsson, G. B., T. D. Butters, R. A. Dwek, and F. M. Platt. 1993. Effects of the imino sugar N-butyldeoxynojirimycin on the N-glycosylation of recombinant gp120. J. Biol. Chem. 268:570-576.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8416962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karpas, A., G. W. Fleet, R. A. Dwek, S. Petursson, S. K. Namgoong, N. G. Ramsden, G. S. Jacob, and T. W. Rademacher. 1988. Aminosugar derivatives as potential anti-human immunodeficiency virus agents. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA 85:9229-9233.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC282712</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3264071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lanciotti, R. S., J. T. Roehrig, V. Deubel, J. Smith, M. Parker, K. Steele, B. Crise, K. E. Volpe, M. B. Crabtree, J. H. Scherret, R. A. Hall, J. S. MacKenzie, C. B. Cropp, B. Panigrahy, E. Ostlund, B. Schmitt, M. Malkinson, C. Banet, J. Weissman, N. Komar, H. M. Savage, W. Stone, T. McNamara, and D. J. Gubler. 1999. Origin of the West Nile virus responsible for an outbreak of encephalitis in the northeastern United States. Science 286:2333-2337.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10600742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, Y. L., L. K. Chen, C. L. Liao, C. T. Yeh, S. H. Ma, J. L. Chen, Y. L. Huang, S. S. Chen, and H. Y. Chiang. 1998. DNA immunization with Japanese encephalitis virus nonstructural protein NS1 elicits protective immunity in mice. J. Virol. 72:191-200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC109364</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9420215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, Y. L., C. L. Liao, L. K. Chen, C. T. Yeh, C. I. Liu, S. H. Ma, Y. Y. Huang, Y. L. Huang, C. L. Kao, and C. C. King. 1998. Study of Dengue virus infection in SCID mice engrafted with human K562 cells. J. Virol. 72:9729-9737.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC110483</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9811707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindenbach, B. D., and C. M. Rice. 1997. trans-Complementation of yellow fever virus NS1 reveals a role in early RNA replication. J. Virol. 71:9608-9617.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC230269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9371625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackenzie, J. M., M. K. Jones, and P. R. Young. 1996. Immunolocalization of the dengue virus nonstructural glycoprotein NS1 suggests a role in viral RNA replication. Virology 220:232-240.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8659120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehta, A., S. Carrouee, B. Conyers, R. Jordan, T. Butters, R. A. Dwek, and T. M. Block. 2001. Inhibition of hepatitis B virus DNA replication by imino sugars without the inhibition of the DNA polymerase: therapeutic implications. Hepatology 33:1488-1495.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11391538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehta, A., X. Lu, T. M. Block, B. S. Blumberg, and R. A. Dwek. 1997. Hepatitis B virus (HBV) envelope glycoproteins vary drastically in their sensitivity to glycan processing: evidence that alteration of a single N-linked glycosylation site can regulate HBV secretion. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA 94:1822-1827.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC20001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9050863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehta, A., N. Zitzmann, P. M. Rudd, T. M. Block, and R. A. Dwek. 1998. Alpha-glucosidase inhibitors as potential broad based anti-viral agents. FEBS Lett. 430:17-22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9678587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mellor, H. R., A. Adam, F. M. Platt, R. A. Dwek, and T. D. Butters. 2000. High-performance cation-exchange chromatography and pulsed amperometric detection for the separation, detection, and quantitation of N-alkylated imino sugars in biological samples. Anal. Biochem. 284:136-142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10933866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monath, T. P. 1994. Dengue: the risk to developed and developing countries. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA 91:2395-2400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC43378</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8146129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monath, T. P., and F. X. Heinz. 1996. Flaviviruses, p. 961-1034. In B. N. Fields, D. M. Knipe, and P. M. Howley (ed.), Fields virology, 3rd ed. Lippincott-Raven Publishers, Philadelphia, Pa.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muylaert, I. R., T. J. Chambers, R. Galler, and C. M. Rice. 1996. Mutagenesis of the N-linked glycosylation sites of the yellow fever virus NS1 protein: effects on virus replication and mouse neurovirulence. Virology 222:159-168.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8806496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muylaert, I. R., R. Galler, and C. M. Rice. 1997. Genetic analysis of the yellow fever virus NS1 protein: identification of a temperature-sensitive mutation which blocks RNA accumulation. J. Virol. 71:291-298.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC191050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8985349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ou, W. J., P. H. Cameron, D. Y. Thomas, and J. J. Bergeron. 1993. Association of folding intermediates of glycoproteins with calnexin during protein maturation. Nature 364:771-776.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8102790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parodi, A. J. 2000. Protein glucosylation and its role in protein folding. Annu. Rev. Biochem. 69:69-93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10966453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rice, C. M. 1996. Flaviviridae: the viruses and their replication, p. 931-959. In B. N. Fields, D. M. Knipe, and P. M. Howley (ed.), Fields virology, 3rd ed. Lippincott-Raven Publishers, Philadelphia, Pa.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robertson, S. E., B. P. Hull, O. Tomori, O. Bele, J. W. LeDuc, and K. Esteves. 1996. Yellow fever: a decade of reemergence. JAMA 276:1157-1162.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8827969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodan, A. R., J. F. Simons, E. S. Trombetta, and A. Helenius. 1996. N-linked oligosaccharides are necessary and sufficient for association of glycosylated forms of bovine RNase with calnexin and calreticulin. EMBO J. 15:6921-6930.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC452518</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9003768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schlesinger, S., A. H. Koyama, C. Malfer, S. L. Gee, and M. J. Schlesinger. 1985. The effects of inhibitors of glucosidase I on the formation of Sindbis virus. Virus Res. 2:139-149.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3158136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schlesinger, S., C. Malfer, and M. J. Schlesinger. 1984. The formation of vesicular stomatitis virus (San Juan strain) becomes temperature-sensitive when glucose residues are retained on the oligosaccharides of the glycoprotein. J. Biol. Chem. 259:7597-7601.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6330065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solomon, T., R. Kneen, N. M. Dung, V. C. Khanh, T. T. Thuy, D. Q. Ha, N. P. Day, A. Nisalak, D. W. Vaughn, and N. J. White. 1998. Poliomyelitis-like illness due to Japanese encephalitis virus. Lancet 351:1094-1097.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9660579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan, A., L. van den Broek, S. van Boeckel, H. Ploegh, and J. Bolscher. 1991. Chemical modification of the glucosidase inhibitor 1-deoxynojirimycin. Structure-activity relationships. J. Biol. Chem. 266:14504-14510.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1650361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor, D. L., L. E. Fellows, G. H. Farrar, R. J. Nash, D. Taylor-Robinson, M. A. Mobberley, T. A. Ryder, D. J. Jeffries, and A. S. Tyms. 1988. Loss of cytomegalovirus infectivity after treatment with castanospermine or related plant alkaloids correlates with aberrant glycoprotein synthesis. Antivir. Res 10:11-26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7134106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2852915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomori, O. 1999. Impact of yellow fever on the developing world. Adv. Virus Res. 53:5-34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10582093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wada, I., D. Rindress, P. H. Cameron, W. J. Ou, J. J. Doherty II, D. Louvard, A. W. Bell, D. Dignard, D. Y. Thomas, and J. J. Bergeron. 1991. SSR alpha and associated calnexin are major calcium binding proteins of the endoplasmic reticulum membrane. J. Biol. Chem. 266:19599-19610.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1918067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walker, B. D., M. Kowalski, W. C. Goh, K. Kozarsky, M. Krieger, C. Rosen, L. Rohrschneider, W. A. Haseltine, and J. Sodroski. 1987. Inhibition of human immunodeficiency virus syncytium formation and virus replication by castanospermine. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA 84:8120-8124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC299490</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2825177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zitzmann, N., A. S. Mehta, S. Carrouee, T. D. Butters, F. M. Platt, J. McCauley, B. S. Blumberg, R. A. Dwek, and T. M. Block. 1999. Imino sugars inhibit the formation and secretion of bovine viral diarrhea virus, a pestivirus model of hepatitis C virus: implications for the development of broad-spectrum anti-hepatitis virus agents. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA 96:11878-11882.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC18380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10518544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>