<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">12208965</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2002</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>30</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2019</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0022-538X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>76</Volume><Issue>19</Issue><PubDate><Year>2002</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of virology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Virol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Activation of terminally differentiated human monocytes/macrophages by dengue virus: productive infection, hierarchical production of innate cytokines and chemokines, and the synergistic effect of lipopolysaccharide.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>9877</StartPage><EndPage>9887</EndPage><MedlinePgn>9877-87</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>Dengue virus (DV) primarily infects blood monocytes (MO) and tissue macrophages (M phi). We have shown in the present study that DV can productively infect primary human MO/M phi regardless of the stage of cell differentiation. After DV infection, the in vitro-differentiated MO/M phi secreted multiple innate cytokines and chemokines, including tumor necrosis factor alpha, alpha interferon (IFN-alpha), interleukin-1 beta (IL-1 beta), IL-8, IL-12, MIP-1 alpha, and RANTES but not IL-6, IL-15, or nitric oxide. Secretion of these mediators was highlighted by distinct magnitude, onset, kinetics, duration, and induction potential. A chemokine-to-cytokine hierarchy was noted in the magnitude and induction potential of secretion, and a chemokine-to-cytokine-to-chemokine/Th1 cytokine cascade could be seen in the production kinetics. Furthermore, we found that terminally differentiated MO/M phi cultured for more than 45 days could support productive DV infection and produce innate cytokines and chemokines, indicating that these mature cells were functionally competent in the context of a viral infection. In addition, DV replication in primary differentiated human MO/M phi was enhanced and prolonged in the presence of lipopolysaccharide (LPS), and LPS-mediated synergistic production of IFN-alpha could be seen in DV-infected MO/M phi. The secretion of innate cytokines and chemokines by differentiated MO/M phi suggests that regional accumulation of these mediators may occur in various tissues to which DV has disseminated and may thus result in local inflammation. The LPS-mediated enhancement of virus replication and synergistic IFN-alpha production suggests that concurrent bacterial infection may modulate cytokine-mediated disease progression during DV infection.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Yun-Chi</ForeName><Initials>YC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Hematology, Department of Medical Research and Education, Veterans General Hospital-Taipei, Taipei, Taiwan, Republic of China. yun-chi.chen@path.ox.ac.uk</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Sheng-Yuan</ForeName><Initials>SY</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Virol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0113724</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0022-538X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D018925">Chemokines</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D016207">Cytokines</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D016898">Interferon-alpha</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D008070">Lipopolysaccharides</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002454" MajorTopicYN="N">Cell Differentiation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002478" MajorTopicYN="N">Cells, Cultured</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018925" MajorTopicYN="N">Chemokines</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000096" MajorTopicYN="Y">biosynthesis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016207" MajorTopicYN="N">Cytokines</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000096" MajorTopicYN="Y">biosynthesis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003713" MajorTopicYN="N">Dendritic Cells</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003716" MajorTopicYN="N">Dengue Virus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016898" MajorTopicYN="N">Interferon-alpha</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000096" MajorTopicYN="N">biosynthesis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008070" MajorTopicYN="N">Lipopolysaccharides</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="Y">pharmacology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008262" MajorTopicYN="Y">Macrophage Activation</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="N">drug effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008264" MajorTopicYN="N">Macrophages</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="Y">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009000" MajorTopicYN="N">Monocytes</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="Y">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014779" MajorTopicYN="N">Virus Replication</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="Y">drug effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2002</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2002</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2002</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12208965</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC136495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/jvi.76.19.9877-9887.2002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Adler, H., T. W. Jungi, H. Pfister, M. Strasser, M. Sileghem, and E. Peterhans. 1996. Cytokine regulation by virus infection: bovine viral diarrhea virus, a flavivirus, downregulates production of tumor necrosis factor alpha in macrophages in vitro. J. Virol. 70:2650-2653.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC190117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8642701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson, R., S. Wang, C. Osiowy, and A. C. Issekutz. 1997. Activation of endothelial cells via antibody-enhanced dengue virus infection of peripheral blood monocytes. J. Virol. 71:4226-4232.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC191637</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9151809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avirutnan, P., P. Malasit, B. Seliger, S. Bhakdi, and M. Husmann. 1998. Dengue virus infection of human endothelial cells leads to chemokine production, complement activation, and apoptosis. J. Immunol. 161:6338-6346.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9834124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babiuk, L. A., M. J. Lawman, and H. B. Ohmann. 1988. Viral-bacterial synergistic interaction in respiratory disease. Adv. Virus Res. 35:219-249.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7172562</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3148270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barnes, W. J., and L. Rosen. 1974. Fatal hemorrhagic disease and shock associated with primary dengue infection on a Pacific island. Am. J. Trop. Med. Hyg. 23:495-506.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4150910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biron, C. A. 1998. Role of early cytokines, including alpha and beta interferons (IFN-alpha/beta), in innate and adaptive immune responses to viral infections. Semin. Immunol. 10:383-390.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9799713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biron, C. A., K. B. Nguyen, G. C. Pien, L. P. Cousens, and T. P. Salazar-Mather. 1999. Natural killer cells in antiviral defense: function and regulation by innate cytokines. Annu. Rev. Immunol. 17:189-220.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10358757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaturvedi, U. C., R. Agarwal, E. A. Elbishbishi, and A. S. Mustafa. 2000. Cytokine cascade in dengue hemorrhagic fever: implications for pathogenesis. FEMS Immunol. Med. Microbiol. 28:183-188.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10865168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chehimi, J., S. E. Starr, I. Frank, A. D'Andrea, X. Ma, R. R. MacGregor, J. Sennelier, and G. Trinchieri. 1994. Impaired interleukin 12 production in human immunodeficiency virus-infected patients. J. Exp. Med. 179:1361-1366.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2191451</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7908324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, Y. C., S. Y. Wang, and C. C. King. 1999. Bacterial lipopolysaccharide inhibits dengue virus infection of primary human monocytes/macrophages by blockade of virus entry via a CD14-dependent mechanism. J. Virol. 73:2650-2657.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC104020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10074110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook, D. N., M. A. Beck, T. M. Coffman, S. L. Kirby, J. F. Sheridan, I. B. Pragnell, and O. Smithies. 1995. Requirement of MIP-1 alpha for an inflammatory response to viral infection. Science 269:1583-1585.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7667639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doughty, L. A., K. B. Nguyen, J. E. Durbin, and C. A. Biron. 2001. A role for IFN-&#x3b1;&#x3b2; in virus infection-induced sensitization to endotoxin. J. Immunol. 166:2658-2664.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11160329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dudding, L. R., and H. M. Garnett. 1987. Interaction of strain AD169 and a clinical isolate of cytomegalovirus with peripheral monocytes: the effect of lipopolysaccharide stimulation. J. Infect. Dis. 155:891-896.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3031171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eram, S., Y. Setyabudi, T. I. Sadono, D. S. Sutrisno, D. J. Gubler, and J. Sulianti Saroso. 1979. Epidemic dengue hemorrhagic fever in rural Indonesia. II. Clinical studies. Am. J. Trop. Med. Hyg. 28:711-716.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">464192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farrar, J. D., and K. M. Murphy. 2000. Type I interferons and T helper development. Immunol. Today 21:484-489.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11071526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furie, M. B., and G. J. Randolph. 1995. Chemokines and tissue injury. Am. J. Pathol. 146:1287-1301.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1870893</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7778669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gale, L. M., and S. R. McColl. 1999. Chemokines: extracellular messengers for all occasions? Bioessays 21:17-28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10070251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon, S. 1995. The macrophage. Bioessays 17:977-986.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8526892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon, S., S. Keshav, and L. P. Chung. 1988. Mononuclear phagocytes: tissue distribution and functional heterogeneity. Curr. Opin. Immunol. 1:26-35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3077297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gubler, D. J. 1998. Dengue and dengue hemorrhagic fever. Clin. Microbiol Rev. 11:480-496.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC88892</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9665979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gubler, D. J., and M. Meltzer. 1999. Impact of dengue/dengue hemorrhagic fever on the developing world. Adv. Virus Res. 53:35-70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10582094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halstead, S. B. 1988. Pathogenesis of dengue: challenges to molecular biology. Science 239:476-481.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3277268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halstead, S. B., and E. J. O'Rourke. 1977. Dengue viruses and mononuclear phagocytes. I. Infection enhancement by nonneutralizing antibody. J. Exp. Med. 146:201-217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2180729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">406347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayes, M. P., J. C. Enterline, T. L. Gerrard, and K. C. Zoon. 1991. Regulation of interferon production by human monocytes: requirements for priming for lipopolysaccharide-induced production. J. Leukoc. Biol. 50:176-181.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1649241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ibanez, C. E., R. Schrier, P. Ghazal, C. Wiley, and J. A. Nelson. 1991. Human cytomegalovirus productively infects primary differentiated macrophages. J. Virol. 65:6581-6588.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC250717</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1658363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karp, C. L., M. Wysocka, L. M. Wahl, J. M. Ahearn, P. J. Cuomo, B. Sherry, G. Trinchieri, and D. E. Griffin. 1996. Mechanism of suppression of cell-mediated immunity by measles virus. Science 273:228-231.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8662504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>King, C. A., J. S. Marshall, H. Alshurafa, and R. Anderson. 2000. Release of vasoactive cytokines by antibody-enhanced dengue virus infection of a human mast cell/basophil line. J. Virol. 74:7146-7150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC112233</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10888655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kreipe, H., H. J. Radzun, P. Rudolph, J. Barth, M. L. Hansmann, K. Heidorn, and M. R. Parwaresch. 1988. Multinucleated giant cells generated in vitro. Terminally differentiated macrophages with down-regulated c-fms expression. Am. J. Pathol. 130:232-243.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1880510</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2963546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krilov, L. R., R. M. Hendry, E. Godfrey, and K. McIntosh. 1987. Respiratory virus infection of peripheral blood monocytes: correlation with ageing of cells and interferon production in vitro. J. Gen. Virol. 68:1749-1753.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3035067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuberski, T., L. Rosen, D. Reed, and J. Mataika. 1977. Clinical and laboratory observations on patients with primary and secondary dengue type 1 infections with hemorrhagic manifestations in Fiji. Am. J. Trop. Med. Hyg. 26:775-783.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">889017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurane, I., and F. A. Ennis. 1994. Cytotoxic T lymphocytes in dengue virus infection. Curr. Top. Microbiol. Immunol. 189:93-108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7924440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurane, I., and F. A. Ennis. 1988. Production of interferon alpha by dengue virus-infected human monocytes. J. Gen. Virol. 69:445-449.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3339332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurane, I., B. L. Innis, S. Nimmannitya, A. Nisalak, A. Meager, and F. A. Ennis. 1993. High levels of interferon alpha in the sera of children with dengue virus infection. Am. J. Trop. Med. Hyg. 48:222-229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8447527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurane, I., B. L. Innis, S. Nimmannitya, A. Nisalak, A. Meager, J. Janus, and F. A. Ennis. 1991. Activation of T lymphocytes in dengue virus infections. High levels of soluble interleukin 2 receptor, soluble CD4, soluble CD8, interleukin 2, and interferon-gamma in sera of children with dengue. J. Clin. Investig. 88:1473-1480.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC295652</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1939640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larregina, A. T., A. E. Morelli, L. A. Spencer, A. J. Logar, S. C. Watkins, A. W. Thomson, and L. D. Falo, Jr. 2001. Dermal-resident CD14+ cells differentiate into Langerhans cells. Nat. Immunol. 2:1151-1158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11702065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lechner, F., J. Machado, G. Bertoni, H. F. Seow, D. A. Dobbelaere, and E. Peterhans. 1997. Caprine arthritis encephalitis virus dysregulates the expression of cytokines in macrophages. J. Virol. 71:7488-7497.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC192095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9311828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, C. H., Y. H. Choi, S. H. Yang, C. W. Lee, S. J. Ha, and Y. C. Sung. 2001. Hepatitis C virus core protein inhibits interleukin 12 and nitric oxide production from activated macrophages. Virology 279:271-279.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11145908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, D. H., S. S. Tam, S. Benyoucef, D. De Groote, V. Deubel, and P. Wattre. 1996. Enhanced TNF alpha production by monocytic-like cells exposed to dengue virus antigens. Immunol. Lett. 53:115-120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9024988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Libraty, D. H., S. Pichyangkul, C. Ajariyakhajorn, T. P. Endy, and F. A. Ennis. 2001. Human dendritic cells are activated by dengue virus infection: enhancement by gamma interferon and implications for disease pathogenesis. J. Virol. 75:3501-3508.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC114841</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11264339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma, X., J. Sun, E. Papasavvas, H. Riemann, S. Robertson, J. Marshall, R. T. Bailer, A. Moore, R. P. Donnelly, G. Trinchieri, and L. J. Montaner. 2000. Inhibition of IL-12 production in human monocyte-derived macrophages by TNF. J. Immunol. 164:1722-1729.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10657616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marianneau, P., A. M. Steffan, C. Royer, M. T. Drouet, D. Jaeck, A. Kirn, and V. Deubel. 1999. Infection of primary cultures of human Kupffer cells by Dengue virus: no viral progeny synthesis, but cytokine production is evident. J. Virol. 73:5201-5206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC112571</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10233989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marrack, P., J. Kappler, and T. Mitchell. 1999. Type I interferons keep activated T cells alive. J. Exp. Med. 189:521-530.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2192920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9927514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murgue, B., O. Cassar, X. Deparis, M. Guigon, and E. Chungue. 1998. Implication of macrophage inflammatory protein-1&#x3b1; in the inhibition of human haematopoietic progenitor growth by dengue virus. J. Gen. Virol. 79:1889-1893.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9714236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen, K. B., and C. A. Biron. 1999. Synergism for cytokine-mediated disease during concurrent endotoxin and viral challenges: roles for NK and T cell IFN-gamma production. J. Immunol. 162:5238-5246.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10227998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Sullivan, M. A., and H. M. Killen. 1994. The differentiation state of monocytic cells affects their susceptibility to infection and the effects of infection by dengue virus. J. Gen. Virol. 75:2387-2392.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8077937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pelus, L. M., O. G. Ottmann, and K. H. Nocka. 1988. Synergistic inhibition of human marrow granulocyte-macrophage progenitor cells by prostaglandin E and recombinant interferon-alpha, -beta, and -gamma and an effect mediated by tumor necrosis factor. J. Immunol. 140:479-484.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3121745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Randolph, G. J., K. Inaba, D. F. Robbiani, R. M. Steinman, and W. A. Muller. 1999. Differentiation of phagocytic monocytes into lymph node dendritic cells in vivo. Immunity 11:753-761.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10626897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rich, E. A., I. S. Chen, J. A. Zack, M. L. Leonard, and W. A. O'Brien. 1992. Increased susceptibility of differentiated mononuclear phagocytes to productive infection with human immunodeficiency virus-1 (HIV-1). J. Clin. Investig. 89:176-183.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC442834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1370293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rollins, B. J. 1997. Chemokines. Blood 90:909-928.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9242519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rothman, A. L., and F. A. Ennis. 1999. Immunopathogenesis of Dengue hemorrhagic fever. Virology 257:1-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10208914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salazar-Mather, T. P., T. A. Hamilton, and C. A. Biron. 2000. A chemokine-to-cytokine-to-chemokine cascade critical in antiviral defense. J. Clin. Investig. 105:985-993.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC377490</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10749577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salazar-Mather, T. P., J. S. Orange, and C. A. Biron. 1998. Early murine cytomegalovirus (MCMV) infection induces liver natural killer (NK) cell inflammation and protection through macrophage inflammatory protein 1&#x3b1; (MIP-1&#x3b1;)-dependent pathways. J. Exp. Med. 187:1-14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2199190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9419206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sallusto, F., and A. Lanzavecchia. 1994. Efficient presentation of soluble antigen by cultured human dendritic cells is maintained by granulocyte/macrophage colony-stimulating factor plus interleukin 4 and downregulated by tumor necrosis factor alpha. J. Exp. Med. 179:1109-1118.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2191432</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8145033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schall, T. J., K. Bacon, K. J. Toy, and D. V. Goeddel. 1990. Selective attraction of monocytes and T lymphocytes of the memory phenotype by cytokine RANTES. Nature 347:669-671.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1699135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spain-Santana, T. A., S. Marglin, F. A. Ennis, and A. L. Rothman. 2001. MIP-1 alpha and MIP-1 beta induction by dengue virus. J. Med. Virol. 65:324-330.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11536240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stockl, J., H. Vetr, O. Majdic, G. Zlabinger, E. Kuechler, and W. Knapp. 1999. Human major group rhinoviruses downmodulate the accessory function of monocytes by inducing IL-10. J. Clin. Investig. 104:957-965.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC408557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10510336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Streatfield, R., G. Bielby, and D. Sinclair. 1993. A primary dengue 2 epidemic with spontaneous haemorrhagic manifestations. Lancet 342:560-561.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8102703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taoufik, Y., O. Lantz, C. Wallon, A. Charles, E. Dussaix, and J. F. Delfraissy. 1997. Human immunodeficiency virus gp120 inhibits interleukin-12 secretion by human monocytes: an indirect interleukin-10-mediated effect. Blood 89:2842-2848.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9108403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Temonen, M., H. Lankinen, O. Vapalahti, T. Ronni, I. Julkunen, and A. Vaheri. 1995. Effect of interferon-alpha and cell differentiation on Puumala virus infection in human monocyte/macrophages. Virology 206:8-15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7831843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trinchieri, G. 1998. Interleukin-12: a cytokine at the interface of inflammation and immunity. Adv. Immunol. 70:83-243.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9755338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tuttle, D. L., J. K. Harrison, C. Anders, J. W. Sleasman, and M. M. Goodenow. 1998. Expression of CCR5 increases during monocyte differentiation and directly mediates macrophage susceptibility to infection by human immunodeficiency virus type 1. J. Virol. 72:4962-4969.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC110058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9573265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, S. Y., H. Castro-Malaspina, L. Lu, and M. A. Moore. 1985. Biological characterization of a granulomonopoietic enhancing activity derived from cultured human lipid-containing macrophages. Blood 65:1181-1190.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3873261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, S. Y., H. Castro-Malaspina, and M. A. Moore. 1985. Long-term culture of human bone marrow macrophages: macrophage development is associated with the production of granulomonopoietic enhancing activity (GM-EA). J. Immunol. 135:1186-1193.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3891852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, S. Y., C. K. Ho, L. Y. Chen, R. C. Wang, M. H. Huang, H. Castro-Malaspina, and M. A. Moore. 1988. Down regulation of myelopoiesis by mediators inhibiting the production of macrophage-derived granulomonopoietic enhancing activity (GM-EA). Blood 72:2001-2006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3143428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, S. Y., K. L. Mak, L. Y. Chen, M. P. Chou, and C. K. Ho. 1992. Heterogeneity of human blood monocyte: two subpopulations with different sizes, phenotypes and functions. Immunology 77:298-303.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1421624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1427982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watts, D. M., K. R. Porter, P. Putvatana, B. Vasquez, C. Calampa, C. G. Hayes, and S. B. Halstead. 1999. Failure of secondary infection with American genotype dengue 2 to cause dengue haemorrhagic fever. Lancet 354:1431-1434.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10543670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, S. J., G. Grouard-Vogel, W. Sun, J. R. Mascola, E. Brachtel, R. Putvatana, M. K. Louder, L. Filgueira, M. A. Marovich, H. K. Wong, A. Blauvelt, G. S. Murphy, M. L. Robb, B. L. Innes, D. L. Birx, C. G. Hayes, and S. S. Frankel. 2000. Human skin Langerhans cells are targets of dengue virus infection. Nat. Med. 6:816-820.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10888933</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>