<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">15184425</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2004</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>29</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0095-1137</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>42</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2004</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of clinical microbiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Clin Microbiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Dengue virus serotyping based on envelope and membrane and nonstructural protein NS1 serotype-specific capture immunoglobulin M enzyme-linked immunosorbent assays.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2489</StartPage><EndPage>2494</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2489-94</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>Envelope and membrane (E/M) and nonstructural protein NS1 serotype-specific capture Immunoglobulin M (IgM) enzyme-linked immunosorbent assays (ELISAs) were developed to differentiate four dengue virus serotypes. A total of 93 anti-dengue virus IgM-positive serum samples collected between days 5 and 45 of illness from 59 confirmed dengue patients were analyzed. The results showed that positive serotype specificity could be identified for 86.1 and 47.6% of serum samples tested for E/M-specific IgM antibodies versus 83.3 and 42.9% of serum samples tested for NS1-specific IgM antibodies from patients with primary and secondary dengue virus infections, respectively. Dual analyses with both E/M and NS1 serotype-specific capture IgM ELISAs showed that positive serotype specificity could be correctly identified for 98.6 and 61.9% of all of the primary and secondary serum samples tested, respectively. These findings suggested that E/M and NS1 serotype-specific capture IgM ELISAs have the potential to be of use in dengue virus serotyping.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shu</LastName><ForeName>Pei-Yun</ForeName><Initials>PY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Laboratory Research and Development, Center for Disease Control, Department of Health, 161, Kun-Yang St., Taipei, Taiwan, Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Li-Kuang</ForeName><Initials>LK</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chang</LastName><ForeName>Shu-Fen</ForeName><Initials>SF</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Su</LastName><ForeName>Chien-Ling</ForeName><Initials>CL</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chien</LastName><ForeName>Li-Jung</ForeName><Initials>LJ</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chin</LastName><ForeName>Chuan</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lin</LastName><ForeName>Ting-Hsiang</ForeName><Initials>TH</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Jyh-Hsiung</ForeName><Initials>JH</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Clin Microbiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7505564</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0095-1137</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000914">Antibodies, Viral</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D007074">Immunoglobulin G</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D007075">Immunoglobulin M</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C100315">NS1 protein, Flavivirus</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D017361">Viral Nonstructural Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000914" MajorTopicYN="N">Antibodies, Viral</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="Y">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003716" MajorTopicYN="N">Dengue Virus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000145" MajorTopicYN="Y">classification</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004797" MajorTopicYN="N">Enzyme-Linked Immunosorbent Assay</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007074" MajorTopicYN="N">Immunoglobulin G</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007075" MajorTopicYN="N">Immunoglobulin M</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="Y">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012703" MajorTopicYN="N">Serotyping</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017361" MajorTopicYN="N">Viral Nonstructural Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="Y">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2004</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2004</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2004</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15184425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC427809</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JCM.42.6.2489-2494.2004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">42/6/2489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Burke, D. S. 1983. Rapid methods in the laboratory diagnosis of dengue virus infections, p. 72-84. In T. Pang and T. Pathmananathan (ed.), Proceedings of the International Conference on Dengue/Dengue Hemorrhagic Fever. University of Malaya, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, L. K., C. L. Liao, C. G. Lin, S. C. Lai, C. I. Liu, S. H. Ma, Y. Y. Huang, and Y. L. Lin. 1996. Persistence of Japanese encephalitis virus is associated with abnormal expression of nonstructural protein NS1 in host cells. Virology 217:220-229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8599206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gubler, D. J. 1997. Dengue and dengue hemorrhagic fever: its history and resurgence as a global public health problem, p. 1-22. In D. J. Gubler and G. Kuno (ed.), Dengue and dengue hemorrhagic fever. CAB International, New York, N.Y.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gubler, D. J. 1998. Dengue and dengue hemorrhagic fever. Clin. Microbiol. Rev. 11:480-496.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC88892</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9665979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halstead, S. B., H. Shotwell, and J. Casals. 1973. Studies on the pathogenesis of dengue infection in monkeys II. Clinical laboratory responses to heterologous infection. J. Infect. Dis. 128:15-22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4198024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halstead, S. B., S. Rojanasuphot, and N. Sangkawibha. 1983. Original antigenic sin in dengue. Am. J. Trop. Med. Hyg. 32:154-156.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6824120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halstead, S. B. 1988. Pathogenesis of dengue: challenge to molecular biology. Science 239:476-481.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3277268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Innis, B. L., A. Nisalak, S. Nimmannitya, S. Kusalerdchariya, V. Chongswasdi, S. Suntayakorn, P. Puttisri, and C. H. Hoke. 1989. An enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay to characterize dengue infections where dengue and Japanese encephalitis co-circulate. Am. J. Trop. Med. Hyg. 40:418-427.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2540664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Innis, B. L. 1997. Antibody responses to dengue virus infection, p. 221-243. In D. J. Gubler and G. Kuno (ed.), Dengue and dengue hemorrhagic fever. CAB International, New York, N.Y.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lanciotti, R. S., C. H. Calisher, D. J. Gubler, G. J. Chang, and A. V. Vorndam. 1992. Rapid detection and typing of dengue viruses from clinical samples by using reverse transcriptase-polymerase chain reaction. J. Clin. Microbiol. 30:545-551.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC265106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1372617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ludolfs, D., S. Schilling, J. Altenschmidt, and H. Schmitz. 2002. Serological differentiation of infections with dengue virus serotypes 1 to 4 by using recombinant antigens. J. Clin. Microbiol. 40:4317-4320.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC139635</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12409419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Makino, Y., M. Tadano, M. Saito, N. Maneekarn, N. Sittisombut, V. Sirisanthana, B. Poneprasert, and T. Fukunaga. 1994. Studies on serological cross-reaction in sequential flavivirus infections. Microbiol. Immunol. 38:951-955.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7723688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin, D. A., B. J. Biggerstaff, B. Allen, A. J. Johnson, R. S. Lanciotti, and J. T. Roehrig. 2002. Use of immunoglobulin M cross-reactions in differential diagnosis of human flaviviral encephalitis infections in the United States. Clin. Diagn. Lab. Immunol. 9:544-549.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC120001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11986257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monath, T. P., R. R. Nystrom, R. E. Bailey, C. H. Calisher, and D. J. Muth. 1984. Immunoglobulin M antibody capture enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay for diagnosis of St. Louis encephalitis. J. Clin. Microbiol. 20:784-790.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC271431</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6386882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nawa, M., K. I. Yamada, T. Takasaki, T. Akatsuka, and I. Kurane. 2000. Serotype-cross-reactive immunoglobulin M responses in dengue virus infections determined by enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay. Clin. Diagn. Lab. Immunol. 7:774-777.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC95954</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10973453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russell, P. K., A. Nisalak, P. Sukhavachana, and S. Vivona. 1967. A plaque reduction test for dengue virus neutralizing antibodies. J. Immunol. 99:285-290.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6031202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shu, P. Y., L. K. Chen, S. F. Chang, Y. Y. Yueh, L. Chow, L. J. Chien, C. Chin, T. H. Lin, and J. H. Huang. 2000. Dengue NS1-specific antibody responses: isotype distribution and serotyping in patients with dengue fever and dengue hemorrhagic fever. J. Med. Virol. 62:224-232.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11002252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shu, P. Y., L. K. Chen, S. F. Chang, Y. Y. Yueh, L. Chow, L. J. Chien, C. Chin, T. H. Lin, and J. H. Huang. 2001. Antibody to the nonstructural protein NS1 of Japanese encephalitis virus: potential application of mAb-based indirect ELISA to differentiate infection from vaccination. Vaccine 19:1753-1763.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11166901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shu, P. Y., L. K. Chen, S. F. Chang, Y. Y. Yueh, L. Chow, L. J. Chien, C. Chin, H. H. Yang, T. H. Lin, and J. H. Huang. 2002. Potential application of nonstructural protein NS1 serotype-specific immunoglobulin G enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay in the seroepidemiologic study of dengue virus infection: correlation of results with those of the plaque reduction neutralization test. J. Clin. Microbiol. 40:1840-1844.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC130672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11980973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shu, P. Y., S. F. Chang, Y. C. Kuo, Y. Y. Yueh, L. J. Chien, C. L. Sue, T. H. Lin, and J. H. Huang. 2003. Development of group- and serotype-specific one-step SYBR Green I-based real-time reverse transcription-PCR assay for dengue virus. J. Clin. Microbiol. 41:2408-2416.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC156548</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12791857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shu, P. Y., L. K. Chen, S. F. Chang, Y. Y. Yueh, L. Chow, L. J. Chien, C. Chin, T. H. Lin, and J. H. Huang. 2003. Comparison of capture immunoglobulin M (IgM) and IgG enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay (ELISA) and nonstructural protein NS1 serotype-specific IgG ELISA for differentiation of primary and secondary dengue virus infections. Clin. Diagn. Lab. Immunol. 10:622-630.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC164246</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12853395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tardei, G., S. Ruta, V. Chitu, C. Rossi, T. F. Tsai, and C. Cernescu. 2000. Evaluation of immunoglobulin M (IgM) and IgG enzyme immunoassay in serologic diagnosis of West Nile virus infections. J. Clin. Microbiol. 38:2232-2239.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC86770</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10834982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. 1997. Dengue haemorrhagic fever: diagnosis, treatment, prevention and control, 2nd ed. World Health Organization, Geneva, Switzerland.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. 1999. Strengthening implementation of the global strategy for dengue fever and dengue haemorrhagic fever, prevention and control. Report of the informal consultation, 18-20 October. World Health Organization, Geneva, Switzerland.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>