<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">15242935</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2005</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>13</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2018</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1071-412X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>11</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2004</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Clinical and diagnostic laboratory immunology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Clin Diagn Lab Immunol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Current advances in dengue diagnosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>642</StartPage><EndPage>650</EndPage><MedlinePgn>642-50</MedlinePgn></Pagination><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shu</LastName><ForeName>Pei-Yun</ForeName><Initials>PY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Laboratory Research and Development, Center for Disease Control, Department of Health, Taipei, Taiwan, Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Jyh-Hsiung</ForeName><Initials>JH</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Clin Diagn Lab Immunol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9421292</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1071-412X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000914">Antibodies, Viral</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000956">Antigens, Viral</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D007074">Immunoglobulin G</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D007075">Immunoglobulin M</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000914" MajorTopicYN="N">Antibodies, Viral</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000956" MajorTopicYN="N">Antigens, Viral</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003715" MajorTopicYN="N">Dengue</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="Y">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003716" MajorTopicYN="N">Dengue Virus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="Y">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003937" MajorTopicYN="N">Diagnosis, Differential</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004797" MajorTopicYN="N">Enzyme-Linked Immunosorbent Assay</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007074" MajorTopicYN="N">Immunoglobulin G</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007075" MajorTopicYN="N">Immunoglobulin M</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020133" MajorTopicYN="N">Reverse Transcriptase Polymerase Chain Reaction</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012680" MajorTopicYN="N">Sensitivity and Specificity</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2004</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2005</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2004</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15242935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC440621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/CDLI.11.4.642-650.2004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">11/4/642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Alcon, S., A. Talarmin, M. Debruyne, A. Falconar, V. Deubel, and M. Flamand. 2002. Enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay to dengue virus type 1 nonstructural protein NS1 reveals circulation of the antigen in the blood during the acute phase of disease in patients experiencing primary or secondary infections. J. Clin. Microbiol. 40:376-381.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC153354</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11825945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balmaseda, A., M. G. Guzman, S. Hammond, G. Robleto, C. Flores, Y. Tellez, E. Videa, S. Saborio, L. Perez, E. Sandoval, Y. Rodriguez, and E. Harris. 2003. Diagnosis of dengue virus infection by detection of specific immunoglobulin M (IgM) and IgA antibodies in serum and saliva. Clin. Diagn. Lab. Immunol. 10:317-322.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC150529</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12626461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Branch, S. L., and P. N. Levett. 1999. Evaluation of four methods for detection of immunoglobulin M antibodies to dengue virus. Clin. Diagn. Lab. Immunol. 6:555-557.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC95727</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10391862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bravo, J. R., M. G. Guzman, and G. P. Kouri. 1987. Why dengue haemorrhagic fever in Cuba? I. Individual risk factors for dengue haemorrhagic fever/dengue shock syndrome (DHF/DSS). Trans. R. Soc. Trop. Med. Hyg. 81:816-820.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3450004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bundo, K., and A. Igarashi. 1985. Antibody-capture ELISA for detection of immunoglobulin M antibodies in sera from Japanese encephalitis and dengue hemorrhagic fever patients. J. Virol. Methods 11:15-22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2989309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke, D. S., A. Nisalak, and M. A. Ussery. 1982. Antibody capture immunoassay detection of Japanese encephalitis virus immunoglobulin M and G antibodies in cerebrospinal fluid. J. Clin. Microbiol. 15:1034-1042.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC272535</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7161371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke, D. S. 1983. Rapid methods in the laboratory diagnosis of dengue virus infections, p. 72-84. In T. Pang and R. Pathmananathan (ed.), Proceedings of the International Conference Dengue/Dengue Hemorrhagic Fever. University of Malaysia, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke, D. S., A. Nisalak, D. E. Johnson, and R. M. Scott. 1988. A prospective study of dengue infections in Bangkok. Am. J. Trop. Med. Hyg. 38:172-180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3341519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Callahan, J. D., S. J. Wu, A. Dion-Schultz, B. E. Mangold, L. F. Peruski, D. M. Watts, K. R. Porter, G. R. Murpgy, W. Suharyono, C. C. King, C. G. Hayes, and J. J. Temenak. 2001. Development and evaluation of serotype- and group-specific fluorogenic reverse transcriptase PCR (TaqMan) assays for dengue virus. J. Clin. Microbiol. 39:4119-4124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC88496</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11682539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardosa, M. J., T. Phaik, and N. Sham. 1988. Development of a dot enzyme immunoassay for dengue 3: a sensitive method for the detection of anti-dengue antibodies. J. Virol. Methods 22:81-88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3058737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chambers, T. J., C. S. Hahn, R. Galler, and C. M. Rice. 1990. Flavivirus genome organization, expression, and replication. Annu. Rev. Microbiol. 44:649-688.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2174669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charrel, R. N., and X. de Lamballerie. 2002. Low specificity of an immunochromatographic serological assay for diagnosis of dengue fever in travelers returning with malaria. Clin. Diagn. Lab. Immunol. 9:1400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC130116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12414786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, R. F., W. T. Yeh, M. Y. Yang, and K. D. Yang. 2001. A model of the real-time correlation of viral titers with immune reactions in antibody-dependent enhancement of dengue-2 infections. FEMS Immunol. Med. Microbiol. 30:1-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11172984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chungue, E., G. Marche, R. Plichart, J. P. Boutin, and J. Roux. 1989. Comparison of immunoglobulin G enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay (IgG-ELISA) and haemagglutination inhibition (HI) test for the detection of dengue antibodies. Prevalence of dengue IgG-ELISA antibodies in Tahiti. Trans. R. Soc. Trop. Med. Hyg. 83:708-711.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2617636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Churdboonchart, V., N. Bhamarapravati, S. Peampramprecha, and S. Sirinavin. 1991. Antibodies against dengue viral proteins in primary and secondary dengue hemorrhagic fever. Am. J. Trop. Med. Hyg. 44:481-493.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2063952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clarke, D. H., and J. Casals. 1958. Techniques for hemagglutination and hemagglutination-inhibition with arthropod-borne virus. Am. J. Trop. Med. Hyg. 7:561-573.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13571577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuzzubbo, A. J., T. P. Endy, A. Nisalak, S. Kalayanarooj, D. W. Vaughn, S. A. Ogata, D. E. Clements, and P. L. Devine. 2001. Use of recombinant envelope proteins for serological diagnosis of dengue virus infection in an immunochromatographic assay. Clin. Diagn. Lab. Immunol. 8:1150-1155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC96242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11687456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deubel, V., R. M. Kinney, and D. W. Trent. 1988. Nucleotide sequence and deduced amino acid sequence of the nonstructural proteins of dengue type 2 virus, Jamaica genotype: comparative analysis of the full-length genome. Virology 165:234-244.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3388770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drosten, C., S. Gottig, S. Schilling, M. Asper, M. Panning, H. Schmitz, and S. Gunther. 2002. Rapid detection and quantitation of RNA of Ebola and Marburg viruses, Lassa virus, Crimean-Congo hemorrhagic fever virus, Rift valley fever virus, dengue virus, and yellow fever virus by real-time reverse transcription-PCR. J. Clin. Microbiol. 40:2323-2330.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC120575</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12089242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Endy, T. P., S. Chunsuttiwat, A. Nisalak, D. H. Libraty, S. Green, A. L. Rothman, D. W. Vaughn, and F. A. Ennis. 2002. Epidemiology of inapparent and symptomatic acute dengue virus infection: a prospective study of primary school children in Kamphaeng Phet, Thailand. Am. J. Epidemiol. 156:40-51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12076887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Falkler, W. A., A. R. Diwan, and S. B. Halstead. 1973. Human antibody to dengue soluble complement-fixing (SCF) antigens. J. Immunol. 111:1804-1809.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4201557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia, G., D. W. Vaughn, and R. M. Del Angel. 1997. Recognition of synthetic oligopeptides from nonstructural proteins NS1 and NS3 of dengue-4 virus by sera from dengue virus-infected children. Am. J. Trop. Med. Hyg. 56:466-470.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9158059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gardner, S. N., T. A. Kuczmarski, E. A. Vitalis, and T. R. Slezak. 2003. Limitations of TaqMan PCR for detecting divergent viral pathogens illustrated by hepatitis A, B, C, and E viruses and human immunodeficiency virus. J. Clin. Microbiol. 41:2417-2427.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC156483</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12791858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gentry, M. K., E. A. Henchal, J. M. McCown, W. E. Brandt, and J. M. Dalrymple. 1982. Identification of distinct determinants on dengue-2 virus using monoclonal antibodies. Am. J. Trop. Med. Hyg. 31:548-555.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6177259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibbons, R. V., and D. W. Vaughn. 2002. Dengue: an escalating problem. BMJ 324:1563-1566.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1123504</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12089096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green, S., D. W. Vaughn, S. Kalayanarooj, S. Nimmannitya, S. Suntayakorn, A. Nisalak, R. Lew, B. L. Innis, I. Kurane, A. L. Rothman, and F. A. Ennis. 1999. Early immune activation in acute dengue illness is related to development of plasma leakage and disease severity. J. Infect. Dis. 179:755-762.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10068569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Groen, J., P. Koraka, J. Velzing, C. Copra, and A. D. M. E. Osterhaus. 2000. Evaluation of six immunoassays for detection of dengue virus-specific immunoglobulin M and G antibodies. Clin. Diagn. Lab. Immunol. 7:867-871.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC95976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11063489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gubler, D. J., and L. Rosen. 1976. A simple technique for demonstrating transmission of dengue virus by mosquitoes without the use of vertebrate hosts. Am. J. Trop. Med. Hyg. 25:146-150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gubler, D. J., D. Reed, L. Rosen, and J. C. J. Hitchcock. 1978. Epidemiologic, clinical, and virologic observations on dengue in the kingdom of Tonga. Am. J. Trop. Med. Hyg. 27:581-589.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">677371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gubler, D. J., and G. E. Sather. 1988. Laboratory diagnosis of dengue and dengue hemorrhagic fever, p. 291-322. In A. Homma and J. F. Cunha (ed.), Proceedings of the International Symposium on Yellow Fever and Dengue. Bio-Manguinhos, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gubler, D. J. 1996. Serologic diagnosis of dengue/dengue haemorrhagic fever. Dengue Bull. 20:20-23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gubler, D. J. 1997. Dengue and dengue hemorrhagic fever: its history and resurgence as a global public health problem, p. 1-22. In D. J. Gubler and G. Kuno (ed.), Dengue and dengue hemorrhagic fever. CAB International, New York, N.Y.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gubler, D. J. 1998. Dengue and dengue hemorrhagic fever. Clin. Microbiol. Rev. 11:480-496.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC88892</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9665979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guzman, M. G., G. Kouri, J. Bravo, M. Soler, S. Vazquez, and L. Morier. 1990. Dengue hemorrhagic fever in Cuba, 1981: a retrospective seroepidemiologic study. Am. J. Trop. Med. Hyg. 42:179-184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2316788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guzman, M. G., and G. Kouri. 1996. Advances in dengue diagnosis. Clin. Diagn. Lab. Immunol. 3:621-627.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC170421</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8914749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guzman, M. G., and G. Kouri. 2003. Dengue: an update. Lancet Infect. Dis. 2:33-42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11892494</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halstead, S. B., H. Shotwell, and J. Casals. 1973. Studies on the pathogenesis of dengue infection in monkeys. II. Clinical laboratory responses to heterologous infection. J. Infect. Dis. 128:15-22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4198024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halstead, S. B. 1988. Pathogenesis of dengue: challenge to molecular biology. Science 239:476-481.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3277268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris, E., T. G. Roberts, L. Smith, J. Selle, L. D. Kramer, S. Valle, E. Sandoval, and A. Balmaseda. 1998. Typing of dengue viruses in clinical specimens and mosquitoes by single-tube multiplex reverse transcriptase PCR. J. Clin. Microbiol. 36:2634-2639.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC105176</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9705406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henchal, E. A., J. M. McCown, M. C. Seguin, M. K. Gentry, and W. E. Brandt. 1983. Rapid identification of dengue virus isolates by using monoclonal antibodies in an indirect immunofluorescence assay. Am. J. Trop. Med. Hyg. 32:164-169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6401944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henchal, E. A., S. L. Polo, V. Vorndam, C. Yaemsiri, B. L. Innis, and C. H. Hoke. 1991. Sensitivity and specificity of a universal primer set for the rapid diagnosis of dengue virus infections by polymerase chain reaction and nucleic acid hybridization. Am. J. Trop. Med. Hyg. 45:418-428.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1951850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Houng, H. H., R. C. M. Chen, D. W. Vaughn, and N. Kanesa-thasan. 2001. Development of a fluorogenic RT-PCR system for quantitative identification of dengue virus serotypes 1-4 using conserved and serotype-specific 3&#x2032;noncoding sequences. J. Virol. Methods 95:19-32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11377710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, J. H., J. J. Wey, C. Chin, and Y. C Wu. 1999. Antibody responses to an immunodominant nonstructural 1 synthetic peptide in patients with dengue fever and dengue hemorrhagic fever. J. Med. Virol. 57:1-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9890415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, J. L., J. H. Huang, R. H. Shyn, C. W. Teng, Y. L. Lin, M. D. Kuo, C. W. Yao, and M. F. Shaio. 2001. High-level expression of immunodominant recombinant dengue viral NS1 protein and its potential use as a diagnostic antigen. J. Med. Virol. 65:553-560.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11596093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hung, N. T., H. Y. Lei, N. T. Lan, Y. S. Lin, K. J. Huang, L. B. Lien, C. F. Lin, T. M. Yeh, D. Q. Ha, V. T. Q. Huong, L. C. Chen, J. H. Huang, L. T. My, C. C. Liu, and S. B. Halstead. 2004. Dengue hemorrhagic fever in infants: a study on clinical and cytokine profiles. J. Infect. Dis. 221-232. 189:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14722886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Innis, B. L., A. Nisalak, S. Nimmannitya, S. Kusalerdchariya, V. Chongswasdi, S. Suntayakorn, P. Puttisri, and C. H. Hoke. 1989. An enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay to characterize dengue infections where dengue and Japanese encephalitis co-circulate. Am. J. Trop. Med. Hyg. 40:418-427.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2540664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Innis, B. L. 1997. Antibody responses to dengue virus infection, p. 221-243. In D. J. Gubler and G. Kuno (ed.), Dengue and dengue hemorrhagic fever. CAB International, New York, N.Y.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koraka, P., B. Murgue, X. Deparis, T. E. Setiati, C. Suharti, E. C. van Gorp, C. E. Hack, A. D. Osterhaus, and J. Groen. 2003. Elevated levels of total and dengue virus-specific immunoglobulin E in patients with varying disease severity. J. Med. Virol. 70:91-98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12629649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koraka, P., C. P. Burghoorn-Maas, A. Falconar, T. E. Setiati, K. Djamiatun, J. Groen, and A. D. M. E. Osterhaus. 2003. Detection of immune-complex-dissociated nonstructural-1 antigen in patients with acute dengue virus infections. J. Clin. Microbiol. 41:4154-4159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC193852</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12958240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuberski, T., and L. Rosen. 1977. A simple technique for the detection of dengue antigen in mosquitoes by immunofluorescence. Am. J. Trop. Med. Hyg. 26:533-537.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">326071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuno, G., A. V. Vorndam, D. J. Gubler, and I. Gomez. 1990. Study of anti-dengue NS1 antibody by Western blot. J. Med. Virol. 32:102-108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2149144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuno, G., I. Gomez, and D. J. Gubler. 1991. An ELISA procedure for the diagnosis of dengue infections. J. Virol. Methods 33:101-113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1939502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuno, G. 1998. Universal diagnostic RT-PCR protocol for arboviruses. J. Virol. Methods 72:27-41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9672130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurane, I., A. L. Rothman, P. G. Livingston, S. Green, S. J. Gagnon, J. Janus, B. L. Innis, S. Nimmannitya, A. Nisalak, and F. A. Ennis. 1994. Immunopathologic mechanisms of dengue hemorrhagic fever and dengue shock syndrome. Arch. Virol. Suppl. 9:59-64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8032282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lam, S. K. 1986. Isolation of dengue viruses by intracerebral inoculation of mosquito larvae. J. Virol. Methods 14:133-140.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2877004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lam, S. K., and P. L. Devine. 1998. Evaluation of capture ELISA and rapid immunochromatographic test for the determination of IgM and IgG antibodies produced during dengue infection. Clin. Diagn. Virol. 10:75-81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9646004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lanciotti, R. S., C. H. Calisher, D. J. Gubler, G. J. Chang, and A. V. Vorndam. 1992. Rapid detection and typing of dengue viruses from clinical samples by using reverse transcriptase-polymerase chain reaction. J. Clin. Microbiol. 30:545-551.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC265106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1372617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laue, T., P. Emmerich, and H. Schmitz. 1999. Detection of dengue virus RNA in patients after primary or secondary dengue infection by using the TaqMan automated amplification system. J. Clin. Microbiol. 37:2543-2547.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC85278</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10405398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lei, H. Y., T. M. Yeh, H. S. Liu, Y. S. Lin., S. H. Chen, and C. C. Liu. 2001. Immunopathogenesis of dengue virus infection. J. Biomed. Sci. 8:377-388.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11549879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leyssen, P., E. D. Clercq, and J. Neyts. 2000. Perspectives for the treatment of infections with Flaviviridae. Clin. Microbiol. Rev. 13:67-82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC88934</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10627492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, C. F., H. Y. Lei, A. L. Shiau, C. C. Liu, H. S. Liu, T. M. Yeh, S. T. Wang, T. I. Zang, F. C. Sheu, C. F. Kuo, and Y. S. Lin. 2001. Generation of IgM anti-platelet autoantibody in dengue patients. J. Med. Virol. 63:143-149.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11170051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ludolfs, D., S. Schilling, J. Altenschmidt, and H. Schmitz. 2002. Serological differentiation of infections with dengue virus serotypes 1 to 4 by using recombinant antigens. J. Clin. Microbiol. 40:4317-4320.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC139635</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12409419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackay, I. M., K. E. Arden, and A. Nitsche. 2002. Real-time PCR in virology. Nucleic Acids Res. 30:1292-1305.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC101343</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11884626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Makino, Y., M. Tadano, M. Saito, N. Maneekarn, N. Sittisombut, V. Sirisanthana, B. Poneprasert, and T. Fukunaga. 1994. Studies on serological cross-reaction in sequential flavivirus infections. Microbiol. Immunol. 38:951-955.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7723688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mantke, O. D., K. Lemmer, S. S. Biel, J. Groen, H. Schmitz, J. P. Durand, H. Zeller, and M. Niedrig. 2004. Quality control assessment for the serological diagnosis of dengue virus infections. J. Clin. Virol. 29:105-112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14747029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin, D. A., B. J. Biggerstaff, B. Allen, A. J. Johnson, R. S. Lanciotti, and J. T. Roehrig. 2002. Use of immunoglobulin M cross-reactions in differential diagnosis of human flaviviral encephalitis infections in the United States. Clin. Diagn. Lab. Immunol. 9:544-549.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC120001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11986257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miagostovich, M. P., R. M. Nogueira, F. B. dos Santos, H. G. Schatzmayr, E. S. Araujo, and V. Vorndam. 1999. Evaluation of an IgG enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay for dengue diagnosis. J. Clin. Virol. 14:183-189.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10614855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morita, K., M. Tanaka, and A. Igarashi. 1991. Rapid identification of dengue virus serotypes by using polymerase chain reaction. J. Clin. Microbiol. 29:2107-2110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC270281</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1682341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nawa, M., K. I. Yamada, T. Takasaki, T. Akatsuka, and I. Kurane. 2000. Serotype-cross-reactive immunoglobulin M responses in dengue virus infections determined by enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay. Clin. Diagn. Lab. Immunol. 7:774-777.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC95954</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10973453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nimmannitya, S. 1987. Clinical spectrum and management of dengue haemorrhagic fever. Southeast Asian J. Trop. Med. Public Health 18:392-397.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3433169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliveira, D. P. S., L. D. Malta, M. Clotteau, N. R. R. J. Pires, and F. B. A. Lopes. 2003. Improved detection of dengue-1 virus from IgM-positive serum samples using C6/36 cell cultures in association with RT-PCR. Intervirology 46:227-231.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12931031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patarapotikul, J., S. Pothipunya, R. Wanotayan, A. Hongyantarachai, and S. Tharavanij. 1993. Western blot analysis of antigens specifically recognized by natural immune responses of patients with Japanese encephalitis infections. Southeast Asian J. Trop. Med. Public Health 24:269-276.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8266229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reynes, J. M., S. Ong, C. Mey, C. Ngan, S. Hoyer, and A. A. Sall. 2003. Improved molecular detection of dengue virus serotype 1 variants. J. Clin. Microbiol. 41:3864-3867.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC179838</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12904404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rice, C. M., E. M. Lenches, S. R. Eddy, S. J. Shin, R. L. Sheets, and J. H. Strauss. 1985. Nucleotide sequence of yellow fever virus. Implications for flavivirus expression and evolution. Science 229:726-733.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4023707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosen, L., and D. Gubler. 1974. The use of mosquitoes to detect and propagate dengue viruses. Am. J. Trop. Med. Hyg. 23:1153-1160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4429185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosen, L. 1977. The Emperor's New Clothes revisited, or reflections on the pathogenesis of dengue hemorrhagic fever. Am. J. Trop. Med. Hyg. 26:337-343.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">869095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russell, P. K., A. Nisalak, P. Sukhavachana, and S. Vivona. 1967. A plaque reduction test for dengue virus neutralizing antibodies. J. Immunol. 99:285-290.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6031202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmitz, H., and P. Emmerich. 1984. Detection of specific immunoglobulin M antibody to different flaviviruses by use of enzyme-labeled antigens. J. Clin. Microbiol. 19:664-667.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC271151</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6330165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seah, C. L. L., V. T. K. Chow, H. C. Tan, and Y. C. Chan. 1995. Rapid single-step RT-PCR typing of dengue viruses using NS3 gene primers. J. Virol. Methods 51:193-200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7738139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Se-Thoe, S. Y., M. M. Ng, and A. E. Ling. 1999. Retrospective study of Western blot profiles in immune sera of natural dengue virus infections. J. Med. Virol. 57:322-330.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10022806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shu, P. Y., L. K. Chen, S. F. Chang, Y. Y. Yueh, L. Chow, L. J. Chien, C. Chin, T. H. Lin, and J. H. Huang. 2000. Dengue NS1-specific antibody responses: isotype distribution and serotyping in patients with dengue fever and dengue hemorrhagic fever. J. Med. Virol. 62:224-232.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11002252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shu, P. Y., L. K. Chen, S. F. Chang, Y. Y. Yueh, L. Chow, L. J. Chien, C. Chin, T. H. Lin, and J. H. Huang. 2001. Antibody to the nonstructural protein NS1 of Japanese encephalitis virus: potential application of mAb-based indirect ELISA to differentiate infection from vaccination. Vaccine 19:1753-1763.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11166901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shu, P. Y., L. K. Chen, S. F. Chang, Y. Y. Yueh, L. Chow, L. J. Chien, C. Chin, H. H. Yang, T. H. Lin, and J. H. Huang. 2002. Potential application of nonstructural protein NS1 serotype-specific immunoglobulin G enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay in the seroepidemiologic study of dengue virus infection: correlation of results with those of the plaque reduction neutralization test. J. Clin. Microbiol. 40:1840-1844.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC130672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11980973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shu, P. Y., S. F. Chang, Y. C. Kuo, Y. Y. Yueh, L. J. Chien, C. L. Sue, T. H. Lin, and J. H. Huang. 2003. Development of group- and serotype-specific one-step SYBR Green I-based real-time reverse transcription-PCR assay for dengue virus. J. Clin. Microbiol. 41:2408-2416.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC156548</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12791857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shu, P. Y., L. K. Chen, S. F. Chang, Y. Y. Yueh, L. Chow, L. J. Chien, C. Chin, T. H. Lin, and J. H. Huang. 2003. Comparison of capture immunoglobulin M (IgM) and IgG enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay (ELISA) and nonstructural protein NS1 serotype-specific IgG ELISA for differentiation of primary and secondary dengue virus infections. Clin. Diagn. Lab. Immunol. 10:622-630.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC164246</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12853395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shu, P. Y., L. K. Chen, S. F. Chang, C. L. Sue, L. J. Chien, C. Chin, T. H. Lin, and J. H. Huang. 2004. Dengue virus serotyping based on envelope/membrane (E/M) and nonstructural protein NS1 serotype-specific capture immunoglobulin M (IgM) enzyme-linked immunosorbent assays (ELISA). J. Clin. Microbiol. 42:2489-2494.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC427809</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15184425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudiro, T. M., H. Ishiko, S. Green, D. W. Vaughn, A. Nisalak, S. Kalayanarooj, A. L. Rothman, B. Raengsakulrach, J. Janus, I. Kurane, and F. A. Ennis. 1997. Rapid diagnosis of dengue viremia by reverse transcriptase-polymerase chain reaction using 3&#x2032;-noncoding region universal primers. Am. J. Trop. Med. Hyg. 56:424-429.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9158052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Talarmin, A., B. Labeau, J. Lelarge, and J. L. Sarthou. 1998. Immunoglobulin A-specific capture enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay for diagnosis of dengue fever. J. Clin. Microbiol. 36:1189-1192.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC104797</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9574674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valdes, K., M. Alvarez, M. Pupo, S. Vazquez, R. Rodriguez, and M. G. Guzman. 2000. Human dengue antibodies against structural and nonstructural proteins. Clin. Diagn. Lab. Immunol. 7:856-857.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC95972</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10973471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vathanophas, K., W. M. Hammon, R. W. Atchison, and G. E. Sather. 1973. Attempted type specific diagnosis of dengue virus infection by the indirect fluorescent antibody method directed at differentiating IgM and IgG responses. Proc. Soc. Exp. Biol. Med. 142:697-702.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4631998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaughn, D. W. 1998. Serological investigation of a febrile outbreak in Delhi, India, using a rapid immunochromatographic test. J. Clin. Microbiol. 36:2795-2796.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC105215</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9742015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaughn, D. W., A. Nisalak, S. Kalayanarooj, T. Solomon, N. M. Dung, A. Cuzzubbo, and P. L. Devine. 1998. Evaluation of a rapid immunochromatographic test for diagnosis of dengue virus infection. J. Clin. Microbiol. 36:234-238.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC124841</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9431954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaughn, D. W., S. Green, S. Kalayanarooj, B. L. Innis, S. Nimmannitya, S. Suntayakorn, T. P. Endy, B. Raengsakulrach, A. L. Rothman, F. A. Ennis, and A. Nisalak. 2000. Dengue viremia titer, antibody response pattern, and virus serotype correlate with disease severity. J. Infect. Dis. 181:2-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10608744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vorndam, V., and G. Kuno. 1997. Laboratory diagnosis of dengue virus infections, p. 313-334. In D. J. Gubler and G. Kuno (ed.), Dengue and dengue hemorrhagic fever. CAB International, New York, N.Y.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, W. K., T. L. Sung, Y. C. Tsai, C. L. Kao, S. M. Chang, and C. C. King. 2002. Detection of dengue virus replication in peripheral blood mononuclear cells from dengue virus type 2-infected patients by a reverse transcription-real-time PCR assay. J. Clin. Microbiol. 40:4472-4478.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC154639</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12454138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warrilow, D., J. A. Northill, A. Pyke, and G. A. Smith. 2002. Single rapid TaqMan fluorogenic probe based PCR assay that detects all four dengue serotypes. J. Med. Virol. 66:524-528.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11857532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Win, T. 1982. Detection of dengue viruses by immunofluorescence of the intracerebral inoculation of mosquitoes. Lancet i:57-64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6119451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong, S. J., R. H. Boyle, V. L. Demarest, A. N. Woodmansee, L. D. Kramer, H. Li, M. Drebot, R. A. Koski, E. Fikrig, D. A. Martin, and P. Y. Shi. 2003. Immunoassay targeting nonstructural protein 5 to differentiate West Nile virus infection from dengue and St. Louis encephalitis virus infections and from flavivirus vaccination. J. Clin. Microbiol. 41:4217-4223.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC193845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12958248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. 1997. Dengue haemorrhagic fever: diagnosis, treatment, prevention and control, 2nd ed. World Health Organization, Geneva, Switzerland.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. 1999. Strengthening implementation of the global strategy for dengue fever and dengue haemorrhagic fever, prevention and control. Report of the informal consultation, 18-20 October. World Health Organization, Geneva, Switzerland.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, S. J., E. M. Lee, R. Putvatana, R. N. Shurtliff, K. R. Porter, W. Suharyono, D. M. Watts, C. C. King, G. S. Murphy, C. G. Hayes, and J. W. Romano. 2001. Detection of dengue viral RNA using a nucleic acid sequence-based amplification assay. J. Clin. Microbiol. 39:2794-2798.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC88241</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11473994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young, P., R., P. A. Hilditch, C. Bletchly, and W. Halloran. 2000. An antigen capture enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay reveals high levels of the dengue virus protein NS1 in the sera of infected patients. J. Clin. Microbiol. 38:1053-1057.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC86336</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10698995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>