<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">17287314</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2007</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>07</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2018</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1556-6811</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>14</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2007</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Clinical and vaccine immunology : CVI</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Clin Vaccine Immunol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Generation and characterization of monoclonal antibodies against dengue virus type 1 for epitope mapping and serological detection by epitope-based peptide antigens.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>404</StartPage><EndPage>411</EndPage><MedlinePgn>404-11</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>Dengue virus (DEN), the pathogen behind dengue hemorrhagic fever, remains a public health problem in Asia and South America. In this study, monoclonal antibodies (MAbs) against DEN serotype 1 (DEN-1) were generated by fusing NSI/1-Ag4-1 mouse myeloma cells with lymphocytes from BALB/c mice immunized with DEN-1. Twelve MAbs were found to react specifically to the DENs by enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay, immunofluorescence analysis, and immunoblotting analysis. Five MAbs, namely, DA4-7, DA6-7, DA9-5, DA10-2, and DA11-13, were found to react with envelope proteins of DEN-1. Two serotype-specific MAbs of DEN-1, DA6-7 and DA11-13, were further shown to neutralize DEN-1 infection by a plaque reduction neutralization test. The neutralizing epitopes of these MAbs were further identified from a random peptide library displayed on phage. Immunopositive phage clones reacted specifically with these MAbs and did not react with normal mouse serum. Epitope-based peptide antigens were proved able to detect antibodies in serum samples collected from DEN-1-infected patients but not in those taken from DEN-2-infected patients or healthy controls. We believe that these MAbs and neutralizing epitopes will provide information that will lead to the development of DEN-1 serotype-specific diagnostic reagents and vaccines.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Yun-Ching</ForeName><Initials>YC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Cellular and Organismic Biology, Academia Sinica, Taipei 115, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Hsien-Neng</ForeName><Initials>HN</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lin</LastName><ForeName>Chin-Tarng</ForeName><Initials>CT</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Yi-Fang</ForeName><Initials>YF</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>King</LastName><ForeName>Chwan-Chuen</ForeName><Initials>CC</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Han-Chung</ForeName><Initials>HC</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2007</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Clin Vaccine Immunol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101252125</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1556-679X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000911">Antibodies, Monoclonal</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000956">Antigens, Viral</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D010455">Peptides</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000911" MajorTopicYN="N">Antibodies, Monoclonal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000096" MajorTopicYN="Y">biosynthesis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000956" MajorTopicYN="N">Antigens, Viral</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="Y">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002460" MajorTopicYN="N">Cell Line</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003716" MajorTopicYN="N">Dengue Virus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="Y">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018604" MajorTopicYN="Y">Epitope Mapping</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051379" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010455" MajorTopicYN="N">Peptides</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="Y">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2007</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2007</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2007</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17287314</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1865613</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/CVI.00249-06</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">CVI.00249-06</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Aaskov, J. G., H. M. Geysen, and T. J. Mason. 1989. Serologically defined linear epitopes in the envelope protein of dengue 2 (Jamaica strain 1409). Arch. Virol. 105:209-221.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2473720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arap, W., R. Pasqualini, and E. Ruoslahti. 1998. Cancer treatment by targeted drug delivery to tumor vasculature in a mouse model. Science 279:377-380.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9430587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atwell, S., M. Ultsch, A. M. De Vos, and J. A. Wells. 1997. Structural plasticity in a remodeled protein-protein interface. Science 278:1125-1128.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9353194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barry, M. A., W. J. Dower, and S. A. Johnston. 1996. Toward cell-targeting gene therapy vectors: selection of cell-binding peptides from random peptide-presenting phage libraries. Nat. Med. 2:299-305.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8612228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhakdi, S., and M. D. Kazatchkine. 1990. Pathogenesis of dengue: an alternative hypothesis. Southeast Asian J. Trop. Med. Public Health 21:652-657.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2098931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bielefeldt-Ohmann, H. 1997. Pathogenesis of dengue virus diseases: missing pieces in the jigsaw. Trends Microbiol. 5:409-413.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9351178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bottger, V., A. Bottger, S. F. Howard, S. M. Picksley, P. Chene, C. Garcia-Echeverria, H. K. Hochkeppel, and D. P. Lane. 1996. Identification of novel mdm2 binding peptides by phage display. Oncogene 13:2141-2147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8950981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bradford, M. M. 1976. A rapid and sensitive method for the quantitation of microgram quantities of protein utilizing the principle of protein-dye binding. Anal. Biochem. 72:248-254.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">942051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castano, A. R., S. Tangri, J. E. Miller, H. R. Holcombe, M. R. Jackson, W. D. Huse, M. Kronenberg, and P. A. Peterson. 1995. Peptide binding and presentation by mouse CD1. Science 269:223-226.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7542403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeLeo, F. R., L. Yu, J. B. Burritt, L. R. Loetterle, C. W. Bond, A. J. Jesaitis, and M. T. Quinn. 1995. Mapping sites of interaction of p47-phox and flavocytochrome b with random-sequence peptide phage display libraries. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA 92:7110-7114.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC41481</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7624379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D'Mello, F., C. D. Partidos, M. W. Steward, and C. R. Howard. 1997. Definition of the primary structure of hepatitis B virus (HBV) pre-S hepatocyte binding domain using random peptide libraries. Virology 237:319-326.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9356343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Essler, M., and E. Ruoslahti. 2002. Molecular specialization of breast vasculature: a breast-homing phage-displayed peptide binds to aminopeptidase P in breast vasculature. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA 99:2252-2257.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC122351</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11854520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Folgori, A., R. Tafi, A. Meola, F. Felici, G. Galfre, R. Cortese, P. Monaci, and A. Nicosia. 1994. A general strategy to identify mimotopes of pathological antigens using only random peptide libraries and human sera. EMBO J. 13:2236-2243.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC395079</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7514533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu, Y., L. N. Shearing, S. Haynes, P. Crewther, L. Tilley, R. F. Anders, and M. Foley. 1997. Isolation from phage display libraries of single chain variable fragment antibodies that recognize conformational epitopes in the malaria vaccine candidate, apical membrane antigen-1. J. Biol. Chem. 272:25678-25684.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9325291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gagnon, S. J., F. A. Ennis, and A. L. Rothman. 1999. Bystander target cell lysis and cytokine production by dengue virus-specific human CD4(+) cytotoxic T-lymphocyte clones. J. Virol. 73:3623-3629.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC104137</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10196254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green, S., D. W. Vaughn, S. Kalayanarooj, S. Nimmannitya, S. Suntayakorn, A. Nisalak, R. Lew, B. L. Innis, I. Kurane, A. L. Rothman, and F. A. Ennis. 1999. Early immune activation in acute dengue illness is related to development of plasma leakage and disease severity. J. Infect. Dis. 179:755-762.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10068569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gubler, D. J. 1998. Dengue and dengue hemorrhagic fever. Clin. Microbiol. Rev. 11:480-496.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC88892</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9665979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gubler, D. J., and G. G. Clark. 1995. Dengue/dengue hemorrhagic fever: the emergence of a global health problem. Emerg. Infect. Dis. 1:55-57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2626838</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8903160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halstead, S. B. 1988. Pathogenesis of dengue: challenges to molecular biology. Science 239:476-481.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3277268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halstead, S. B., C. N. Venkateshan, M. K. Gentry, and L. K. Larsen. 1984. Heterogeneity of infection enhancement of dengue 2 strains by monoclonal antibodies. J. Immunol. 132:1529-1532.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6607288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henchal, E. A., M. K. Gentry, J. M. McCown, and W. E. Brandt. 1982. Dengue virus-specific and flavivirus group determinants identified with monoclonal antibodies by indirect immunofluorescence. Am. J. Trop. Med. Hyg. 31:830-836.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6285749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hiramatsu, K., M. Tadano, R. Men, and C. J. Lai. 1996. Mutational analysis of a neutralization epitope on the dengue type 2 virus (DEN2) envelope protein: monoclonal antibody resistant DEN2/DEN4 chimeras exhibit reduced mouse neurovirulence. Virology 224:437-445.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8874504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Innis, B. L., V. Thirawuth, and C. Hemachudha. 1989. Identification of continuous epitopes of the envelope glycoprotein of dengue type 2 virus. Am. J. Trop. Med. Hyg. 40:676-687.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2472749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>King, C. A., J. S. Marshall, H. Alshurafa, and R. Anderson. 2000. Release of vasoactive cytokines by antibody-enhanced dengue virus infection of a human mast cell/basophil line. J. Virol. 74:7146-7150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC112233</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10888655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kohler, G., and C. Milstein. 1975. Continuous cultures of fused cells secreting antibody of predefined specificity. Nature 256:495-497.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1172191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koivunen, E., W. Arap, D. Rajotte, J. Lahdenranta, and R. Pasqualini. 1999. Identification of receptor ligands with phage display peptide libraries. J. Nucl. Med. 40:883-888.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10319765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraft, S., B. Diefenbach, R. Mehta, A. Jonczyk, G. A. Luckenbach, and S. L. Goodman. 1999. Definition of an unexpected ligand recognition motif for alphav beta6 integrin. J. Biol. Chem. 274:1979-1985.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9890954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurane, I., B. L. Innis, A. Nisalak, C. Hoke, S. Nimmannitya, A. Meager, and F. A. Ennis. 1989. Human T cell responses to dengue virus antigens. Proliferative responses and interferon gamma production. J. Clin. Investig. 83:506-513.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC303708</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2521489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lam, S. K., and P. L. Devine. 1998. Evaluation of capture ELISA and rapid immunochromatographic test for the determination of IgM and IgG antibodies produced during dengue infection. Clin. Diagn. Virol. 10:75-81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9646004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lanciotti, R. S., C. H. Calisher, D. J. Gubler, G. J. Chang, and A. V. Vorndam. 1992. Rapid detection and typing of dengue viruses from clinical samples by using reverse transcriptase-polymerase chain reaction. J. Clin. Microbiol. 30:545-551.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC265106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1372617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, T. Y., H. C. Wu, Y. L. Tseng, and C. T. Lin. 2004. A novel peptide specifically binding to nasopharyngeal carcinoma for targeted drug delivery. Cancer Res. 64:8002-8008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15520208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leitmeyer, K. C., D. W. Vaughn, D. M. Watts, R. Salas, I. Villalobos, C. de Ramos, and R. Rico-Hesse. 1999. Dengue virus structural differences that correlate with pathogenesis. J. Virol. 73:4738-4747.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC112516</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10233934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, B., J. Y. Tom, D. Oare, R. Yen, W. J. Fairbrother, J. A. Wells, and B. C. Cunningham. 1995. Minimization of a polypeptide hormone. Science 270:1657-1660.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7502074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, B., C. R. Parrish, J. M. Murray, and P. J. Wright. 1994. Localization of a neutralizing epitope on the envelope protein of dengue virus type 2. Virology 202:885-890.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7518164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Littaua, R., I. Kurane, and F. A. Ennis. 1990. Human IgG Fc receptor II mediates antibody-dependent enhancement of dengue virus infection. J. Immunol. 144:3183-3186.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2139079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, I. J., P. R. Hsueh, C. T. Lin, C. Y. Chiu, C. L. Kao, M. Y. Liao, and H. C. Wu. 2004. Disease-specific B cell epitopes for serum antibodies from patients with severe acute respiratory syndrome (SARS) and serologic detection of SARS antibodies by epitope-based peptide antigens. J. Infect. Dis. 190:797-809.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7109815</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15272409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mady, B. J., D. V. Erbe, I. Kurane, M. W. Fanger, and F. A. Ennis. 1991. Antibody-dependent enhancement of dengue virus infection mediated by bispecific antibodies against cell surface molecules other than Fc gamma receptors. J. Immunol. 147:3139-3144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1680925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mason, P. W., M. U. Zugel, A. R. Semproni, M. J. Fournier, and T. L. Mason. 1990. The antigenic structure of dengue type 1 virus envelope and NS1 proteins expressed in Escherichia coli. J. Gen. Virol. 71:2107-2114.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1698924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazzucchelli, L., J. B. Burritt, A. J. Jesaitis, A. Nusrat, T. W. Liang, A. T. Gewirtz, F. J. Schnell, and C. A. Parkos. 1999. Cell-specific peptide binding by human neutrophils. Blood 93:1738-1748.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10029604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Megret, F., J. P. Hugnot, A. Falconar, M. K. Gentry, D. M. Morens, J. M. Murray, J. J. Schlesinger, P. J. Wright, P. Young, M. H. Van Regenmortel, et al. 1992. Use of recombinant fusion proteins and monoclonal antibodies to define linear and discontinuous antigenic sites on the dengue virus envelope glycoprotein. Virology 187:480-491.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1372140</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morens, D. M. 1994. Antibody-dependent enhancement of infection and the pathogenesis of viral disease. Clin. Infect. Dis. 19:500-512.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7811870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nord, K., E. Gunneriusson, J. Ringdahl, S. Stahl, M. Uhlen, and P. A. Nygren. 1997. Binding proteins selected from combinatorial libraries of an alpha-helical bacterial receptor domain. Nat. Biotechnol. 15:772-777.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9255793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palmer, C. J., S. D. King, R. R. Cuadrado, E. Perez, M. Baum, and A. L. Ager. 1999. Evaluation of the MRL Diagnostics Dengue Fever Virus IgM Capture ELISA and the PanBio Rapid Immunochromatographic Test for diagnosis of dengue fever in Jamaica. J. Clin. Microbiol. 37:1600-1601.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC84845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10203534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pasqualini, R., E. Koivunen, and E. Ruoslahti. 1995. A peptide isolated from phage display libraries is a structural and functional mimic of an RGD-binding site on integrins. J. Cell Biol. 130:1189-1196.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2120548</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7657703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pasqualini, R., and E. Ruoslahti. 1996. Organ targeting in vivo using phage display peptide libraries. Nature 380:364-366.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8598934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prezzi, C., M. Nuzzo, A. Meola, P. Delmastro, G. Galfre, R. Cortese, A. Nicosia, and P. Monaci. 1996. Selection of antigenic and immunogenic mimics of hepatitis C virus using sera from patients. J. Immunol. 156:4504-4513.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8666827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rico-Hesse, R., L. M. Harrison, R. A. Salas, D. Tovar, A. Nisalak, C. Ramos, J. Boshell, M. T. de Mesa, R. M. Nogueira, and A. T. da Rosa. 1997. Origins of dengue type 2 viruses associated with increased pathogenicity in the Americas. Virology 230:244-251.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9143280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roehrig, J. T., R. A. Bolin, and R. G. Kelly. 1998. Monoclonal antibody mapping of the envelope glycoprotein of the dengue 2 virus, Jamaica. Virology 246:317-328.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9657950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosen, L. 1977. The Emperor's New Clothes revisited, or reflections on the pathogenesis of dengue hemorrhagic fever. Am. J. Trop. Med. Hyg. 26:337-343.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">869095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rothman, A. L., and F. A. Ennis. 1999. Immunopathogenesis of dengue hemorrhagic fever. Virology 257:1-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10208914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakuntabhai, A., C. Turbpaiboon, I. Casademont, A. Chuansumrit, T. Lowhnoo, A. Kajaste-Rudnitski, S. M. Kalayanarooj, K. Tangnararatchakit, N. Tangthawornchaikul, S. Vasanawathana, W. Chaiyaratana, P. T. Yenchitsomanus, P. Suriyaphol, P. Avirutnan, K. Chokephaibulkit, F. Matsuda, S. Yoksan, Y. Jacob, G. M. Lathrop, P. Malasit, P. Despres, and C. Julier. 2005. A variant in the CD209 promoter is associated with severity of dengue disease. Nat. Genet. 37:507-513.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7096904</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15838506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott, J. K., and G. P. Smith. 1990. Searching for peptide ligands with an epitope library. Science 249:386-390.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1696028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith, W. C., J. H. McDowell, D. R. Dugger, R. Miller, A. Arendt, M. P. Popp, and P. A. Hargrave. 1999. Identification of regions of arrestin that bind to rhodopsin. Biochemistry 38:2752-2761.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10052946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trirawatanapong, T., B. Chandran, R. Putnak, and R. Padmanabhan. 1992. Mapping of a region of dengue virus type-2 glycoprotein required for binding by a neutralizing monoclonal antibody. Gene 116:139-150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7125935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1634111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaughn, D. W., S. Green, S. Kalayanarooj, B. L. Innis, S. Nimmannitya, S. Suntayakorn, T. P. Endy, B. Raengsakulrach, A. L. Rothman, F. A. Ennis, and A. Nisalak. 2000. Dengue viremia titer, antibody response pattern, and virus serotype correlate with disease severity. J. Infect. Dis. 181:2-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10608744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaughn, D. W., A. Nisalak, S. Kalayanarooj, T. Solomon, N. M. Dung, A. Cuzzubbo, and P. L. Devine. 1998. Evaluation of a rapid immunochromatographic test for diagnosis of dengue virus infection. J. Clin. Microbiol. 36:234-238.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC124841</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9431954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaughn, D. W., A. Nisalak, T. Solomon, S. Kalayanarooj, M. D. Nguyen, R. Kneen, A. Cuzzubbo, and P. L. Devine. 1999. Rapid serologic diagnosis of dengue virus infection using a commercial capture ELISA that distinguishes primary and secondary infections. Am. J. Trop. Med. Hyg. 60:693-698.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10348250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westaway, E. G., and J. Blok. 1997. Taxonomy and evolutionary relationships of flaviviruses. CAB International, New York, NY.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilder-Smith, A., and E. Schwartz. 2005. Dengue in travelers. N. Engl. J. Med. 353:924-932.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16135837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, H. C., Y. L. Huang, T. T. Chao, J. T. Jan, J. L. Huang, H. Y. Chiang, C. C. King, and M. F. Shaio. 2001. Identification of B-cell epitope of dengue virus type 1 and its application in diagnosis of patients. J. Clin. Microbiol. 39:977-982.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC87860</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11230414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, H. C., M. Y. Jung, C. Y. Chiu, T. T. Chao, S. C. Lai, J. T. Jan, and M. F. Shaio. 2003. Identification of a dengue virus type 2 (DEN-2) serotype-specific B-cell epitope and detection of DEN-2-immunized animal serum samples using an epitope-based peptide antigen. J. Gen. Virol. 84:2771-2779.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13679612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, H. C., C. T. Yeh, Y. L. Huang, L. J. Tarn, and C. C. Lung. 2001. Characterization of neutralizing antibodies and identification of neutralizing epitope mimics on the Clostridium botulinum neurotoxin type A. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 67:3201-3207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC93001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11425742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>