<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">17360740</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2007</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>12</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2018</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0022-538X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>81</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2007</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of virology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Virol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Both virus and tumor necrosis factor alpha are critical for endothelium damage in a mouse model of dengue virus-induced hemorrhage.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>5518</StartPage><EndPage>5526</EndPage><MedlinePgn>5518-26</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>Hemorrhage is a common clinical manifestation in dengue patients. However, the pathogenic mechanism of dengue virus (DV)-induced hemorrhage awaits clarification. We established a mouse model of DV hemorrhage using immunocompetent C57BL/6 mice by injecting DV serotype 2 strain 16681 intradermally. While inoculation of 3 x 10(9) PFU of DV induced systemic hemorrhage in all of the mice by day 3 of infection, one out of three of those injected with 4 x 10(7) to 8 x 10(7) PFU developed hemorrhage in the subcutaneous tissues. The mice that were inoculated with 4 x 10(7) to 8 x 10(7) PFU but that did not develop hemorrhage were used as a basis for comparison to explore the pathogenic mechanism of dengue hemorrhage. The results showed that mice with severe thrombocytopenia manifested signs of vascular leakage and hemorrhage. We observed that high viral titer, macrophage infiltration, and tumor necrosis factor alpha (TNF-alpha) production in the local tissues are three important events that lead to hemorrhage. Immunofluorescence staining revealed that DV targeted both endothelial cells and macrophages. In addition, the production of high levels of TNF-alpha in tissues correlated with endothelial cell apoptosis and hemorrhage. By comparing TNF-alpha(-/-) to IgH(-/-), C5(-/-), and wild-type mice, we found that TNF-alpha was important for the development of hemorrhage. In vitro studies showed that mouse primary microvascular endothelial cells were susceptible to DV but that TNF-alpha enhanced DV-induced apoptosis. Our mouse model illustrated that intradermal inoculation of high titers of DV predisposes endothelial cells to be susceptible to TNF-alpha-induced cell death, which leads to endothelium damage and hemorrhage development. This finding highlights the contribution of the innate immune response to dengue hemorrhage.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Hsuen-Chin</ForeName><Initials>HC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate Institute of Immunology, National Taiwan University College of Medicine, No. 1 Jen-Ai Road, Section 1, Taipei 10051, Taiwan, Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hofman</LastName><ForeName>Florence M</ForeName><Initials>FM</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kung</LastName><ForeName>John T</ForeName><Initials>JT</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lin</LastName><ForeName>Yang-Ding</ForeName><Initials>YD</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu-Hsieh</LastName><ForeName>Betty A</ForeName><Initials>BA</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2007</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Virol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0113724</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0022-538X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D014409">Tumor Necrosis Factor-alpha</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017209" MajorTopicYN="N">Apoptosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003716" MajorTopicYN="N">Dengue Virus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000472" MajorTopicYN="Y">pathogenicity</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004195" MajorTopicYN="Y">Disease Models, Animal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004730" MajorTopicYN="N">Endothelium, Vascular</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="Y">pathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="Y">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051379" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008805" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice, Inbred A</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008810" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice, Inbred C57BL</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018345" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice, Knockout</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019595" MajorTopicYN="N">Severe Dengue</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="Y">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014409" MajorTopicYN="N">Tumor Necrosis Factor-alpha</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000172" MajorTopicYN="N">deficiency</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2007</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2007</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2007</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17360740</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1900309</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JVI.02575-06</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">JVI.02575-06</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Baldwin, H. S., H. M. Shen, H. C. Yan, H. M. DeLisser, A. Chung, C. Mickanin, T. Trask, N. E. Kirschbaum, P. J. Newman, S. M. Albelda, et al. 1994. Platelet endothelial cell adhesion molecule-1 (PECAM-1/CD31): alternatively spliced, functionally distinct isoforms expressed during mammalian cardiovascular development. Development 120:2539-2553.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7956830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bethell, D. B., K. Flobbe, X. T. Cao, N. P. Day, T. P. Pham, W. A. Buurman, M. J. Cardosa, N. J. White, and D. Kwiatkowski. 1998. Pathophysiologic and prognostic role of cytokines in dengue hemorrhagic fever. J. Infect. Dis. 177:778-782.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9498463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carr, J. M., H. Hocking, K. Bunting, P. J. Wright, A. Davidson, J. Gamble, C. J. Burrell, and P. Li. 2003. Supernatants from dengue virus type-2 infected macrophages induce permeability changes in endothelial cell monolayers. J. Med. Virol. 69:521-528.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12601760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, H. C., S. Y. Lai, J. M. Sung, S. H. Lee, Y. C. Lin, W. K. Wang, Y. C. Chen, C. L. Kao, C. C. King, and B. A. Wu-Hsieh. 2004. Lymphocyte activation and hepatic cellular infiltration in immunocompetent mice infected by dengue virus. J. Med. Virol. 73:419-431.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15170638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Espina, L. M., N. J. Valero, J. M. Hernandez, and J. A. Mosquera. 2003. Increased apoptosis and expression of tumor necrosis factor-alpha caused by infection of cultured human monocytes with dengue virus. Am. J. Trop. Med. Hyg. 68:48-53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12556148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandez-Mestre, M. T., K. Gendzekhadze, P. Rivas-Vetencourt, and Z. Layrisse. 2004. TNF-alpha-308A allele, a possible severity risk factor of hemorrhagic manifestation in dengue fever patients. Tissue Antigens 64:469-472.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15361124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gagnon, S. J., F. A. Ennis, and A. L. Rothman. 1999. Bystander target cell lysis and cytokine production by dengue virus-specific human CD4+ cytotoxic T-lymphocyte clones. J. Virol. 73:3623-3629.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC104137</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10196254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green, S., D. W. Vaughn, S. Kalayanarooj, S. Nimmannitya, S. Suntayakorn, A. Nisalak, R. Lew, B. L. Innis, I. Kurane, A. L. Rothman, and F. A. Ennis. 1999. Early immune activation in acute dengue illness is related to development of plasma leakage and disease severity. J. Infect. Dis. 179:755-762.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10068569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gubler, D. J. 1998. Dengue and dengue hemorrhagic fever. Clin. Microbiol. Rev. 11:480-496.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC88892</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9665979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halstead, S. B. 1989. Antibody, macrophages, dengue virus infection, shock, and hemorrhage: a pathogenetic cascade. Rev. Infect. Dis. 11(Suppl. 4):S830-S839.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2665015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halstead, S. B. 2002. Dengue. Curr. Opin. Infect. Dis. 15:471-476.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12686878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hober, D., A. S. Delannoy, S. Benyoucef, D. De Groote, and P. Wattre. 1996. High levels of sTNFR p75 and TNF alpha in dengue-infected patients. Microbiol. Immunol. 40:569-573.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8887351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hober, D., L. Poli, B. Roblin, P. Gestas, E. Chungue, G. Granic, P. Imbert, J. L. Pecarere, R. Vergez-Pascal, P. Wattre, et al. 1993. Serum levels of tumor necrosis factor-alpha (TNF-alpha), interleukin-6 (IL-6), and interleukin-1 beta (IL-1 beta) in dengue-infected patients. Am. J. Trop. Med. Hyg. 48:324-331.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8470771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, K. J., S. Y. Li, S. C. Chen, H. S. Liu, Y. S. Lin, T. M. Yeh, C. C. Liu, and H. Y. Lei. 2000. Manifestation of thrombocytopenia in dengue-2-virus-infected mice. J. Gen. Virol. 81:2177-2182.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10950974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jessie, K., M. Y. Fong, S. Devi, S. K. Lam, and K. T. Wong. 2004. Localization of dengue virus in naturally infected human tissues, by immunohistochemistry and in situ hybridization. J. Infect. Dis. 189:1411-1418.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15073678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson, A. J., and J. T. Roehrig. 1999. New mouse model for dengue virus vaccine testing. J. Virol. 73:783-786.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC103889</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9847388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaiser, L., and H. V. Sparks, Jr. 1987. Endothelial cells. Not just a cellophane wrapper. Arch. Intern. Med. 147:569-573.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3827434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, Y. L., C. L. Liao, L. K. Chen, C. T. Yeh, C. I. Liu, S. H. Ma, Y. Y. Huang, Y. L. Huang, C. L. Kao, and C. C. King. 1998. Study of dengue virus infection in SCID mice engrafted with human K562 cells. J. Virol. 72:9729-9737.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC110483</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9811707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malasit, P. 1987. Complement and dengue haemorrhagic fever/shock syndrome. Southeast Asian J. Trop. Med. Public Health 18:316-320.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3501613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mangada, M. M., T. P. Endy, A. Nisalak, S. Chunsuttiwat, D. W. Vaughn, D. H. Libraty, S. Green, F. A. Ennis, and A. L. Rothman. 2002. Dengue-specific T cell responses in peripheral blood mononuclear cells obtained prior to secondary dengue virus infections in Thai schoolchildren. J. Infect. Dis. 185:1697-1703.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12085313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mangada, M. M., and A. L. Rothman. 2005. Altered cytokine responses of dengue-specific CD4+ T cells to heterologous serotypes. J. Immunol. 175:2676-2683.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16081844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rico-Hesse, R. 1990. Molecular evolution and distribution of dengue viruses type 1 and 2 in nature. Virology 174:479-493.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2129562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rothman, A. L., and F. A. Ennis. 1999. Immunopathogenesis of dengue hemorrhagic fever. Virology 257:1-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10208914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russell, P. K., S. Udomsakdi, and S. B. Halstead. 1967. Antibody response in dengue and dengue hemorrhagic fever. Jpn. J. Med. Sci. Biol. 20:103-108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4968625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabin, A. B. 1952. Research on dengue during World War II. Am. J. Trop. Med. Hyg. 1:30-50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14903434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaio, M. F., F. Y. Chang, and S. C. Hou. 1992. Complement pathway activity in serum from patients with classical dengue fever. Trans. R. Soc. Trop. Med. Hyg. 86:672-675.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1287942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shresta, S., K. L. Sharar, D. M. Prigozhin, P. R. Beatty, and E. Harris. 2006. Murine model for dengue virus-induced lethal disease with increased vascular permeability. J. Virol. 80:10208-10217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1617308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17005698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shresta, S., K. L. Sharar, D. M. Prigozhin, H. M. Snider, P. R. Beatty, and E. Harris. 2005. Critical roles for both STAT1-dependent and STAT1-independent pathways in the control of primary dengue virus infection in mice. J. Immunol. 175:3946-3954.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16148142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vassalli, P. 1992. The pathophysiology of tumor necrosis factors. Annu. Rev. Immunol. 10:411-452.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1590993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, W. K., T. L. Sung, Y. C. Tsai, C. L. Kao, S. M. Chang, and C. C. King. 2002. Detection of dengue virus replication in peripheral blood mononuclear cells from dengue virus type 2-infected patients by a reverse transcription-real-time PCR assay. J. Clin. Microbiol. 40:4472-4478.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC154639</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12454138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson, A. G., J. A. Symons, T. L. McDowell, H. O. McDevitt, and G. W. Duff. 1997. Effects of a polymorphism in the human tumor necrosis factor alpha promoter on transcriptional activation. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA 94:3195-3199.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC20345</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9096369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, S. J., C. G. Hayes, D. R. Dubois, M. G. Windheuser, Y. H. Kang, D. M. Watts, and D. G. Sieckmann. 1995. Evaluation of the severe combined immunodeficient (SCID) mouse as an animal model for dengue viral infection. Am. J. Trop. Med. Hyg. 52:468-476.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7771614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, Z., F. M. Hofman, and B. V. Zlokovic. 2003. A simple method for isolation and characterization of mouse brain microvascular endothelial cells. J. Neurosci. Methods 130:53-63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14583404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yadav, M., K. R. Kamath, N. Iyngkaran, and M. Sinniah. 1991. Dengue haemorrhagic fever and dengue shock syndrome: are they tumour necrosis factor-mediated disorders? FEMS Microbiol. Immunol. 4:45-49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1815710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>