<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">18350148</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2008</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>08</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1932-6203</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>3</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2008</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>19</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PloS one</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PLoS One</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>High genetic stability of dengue virus propagated in MRC-5 cells as compared to the virus propagated in vero cells.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e1810</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e1810</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e1810</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1371/journal.pone.0001810</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This work investigated the replication kinetics of the four dengue virus serotypes (DEN-1 to DEN-4), including dengue virus type 4 (DEN-4) recovered from an infectious cDNA clone, in Vero cells and in MRC-5 cells grown on Cytodex 1 microcarriers. DEN-1 strain Hawaii, DEN-2 strain NGC, DEN-3 strain H-87, and DEN-4 strain H-241 , and DEN-4 strain 814669 derived from cloned DNA, were used to infect Vero cells and MRC-5 cells grown in serum-free or serum-containing microcarrier cultures. Serum-free and serum-containing cultures were found to yield comparable titers of these viruses. The cloned DNA-derived DEN-4 started genetically more homogeneous was used to investigate the genetic stability of the virus propagated in Vero cells and MRC-5 cells. Sequence analysis revealed that the DEN-4 propagated in MRC-5 cells maintained a high genetic stability, compared to the virus propagated in Vero cells. Amino acid substitutions of Gly(104)Cys and Phe(108)Ile were detected at 70%, 60%, respectively, in the envelope (E) protein of DEN-4 propagated in Vero cells, whereas a single mutation of Glu(345)Lys was detected at 50% in E of the virus propagated in MRC-5 cells. Sequencing of multiple clones of three separate DNA fragments spanning 40% of the genome also indicated that DEN-4 propagated in Vero cells contained a higher number of mutations than the virus growing in MRC-5 cells. Although Vero cells yielded a peak virus titer approximately 1 to 17 folds higher than MRC-5 cells, cloned DEN-4 from MRC-5 cells maintained a greater stability than the virus from Vero cells. Serum-free microcarrier cultures of MRC-5 cells offer a potentially valuable system for the large-scale production of live-attenuated DEN vaccines.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Chia-Chyi</ForeName><Initials>CC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Biotechnology, Department of Life Science, National Tsing Hua University, Hsinchu, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Shiang-Chi</ForeName><Initials>SC</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Butler</LastName><ForeName>Michael</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Suh-Chin</ForeName><Initials>SC</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2008</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PLoS One</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101285081</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1932-6203</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D016895">Culture Media, Serum-Free</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019943" MajorTopicYN="N">Amino Acid Substitution</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001769" MajorTopicYN="N">Blood</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002460" MajorTopicYN="N">Cell Line</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002522" MajorTopicYN="N">Chlorocebus aethiops</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006224" MajorTopicYN="N">Cricetinae</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016895" MajorTopicYN="N">Culture Media, Serum-Free</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003716" MajorTopicYN="N">Dengue Virus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="Y">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000254" MajorTopicYN="N">growth &amp; development</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009154" MajorTopicYN="N">Mutation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013045" MajorTopicYN="N">Species Specificity</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement><b>Competing Interests: </b>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2007</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2008</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2008</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2008</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2008</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18350148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2265545</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0001810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Gubler DJ. Epidemic dengue/dengue hemorrhagic fever as a public health, social and economic problem in the 21st century. Trends Microbiol. 2002;10(2):100&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11827812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rigau-Perez JG, Clark GG, Gubler DJ, Reiter P, Sanders EJ, et al. Dengue and dengue haemorrhagic fever. Lancet. 1998;352(9132):971&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9752834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halstead SB. Pathogenesis of dengue: challenges to molecular biology. Science. 1988;239(4839):476&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3277268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitehead SS, Blaney JE, Durbin AP, Murphy BR. Prospects for a dengue virus vaccine. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2007;5(7):518&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17558424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhamarapravati N, Sutee Y. Live attenuated tetravalent dengue vaccine. Vaccine. 2000;18(Suppl.2):44&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10821973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabchareon A, Lang J, Chanthavanich P, Yoksan S, Forrat R, et al. Safety and immunogenicity of tetravalent live-attenuated dengue vaccines in Thai adult volunteers: role of serotype concentration, ratio, and multiple doses. Am J Trop Med Hyg. 2002;66(3):264&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12139219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabchareon A, Lang J, Chanthavanich P, Yoksan S, Forrat R, et al. Safety and immunogenicity of a three dose regimen of two tetravalent live-attenuated dengue vaccines in five- to twelve-year-old Thai children. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2004;23(2):99&#x2013;109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14872173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edelman R, Wasserman SS, Bodison SA, Putnak RJ, Eckels KH, et al. Phase I trial of 16 formulations of a tetravalent live-attenuated dengue vaccine. Am J Trop Med Hyg. 2003;69(6 Suppl):48&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14740955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanesa-Thasan N, Edelman R, Tacket CO, Wasserman SS, Vaughn DW, et al. Phase 1 studies of Walter Reed Army Institute of Research candidate attenuated dengue vaccines: selection of safe and immunogenic monovalent vaccines. Am J Trop Med Hyg. 2003;69(6 Suppl):17&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14740951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun W, Edelman R, Kanesa-Thasan N, Eckels KH, Putnak JR, et al. Vaccination of human volunteers with monovalent and tetravalent live-attenuated dengue vaccine candidates. Am J Trop Med Hyg. 2003;69(6 Suppl):24&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14740952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kinney RM, Butrapet S, Chang GJ, Tsuchiya KR, Roehrig JT, et al. Construction of infectious cDNA clones for dengue 2 virus: strain 16681 and its attenuated vaccine derivative, strain PDK-53. Virology. 1997;230:300&#x2013;308.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9143286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai CJ, Zhao BT, Hori H, Bray M. Infectious RNA transcribed from stably cloned full-length cDNA of dengue type 4 virus. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 1991;88:5139&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC51827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2052593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Men R, Bray M, Clark D, Chanock RM, Lai CJ. Dengue type 4 virus mutants containing deletions in the 3&#x2032;noncoding region of the RNA genome: Analysis of growth restriction in cell culture and altered viremia pattern and immunogenicity in rhesus monkeys. J Virol. 1996;70:3930&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC190271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8648730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai CJ, Bray M, Men R, Cahour A, Chen W, et al. Evaluation of molecular strategies to develop a live dengue vaccine. Clin Diag Virol. 1998;10:173&#x2013;179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9741643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang CY, Butrapet S, Tsuchiya KR, Bhamarapravati N, Gubler DJ, et al. Dengue 2 PDK-53 virus as a chimeric carrier for tetravalent dengue vaccine development. J Virol. 2003;77(21):11436&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC229366</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14557629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durbin AP, Karron RA, Sun W, Vaughn DW, Reynolds MJ, et al. Attenuation and immunogenicity in humans of a live dengue virus type-4 vaccine candidate with a 30 nucleotide deletion in its 3&#x2032;-untranslated region. Am J Trop Med Hyg. 2001;65(5):405&#x2013;413.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11716091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guirakhoo F, Weltzin R, Chambers TJ, Zhang ZX, Soike K, et al. Recombinant chimeric yellow fever-dengue type 2 virus is immunogenic and protective in nonhuman primates. J Virol. 2000;74(12):5477&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC112032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10823852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guirakhoo F, Arroyo J, Pugachev KV, Miller C, Zhang ZX, et al. Construction, safety, and immunogenicity in nonhuman primates of a chimeric yellow fever-dengue virus tetravalent vaccine. J Virol. 2001;75:7290&#x2013;304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC114964</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11462001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guirakhoo F, Pugachev KV, Arroyo J, Miller C, Zhang ZX, et al. Viremia and immunogenicity in nonhuman primates of a tetravalent yellow fever-dengue chimeric vaccine: genetic reconstructions, dose adjustment, and antibody responses against wild-type dengue virus isolates. Virology. 2002;298:146&#x2013;159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12093182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guirakhoo F, Pugachev K, Zhang Z, Myers G, Levenbook I, et al. Safety and efficacy of chimeric yellow Fever-dengue virus tetravalent vaccine formulations in nonhuman primates. J Virol. 2004;78(9):4761&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC387722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15078958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blaney JE, Jr, Manipon GG, Firestone CY, Johnson DH, Hanson CT, et al. Mutations which enhance the replication of dengue virus type 4 and an antigenic chimeric dengue virus type 2/4 vaccine candidate in Vero cells. Vaccine. 2003;21(27&#x2013;30):4317&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14505914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blaney JE, Johnson DH, Manipon GG, Firestone CY, Hanson CT, et al. Genetic basis of attenuation of dengue virus type 4 small plaque mutants with restricted replication in suckling mice and in SCID mice transplanted with human liver cells. Virology. 2002;300:125&#x2013;139.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12202213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stinchcomb DT, Kinney RM, Huang CY, Wiggan O, Kalanidhi AP, et al. Taipei, Taiwan: Third Asian Regional Dengue Research Network Meeting; 2007. Development of dengue 2-PDK-53-based chimeric tetravalent dengue vaccines. p. 58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butler M, Burgener A, Patrick M, Berry M, Moffatt D, et al. Application of a serum-free medium for the growth of Vero cells and the production or reovirus. Biotechnol Prog. 2000;16:854&#x2013;858.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11027181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu SC, Huang GYL. Stationary and microcarrier cell culture processes for propagating Japanese encephalitis virus. Biotechnol Prog. 2002;18:124&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11822910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu SC, Liu CC, Lian WC. Optimization of microcarrier cell culture process for the inactivated enterovirus type 71 vaccine development. Vaccine. 2004;22(29&#x2013;30):3858&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15364432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu CC, Lian WC, Butler M, Wu SC. High immunogenic enterovirus 71 strain and its production using serum-free microcarrier Vero cell culture. Vaccine. 2007;25(1):19&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16919374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aunins JG. Viral vaccine production in cell culture. In: Spier RE, editor. Encyclopedia of Cell Technology. Vol. 2. John Wiley &amp; Sons; 2000. pp. 1182&#x2013;1217.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawano H, Rostapsov V, Rosen L, Lai CJ. Genetic determinants of dengue type 4 virus neurovirulence for mice. J Virol. 1993;67(11):6567&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC238094</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8411360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitehead SS, Hanley KA, Blaney JE, Jr, Gilmore LE, Elkins WR, et al. Substitution of the structural genes of dengue virus type 4 with those of type 2 results in chimeric vaccine candidates which are attenuated for mosquitoes, mice, and rhesus monkeys. Vaccine. 2003;21(27&#x2013;30):4307&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14505913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang WF, Eshita Y, Tadano M, Morita K, Makino Y. Molecular basis for adaptation of a chimeric dengue type-4/Japanese encephalitis virus to Vero cells. Microbiol Immunol. 2005;49(3):285&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15782002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chao DY, King CC, Wang WK, Chen WJ, Wu HL, et al. Strategically examining the full-genome of dengue virus type 3 in clinical isolates reveals its mutation spectra. Virol J. 2005;2:72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1208963</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16120221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu CC, Wu SC. Mosquito and mammalian cells grown on microcarriers for four-serotype dengue virus production: variations in virus titer, plaque morphology, and replication rate. Biotechnol Bioeng. 2004;85(5):482&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14760688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu T, Mo H, Wang N, Nam DS, Cao Y, et al. Genotypic and phenotypic characterization of HIV-1 in patients with primary infection. Science. 1993;261:1179&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8356453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang WK, Lin SR, Lee CM, King CC, Chang SC. Dengue-3 virus in plasma is a population of closely related genomes: Quasispecies. J Virol. 2002;76(9):4662&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC155095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11932434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>