<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">18448542</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2008</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>06</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1098-5514</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>82</Volume><Issue>13</Issue><PubDate><Year>2008</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of virology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Virol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Antibodies to envelope glycoprotein of dengue virus during the natural course of infection are predominantly cross-reactive and recognize epitopes containing highly conserved residues at the fusion loop of domain II.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>6631</StartPage><EndPage>6643</EndPage><MedlinePgn>6631-43</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1128/JVI.00316-08</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The antibody response to the envelope (E) glycoprotein of dengue virus (DENV) is known to play a critical role in both protection from and enhancement of disease, especially after primary infection. However, the relative amounts of homologous and heterologous anti-E antibodies and their epitopes remain unclear. In this study, we examined the antibody responses to E protein as well as to precursor membrane (PrM), capsid, and nonstructural protein 1 (NS1) of four serotypes of DENV by Western blot analysis of DENV serotype 2-infected patients with different disease severity and immune status during an outbreak in southern Taiwan in 2002. Based on the early-convalescent-phase sera tested, the rates of antibody responses to PrM and NS1 proteins were significantly higher in patients with secondary infection than in those with primary infection. A blocking experiment and neutralization assay showed that more than 90% of anti-E antibodies after primary infection were cross-reactive and nonneutralizing against heterologous serotypes and that only a minor proportion were type specific, which may account for the type-specific neutralization activity. Moreover, the E-binding activity in sera of 10 patients with primary infection was greatly reduced by amino acid replacements of three fusion loop residues, tryptophan at position 101, leucine at position 107, and phenylalanine at position 108, but not by replacements of those outside the fusion loop of domain II, suggesting that the predominantly cross-reactive anti-E antibodies recognized epitopes involving the highly conserved residues at the fusion loop of domain II. These findings have implications for our understanding of the pathogenesis of dengue and for the future design of subunit vaccine against DENV as well.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lai</LastName><ForeName>Chih-Yun</ForeName><Initials>CY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Microbiology, College of Medicine, National Taiwan University, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tsai</LastName><ForeName>Wen-Yang</ForeName><Initials>WY</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lin</LastName><ForeName>Su-Ru</ForeName><Initials>SR</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kao</LastName><ForeName>Chuan-Liang</ForeName><Initials>CL</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hu</LastName><ForeName>Hsien-Ping</ForeName><Initials>HP</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>King</LastName><ForeName>Chwan-Chuen</ForeName><Initials>CC</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Han-Chung</ForeName><Initials>HC</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chang</LastName><ForeName>Gwong-Jen</ForeName><Initials>GJ</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Wei-Kung</ForeName><Initials>WK</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D003160">Comparative Study</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2008</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Virol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0113724</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0022-538X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000914">Antibodies, Viral</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D017931">DNA Primers</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C051821">E-glycoprotein, Dengue virus type 2</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000939">Epitopes</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D014759">Viral Envelope Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000914" MajorTopicYN="N">Antibodies, Viral</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="Y">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015153" MajorTopicYN="N">Blotting, Western</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002460" MajorTopicYN="N">Cell Line</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003429" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross Reactions</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="Y">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017931" MajorTopicYN="N">DNA Primers</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003716" MajorTopicYN="N">Dengue Virus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="Y">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004797" MajorTopicYN="N">Enzyme-Linked Immunosorbent Assay</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000939" MajorTopicYN="N">Epitopes</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020125" MajorTopicYN="N">Mutation, Missense</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009500" MajorTopicYN="N">Neutralization Tests</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017434" MajorTopicYN="N">Protein Structure, Tertiary</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013624" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Taiwan</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014759" MajorTopicYN="N">Viral Envelope Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="Y">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="Y">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2008</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2008</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2008</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18448542</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2447043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JVI.00316-08</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">JVI.00316-08</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Alvarez, M., R. Rodriguez-Roche, L. Bernardo, S. Vazquez, L. Morier, D. Gonzalez, O. Castro, G. Kouri, S. B. Halstead, and M. G. Guzman. 2006. Dengue hemorrhagic Fever caused by sequential dengue 1-3 virus infections over a long time interval: Havana epidemic, 2001-2002. Am. J. Trop. Med. Hyg. 751113-1117.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17172378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beasley, D. W. C., and A. D. T. Barrett. 2002. Identification of neutralizing epitopes within structural domain III of the West Nile virus envelope protein. J. Virol. 7613097-13100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC136710</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12438639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bray, M., and C. J. Lai. 1991. Dengue virus premembrane and membrane proteins elicit a protective immune response. Virology 185505-508.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1926792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke, D. S., A. Nisalak, D. E. Johnson, and R. M. Scott. 1988. A prospective study of dengue infections in Bangkok. Am. J. Trop. Med. Hyg. 38172-180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3341519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Churdboonchart, V., N. Bhamarapravati, S. Peampramprecha, and S. Sirinavin. 1991. Antibodies against dengue viral proteins in primary and secondary dengue hemorrhagic fever. Am. J. Trop. Med. Hyg. 44481-493.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2063952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crill, W. D., and G. J. J. Chang. 2004. Localization and characterization of flavivirus envelope glycoprotein cross-reactive epitopes. J. Virol. 7813975-13986.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC533943</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15564505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crill, W. D., and J. T. Roehrig. 2001. Monoclonal antibodies that bind to domain III of dengue virus E glycoprotein are the most efficient blockers of virus adsorption to Vero cells. J. Virol. 757769-7773.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC115016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11462053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Endy, T. P., A. Nisalak, S. Chunsuttitwat, D. W. Vaughn, S. Green, F. A. Ennis, A. L. Rothman, and D. H. Libraty. 2004. Relationship of preexisting dengue virus (DV) neutralizing antibody levels to viremia and severity of disease in a prospective cohort study of DV infection in Thailand. J. Infect. Dis. 189990-1000.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14999601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Falconar, A. K. 1997. The dengue virus nonstructural-1 protein (NS1) generates antibodies to common epitopes on human blood clotting, integrin/adhesion proteins and binds to human endothelial cells: potential implications in hemorrhagic fever pathogenesis. Arch. Virol. 143897-916.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9191856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Falconar, A. K., and P. R. Young. 1991. Production of dimer-specific and dengue virus group cross-reactive mouse monoclonal antibodies to the dengue 2 virus non-structural glycoprotein NS1. J. Gen. Virol. 72961-965.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1849979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Falgout, B., M. Bray, J. J. Schlesinger, and C. J. Lai. 1990. Immunization of mice with recombinant vaccinia virus expressing authentic dengue virus nonstructural protein NS1 protects against lethal dengue virus encephalitis. J. Virol. 644356-4363.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC247903</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2143542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goncalvez, A. P., R. H. Purcell, and C. J. Lai. 2004. Epitope determinants of a chimpanzee Fab antibody that efficiently cross-neutralizes dengue type 1 and type 2 viruses map to inside and in close proximity to fusion loop of the dengue type 2 virus envelope glycoprotein. J. Virol. 7812919-12928.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC525008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15542644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez, D., O. E. Castro, G. Kouri, J. Perez, E. Martinez, S. Vazquez, D. Rosario, R. Cancio, and M. G. Guzman. 2005. Classical dengue hemorrhagic fever resulting from two dengue infection spaced 20 years or more apart: Havana, dengue 3 epidemic, 2001-2002. Int. J. Infect. Dis. 9280-285.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16023878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gubler, D. J. 1998. Dengue and dengue hemorrhagic fever. Clin. Microbiol. Rev. 11480-496.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC88892</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9665979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gubler, D. J. 2002. Epidemic dengue/dengue hemorrhagic fever as a public health, social and economic problem in the 21st century. Trends Microbiol. 10100-103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11827812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guzman, M. G., M. Alvarez, R. Rodriguez-Roche, L. Bernardo, T. Montes, S. Vazquez, L. Morier, A. Alvarez, E. A. Gould, G. Kouri, and S. B. Halstead. 2007. Neutralizing antibodies after infection with dengue 1 virus. Emerg. Infect. Dis. 13282-286.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2725871</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17479892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guzman, M. G., and G. Kouri. 2002. Dengue: an update. Lancet Infect. Dis. 233-42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11892494</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guzman, M. G., G. P. Kouri, J. Bravo, M. Soler, S. Vazquez, and L. Morier. 1990. Dengue hemorrhagic fever in Cuba, 1981: a retrospective seroepidemiologic study. Am. J. Trop. Med. Hyg. 42179-184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2316788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guzman, M. G., G. Kouri, L. Valdes, J. Bravo, M. Alvarez, S. Vazquez, I. Delgado, and S. B. Halstead. 2000. Epidemiologic studies on dengue in Santiago de Cuba, 1997. Am. J. Epidemiol. 152793-799.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11085389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guzman, M. G., G. Kouri, L. Valdes, J. Bravo, S. Vazquez, and S. B. Halstead. 2002. Enhanced severity of secondary dengue-2 infections: death rates in 1981 and 1997 Cuban outbreaks. Rev. Panam. Salud Publica 11223-227.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12049030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halstead, S. B. 1988. Pathogenesis of dengue: challenges to molecular biology. Science 239476-481.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3277268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halstead, S. B. 2003. Neutralization and antibody-dependent enhancement of dengue viruses. Adv. Virus Res. 60421-467.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14689700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halstead, S. B., and E. J. O'Rourke. 1977. Antibody-enhanced dengue virus infection in primate leukocytes. Nature 265739-741.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">404559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henchal, E. A., M. K. Gentry, J. M. McCown, and W. E. Brandt. 1982. Dengue virus-specific and flavivirus group determinants identified with monoclonal antibodies by indirect immunofluorescence. Am. J. Trop. Med. Hyg. 31830-836.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6285749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henchal, E. A., L. S. Henchal, and J. J. Schlesinger. 1988. Synergistic interactions of anti-NS1 monoclonal antibodies protect passively immunized mice from lethal challenge with dengue 2 virus. J. Gen. Virol. 692101-2107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3404125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu, H. P., S. C. Hsieh, C. C. King, and W. K. Wang. 2007. Characterization of retrovirus-based reporter viruses pseudotyped with the precursor membrane and envelope glycoproteins of four serotypes of dengue viruses. Virology 368376-387.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7126519</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17662331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, K. J., Y. C. Yang, Y. S. Lin, J. H. Huang, H. S. Liu, T. M. Yeh, S. H. Chen, C. C. Liu, and H. Y. Lei. 2006. The dual-specific binding of dengue virus and target cells for the antibody-dependent enhancement of dengue virus infection. J. Immunol. 1762825-2832.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16493039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Innis, B. L., V. Thirawuth, and C. Hemachudha. 1989. Identification of continuous epitopes of the envelope glycoprotein of dengue type 2 virus. Am. J. Trop. Med. Hyg. 40676-687.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2472749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kochel, T. J., D. M. Watts, S. B. Halstead, C. G. Hayes, A. Espinoza, V. Felices, R. Caceda, C. T. Bautista, Y. Montoya, S. Douglas, and K. L. Russell. 2002. Effect of dengue-1 antibodies on American dengue-2 viral infection and dengue haemorrhagic fever. Lancet 360310-312.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12147378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuno, G., A. V. Vorndam, D. J. Gubler, and I. Gomez. 1990. Study of anti-dengue NS1 antibody by Western blot. J. Med. Virol. 32102-108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2149144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai, C. Y., H. P. Hu, C. C. King, and W. K. Wang. 2008. Incorporation of dengue virus replicon into virus-like particles by a cell line stably expressing precursor membrane and envelope proteins of dengue virus type 2. J. Biomed. Sci. 1515-27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17768670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, C. F., S. C. Chiu, Y. L. Hsiao, S. W. Wen, H. Y. Lei, A. L. Shiau, H. S. Liu, T. M. Yeh, S. H. Chen, C. C. Liu, and Y. S. Lee. 2005. Expression of cytokine, chemokine, and adhesion molecules during endothelial cell activation induced by antibodies against dengue virus nonstructural protein 1. J. Immunol. 174395-403.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15611263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, C. F., H. Y. Lei, A. L. Shiau, H. S. Liu, T. M. Yeh, S. H. Chen, C. C. Liu, S. C. Chiu, and Y. S. Lee. 2002. Endothelial cell apoptosis induced by antibodies against dengue virus nonstructural protein 1 via production of nitric oxide. J. Immunol. 169657-664.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12097367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindenbach, B. D., and C. M. Rice. 2001. Flaviviridae: the viruses and their replication, p. 991-1041. In D. M. Knipe, P. M. Howley, and D. E. Griffin (ed.), Fields virology. Lippincott William &amp; Wilkins, Philadelphia, PA.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandl, C. W., F. Guirakhoo, H. Holzmann, F. X. Heinz, and C. Kunz. 1989. Antigenic structure of the flavivirus envelope protein E at the molecular level, using tick-borne encephalitis virus as a model. J. Virol. 63564-571.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC247724</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2463377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazumder, R., Z. Z. Hu, C. R. Vinayaka, J. L. Sagripanti, S. D. W. Frost, S. L. K. Pond, and C. H. Wu. 2007. Computational analysis and identification of amino acid sites in dengue E protein relevant to development of diagnostics and vaccines. Virus Genes 35175-186.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17508277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Modis, Y., S. Ogata, D. Clements, and S. C. Harrison. 2003. A ligand-binding pocket in the dengue virus envelope glycoprotein. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA 1006986-6991.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC165817</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12759475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Modis, Y., S. Ogata, D. Clements, and S. C. Harrison. 2004. Structure of the dengue virus envelope protein after membrane fusion. Nature 427313-319.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14737159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morens, D. M. 1994. Antibody-dependent enhancement of infection and the pathogenesis of viral disease. Clin. Infect. Dis. 19500-512.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7811870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morens, D. M., C. N. Venkateshan, and S. B. Halstead. 1987. Dengue 4 virus monoclonal antibodies identify epitopes that mediate immune infection enhancement of dengue 2 viruses. J. Gen. Virol. 6891-98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2433388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliphant, T., M. Engle, G. E. Nybakken, C. Doane, S. Johnson, L. Huang, S. Gorlatov, E. Mehlhop, A. Marri, K. M. Chung, G. D. Ebel, L. D. Kramer, D. H. Fremont, and M. S. Diamond. 2005. Development of a humanized monoclonal antibody with therapeutic potential against West Nile virus. Nat. Med. 11522-530.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1458527</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15852016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliphant, T., G. E. Nybakken, M. Engle, O. Xu, C. A. Nelson, S. Sukupolvi-Petty, A. Marri, B. E. Lachmi, U. Olshevsky, D. H. Fremont, T. C. Pierson, and M. Diamond. 2006. Antibody recognition and neutralization determinants on domains I and II of West Nile virus envelope protein. J. Virol. 8012149-12159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1676294</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17035317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qu, X., W. Chen, T. Maguire, and F. Austin. 1993. Immunoreactivity and protective effects in mice of a recombinant dengue 2 Tonga virus NS1 protein produced in baculovirus expression system. J. Gen. Virol. 7489-97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8423452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rey, F. A., F. X. Heinz, C. Mandl, C. Kunz, and S. C. Harrison. 1995. The envelope glycoprotein from tick-borne encephalitis virus at 2 &#xc5; resolution. Nature 375291-298.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7753193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roehrig, J. T., R. A. Bolin, and R. G. Kelly. 1998. Monoclonal antibody mapping of the envelope glycoprotein of the dengue 2 virus, Jamaica. Virology 246317-328.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9657950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roehrig, J. T., A. J. Johnson, A. R. Hunt, R. A. Bolin, and M. C. Chu. 1990. Antibodies to dengue 2 virus E-glycoprotein synthetic peptides identify antigenic conformation. Virology 177668-675.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2371772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roehrig, J. T., K. E. Volpe, J. Squires, A. R. Hunt, B. S. Davis, and G. J. J. Chang. 2004. Contribution of disulfide bridging to epitope expression of the dengue type 2 virus envelope glycoprotein. J. Virol. 782648-2652.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC369223</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14963174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabin, A. B. 1952. Research on dengue during World War II. Am. J. Trop. Med. Hyg. 130-50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14903434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanchez, M. D., T. C. Pierson, D. McAllister, S. L. Hanna, B. A. Puffer, L. E. Valentine, M. M. Murtadha, J. A. Hoxie, and R. W. Doms. 2005. Characterization of neutralizing antibodies to West Nile virus. Virology 33670-82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15866072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sangkawibha, N., S. Rojanasuphot, S. Ahandrik, S. Viriyapongse, S. Jatanasen, V. Salitul, B. Phanthumachinda, and S. B. Halstead. 1984. Risk factors in dengue shock syndrome: a prospective epidemiologic study in Rayong, Thailand. I. The 1980 outbreak. Am. J. Epidemiol. 120653-669.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6496446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schlesinger, J. J., M. W. Brandriss, and E. E. Walsh. 1987. Protection of mice against dengue 2 virus encephalitis by immunization with the dengue 2 virus non-structural glycoprotein NS1. J. Gen. Virol. 68853-857.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3819700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Se-Thoe, S. Y., M. M. Ng, and A. E. Ling. 1999. Retrospective study of Western blot profiles in immune sera of natural dengue virus infections. J. Med. Virol. 57322-330.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10022806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shu, P. Y., L. K. Chen, S. F. Chang, Y. Y. Yueh, L. Chow, L. J. Chien, C. Chin, T. H. Lin, and J. H. Huang. 2003. Comparison of capture immunoglobulin M (IgM) and IgG enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay (ELISA) and nonstructural protein NS1 serotype-specific IgG ELISA for differentiation of primary and secondary dengue virus infections. Clin. Diagn. Lab. Immunol. 10622-630.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC164246</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12853395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stiasny, K., S. Kiermayr, H. Holzmann, and F. X. Heinz. 2006. Cryptic properties of a cluster of dominant flavivirus cross-reactive antigenic sites. J. Virol. 809557-9568.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1617264</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16973559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sukupolvi-Petty, S., K. Austin, W. E. Purtha, T. Oliphant, G. E. Nybakken, J. J. Schlesinger, J. T. Roehrig, G. D. Gromowski, A. D. Barrett, D. H. Fremont, and M. Diamond. 2007. Type and subcomplex-specific neutralizing antibodies against domain III of dengue virus type 2 envelope protein recognize adjacent epitopes. J. Virol. 8112816-12826.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2169112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17881453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thali, M., C. Furman, D. D. Ho, J. Robinson, S. Tilley, A. Pinter, and J. Sodroski. 1992. Discontinuous, conserved neutralization epitopes overlapping the CD4-binding region of human immunodeficiency virus type 1 gp120 envelope glycoprotein. J. Virol. 665635-5641.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC289129</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1380099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Throsby, M., C. Geuijen, J. Goudsmit, A. Q. Bakker, J. Korimbocus, R. A. Kramer, M. C. der Horst, M. de Jong, M. Jongeneelen, S. Thijsse, R. Smit, T. J. Visser, N. Bijl, W. E. Marissen, M. Loeb, D. J. Kelvin, W. Preiser, J. ter Meulen, and J. der Kruif. 2006. Isolation and characterization of human monoclonal antibodies from individuals infected with West Nile virus. J. Virol. 806982-6992.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1489037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16809304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valdes, K., M. Alvarez, M. Pupo, S. Vazquez, R. Rodriguez, and M. G. Guzman. 2000. Human dengue antibodies against structural and nonstructural proteins. Clin. Diagn. Lab. Immunol. 7856-857.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC95972</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10973471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, W. K., H. L. Chen, C. F. Yang, S. C. Hsieh, C. C. Juan, S. M. Chang, C. C. Yu, L. H. Lin, J. H. Huang, and C. C. King. 2006. Slower rates of clearance of viral load and virus-containing immune complexes in patients with dengue hemorrhagic fever. Clin. Infect. Dis. 431023-1030.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16983615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. 1997. Dengue hemorrhagic fever, diagnosis, treatment and control, 2nd ed. World Health Organization, Geneva, Switzerland.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>