<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">21826249</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2011</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1932-6203</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>6</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2011</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PloS one</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PLoS One</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A novel single-dose dengue subunit vaccine induces memory immune responses.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e23319</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e23319</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e23319</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1371/journal.pone.0023319</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>To protect against dengue viral infection, a novel lipidated dengue subunit vaccine was rationally designed to contain the consensus amino acid sequences derived from four serotypes of dengue viruses. We found that the lipidated consensus dengue virus envelope protein domain III (LcED III) is capable of activating antigen-presenting cells and enhancing cellular and humoral immune responses. A single-dose of LcED III immunization in mice without extra adjuvant formulation is sufficient to elicit neutralizing antibodies against all four serotypes of dengue viruses. In addition, strong memory responses were elicited in mice immunized with a single-dose of LcED III. Quick, anamnestic neutralizing antibody responses to a live dengue virus challenge were elicited at week 28 post-immunization. These results demonstrate the promising possibility of a future successful tetravalent vaccine against dengue viral infections that utilizes one-dose vaccination with LcED III.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chiang</LastName><ForeName>Chen-Yi</ForeName><Initials>CY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vaccine Research and Development Center, National Health Research Institutes, Zhunan, Miaoli, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Shih-Jen</ForeName><Initials>SJ</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tsai</LastName><ForeName>Jy-Ping</ForeName><Initials>JP</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Yi-Shiuan</ForeName><Initials>YS</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Mei-Yu</ForeName><Initials>MY</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Hsueh-Hung</ForeName><Initials>HH</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chong</LastName><ForeName>Pele</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Leng</LastName><ForeName>Chih-Hsiang</ForeName><Initials>CH</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Hsin-Wei</ForeName><Initials>HW</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2011</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PLoS One</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101285081</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1932-6203</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D053059">Dengue Vaccines</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D049109" MajorTopicYN="N">Cell Proliferation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053059" MajorTopicYN="N">Dengue Vaccines</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="Y">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004797" MajorTopicYN="N">Enzyme-Linked Immunosorbent Assay</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005455" MajorTopicYN="N">Fluorescent Antibody Technique</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007156" MajorTopicYN="N">Immunologic Memory</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="Y">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020014" MajorTopicYN="N">K562 Cells</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008214" MajorTopicYN="N">Lymphocytes</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051379" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008807" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice, Inbred BALB C</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement><b>Competing Interests: </b>S-JL, PC, C-HL, and H-WC are named on patents relating to the preparation and use of dengue virus peptide vaccine and lipidated vaccine against dengue virus infection. This does not alter the authors' adherence to all the PLoS ONE policies on sharing data and materials. All other authors have no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2011</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2011</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2011</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2011</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2011</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21826249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3149651</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0023319</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PONE-D-11-01890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Chambers TJ, Hahn CS, Galler R, Rice CM. Flavivirus genome organization, expression, and replication. Annu Rev Microbiol. 1990;44:649&#x2013;688.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2174669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gubler DJ, Clark GG. Dengue/dengue hemorrhagic fever: the emergence of a global health problem. Emerg Infect Dis. 1995;1:55&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2626838</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8903160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halstead SB. Pathogenesis of dengue: challenges to molecular biology. Science. 1988;239:476&#x2013;481.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3277268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chambers TJ, Tsai TF, Pervikov Y, Monath TP. Vaccine development against dengue and Japanese encephalitis: report of a World Health Organization meeting. Vaccine. 1997;15:1494&#x2013;1502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9330458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitehead SS, Blaney JE, Durbin AP, Murphy BR. Prospects for a dengue virus vaccine. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2007;5:518&#x2013;528.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17558424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angsubhakorn S, Yoksan S, Pradermwong A, Nitatpattana N, Sahaphong S, et al. Dengue-3 (16562) PGMK 33 vaccine: neurovirulence, viremia and immune responses in Macaca fascicularis. Southeast Asian J Trop Med Public Health. 1994;25:554&#x2013;559.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7777925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edelman R, Tacket CO, Wasserman SS, Vaughn DW, Eckels KH, et al. A live attenuated dengue-1 vaccine candidate (45AZ5) passaged in primary dog kidney cell culture is attenuated and immunogenic for humans. J Infect Dis. 1994;170:1448&#x2013;1455.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7995984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoke CH, Jr, Malinoski FJ, Eckels KH, Scott RM, Dubois DR, et al. Preparation of an attenuated dengue 4 (341750 Carib) virus vaccine. II. Safety and immunogenicity in humans. Am J Trop Med Hyg. 1990;43:219&#x2013;226.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2389825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaughn DW, Hoke CH, Jr, Yoksan S, LaChance R, Innis BL, et al. Testing of a dengue 2 live-attenuated vaccine (strain 16681 PDK 53) in ten American volunteers. Vaccine. 1996;14:329&#x2013;336.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8744561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Putnak JR, Coller BA, Voss G, Vaughn DW, Clements D, et al. An evaluation of dengue type-2 inactivated, recombinant subunit, and live-attenuated vaccine candidates in the rhesus macaque model. Vaccine. 2005;23:4442&#x2013;4452.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16005749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Putnak R, Cassidy K, Conforti N, Lee R, Sollazzo D, et al. Immunogenic and protective response in mice immunized with a purified, inactivated, Dengue-2 virus vaccine prototype made in fetal rhesus lung cells. Am J Trop Med Hyg. 1996;55:504&#x2013;510.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8940981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bray M, Men R, Lai CJ. Monkeys immunized with intertypic chimeric dengue viruses are protected against wild-type virus challenge. J Virol. 1996;70:4162&#x2013;4166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC190310</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8648761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kinney RM, Butrapet S, Chang GJ, Tsuchiya KR, Roehrig JT, et al. Construction of infectious cDNA clones for dengue 2 virus: strain 16681 and its attenuated vaccine derivative, strain PDK-53. Virology. 1997;230:300&#x2013;308.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9143286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Men R, Bray M, Clark D, Chanock RM, Lai CJ. Dengue type 4 virus mutants containing deletions in the 3&#x2032; noncoding region of the RNA genome: analysis of growth restriction in cell culture and altered viremia pattern and immunogenicity in rhesus monkeys. J Virol. 1996;70:3930&#x2013;3937.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC190271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8648730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blaney JE, Jr, Sathe NS, Goddard L, Hanson CT, Romero TA, et al. Dengue virus type 3 vaccine candidates generated by introduction of deletions in the 3&#x2032; untranslated region (3&#x2032;-UTR) or by exchange of the DENV-3 3&#x2032;-UTR with that of DENV-4. Vaccine. 2008;26:817&#x2013;828.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2246307</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18191005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brandler S, Ruffie C, Najburg V, Frenkiel MP, Bedouelle H, et al. Pediatric measles vaccine expressing a dengue tetravalent antigen elicits neutralizing antibodies against all four dengue viruses. Vaccine. 2010;28:6730&#x2013;6739.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20688034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khanam S, Khanna N, Swaminathan S. Induction of neutralizing antibodies and T cell responses by dengue virus type 2 envelope domain III encoded by plasmid and adenoviral vectors. Vaccine. 2006;24:6513&#x2013;6525.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16860446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khanam S, Pilankatta R, Khanna N, Swaminathan S. An adenovirus type 5 (AdV5) vector encoding an envelope domain III-based tetravalent antigen elicits immune responses against all four dengue viruses in the presence of prior AdV5 immunity. Vaccine. 2009;27:6011&#x2013;6021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19665609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konishi E, Kosugi S, Imoto J. Dengue tetravalent DNA vaccine inducing neutralizing antibody and anamnestic responses to four serotypes in mice. Vaccine. 2006;24:2200&#x2013;2207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16316713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raviprakash K, Ewing D, Simmons M, Porter KR, Jones TR, et al. Needle-free Biojector injection of a dengue virus type 1 DNA vaccine with human immunostimulatory sequences and the GM-CSF gene increases immunogenicity and protection from virus challenge in Aotus monkeys. Virology. 2003;315:345&#x2013;352.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14585337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mota J, Acosta M, Argotte R, Figueroa R, Mendez A, et al. Induction of protective antibodies against dengue virus by tetravalent DNA immunization of mice with domain III of the envelope protein. Vaccine. 2005;23:3469&#x2013;3476.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15837370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babu JP, Pattnaik P, Gupta N, Shrivastava A, Khan M, et al. Immunogenicity of a recombinant envelope domain III protein of dengue virus type-4 with various adjuvants in mice. Vaccine. 2008;26:4655&#x2013;4663.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18640168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clements DE, Coller BA, Lieberman MM, Ogata S, Wang G, et al. Development of a recombinant tetravalent dengue virus vaccine: immunogenicity and efficacy studies in mice and monkeys. Vaccine. 2010;28:2705&#x2013;2715.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2837772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20097152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lazo L, Hermida L, Zulueta A, Sanchez J, Lopez C, et al. A recombinant capsid protein from Dengue-2 induces protection in mice against homologous virus. Vaccine. 2007;25:1064&#x2013;1070.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17097199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leng CH, Liu SJ, Tsai JP, Li YS, Chen MY, et al. A novel dengue vaccine candidate that induces cross-neutralizing antibodies and memory immunity. Microbes Infect. 2009;11:288&#x2013;295.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19114121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valdes I, Hermida L, Martin J, Menendez T, Gil L, et al. Immunological evaluation in nonhuman primates of formulations based on the chimeric protein P64k-domain III of dengue 2 and two components of Neisseria meningitidis. Vaccine. 2009;27:995&#x2013;1001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19100804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernardo L, Hermida L, Martin J, Alvarez M, Prado I, et al. Anamnestic antibody response after viral challenge in monkeys immunized with dengue 2 recombinant fusion proteins. Arch Virol. 2008;153:849&#x2013;854.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18299795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hermida L, Bernardo L, Martin J, Alvarez M, Prado I, et al. A recombinant fusion protein containing the domain III of the dengue-2 envelope protein is immunogenic and protective in nonhuman primates. Vaccine. 2006;24:3165&#x2013;3171.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16490289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Block OK, Rodrigo WW, Quinn M, Jin X, Rose RC, et al. A tetravalent recombinant dengue domain III protein vaccine stimulates neutralizing and enhancing antibodies in mice. Vaccine. 2010;28:8085&#x2013;8094.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20959154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Modis Y, Ogata S, Clements D, Harrison SC. A ligand-binding pocket in the dengue virus envelope glycoprotein. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2003;100:6986&#x2013;6991.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC165817</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12759475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Modis Y, Ogata S, Clements D, Harrison SC. Variable Surface Epitopes in the Crystal Structure of Dengue Virus Type 3 Envelope Glycoprotein. J Virol. 2005;79:1223&#x2013;1231.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC538574</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15613349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nayak V, Dessau M, Kucera K, Anthony K, Ledizet M, et al. Crystal structure of dengue virus type 1 envelope protein in the postfusion conformation and its implications for membrane fusion. J Virol. 2009;83:4338&#x2013;4344.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2668458</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19244332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y, Maguire T, Hileman RE, Fromm JR, Esko JD, et al. Dengue virus infectivity depends on envelope protein binding to target cell heparan sulfate. Nat Med. 1997;3:866&#x2013;871.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9256277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hung J-J, Hsieh M-T, Young M-J, Kao C-L, King C-C, et al. An External Loop Region of Domain III of Dengue Virus Type 2 Envelope Protein Is Involved in Serotype-Specific Binding to Mosquito but Not Mammalian Cells. J Virol. 2004;78:378&#x2013;388.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC303388</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14671119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crill WD, Roehrig JT. Monoclonal Antibodies That Bind to Domain III of Dengue Virus E Glycoprotein Are the Most Efficient Blockers of Virus Adsorption to Vero Cells. J Virol. 2001;75:7769&#x2013;7773.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC115016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11462053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hiramatsu K, Tadano M, Men R, Lai C-J. Mutational Analysis of a Neutralization Epitope on the Dengue Type 2 Virus (DEN2) Envelope Protein: Monoclonal Antibody Resistant DEN2/DEN4 Chimeras Exhibit Reduced Mouse Neurovirulence. Virology. 1996;224:437&#x2013;445.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8874504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roehrig JT, Bolin RA, Kelly RG. Monoclonal Antibody Mapping of the Envelope Glycoprotein of the Dengue 2 Virus, Jamaica. Virology. 1998;246:317&#x2013;328.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9657950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roehrig JT, Risi PA, Brubaker JR, Hunt AR, Beaty BJ, et al. T-Helper Cell Epitopes on the E-Glycoprotein of Dengue 2 Jamaica Virus. Virology. 1994;198:31&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7505071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thullier P, Demangel C, Bedouelle H, Megret F, Jouan A, et al. Mapping of a dengue virus neutralizing epitope critical for the infectivity of all serotypes: insight into the neutralization mechanism. J Gen Virol. 2001;82:1885&#x2013;1892.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11457994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trirawatanapong T, Chandran B, Putnak R, Padmanabhan R. Mapping of a region of dengue virus type-2 glycoprotein required for binding by a neutralizing monoclonal antibody. Gene. 1992;116:139&#x2013;150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7125935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1634111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen HW, Liu SJ, Liu HH, Kwok Y, Lin CL, et al. A novel technology for the production of a heterologous lipoprotein immunogen in high yield has implications for the field of vaccine design. Vaccine. 2009;27:1400&#x2013;1409.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19150476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leng CH, Chen HW, Chang LS, Liu HH, Liu HY, et al. A recombinant lipoprotein containing an unsaturated fatty acid activates NF-kappaB through the TLR2 signaling pathway and induces a differential gene profile from a synthetic lipopeptide. Mol Immunol. 2010;47:2015&#x2013;2021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20478617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimizu T, Kida Y, Kuwano K. A triacylated lipoprotein from Mycoplasma genitalium activates NF-kappaB through Toll-like receptor 1 (TLR1) and TLR2. Infect Immun. 2008;76:3672&#x2013;3678.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2493199</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18474641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tawaratsumida K, Furuyashiki M, Katsumoto M, Fujimoto Y, Fukase K, et al. Characterization of N-terminal structure of TLR2-activating lipoprotein in Staphylococcus aureus. J Biol Chem. 2009;284:9147&#x2013;9152.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2666565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19218237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thakran S, Li H, Lavine CL, Miller MA, Bina JE, et al. Identification of Francisella tularensis lipoproteins that stimulate the toll-like receptor (TLR) 2/TLR1 heterodimer. J Biol Chem. 2008;283:3751&#x2013;3760.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18079113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guzman MG, Hermida L, Bernardo L, Ramirez R, Guillen G. Domain III of the envelope protein as a dengue vaccine target. Expert Rev Vaccines. 2010;9:137&#x2013;147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20109025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>