<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">21845159</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2011</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1660-4601</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>8</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2011</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of environmental research and public health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Environ Res Public Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Using geographically weighted regression (GWR) to explore spatial varying relationships of immature mosquitoes and human densities with the incidence of dengue.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2798</StartPage><EndPage>2815</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2798-815</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/ijerph8072798</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The only way for dengue to spread in the human population is through the human-mosquito-human cycle. Most research in this field discusses the dengue-mosquito or dengue-human relationships over a particular study area, but few have explored the local spatial variations of dengue-mosquito and dengue-human relationships within a study area. This study examined whether spatial heterogeneity exists in these relationships. We used Ordinary Least Squares (OLS) and Geographically Weighted Regression (GWR) models to analyze spatial relationships and identify the geographical heterogeneities by using the information of entomology and dengue cases in the cities of Kaohsiung and Fengshan in 2002. Our findings indicate that dengue-mosquito and dengue-human relationships were significantly spatially non-stationary. This means that in some areas higher dengue incidences were associated with higher vector/host densities, but in some areas higher incidences were related to lower vector/host densities. We demonstrated that a GWR model can be used to geographically differentiate the relationships of dengue incidence with immature mosquito and human densities. This study provides more insights into spatial targeting of intervention and control programs against dengue outbreaks within the study areas.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lin</LastName><ForeName>Chia-Hsien</ForeName><Initials>CH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Geography, College of Science, National Taiwan University, Taipei 106, Taiwan. chlin1983@gmail.com</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wen</LastName><ForeName>Tzai-Hung</ForeName><Initials>TH</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2011</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Environ Res Public Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101238455</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1660-4601</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000330" MajorTopicYN="N">Aedes</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000254" MajorTopicYN="N">growth &amp; development</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="N">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003715" MajorTopicYN="N">Dengue</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="Y">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="N">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003716" MajorTopicYN="Y">Dengue Virus</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017753" MajorTopicYN="N">Ecosystem</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004777" MajorTopicYN="N">Environment</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015994" MajorTopicYN="N">Incidence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007303" MajorTopicYN="N">Insect Vectors</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="N">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007814" MajorTopicYN="N">Larva</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="N">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016018" MajorTopicYN="N">Least-Squares Analysis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008954" MajorTopicYN="N">Models, Biological</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011157" MajorTopicYN="Y">Population Dynamics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012044" MajorTopicYN="N">Regression Analysis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013624" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Taiwan</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Aedes mosquitoes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dengue</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">geographically weighted regression (GWR)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">human density</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">spatial heterogeneity</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2011</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2011</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2011</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2011</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2011</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2011</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21845159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3155330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph8072798</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ijerph8072798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization (WHO) Dengue: Guidelines for Diagnosis, Treatment, Prevention and Control-New Edition. WHO; Geneva, Switzerland: 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akagi K, Kojima D. Experimental studies for the pathogen of dengue fever. J Formosan Med Assoc. 1915;158:1049&#x2013;1078. (in Japanese)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taiwan Centers For Disease Control (CDC) Guidelines for Dengue Control. CDC; Taipei city Taiwan: 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gubler DJ. Dengue and dengue hemorrhagic fever. Clin. Microbiol. Rev. 1998;11:480&#x2013;496.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC88892</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9665979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guzman A, Ist&#xfa;riz RE. Update on the global spread of dengue. Int. J. Antimicrob. Agents. 2010;36:S40&#x2013;S42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20833000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu PC, Lay JG, Guo HR, Lin CY, Lung SC, Su HJ. Higher temperature and urbanization affect the spatial patterns of dengue fever transmission in subtropical Taiwan. Sci. Total Environ. 2009;407:2224&#x2013;2233.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19157509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu PC, Guo HR, Lung SC, Lin CY, Su HJ. Weather as an effective predictor for occurrence of dengue fever in Taiwan. Acta Trop. 2007;103:50&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17612499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Focks DA. A Review of Entomological Sampling Methods and Indicators for Dengue Vectors. World Health Organization; Geneva, Switzerland: 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sulaiman S, Pawanchee ZA, Arifin Z, Wahab A. Relationship between Breteau and house indices and cases of dengue/dengue hemorrhagic fever in Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia. J. Am. Mosq. Control Assoc. 1996;12:494&#x2013;496.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8887232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teixeira MG, Barreto ML, Costa MC, Ferreira LD, Vasconcelos PF, Cairncross S. Dynamics of dengue virus circulation: a silent epidemic in a complex urban area. Trop. Med. Int. Health. 2002;7:757&#x2013;762.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12225506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chadee DD, Shivnauth B, Rawlins SC, Chen AA. Climate, mosquito indices and the epidemiology of dengue fever in Trinidad (2002&#x2013;2004) Ann. Trop. Med. Parasitol. 2007;101:69&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17244411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanchez L, Cortinas J, Pelaez O, Gutierrez H, Concepcion D, van der Stuyft P. Breteau Index threshold levels indicating risk for dengue transmission in areas with low Aedes infestation. Trop. Med. Int. Health. 2010;15:173&#x2013;175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20409286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thammapalo S, Chongsuvivatwong V, Geater A, Dueravee M. Environmental factors and incidence of dengue fever and dengue haemorrhagic fever in an urban area, Southern Thailand. Epidemiol. Infect. 2008;136:135&#x2013;143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2870760</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17359563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chadee DD, Williams FLR, Kitron UD. Impact of vector control on a dengue fever outbreak in Trinidad, West Indies, in 1998. Trop. Med. Int. Health. 2005;10:748&#x2013;754.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16045461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siqueira JB, Martelli CMT, Maciel IJ, Oliveira RM, Ribeiro MG, Amorim FP, Moreira BC, Cardoso DDP, Souza WV, Andrade AL. Household survey of dengue infection in Central Brazil: Spatial point pattern analysis and risk factors assessment. Am. J. Trop. Med. Hyg. 2004;71:646&#x2013;651.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15569799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ko YC. Epidemiology of dengue fever in Taiwan. Kaohsiung J. Med. Sci. 1989;5:1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2659810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morrison AC, Getis A, Santiago M, Rigau-Perez JG, Reiter P. Exploratory space-time analysis of reported dengue cases during an outbreak in Florida, Puerto Rico, 1991&#x2013;1992. Am. J. Trop. Med. Hyg. 1998;58:287&#x2013;298.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9546405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carbajo AE, Schweigmann N, Curto SI, De Garin A, Bejaran R. Dengue transmission risk maps of Argentina. Trop. Med. Int. Health. 2001;6:170&#x2013;183.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11299033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kolivras KN. Mosquito habitat and dengue risk potential in Hawaii: A conceptual framework and GIS application. Prof. Geographer. 2006;58:139&#x2013;154.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mammen MP, Pimgate C, Koenraadt CJ, Rothman AL, Aldstadt J, Nisalak A, Jarman RG, Jones JW, Srikiatkhachorn A, Ypil-Butac CA, et al. Spatial and temporal clustering of dengue virus transmission in Thai villages. PLos Med. 2008;5:e205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2577695</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18986209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menard S. Applied Logistic Regression Analysis. 2nd ed. Sage; Newbury Park, CA, USA: 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong DWS, Lee J. Statistical Analysis of Geographic Information with ArcView GIS And ArcGIS. John Wiley and Sons; Hoboken, NJ, USA: 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moran PAP. Notes on Continuous Stochastic Phenomena. Biometrika. 1950;37:17&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15420245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fotheringham AS, Brunsdon C, Charlton M. Geographically Weighted Regression: The Analysis of Spatially Varying Relationships. Wiley; New York, NY, USA: 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fotheringham AS, Brunsdon C, Charlton M. Quantitative Geography: Perspectives on Spatial Data Analysis. Sage; Newbury Park, CA, USA: 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wen TH, Lin NH, Chao DY, Hwang KP, Kan CC, Lin KCM, Wu JTS, Huang SYJ, Fan IC, King CC. Spatial-temporal patterns of dengue in areas at risk of dengue hemorrhagic fever in Kaohsiung, Taiwan, 2002. Int. J. Infect. Dis. 2010;14:e334&#x2013;e343.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19716331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harrington LC, Scott TW, Lerdthusnee KRIA, Coleman RC, Costero ADRI, Clark GG, Jones JJ, Kitthawee SANG, Kittayapong PATT, Sithiprasasna RATA, et al. Dispersal of the dengue vector Aedes aegypti within and between rural communities. Am. J. Trop. Med. Hyg. 2005;72:209&#x2013;220.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15741559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Favier C, Schmit D, M&#xfc;ller-Graf CDM, Cazelles B, Degallier N, Mondet B, Dubois MA. Influence of spatial heterogeneity on an emerging infectious disease: the case of dengue epidemics. Proc. R. Soc B. 2005;272:1171&#x2013;1177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1559809</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16024379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vanwambeke SO, van Benthem BH, Khantikul N, Burghoorn-Maas C, Panart K, Oskam L, Lambin E, Somboon P. Multi-level analyses of spatial and temporal determinants for dengue infection. Int. J. Health Geogr. 2006;5:5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1373612</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16420702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koh BK, Ng LC, Kita Y, Tang CS, Li Ang LW, Wong KY, James L, Goh KT. The 2005 Dengue epidemic in Singapore-epidemiology, prevention and control. Ann. Acad. Med. Singapore. 2008;37:538&#x2013;545.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18695764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almeida MCD, Caiaffa WT, Assuncao RM, Proietti FA. Spatial vulnerability to dengue in a Brazilian urban area during a 7-year surveillance. J. Urban Health. 2007;84:334&#x2013;345.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2231833</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17243024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thai KTD, Nagelkerke N, Phuong HL, Nga TTT, Giao PT, Hung LQ, Binh TQ, Nam NV, de Vries PJ. Geographical heterogeneity of dengue transmission in two villages in southern Vietnam. Epidemiol. Infect. 2010;138:585&#x2013;591.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19653925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith DL, Dushoff J, McKenzie FE. The risk of a mosquito-borne infection in a heterogeneous environment. Plos Biol. 2004;2:1957&#x2013;1964.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cummings DAT, Irizarry RA, Huang NE, Endy TP, Nisalak A, Ungchusak K, Burke DS. Travelling waves in the occurrence of dengue haemorrhagic fever in Thailand. Nature. 2004;427:344&#x2013;347.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14737166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shang CS, Fang CT, Liu CM, Wen TH, Tsai KH, King CC. The role of imported cases and favorable meteorological conditions in the onset of dengue epidemics. PLoS Neglected Trop. Dis. 2010;4:e775.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2914757</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20689820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pai HH, Lu YL, Hong YJ, Hsu EL. The differences of dengue vectors and human behavior between families with and without members having dengue fever/dengue hemorrhagic fever. Int. J. Environ. Health Res. 2005;15:263&#x2013;269.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16175742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bohra A, Andrianasolo H. Application of GIS in modeling of dengue risk based on sociocultural data: Case of Jalore, Rajasthan, India. Dengue Bull. 2001;25:92&#x2013;102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chowell G, Torre CA, Munayco-Escate C, Suarez-Ognio L, Lopez-Cruz R, Hyman JM, Castillo-Chavez C. Spatial and temporal dynamics of dengue fever in Peru: 1994&#x2013;2006. Epidemiol. Infect. 2008;136:1667&#x2013;1677.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2870787</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18394264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reiter P, Lathrop S, Bunning M, Biggerstaff B, Singer D, Tiwari T, Baber L, Amador M, Thirion J, Hayes J, et al. Texas lifestyle limits transmission of dengue virus. Emerging Infect. Dis. 2003;9:86&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2873752</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12533286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Connor ME, Monroe WM. Stegomyia Indices and Their Value in Yellow Fever Control. Am J Trop Med Hyg. 1923:S1&#x2013;3. 9&#x2013;19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sauthowo TR, Tonn RJ, Yasuno M, Reader PM, Murdie G. Studies on Life Budget of Aedes aegypti in Wat Samphaya, Bangkok, Thailand. Bull. W. H. O. 1972;46:211&#x2013;226.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2480713</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4537483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Focks DA, Brenner RJ, Hayes J, Daniels E. Transmission thresholds for dengue in terms of Aedes aegypti pupae per person with discussion of their utility in source reduction efforts. Am. J. Trop. Med. Hyg. 2000;62:11&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10761719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halstead SB. Etiologies of the Experimental Dengues of Siler and Simmons. Am. J. Trop. Med. Hyg. 1974;23:974&#x2013;982.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4615598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isik O, Pinarcioglu MM. Geographies of a silent transition: A geographically weighted regression approach to regional fertility differences in Turkey. Eur. J. Popul. 2006;22:399&#x2013;421.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mennis J. Mapping the results of geographically weighted regression. Cartogr. J. 2006;43:171&#x2013;179.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wen TH, Chen DR, Tsai MJ. Identifying geographical variations in poverty-obesity relationships: empirical evidence from Taiwan. Geospat. Health. 2010;4:257&#x2013;265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20503193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wheeler D, Tiefelsdorf M. Multicollinearity and correlation among local regression coefficients in geographically weighted regression. J. Geogr. Syst. 2005;7:161&#x2013;187.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiu X, Wu SS. Global and Local Regression Analysis of Factors of American College Test (ACT) Score for Public High Schools in the State of Missouri. Ann. Assoc. Am. Geogr. 2011;101:63&#x2013;83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waller LA, Zhu L, Gotway CA, Gorman DM, Gruenewald PJ. Quantifying geographic variations in associations between alcohol distribution and violence: A comparison of geographically weighted regression and spatially varying coefficient models. Stoch. Environ. Res. Risk Assess. 2007;21:573&#x2013;588.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>