<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">27347055</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1792-0981</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>12</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2016</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Experimental and therapeutic medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Exp Ther Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Inflammatory molecules expression pattern for identifying pathogen species in febrile patient serum.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>312</StartPage><EndPage>318</EndPage><MedlinePgn>312-318</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>Inflammatory molecules, such as cytokines and chemokines, have been considered markers for bacterial or viral infection in serum of patients in numerous studies. The aim of the present study was to investigate whether we were able to identify the pathogen species through patterns of inflammatory molecules. A total of 132 patients with elevated body temperature (tympanic temperature, &gt;38.3&#xb0;C) were recruited for this study. The concentrations of various inflammatory molecules in the patients' serum were evaluated using a cytometric bead array. Higher concentrations of interleukin (IL)-6 and IL-8 were detected in bacterial infection groups (patients with positive and negative blood cultures), as compared with the viral infection group. Viral infection (including influenza and dengue viral infections) was associated with higher concentrations of interferon-&#x3b3;-inducible protein 10 (IP-10), as compared with the bacterial infection group. In addition, IL-8 levels in the gram-negative bacteria group were higher, as compared with the gram-positive bacteria group. However, IL-8 was insufficient for bacterial species identification. By contrast, dengue virus infection induced the highest serum level of IP-10 among all groups. In conclusion, detection of the patterns of inflammatory molecules may aid the subsequent management and treatment modalities in hospitals, although evaluation of these molecules alone may be insufficient for identifying the pathogen species.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Kuan-Ting</ForeName><Initials>KT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate Institute of Clinical Medicine, College of Medicine, Kaohsiung Medical University, Kaohsiung 807, Taiwan, R.O.C.; School of Medicine, College of Medicine, Kaohsiung Medical University, Kaohsiung 807, Taiwan, R.O.C.; Department of Emergency Medicine, Kaohsiung Medical University Hospital, Kaohsiung 807, Taiwan, R.O.C.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Yao-Hua</ForeName><Initials>YH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Emergency Medicine, Kaohsiung Medical University Hospital, Kaohsiung 807, Taiwan, R.O.C.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lin</LastName><ForeName>Chun-Yu</ForeName><Initials>CY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, College of Medicine, Kaohsiung Medical University, Kaohsiung 807, Taiwan, R.O.C.; Division of Infectious Diseases, Kaohsiung Medical University Hospital, Kaohsiung 807, Taiwan, R.O.C.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kuo</LastName><ForeName>Po-Lin</ForeName><Initials>PL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate Institute of Clinical Medicine, College of Medicine, Kaohsiung Medical University, Kaohsiung 807, Taiwan, R.O.C.; Institute of Medical Science and Technology, National Sun Yat-Sen University, Kaohsiung 804, Taiwan, R.O.C.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yen</LastName><ForeName>Meng-Chi</ForeName><Initials>MC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Emergency Medicine, Kaohsiung Medical University Hospital, Kaohsiung 807, Taiwan, R.O.C.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2016</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Greece</Country><MedlineTA>Exp Ther Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101531947</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1792-0981</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bacterial infection</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chemokine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cytokine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sepsis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">serum</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">viral infection</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2015</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2016</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2016</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2016</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2016</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27347055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4907082</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3892/etm.2016.3323</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ETM-0-0-3323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez Lopez A, Luaces Cubells C, Garc&#xed;a Garc&#xed;a JJ, Fern&#xe1;ndez Pou J. Spanish Society of Pediatric Emergencies: Procalcitonin in pediatric emergency departments for the early diagnosis of invasive bacterial infections in febrile infants: Results of a multicenter study and utility of a rapid qualitative test for this marker. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2003;22:895&#x2013;903. doi: 10.1097/01.inf.0000091360.11784.21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/01.inf.0000091360.11784.21</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14551491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fitch MT, van de Beek D. Emergency diagnosis and treatment of adult meningitis. Lancet Infect Dis. 2007;7:191&#x2013;200. doi: 10.1016/S1473-3099(07)70050-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1473-3099(07)70050-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17317600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andreola B, Bressan S, Callegaro S, Liverani A, Plebani M, Da Dalt L. Procalcitonin and C-reactive protein as diagnostic markers of severe bacterial infections in febrile infants and children in the emergency department. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2007;26:672&#x2013;677. doi: 10.1097/INF.0b013e31806215e3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/INF.0b013e31806215e3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17848876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hatherill M, Tibby SM, Sykes K, Turner C, Murdoch IA. Diagnostic markers of infection: Comparison of procalcitonin with C reactive protein and leucocyte count. Arch Dis Child. 1999;81:417&#x2013;421. doi: 10.1136/adc.81.5.417.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/adc.81.5.417</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1718133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10519716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Poll T, de Waal Malefyt R, Coyle SM, Lowry SF. Antiinflammatory cytokine responses during clinical sepsis and experimental endotoxemia: Sequential measurements of plasma soluble interleukin (IL)-1 receptor type II, IL-10, and IL-13. J Infect Dis. 1997;175:118&#x2013;122. doi: 10.1093/infdis/175.1.118.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/infdis/175.1.118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8985204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damas P, Reuter A, Gysen P, Demonty J, Lamy M, Franchimont P. Tumor necrosis factor and interleukin-1 serum levels during severe sepsis in humans. Crit Care Med. 1989;17:975&#x2013;978. doi: 10.1097/00003246-198910000-00001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00003246-198910000-00001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2791581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damas P, Ledoux D, Nys M, Vrindts Y, De Groote D, Franchimont P, Lamy M. Cytokine serum level during severe sepsis in human Il-6 as a marker of severity. Ann Surg. 1992;215:356&#x2013;362. doi: 10.1097/00000658-199204000-00009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00000658-199204000-00009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1242452</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1558416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grobmyer SR, Lin E, Lowry SF, Rivadeneira DE, Potter S, Barie PS, Nathan CF. Elevation of IL-18 in human sepsis. J Clin Immunol. 2000;20:212&#x2013;215. doi: 10.1023/A:1006641630904.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1023/A:1006641630904</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10941829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel RT, Deen KI, Youngs D, Warwick J, Keighley MR. Interleukin-6 is a prognostic indicator of outcome in severe intra-abdominal sepsis. Br J Surg. 1994;81:1306&#x2013;1308. doi: 10.1002/bjs.1800810914.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/bjs.1800810914</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7953393</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casey LC, Balk RA, Bone RC. Plasma cytokine and endotoxin levels correlate with survival in patients with the sepsis syndrome. Ann Intern Med. 1993;119:771&#x2013;778. doi: 10.7326/0003-4819-119-8-199310150-00001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7326/0003-4819-119-8-199310150-00001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8379598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurt AN, Aygun AD, Godekmerdan A, Kurt A, Dogan Y, Yilmaz E. Serum IL-1beta, IL-6, IL-8, and TNF-alpha levels in early diagnosis and management of neonatal sepsis. Mediators Inflamm. 2007;2007:31397. doi: 10.1155/2007/31397.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2007/31397</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2220039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18274637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ng PC, Li K, Chui KM, Leung TF, Wong RP, Chu WC, Wong E, Fok TF. IP-10 is an early diagnostic marker for identification of late-onset bacterial infection in preterm infants. Pediatr Res. 2007;61:93&#x2013;98. doi: 10.1203/01.pdr.0000250207.95723.96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1203/01.pdr.0000250207.95723.96</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17211148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ng PC, Li K, Leung TF, Wong RP, Li G, Chui KM, Wong E, Cheng FW, Fok TF. Early prediction of sepsis-induced disseminated intravascular coagulation with interleukin-10, interleukin-6, and RANTES in preterm infants. Clin Chem. 2006;52:1181&#x2013;1189. doi: 10.1373/clinchem.2005.062075.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1373/clinchem.2005.062075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16613997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akira S, Uematsu S, Takeuchi O. Pathogen recognition and innate immunity. Cell. 2006;124:783&#x2013;801. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2006.02.015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cell.2006.02.015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16497588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Shea JJ, Murray PJ. Cytokine signaling modules in inflammatory responses. Immunity. 2008;28:477&#x2013;487. doi: 10.1016/j.immuni.2008.03.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.immuni.2008.03.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2782488</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18400190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar A, Roberts D, Wood KE, Light B, Parrillo JE, Sharma S, Suppes R, Feinstein D, Zanotti S, Taiberg L, et al. Duration of hypotension before initiation of effective antimicrobial therapy is the critical determinant of survival in human septic shock. Crit Care Med. 2006;34:1589&#x2013;1596. doi: 10.1097/01.CCM.0000217961.75225.E9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/01.CCM.0000217961.75225.E9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16625125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin CM, Priestap F, Fisher H, Fowler RA, Heyland DK, Keenan SP, Longo CJ, Morrison T, Bentley D, Antman N. STAR Registry Investigators: A prospective, observational registry of patients with severe sepsis: The Canadian sepsis treatment and response registry. Crit Care Med. 2009;37:81&#x2013;88. doi: 10.1097/CCM.0b013e31819285f0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/CCM.0b013e31819285f0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19050636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brun-Buisson C, Meshaka P, Pinton P, Vallet B. EPISEPSIS Study Group: EPISEPSIS: A reappraisal of the epidemiology and outcome of severe sepsis in French intensive care units. Intensive Care Med. 2004;30:580&#x2013;588. doi: 10.1007/s00134-003-2121-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00134-003-2121-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14997295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin GS, Mannino DM, Eaton S, Moss M. The epidemiology of sepsis in the United States from 1979 through 2000. N Engl J Med. 2003;348:1546&#x2013;1554. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa022139.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa022139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12700374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vincent JL, Sakr Y, Sprung CL, Ranieri VM, Reinhart K, Gerlach H, Moreno R, Carlet J, Le Gall JR, Payen D. Sepsis Occurrence in Acutely Ill Patients Investigators: Sepsis in European intensive care units: Results of the SOAP study. Crit Care Med. 2006;34:344&#x2013;353. doi: 10.1097/01.CCM.0000194725.48928.3A.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/01.CCM.0000194725.48928.3A</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16424713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hottz ED, Medeiros-de-Moraes IM, Vieira-de-Abreu A, de Assis EF, Vals-de-Souza R, Castro-Faria-Neto HC, Weyrich AS, Zimmerman GA, Bozza FA, Bozza PT. Platelet activation and apoptosis modulate monocyte inflammatory responses in dengue. J Immunol. 2014;193:1864&#x2013;1872. doi: 10.4049/jimmunol.1400091.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4049/jimmunol.1400091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4137323</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25015827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Cromphaut SJ, Vanhorebeek I, Van den Berghe G. Glucose metabolism and insulin resistance in sepsis. Curr Pharm Des. 2008;14:1887&#x2013;1899. doi: 10.2174/138161208784980563.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/138161208784980563</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18691100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yegenaga I, Hoste E, Van Biesen W, Vanholder R, Benoit D, Kantarci G, Dhondt A, Colardyn F, Lameire N. Clinical characteristics of patients developing ARF due to sepsis/systemic inflammatory response syndrome: Results of a prospective study. Am J Kidney Dis. 2004;43:817&#x2013;824. doi: 10.1053/j.ajkd.2003.12.045.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/j.ajkd.2003.12.045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15112172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Livaditi O, Kotanidou A, Psarra A, Dimopoulou I, Sotiropoulou C, Augustatou K, Papasteriades C, Armaganidis A, Roussos C, Orfanos SE, Douzinas EE. Neutrophil CD64 expression and serum IL-8: sensitive early markers of severity and outcome in sepsis. Cytokine. 2006;36:283&#x2013;290. doi: 10.1016/j.cyto.2007.02.007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cyto.2007.02.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17368039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wunder C, Eichelbr&#xf6;nner O, Roewer N. Are IL-6, IL-10 and PCT plasma concentrations reliable for outcome prediction in severe sepsis? A comparison with APACHE III and SAPS II. Inflamm Res. 2004;53:158&#x2013;163. doi: 10.1007/s00011-003-1239-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00011-003-1239-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15060722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrade SS, Bispo PJ, Gales AC. Advances in the microbiological diagnosis of sepsis. Shock. 2008;30(Suppl 1):S41&#x2013;S46. doi: 10.1097/SHK.0b013e3181819f6c.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/SHK.0b013e3181819f6c</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18704010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tissari P, Zumla A, Tarkka E, Mero S, Savolainen L, Vaara M, Aittakorpi A, Laakso S, Lindfors M, Piiparinen H, et al. Accurate and rapid identification of bacterial species from positive blood cultures with a DNA-based microarray platform: An observational study. Lancet. 2010;375:224&#x2013;230. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(09)61569-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(09)61569-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20004964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charles PE, Ladoire S, Aho S, Quenot JP, Doise JM, Prin S, Olsson NO, Blettery B. Serum procalcitonin elevation in critically ill patients at the onset of bacteremia caused by either gram negative or gram positive bacteria. BMC Infect Dis. 2008;8:38. doi: 10.1186/1471-2334-8-38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2334-8-38</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2289831</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18366777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skovbjerg S, Martner A, Hynsj&#xf6; L, Hessle C, Olsen I, Dewhirst FE, Tham W, Wold AE. Gram-positive and gram-negative bacteria induce different patterns of cytokine production in human mononuclear cells irrespective of taxonomic relatedness. J Interferon Cytokine Res. 2010;30:23&#x2013;32. doi: 10.1089/jir.2009.0033.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/jir.2009.0033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20028205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hessle CC, Andersson B, Wold AE. Gram-positive and Gram-negative bacteria elicit different patterns of pro-inflammatory cytokines in human monocytes. Cytokine. 2005;30:311&#x2013;318. doi: 10.1016/j.cyto.2004.05.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cyto.2004.05.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15935951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Engel A, Mack E, Kern P, Kern WV. An analysis of interleukin-8, interleukin-6 and C-reactive protein serum concentrations to predict fever, gram-negative bacteremia and complicated infection in neutropenic cancer patients. Infection. 1998;26:213&#x2013;221. doi: 10.1007/BF02962366.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF02962366</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9717678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feezor RJ, Oberholzer C, Baker HV, Novick D, Rubinstein M, Moldawer LL, Pribble J, Souza S, Dinarello CA, Ertel W, Oberholzer A. Molecular characterization of the acute inflammatory response to infections with gram-negative versus gram-positive bacteria. Infect Immun. 2003;71:5803&#x2013;5813. doi: 10.1128/IAI.71.10.5803-5813.2003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/IAI.71.10.5803-5813.2003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC201043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14500502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berres ML, Trautwein C, Schmeding M, Eurich D, Tacke F, Bahra M, Neuhaus P, Neumann UP, Wasmuth HE. Serum chemokine CXC ligand 10 (CXCL10) predicts fibrosis progression after liver transplantation for hepatitis C infection. Hepatology. 2011;53:596&#x2013;603. doi: 10.1002/hep.24098.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hep.24098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21274880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeremski M, Markatou M, Brown QB, Dorante G, Cunningham-Rundles S, Talal AH. Interferon gamma-inducible protein 10: A predictive marker of successful treatment response in hepatitis C virus/HIV-coinfected patients. J Acquir Immune Defic Syndr. 2007;45:262&#x2013;268.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17414926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reiberger T, Aberle JH, Kundi M, Kohrgruber N, Rieger A, Gangl A, Holzmann H, Peck-Radosavljevic M. IP-10 correlates with hepatitis C viral load, hepatic inflammation and fibrosis and predicts hepatitis C virus relapse or non-response in HIV-HCV coinfection. Antivir Ther. 2008;13:969&#x2013;976.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19195322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conroy AL, G&#xe9;lvez M, Hawkes M, Rajwans N, Liles WC, Villar-Centeno LA, Kain KC. Host biomarkers distinguish dengue from leptospirosis in Colombia: A case-control study. BMC Infect Dis. 2014;14:35. doi: 10.1186/1471-2334-14-35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2334-14-35</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3909480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24444080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Punyadeera C, Schneider EM, Schaffer D, Hsu HY, Joos TO, Kriebel F, Weiss M, Verhaegh WF. A biomarker panel to discriminate between systemic inflammatory response syndrome and sepsis and sepsis severity. J Emerg Trauma Shock. 2010;3:26&#x2013;35. doi: 10.4103/0974-2700.58666.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/0974-2700.58666</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2823139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20165718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loetscher M, Gerber B, Loetscher P, Jones SA, Piali L, Clark-Lewis I, Baggiolini M, Moser B. Chemokine receptor specific for IP10 and Mig: Structure, function, and expression in activated T-lymphocytes. J Exp Med. 1996;184:963&#x2013;969. doi: 10.1084/jem.184.3.963.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1084/jem.184.3.963</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2192763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9064356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsieh MF, Lai SL, Chen JP, Sung JM, Lin YL, Wu-Hsieh BA, Gerard C, Luster A, Liao F. Both CXCR3 and CXCL10/IFN-inducible protein 10 are required for resistance to primary infection by dengue virus. J Immunol. 2006;177:1855&#x2013;1863. doi: 10.4049/jimmunol.177.3.1855.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4049/jimmunol.177.3.1855</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16849497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>