<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">30321168</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2019</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>09</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2019</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1935-2735</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>12</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2018</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PLoS neglected tropical diseases</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PLoS Negl Trop Dis</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Location, seasonal, and functional characteristics of water holding containers with juvenile and pupal Aedes aegypti in Southern Taiwan: A cross-sectional study using hurdle model analyses.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e0006882</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e0006882</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e0006882</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1371/journal.pntd.0006882</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Aedes aegypti carries several viruses of public health importance, including the dengue virus. Dengue is the most rapidly spreading mosquito-borne viral disease in the world. Prevention and control of dengue mainly rely on mosquito control as there is no antiviral treatment or a WHO-approved vaccine. To reduce the Ae. aegypti population, studying the characteristics of their habitats is necessary. Aedes aegypti prefer breeding in artificial water holding containers in peridomestic or domestic settings. Their juveniles (1st - 4th instar larvae and pupae) have a tendency to cluster in certain types of containers. To inform control strategies, it is important to assess whether the pupae subgroup has a distinct distribution by container type as compared to the overall group of juveniles. The objective of this study was to assess for distinct predictors (location, season, and function) of Ae. aegypti juveniles and pupae numbers in water holding containers by applying hurdle model analyses.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODOLOGY">The field component of this study was carried out from November 2013 to July 2015 in Southern Taiwan where annual autochthonous dengue has been reported for decades. Water holding containers with stagnant water were identified in a predefined urban area in Kaohsiung City (KH) and a rural area in Pingtung County. Given that mosquito survey data often include many containers with zero Ae. aegypti, a negative binomial hurdle model was applied to model the association between location, seasonal and functional characteristics of the water holding containers and the number of Ae. aegypti in each container.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">The results showed that Ae. aegypti were almost exclusively present in the urban area. In this area, the negative binomial hurdle model predicted significantly more juveniles as well as pupae Ae. aegypti in water holding containers during the wet season when compared to the dry season. Notably, the model predicted more juveniles in containers located on private property compared to those on government property, irrespective of season. As for pupae, the model predicted higher amounts in indoor containers used for water storage compared to outdoor water storage containers, irrespective of season. However, for the specific category 'other water receptacle', higher amounts of pupae were predicted in outdoor compared to indoor in water receptacles, such as flower pot saucers and water catchment buckets.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">The difference in predictors for juveniles and the pupae subgroup was identified and it may be of importance to the control strategies of the authorities in KH. At present the authorities focus control activities on all water holding containers found on government property. To improve the ongoing control efforts in KH, the focus of control activities maintained by the KH authorities should be expanded to indoor water storage containers and outdoor water receptacles on both private and government properties to adequately address habitats harboring greater numbers of pupae. In addition, it is proposed to increase community engagement in managing water in all types of water holding containers located on privately owned properties (indoor and outdoor), especially during wet season.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lin</LastName><ForeName>Chia-Hsien</ForeName><Initials>CH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8325-648X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Global Health Section, Department of Public Health, University of Copenhagen, Copenhagen, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schi&#xf8;ler</LastName><ForeName>Karin Linda</ForeName><Initials>KL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Global Health Section, Department of Public Health, University of Copenhagen, Copenhagen, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ekstr&#xf8;m</LastName><ForeName>Claus Thorn</ForeName><Initials>CT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Section of Biostatistics, Department of Public Health, University of Copenhagen, Copenhagen, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Konradsen</LastName><ForeName>Flemming</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Global Health Section, Department of Public Health, University of Copenhagen, Copenhagen, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2018</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PLoS Negl Trop Dis</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101291488</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1935-2727</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>059QF0KO0R</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D014867">Water</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000330" MajorTopicYN="N">Aedes</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000254" MajorTopicYN="Y">growth &amp; development</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003430" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Sectional Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005843" MajorTopicYN="N">Geography</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007814" MajorTopicYN="N">Larva</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000254" MajorTopicYN="N">growth &amp; development</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000072138" MajorTopicYN="N">Mosquito Vectors</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000254" MajorTopicYN="Y">growth &amp; development</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011679" MajorTopicYN="N">Pupa</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000254" MajorTopicYN="N">growth &amp; development</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012621" MajorTopicYN="N">Seasons</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013624" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Taiwan</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014867" MajorTopicYN="N">Water</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000469" MajorTopicYN="Y">parasitology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2018</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2018</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2018</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2018</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2019</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2018</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30321168</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6201951</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pntd.0006882</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PNTD-D-18-00486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization and Special Programme for Research and Training in Tropical Diseases. Dengue: guidelines for diagnosis, treatment, prevention and control. New ed. Geneva: 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Global strategy for dengue prevention and control 2012&#x2013;2020. Geneva: 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. A global brief on vector-borne diseases. 2014. Available from: http://apps.who.int/iris/bitstream/10665/111008/1/WHO_DCO_WHD_2014.1_eng.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shepard DS, Undurraga EA, Halasa YA. Economic and disease burden of dengue in Southeast Asia. PLoS Negl Trop Dis. 2013;7(2):e2055 10.1371/journal.pntd.0002055</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pntd.0002055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3578748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23437406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Immunization, Vaccines and Biologicals: Questions and Answers on Dengue Vaccines. 2017. Available from: http://www.who.int/immunization/research/development/dengue_q_and_a/en/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Focks DA, Brenner RJ, Hayes J, Daniels E. Transmission thresholds for dengue in terms of Aedes aegypti pupae per person with discussion of their utility in source reduction efforts. Am J Trop Med Hyg. 2000;62(1):11&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10761719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Focks DA, Alexander N. Multicountry study of Aedes aegypti pupal productivity survey methodology&#x2014;Findings and recommendations. Geneva: WHO/TDR; 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Focks DA. A review of entomological sampling methods and indicators for dengue vectors. (TDR/IDE/DEN/03.1). Geneva: World Health Organization Press; 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Focks DA, Chadee DD. Pupal survey: an epidemiologically significant surveillance method for Aedes aegypti: An example using data from Trinidad. Am J Trop Med Hyg. 1997;56(2):156&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9080874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin CH, Schioler KL, Jepsen MR, Ho CK, Li SH, Konradsen F. Dengue outbreaks in high-income area, Kaohsiung City, Taiwan, 2003&#x2013;2009. Emerg Infect Dis. 2012;18(10):1603&#x2013;11. 10.3201/eid1810.111929</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3201/eid1810.111929</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3471615</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23017369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control ROCT. Taiwan National Infectious Diseases Statistics System (https://nidss.cdc.gov.tw/en/). 2017. Available from: https://nidss.cdc.gov.tw/en/NIDSS_DiseaseMap.aspx?dc=1&amp;dt=4&amp;disease=061</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang FS, Tseng YT, Hsu PS, Chen CD, Lian I, Chao DY. Re-assess vector indices threshold as an early warning tool for predicting dengue epidemic in a dengue non-endemic country. PLoS Negl Trop Dis. 2015;9(9):e0004043 10.1371/journal.pntd.0004043</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pntd.0004043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4569482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26366874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control ROCT. Guidelines for Dengue/Chikungunya control 2017 [Chinese]. Centers for Disease Control,R.O.C.(Taiwan); 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Civil Affairs Bureau KCG. Year-end population in each district of Kaohsiung City. 2016. Available from: https://cabu.kcg.gov.tw/Web/StatRptsFileList.aspx?catId=77b7174e-f379-49ec-b2fd-2b42abf650ca</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taiwan Water Corporation. Population and percentage of pipped water avalibale. 2014. Available from: http://data.gov.tw/node/6309</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Central Weather Bureau. CWB Observation Data Inquire System. 2016. Available from: http://e-service.cwb.gov.tw/HistoryDataQuery/index.jsp</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Land Surveying and Mapping Center T. Boundary of city and county. 2018. Available from: https://data.gov.tw/datasets/search?qs=tid%3A667&amp;order=downloadcount&amp;type=dataset</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silver JB. Sampling the larval population In: Mosquito ecology: field sampling methods. Springer; 2008. pp. 137&#x2013;338.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rueda LM. Pictorial keys for the identification of mosquitoes (Diptera: Culicidae) associated with dengue virus transmission. Zootaxa. 2004;(589):1&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cameron AC, Trivedi P.K. Regression analysis of count data. Cambridge University Press; 1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mullahy J. Specification and testing of some modified count data models. J Econom. 1986;33(3):341&#x2013;65. 10.1016/0304-4076(86)90002-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0304-4076(86)90002-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuur AF, Ieno EN, Walker NJ, Saveliev AA, Smith GM. Mixed effects models and extensions in ecology with R. Springer; 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin TG, Wintle BA, Rhodes JR, Kuhnert PM, Field SA, Low-Choy SJ et al. Zero tolerance ecology: improving ecological inference by modelling the source of zero observations. Ecol Lett. 2005;8(11):1235&#x2013;46. 10.1111/j.1461-0248.2005.00826.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1461-0248.2005.00826.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21352447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>R Core Team (2017). R: A language and environment for statistical computing. R Foundation for Statistical Computing, Vienna, Austria:  2017. Available from: https://www.R-project.org/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeileis A, Kleiber C, Jackman S. Regression models for count data in R. J Stat Softw. 2008;27(8). doi: 10.18637/jss.v027.i08</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18637/jss.v027.i08</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackman S. pscl: Classes and Methods for R Developed in the Political Science Computational Laboratory. 2017. Available from: https://github.com/atahk/pscl/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazerolle MJ. AICcmodavg: model selection and multimodel inference based on (Q)AIC(c). 2017. Available from: https://cran.r-project.org/package=AICcmodavg</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bates D, M&#xe4;chler M, Bolker B, Walker S. Fitting linear mixed-effects models using lme4. Journal of Statistical Software. 2015;67(1). doi: 10.18637/jss.v067.i01</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18637/jss.v067.i01</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hwang JS. Ecology of Aedes mosquitoes and their relationship with dengue epidemics in Taiwan area. Chinese Journal of Entomology special publication, Proceedings of the IVth national vector control symposium, Taichung, R O C (Taiwan). 1991;6105&#x2013;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tuan YC, Hung MN, Lin LJ, Shih WY, Huang CC, Chang CC et al. Analysis on dengue vector density survey in Kaohsiung and Pingtung areas of Southern Taiwan, 2004&#x2013;2008. Taiwan epidemiology bulletin. 2009;25(7).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su AF, Pei ZC, Fu JC, Li CG, Feng F, Chu C et al. Analysis of distribution and population density changes of Aedes egypti the transmission vector of dengue fever in Haikou City [Chinese]. China Tropical Medicine. 2005;5(6):1394&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nasci RS, Hare SG, Willis FS. Interspecific mating between Louisiana strains of Aedes albopictus and Aedes aegypti in the field and laboratory. J Am Mosq Control Assoc. 1989;5(3).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2584975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juliano SA. Species introduction and replacement among mosquitoes: interspecific resource competition or apparent competition? Ecology. 1998;79(1):255&#x2013;68. 10.2307/176880</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2307/176880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hiwat H, Doerdjan K, Kerpens M, Samjhawan A, Sardjoe P, Soekhoe T. Importance of domestic water containers as Aedes aegypti breeding sites in Suriname, implications for dengue control. Acad J Sur. 2013;4403&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Dengue control- Environmental management. 2017. Available from: http://www.who.int/denguecontrol/control_strategies/environmental_management/en/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu HH, Wang CY, Teng HJ, Lin C, Lu LC, Jian SW et al. A dengue vector surveillance by human population-stratified ovitrap survey for Aedes (Diptera: Culicidae) adult and egg collections in high dengue-risk areas of Taiwan. J Med Entomol. 2013;50(2):261&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23540112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsuzuki A, Vu TD, Higa Y, Nguyen TY, Takagi M. Effect of peridomestic environments on repeated infestation by preadult Aedes aegypti in urban premises in Nha Trang City, Vietnam. Am J Trop Med Hyg. 2009;81(4):645&#x2013;50. 10.4269/ajtmh.2009.08-0175</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4269/ajtmh.2009.08-0175</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19815880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wai KT, Arunachalam N, Tana S, Espino F, Kittayapong P, Abeyewickreme W et al. Estimating dengue vector abundance in the wet and dry season: implications for targeted vector control in urban and peri-urban Asia. Path Glob Hlth. 2012;106 10.1179/2047773212Y.0000000063</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1179/2047773212Y.0000000063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3541889</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23318235</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho BC, Chan KL, Chan YC. Aedes aegypti (L.) and Aedes albopictus (Skuse) in Singapore City. 3. Population fluctuations. Bull World Health Organ. 1971;44(5):635&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2427847</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5316747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu QY, Guo YH, Lai SJ, Hung Q, Ren QH, Zou JH et al. Coexistence of Aedes aegypti and Aedes albopictus in Jinghong City, Yunnan Province: a survey of Aedes aegypti invasion. J Trop Dis. 2016;4(227). 10.4172/2329-891X.1000227</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4172/2329-891X.1000227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hwang JS, Wu HH, Chang NT. The breeding habitats of Aedes mosquitoes and the epidemic of dengue fever in Sanmin District, Kaohsiung City, Taiwan. Formos Entomol. 1995;15(3):215&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Center for Dengue Research Kaohsiung City. Newsletter-dengue update. 2017. Available from: https://orgws.kcg.gov.tw/001/KcgOrgUploadFiles/267/relfile/16925/115999/c9c10c98-aca7-47ed-ae89-fe0e8e103f80.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Environment Agency SG. Know The Potential Aedes Breeding Sites. 2018. Available from: https://www.nea.gov.sg/dengue-zika/prevent-aedes-mosquito-breeding/know-the-potential-aedes-breeding-sites</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pai HH, Hong YJ, Hsu EL. Impact of a short-term community-based cleanliness campaign on the sources of dengue vectors: an entomological and human behavior study. J Environ Health. 2006;68(6):35&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16483083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Espinoza-Gomez F, Hernandez-Suarez CM, Coll-Cardenas R. Educational campaign versus malathion spraying for the control of Aedes aegypti in Colima, Mexico. J Epidemiol Community Health. 2002;56(2):148&#x2013;52. 10.1136/jech.56.2.148</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jech.56.2.148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1732074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11812816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madeira NG, Macharelli CA, Pedras JF, Delfino MC. Education in primary school as a strategy to control dengue. Rev Soc Bras Med Trop. 2002;35(3):221&#x2013;6. 10.1590/S0037-86822002000300004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/S0037-86822002000300004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12045814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boo CS. Legislation for Control of Dengue in Singapore. Dengue Bulletin. 2001;2570&#x2013;3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang CY, Teng HJ, Lee SJ, Lin C, Wu JW, Wu HS. Efficacy of various larvicides against Aedes aegypti immatures in the laboratory. Jpn J Infect Dis. 2013;66(4):341&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23883850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsai PJ, Lin TH, Teng HJ, Yeh HC. Critical low temperature for the survival of Aedes aegypti in Taiwan. Parasit Vectors. 2018;11(1):22 10.1186/s13071-017-2606-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13071-017-2606-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5759216</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29310716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eisen L, Monaghan AJ, Lozano-Fuentes S, Steinhoff DF, Hayden MH, Bieringer PE. The impact of temperature on the bionomics of Aedes (Stegomyia) aegypti, with special reference to the cool geographic range margins. J Med Entomol. 2014;51(3):496&#x2013;516.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24897844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>