<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">30679913</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1178-6973</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>12</Volume><PubDate><Year>2019</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Infection and drug resistance</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Infect Drug Resist</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Resistance rates of non-<i>albicans Candida</i> infections in Taiwan after the revision of 2012 Clinical and Laboratory Standards Institute breakpoints.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>235</StartPage><EndPage>240</EndPage><MedlinePgn>235-240</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2147/IDR.S184884</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">In 2012, the Clinical and Laboratory Standards Institute (CLSI) revised its breakpoints for drugs and species because of the increase in non-<i>albicans Candida</i> infections and their drug resistance. Following global trends, the non-<i>albicans</i> candidemia resistance rate has increased in Taiwan as well. To update the antifungal susceptibility of non-<i>albicans</i> candidemia isolates, we conducted a multicenter study using the revised break points.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PATIENTS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Patients with non-<i>albicans</i> candidemia infections were identified at five tertiary hospitals in Taiwan from July 1, 2011, to June 30, 2014. The broth microdilution method using a Sensititre YeastOne system was performed for the determination of minimum inhibitory concentration (MIC). The susceptibility was interpreted based on the guidelines of the CLSI (CLSI M27-S4 and M27-S3).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS"><i>Candida tropicalis</i> was the predominant non-<i>albicans</i> candidemia pathogen (42.4%), and it showed increased fluconazole non-susceptibility (36.3%) when compared to the results from previous studies. In particular, <i>C. tropicalis</i> showed high cross-resistance to azole agents. <i>C. tropicalis</i> isolates that were found to be resistant to fluconazole also showed increased resistance to voriconazole (82.2%) and posaconazole (100%). The increased non-susceptibility of <i>Candida glabrata</i> to multiple antifungal agents, based on the revised break points, resulted from an increase in dose-dependent susceptibility (94.4%) rather than from an increase in resistance (5.6%).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The resistance rate of non-<i>albicans</i> candidemia isolates is increasing, particularly for <i>C. tropicalis</i> and <i>C. glabrata</i>.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hii</LastName><ForeName>Ing-Moi</ForeName><Initials>IM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Infectious Disease, Department of Internal Medicine, Changhua Christian Hospital, Changhua, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Chun-Eng</ForeName><Initials>CE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Infectious Disease, Department of Internal Medicine, Changhua Christian Hospital, Changhua, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Yu-Lin</ForeName><Initials>YL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Infectious Disease, Department of Internal Medicine, Changhua Christian Hospital, Changhua, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Wei-Lun</ForeName><Initials>WL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Emergency and Critical Care Medicine, Fu Jen Catholic University Hospital, New Taipei City, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, College of Medicine, Fu Jen Catholic University, New Taipei City, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Ping-Feng</ForeName><Initials>PF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Infectious Disease, Department of Medicine, Taipei Veterans General Hospital, Taipei, Taiwan, fdwang@vghtpe.gov.tw.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, National Yang-Ming University, Taipei, Taiwan, fdwang@vghtpe.gov.tw.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hsieh</LastName><ForeName>Min-Han</ForeName><Initials>MH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Infectious Diseases, Department of Internal Medicine, Kaohsiung Medical University Hospital, Kaohsiung Medical University, Kaohsiung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ho</LastName><ForeName>Mao-Wang</ForeName><Initials>MW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Infectious Diseases, Department of Internal Medicine, China Medical University Hospital, China Medical University, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Yen-Hsu</ForeName><Initials>YH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biological Science and Technology, College of Biological Science and Technology, National Chiao Tung University, HsinChu, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Kaohsiung Municipal Ta-Tung Hospital, Kaohsiung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, Graduate Institute of Medicine, Sepsis Research Center, Center of Dengue Fever Control and Research, Kaohsiung Medical University, Kaohsiung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Fu-Der</ForeName><Initials>FD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Infectious Disease, Department of Medicine, Taipei Veterans General Hospital, Taipei, Taiwan, fdwang@vghtpe.gov.tw.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, National Yang-Ming University, Taipei, Taiwan, fdwang@vghtpe.gov.tw.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2019</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>New Zealand</Country><MedlineTA>Infect Drug Resist</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101550216</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1178-6973</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">non-albicans candidemia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">resistance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">susceptibility</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Disclosure The authors report no conflicts of interest in this work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2019</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30679913</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6338119</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/IDR.S184884</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">idr-12-235</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Wayne PA, Clinical and Laboratory Standards Institute Reference Method for Broth Dilution Antifungal Susceptibility Testing of Yeasts; Fourth International Supplement. CLSI document. 2012:M27&#x2013;S4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cleveland AA, Harrison LH, Farley MM, et al. Declining incidence of candidemia and the shifting epidemiology of Candida resistance in two US metropolitan areas, 2008-2013: results from population-based surveillance. PLoS One. 2015;10(3):e0120452.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4378850</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25822249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arendrup MC, Dzajic E, Jensen RH, et al. Epidemiological changes with potential implication for antifungal prescription recommendations for fungaemia: data from a nationwide fungaemia surveillance programme. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2013;19(8):e343&#x2013;e353.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23607326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandven P, Bevanger L, Digranes A, et al. Candidemia in Norway (1991 to 2003): results from a nationwide study. J Clin Microbiol. 2006;44(6):1977&#x2013;1981.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1489391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16757587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diekema D, Arbefeville S, Boyken L, Kroeger J, Pfaller M. The changing epidemiology of healthcare-associated candidemia over three decades. Diagn Microbiol Infect Dis. 2012;73(1):45&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22578938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arendrup MC. Epidemiology of invasive candidiasis. Curr Opin Crit Care. 2010;16(5):445&#x2013;452.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20711075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pfaller MA, Andes D, Diekema DJ, Espinel-Ingroff A, Sheehan D, CLSI Subcommittee for Antifungal Susceptibility Testing Wild-type MIC distributions, epidemiological cutoff values and species-specific clinical breakpoints for fluconazole and Candida: time for harmonization of CLSI and EUCAST broth microdilution methods. Drug Resist Updat. 2010;13(6):180&#x2013;195.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21050800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pfaller MA, Andes D, Arendrup MC, et al. Clinical breakpoints for voriconazole and Candida spp. revisited: review of microbiologic, molecular, pharmacodynamic, and clinical data as they pertain to the development of species-specific interpretive criteria. Diagn Microbiol Infect Dis. 2011;70(3):330&#x2013;343.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21546199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pfaller MA, Diekema DJ, Andes D, et al. CLSI Subcommittee for Anti-fungal Testing Clinical breakpoints for the echinocandins and Candida revisited: integration of molecular, clinical, and microbiological data to arrive at species-specific interpretive criteria. Drug Resist Updat. 2011;14(3):164&#x2013;176.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21353623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wayne PA, Clinical and Laboratory Standards Institute Reference Method for Broth Dilution Antifungal Susceptibility Testing of Yeasts; Fourth International Supplement. CLSI document. 2008:M27&#x2013;S3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan TY, Hsu LY, Alejandria MM, et al. Antifungal susceptibility of invasive Candida bloodstream isolates from the Asia-Pacific region. Med Mycol. 2016;54(5):471&#x2013;477.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26868904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Falagas ME, Roussos N, Vardakas KZ. Relative frequency of albicans and the various non-albicans Candida spp among candidemia isolates from inpatients in various parts of the world: a systematic review. Int J Infect Dis. 2010;14(11):e954&#x2013;e966.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20797887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H, Xu YC, Hsueh PR. Epidemiology of candidemia and antifungal susceptibility in invasive Candida species in the Asia-Pacific region. Future Microbiol. 2016;11(11):1461&#x2013;1477.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27750452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin CC, Liu CP, Hsieh FC, Lee CM, Wang WS. Antimicrobial susceptibility and clinical outcomes of Candida parapsilosis bloodstream infections in a tertiary teaching hospital in Northern Taiwan. J Microbiol Immunol Infect. 2015;48(5):552&#x2013;558.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25315213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen YC, Kuo SF, Chen FJ, Lee CH. Antifungal susceptibility of Candida species isolated from patients with candidemia in southern Taiwan, 2007&#x2013;2012: impact of new antifungal breakpoints. Mycoses. 2017;60(2):89&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27621210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen LY, Liao SY, Kuo SC, et al. Changes in the incidence of candidaemia during 2000-2008 in a tertiary medical centre in northern Taiwan. J Hosp Infect. 2011;78(1):50&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21316800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang YL, Chen HT, Lin CC, Chu WL, Lo HJ, TSARY Hospitals Species distribution and drug susceptibilities of Candida isolates in TSARY 2010. Diagn Microbiol Infect Dis. 2013;76(2):182&#x2013;186.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23574935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang YT, Liu CY, Liao CH, Chung KP, Sheng WH, Hsueh PR. Antifungal susceptibilities of Candida isolates causing bloodstream infections at a medical center in Taiwan, 2009-2010. Antimicrob Agents Chemother. 2014;58(7):3814&#x2013;3819.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4068559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24752274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Espinel-Ingroff A, Arendrup MC, Pfaller MA, et al. Interlaboratory variability of Caspofungin MICs for Candida spp. Using CLSI and EUCAST methods: should the clinical laboratory be testing this agent? Antimicrob Agents Chemother. 2013;57(12):5836&#x2013;5842.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3837874</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24018263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forastiero A, Mesa-Arango AC, Alastruey-Izquierdo A, et al. Candida tropicalis antifungal cross-resistance is related to different azole target (Erg11p) modifications. Antimicrob Agents Chemother. 2013;57(10):4769&#x2013;4781.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3811422</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23877676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pfaller MA, Messer SA, Boyken L, et al. Use of fluconazole as a surrogate marker to predict susceptibility and resistance to voriconazole among 13,338 clinical isolates of Candida spp. Tested by clinical and laboratory standards institute-recommended broth microdilution methods. J Clin Microbiol. 2007;45(1):70&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1828974</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17079501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>