<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">32671658</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1434-9949</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>40</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Clinical rheumatology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Clin Rheumatol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Lower risk of primary Sjogren's syndrome in patients with dengue virus infection: a nationwide cohort study in Taiwan.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>537</StartPage><EndPage>546</EndPage><MedlinePgn>537-546</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s10067-020-05282-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The data concerning the association between dengue viruses (DV) infection and autoimmune diseases (ADs) remain unclear and are scarce. This nationwide population-based cohort study assessed the risk of ADs among patients with DV infection. We analyzed Taiwanese medical data from the Registry of the National Notifiable Disease Reporting System of Taiwan's Centers for Disease Control between 1998 and 2015 and identified patients with DV infection. From the entire general population data in the National Health Insurance Research Database, we randomly selected a comparison cohort that was individual matching by age, sex, residence, and index date. We analyzed the risk of ADs using a Cox proportional hazards regression model stratified by sex, age, and residence. We enrolled 29,365 patients with DV infection (50.68% men; mean age, 44.13&#xa0;years) and 117,460 age-, sex-, and residence-matched controls in the present study. The incidence rates of organ-specific ADs were nonsignificantly higher in the DV cohort than in the non-DV control cohort. An approximately 70% lower risk of primary Sjogren syndrome (pSS) was evident in the DV cohort than in the non-DV control cohort with an adjusted hazard ratio of 0.30 (95% confidence interval 0.13-0.67) after adjusting for comorbidities in matched design. By contrast, the other systemic ADs were nonsignificantly lower in the DV cohort than in the non-DV control cohort. This nationwide long-term cohort study demonstrated that patients with DV infection had a lower risk of primary Sjogren syndrome than those without DV infection. Key Points &#x2022; This retrospective, longitudinal cohort observational study shows that patients with DV infection had a lower risk of pSS than those without DV infection. &#x2022; The DV cohort had an approximately 70% lower risk of pSS than the control group, with a multivariate-adjusted HR of 0.30. &#x2022; On the basis of this result, we contended that DV infection has a protective effect that reduces the risk of pSS.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chang</LastName><ForeName>Chi-Ching</ForeName><Initials>CC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2336-2787</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Allergy, Immunology and Rheumatology, Department of Internal Medicine, School of Medicine, College of Medicine, Taipei Medical University, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Rheumatology, Immunology and Allergy, Department of Internal Medicine, Taipei Medical University Hospital, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yen</LastName><ForeName>Yu-Chun</ForeName><Initials>YC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Center of Biostatistics, College of Management, Taipei Medical University, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Cheng-Yi</ForeName><Initials>CY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Epidemic Intelligence Center, Taiwan Centers for Disease Control, Ministry of Health and Welfare, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Health Policy and Management, College of Public Health, National Taiwan University, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lin</LastName><ForeName>Chiou-Feng</ForeName><Initials>CF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Microbiology and Immunology, School of Medicine, College of Medicine, Taipei Medical University, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate Institute of Medical Sciences, College of Medicine, Taipei Medical University, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Chao-Ching</ForeName><Initials>CC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, School of medicine, College of Medicine, Taipei Medical University, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tsai</LastName><ForeName>Ching Wen</ForeName><Initials>CW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Center of Biostatistics, College of Management, Taipei Medical University, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Chuang</LastName><ForeName>Ting-Wu</ForeName><Initials>TW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Molecular Parasitology and Tropical Diseases, School of Medicine, College of Medicine, Taipei Medical University, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Bai</LastName><ForeName>Chyi-Huey</ForeName><Initials>CH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health, School of Public Health, College of Public Health, Taipei Medical University, 252, Wu-Hsing Street, Taipei, Taiwan. baich@tmu.edu.tw.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D064888">Observational Study</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Clin Rheumatol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8211469</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0770-3198</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015331" MajorTopicYN="N">Cohort Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003715" MajorTopicYN="Y">Dengue</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015994" MajorTopicYN="N">Incidence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016016" MajorTopicYN="N">Proportional Hazards Models</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012307" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012859" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sjogren's Syndrome</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013624" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Taiwan</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014777" MajorTopicYN="Y">Virus Diseases</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Autoimmune disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cohort study</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dengue virus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Risk</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32671658</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7817565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10067-020-05282-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s10067-020-05282-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Simmons CP, Farrar JJ, van Vinh Chau N, Wills B. Dengue. N Engl J Med. 2012;366:1423&#x2013;1432.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22494122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dengue: Guidelines for diagnosis, treatment, prevention and control. New edition. World Health Organization; 2009</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ranjit S, Kissoon N. Dengue hemorrhagic fever and shock syndromes. Pediatr Crit Care Med. 2011;12:90&#x2013;100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20639791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a G, Gonz&#xe1;lez N, P&#xe9;rez AB, Sierra B, Aguirre E, Rizo D, et al. Long-term persistence of clinical symptoms in dengue-infected persons and its association with immunological disorders. Int J Infect Dis. 2011;15:38&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21112804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wan SW, Lin CF, Yeh TM, Liu CC, Liu HS, Wang S, Ling P, Anderson R, Lei HY, Lin YS. Autoimmunity in dengue pathogenesis. J Formos Med Assoc. 2013;112(1):3&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23332423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin CF, Wan SW, Cheng HJ, Lei HY, Lin YS. Autoimmune pathogenesis in dengue virus infection. Viral Immunol. 2006;19(2):127&#x2013;132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16817755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu IJ, Chiu CY, Chen YC, Wu HC. Molecular mimicry of human endothelial cell antigen by autoantibodies to nonstructural protein 1 of dengue virus. J Biol Chem. 2011;286:9726e36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3058979</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21233208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kivity S, Arango MT, Ehrenfeld M, Tehori O, Shoenfeld Y, Anaya JM, Agmon-Levin N. Infection and autoimmunity in Sjogren&#x2019;s syndrome: a clinical study and comprehensive review. J Autoimmun. 2014;51:17&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24637076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Versini M, Jeandel PY, Bashi T, Bizzaro G, Blank M, Shoenfeld Y. Unraveling the hygiene hypothesis of helminthes and autoimmunity: origins, pathophysiology, and clinical applications. BMC Med. 2015;13:81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4396177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25879741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martina BE, Koraka P, Osterhaus AD. Dengue virus pathogenesis: an integrated view. Clin Microbiol Rev. 2009;22(4):564&#x2013;581.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2772360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19822889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng TM. Taiwan&#x2019;s National Health Insurance system: high value for the dollar. In: Okma KGH, Crivelli L, editors. Six countries, six reform models: the health reform experience of Israel, the Netherlands, New Zealand, Singapore, Switzerland and Taiwan. Hackensack: World Scientific; 2009. pp. 71&#x2013;204.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang CC, Chang YS, Chen WS, Chen YH, Chen JH. Effects of annual influenza vaccination on morbidity and mortality in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: a nationwide cohort study. Sci Rep. 2016;6:37817.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5133584</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27910867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang CC, Chiou CS, Lin HL, Wang LH, Chang YS, Lin HC. Increased risk of acute pancreatitis in patients with rheumatoid arthritis: a population-based cohort study. PLoS One. 2015;10(8):e0135187.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4532490</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26262880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fridkis-Hareli M. Immunogenetic mechanisms for the coexistence of organ-specific and systemic autoimmune diseases. J Autoimmune Dis. 2008;5:1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2265707</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18275618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hochberg MC. Updating the American College of Rheumatology revised criteria for the classification of systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Rheum. 1997;40:1725.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9324032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnett FC, Edworthy SM, Bloch DA, Mcshane DJ, Fries JF, Cooper NS, Healey LA, Kaplan SR, Liang MH, Luthra HS, Medsger TA, Mitchell DM, Neustadt DH, Pinals RS, Schaller JG, Sharp JT, Wilder RL, Hunder GG. The American Rheumatism Association 1987 revised criteria for the classification of rheumatoid arthritis. Arthritis Rheum. 1988;31:315&#x2013;324.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3358796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Rheumatism Association Diagnostic and Therapeutic Criteria Committee Preliminary criteria for the classification of systemic sclerosis (scleroderma). Subcommittee for scleroderma criteria of the American Rheumatism Association Diagnostic and Therapeutic Criteria Committee. Arthritis Rheum. 1980;23:581&#x2013;590.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7378088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vitali C, Bombardieri S, Jonsson R, Moutsopoulos HM, Alexander EL, Carsons SE, Daniels TE, Fox PC, Fox RI, Kassan SS, Pillemer SR, Talal N, Weisman MH, European Study Group on Classification Criteria for Sj&#xf6;gren&#x2019;s Syndrome Classification criteria for Sjogren&#x2019;s syndrome: a revised version of the European criteria proposed by the American-European consensus group. Ann Rheum Dis. 2002;61:554&#x2013;558.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1754137</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12006334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bohan A, Peter JB. Polymyositis and dermatomyositis (second of two parts) N Engl J Med. 1975;292:403&#x2013;407.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1089199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bohan A, Peter JB. Polymyositis and dermatomyositis (first of two parts) N Engl J Med. 1975;292:344&#x2013;347.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1090839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>International Study Group for Beh&#xe7;et&#x2019;s Disease Criteria for diagnosis of Beh&#xe7;et&#x2019;s disease. Lancet. 1990;335:1078&#x2013;1080.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1970380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunder GG, Bloch DA, Michel BA, Stevens MB, Arend WP, Calabrese LH, Edworthy SM, Fauci AS, Leavitt RY, Lie JT. The American College of Rheumatology 1990 criteria for the classification of giant cell arteritis. Arthritis Rheum. 1990;33:1122&#x2013;1128.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2202311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leavitt RY, Fauci AS, Bloch DA, Michel BA, Hunder GG, Arend WP, Calabrese LH, Fries JF, Lie JT, Lightfoot RW Jr The American College of Rheumatology 1990 criteria for the classification of Wegener&#x2019;s granulomatosis. Arthritis Rheum. 1990;33:1101&#x2013;1107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2202308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arend WP, Michel BA, Bloch DA, Hunder GG, Calabrese LH, Edworthy SM, Fauci AS, Leavitt RY, Lie JT, Lightfoot RW Jr The American College of Rheumatology 1990 criteria for the classification of Takayasu arteritis. Arthritis Rheum. 1990;33:1129&#x2013;1134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1975175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuo CF, Grainge MJ, Valdes AM, See LC, Luo SF, Yu KH, Zhang W, Doherty M. Familial aggregation of systemic lupus erythematosus and coaggregation of autoimmune diseases in affected families. JAMA Intern Med. 2015;175:1518&#x2013;1526.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26193127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuo CF, Grainge MJ, Valdes AM, See LC, Luo SF, Yu KH, Zhang W, Doherty M. Familial risk of Sj&#xf6;gren&#x2019;s syndrome and co-aggregation of autoimmune diseases in affected families: a nationwide population study. Arthritis Rheumatol. 2015;67:1904&#x2013;1912.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5034806</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25940005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tracy S, Drescher KM, Chapman NM, Kim KS, Carson SD, Pirruccello S, Lane PH, Romero JR, Leser JS. Toward testing the hypothesis that group B coxsackieviruses (CVB) trigger insulin-dependent diabetes: inoculating nonobese diabetic mice with CVB markedly lowers diabetes incidence. J Virol. 2002;76:12097&#x2013;12111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC136885</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12414951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horwitz MS, Bradley LM, Harbertson J, Krahl T, Lee J, Sarvetnick N. Diabetes induced by coxsackie virus: initiation by bystander damage and not molecular mimicry. Nat Med. 1998;4:781&#x2013;785.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9662368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christen U, Benke D, Wolfe T, Rodrigo E, Rhode A, Hughes AC, Oldstone MB, Von Herrath MG. Cure of prediabetic mice by viral infections involves lymphocyte recruitment along an IP-10 gradient. J Clin Invest. 2004;113:74&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC300760</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14702111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaccone P, Fehervari Z, Jones FM, Sidobre S, Kronenberg M, Dunne DW, Cooke A. Schistosoma mansoni antigens modulate the activity of the innate immune response and prevent onset of type 1 diabetes. Eur J Immunol. 2003;33:1439&#x2013;1449.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12731071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horwitz MS, La Cava A, Fine C, Rodriguez E, Ilic A, Sarvetnick N. Pancreatic expression of interferon-_ protects mice from lethal coxsackievirus B3 infection and subsequent myocarditis. Nat Med. 2000;6:693&#x2013;697.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10835688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tracy S, Drescher KM, Chapman NM, Kim KS, Carson SD, Pirruccello S, Lane PH, Romero JR, Leser JS. Toward testing the hypothesis that group B coxsackie viruses (CVB) trigger insulin-dependent diabetes: inoculating nonobese diabetic mice with CVB markedly lowers diabetes incidence. J Virol. 2002;76:12097&#x2013;12111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC136885</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12414951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacob CO, Aiso S, Michie SA, McDevitt HO, Acha-Orbea H. Prevention of diabetes in nonobese diabetic mice by tumor necrosis factor (TNF): similarities between TNF-&#x3b1;and interleukin 1. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 1990;87:968&#x2013;972.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC53391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2405400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christen U, Wolfe T, Mohrle U, Hughes AC, Rodrigo E, Green EA, Flavell RA, von Herrath MG. A dual role for TNF-&#x3b1; in type 1 diabetes: islet-specific expression abrogates the ongoing autoimmune process when induced late but not early during pathogenesis. J Immunol. 2001;166:7023&#x2013;7032.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11390446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okada H, Kuhn C, Feillet H, Bach JF. The &#x2018;hygiene hypothesis&#x2019; for autoimmune and allergic diseases: an update. Clin Exp Immunol. 2010;160(1):1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2841828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20415844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendez S, Reckling SK, Piccirillo CA, Sacks D, Belkaid Y. Role for CD4_CD25_ regulatory T cells in reactivation of persistent leishmaniasis and control of concomitant immunity. J Exp Med. 2004;200:201&#x2013;210.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2212012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15263027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toka FN, Suvas S, Rouse BT. CD4_CD25_ T cells regulate vaccinegenerated primary and memory CD8_ T-cell responses against herpes simplex virus type 1. J Virol. 2004;78:13082&#x2013;13089.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC525021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15542660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dittmer U, He H, Messer RJ, Schimmer S, Olbrich AR, Ohlen C, Greenberg PD, Stromnes IM, Iwashiro M, Sakaguchi S, et al. Functional impairment of CD8_ T cells by regulatory T cells during persistent retroviral infection. Immunity. 2004;20:293&#x2013;303.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15030773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murali-Krishna K, Altman JD, Suresh M, Sourdive DJ, Zajac AJ, Miller JD, Slansky J, Ahmed R. Counting antigen-specific CD8 T cells: a reevaluation of bystander activation during viral infection. Immunity. 1998;8:177&#x2013;187.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9491999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Homann D, Teyton L, Oldstone MB. Differential regulation of antiviral T-cell immunity results in stable CD8_ but declining CD4_ T-cell memory. Nat Med. 2001;7:913&#x2013;919.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11479623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oldstone MB. Viruses as therapeutic agents. I Treatment of nonobese insulin- dependent diabetes mice with virus prevents insulin-dependent diabetes mellitus while maintaining general immune competence. J Exp Med. 1990;171:2077&#x2013;2089.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2187941</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1972180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oldstone MB. Prevention of type I diabetes in nonobese diabetic mice by virus infection. Science. 1988;239:500&#x2013;502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3277269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manoussakis MN, Moutsopoulos HM. Sjogren&#x2019;s syndrome: current concepts. Adv Intern Med. 2001;47:191&#x2013;217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11795075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zinkernagel RM. Antiinfection immunity and autoimmunity. Ann N Y Acad Sci. 2002;958:3&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12021079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Triantafyllopoulou A, Tapinos N, Moutsopoulos HM. Evidence for coxsackievirus infection in primary Sjogren&#x2019;s syndrome. Arthritis Rheum. 2004;50:2897&#x2013;2902.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15457458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sipsas NV, Gamaletsou MN, Moutsopoulos HM. Is Sj&#xf6;gren&#x2019;s syndrome a retroviral disease? Arthritis Res Ther. 2011;13:212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3132012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21489323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christen U, von Herrath MG. Infections and autoimmunity--good or bad? J Immunol. 2005;174(12):7481&#x2013;7486.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15944245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>