<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">32748124</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>31</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0303-4240</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>185</Volume><PubDate><Year>2023</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Reviews of physiology, biochemistry and pharmacology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Rev Physiol Biochem Pharmacol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Endo-Lysosomal Cation Channels and Infectious Diseases.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>259</StartPage><EndPage>276</EndPage><MedlinePgn>259-276</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/112_2020_31</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Among the infectious diseases caused by pathogenic microorganisms such as bacteria, viruses, parasites, or fungi, the most prevalent ones today are malaria, tuberculosis, influenza, HIV/AIDS, Ebola, dengue fever, and methicillin-resistant Staphylococcus aureus (MRSA) infection, and most recently Covid-19 (SARS-CoV2). Others with a rather devastating history and high fatality rates such as plague, cholera, or typhus seem less threatening today but have not been eradicated, and with a declining efficacy of current antibiotics they ought to be watched carefully. Another emerging issue in this context is health-care associated infection. About 100,000 hospitalized patients in the USA ( www.cdc.gov ) and 33,000 in Europe ( https://www.ecdc.europa.eu ) die each year as a direct consequence of an infection caused by bacteria resistant to antibiotics. Among viral infections, influenza is responsible for about 3-5 million cases of severe illness, and about 250,000 to 500,000 deaths annually ( www.who.int ). About 37 million people are currently living with HIV infection and about one million die from it each year. Coronaviruses such as MERS-CoV, SARS-CoV, but in particular the recent outbreak of Covid-19 (caused by SARS-CoV2) have resulted in large numbers of infections worldwide with an estimated several hundred thousand deaths (anticipated fatality rate: &lt;5%). With a comparatively low mortality rate dengue virus causes between 50 and 100 million infections every year, leading to 50,000 deaths. In contrast, Ebola virus is the causative agent for one of the deadliest viral diseases. The Ebola outbreak in West Africa in 2014 is considered the largest outbreak in history with more than 11,000 deaths. Many of the deadliest pathogens such as Ebola virus, influenza virus, mycobacterium tuberculosis, dengue virus, and cholera exploit the endo-lysosomal trafficking system of host cells for penetration into the cytosol and replication. Defects in endo-lysosomal maturation, trafficking, fusion, or pH homeostasis can efficiently reduce the cytotoxicity caused by these pathogens. Most of these functions critically depend on endo-lysosomal membrane proteins such as transporters and ion channels. In particular, cation channels such as the mucolipins (TRPMLs) or the two-pore channels (TPCs) are involved in all of these aspects of endo-lysosomal integrity. In this review we will discuss the correlations between pathogen toxicity and endo-lysosomal cation channel function, and their potential as drug targets for infectious disease therapy.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020. Springer Nature Switzerland AG.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chao</LastName><ForeName>Yu-Kai</ForeName><Initials>YK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Walther Straub Institute of Pharmacology and Toxicology, Faculty of Medicine, Ludwig-Maximilians-Universit&#xe4;t, Munich, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chang</LastName><ForeName>Sui-Yuan</ForeName><Initials>SY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Laboratory Sciences and Medical Biotechnology, National Taiwan University College of Medicine, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Laboratory Medicine, National Taiwan University Hospital and National Taiwan University College of Medicine, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Grimm</LastName><ForeName>Christian</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Walther Straub Institute of Pharmacology and Toxicology, Faculty of Medicine, Ludwig-Maximilians-Universit&#xe4;t, Munich, Germany. christian.grimm@med.uni-muenchen.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Rev Physiol Biochem Pharmacol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0434624</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0303-4240</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D012367">RNA, Viral</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D002412">Cations</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019142" MajorTopicYN="Y">Hemorrhagic Fever, Ebola</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007251" MajorTopicYN="Y">Influenza, Human</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002771" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cholera</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015658" MajorTopicYN="Y">HIV Infections</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055624" MajorTopicYN="Y">Methicillin-Resistant Staphylococcus aureus</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012367" MajorTopicYN="N">RNA, Viral</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008247" MajorTopicYN="N">Lysosomes</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D029043" MajorTopicYN="Y">Ebolavirus</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002412" MajorTopicYN="N">Cations</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Endosome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Lysosome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">TPC1</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">TPC2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">TRPML1</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">TRPML2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">TRPML3</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32748124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/112_2020_31</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ambrosio AL, Boyle JA, Aradi AE, Christian KA, Di Pietro SM (2016) TPC2 controls pigmentation by regulating melanosome pH and size. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 113(20):5622&#x2013;5627</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amorim MJ, Bruce EA, Read EK, Foeglein A, Mahen R, Stuart AD, Digard P (2011) A Rab11- and microtubule-dependent mechanism for cytoplasmic transport of influenza A virus viral RNA. J Virol 85(9):4143&#x2013;4156</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arredouani A, Ruas M, Collins SC, Parkesh R, Clough F, Pillinger T, Coltart G, Rietdorf K, Royle A, Johnson P, Braun M, Zhang Q, Sones W, Shimomura K, Morgan AJ, Lewis AM, Chuang KT, Tunn R, Gadea J, Teboul L, Heister PM, Tynan PW, Bellomo EA, Rutter GA, Rorsman P, Churchill GC, Parrington J, Galione A (2015) Nicotinic acid adenine dinucleotide phosphate (NAADP) and Endolysosomal two-pore channels modulate membrane excitability and stimulus-secretion coupling in mouse pancreatic beta cells. J Biol Chem 290(35):21376&#x2013;21392</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bae M, Patel N, Xu H, Lee M, Tominaga-Yamanaka K, Nath A, Geiger J, Gorospe M, Mattson MP, Haughey NJ (2014) Activation of TRPML1 clears intraneuronal abeta in preclinical models of HIV infection. J Neurosci 34(34):11485&#x2013;11503</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellono NW, Escobar IE, Oancea E (2016) A melanosomal two-pore sodium channel regulates pigmentation. Sci Rep 6:26570</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bharati K, Ganguly NK (2011) Cholera toxin: a paradigm of a multifunctional protein. Indian J Med Res 33:179&#x2013;187</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bottcher-Friebertshauser E, Garten W, Matrosovich M, Klenk HD (2014) The hemagglutinin: a determinant of pathogenicity. Curr Top Microbiol Immunol 385:3&#x2013;34</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bretou M, Saez PJ, Sanseau D, Maurin M, Lankar D, Chabaud M, Spampanato C, Malbec O, Barbier L, Muallem S, Maiuri P, Ballabio A, Helft J, Piel M, Vargas P, Lennon-Dumenil AM (2017) Lysosome signaling controls the migration of dendritic cells. Sci Immunol 2(16):eaak9573</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bui M, Whittaker G, Helenius A (1996) Effect of M1 protein and low pH on nuclear transport of influenza virus ribonucleoproteins. J Virol 70(12):8391&#x2013;8401</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bullough PA, Hughson FM, Skehel JJ, Wiley DC (1994) Structure of influenza haemagglutinin at the pH of membrane fusion. Nature 371(6492):37&#x2013;43</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bussi C, Gutierrez MG (2019) Mycobacterium tuberculosis infection of host cells in space and time. FEMS Microbiol Rev 43(4):341&#x2013;361</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calcraft PJ, Ruas M, Pan Z, Cheng X, Arredouani A, Hao X, Tang J, Rietdorf K, Teboul L, Chuang KT, Lin P, Xiao R, Wang C, Zhu Y, Lin Y, Wyatt CN, Parrington J, Ma J, Evans AM, Galione A, Zhu MX (2009) NAADP mobilizes calcium from acidic organelles through two-pore channels. Nature 459(7246):596&#x2013;600</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cang C, Zhou Y, Navarro B, Seo YJ, Aranda K, Shi L, Battaglia-Hsu S, Nissim I, Clapham DE, Ren D (2013) mTOR regulates lysosomal ATP-sensitive two-pore Na(+) channels to adapt to metabolic state. Cell 152(4):778&#x2013;790</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cang C, Aranda K, Seo YJ, Gasnier B, Ren D (2015) TMEM175 is an organelle K(+) channel regulating Lysosomal function. Cell 162(5):1101&#x2013;1112</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao Q, Zhong XZ, Zou Y, Murrell-Lagnado R, Zhu MX, Dong XP (2015a) Calcium release through P2X4 activates calmodulin to promote endolysosomal membrane fusion. J Cell Biol 209(6):879&#x2013;894</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao Q, Zhong XZ, Zou Y, Zhang Z, Toro L, Dong XP (2015b) BK channels alleviate Lysosomal storage diseases by providing positive feedback regulation of Lysosomal Ca2+ release. Dev Cell 33(4):427&#x2013;441</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Capurro MI, Greenfield LK, Prashar A, Xia S, Abdullah M, Wong H, Zhong XZ, Bertaux-Skeirik N, Chakrabarti J, Siddiqui I, O'Brien C, Dong X, Robinson L, Peek RM Jr, Philpott DJ, Zavros Y, Helmrath M, Jones NL (2019) VacA generates a protective intracellular reservoir for helicobacter pylori that is eliminated by activation of the lysosomal calcium channel TRPML1. Nat Microbiol 4(8):1411&#x2013;1423</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carette JE, Raaben M, Wong AC, Herbert AS, Obernosterer G, Mulherkar N, Kuehne AI, Kranzusch PJ, Griffin AM, Ruthel G, Dal Cin P, Dye JM, Whelan SP, Chandran K, Brummelkamp TR (2011) Ebola virus entry requires the cholesterol transporter Niemann-pick C1. Nature 477(7364):340&#x2013;343</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castonguay J, Orth JHC, Muller T, Sleman F, Grimm C, Wahl-Schott C, Biel M, Mallmann RT, Bildl W, Schulte U, Klugbauer N (2017) The two-pore channel TPC1 is required for efficient protein processing through early and recycling endosomes. Sci Rep 7(1):10038</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen C, Zhuang X (2008) Epsin 1 is a cargo-specific adaptor for the clathrin-mediated endocytosis of the influenza virus. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 105(33):11790&#x2013;11795</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen CC, Keller M, Hess M, Schiffmann R, Urban N, Wolfgardt A, Schaefer M, Bracher F, Biel M, Wahl-Schott C, Grimm C (2014) A small molecule restores function to TRPML1 mutant isoforms responsible for mucolipidosis type IV. Nat Commun 5:4681</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen CC, Butz ES, Chao YK, Grishchuk Y, Becker L, Heller S, Slaugenhaupt SA, Biel M, Wahl-Schott C, Grimm C (2017) Small molecules for early endosome-specific patch clamping. Cell Chem Biol 24(7):907&#x2013;916.e904</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Csoka B, Nemeth ZH, Szabo I, Davies DL, Varga ZV, Paloczi J, Falzoni S, Di Virgilio F, Muramatsu R, Yamashita T, Pacher P, Hasko G (2018) Macrophage P2X4 receptors augment bacterial killing and protect against sepsis. JCI Insight 3(11)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuajungco MP, Silva J, Habibi A, Valadez JA (2016) The mucolipin-2 (TRPML2) ion channel: a tissue-specific protein crucial to normal cell function. Pflugers Arch 468(2):177&#x2013;192</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dayam RM, Saric A, Shilliday RE, Botelho RJ (2015) The Phosphoinositide-gated Lysosomal Ca(2+) channel, TRPML1, is required for Phagosome maturation. Traffic 16(9):1010&#x2013;1026</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dayam RM, Sun CX, Choy CH, Mancuso G, Glogauer M, Botelho RJ (2017) The lipid kinase PIKfyve coordinates the neutrophil immune response through the activation of the Rac GTPase. J Immunol 199(6):2096&#x2013;2105</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Castro Martin IF, Fournier G, Sachse M, Pizarro-Cerda J, Risco C, Naffakh N (2017) Influenza virus genome reaches the plasma membrane via a modified endoplasmic reticulum and Rab11-dependent vesicles. Nat Commun 8(1):1396</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Haan L, Hirst TR (2004) Cholera toxin: a paradigm for multi-functional engagement of cellular mechanisms. Mol Membr Biol 21(2):77&#x2013;92</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Vries E, Tscherne DM, Wienholts MJ, Cobos-Jimenez V, Scholte F, Garcia-Sastre A, Rottier PJ, de Haan CA (2011) Dissection of the influenza A virus endocytic routes reveals macropinocytosis as an alternative entry pathway. PLoS Pathog 7(3):e1001329</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong XP, Shen D, Wang X, Dawson T, Li X, Zhang Q, Cheng X, Zhang Y, Weisman LS, Delling M, Xu H (2010) PI(3,5)P(2) controls membrane trafficking by direct activation of mucolipin Ca(2+) release channels in the endolysosome. Nat Commun 1:38</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eisfeld AJ, Kawakami E, Watanabe T, Neumann G, Kawaoka Y (2011) RAB11A is essential for transport of the influenza virus genome to the plasma membrane. J Virol 85(13):6117&#x2013;6126</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Favia A, Desideri M, Gambara G, D'Alessio A, Ruas M, Esposito B, Del Bufalo D, Parrington J, Ziparo E, Palombi F, Galione A, Filippini A (2014) VEGF-induced neoangiogenesis is mediated by NAADP and two-pore channel-2-dependent Ca2+ signaling. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 111(44):E4706&#x2013;E4715</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodridge JP, Jacobs B, Saetersmoen ML, Clement D, Hammer Q, Clancy T, Skarpen E, Brech A, Landskron J, Grimm C, Pfefferle A, Meza-Zepeda L, Lorenz S, Wiiger MT, Louch WE, Ask EH, Liu LL, Oei VYS, Kjallquist U, Linnarsson S, Patel S, Tasken K, Stenmark H, Malmberg KJ (2019) Remodeling of secretory lysosomes during education tunes functional potential in NK cells. Nat Commun 10(1):514</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grimm C, Jors S, Saldanha SA, Obukhov AG, Pan B, Oshima K, Cuajungco MP, Chase P, Hodder P, Heller S (2010) Small molecule activators of TRPML3. Chem Biol 17(2):135&#x2013;148</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grimm C, Hassan S, Wahl-Schott C, Biel M (2012) Role of TRPML and two-pore channels in endolysosomal cation homeostasis. J Pharmacol Exp Ther 342(2):236&#x2013;244</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grimm C, Holdt LM, Chen CC, Hassan S, Muller C, Jors S, Cuny H, Kissing S, Schroder B, Butz E, Northoff B, Castonguay J, Luber CA, Moser M, Spahn S, Lullmann-Rauch R, Fendel C, Klugbauer N, Griesbeck O, Haas A, Mann M, Bracher F, Teupser D, Saftig P, Biel M, Wahl-Schott C (2014) High susceptibility to fatty liver disease in two-pore channel 2-deficient mice. Nat Commun 5:4699</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gunaratne GS, Yang Y, Li F, Walseth TF, Marchant JS (2018) NAADP-dependent Ca(2+) signaling regulates Middle East respiratory syndrome-coronavirus pseudovirus translocation through the endolysosomal system. Cell Calcium 75:30&#x2013;41</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herbert AS, Davidson C, Kuehne AI, Bakken R, Braigen SZ, Gunn KE, Whelan SP, Brummelkamp TR, Twenhafel NA, Chandran K, Walkley SU, Dye JM (2015) Niemann-pick C1 is essential for ebolavirus replication and pathogenesis in vivo. MBio 6(3):e00565&#x2013;e00515</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang P, Zou Y, Zhong XZ, Cao Q, Zhao K, Zhu MX, Murrell-Lagnado R, Dong XP (2014) P2X4 forms functional ATP-activated cation channels on lysosomal membranes regulated by luminal pH. J Biol Chem 289(25):17658&#x2013;17667</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karacsonyi C, Miguel AS, Puertollano R (2007) Mucolipin-2 localizes to the Arf6-associated pathway and regulates recycling of GPI-APs. Traffic 8(10):1404&#x2013;1414</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan N, Lakpa KL, Halcrow PW, Afghah Z, Miller NM, Geiger JD, Chen X (2019) BK channels regulate extracellular tat-mediated HIV-1 LTR transactivation. Sci Rep 9(1):12285</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim HJ, Soyombo AA, Tjon-Kon-Sang S, So I, Muallem S (2009) The Ca(2+) channel TRPML3 regulates membrane trafficking and autophagy. Traffic 10(8):1157&#x2013;1167</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim GH, Dayam RM, Prashar A, Terebiznik M, Botelho RJ (2014) PIKfyve inhibition interferes with phagosome and endosome maturation in macrophages. Traffic 15(10):1143&#x2013;1163</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiselyov KK, Ahuja M, Rybalchenko V, Patel S, Muallem S (2012) The intracellular Ca(2)(+) channels of membrane traffic. Channels (Austin) 6(5):344&#x2013;351</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lakadamyali M, Rust MJ, Babcock HP, Zhuang X (2003) Visualizing infection of individual influenza viruses. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 100(16):9280&#x2013;9285</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lange I, Yamamoto S, Partida-Sanchez S, Mori Y, Fleig A, Penner R (2009) TRPM2 functions as a lysosomal Ca2+-release channel in beta cells. Sci Signal 2(71):ra23</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee C, Guo J, Zeng W, Kim S, She J, Cang C, Ren D, Jiang Y (2017) The lysosomal potassium channel TMEM175 adopts a novel tetrameric architecture. Nature 547(7664):472&#x2013;475</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, Saitoh S, Shibata T, Tanimura N, Fukui R, Miyake K (2015) Mucolipin 1 positively regulates TLR7 responses in dendritic cells by facilitating RNA transportation to lysosomes. Int Immunol 27(2):83&#x2013;94</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin PH, Duann P, Komazaki S, Park KH, Li H, Sun M, Sermersheim M, Gumpper K, Parrington J, Galione A, Evans AM, Zhu MX, Ma J (2015) Lysosomal two-pore channel subtype 2 (TPC2) regulates skeletal muscle autophagic signaling. J Biol Chem 290(6):3377&#x2013;3389</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindvall JM, Blomberg KE, Wennborg A, Smith CI (2005) Differential expression and molecular characterisation of Lmo7, Myo1e, Sash1, and Mcoln2 genes in Btk-defective B-cells. Cell Immunol 235(1):46&#x2013;55</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin-Moshier Y, Keebler MV, Hooper R, Boulware MJ, Liu X, Churamani D, Abood ME, Walseth TF, Brailoiu E, Patel S, Marchant JS (2014) The two-pore channel (TPC) interactome unmasks isoform-specific roles for TPCs in endolysosomal morphology and cell pigmentation. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 111(36):13087&#x2013;13092</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martina JA, Lelouvier B, Puertollano R (2009) The calcium channel mucolipin-3 is a novel regulator of trafficking along the endosomal pathway. Traffic 10(8):1143&#x2013;1156</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCutchan FE (2006) Global epidemiology of HIV. J Med Virol 78(Suppl 1):S7&#x2013;S12</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miao Y, Li G, Zhang X, Xu H, Abraham SN (2015) A TRP channel senses lysosome neutralization by pathogens to trigger their expulsion. Cell 161(6):1306&#x2013;1319</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miklavc P, Mair N, Wittekindt OH, Haller T, Dietl P, Felder E, Timmler M, Frick M (2011) Fusion-activated Ca2+ entry via vesicular P2X4 receptors promotes fusion pore opening and exocytotic content release in pneumocytes. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 108(35):14503&#x2013;14508</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Momose F, Sekimoto T, Ohkura T, Jo S, Kawaguchi A, Nagata K, Morikawa Y (2011) Apical transport of influenza A virus ribonucleoprotein requires Rab11-positive recycling endosome. PLoS One 6(6):e21123</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mulangu S, Dodd LE, Davey RT Jr, Tshiani Mbaya O, Proschan M, Mukadi D, Lusakibanza Manzo M, Nzolo D, Tshomba Oloma A, Ibanda A, Ali R, Coulibaly S, Levine AC, Grais R, Diaz J, Lane HC, Muyembe-Tamfum JJ, PALM Writing Group, Sivahera B, Camara M, Kojan R, Walker R, Dighero-Kemp B, Cao H, Mukumbayi P, Mbala-Kingebeni P, Ahuka S, Albert S, Bonnett T, Crozier I, Duvenhage M, Proffitt C, Teitelbaum M, Moench T, Aboulhab J, Barrett K, Cahill K, Cone K, Eckes R, Hensley L, Herpin B, Higgs E, Ledgerwood J, Pierson J, Smolskis M, Sow Y, Tierney J, Sivapalasingam S, Holman W, Gettinger N, Vallee D, Nordwall J, PALM Consortium Study Team (2019) A randomized, controlled trial of Ebola virus disease therapeutics. N Engl J Med 381(24):2293&#x2013;2303</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murrell-Lagnado RD, Frick M (2019) P2X4 and lysosome fusion. Curr Opin Pharmacol 47:126&#x2013;132</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ou X, Liu Y, Lei X, Li P, Mi D, Ren L, Guo L, Guo R, Chen T, Hu J, Xiang Z, Mu Z, Chen X, Chen J, Hu K, Jin Q, Wang J, Qian Z (2020) Characterization of spike glycoprotein of SARS-CoV-2 on virus entry and its immune cross-reactivity with SARS-CoV. Nat Commun 11(1):1620. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-020-15562-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-020-15562-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Penny CJ, Vassileva K, Jha A, Yuan Y, Chee X, Yates E, Mazzon M, Kilpatrick BS, Muallem S, Marsh M, Rahman T, Patel S (2019) Mining of Ebola virus entry inhibitors identifies approved drugs as two-pore channel pore blockers. Biochim Biophys Acta, Mol Cell Res 1866(7):1151&#x2013;1161</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pettengill MA, Marques-da-Silva C, Avila ML, d'Arc dos Santos Oliveira S, Lam VW, Ollawa I, Sater AAA, Coutinho-Silva R, Hacker G, Ojcius DM (2012) Reversible inhibition of chlamydia trachomatis infection in epithelial cells due to stimulation of P2X(4) receptors. Infect Immun 80(12):4232&#x2013;4238</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinto LH, Lamb RA (2006) The M2 proton channels of influenza A and B viruses. J Biol Chem 281(14):8997&#x2013;9000</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plesch E, Chen CC, Butz E, Scotto Rosato A, Krogsaeter EK, Yinan H, Bartel K, Keller M, Robaa D, Teupser D, Holdt LM, Vollmar AM, Sippl W, Puertollano R, Medina D, Biel M, Wahl-Schott C, Bracher F, Grimm C (2018) Selective agonist of TRPML2 reveals direct role in chemokine release from innate immune cells. Elife 7:e39720</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qureshi OS, Paramasivam A, Yu JC, Murrell-Lagnado RD (2007) Regulation of P2X4 receptors by lysosomal targeting, glycan protection and exocytosis. J Cell Sci 120(Pt 21):3838&#x2013;3849</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rinkenberger N, Schoggins JW (2018) Mucolipin-2 cation channel increases trafficking efficiency of endocytosed viruses. MBio 9(1)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts EA, Chua J, Kyei GB, Deretic V (2006) Higher order Rab programming in phagolysosome biogenesis. J Cell Biol 174(7):923&#x2013;929. https://doi.org/10.1083/jcb.200603026</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roy AM, Parker JS, Parrish CR, Whittaker GR (2000) Early stages of influenza virus entry into Mv-1 lung cells: involvement of dynamin. Virology 267(1):17&#x2013;28</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruas M, Rietdorf K, Arredouani A, Davis LC, Lloyd-Evans E, Koegel H, Funnell TM, Morgan AJ, Ward JA, Watanabe K, Cheng X, Churchill GC, Zhu MX, Platt FM, Wessel GM, Parrington J, Galione A (2010) Purified TPC isoforms form NAADP receptors with distinct roles for Ca(2+) signaling and endolysosomal trafficking. Curr Biol 20(8):703&#x2013;709</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruas M, Chuang KT, Davis LC, Al-Douri A, Tynan PW, Tunn R, Teboul L, Galione A, Parrington J (2014) TPC1 has two variant isoforms, and their removal has different effects on endo-lysosomal functions compared to loss of TPC2. Mol Cell Biol 34(21):3981&#x2013;3992</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rust MJ, Lakadamyali M, Zhang F, Zhuang X (2004) Assembly of endocytic machinery around individual influenza viruses during viral entry. Nat Struct Mol Biol 11(6):567&#x2013;573</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakurai Y, Kolokoltsov AA, Chen CC, Tidwell MW, Bauta WE, Klugbauer N, Grimm C, Wahl-Schott C, Biel M, Davey RA (2015) Ebola virus. Two-pore channels control Ebola virus host cell entry and are drug targets for disease treatment. Science 347(6225):995&#x2013;998</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salata C, Calistri A, Alvisi G, Celestino M, Parolin C, Palu G (2019) Ebola virus entry: from molecular characterization to drug discovery. Viruses 11(3)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samie M, Wang X, Zhang X, Goschka A, Li X, Cheng X, Gregg E, Azar M, Zhuo Y, Garrity AG, Gao Q, Slaugenhaupt S, Pickel J, Zolov SN, Weisman LS, Lenk GM, Titus S, Bryant-Genevier M, Southall N, Juan M, Ferrer M, Xu H (2013) A TRP channel in the lysosome regulates large particle phagocytosis via focal exocytosis. Dev Cell 26(5):511&#x2013;524</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shang S, Zhu F, Liu B, Chai Z, Wu Q, Hu M, Wang Y, Huang R, Zhang X, Wu X, Sun L, Wang Y, Wang L, Xu H, Teng S, Liu B, Zheng L, Zhang C, Zhang F, Feng X, Zhu D, Wang C, Liu T, Zhu MX, Zhou Z (2016) Intracellular TRPA1 mediates Ca2+ release from lysosomes in dorsal root ganglion neurons. J Cell Biol 215(3):369&#x2013;381</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen D, Wang X, Li X, Zhang X, Yao Z, Dibble S, Dong XP, Yu T, Lieberman AP, Showalter HD, Xu H (2012) Lipid storage disorders block lysosomal trafficking by inhibiting a TRP channel and lysosomal calcium release. Nat Commun 3:731</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sieczkarski SB, Whittaker GR (2002) Influenza virus can enter and infect cells in the absence of clathrin-mediated endocytosis. J Virol 76(20):10455&#x2013;10464</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song Y, Dayalu R, Matthews SA, Scharenberg AM (2006) TRPML cation channels regulate the specialized lysosomal compartment of vertebrate B-lymphocytes. Eur J Cell Biol 85(12):1253&#x2013;1264</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sturgill-Koszycki S, Schlesinger PH, Chakraborty P, Haddix PL, Collins HL, Fok AK, Allen RD, Gluck SL, Heuser J, Russell DG (1994) Lack of acidification in Mycobacterium phagosomes produced by exclusion of the vesicular proton-ATPase. Science 263(5147):678&#x2013;681</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sumoza-Toledo A, Lange I, Cortado H, Bhagat H, Mori Y, Fleig A, Penner R, Partida-Sanchez S (2011) Dendritic cell maturation and chemotaxis is regulated by TRPM2-mediated lysosomal Ca2+ release. FASEB J 25(10):3529&#x2013;3542</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun L, Hua Y, Vergarajauregui S, Diab HI, Puertollano R (2015) Novel role of TRPML2 in the regulation of the innate immune response. J Immunol 195(10):4922&#x2013;4932</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tai W, He L, Zhang X, Pu J, Voronin D, Jiang S, Zhou Y, Du L (2020) Characterization of the receptor-binding domain (RBD) of 2019 novel coronavirus: implication for development of RBD protein as a viral attachment inhibitor and vaccine. Cell Mol Immunol 17:613. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41423-020-0400-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41423-020-0400-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tumpey TM, Basler CF, Aguilar PV, Zeng H, Solorzano A, Swayne DE, Cox NJ, Katz JM, Taubenberger JK, Palese P, Garcia-Sastre A (2005) Characterization of the reconstructed 1918 Spanish influenza pandemic virus. Science 310(5745):77&#x2013;80</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tumpey TM, Maines TR, Van Hoeven N, Glaser L, Solorzano A, Pappas C, Cox NJ, Swayne DE, Palese P, Katz JM, Garcia-Sastre A (2007) A two-amino acid change in the hemagglutinin of the 1918 influenza virus abolishes transmission. Science 315(5812):655&#x2013;659</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venkatachalam K, Hofmann T, Montell C (2006) Lysosomal localization of TRPML3 depends on TRPML2 and the mucolipidosis-associated protein TRPML1. J Biol Chem 281(25):17517&#x2013;17527</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vergne I, Chua J, Singh SB, Deretic V (2004) Cell biology of mycobacterium tuberculosis phagosome. Annu Rev Cell Dev Biol 20:367&#x2013;394</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>