<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">34180565</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1742-1241</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>75</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of clinical practice</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Clin Pract</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Incidence of dementia after dengue fever: Results of a longitudinal population-based study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e14318</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e14318</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/ijcp.14318</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To investigate the epidemiological relationship between dengue fever and the subsequent development of dementia.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Using nationwide Taiwan registries from the National Health Insurance Research (NHIRD), we identified adults aged over 40&#xa0;years who received a dengue fever diagnosis from 1 January 2000 to 31 December 2012 and who did not have a history of dementia. We used a propensity score match (PSM) to balance the baseline characteristics between groups. All eligible adults were sorted into either the dengue group or non-dengue group at a ratio of 1:4, matching by age, sex, index years, income level, and relevant comorbidities. Using Cox regression with proportional hazards models, we estimated the risk of dementia. The study period started from 1 January 2000 to 31 December 2013. We conducted sensitivity analyses to cross-validate study results.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">With a median of 8.01&#xa0;years of follow-up, patients in the dengue group were more at risk of developing dementia than the non-dengue group. The estimated cumulative incidence of dementia was 7.21% in the dengue group and 4.03% in the non-dengue group (adjusted hazard ratio (aHR), 1.71; 95% CI, 1.03 to 2.83). Sensitivity analyses yielded consistent findings. We excluded any stroke cases before the end of the study, and subgroup analysis by follow-up time showed that the dengue group has a significantly higher risk of new-onset dementia &gt;6&#xa0;years after the index date (aHR 3.24; 95% CI, 1.42 to 7.37). The P value for interaction was significant (&lt;.0001).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This study demonstrated a significantly higher risk of dementia in patients with dengue fever in Taiwan than in those without dengue fever.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chang</LastName><ForeName>Shu-Han</ForeName><Initials>SH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0909-590X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Neurosurgery, Department of Surgery, Kaohsiung Medical University Hospital, Kaohsiung Medical University, Kaohsiung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chang</LastName><ForeName>Renin</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1016-2233</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Emergency Medicine, Kaohsiung Veterans General Hospital, Kaohsiung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Su</LastName><ForeName>Chen-San</ForeName><Initials>CS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Neurology, Department of Medicine, Kaohsiung Veterans General Hospital, Kaohsiung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wei</LastName><ForeName>James Cheng-Chung</ForeName><Initials>JC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1235-0679</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Allergy, Immunology and Rheumatology, Chung Shan Medical University Hospital, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Medicine, Chung Shan Medical University, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate Institute of Integrated Medicine, China Medical University, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yip</LastName><ForeName>Hei-Tung</ForeName><Initials>HT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Management Office for Health Data, China Medical University Hospital, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Yu-Cih</ForeName><Initials>YC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Management Office for Health Data, China Medical University Hospital, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Kuan-Ying</ForeName><Initials>KY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Kaohsiung Medical University Hospital, Kaohsiung Medical University, Kaohsiung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, School of Medicine, College of Medicine, Kaohsiung Medical University, Kaohsiung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neuroscience Research Center, Kaohsiung Medical University, Kaohsiung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hung</LastName><ForeName>Yao-Min</ForeName><Initials>YM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6920-8799</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Medicine, Chung Shan Medical University, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Research, Taichung Veterans General Hospital, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Health and Nursing, Meiho University, Pingtung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>MOHW109-TDU-B-212-114004</GrantID><Agency>Taiwan Ministry of Health and Welfare Clinical Trial Center</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>India</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Clin Pract</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9712381</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1368-5031</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015897" MajorTopicYN="N">Comorbidity</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003704" MajorTopicYN="Y">Dementia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003715" MajorTopicYN="Y">Dengue</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015994" MajorTopicYN="N">Incidence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016016" MajorTopicYN="N">Proportional Hazards Models</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012307" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013624" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Taiwan</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34180565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ijcp.14318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Carod-Artal FJ, Wichmann O, Farrar J, Gasc&#xf3;n J. Neurological complications of dengue virus infection. Lancet Neurol. 2013;12:906-919.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhatt S, Gething PW, Brady OJ, et al. The global distribution and burden of dengue. Nature. 2013;496:504-507.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Araujo FMC, Araujo MS, Nogueira RMR, et al. Central nervous system involvement in dengue: a study in fatal cases from a dengue endemic area. Neurology. 2012;78:736-742.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Misra UK, Kalita J, Mani VE, Chauhan PS, Kumar P. Central nervous system and muscle involvement in dengue patients: a study from a tertiary care center. J Clin Virol. 2015;72:146-151.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kankirawatana P, Chokephaibulkit K, Puthavathana P, Yoksan S, Apintanapong S, Pongthapisit V. Dengue infection presenting with central nervous system manifestation. J Child Neurol. 2000;15:544-547.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson TP, Larman HB, Lee M-H, et al. Chronic dengue virus panencephalitis in a patient with progressive dementia with extrapyramidal features. Ann Neurol. 2019;86:695-703.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wen CP, Tsai SP, Chung WS. A 10-year experience with universal health insurance in Taiwan: measuring changes in health and health disparity. Ann Intern Med. 2008;148:258-267.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsing AW, Ioannidis JP. Nationwide population science: lessons from the taiwan national health insurance research database. JAMA Intern Med. 2015;175:1527-1529.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu T-M, Chuang Y-W, Yu M-C, et al. Risk of cancer in patients with polycystic kidney disease: a propensity-score matched analysis of a nationwide, population-based cohort study. Lancet Oncol. 2016;17:1419-1425.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen ML, Kao WM, Huang JY, Hung YM, Wei JC. Human papillomavirus infection associated with increased risk of new-onset psoriasis: a nationwide population-based cohort study. Int J Epidemiol. 2020;49:786-797.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chu KA, Chen W, Hsu CY, Hung YM, Wei JC. Association of scrub typhus with the risk of autoimmune diseases: a population-based cohort study. Am J Epidemiol. 2019;188:1311-1318.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang KO, Lu P-L, Ko W-C, et al. Dengue fever scoring system: new strategy for the early detection of acute dengue virus infection in Taiwan. J Formosan Med Assoc = Taiwan yi zhi. 2009;108:879-885.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woon YL, Lee KY, Mohd Anuar SFZ, Goh PP, Lim TO. Validity of International Classification of Diseases (ICD) coding for dengue infections in hospital discharge records in Malaysia. BMC Health Serv Res. 2018;18:292.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li HM, Huang YK, Su YC, Kao CH. Risk of stroke in patients with dengue fever: a population-based cohort study. CMAJ. 2018;190:E285-E290.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arvanitakis Z, Shah RC, Bennett DA. Diagnosis and management of dementia: review. JAMA. 2019;322:1589-1599.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fuh JL, Wang SJ. Dementia in Taiwan: past, present, and future. Acta Neurol Taiwan. 2008;17:153-161.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiu EC, Yip PK, Woo P, Lin YT. Test-retest reliability and minimal detectable change of the cognitive abilities screening instrument in patients with dementia. PLoS One. 2019;14:e0216450.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen HH, Perng WT, Chiou JY, Wang YH, Huang JY, Wei JC. Risk of dementia among patients with Sjogren's syndrome: a nationwide population-based cohort study in Taiwan. Semin Arthritis Rheum. 2019;48:895-899.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen WJ. Dengue outbreaks and the geographic distribution of dengue vectors in Taiwan: a 20-year epidemiological analysis. Biomed J. 2018;41:283-289.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen JH, Lin KP, Chen YC. Risk factors for dementia. J Formosan Med Assoc = Taiwan yi zhi. 2009;108:754-764.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu CK, Lai CL, Tai CT, Lin RT, Yen YY, Howng SL. Incidence and subtypes of dementia in southern Taiwan: impact of socio-demographic factors. Neurology. 1998;50:1572-1579.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harry GJ, Kraft AD. Neuroinflammation and microglia: considerations and approaches for neurotoxicity assessment. Expert Opin Drug Metab Toxicol. 2008;4:1265-1277.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heneka MT, Carson MJ, Khoury JE, et al. Neuroinflammation in Alzheimer's disease. Lancet Neurol. 2015;14:388-405.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sochocka M, Zwoli&#x144;ska K, Leszek J. The infectious etiology of Alzheimer's disease. Curr Neuropharmacol. 2017;15:996-1009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Despr&#xe8;s P, Frenkiel MP, Ceccaldi PE, Duarte Dos Santos C, Deubel V. Apoptosis in the mouse central nervous system in response to infection with mouse-neurovirulent dengue viruses. J Virol. 1998;72:823-829.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niranjan R, Muthukumaravel S, Jambulingam P. The involvement of neuroinflammation in dengue viral disease: importance of innate and adaptive immunity. NeuroImmunoModulation. 2019;26:111-118.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaturvedi UC, Dhawan R, Khanna M, Mathur A. Breakdown of the blood-brain barrier during dengue virus infection of mice. J Gen Virol. 1991;72859-866.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calder&#xf3;n-Pel&#xe1;ez MA, Velandia-Romero ML, Bastidas-Legarda LY, Beltr&#xe1;n EO, Camacho-Ortega SJ, Castellanos JE. Dengue virus infection of blood-brain barrier cells: consequences of severe disease. Front Microbiol. 2019;10:1435.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ginhoux F, Prinz M. Origin of microglia: current concepts and past controversies. Cold Spring Harb Perspect Biol. 2015;7:a020537.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsai T-T, Chen C-L, Lin Y-S, et al. Microglia retard dengue virus-induced acute viral encephalitis. Sci Rep. 2016;6:27670.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>John CC, Carabin H, Montano SM, Bangirana P, Zunt JR, Peterson PK. Global research priorities for infections that affect the nervous system. Nature. 2015;527:S178-S186.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butthep P, Chunhakan S, Yoksan S, Tangnararatchakit K, Chuansumrit A. Alteration of cytokines and chemokines during febrile episodes associated with endothelial cell damage and plasma leakage in dengue hemorrhagic fever. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2012;31:e232-e238.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patro ARK, Mohanty S, Prusty BK, et al. Cytokine signature associated with disease severity in dengue. Viruses. 2019;11:34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malavige GN, Ogg GS. Pathogenesis of vascular leak in dengue virus infection. Immunology. 2017;151:261-269.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang WY, Tan MS, Yu JT, Tan L. Role of pro-inflammatory cytokines released from microglia in Alzheimer's disease. Ann Transl Med. 2015;3:136.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tree MO, Londono-Renteria B, Troupin A, Clark KM, Colpitts TM, Conway MJ. Dengue virus reduces expression of low-density lipoprotein receptor-related protein 1 to facilitate replication in Aedes aegypti. Sci Rep. 2019;9:6352.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanekiyo T, Liu CC, Shinohara M, Li J, Bu G. LRP1 in brain vascular smooth muscle cells mediates local clearance of Alzheimer's amyloid-&#x3b2;. J Neurosci. 2012;32:16458-16465.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moroney JT, Bagiella E, Desmond DW, Paik MC, Stern Y, Tatemichi TK. Risk factors for incident dementia after stroke. Role of hypoxic and ischemic disorders. Stroke. 1996;27:1283-1289.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tatemichi TK, Paik M, Bagiella E, et al. Risk of dementia after stroke in a hospitalized cohort: results of a longitudinal study. Neurology. 1994;44:1885-1891.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan YC, Hsu JL, Tung HY, Chou CC, Bai CH. Increased dementia risk predominantly in diabetes mellitus rather than in hypertension or hyperlipidemia: a population-based cohort study. Alzheimer's Res Ther. 2017;9:7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S-F, Chang KO, Loh E-W, et al. Consecutive large dengue outbreaks in Taiwan in 2014-2015. Emerg Microbes Infect. 2016;5:e123.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang CJ, Chen CS, Tien CJ, Lu MR. Epidemiological, clinical and climatic characteristics of dengue fever in Kaohsiung City, Taiwan with implication for prevention and control. PLoS One. 2018;13:e0190637.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>