<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">34223707</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>28</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1863-2378</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>68</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Zoonoses and public health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Zoonoses Public Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Epidemiology and risk factors of scrub typhus in Taiwan: A nationwide database study from 1996 to 2014.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>876</StartPage><EndPage>883</EndPage><MedlinePgn>876-883</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/zph.12876</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Scrub typhus (ST) is one of the most underdiagnosed, potentially fatal febrile diseases in the Asia-Pacific region. We conducted a comprehensive review of the risk factors of ST over 19&#xa0;years using data from a nationwide database.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">We used data on ST from the nationwide database of the Taiwan Centers for Disease Control from 1996 to 2014 to analyse the incidence rates and relative risks of ST according to different regions. The trends of incidence rates over the study period were also evaluated. The distribution of confirmed ST cases was mapped using geographic information system software. The characteristics of confirmed ST cases and non-ST cases (cases with suspected ST but negative test findings) were compared.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Among the 38,127 reported cases, there were 6,791 (17.8%) confirmed ST cases. The overall incidence rate of ST in Taiwan was 1.49 per 100,000 residents per year. The trend of incidence rates increased over time. The Island region had the highest incidence rate (56.55 per 100,000 residents per year), followed by the Eastern region (15.13 per 100,000 residents per year). More confirmed ST cases were distributed in mountainous areas of Taiwan Main Island and Island region. Compared to non-ST cases, individuals with confirmed ST were younger (median [interquartile range] age: 44 [26-57] years versus 45 [30-60]&#xa0;years, p&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;.001) and more likely to engage in at-risk occupations (29.4% versus 13.3%, p&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;.001), including farming and animal husbandry (16.6% versus 9.0%, p&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;.001) and the armed forces (12.3% versus 3.5%, p&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;.001); however, they had a lower rate of animal contact (12.8% versus 20.1%, p&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;.001).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">ST is an endemic disease in Taiwan, particularly in the Island region, Eastern region and mountainous areas. Patients engaged in at-risk occupations and presenting with acute febrile diseases should undergo investigations for ST.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 Wiley-VCH GmbH.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chang</LastName><ForeName>Yi-Chin</ForeName><Initials>YC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0078-2052</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Infectious Diseases, Department of Internal Medicine, Kaohsiung Chang Gung Memorial Hospital, Kaohsiung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sun</LastName><ForeName>Wu</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Infection Control Department, Pao-Chien Hospital, Pingtung County, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lin</LastName><ForeName>Jiun-Nong</ForeName><Initials>JN</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4417-5350</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Infectious Diseases, Department of Internal Medicine, E-Da Hospital, Kaohsiung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Critical Care Medicine, E-Da Hospital, Kaohsiung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, College of Medicine, I-Shou University, Kaohsiung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Yen-Hsu</ForeName><Initials>YH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Infectious Diseases, Department of Internal Medicine, Kaohsiung Medical University Hospital, Kaohsiung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, Kaohsiung Medical University, Kaohsiung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate Institute of Medicine, Kaohsiung Medical University, Kaohsiung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sepsis Research Center, Center of Dengue Fever Control and Research, Kaohsiung Medical University, Kaohsiung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lai</LastName><ForeName>Chung-Hsu</ForeName><Initials>CH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1895-3673</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Infectious Diseases, Department of Internal Medicine, E-Da Hospital, Kaohsiung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, College of Medicine, I-Shou University, Kaohsiung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Infection Control Laboratory, E-Da Hospital, Kaohsiung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Chen-Hsiang</ForeName><Initials>CH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9302-5220</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Infectious Diseases, Department of Internal Medicine, Kaohsiung Chang Gung Memorial Hospital, Kaohsiung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Medicine, Chang Gung University, Kaohsiung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Zoonoses Public Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101300786</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1863-1959</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016208" MajorTopicYN="N">Databases, Factual</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015994" MajorTopicYN="N">Incidence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012285" MajorTopicYN="Y">Orientia tsutsugamushi</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012307" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012612" MajorTopicYN="Y">Scrub Typhus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000662" MajorTopicYN="N">veterinary</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013624" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Taiwan</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">
Orientia tsutsugamushi
</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Rickettsiaceae infections</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Scrub typhus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Zoonoses</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">vector-borne transmission</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34223707</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/zph.12876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Bonell, A., Lubell, Y., Newton, P. N., Crump, J. A., &amp; Paris, D. H. (2017). Estimating the burden of scrub typhus: A systematic review. PLoS Neglected Tropical Diseases, 11, e0005838. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pntd.0005838</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang, Y. C., Kuo, K. C., Sun, W., Lin, J. N., Lai, C. H., &amp; Lee, C. H. (2019). Clinicoepidemiologic characteristics of scrub typhus and murine typhus: A multi-center study in southern Taiwan. Journal of Microbiology, Immunology, and Infection, 52, 769-778. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmii.2019.04.004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Department of Household Registration (2020). Statistics. Ministry of the Interior. Republic of China (Taiwan). https://www.ris.gov.tw/app/en/3910</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eamsila, C., Singsawat, P., Duangvaraporn, A., &amp; Strickman, D. (1996). Antibodies to Orientia tsutsugamushi in Thai soldiers. American Journal of Tropical Medicine and Hygiene, 55, 556-559. https://doi.org/10.4269/ajtmh.1996.55.556</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elliott, I., Pearson, I., Dahal, P., Thomas, N. V., Roberts, T., &amp; Newton, P. N. (2019). Scrub typhus ecology: A systematic review of Orientia in vectors and hosts. Parasit Vectors, 12, 513. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13071-019-3751-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gentry, J. W., Phang, O. W., &amp; Manikumaran, C. (1977). The effects of rainfall on trombiculid (Acarina:Trombiculidae) larval populations in peninsular Malaysia. Southeast Asian Journal of Tropical Medicine and Public Health, 8, 217-220.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamaguchi, S., Cuong, N. C., Tra, D. T., Doan, Y. H., Shimizu, K., Tuan, N. Q., Yoshida, L., Mai, L. Q., Duc-Anh, D., Ando, S., Arikawa, J., Parry, C. M., Ariyoshi, K., &amp; Thuy, P. T. (2015). Clinical and epidemiological characteristics of scrub typhus and murine typhus among hospitalized patients with acute undifferentiated fever in Northern Vietnam. American Journal of Tropical Medicine and Hygiene, 92, 972-978. https://doi.org/10.4269/ajtmh.14-0806</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris, P. N. A., Oltvolgyi, C., Islam, A., Hussain-Yusuf, H., Loewenthal, M. R., Vincent, G., Stenos, J., &amp; Graves, S. (2016). An outbreak of scrub typhus in military personnel despite protocols for antibiotic prophylaxis: Doxycycline resistance excluded by a quantitative PCR-based susceptibility assay. Microbes and Infection, 18, 406-411. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.micinf.2016.03.006</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang, J., &amp; Richards, A. L. (2018). Scrub typhus: No longer restricted to the Tsutsugamushi Triangle. Tropical Medicine and Infectious Disease, 3, 11. https://doi.org/10.3390/tropicalmed3010011</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juckett, G. (2013). Arthropod bites. American Family Physician, 88, 841-847.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, D. S., Acharya, D., Lee, K., Yoo, S. J., Park, J. H., &amp; Lim, H. S. (2018). Awareness and work-related factors associated with scrub typhus: A case-control study from South Korea. International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health, 15, 1143. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph15061143</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kitchen, L. W., Lawrence, K. L., &amp; Coleman, R. E. (2009). The role of the United States military in the development of vector control products, including insect repellents, insecticides, and bed nets. Journal of Vector Ecology, 34, 50-61. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1948-7134.2009.00007.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuo, C. C., Huang, J. L., Shu, P. Y., Lee, P. L., Kelt, D. A., &amp; Wang, H. C. (2012). Cascading effect of economic globalization on human risks of scrub typhus and tick-borne rickettsial diseases. Ecological Applications, 22, 1803-1816. https://doi.org/10.1890/12-0031.1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai, C. H., Huang, C. K., Weng, H. C., Chung, H. C., Liang, S. H., Lin, J. N., Lin, C. W., Hsu, C. Y., &amp; Lin, H. H. (2009). The difference in clinical characteristics between acute Q fever and scrub typhus in southern Taiwan. International Journal of Infectious Diseases, 13, 387-393. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijid.2008.07.020</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai, C. H., Sun, W., Lee, C. H., Lin, J. N., Liao, M. H., Liu, S. S., Chang, T. Y., Tsai, K. F., Chang, Y. C., Lin, H. H., &amp; Chen, Y. H. (2017). The epidemiology and characteristics of Q fever and co-infections with scrub typhus, murine typhus or leptospirosis in Taiwan: A nationwide database study. Zoonoses Public Health, 64, 517-526. https://doi.org/10.1111/zph.12333</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, Y. S., Wang, P. H., Tseng, S. J., Ko, C. F., &amp; Teng, H. J. (2006). Epidemiology of scrub typhus in eastern Taiwan, 2000-2004. Japanese Journal of Infectious Diseases, 59, 235-238.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, P. R., Tsai, H. P., Weng, M. H., Lin, H. C., Chen, K. C., Kuo, M. D., Tsui, P. Y., Hung, Y. W., Hsu, H. L., &amp; Liu, W. T. (2014). Field assessment of Orientia tsutsugamushi infection in small mammals and its association with the occurrence of human scrub typhus in Taiwan. Acta Tropica, 131, 117-123. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actatropica.2013.11.029</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luce-Fedrow, A., Lehman, M. L., Kelly, D. J., Mullins, K., Maina, A. N., Stewart, R. L., Ge, H., John, H. S., Jiang, J., &amp; Richards, A. L. (2018). A review of scrub typhus (Orientia tsutsugamushi and related organisms): Then, now, and tomorrow. Tropical Medicine and Infectious Disease, 3, 8. https://doi.org/10.3390/tropicalmed3010008</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minahan, N. T., Chao, C. C., &amp; Tsai, K. H. (2017). The Re-Emergence and Emergence of Vector-Borne Rickettsioses in Taiwan. Tropical Medicine and Infectious Disease, 3, 1. https://doi.org/10.3390/tropicalmed3010001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morse, S. S. (1995). Factors in the emergence of infectious diseases. Emerging Infectious Diseases, 1, 7-15. https://doi.org/10.3201/eid0101.950102</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olson, J. G., Bourgeois, A. L., Fang, R. C., Coolbaugh, J. C., &amp; Dennis, D. T. (1980). Prevention of scrub typhus. Prophylactic administration of doxycycline in a randomized double blind trial. American Journal of Tropical Medicine and Hygiene, 29, 989-997. https://doi.org/10.4269/ajtmh.1980.29.989</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paris, D. H., Shelite, T. R., Day, N. P., &amp; Walker, D. H. (2013). Unresolved problems related to scrub typhus: A seriously neglected life-threatening disease. American Journal of Tropical Medicine and Hygiene, 89, 301-307. https://doi.org/10.4269/ajtmh.13-0064</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Premaratna, R., Ariyaratna, N., Attanayake, C., Bandara, W., Chandrasena, N., &amp; de Silva, H. J. (2014). Rickettsial infection among military personnel deployed in Northern Sri Lanka. BMC Infectious Diseases, 14, 3864. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12879-014-0688-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takahashi, M., Machida, K., Murata, M., Misumi, H., Hori, E., Kawamura, A. Jr, &amp; Tanaka, H. (1993). Seasonal development of Leptotrombidium pallidum (Acari: Trombiculidae) observed by experimental rearing in the natural environment. Journal of Medical Entomology, 30, 320-325. https://doi.org/10.1093/jmedent/30.2.320</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor, A. J., Paris, D. H., &amp; Newton, P. N. (2015). A systematic review of mortality from untreated scrub typhus (Orientia tsutsugamushi). PLoS Neglected Tropical Diseases, 9, e0003971. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pntd.0003971</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Traub, R., &amp; Wisseman, C. L. Jr (1974). The ecology of chigger-borne rickettsiosis (scrub typhus). Journal of Medical Entomology, 11, 237-303. https://doi.org/10.1093/jmedent/11.3.237</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsai, P. J., &amp; Yeh, H. C. (2013). Scrub typhus islands in the Taiwan area and the association between scrub typhus disease and forest land use and farmer population density: Geographically weighted regression. BMC Infectious Diseases, 13, 191. https://doi.org/10.1186/1471-2334-13-191</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tshokey, T., Stenos, J., Durrheim, D. N., Eastwood, K., Nguyen, C., &amp; Graves, S. R. (2017). Seroprevalence of rickettsial infections and Q fever in Bhutan. PLoS Neglected Tropical Diseases, 11, e0006107. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pntd.0006107</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vall&#xe9;e, J., Thaojaikong, T., Moore, C. E., Phetsouvanh, R., Richards, A. L., Souris, M., Fournet, F., Salem, G., Gonzalez, J. P., &amp; Newton, P. N. (2010). Contrasting spatial distribution and risk factors for past infection with scrub typhus and murine typhus in Vientiane City, Lao PDR. PLoS Neglected Tropical Diseases, 4, e909. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pntd.0000909</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Y. C., Chen, P. C., Lee, K. F., Wu, Y. C., &amp; Chiu, C. H. (2013). Scrub typhus cases in a teaching hospital in Penghu, Taiwan, 2006-2010. Vector-Borne and Zoonotic Diseases, 13, 154-159. https://doi.org/10.1089/vbz.2012.1059</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wardrop, N. A., Kuo, C. C., Wang, H. C., Clements, A. C., Lee, P. F., &amp; Atkinson, P. M. (2013). Bayesian spatial modelling and the significance of agricultural land use to scrub typhus infection in Taiwan. Geospatial Health, 8, 229-239. https://doi.org/10.4081/gh.2013.69</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watt, G., &amp; Strickman, D. (1994). Life-Threatening Scrub Typhus in a Traveler Returning from Thailand. Clinical Infectious Diseases, 18, 624-626. https://doi.org/10.1093/clinids/18.4.624</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. (1999). WHO recommended surveillance standards. Second Edition. https://www.who.int/csr/resources/publications/surveillance/WHO_CDS_CSR_ISR_99_2_EN/en/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, G., Walker, D. H., Jupiter, D., Melby, P. C., &amp; Arcari, C. M. (2017). A review of the global epidemiology of scrub typhus. PLoS Neglected Tropical Diseases, 11, e0006062. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pntd.0006062</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, L. P., Liu, J., Wang, X. J., Ma, W., Jia, C. X., &amp; Jiang, B. F. (2014). Effects of meteorological factors on scrub typhus in a temperate region of China. Epidemiology and Infection, 142, 2217-2226. https://doi.org/10.1017/s0950268813003208</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>