<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">34390293</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>11</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1526-4998</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>77</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Pest management science</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Pest Manag Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of piperonyl butoxide synergism and cuticular thickening on the contact irritancy response of field Aedes aegypti (Diptera: Culicidae) to deltamethrin.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>5557</StartPage><EndPage>5565</EndPage><MedlinePgn>5557-5565</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/ps.6597</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Exploiting indoor-resting mosquitoes' innate behavioral responses to commonly used insecticide is crucial in vector control programs. Indoor residual spraying (IRS) and long-lasting insecticidal nets (LLINs) treated with pyrethroids have become widely used for controlling dengue fever vectors. The present study tested the effects of piperonyl butoxide (PBO) synergism and cuticular thickening on the contact irritancy response of field A. aegypti (Diptera: Culicidae) to deltamethrin in Taiwan and Thailand.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The escape response of field mosquitoes treated with PBO was significantly elicited, with an escape percentage increase between 2- and 10-fold. In addition, the escape time was significantly lower in PBO-pretreated mosquitoes compared with field mosquitoes treated with deltamethrin alone. PBO-pretreated mosquitoes from seven out of 11 field strains exhibited a knockdown percentage of 11.23-54.91%, significantly higher than that of mosquitoes in corresponding strains treated with deltamethrin only. The Annan, Zhongxi, Sanmin, and North strains exhibited weak knockdown responses (&#x2264;3.75%). The mortality of PBO-pretreated field mosquitoes increased 2- to 75-fold compared with those treated with deltamethrin alone (mortality: 0-6.70%). Furthermore, the effect of cuticular thickness on the escape response of field mosquitoes was significant, that is, the escape response marginally increased inversely to cuticular thickness. By contrast, cuticular thickness was not significantly associated with knockdown or mortality percentage.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Irritant behavior in mosquitoes was significantly elicited by PBO synergism. PBO incorporating deltamethrin IRS or LLINs may be effective for controlling dengue fever vectors. &#xa9; 2021 Society of Chemical Industry.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 Society of Chemical Industry.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yu</LastName><ForeName>Jin-Jia</ForeName><Initials>JJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Entomology, National Chung Hsing University, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bong</LastName><ForeName>Lee-Jin</ForeName><Initials>LJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Entomology, National Chung Hsing University, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Panthawong</LastName><ForeName>Amonrat</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Entomology, Faculty of Agriculture, Kasetsart University, Bangkok, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chareonviriyaphap</LastName><ForeName>Theeraphap</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Entomology, Faculty of Agriculture, Kasetsart University, Bangkok, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Wei-Ting</ForeName><Initials>WT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathology and Laboratory Medicine, Taipei Veterans General Hospital, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Neoh</LastName><ForeName>Kok-Boon</ForeName><Initials>KB</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0330-1493</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Entomology, National Chung Hsing University, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>i-Center for Advanced Science and Technology</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><Agency>Ministry of Science and Technology, Taiwan</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><Agency>National Health Research Institutes</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Pest Manag Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100898744</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1526-498X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D007306">Insecticides</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D007509">Irritants</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D009570">Nitriles</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D011722">Pyrethrins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>2JTS8R821G</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C017180">decamethrin</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>LWK91TU9AH</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D010882">Piperonyl Butoxide</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000330" MajorTopicYN="Y">Aedes</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007305" MajorTopicYN="N">Insecticide Resistance</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007306" MajorTopicYN="Y">Insecticides</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007509" MajorTopicYN="N">Irritants</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009032" MajorTopicYN="N">Mosquito Control</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000072138" MajorTopicYN="N">Mosquito Vectors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009570" MajorTopicYN="N">Nitriles</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010882" MajorTopicYN="N">Piperonyl Butoxide</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011722" MajorTopicYN="Y">Pyrethrins</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cuticular permeability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">excito-repellency</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">indoor residual spraying</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">irritant behavior</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long-lasting insecticidal nets</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34390293</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ps.6597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Chadee DD, Landing periodicity of the mosquito Aedes aegypti in Trinidad in relation to the timing of insecticidal space-spraying. Med Vet Entomol 2:189-192 (1988).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chadee DD, Resting behaviour of Aedes aegypti in Trinidad: with evidence for the re-introduction of indoor residual spraying (IRS) for dengue control. Parasit Vectors 6:255 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dunbar MW, Correa-Morales F, Dzul-Manzanilla F, Medina-Barreiro A, Bibiano-Mar&#xed;n W, Morales-R&#xed;os E et al., Efficacy of novel indoor residual spraying methods targeting pyrethroid-resistant Aedes aegypti within experimental houses. PLoS Negl Trop Dis 13:e0007203 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herrera-Boj&#xf3;rquez J, Trujillo-Pe&#xf1;a E, Vadillo-S&#xe1;nchez J, Riestra-Morales M, Che-Mendoza A, Delf&#xed;n-Gonz&#xe1;lez H et al., Efficacy of long-lasting insecticidal nets with declining physical and chemical integrity on Aedes aegypti (Diptera: Culicidae). J Med Entomol 57:503-510 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paredes-Esquivel C, Lenhart A, Del R&#xed;o R, Leza M, Estrugo M, Chalco E et al., The impact of indoor residual spraying of deltamethrin on dengue vector populations in the Peruvian Amazon. Acta Trop 154:139-144 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hladish TJ, Pearson CA, Rojas DP, Gomez-Dantes H, Halloran ME, Vazquez-Prokopec GM et al., Forecasting the effectiveness of indoor residual spraying for reducing dengue burden. PLoS Negl Trop Dis 12:e0006570 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vazquez-Prokopec GM, Montgomery BL, Horne P, Clennon JA and Ritchie SA, Combining contact tracing with targeted indoor residual spraying significantly reduces dengue transmission. Sci Adv 3:e1602024 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowman LR, Donegan S and McCall PJ, Is dengue vector control deficient in effectiveness or evidence? Systematic review and meta-analysis. PLoS Negl Trop Dis 10:e0004551 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haddi K, Tom&#xe9; HVV, Du Y, Valbon WR, Nomura Y, Martins GF et al., Detection of a new pyrethroid resistance mutation (V410L) in thesodium channel of Aedes aegypti: a potential challenge for mosquitocontrol. Sci Rep 7:46549 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du Y, Nomura Y, Zhorov BS and Dong K, Sodium channel mutations and pyrethroid resistance in Aedes aegypti. Insects 7:60 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu N, Xu Q, Zhu F and Zhang L, Pyrethroid resistance in mosquitoes. Insect Sci 13:159-166 (2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu J-J, Bong L-J, Panthawong A, Chareonviriyaphap T and Neoh K-B, Repellency and contact irritancy responses of Aedes aegypti (Diptera: Culicidae) against Deltamethrin and permethrin: a cross-regional comparison. J Med Entomol 58:379-389 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deletre E, Martin T, Dum&#xe9;nil C and Chandre F, Insecticide resistance modifies mosquito response to DEET and natural repellents. Parasit Vectors 12:89 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith LB, Kasai S and Scott JG, Pyrethroid resistance in Aedes aegypti and Aedes albopictus: important mosquito vectors of human diseases. Pest Biochem Physiol 133:1-12 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization, Conditions for Use of Long-Lasting Insecticidal Nets Treated with a Pyrethroid and Piperonyl Butoxide: 21-23 September 2015, Geneva: WHO evidence review group meeting report. World Health Organization, Geneva (2015)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Awolola ST, Adeogun AO, Olojede JB, Oduola AO, Oyewole IO and Amajoh CN, Impact of PermaNet 3.0 on entomological indices in an area of pyrethroid resistant Anopheles gambiae in South-Western Nigeria. Parasit Vectors 7:1-10 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pennetier C, Bouraima A, Chandre F, Piameu M, Etang J, Rossignol M et al., Efficacy of Olyset plus, a new long-lasting insecticidal net incorporating permethrin and piperonil-butoxide against multi-resistant malaria vectors. PLoS One 8:e75134 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gleave K, Lissenden N, Richardson M, Choi L and Ranson H, Piperonyl butoxide (PBO) combined with pyrethroids in insecticide-treated nets to prevent malaria in Africa. Cochrane Database Syst Rev 11:CD012776 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Protopopoff N, Mosha JF, Lukole E, Charlwood JD, Wright A, Mwalimu CD et al., Effectiveness of a long-lasting piperonyl butoxide-treated insecticidal net and indoor residual spray interventions, separately and together, against malaria transmitted by pyrethroid-resistant mosquitoes: a cluster, randomised controlled, two-by-two factorial design trial. Lancet 391:1577-1588 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmad M, Denholm I and Bromilow RH, Delayed cuticular penetration and enhanced metabolism of deltamethrin in pyrethroid-resistant strains of Helicoverpa armigera from China and Pakistan. Pest Manag Sci 62:805-810 (2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anspaugh DD, Rose RL, Koehler PG, Hodgson E and Roe RM, Multiple mechanisms of pyrethroid resistance in the German cockroach, Blattella germanica (L.). Pest Biochem Physiol 50:138-148 (1994).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bull D and Patterson R, Characterization of pyrethroid resistance in a strain of the German cockroach (Dictyoptera: Blattellidae). J Econ Entomol 86:20-25 (1993).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lilly DG, Latham SL, Webb CE and Doggett SL, Cuticle thickening in a pyrethroid-resistant strain of the common bed bug, Cimex lectularius L.(Hemiptera: Cimicidae). PLoS One 11:e0153302 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedrini N, Mijailovsky SJ, Girotti JR, Stariolo R, Cardozo RM, Gentile A et al., Control of pyrethroid-resistant Chagas disease vectors with entomopathogenic fungi. PLoS Negl Trop Dis 3:e434 (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wood O, Hanrahan S, Coetzee M, Koekemoer L and Brooke B, Cuticle thickening associated with pyrethroid resistance in the major malaria vector Anopheles funestus. Parasit Vectors 3:67 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yahou&#xe9;do GA, Chandre F, Rossignol M, Ginibre C, Balabanidou V, Mendez NGA et al., Contributions of cuticle permeability and enzyme detoxification to pyrethroid resistance in the major malaria vector Anopheles gambiae. Sci Rep 7:11091 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balabanidou V, Kampouraki A, MacLean M, Blomquist GJ, Tittiger C, Ju&#xe1;rez MP et al., Cytochrome P450 associated with insecticide resistance catalyzes cuticular hydrocarbon production in Anopheles gambiae. Proc Natl Acad Sci 113:9268-9273 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang F, Wang W, Zhang D, Lv Y, Zhou D, Ma L et al., The cuticle proteins: a putative role for deltamethrin resistance in Culex pipiens pallens. Parasitol Res 114:4421-4429 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasai S, Komagata O, Itokawa K, Shono T, Ng LC, Kobayashi M et al., Mechanisms of pyrethroid resistance in the dengue mosquito vector, Aedes aegypti: target site insensitivity, penetration, and metabolism. PLoS Negl Trop Dis 8:e2948 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saingamsook J, Yanola J, Lumjuan N, Walton C and Somboon P, Investigation of relative development and reproductivity fitness cost in three insecticide-resistant strains of Aedes aegypti from Thailand. Insects 10:265 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chareonviriyaphap T, Bangs MJ, Suwonkerd W, Kongmee M, Corbel V and Ngoen-Klan R, Review of insecticide resistance and behavioral avoidance of vectors of human diseases in Thailand. Parasit Vectors 6:280 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plernsub S, Saingamsook J, Yanola J, Lumjuan N, Tippawangkosol P, Walton C et al., Temporal frequency of knockdown resistance mutations, F1534C and V1016G, in Aedes aegypti in Chiang Mai city, Thailand and the impact of the mutations on the efficiency of thermal fogging spray with pyrethroids. Acta Trop 162:125-132 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kongmee M, Thanispong K, Sathantriphop S, Sukkanon C, Bangs MJ and Chareonviriyaphap T, Enhanced mortality in deltamethrin-resistant Aedes aegypti in Thailand using a piperonyl butoxide synergist. Acta Trop 189:76-83 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chareonviriyaphap T, Prabaripai A and Sungvornyothrin S, An improved excito-repellency test chamber for mosquito behavioral tests. J Vector Ecol 27:250-252 (2002).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization (WHO), Test Procedures for Insecticide Resistance Monitoring in Malaria Vector Mosquitoes, 2nd edn. World Health Organization, Geneva, p. 48 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu W-T, Tu W-C, Lin C-H, Yang U-C and Chen C-C, Involvement of cecropin B in the formation of the Aedes aegypti mosquito cuticle. Sci Rep 7:1-17 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schindelin J, Arganda-Carreras I, Frise E, Kaynig V, Longair M, Pietzsch T et al., Fiji: an open-source platform for biological-image analysis. Nat Methods 9:676-682 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kleiber C and Zeileis A, Applied Econometrics with R. Springer-Verlag. Available: https://CRAN.R-project.org/package=AER, New York (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Core Team R, R: A Language and Environment for Statistical Computing. R Foundation for Statistical Computing, Vienna, Austria (2017). Available: https://www.R-project.org/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun Y-P and Johnson E, Quasi-synergism and penetration of insecticides. J Econ Entomol 65:349-353 (1972).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young SJ, Gunning RV and Moores GD, Effect of pretreatment with piperonyl butoxide on pyrethroid efficacy against insecticide-resistant Helicoverpa armigera (Lepidoptera: Noctuidae) and Bemisia tabaci (Sternorrhyncha: Aleyrodidae). Pest Manag Sci 62:114-119 (2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bingham G, Strode C, Tran L, Khoa PT and Jamet HP, Can piperonyl butoxide enhance the efficacy of pyrethroids against pyrethroid-resistant Aedes aegypti? Trop Med Int Health 16:492-500 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization (2017). Conditions for deployment of mosquito nets treated with a pyrethroid and piperonyl butoxide. Available: https://www.who.int/malaria/publications/atoz/use-of-pbo-treated-llins/en/.[18 JUNE 2019]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koudou BG, Koffi AA, Malone D and Hemingway J, Efficacy of PermaNet&#xae; 2.0 and PermaNet&#xae; 3.0 against insecticide-resistant Anopheles gambiae in experimental huts in C&#xf4;te d'Ivoire. Malar J 10:172 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N'Guessan R, Asidi A, Boko P, Odjo A, Akogbeto M, Pigeon O et al., An experimental hut evaluation of PermaNet 3.0, a deltamethrin-piperonyl butoxide combination net, against pyrethroid-resistant Anopheles gambiae and Culex quinquefasciatus mosquitoes in southern Benin. Trans R Soc Trop Med Hyg 104:758-765 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tungu P, Magesa S, Maxwell C, Malima R, Masue D, Sudi W et al., Evaluation of PermaNet 3.0 a deltamethrin-PBO combination net against Anopheles gambiae and pyrethroid resistant Culex quinquefasciatus mosquitoes: an experimental hut trial in Tanzania. Malar J 9:21 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corbel V, Chabi J, Dabir&#xe9; RK, Etang J, Nwane P, Pigeon O et al., Field efficacy of a new mosaic long-lasting mosquito net (PermaNet 3.0) against pyrethroid-resistant malaria vectors: a multi centre study in Western and Central Africa. Malar J 9:113 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adeogun A, Olojede J, Oduola A and Awolola T, Efficacy of a combination long lasting insecticidal net (PermaNet 3.0) against pyrethroid resistant Anopheles gambiae ss. And Culex quinquefasciatus: an experimental hut trial in Nigeria. Niger J Clin Biomed Res 6:37-50 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hemingway J and Ranson H, Insecticide resistance in insect vectors of human disease. Annu Rev Entomol 45:371-391 (2000).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardstone MC, Leichter C, Harrington LC, Kasai S, Tomita T and Scott JG, Cytochrome P450 monooxygenase-mediated permethrin resistance confers limited and larval specific cross-resistance in the southern house mosquito, Culex pipiens quinquefasciatus. Pestic Biochem Physiol 89:175-184 (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasai S, Weerashinghe IS and Shono T, P450 monooxygenases are an important mechanism of permethrin resistance in Culex quinquefasciatus say larvae. Arch Insect Biochem Physiol 37:47-56 (1998).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin Y-H, Tsen W-L, Tien N-Y and Luo Y-P, Biochemical and molecular analyses to determine pyrethroid resistance in Aedes aegypti. Pestic Biochem Physiol 107:266-276 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balabanidou V, Grigoraki L and Vontas J, Insect cuticle: a critical determinant of insecticide resistance. Curr Opin Insect Sci 27:68-74 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonizzoni M, Afrane Y, Dunn WA, Atieli FK, Zhou G, Zhong D et al., Comparative transcriptome analyses of deltamethrin-resistant and-susceptible Anopheles gambiae mosquitoes from Kenya by RNA-Seq. PLoS One 7:e44607 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kefi M, Balabanidou V, Douris V, Lycett G, Feyereisen R and Vontas J, Two functionally distinct CYP4G genes of Anopheles gambiae contribute to cuticular hydrocarbon biosynthesis. Insect Biochem Mol Biol 110:52-59 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones CM, Haji KA, Khatib BO, Bagi J, Mcha J, Devine GJ et al., The dynamics of pyrethroid resistance in anopheles arabiensis from Zanzibar and an assessment of the underlying genetic basis. Parasit Vectors 6:343 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen N, Pei XJ, Li S, Fan YL and Liu TX, Involvement of integument-rich CYP4G19 in hydrocarbon biosynthesis and cuticular penetration resistance in Blattella germanica (L.). Pest Manag Sci 76:215-226 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Che-Mendoza A, Medina-Barreiro A, Koyoc-Carde&#xf1;a E, Uc-Puc V, Contreras-Perera Y, Herrera-Boj&#xf3;rquez J et al., House screening with insecticide-treated netting provides sustained reductions in domestic populations of Aedes aegypti in Merida, Mexico. PLoS Negl Trop Dis 12:e0006283 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Estep AS, Sanscrainte ND, Cuba I, Allen GM, Becnel JJ and Linthicum KJ, Failure of permethrin-treated military uniforms to protect against a laboratory-maintained knockdown-resistant strain of Aedes aegypti. J Am Mosq Control Assoc 36:127-130 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taiwan National Infectious Disease Statistics System [Internet]. Taipei (Taiwan): Taiwan Centers for Disease Control (2021) Available: http://nidss.cdc.gov.tw/en/ [17 JANUARY 2021]</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>