<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">36724496</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>21</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1756-185X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of rheumatic diseases</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Rheum Dis</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Tuberculosis mimicking the onset of systemic lupus erythematosus flare: Case based review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1143</StartPage><EndPage>1148</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1143-1148</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/1756-185X.14585</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="AIM" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To analyze the clinical features of lupus-like tuberculosis (TB).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Three cases of TB imitating systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) flare were collected in our hospital. Based on literature review, there are only 3 reports of TB resembling lupus flare rather than SLE per se.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The 3 cases of lupus mimickers, with a mean age of 30.3&#x2009;years, ranging from 27 to 32&#x2009;years, had atypical features of SLE, namely no typical butterfly erythema, lupus hair, alopecia or proteinuria, similar to the patients reported in the 3 previously mentioned studies. Emergence of different autoantibodies like anti-nuclear antibodies, anti-double-stranded DNA, anti-nucleosome antibodies, and anti-histone antibodies could occur in TB, mostly as an epiphenomenon. In patients with specific serological anti-Sm and hypocomplementemia, active TB cannot be easily ruled out. The presence of autoantibodies neither altered the clinical manifestations and radiographic findings of active TB, nor were detectable after infections are resolved. The resistance of the SLE manifestations to the steroid and immunosuppressive treatment suggests the contribution of an infectious disease.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">TB stimulated the production of autoantibodies, with shared affinity for mycobacteria and human antigens, which may have led to lupus mimickers.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 Asia Pacific League of Associations for Rheumatology and John Wiley &amp; Sons Australia, Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Yang</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4933-7854</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rheumatology and Immunology, Shanxi Bethune Hospital, Shanxi Academy of Medical Sciences, Tongji Shanxi Hospital, Third Hospital of Shanxi Medical University, Taiyuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Tongji Hospital, Tongji Medical College, Huazhong University of Science and Technology, Wuhan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Che</LastName><ForeName>Guozhu</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rheumatology and Immunology, Shanxi Bethune Hospital, Shanxi Academy of Medical Sciences, Tongji Shanxi Hospital, Third Hospital of Shanxi Medical University, Taiyuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Tongji Hospital, Tongji Medical College, Huazhong University of Science and Technology, Wuhan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Ying</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rheumatology and Immunology, Shanxi Bethune Hospital, Shanxi Academy of Medical Sciences, Tongji Shanxi Hospital, Third Hospital of Shanxi Medical University, Taiyuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Tongji Hospital, Tongji Medical College, Huazhong University of Science and Technology, Wuhan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Ke</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rheumatology and Immunology, Shanxi Bethune Hospital, Shanxi Academy of Medical Sciences, Tongji Shanxi Hospital, Third Hospital of Shanxi Medical University, Taiyuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Tongji Hospital, Tongji Medical College, Huazhong University of Science and Technology, Wuhan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>81871292</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>201803D31136</GrantID><Agency>the Key Research and Development (R&amp;D) Projects of Shanxi Province</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Rheum Dis</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101474930</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1756-1841</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000974">Antibodies, Antinuclear</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D001323">Autoantibodies</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000974" MajorTopicYN="N">Antibodies, Antinuclear</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001323" MajorTopicYN="N">Autoantibodies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000067251" MajorTopicYN="N">Symptom Flare Up</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014376" MajorTopicYN="Y">Tuberculosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">autoantibody</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">immunity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mimicker</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">systemic lupus erythematosus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tuberculosis</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36724496</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1756-185X.14585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Calixto OJ, Franco JS, Anaya JM. Lupus mimickers. Autoimmun Rev. 2014;13(8):865-872.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lao M, Chen D, Wu X, et al. Active tuberculosis in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus from southern China: a retrospective study. Clin Rheumatol. 2019;38(2):535-543.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro FM, Szyper-Kravitz M, Klumb EM, et al. Can lupus flares be associated with tuberculosis infection? Clin Rev Allergy Immunol. 2010;38(2-3):163-168.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan EM, Cohen AS, Fries JF, et al. The 1982 revised criteria for the classification of systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Rheum. 1982;25(11):1271-1277.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hochberg MC. Updating the American College of Rheumatology revised criteria for the classification of systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Rheum. 1997;40(9):1725.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petri M, Orbai AM, Alarcon GS, et al. Derivation and validation of the systemic lupus international collaborating clinics classification criteria for systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Rheum. 2012;64(8):2677-2686.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>James MA. Use of the Medical Research Council muscle strength grading system in the upper extremity. J Hand Surg Am. 2007;32(2):154-156.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li JC, Fong W, Wijaya L, Leung YY. Disseminated tuberculosis masquerading as a presentation of systemic lupus erythematosus. Int J Rheum Dis. 2018;21(1):352-355.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ting LY, Shrestha B, Lu YL, Ping F. Post-delivery mycobacterium tuberculosis infection misdiagnosed as systemic lupus erythematosus. J Infect Dev Ctries. 2016;10(12):1352-1356.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen WT, Liu ZC, Li MS, Zhou Y, Liang SJ, Yang Y. Tuberculosis-associated hemophagocytic lymphohistiocytosis misdiagnosed as systemic lupus erythematosus: a case report. World J Clin Cases. 2022;10(10):3178-3187.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ong CWM, Migliori GB, Raviglione M, et al. Epidemic and pandemic viral infections: impact on tuberculosis and the lung: a consensus by the world Association for Infectious Diseases and Immunological Disorders (WAidid), global tuberculosis network (GTN), and members of the European Society of Clinical Microbiology and Infectious Diseases study Group for Mycobacterial Infections (ESGMYC). Eur Respir J. 2020;56(4):2001727.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Senbagavalli P, Geetha ST, Venkatesan P, Ramanathan VD. Defective solubilization of immune complexes and activation of the complement system in patients with pulmonary tuberculosis. J Clin Immunol. 2009;29(5):674-680.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Araujo Z, Gonzalez N, de Cubeddu L, et al. Levels of complement C3 and C4 components in Amerindians living in an area with high prevalence of tuberculosis. Mem Inst Oswaldo Cruz. 2006;101(4):359-364.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hur YG, Kim A, Kang YA, et al. Evaluation of antigen-specific immunoglobulin g responses in pulmonary tuberculosis patients and contacts. J Clin Microbiol. 2015;53(3):904-909.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elkayam O, Caspi D, Lidgi M, Segal R. Auto-antibody profiles in patients with active pulmonary tuberculosis. Int J Tuberc Lung Dis. 2007;11(3):306-310.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katz I, De Luca F, Dzudzor B, et al. Seroprevalences of autoantibodies and anti-infectious antibodies among Ghana's healthy population. Sci Rep. 2020;10(1):2814.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen CY, Hsieh SC, Yu CL, Wang JY, Lee LN, Yu CJ. Autoantibody prevalence in active tuberculosis: reactive or pathognomonic? BMJ Open. 2013;3(7):e002665.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lalvani A, Millington KA. Screening for tuberculosis infection prior to initiation of anti-TNF therapy. Autoimmun Rev. 2008;8(2):147-152.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mamishi S, Pourakbari B, Marjani M, Mahmoudi S. Diagnosis of latent tuberculosis infection among immunodeficient individuals: review of concordance between interferon-gamma release assays and the tuberculin skin test. Br J Biomed Sci. 2014;71(3):115-124.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pai M, Zwerling A, Menzies D. Systematic review: T-cell-based assays for the diagnosis of latent tuberculosis infection: an update. Ann Intern Med. 2008;149(3):177-184.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pai M, Behr M. Latent Mycobacterium tuberculosis infection and interferon-gamma release assays. Microbiol Spectr. 2016;4(5). doi:10.1128/microbiolspec.TBTB2-0023-2016</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edwards A, Gao Y, Allan RN, et al. Corticosteroids and infliximab impair the performance of interferon-gamma release assays used for diagnosis of latent tuberculosis. Thorax. 2017;72(10):946-949.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao X, Da G, Xie X, et al. Tuberculosis in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus-a 37-year longitudinal survey-based study. J Intern Med. 2021;290(1):101-115.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>