<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36737814</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>07</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1479-5876</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>21</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>03</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of translational medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Transl Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Incorporating knowledge of disease-defining hub genes and regulatory network into a machine learning-based model for predicting treatment response in lupus nephritis after the first renal flare.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>76</StartPage><MedlinePgn>76</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">76</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12967-023-03931-z</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Identifying candidates responsive to treatment is important in lupus nephritis (LN) at the renal flare (RF) because an effective treatment can lower the risk of progression to end-stage kidney disease. However, machine learning (ML)-based models that address this issue are lacking.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Transcriptomic profiles based on DNA microarray data were extracted from the GSE32591 and GSE112943 datasets. Comprehensive bioinformatics analyses were performed to identify disease-defining genes (DDGs). Peripheral blood samples (GSE81622, GSE99967, and GSE72326) were used to evaluate the effect of DDGs. Single-sample gene set enrichment analysis (ssGSEA) scores of the DDGs were calculated and correlated with specific immunology genes listed in the nCounter panel. GSE60681 and GSE69438 were used to examine the ability of the DDGs to discriminate LN from other renal diseases. K-means clustering was used to obtain the separate gene sets. The clustering results were extended to data derived using the nCounter technique. The least absolute shrinkage and selection operator (LASSO) algorithm was used to identify genes with high predictive value for treatment response after the first RF in each cluster. LASSO models with tenfold validation were built in GSE200306 and assessed by receiver operating characteristic (ROC) analysis with area under curve (AUC). The models were validated by using an independent dataset (GSE113342).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Forty-five hub genes specific to LN were identified. Eight optimal disease-defining clusters (DDCs) were identified in this study. Th1 and Th2 cell differentiation pathway was significantly enriched in DDC-6. LCK in DDC-6, whose expression positively correlated with various subsets of T cell infiltrations, was found to be differentially expressed between responders and non-responders and was ranked high in regulatory network analysis. Based on DDC-6, the prediction model had the best performance (AUC: 0.75; 95% confidence interval: 0.44-1 in the testing set) and high precision (0.83), recall (0.71), and F1 score (0.77) in the validation dataset.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Our study demonstrates that incorporating knowledge of biological phenotypes into the ML model is feasible for evaluating treatment response after the first RF in LN. This knowledge-based incorporation improves the model's transparency and performance. In addition, LCK may serve as a biomarker for T-cell infiltration and a therapeutic target in LN.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Ding-Jie</ForeName><Initials>DJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Nephrology, Department of Internal Medicine, Tri-Service General Hospital, National Defense Medical Center, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tsai</LastName><ForeName>Ping-Huang</ForeName><Initials>PH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Nephrology, Department of Internal Medicine, Tri-Service General Hospital, National Defense Medical Center, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Chien-Chou</ForeName><Initials>CC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Nephrology, Department of Internal Medicine, Tri-Service General Hospital, National Defense Medical Center, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Tri-Service General Hospital Songshan Branch, National Defense Medical Center, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dai</LastName><ForeName>Yang-Hong</ForeName><Initials>YH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8054-0944</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiation Oncology, Tri-Service General Hospital, National Defense Medical Center, Taipei, Taiwan. he165076373@hotmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Transl Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101190741</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1479-5876</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008181" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lupus Nephritis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007668" MajorTopicYN="N">Kidney</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007676" MajorTopicYN="Y">Kidney Failure, Chronic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000465" MajorTopicYN="N">Algorithms</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000069550" MajorTopicYN="N">Machine Learning</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Lupus nephritis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Machine learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Prediction model</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Renal flare</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Transcriptomics</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>8</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36737814</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9898995</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12967-023-03931-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12967-023-03931-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bajema IM, Wilhelmus S, Alpers CE, Bruijn JA, Colvin RB, Cook HT, D'Agati VD, Ferrario F, Haas M, Jennette JC, et al. Revision of the international society of nephrology/renal pathology society classification for lupus nephritis: clarification of definitions, and modified National Institutes of Health activity and chronicity indices. Kidney Int. 2018;93(4):789&#x2013;796.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29459092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cervera R, Khamashta MA, Font J, Sebastiani GD, Gil A, Lavilla P, Mejia JC, Aydintug AO, Chwalinska-Sadowska H, de Ramon E, et al. Morbidity and mortality in systemic lupus erythematosus during a 10-year period: a comparison of early and late manifestations in a cohort of 1,000 patients. Medicine (Baltimore) 2003;82(5):299&#x2013;308.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14530779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernatsky S, Boivin JF, Joseph L, Manzi S, Ginzler E, Gladman DD, Urowitz M, Fortin PR, Petri M, Barr S, et al. Mortality in systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Rheum. 2006;54(8):2550&#x2013;2557.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16868977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Croca SC, Rodrigues T, Isenberg DA. Assessment of a lupus nephritis cohort over a 30-year period. Rheumatology (Oxford) 2011;50(8):1424&#x2013;1430.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21415024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parikh SV, Almaani S, Brodsky S, Rovin BH. Update on lupus nephritis: core curriculum 2020. Am J Kidney Dis. 2020;76(2):265&#x2013;281.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32220510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Appel GB, Silva FG, Pirani CL, Meltzer JI, Estes D. Renal involvement in systemic lupud erythematosus (SLE): a study of 56 patients emphasizing histologic classification. Medicine (Baltimore) 1978;57(5):371&#x2013;410.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">682942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sprangers B, Monahan M, Appel GB. Diagnosis and treatment of lupus nephritis flares&#x2013;an update. Nat Rev Nephrol. 2012;8(12):709&#x2013;717.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23147758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moroni G, Quaglini S, Maccario M, Banfi G, Ponticelli C. "Nephritic flares" are predictors of bad long-term renal outcome in lupus nephritis. Kidney Int. 1996;50(6):2047&#x2013;2053.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8943489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ioannidis JP, Boki KA, Katsorida ME, Drosos AA, Skopouli FN, Boletis JN, Moutsopoulos HM. Remission, relapse, and re-remission of proliferative lupus nephritis treated with cyclophosphamide. Kidney Int. 2000;57(1):258&#x2013;264.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10620207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson JC, Mahajan A, Scott DA, Gairy K. The economic burden of lupus nephritis: a systematic literature review. Rheumatol Ther. 2022;9(1):25&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8814085</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34731412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Houssiau FA, Ginzler EM. Current treatment of lupus nephritis. Lupus. 2008;17(5):426&#x2013;430.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18490421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parikh SV, Malvar A, Song H, Shapiro J, Mejia-Vilet JM, Ayoub I, Almaani S, Madhavan S, Alberton V, Besso C, et al. Molecular profiling of kidney compartments from serial biopsies differentiate treatment responders from non-responders in lupus nephritis. Kidney Int. 2022;102(4):845&#x2013;865.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9613357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35788359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aragon CC, Tafur RA, Suarez-Avellaneda A, Martinez MT, Salas AL, Tobon GJ. Urinary biomarkers in lupus nephritis. J Transl Autoimmun. 2020;3:100042.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7388339</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32743523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu L, Wang R, Ding H, Tian L, Gao T, Bao C. The utility of urinary biomarker panel in predicting renal pathology and treatment response in Chinese lupus nephritis patients. PLoS ONE. 2020;15(10):e0240942.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7591050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33108403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayoub I, Wolf BJ, Geng L, Song H, Khatiwada A, Tsao BP, Oates JC, Rovin BH. Prediction models of treatment response in lupus nephritis. Kidney Int. 2022;101(2):379&#x2013;389.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8792241</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34871620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radin M, Miraglia P, Barinotti A, Fenoglio R, Roccatello D, Sciascia S. Prognostic and diagnostic values of novel serum and urine biomarkers in lupus nephritis: a systematic review. Am J Nephrol. 2021;52(7):559&#x2013;571.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34515043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mejia-Vilet JM, Parikh SV, Song H, Fadda P, Shapiro JP, Ayoub I, Yu L, Zhang J, Uribe-Uribe N, Rovin BH. Immune gene expression in kidney biopsies of lupus nephritis patients at diagnosis and at renal flare. Nephrol Dial Transplant. 2019;34(7):1197&#x2013;1206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7967887</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29800348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sham PC, Purcell SM. Statistical power and significance testing in large-scale genetic studies. Nat Rev Genet. 2014;15(5):335&#x2013;346.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24739678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guan X, Runger G, Liu L. Dynamic incorporation of prior knowledge from multiple domains in biomarker discovery. BMC Bioinformatics. 2020;21(Suppl 2):77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7068914</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32164534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berthier CC, Bethunaickan R, Gonzalez-Rivera T, Nair V, Ramanujam M, Zhang W, Bottinger EP, Segerer S, Lindenmeyer M, Cohen CD, et al. Cross-species transcriptional network analysis defines shared inflammatory responses in murine and human lupus nephritis. J Immunol. 2012;189(2):988&#x2013;1001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3392438</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22723521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ko WC, Li L, Young TR, McLean-Mandell RE, Deng AC, Vanguri VK, Dresser K, Harris JE. Gene expression profiling in the skin reveals strong similarities between subacute and chronic cutaneous lupus that are distinct from lupus nephritis. J Invest Dermatol. 2021;141(12):2808&#x2013;2819.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34153327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ju W, Nair V, Smith S, Zhu L, Shedden K, Song PXK, Mariani LH, Eichinger FH, Berthier CC, Randolph A, et al. Tissue transcriptome-driven identification of epidermal growth factor as a chronic kidney disease biomarker. Sci Transl Med. 2015;7(316):316ra193.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4861144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26631632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rudnicki M, Perco P, Dhaene B, Leierer J, Heinzel A, Muhlberger I, Schweibert N, Sunzenauer J, Regele H, Kronbichler A, et al. Renal microRNA- and RNA-profiles in progressive chronic kidney disease. Eur J Clin Invest. 2016;46(3):213&#x2013;226.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26707063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koppelstaetter C, Leierer J, Rudnicki M, Kerschbaum J, Kronbichler A, Melk A, Mayer G, Perco P. Computational drug screening identifies compounds targeting renal age-associated molecular profiles. Comput Struct Biotechnol J. 2019;17:843&#x2013;853.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6611921</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31316728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim GB, Kim YA, Seo JH, Lee HJ, Gong G, Park SH. Prediction of prognostic signatures in triple-negative breast cancer based on the differential expression analysis via NanoString nCounter immune panel. BMC Cancer. 2020;20(1):1052.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7607642</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33138797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chin CH, Chen SH, Wu HH, Ho CW, Ko MT, Lin CY. cytoHubba: identifying hub objects and sub-networks from complex interactome. BMC Syst Biol. 2014;8(Suppl 4):S11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4290687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25521941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szklarczyk D, Gable AL, Lyon D, Junge A, Wyder S, Huerta-Cepas J, Simonovic M, Doncheva NT, Morris JH, Bork P, et al. STRING v11: protein-protein association networks with increased coverage, supporting functional discovery in genome-wide experimental datasets. Nucleic Acids Res. 2019;47(D1):D607&#x2013;D613.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6323986</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30476243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jimenez-Sanchez A, Cast O, Miller ML. Comprehensive benchmarking and integration of tumor microenvironment cell estimation methods. Cancer Res. 2019;79(24):6238&#x2013;6246.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31641033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bindea G, Mlecnik B, Tosolini M, Kirilovsky A, Waldner M, Obenauf AC, Angell H, Fredriksen T, Lafontaine L, Berger A, et al. Spatiotemporal dynamics of intratumoral immune cells reveal the immune landscape in human cancer. Immunity. 2013;39(4):782&#x2013;795.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24138885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aran D, Hu Z, Butte AJ. xCell: digitally portraying the tissue cellular heterogeneity landscape. Genome Biol. 2017;18(1):220.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5688663</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29141660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Danaher P, Warren S, Dennis L, D'Amico L, White A, Disis ML, Geller MA, Odunsi K, Beechem J, Fling SP. Gene expression markers of tumor infiltrating leukocytes. J Immunother Cancer. 2017;5:18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5319024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28239471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ronnblom L, Leonard D. Interferon pathway in SLE: one key to unlocking the mystery of the disease. Lupus Sci Med. 2019;6(1):e000270.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6703304</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31497305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakashima H, Akahoshi M, Masutani K. Th1/Th2 balance of SLE patients with lupus nephritis. Rinsho Byori. 2006;54(7):706&#x2013;713.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16913661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu L, Yang X, Ji Y, Chen W, Guan W, Zhou SF, Yu X. Up-regulated renal expression of TNF-alpha signalling adapter proteins in lupus glomerulonephritis. Lupus. 2009;18(2):116&#x2013;127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19151112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banchereau J, Pascual V. Type I interferon in systemic lupus erythematosus and other autoimmune diseases. Immunity. 2006;25(3):383&#x2013;392.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16979570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lech M, Anders HJ. The pathogenesis of lupus nephritis. J Am Soc Nephrol. 2013;24(9):1357&#x2013;1366.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3752952</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23929771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong J, Wang QX, Zhou CY, Ma XF, Zhang YC. Activation of the STAT1 signalling pathway in lupus nephritis in MRL/lpr mice. Lupus. 2007;16(2):101&#x2013;109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17402366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis SE, Khatua AK, Popik W. Nucleosomal dsDNA stimulates APOL1 expression in human cultured podocytes by activating the cGAS/IFI16-STING signaling pathway. Sci Rep. 2019;9(1):15485.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6820523</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31664093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimizu Y, Yasuda S, Kimura T, Nishio S, Kono M, Ohmura K, Shimamura S, Kono M, Fujieda Y, Kato M, et al. Interferon-inducible Mx1 protein is highly expressed in renal tissues from treatment-naive lupus nephritis, but not in those under immunosuppressive treatment. Mod Rheumatol. 2018;28(4):661&#x2013;669.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29189089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsu CL, Ou DL, Bai LY, Chen CW, Lin L, Huang SF, Cheng AL, Jeng YM, Hsu C. Exploring markers of exhausted CD8 T cells to predict response to immune checkpoint inhibitor therapy for hepatocellular carcinoma. Liver Cancer. 2021;10(4):346&#x2013;359.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8339511</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34414122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lima G, Trevino-Tello F, Atisha-Fregoso Y, Llorente L, Fragoso-Loyo H, Jakez-Ocampo J. Exhausted T cells in systemic lupus erythematosus patients in long-standing remission. Clin Exp Immunol. 2021;204(3):285&#x2013;295.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8119791</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33475152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al Taweraqi N, King RD. Improved prediction of gene expression through integrating cell signalling models with machine learning. BMC Bioinformatics. 2022;23(1):323.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9356471</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35933367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Novakovsky G, Dexter N, Libbrecht MW, Wasserman WW, Mostafavi S. Obtaining genetics insights from deep learning via explainable artificial intelligence. Nat Rev Genet. 2022 doi: 10.1038/s41576-022-00532-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41576-022-00532-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36192604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohamad MS, Omatu S, Deris S, Yoshioka M. A modified binary particle swarm optimization for selecting the small subset of informative genes from gene expression data. IEEE Trans Inf Technol Biomed. 2011;15(6):813&#x2013;822.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21914573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vabalas A, Gowen E, Poliakoff E, Casson AJ. Machine learning algorithm validation with a limited sample size. PLoS ONE. 2019;14(11):e0224365.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6837442</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31697686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiong Y, Ling QH, Han F, Liu QH. An efficient gene selection method for microarray data based on LASSO and BPSO. BMC Bioinformatics. 2019;20(Suppl 22):715.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6936154</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31888444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu H, Lien T, Bergholtz H, Fleischer T, Djerroudi L, Vincent-Salomon A, Sorlie T, Aittokallio T. Multi-omics marker analysis enables early prediction of breast tumor progression. Front Genet. 2021;12:670749.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8209521</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34149812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Z, Wang S, Zucknick M, Aittokallio T. Tissue-specific identification of multi-omics features for pan-cancer drug response prediction. iScience. 2022;25(8):104767.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9385562</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35992090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richard AC, Lyons PA, Peters JE, Biasci D, Flint SM, Lee JC, McKinney EF, Siegel RM, Smith KG. Comparison of gene expression microarray data with count-based RNA measurements informs microarray interpretation. BMC Genomics. 2014;15:649.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4143561</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25091430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma J, Yu MK, Fong S, Ono K, Sage E, Demchak B, Sharan R, Ideker T. Using deep learning to model the hierarchical structure and function of a cell. Nat Methods. 2018;15(4):290&#x2013;298.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5882547</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29505029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elmarakeby HA, Hwang J, Arafeh R, Crowdis J, Gang S, Liu D, AlDubayan SH, Salari K, Kregel S, Richter C, et al. Biologically informed deep neural network for prostate cancer discovery. Nature. 2021;598(7880):348&#x2013;352.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8514339</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34552244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katsuyama T, Tsokos GC, Moulton VR. Aberrant T cell signaling and subsets in systemic lupus erythematosus. Front Immunol. 2018;9:1088.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5967272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29868033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar Singh P, Kashyap A, Silakari O. Exploration of the therapeutic aspects of Lck: A kinase target in inflammatory mediated pathological conditions. Biomed Pharmacother. 2018;108:1565&#x2013;1571.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30372858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen PM, Tsokos GC. The role of CD8+ T-cell systemic lupus erythematosus pathogenesis: an update. Curr Opin Rheumatol. 2021;33(6):586&#x2013;591.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8567317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34183542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eftekhari A, Vahed SZ, Kavetskyy T, Rameshrad M, Jafari S, Chodari L, Hosseiniyan SM, Derakhshankhah H, Ahmadian E, Ardalan M. Cell junction proteins: crossing the glomerular filtration barrier in diabetic nephropathy. Int J Biol Macromol. 2020;148:475&#x2013;482.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31962072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ganugula R, Arora M, Zou D, Agarwal SK, Mohan C, Kumar M. A highly potent lymphatic system-targeting nanoparticle cyclosporine prevents glomerulonephritis in mouse model of lupus. Sci Adv. 2020;6(24):eabb3900.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7292630</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32582860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eftekhari A, Maleki Dizaj S, Ahmadian E, Przekora A, Hosseiniyan Khatibi SM, Ardalan M, Zununi Vahed S, Valiyeva M, Mehraliyeva S, Khalilov R, et al. Application of advanced nanomaterials for kidney failure treatment and regeneration. Materials (Basel) 2021;14(11):2939.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8198057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34072461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>