<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36759862</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>13</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1478-6362</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>25</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>09</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Arthritis research &amp; therapy</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Arthritis Res Ther</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Hashimoto's thyroiditis increases the risk of new-onset systemic lupus erythematosus: a nationwide population-based cohort study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>20</StartPage><MedlinePgn>20</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">20</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13075-023-02999-8</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Previous studies have shown systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) patients had a significantly higher prevalence of thyroid diseases and hypothyroidism than matched controls, and some case reports showed SLE may occur after Hashimoto's thyroiditis (HT).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">This study aimed to investigate the subsequent risk of SLE in patients with HT.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">In this retrospective cohort study done by the Taiwan National Health Insurance Research Database, the HT group (exposure group) and the non-HT group (comparator group) were propensity score matched at a ratio of 1:2 by demographic data, comorbidities, medications, and the index date. We used Cox proportional hazards models to estimate hazard ratios (HRs) and 95% confidence intervals (CIs). Several sensitivity analyses were done for cross-validation of our findings.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">We identified 15,512 HT patients and matched 31,024 individuals. The incidence rate ratio of SLE was 3.58 (95% CI, 2.43-5.28; p &lt; 0.01). Several sensitivity analyses show adjusted hazard ratio (aHR) (CIs) of 4.35 (3.28-5.76), 4.39 (3.31-5.82), 5.11 (3.75-6.98), and 4.70 (3.46-6.38), consistent with the results of the main model.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">Our study showed an increased risk of SLE in the HT group after adjustment for baseline characteristics, comorbidities, and medical confounders compared with the reference group.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Lin</LastName><ForeName>Hong-Ci</ForeName><Initials>HC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, Department of Medicine, Chung Shan Medical University, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Chang</LastName><ForeName>Hsu-Min</ForeName><Initials>HM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Education and Research, Kaohsiung Veterans General Hospital, Kaohsiung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hung</LastName><ForeName>Yao-Min</ForeName><Initials>YM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Kaohsiung Municipal United Hospital, Kaohsiung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Health and Nursing, Meiho University, Pingtung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chang</LastName><ForeName>Renin</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Emergency Medicine, Kaohsiung Veterans General Hospital, Kaohsiung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Hsin-Hua</ForeName><Initials>HH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Allergy, Immunology and Rheumatology, Taichung Veterans General Hospital, Taichung, Taiwan. shc5555@hotmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Biomedical Science and Rong Hsing Research Centre for Translational Medicine, Chung Hsing University, Taichung, Taiwan. shc5555@hotmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Industrial Engineering and Enterprise Information, Tunghai University, Taichung, Taiwan. shc5555@hotmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wei</LastName><ForeName>James Cheng-Chung</ForeName><Initials>JC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Allergy, Immunology and Rheumatology, Chung Shan Medical University Hospital, Taichung, Taiwan. wei3228@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Medicine, Chung Shan Medical University Hospital, Taichung, Taiwan. wei3228@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate Institute of Integrated Medicine, China Medical University, Taichung, Taiwan. wei3228@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Arthritis Res Ther</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101154438</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1478-6354</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015331" MajorTopicYN="N">Cohort Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D050031" MajorTopicYN="Y">Hashimoto Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015897" MajorTopicYN="N">Comorbidity</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015994" MajorTopicYN="N">Incidence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013624" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Taiwan</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012307" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hashimoto&#x2019;s thyroiditis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective cohort study</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Systemic lupus erythematosus</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36759862</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9909872</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13075-023-02999-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13075-023-02999-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Fava A, Petri M. Systemic lupus erythematosus: diagnosis and clinical management. J Autoimmun. 2019;96:1&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6310637</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30448290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrari SM, Elia G, Virili C, Centanni M, Antonelli A, Fallahi P. Systemic lupus erythematosus and thyroid autoimmunity. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne) 2017;8:138.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5474463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28674523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gravano DM, Hoyer KK. Promotion and prevention of autoimmune disease by CD8+ T cells. J Autoimmun. 2013;45:68&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23871638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yurasov S, Wardemann H, Hammersen J, Tsuiji M, Meffre E, Pascual V, Nussenzweig MC. Defective B cell tolerance checkpoints in systemic lupus erythematosus. J Exp Med. 2005;201(5):703&#x2013;711.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2212839</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15738055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deapen D, Escalante A, Weinrib L, Horwitz D, Bachman B, Roy-Burman P, Walker A, Mack TM. A revised estimate of twin concordance in systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Rheum. 1992;35(3):311&#x2013;318.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1536669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooper GS, Miller FW, Pandey JP. The role of genetic factors in autoimmune disease: implications for environmental research. Environ Health Perspect. 1999;107(Suppl 5):693&#x2013;700.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1566257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10502533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooper GS, Dooley MA, Treadwell EL, St Clair EW, Parks CG, Gilkeson GS. Hormonal, environmental, and infectious risk factors for developing systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Rheum. 1998;41(10):1714&#x2013;1724.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9778212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cojocaru M, Cojocaru IM, Silosi I. Multiple autoimmune syndrome. Maedica (Bucur) 2010;5(2):132&#x2013;134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3150011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21977137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sloka S. Observations on recent studies showing increased co-occurrence of autoimmune diseases. J Autoimmun. 2002;18(3):251&#x2013;257.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12126638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Vito P, Incerpi S, Pedersen JZ, Luly P, Davis FB, Davis PJ. Thyroid hormones as modulators of immune activities at the cellular level. Thyroid. 2011;21(8):879&#x2013;890.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21745103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rubingh J, van der Spek A, Fliers E, Boelen A. The role of thyroid hormone in the innate and adaptive immune response during infection. Compr Physiol. 2020;10(4):1277&#x2013;1287.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32969509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson MV, Obut TA, Melnikova EV, Trufakin VA. Parameters of cellular and humoral immunity in experimental hyperthyroidism and its correction. Bull Exp Biol Med. 2014;156(4):473&#x2013;475.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24771430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson MV, Obut TA, Mel&#x2019;nikova EV, Trufakin VA. Effects of thyroxin and mercazolyl on immunological parameters of blood lymphocytes and lymphoid organs. Bull Exp Biol Med. 2013;156(2):236&#x2013;238.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24319757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marino F, Guasti L, Cosentino M, De Piazza D, Simoni C, Piantanida E, Cimpanelli M, Klersy C, Bartalena L, Venco A, et al. Thyroid hormone regulation of cell migration and oxidative metabolism in polymorphonuclear leukocytes: clinical evidence in thyroidectomized subjects on thyroxine replacement therapy. Life Sci. 2006;78(10):1071&#x2013;1077.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16154598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ortega E, Forner MA, Garcia JJ, Rodriguez AB, Barriga C. Enhanced chemotaxis of macrophages by strenuous exercise in trained mice: thyroid hormones as possible mediators. Mol Cell Biochem. 1999;201(1-2):41&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10630621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magsino CH, Jr, Hamouda W, Ghanim H, Browne R, Aljada A, Dandona P. Effect of triiodothyronine on reactive oxygen species generation by leukocytes, indices of oxidative damage, and antioxidant reserve. Metabolism. 2000;49(6):799&#x2013;803.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10877210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watad A, Mahroum N, Whitby A, Gertel S, Comaneshter D, Cohen AD, Amital H. Hypothyroidism among SLE patients: case-control study. Autoimmun Rev. 2016;15(5):484&#x2013;486.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26826435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakr A, Laimon W, El-Ziny MA, Hammad A, El-Hawary AK, Elsharkawy AA, El-Refaey AM, Salem NA, El-Mougy A, Zedan MM, et al. The emergence of systemic lupus erythematosus in hypothyroid patients: two case reports and mini review. Lupus. 2014;23(8):825&#x2013;828.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24569395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhir R, Ahluwalia AI, Sridhar J, Mani H, Pruthi HS, Shah KM. Autoimmune thyroiditis perdating the presentation of systemic lupus erythematosus: two cases and a review of literature. Indian J Dermatol Venereol Leprol. 2002;68(5):292&#x2013;294.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17656975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li W, Deng C, Yang H, Wang G. The regulatory T cell in active systemic lupus erythematosus patients: a systemic review and meta-analysis. Front Immunol. 2019;10:159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6387904</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30833946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glick AB, Wodzinski A, Fu P, Levine AD, Wald DN. Impairment of regulatory T-cell function in autoimmune thyroid disease. Thyroid. 2013;23(7):871&#x2013;878.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3704106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23379353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scheinecker C, Bonelli M, Smolen JS. Pathogenetic aspects of systemic lupus erythematosus with an emphasis on regulatory T cells. J Autoimmun. 2010;35(3):269&#x2013;275.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20638240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu Y, Zhang L, Chen H, Liu X, Zheng X, Shi H, Jiang L, Cui D. Analysis of regulatory T cell subsets and their expression of Helios and PD-1 in patients with hashimoto thyroiditis. Int J Endocrinol. 2019;2019:5368473.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6535823</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31214258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miossec P, Kolls JK. Targeting IL-17 and TH17 cells in chronic inflammation. Nat Rev Drug Discov. 2012;11(10):763&#x2013;776.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23023676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tabarkiewicz J, Pogoda K, Karczmarczyk A, Pozarowski P, Giannopoulos K. The role of IL-17 and Th17 lymphocytes in autoimmune diseases. Arch Immunol Ther Exp (Warsz) 2015;63(6):435&#x2013;449.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4633446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26062902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pernis AB. Th17 cells in rheumatoid arthritis and systemic lupus erythematosus. J Intern Med. 2009;265(6):644&#x2013;652.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19493058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li D, Cai W, Gu R, Zhang Y, Zhang H, Tang K, Xu P, Katirai F, Shi W, Wang L, et al. Th17 cell plays a role in the pathogenesis of Hashimoto&#x2019;s thyroiditis in patients. Clin Immunol. 2013;149(3):411&#x2013;420.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24211715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fiducia M, Lauretta R, Lunghi R, Kyanvash S, Pallotti S. Hashimoto&#x2019;s thyroiditis and autoimmunity parameters: descriptive study. Minerva Med. 2007;98(2):95&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17519851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wichainun R, Kasitanon N, Wangkaew S, Hongsongkiat S, Sukitawut W, Louthrenoo W. Sensitivity and specificity of ANA and anti-dsDNA in the diagnosis of systemic lupus erythematosus: a comparison using control sera obtained from healthy individuals and patients with multiple medical problems. Asian Pac J Allergy Immunol. 2013;31(4):292&#x2013;298.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24383972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perrotta C, Buldorini M, Assi E, Cazzato D, De Palma C, Clementi E, Cervia D. The thyroid hormone triiodothyronine controls macrophage maturation and functions: protective role during inflammation. Am J Pathol. 2014;184(1):230&#x2013;247.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24215914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hampton LMT, Finch MG, Martyniuk CJ, Venables BJ, Jeffries MKS. Developmental thyroid disruption causes long-term impacts on immune cell function and transcriptional responses to pathogen in a small fish model. Sci Rep. 2021;11(1):14496.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8280131</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34262125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma C, Xia Y, Yang Q, Zhao Y. The contribution of macrophages to systemic lupus erythematosus. Clin Immunol. 2019;207:1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31255802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#xfc;ndar HZ, Sarkut P, K&#x131;rdak T, Korun N. Primary thyroid lymphoma. Ulus Cerrahi Derg. 2016;32(1):75&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4771433</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26985163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Q, Deng N, Chen S, Cui Y, Du X, Gu Z. Systemic lupus erythematosus is associated with negatively variable impacts on domains of sleep disturbances: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Psychol Health Med. 2018;23(6):685&#x2013;697.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29488396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hannah JR, D&#x2019;Cruz DP. Pulmonary complications of systemic lupus erythematosus. Semin Respir Crit Care Med. 2019;40(2):227&#x2013;234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31137062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torres A, Askari AD, Malemud CJ. Cardiovascular disease complications in systemic lupus erythematosus. Biomark Med. 2009;3(3):239&#x2013;252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20477476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samnaliev M, Barut V, Weir S, Langham J, Langham S, Wang X, Desta B, Hammond E. Health-care utilization and costs in adults with systemic lupus erythematosus in the United Kingdom: a real-world observational retrospective cohort analysis. Rheumatol Adv Pract. 2021;5(3):rkab071.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8493101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34622127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bijl M, Kallenberg CG. Ultraviolet light and cutaneous lupus. Lupus. 2006;15(11):724&#x2013;727.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17153842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zandman-Goddard G, Shoenfeld Y. Infections and SLE. Autoimmunity. 2005;38(7):473&#x2013;485.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16373252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Navarra SV, Leynes MS. Infections in systemic lupus erythematosus. Lupus. 2010;19(12):1419&#x2013;1424.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20947551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tu TY, Yeh CY, Hung YM, Chang R, Chen HH, Wei JC. Association between a history of nontyphoidal Salmonella and the risk of systemic lupus erythematosus: a population-based, case-control study. Front Immunol. 2021;12:725996.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8650632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34887848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun F, Chen Y, Wu W, Guo L, Xu W, Chen J, Sun S, Li J, Chen Z, Gu L, et al. Varicella zoster virus infections increase the risk of disease flares in patients with SLE: a matched cohort study. Lupus Sci Med. 2019;6(1):e000339.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6667776</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31413853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen-Solal JF, Jeganathan V, Hill L, Kawabata D, Rodriguez-Pinto D, Grimaldi C, Diamond B. Hormonal regulation of B-cell function and systemic lupus erythematosus. Lupus. 2008;17(6):528&#x2013;532.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18539705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes GC, Clark EA, Wong AH. The intracellular progesterone receptor regulates CD4+ T cells and T cell-dependent antibody responses. J Leukoc Biol. 2013;93(3):369&#x2013;375.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3579022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23307939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnalich F, Benito-Urbina S, Gonzalez-Gancedo P, Iglesias E, de Miguel E, Gijon-Ba&#xf1;os J. Inadequate production of progesterone in women with systemic lupus erythematosus. Br J Rheumatol. 1992;31(4):247&#x2013;251.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1555040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shahbaz A, Aziz K, Umair M, Sachmechi I. Prolonged duration of hashitoxicosis in a patient with Hashimoto&#x2019;s thyroiditis: a case report and review of literature. Cureus. 2018;10(6):e2804.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6093271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30123726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsing AW, Ioannidis JP. Nationwide population science: lessons from the Taiwan National Health Insurance Research Database. JAMA Intern Med. 2015;175(9):1527&#x2013;1529.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26192815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbhaiya M, Tedeschi SK, Lu B, Malspeis S, Kreps D, Sparks JA, Karlson EW, Costenbader KH. Cigarette smoking and the risk of systemic lupus erythematosus, overall and by anti-double stranded DNA antibody subtype, in the Nurses&#x2019; Health Study cohorts. Ann Rheum Dis. 2018;77(2):196&#x2013;202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5994168</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28988206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung WS, Kung PT, Chang HY, Tsai WC. Demographics and medical disorders associated with smoking: a population-based study. BMC Public Health. 2020;20(1):702.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7227312</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32414354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhong Y, Lu TT, Liu XM, Liu BL, Hu Y, Liu S, Wang J, Li GQ, Mao XM. High levels of thyroid hormone impair regulatory T cell function via reduced PD-1 expression. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2021;106(9):2738&#x2013;2753.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33758937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>