<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36762574</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>28</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1096-9071</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>95</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of medical virology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Med Virol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Disentangling the common genetic architecture and causality of rheumatoid arthritis and systemic lupus erythematosus with COVID-19 outcomes: Genome-wide cross trait analysis and bidirectional Mendelian randomization study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e28570</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e28570</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jmv.28570</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Coronavirus Disease&#xa0;(COVID-19) may cause a dysregulation of the immune system and has complex relationships with multiple autoimmune diseases, including rheumatoid arthritis (RA) and systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE). However, little is known about their common genetic architecture. Using the latest data from COVID-19 host genetics consortium and consortia on RA and SLE, we conducted a genome-wide cross-trait analysis to examine the shared genetic etiology between COVID-19 and RA/SLE and evaluated their causal associations using bidirectional Mendelian randomization (MR). The cross-trait meta-analysis identified 23, 28, and 10 shared genetic loci for severe COVID-19, COVID-19 hospitalization, and SARS-CoV-2 infection with RA, and 14, 17, and 7 shared loci with SLE, respectively. Co-localization analysis identified five causal variants in TYK2, IKZF3, PSORS1C1, and COG6 for COVID-19 with RA, and four in CRHR1, FUT2, and NXPE3 for COVID-19 with SLE, involved in immune function, angiogenesis and coagulation. Bidirectional MR analysis suggested RA is associated with a higher risk of COVID-19 hospitalization, and COVID-19 is not related to RA or SLE. Our novel findings improved the understanding of the genetic etiology shared by COVID-19, RA and SLE, and suggested an increased risk of COVID-19 hospitalization in people with higher genetic liability to RA.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yao</LastName><ForeName>Minhao</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Statistics and Actuarial Science, The University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Xin</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Public Health, Li Ka Shing Faculty of Medicine, The University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guo</LastName><ForeName>Yunshan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Statistics and Actuarial Science, The University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Jie V</ForeName><Initials>JV</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1564-0057</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Public Health, Li Ka Shing Faculty of Medicine, The University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Zhonghua</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3048-9823</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biostatistics, Mailman School of Public Health, Columbia University, New York, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Med Virol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7705876</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0146-6615</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057182" MajorTopicYN="N">Mendelian Randomization Analysis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001172" MajorTopicYN="Y">Arthritis, Rheumatoid</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055106" MajorTopicYN="N">Genome-Wide Association Study</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020641" MajorTopicYN="N">Polymorphism, Single Nucleotide</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">GWAS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mendelian randomization</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cross-trait</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rheumatoid arthritis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">shared genetics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">systemic lupus erythematosus</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36762574</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmv.28570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Mehta P, McAuley DF, Brown M, Sanchez E, Tattersall RS, Manson JJ. COVID-19: consider cytokine storm syndromes and immunosuppression. Lancet. 2020;395(10229):1033-1034.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hejazian SS, Hejazian SM, Farnood F, Abedi Azar S. Dysregulation of immunity in COVID-19 and SLE. Inflammopharmacology. 2022;30(5):1517-1531.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dewanjee S, Kandimalla R, Kalra RS, et al. COVID-19 and rheumatoid arthritis crosstalk: emerging association, therapeutic options and challenges. Cells. 2021;10(12):3291.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ailioaie LM, Ailioaie C, Litscher G. Biomarkers in systemic juvenile idiopathic arthritis, macrophage activation syndrome and their importance in COVID era. Int J Mol Sci. 2022;23(21):12757.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdirakhmanova A, Sazonov V, Mukusheva Z, Assylbekova M, Abdukhakimova D, Poddighe D. Macrophage activation syndrome in pediatric systemic lupus erythematosus: a systematic review of the diagnostic aspects. Front Med. 2021;8:681875.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giamarellos-Bourboulis EJ, Netea MG, Rovina N, et al. Complex immune dysregulation in COVID-19 patients with severe respiratory failure. Cell Host Microbe. 2020;27(6):992-1000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williamson EJ, Walker AJ, Bhaskaran K, et al. Factors associated with COVID-19-related death using OpenSAFELY. Nature. 2020;584:430-436.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye C, Cai S, Shen G, et al. Clinical features of rheumatic patients infected with COVID-19 in Wuhan, China. Ann Rheum Dis. 2020;79(8):1007-1013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandez-Ruiz R, Paredes JL, Niewold TB. COVID-19 in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: lessons learned from the inflammatory disease. Transl Res. 2021;232:13-36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Derksen V, Kissel T, Lamers-Karnebeek FBG, et al. Onset of rheumatoid arthritis after COVID-19: coincidence or connected? Ann Rheum Dis. 2021;80:1096-1098.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawlor DA, Harbord RM, Sterne JAC, Timpson N, Davey Smith G. Mendelian randomization: using genes as instruments for making causal inferences in epidemiology. Stat Med. 2008;27(8):1133-1163.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niemi MEK, Karjalainen J, Liao RG, et al. Mapping the human genetic architecture of COVID-19. Nature. 2021;600(7889):472-477.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okada Y, Wu D, Trynka G, et al. Genetics of rheumatoid arthritis contributes to biology and drug discovery. Nature. 2014;506(7488):376-381.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hom G, Graham RR, Modrek B, et al. Association of Systemic Lupus Erythematosus with C8orf13-BLK and ITGAM-ITGAX. N Engl J Med. 2008;358(9):900-909.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bentham J, Morris DL, Cunninghame Graham DS, et al. Genetic association analyses implicate aberrant regulation of innate and adaptive immunity genes in the pathogenesis of systemic lupus erythematosus. Nature Genet. 2015;47(12):1457-1464.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bulik-Sullivan BK, Loh PR, Finucane HK, et al. LD score regression distinguishes confounding from polygenicity in genome-wide association studies. Nature Genet. 2015;47(3):291-295.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang J, Weedon MN, Purcell S, et al. Genomic inflation factors under polygenic inheritance. Eur J Human Genet. 2011;19(7):807-812.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finucane HK, Bulik-Sullivan B, Gusev A, et al. Partitioning heritability by functional annotation using genome-wide association summary statistics. Nature Genet. 2015;47(11):1228-1235.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turley P, Walters RK, Maghzian O, et al. Multi-trait analysis of genome-wide association summary statistics using MTAG. Nature Genet. 2018;50(2):229-237.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bone WP, Siewert KM, Jha A, et al. Multi-trait association studies discover pleiotropic loci between Alzheimer's disease and cardiometabolic traits. Alzheimers Res Ther. 2021;13(1):34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farh KKH, Marson A, Zhu J, et al. Genetic and epigenetic fine mapping of causal autoimmune disease variants. Nature. 2015;518(7539):337-343.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giambartolomei C, Vukcevic D, Schadt EE, et al. Bayesian test for colocalisation between pairs of genetic association studies using summary statistics. PLoS Genet. 2014;10(5):e1004383.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pei G, Dai Y, Zhao Z, Jia P. deTS: tissue-specific enrichment analysis to decode tissue specificity. Bioinformatics. 2019;35(19):3842-3845.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Duncan D, Shi Z, Zhang B. WEB-based GEne SeT AnaLysis Toolkit (WebGestalt): update 2013. Nucleic Acids Res. 2013;41(Web Server issue):W77-W83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burgess S, Foley CN, Allara E, Staley JR, Howson JMM. A robust and efficient method for Mendelian randomization with hundreds of genetic variants. Nat Commun. 2020;11(1):376.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tavasolian F, Rashidi M, Hatam GR, et al. HLA, immune response, and susceptibility to COVID-19. Front Immunol. 2021;11:601886.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shelton JF, Shastri AJ, Ye C, et al. Trans-ancestry analysis reveals genetic and nongenetic associations with COVID-19 susceptibility and severity. Nature Genet. 2021;53(6):801-808.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pathak GA, Karjalainen J,&#xa0;Stevens C, et al. A first update on mapping the human genetic architecture of COVID-19. Nature. 2022;608(7921):E1-E10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dedmon LE. The genetics of rheumatoid arthritis. Rheumatology. 2020;59(10):2661-70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langton DJ, Bourke SC, Lie BA, et al. The influence of HLA genotype on the severity of COVID-19 infection. Hla. 2021;98(1):14-22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu X, Ho K, Shen Z, et al. The Association of Human Leukocyte Antigen and COVID-19 in Southern China. Open Forum Infect Dis. 2021;8(9):ofab410.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castelli EC, de Castro MV, Naslavsky MS, et al. MHC variants associated with symptomatic versus asymptomatic SARS-CoV-2 infection in highly exposed individuals. Front Immunol. 2021;12:742881.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Arbesu R, Ballina-Garcia FJ, Alperi-Lopez M, et al. MHC class I chain-related gene B (MICB) is associated with rheumatoid arthritis susceptibility. Rheumatology. 2007;46(3):426-430.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z, Rotival M, Patin E, Michel F, Pellegrini S. Two common disease-associated TYK2 variants impact exon splicing and TYK2 dosage. PLoS One. 2020;15(1):e0225289.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dieter C, de Almeida Brondani L, Lemos NE, et al. Polymorphisms in ACE1, TMPRSS2, IFIH1, IFNAR2, and TYK2 genes are associated with worse clinical outcomes in COVID-19. Genes. 2023;14(1):29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Velavan TP, Pallerla SR, R&#xfc;ter J, et al. Host genetic factors determining COVID-19 susceptibility and severity. EBioMedicine. 2021;72:103629.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stikker BS, Stik G, van Ouwerkerk AF, et al. Severe COVID-19-associated variants linked to chemokine receptor gene control in monocytes and macrophages. Genome Biol. 2022;23(1):96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Zhao Q. Expression of CCR3, SOX5 and LC3 in patients with elderly onset rheumatoid arthritis and the clinical significance. Exp Ther Med. 2017;14(4):3573-3576.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Chen Z, Yao X, et al. mRNA expression of chemokine receptors on peripheral blood mononuclear cells and correlation with clinical features in systemic lupus erythematosus patients. Chin Med Sci J. 2010;25(3):162-168.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh E, Matada GSP, Abbas N, Dhiwar PS, Ghara A, Das A. Management of COVID-19-induced cytokine storm by Keap1-Nrf2 system: a review. Inflammopharmacology. 2021;29(5):1347-1355.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohl K, Tenbrock K. Oxidative stress in SLE T cells, is NRF2 really the target to treat? Front Immunol. 2021;12:633845.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Im E. Corticotropin-releasing hormone and its biological diversity toward angiogenesis. Intest Res. 2014;12(2):96-102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siddiqi HK, Libby P, Ridker PM. COVID-19 - A vascular disease. Trends Cardiovascul Med. 2021;31(1):1-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swystun LL, Lillicrap D. Genetic regulation of plasma von Willebrand factor levels in health and disease. J Thromb Haemostasis. 2018;16(12):2375-2390.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valenti L, Villa S, Baselli G, et al. Association of ABO blood group and secretor phenotype with severe COVID-19. Transfusion. 2020;60(12):3067-3070.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langer H, May AE, B&#xfc;ltmann A, Gawaz M. ADAM 15 is an adhesion receptor for platelet GPIIb-IIIa and induces platelet activation. Thromb Haemost. 2005;94(3):555-561.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishimi S, Isozaki T, Wakabayashi K, Takeuchi H, Kasama T. A disintegrin and metalloprotease 15 is expressed on rheumatoid arthritis synovial tissue endothelial cells and May mediate angiogenesis. Cells. 2019;8(1):32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>England BR, Roul P, Yang Y, et al. Risk of COVID-19 in rheumatoid arthritis: a national veterans affairs matched cohort study in at-risk individuals. Arthritis Rheum. 2021;73(12):2179-2188.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Landew&#xe9; RB, Machado PM, Kroon F, et al. EULAR provisional recommendations for the management of rheumatic and musculoskeletal diseases in the context of SARS-CoV-2. Ann Rheum Dis. 2020;79(7):851-858.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geisen UM, Berner DK, Tran F, et al. Immunogenicity and safety of anti-SARS-CoV-2 mRNA vaccines in patients with chronic inflammatory conditions and immunosuppressive therapy in a monocentric cohort. Ann Rheum Dis. 2021;80(10):1306-1311.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>