<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">36781170</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>13</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1521-4141</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>53</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of immunology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Immunol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Bach2 in CD4<sup>+</sup> T cells from SLE patients modulates B-cell differentiation and IgG production.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e2250109</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e2250109</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/eji.202250109</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>T and B cells participate in the development of systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE). BTB and CNC homology 2 (Bach2) is an irreplaceable regulator in the T and B lineages that helps to maintain immune homeostasis. However, the function of Bach2 in the pathogenesis of SLE has not been studied in depth. Flow cytometry and qRT-PCR were used to assess Bach2 levels, bisulfite sequencing PCR was used to measure the methylation level, and silencing by electroporation and stimulation with a cytokine concentration gradient were used to investigate the effect of Bach2 on T cells. Bach2 expression was elevated in the helper T-cell subsets (T follicular helper, Th1, Th2, Th17, and Treg cells) of SLE patients and negatively correlated with disease severity and autoantibody levels. CD4<sup>+</sup> T cells from SLE patients had decreased methylation levels in the Bach2 promoter region. Silencing Bach2 in CD4<sup>+</sup> T cells induced increases in the CD19<sup>+</sup> B-cell count, plasmablasts, and secretion of IgG by prompting the secretion of cytokines. The activation signals CD3/CD28, IL-6, and IL-21 upregulated Bach2 expression in CD4<sup>+</sup> T cells. The regulation of Bach2 by cytokines and T-cell activation signals in CD4<sup>+</sup> T cells was shown to act on B cells and play a protective role against SLE.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 Wiley-VCH GmbH.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Long</LastName><ForeName>Di</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Hunan Key Laboratory of Medical Epigenomics, Second Xiangya Hospital, Central South University, Changsha, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Bingyi</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Hunan Key Laboratory of Medical Epigenomics, Second Xiangya Hospital, Central South University, Changsha, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Ming</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Hunan Key Laboratory of Medical Epigenomics, Second Xiangya Hospital, Central South University, Changsha, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xiong</LastName><ForeName>Feng</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Hunan Key Laboratory of Medical Epigenomics, Second Xiangya Hospital, Central South University, Changsha, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Xuejing</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nephrology, Hunan Key Laboratory of Kidney Disease and Blood Purification, Second Xiangya Hospital, Central South University, Changsha, Hunan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tan</LastName><ForeName>Yixin</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5163-2938</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Hunan Key Laboratory of Medical Epigenomics, Second Xiangya Hospital, Central South University, Changsha, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Haijing</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Hunan Key Laboratory of Medical Epigenomics, Second Xiangya Hospital, Central South University, Changsha, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Immunol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>1273201</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0014-2980</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C491123">BACH2 protein, human</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D050976">Basic-Leucine Zipper Transcription Factors</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D016207">Cytokines</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D007074">Immunoglobulin G</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D050976" MajorTopicYN="N">Basic-Leucine Zipper Transcription Factors</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002454" MajorTopicYN="N">Cell Differentiation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016207" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cytokines</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007074" MajorTopicYN="N">Immunoglobulin G</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016176" MajorTopicYN="N">T-Lymphocyte Subsets</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D050378" MajorTopicYN="N">T-Lymphocytes, Regulatory</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015496" MajorTopicYN="N">CD4-Positive T-Lymphocytes</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001402" MajorTopicYN="N">B-Lymphocytes</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bach2 &#x22c5; B cells &#x22c5; helper T (Th) cell &#x22c5; IgG &#x22c5; SLE</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36781170</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/eji.202250109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Fava, A. and Petri, M., Systemic lupus erythematosus: diagnosis and clinical management. J. Autoimmun. 2019. 96: 1-13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, H., Zeng, J., Yin, J., Peng, Q., Zhao, M. and Lu, Q., Organ-specific biomarkers in lupus. Autoimmun. Rev. 2017. 16: 391-397.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan, L., Lu, M. P., Wang, J. H., Xu, M. and Yang, S. R., Immunological pathogenesis and treatment of systemic lupus erythematosus. World J. Pediatr. 2020. 16: 19-30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, M., Long, D., Hu, L., Zhao, Z., Li, Q., Guo, Y., He, Z. et&#xa0;al., AIM2 deficiency in B cells ameliorates systemic lupus erythematosus by regulating Blimp-1-Bcl-6 axis-mediated B-cell differentiation. Signal Transduct. Target Ther. 2021. 6: 341.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, H., Deng, Y., Long, D., Yang, M., Li, Q., Feng, Y., Chen, Y. et&#xa0;al., The IL-21-TET2-AIM2-c-MAF pathway drives the T follicular helper cell response in lupus-like disease. Clin. Transl. Med. 2022. 12: e781.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohan, C., Adams, S., Stanik, V. and Datta, S. K., Nucleosome: a major immunogen for pathogenic autoantibody-inducing T cells of lupus. J. Exp. Med. 1993. 177: 1367-1381.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, Y., Wu, H., Zhao, M., Chang, C. and Lu, Q., The Bach family of transcription factors: a comprehensive review. Clin. Rev. Allergy Immunol. 2016. 50: 345-356.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richer, M. J., Lang, M. L. and Butler, N. S., T cell fates zipped up: how the Bach2 basic leucine zipper transcriptional repressor directs T cell differentiation and function. J. Immunol. 2016. 197: 1009-1015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Igarashi, K., Ochiai, K., Itoh-Nakadai, A. and Muto, A., Orchestration of plasma cell differentiation by Bach2 and its gene regulatory network. Immunol. Rev. 2014. 261: 116-125.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muto, A., Hoshino, H., Madisen, L., Yanai, N., Obinata, M., Karasuyama, H., Hayashi, N. et&#xa0;al., Identification of Bach2 as a B-cell-specific partner for small maf proteins that negatively regulate the immunoglobulin heavy chain gene 3' enhancer. EMBO J. 1998. 17: 5734-5743.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roychoudhuri, R., Hirahara, K., Mousavi, K., Clever, D., Klebanoff, C. A., Bonelli, M., Sciume, G. et&#xa0;al., BACH2 represses effector programs to stabilize T(reg)-mediated immune homeostasis. Nature 2013. 498: 506-510.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roychoudhuri, R., Clever, D., Li, P., Wakabayashi, Y., Quinn, K. M., Klebanoff, C. A., Ji, Y. et&#xa0;al., BACH2 regulates CD8(+) T cell differentiation by controlling access of AP-1 factors to enhancers. Nat. Immunol. 2016. 17: 851-860.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geng, J., Wei, H., Shi, B., Wang, Y. H., Greer, B. D., Pittman, M., Smith, E. et&#xa0;al., Bach2 negatively regulates T follicular helper cell differentiation and is critical for CD4(+) T cell memory. J. Immunol. 2019. 202: 2991-2998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jang, E., Kim, U. K., Jang, K., Song, Y. S., Cha, J. Y., Yi, H. and Youn, J., Bach2 deficiency leads autoreactive B cells to produce IgG autoantibodies and induce lupus through a T cell-dependent extrafollicular pathway. Exp. Mol. Med. 2019. 51: 1-13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lahmann, A., Kuhrau, J., Fuhrmann, F., Heinrich, F., Bauer, L., Durek, P., Mashreghi, M. F. et&#xa0;al., Bach2 controls T follicular helper cells by direct repression of Bcl-6. J. Immunol. 2019. 202: 2229-2239.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu, X., Lao, Y., Teng, X. L., Li, S., Zhou, Y., Wang, F., Guo, X. et&#xa0;al., SENP3 maintains the stability and function of regulatory T cells via BACH2 deSUMOylation. Nat. Commun. 2018. 9: 3157.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, M., Iwata, S., Hajime, M., Ohkubo, N., Todoroki, Y., Miyata, H., Ueno, M. et&#xa0;al., Methionine commits cells to differentiate into plasmablasts through epigenetic regulation of BTB and CNC homolog 2 by the methyltransferase EZH2. Arthritis Rheum. 2020. 72: 1143-1153.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng, Y., Lu, Y., Huang, X., Han, L., Chen, Z., Zhou, B., Ma, Y. et&#xa0;al., BACH2 regulates the function of human CD4(+) CD45RA(&#x2212;) Foxp3(l) degrees cytokine-secreting T cells and promotes B-cell response in systemic lupus erythematosus. Eur. J. Immunol. 2020. 50: 426-438.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, H., Hu, Q., Zhang, M., Yang, F., Peng, C., Zhang, Z. and Huang, C., Bach2 deficiency leads to spontaneous expansion of IL-4-producing T follicular helper cells and autoimmunity. Front. Immunol. 2019. 10: 2050.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sidwell, T., Liao, Y., Garnham, A. L., Vasanthakumar, A., Gloury, R., Blume, J., Teh, P. P. et&#xa0;al., Attenuation of TCR-induced transcription by Bach2 controls regulatory T cell differentiation and homeostasis. Nat. Commun. 2020. 11: 252.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roychoudhuri, R., Eil, R. L., Clever, D., Klebanoff, C. A., Sukumar, M., Grant, F. M., Yu, Z. et&#xa0;al., The transcription factor BACH2 promotes tumor immunosuppression. J. Clin. Invest. 2016. 126: 599-604.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuchen, S., Robbins, R., Sims, G. P., Sheng, C., Phillips, T. M., Lipsky, P. E. and Ettinger, R., Essential role of IL-21 in B cell activation, expansion, and plasma cell generation during CD4+ T cell-B cell collaboration. J. Immunol. 2007. 179: 5886-5896.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bryant, V. L., Ma, C. S., Avery, D. T., Li, Y., Good, K. L., Corcoran, L. M., de Waal Malefyt, R. et&#xa0;al., Cytokine-mediated regulation of human B cell differentiation into Ig-secreting cells: predominant role of IL-21 produced by CXCR5+ T follicular helper cells. J. Immunol. 2007. 179: 8180-8190.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore, K. W., de Waal Malefyt, R., Coffman, R. L. and O'Garra, A., Interleukin-10 and the interleukin-10 receptor. Annu. Rev. Immunol. 2001. 19: 683-765.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu, C., Gershwin, M. E. and Chang, C., Diagnostic criteria for systemic lupus erythematosus: a critical review. J. Autoimmun. 2014. 48-49: 10-13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yaniv, G., Twig, G., Shor, D. B., Furer, A., Sherer, Y., Mozes, O., Komisar, O. et&#xa0;al., A volcanic explosion of autoantibodies in systemic lupus erythematosus: a diversity of 180 different antibodies found in SLE patients. Autoimmun. Rev. 2015. 14: 75-79.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehra, S. and Fritzler, M. J., The spectrum of anti-chromatin/nucleosome autoantibodies: independent and interdependent biomarkers of disease. J. Immunol. Res. 2014. 2014: 368274.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruns, A., Blass, S., Hausdorf, G., Burmester, G. R. and Hiepe, F., Nucleosomes are major T and B cell autoantigens in systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Rheum. 2000. 43: 2307-2315.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cozzani, E., Drosera, M., Gasparini, G. and Parodi, A., Serology of lupus erythematosus: correlation between immunopathological features and clinical aspects. Autoimmune Dis. 2014. 2014: 321359.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Afzali, B., Gronholm, J., Vandrovcova, J., O'Brien, C., Sun, H. W., Vanderleyden, I., Davis, F. P. et&#xa0;al., BACH2 immunodeficiency illustrates an association between super-enhancers and haploinsufficiency. Nat. Immunol. 2017. 18: 813-823.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuwahara, M., Suzuki, J., Tofukuji, S., Yamada, T., Kanoh, M., Matsumoto, A., Maruyama, S. et&#xa0;al., The Menin-Bach2 axis is critical for regulating CD4 T-cell senescence and cytokine homeostasis. Nat. Commun. 2014. 5: 3555.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, H., Dai, D., Hu, Q., Yang, F., Xue, Y., Li, F., Shen, N. et&#xa0;al., Bach2 attenuates IL-2R signaling to control Treg homeostasis and Tfr development. Cell Rep. 2021. 35: 109096.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edwards, C. L., de Oca, M. M., de Labastida Rivera, F., Kumar, R., Ng, S. S., Wang, Y., Amante, F. H. et&#xa0;al., The role of BACH2 in T cells in experimental malaria caused by Plasmodium chabaudi chabaudi AS. Front. Immunol. 2018. 9: 2578.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, L., Chen, S., Zhao, Q., Sun, Y. and Nie, H., The critical role of Bach2 in shaping the balance between CD4(+) T cell subsets in immune-mediated diseases. Mediators Inflamm. 2019. 2019: 2609737.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caielli, S., Veiga, D. T., Balasubramanian, P., Athale, S., Domic, B., Murat, E., Banchereau, R. et&#xa0;al., A CD4(+) T cell population expanded in lupus blood provides B cell help through interleukin-10 and succinate. Nat. Med. 2019. 25: 75-81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Talaat, R. M., Mohamed, S. F., Bassyouni, I. H. and Raouf, A. A., Th1/Th2/Th17/Treg cytokine imbalance in systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) patients: correlation with disease activity. Cytokine 2015. 72: 146-153.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quan, W., An, J., Li, G., Qian, G., Jin, M., Feng, C., Li, S. et&#xa0;al., Th cytokine profile in childhood-onset systemic lupus erythematosus. BMC Pediatr. 2021. 21: 187.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Godsell, J., Rudloff, I., Kandane-Rathnayake, R., Hoi, A., Nold, M. F., Morand, E. F. and Harris, J., Clinical associations of IL-10 and IL-37 in systemic lupus erythematosus. Sci. Rep. 2016. 6: 34604.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geginat, J., Vasco, M., Gerosa, M., Tas, S. W., Pagani, M., Grassi, F., Flavell, R. A. et&#xa0;al., IL-10 producing regulatory and helper T-cells in systemic lupus erythematosus. Semin. Immunol. 2019. 44: 101330.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>