<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">36781038</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>24</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1873-0183</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>22</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Autoimmunity reviews</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Autoimmun Rev</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Development of systemic lupus erythematosus in patients with immune thrombocytopenic purpura: A systematic meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>103297</StartPage><MedlinePgn>103297</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.autrev.2023.103297</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S1568-9972(23)00031-9</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Recent population-based cohort studies suggest that the incidence of systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) is increased in patients with immune thrombocytopenic purpura (ITP). We performed a systematic review and meta-analysis to evaluate the development of SLE in patients with ITP.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Literature search was performed in PubMed, Web of Science and Cochrane Library for studies published prior to October 2022. Studies were included that reported development of SLE in ITP patients. Forest plot was used to detect overall SLE frequency in ITP and compare risk ratios for SLE development in different ITP subgroups. Study heterogeneity was assessed by using I<sup>2</sup> statistics.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">26 eligible studies comprising 14867 ITP patients were included in analysis. 311 ITP patients developed SLE during the follow-up period (range: 1.1-14&#xa0;years) (2.09%, 95%CI: 1.87-2.33). Relative risk (RR) for developing SLE was significantly higher in female ITP patients (RR: 4.23, 95%CI: 2.52-7.12, p&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;0.0001). Anti-nuclear antibody (ANA) was reported in 23 studies, there were 766/4377 ANA positive patients with ITP (17.5%). The risk of SLE development in ANA positive ITP patients was significant (RR: 26.29, 95%CI: 14.45-47.81, p&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;0.0001).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Our study suggests ITP patients are at high risk of developing SLE in future. Pooled data revealed that females and patients with a positive ANA titer are at a significantly high risk of developing SLE.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pamuk</LastName><ForeName>Omer Nuri</ForeName><Initials>ON</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Rheumatology, University Hospitals/Case Western Reserve University, 11100 Euclid Ave, Cleveland, OH, 44106, USA; Rheumatology Fellowship and Training Branch, NIAMS, NIH, Bethesda, MD, USA. Electronic address: omer.pamuk@uhhospitals.org.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ali</LastName><ForeName>Saja Mustafa</ForeName><Initials>SM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rheumatology Fellowship and Training Branch, NIAMS, NIH, Bethesda, MD, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hasni</LastName><ForeName>Sarfaraz</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Lupus Clinical Trials Unit, NIAMS, NIH, Bethesda, MD, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>ZIA AR041232</GrantID><Acronym>ImNIH</Acronym><Agency>Intramural NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>11</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Autoimmun Rev</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101128967</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1568-9972</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000974">Antibodies, Antinuclear</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000974" MajorTopicYN="N">Antibodies, Antinuclear</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015994" MajorTopicYN="N">Incidence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016553" MajorTopicYN="Y">Purpura, Thrombocytopenic, Idiopathic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Anti-nuclear antibody</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Immune thrombocytopenia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Systematic review</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Systemic lupus erythematosus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">meta-analysis</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of Competing Interest The authors declare the following financial interests/personal relationships which may be considered as potential competing interests: Sarfaraz Hasni reports a relationship with National Institute of Arthritis and Musculoskeletal and Skin Diseases that includes: employment.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36781038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS1877970</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10078978</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.autrev.2023.103297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S1568-9972(23)00031-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Wei Y, Hou M. T cells in the pathogenesis of immune thrombocytopenia. Semin Hematol 2016; 53(suppl 1):S13&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27312155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Audia S, Mahevas M, Samson M, Godeau B, Bonnotte B. Pathogenesis of immune thrombocytopenia. Autoimmune Rev 2017;16:620&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28428120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fanouriakis A, Bertsias G, Boumpas DT. Population-based studies in systemic lupus erythematosus: immune thrombocytopenic purpura or &#x2018;blood-dominant&#x2019; lupus? Ann Rheum Dis 2020;79:683&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32312772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linge P, Fortin PR, Lood C, Bengtsson Boilard E. The non-haemostatic role of platelets in systemic lupus erythematosus. Nat Rev Rheumatol 2018;14:195&#x2013;213.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29559714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu FX, Huang JY, Ye Z, Wen QQ, Wei JCC. Risk of systemic lupus erythematosus in patients with idiopathic thrombocytopenic purpura: a population-based cohort study. Ann Rheum Dis 2020;79:793&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32241798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao H, Li S, Yang R. Thrombocytopenia in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: significant in the clinical implication and prognosis. Platelets 2010;21:380&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20433308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ziakas PD, Giannouli S, Zintzaras E, Tzioufas AG, Voulgarelis M. Lupus thrombocytopenia: clinical implications and prognostic significance. Ann Rheum Dis 2005;64:1366&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1755663</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16100344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maquet J, Lafaurie M, Lapeyre-Mestre M. Correspondance on &#x2018;Risk of systemic lupus erythematosus after immune thrombocytopenia and autoimmune haemolytic anemia: a nationwide French study&#x2019; Ann Rheum Dis 2020;0:1&#x2013;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33310730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y, Chen S, Yang G, Wang B, Lan J, Dai F, et al. ANA-positive primary immune thrombocytopenia: a different clinical entity with increased risk of connective tissue diseases. Lupus Sci Med 2021;8:e000523.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8493907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34610996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liberati A, Altman DG, Tetzlaff J, Mulrow C, Gotzsche PC, Ioannidis JP, et al. The PRISMA statement for reporting systematic reviews and meta-analyses of studies that evaluate healthcare interventions: explanation and elaboration. Br Med J 2009;339:b2700.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2714672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19622552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hochberg MC. Updating the American College of rheumatology revised criteria for the classification of systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Rheum 1997;40:1725.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9324032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson MJ, Peebles CL, McMillan R, Curd JG. Fluorescent antinuclear antibodies and anti-SS-A/Ro in patients with immune thrombocytopenia subsequently developing systemic lupus erythematosus. Ann Intern Med 1985;103:548&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3898952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perez HD, Katler E, Embury S. Idiopathic thrombocytopenic purpura with high-titer, speckled pattern antinuclear antibodies: possible marker for systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Rheum 1985;28:596&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3873946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panzer S, Penner E, GRaninger W, Schulz E, Smolen JS. Antinuclear antibodies in patients with chronic idiopathic autoimmune thrombocytopenia followed 2&#x2013;30 years. Am J Hematol 1989;32:100&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2787955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adachi M, Mita S, Obana M, Matsuoka Y, Harada K, Irimajiri S. Thrombocytopenia subsequently develops systemic lupus erythematosus &#x2013;Can anti-SS-A antibody predict the next event? Jpn J Med 1990;29:481&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2089172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurata Y, Miyagawa S, Kosugi S, Kashiwagi H, Honda S, Mizutani H, et al. High-titer antinuclear antibodies, anti-SSA/Ro antibodies and anti-nuclear RNP antibodies in patients with idiopathic thrombocytopenic purpura. Thromb Haemost. 1994;71:184&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8191396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stasi R, Stipa E, Masi M, Oliva F, Sciarra A, Perrotti A, et al. Prevalence and clinical significance of elevated antiphospholipid antibodies in patients with idiopathic thrombocytopenic purpura. Blood 1994;84:4203&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7994034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mestanza-Peralta M, Ariza-Ariza R, Cardiel MH, Alcocer-Varela J. Thrombocytopenic purpura as initial manifestation of systemic lupus erythematosus. J Rheumatol 1997;24:867&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9150074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zimmerman SA, Ware RE. Clinical significance of the antinuclear antibody test in selected children with idiopathic thrombocytopenic purpura. J Pediatr Hematol Oncol 1997;19:297&#x2013;303.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9256827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vantelon JM, Godeau B, Andre C, Bierling P. Screening for autoimmune markers is unnecessary during follow-up of adults with autoimmune thrombocytopenic purpura and no autoimmune markers at onset. Thromb Haemast 2000;83:42&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10669152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leung AYH, Chim CS, Kwong YL, Lie AKW, An WY, Liang R. Clinicopathologic and prognostic features of chronic idiopathic thrombocytopenic purpura in adult Chinese patients: ANA analysis of 220 cases. Ann Hematol 2001;80:384&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11529462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pamuk GE, Pamuk ON, Baslar Z, Ongoren S, Soysal T, Ferhanoglu B, et al. Overview of 321 patients with idiopathic thrombocytopenic purpura: retrospective analysis of the clinical features and response to therapy. Ann Hematol 2002:81:436&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12224000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li HG, Zhang L, Zhao H, Ji LX, Yang R. Chronic idiopathic thrombocytopenic purpura in adult Chinese patients: a retrospective single-centered analysis of 1791 cases. Chin Med J 2005;118:36&#x2013;37</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15642223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hazzan R, Mukamel M, Yacobovich J, Yaniv I, Tamary H. Risk factors for future development of systemic lupus erythematosus in children with idiopathic thrombocytopenic purpura. Pediatr Blood Cancer 2006;47:657&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16933242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altintas A, Ozel A, Okur N, Okur N, Cil T, Pasa S, et al. Prevalence and clinical significance of elavted antinuclear antibody test in children and adult patients with idiopathic thrombocytopenic purpura. J Thromb Thrombolysis 2007;24:163&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17436144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abbasi SY, Milhem M, Zaru L. A positive antinuclear antibody test predicts for a poor response to initial steroid therapy in adults with idiopathic thrombocytopenic purpura. Ann Hematol 2008;87:459&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18265983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaman A, Gaman G, Rotaru I. The antiphospholipid antibodies, a risk factor to developed antiphospholipide syndrome or systemic lupus Erythematous in the patients with immune thrombocytopenic purpura (ITP). Haematologica 2013;98:742.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koylu A, Pamuk GE, Uyanik MS, Demir M, Pamuk ON. Immune thrombocytopenia: epidemiological and clinical features of 216 patients in northwestern Turkey. Ann Hematol 2015;94:459&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25238800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayesh M, Alawneh K, Khader Y. Risk of lupus after primary immune thrombocytopenic purpura: a 14 year single center experience. Haematologica 2017;102:840&#x2013;1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moulis G, Gemain J, Comont T, Brun N, Dingremont C, Castel B, Arista S, et al. Newly diagnosed immune thrombocytopenia adults: clinical epidemiology, exposure to treatments, and evolution. Results of the CARMEN multicenter prospective cohort. Am J Hematol 2017;92:493&#x2013;500.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28240787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saettini F, Cattoni A, Redaelli M, Silvestri D, Ferrari GM, Biondi A, et al. Primary immunodeficiencies, autoimmune hyperthyroidism, coeliac disease and systemic lupus erythematosus in childhood immune thrombocytopenia. Acta Pediatrica 2021;110:643&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33025591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kittivisuit S, Vachvanichsanong P, McNell E, Chotsampancharoen T. Childhood-onset systemic lupus erythematosus and immune thrombocytopenia: Prevalence and risk factors. Pediatr Blood Cancer 2021;68:e29146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34047041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahn SM, Choi EJ, Oh JS, Kim YG, Lee CK, Yoo B, Hong S. Prognostic factors for the development of systemic lupus erythematosus in patients with immune thrombocytopenia. Arthritis Res Ther 2022;24:213.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9446556</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36068638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alle G, Scolnik M, Scaglioni V, Gallego JFJ, Jaramillo MAT, Alvarado R, et al. Immune thrombocytopenic purpura and subsequent development of systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Rheumatol 2022;74(Suppl):2872&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsokos GC. Autoimmunity and organ damage in systemic lupus erythematosus. Nature Immunol 2020;21:605&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8135909</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32367037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramezankhani R, Minaei N, Haddadi M, Solhi R, Taleahmad S. The impact of sex on susceptibility to systemic lupus erythematosus and rheumatoid arthritis; a bioinformatics point of view. Cell Sig 2021;88:110171.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34662716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nhek S, Clancy R, Lee KA, Allen NM, Barrett T, Marcantoni E, et al. Activated platelets induce endothelial cell activation via an interleukin-1B pathway in systemic lupus erythematosus. Arterioscler Thromb Vasc Biol 2017;37:707&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5597960</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28153882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang Y, Cheng Y, Ma S, Li T, Chen Z, Zuo X, Zhang X. Systemic lupus erythematosus-complicating immune thrombocytopenia: from pathogenesis to treatment. J Autoimmunity 2022. Aug 24;102887.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36030136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>