<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36806905</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>04</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1756-185X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of rheumatic diseases</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Rheum Dis</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Purtscher-like retinopathy associated with systemic lupus erythematosus treated with rituximab plus low-dose interleukin-2: A case report.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1373</StartPage><EndPage>1376</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1373-1376</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/1756-185X.14623</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Purtscher-like retinopathy, an occlusive microvasculopathy, is a rare and severe ophthalmic complication of systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) characterized by a sudden loss of vision with retinal whitening, cotton wool spots and minimal intraretinal hemorrhage. Recovery in visual acuity is usually poor even with prompt treatment. This case showed a patient with SLE concurrent Purtscher-like retinopathy treated with rituximab and interleukin-2 (IL-2) with good prognosis. A 16-year-old female with a 2-year history of SLE was admitted because of&#xa0;unrelieved&#xa0;disease&#xa0;activity&#xa0;of&#xa0;SLE when treated with a high dose of corticosteroids and immunosuppressants and she further suffered from reduced visual acuity in both eyes. She was diagnosed with Purtscher-like retinopathy secondary to SLE after ocular examination. Rituximab and low-dose IL-2 for systemic treatment and intravitreal injection of anti-vascular endothelial growth factor antibody to right eye were given. The SLE disease was completely relieved with the sight recovering and no recurrence of Purtscher-like retinopathy was reported during 6-year follow-up. Purtscher-like retinopathy associated with SLE should be treated early and promptly. Rituximab should be considered in SLE patients with Purtscher-like retinopathy who have an incomplete response to initial immunosuppressive therapy and low-dose IL-2 may help induction of clinical remission.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 Asia Pacific League of Associations for Rheumatology and John Wiley &amp; Sons Australia, Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Min</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1687-8227</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rheumatology and Immunology, Peking University People's Hospital, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jin</LastName><ForeName>Yuebo</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3379-8998</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rheumatology and Immunology, Peking University People's Hospital, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>He</LastName><ForeName>Jing</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3904-8928</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rheumatology and Immunology, Peking University People's Hospital, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>82071813</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>82171772</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Rheum Dis</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101474930</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1756-1841</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>4F4X42SYQ6</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000069283">Rituximab</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D007376">Interleukin-2</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000069283" MajorTopicYN="N">Rituximab</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007376" MajorTopicYN="N">Interleukin-2</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012164" MajorTopicYN="Y">Retinal Diseases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014786" MajorTopicYN="N">Vision Disorders</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Purtscher-like retinopathy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">low-dose interleukin-2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rituximab</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">systemic lupus erythematosus</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36806905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1756-185X.14623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Otte A, Weiner SM. Systemic lupus erythematosus. Lancet. 2001;358(9281):585.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dammacco R. Systemic lupus erythematosus and ocular involvement: an overview. Clin Exp Med. 2018;18(2):135-149.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tripathy K, Patel BC. Purtscher retinopathy. StatPearls. StatPearls Publishing; 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu C, Dai R, Dong F, Wang Q. Purtscher-like retinopathy in systemic lupus erythematosus. Am J Ophthalmol. 2014;158(6):1335-1341.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agrawal A, McKibbin MA. Purtscher's and Purtscher-like retinopathies: a review. Surv Ophthalmol. 2006;51(2):129-136.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies JB, Rao PK. Ocular manifestations of systemic lupus erythematosus. Curr Opin Ophthalmol. 2008;19(6):512-518.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stafford-Brady FJ, Urowitz MB, Gladman DD, Easterbrook M. Lupus retinopathy. Patterns, associations, and prognosis. Arthritis Rheum. 1988;31(9):1105-1110.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Au A, O'Day J. Review of severe vaso-occlusive retinopathy in systemic lupus erythematosus and the antiphospholipid syndrome: associations, visual outcomes, complications and treatment. Clin Exp Ophthalmol. 2004;32(1):87-100.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miguel AI, Henriques F, Azevedo LF, Loureiro AJ, Maberley DA. Systematic review of Purtscher's and Purtscher-like retinopathies. Eye (Lond). 2013;27(1):1-13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kunavisarut P, Pathanapitoon K, Rothova A. Purtscher-like retinopathy associated with systemic Lupus erythematosus. Ocul Immunol Inflamm. 2016;24(1):60-68.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alahmadi RM, Hashim RT, Almogairin SM, Abu AM. Purtscher-like retinopathy as a first presentation of systematic lupus erythematosus. Ann Saudi Med. 2016;36(1):85-88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jabs DA, Fine SL, Hochberg MC, Al E. Severe retinal vaso-occlusive disease in systemic lupus erythematosus. Arch Ophthalmol. 1986;104(4):558-563.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sellami D, Ben ZZ, Jelliti B, Abid D, Feki J, Chaabouni M. Purtscher-like retinopathy in systemic lupus erythematosus. Two cases. J Fr Ophtalmol. 2002;25(1):52-55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hickman RA, Denniston AK, Yee CS, Toescu V, Murray PI, Gordon C. Bilateral retinal vasculitis in a patient with systemic lupus erythematosus and its remission with rituximab therapy. Lupus. 2010;19(3):327-329.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damato E, Chilov M, Lee R, Singh A, Harper S, Dick A. Plasma exchange and rituximab in the management of acute occlusive retinal vasculopathy secondary to systemic lupus erythematosus. Ocul Immunol Inflamm. 2011;19(5):379-381.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tselios K, Lam WC, Urowitz MB, Gladman DD. Rituximab for sight-threatening Lupus-related retinal Vasculitis. J Clin Rheumatol. 2018;24(2):93-94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohl K, Tenbrock K. Regulatory T cells in systemic lupus erythematosus. Eur J Immunol. 2015;45(2):344-355.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Humrich JY, Morbach H, Undeutsch R, et al. Homeostatic imbalance of regulatory and effector T cells due to IL-2 deprivation amplifies murine lupus. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2010;107(1):204-209.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He J, Zhang R, Shao M, et al. Efficacy and safety of low-dose IL-2 in the treatment of systemic lupus erythematosus: a randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Ann Rheum Dis. 2020;79(1):141-149.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Humrich JY, von Spee-Mayer C, Siegert E, et al. Rapid induction of clinical remission by low-dose interleukin-2 in a patient with refractory SLE. Ann Rheum Dis. 2015;74(4):791-792.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He J, Zhang X, Wei Y, et al. Low-dose interleukin-2 treatment selectively modulates CD4(+) T cell subsets in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. Nat Med. 2016;22(9):991-993.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou P, Chen J, He J, et al. Low-dose IL-2 therapy invigorates CD8+ T cells for viral control in systemic lupus erythematosus. PLoS Pathog. 2021;17(10):e1009858.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zwirner NW, Domaica CI. Cytokine regulation of natural killer cell effector functions. Biofactors. 2010;36(4):274-288.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Littwitz-Salomon E, Dittmer U, Sutter K. Insufficient natural killer cell responses against retroviruses: how to improve NK cell killing of retrovirus-infected cells. Retrovirology. 2016;13(1):77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang JQ, Zhang SX, Wang J, et al. Low-dose IL-2 therapy limits the reduction in absolute numbers of peripheral lymphocytes in systemic lupus erythematosus patients with infection. Curr Med Res Opin. 2022;38(6):1037-1044.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>