<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36807718</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>31</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2326-5205</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>75</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Arthritis &amp; rheumatology (Hoboken, N.J.)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Arthritis Rheumatol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Elevated Levels of Interferon-&#x3b1; Act Directly on B Cells to Breach Multiple Tolerance Mechanisms Promoting Autoantibody Production.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1542</StartPage><EndPage>1555</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1542-1555</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/art.42482</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">Elevated levels of serum interferon-&#x3b1; (IFN&#x3b1;) and the disruption of B cell tolerance are central to systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) immunopathogenesis; however, the relationship between these 2 processes remains unclear. The purpose of this study was to investigate the impact of elevated IFN&#x3b1; levels on B cell tolerance mechanisms in vivo and determine whether any changes observed were due to the direct effect of IFN&#x3b1; on B cells.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Two classical mouse models of B cell tolerance were used in conjunction with an adenoviral vector encoding IFN&#x3b1; to mimic the sustained elevations of IFN&#x3b1; seen in SLE. The role of B cell IFN&#x3b1; signaling, T cells, and Myd88 signaling was determined using B cell-specific IFN&#x3b1; receptor-knockout, CD4+ T cell-depleted, or Myd88-knockout mice, respectively. Flow cytometry, enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay, real-time quantitative polymerase chain reaction, and cell cultures were used to study the effects of elevated IFN&#x3b1; on the immunologic phenotype.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Elevation of serum IFN&#x3b1; disrupts multiple B cell tolerance mechanisms and leads to autoantibody production. This disruption was dependent upon B cell expression of IFN&#x3b1; receptor. Many of the IFN&#x3b1;-mediated alterations also required the presence of CD4+ T cells as well as Myd88, suggesting that IFN&#x3b1; acts directly on B cells to modify their response to Myd88 signaling and their ability to interact with T cells.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">The results provide evidence that elevated IFN&#x3b1; levels act directly on B cells to facilitate autoantibody production and further highlight the importance of IFN signaling as a potential therapeutic target in SLE.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Authors. Arthritis &amp; Rheumatology published by Wiley Periodicals LLC on behalf of American College of Rheumatology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ferri</LastName><ForeName>Dario M</ForeName><Initials>DM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Schroeder Arthritis Institute, Krembil Research Institute, University Health Network, Toronto, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nassar</LastName><ForeName>Carol</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Schroeder Arthritis Institute, Krembil Research Institute, University Health Network, Toronto, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Manion</LastName><ForeName>Kieran P</ForeName><Initials>KP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Schroeder Arthritis Institute, Krembil Research Institute, University Health Network, Toronto, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Michael</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Schroeder Arthritis Institute, Krembil Research Institute, University Health Network, Toronto, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Baglaenko</LastName><ForeName>Yuriy</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Schroeder Arthritis Institute, Krembil Research Institute, University Health Network, Toronto, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mu&#xf1;oz-Grajales</LastName><ForeName>Carolina</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Schroeder Arthritis Institute, Krembil Research Institute, University Health Network, Toronto, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wither</LastName><ForeName>Joan E</ForeName><Initials>JE</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5961-9228</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Schroeder Arthritis Institute, Krembil Research Institute, and Division of Rheumatology, Schroeder Arthritis Institute, University Health Network, and Departments of Medicine and Immunology, University of Toronto, Toronto, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Arthritis Rheumatol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101623795</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2326-5191</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D016898">Interferon-alpha</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D053594">Myeloid Differentiation Factor 88</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D001323">Autoantibodies</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051379" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016898" MajorTopicYN="Y">Interferon-alpha</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053594" MajorTopicYN="N">Myeloid Differentiation Factor 88</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001402" MajorTopicYN="N">B-Lymphocytes</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001323" MajorTopicYN="N">Autoantibodies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36807718</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/art.42482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Yurasov S, Wardemann H, Hammersen J, et al. Defective B cell tolerance checkpoints in systemic lupus erythematosus. J Exp Med 2005;201:703-11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karrar S, Cunninghame Graham DS. Abnormal B cell development in systemic lupus erythematosus: what the genetics tell us [review]. Arthritis Rheumatol 2018;70:496-507.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsokos GC, Lo MS, Reis PC, et al. New insights into the immunopathogenesis of systemic lupus erythematosus [review]. Nat Rev Rheumatol 2016;12:716-30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banchereau J, Pascual V. Type I interferon in systemic lupus erythematosus and other autoimmune diseases. Immunity 2006;25:383-92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crow MK. Type I interferon in organ-targeted autoimmune and inflammatory diseases. Arthritis Res Ther 2010;12 Suppl:S5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crow MK. Type I interferon in the pathogenesis of lupus. J Immunol 2014;192:5459-68.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mountz JD, Hsu HC, Ballesteros-Tato A. Dysregulation of T follicular helper cells in lupus. J Immunol 2019;202:1649-58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braun D, Caramalho I, Demengeot J. IFN-&#x3b1;/&#x3b2; enhances BCR-dependent B cell responses. Int Immunol 2002;14:411-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giordani L, Sanchez M, Libri I, et al. IFN-&#x3b1; amplifies human naive B cell TLR-9-mediated activation and Ig production. J Leukoc Biol 2009;86:261-71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang NH, Li TT, Kim JJ, et al. Interferon-&#x3b1; induces altered transitional B cell signaling and function in Systemic Lupus Erythematosus. J Autoimmun 2015;58:100-10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodnow CC, Crosbie J, Adelstein S, et al. Altered immunoglobulin expression and functional silencing of self-reactive B lymphocytes in transgenic mice. Nature 1988;334:676-82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu JQ, Barab&#xe9; ND, Huang YM, et al. Pre- and post-exposure protection against Western equine encephalitis virus after single inoculation with adenovirus vector expressing interferon alpha. Virology 2007;369:206-13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang NH, MacLeod R, Wither JE. Autoreactive B cells in lupus-prone New Zealand black mice exhibit aberrant survival and proliferation in the presence of self-antigen in vivo. J Immunol 2004;172:1553-60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang NH, Manion KP, Loh C, et al. Multiple tolerance defects contribute to the breach of B cell tolerance in New Zealand Black chromosome 1 congenic mice. PLoS One 2017;12:e0179506.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang SH, Kim TJ, Kim YJ, et al. The lupus susceptibility locus Sle1 facilitates the peripheral development and selection of anti-DNA B cells through impaired receptor editing. J Immunol 2014;192:5579-85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erikson J, Radic MZ, Camper SA, et al. Expression of anti-DNA immunoglobulin transgenes in non-autoimmune mice. Nature 1991;349:331-4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandik-Nayak L, Bui A, Noorchashm H, et al. Regulation of anti-double-stranded DNA B cells in nonautoimmune mice: localization to the T-B interface of the splenic follicle. J Exp Med 1997;186:1257-67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woloschak GE, Krco CJ. Regulation of &#x3ba;/&#x3bb; immunoglobulin light chain expression in normal murine lymphocytes. Mol Immunol 1987;24:751-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ota M, Duong BH, Torkamani A, et al. Regulation of the B cell receptor repertoire and self-reactivity by BAFF. J Immunol 2010;185:4128-36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isnardi I, Ng YS, Srdanovic I, et al. IRAK-4- and MyD88-dependent pathways are essential for the removal of developing autoreactive B cells in humans. Immunity 2008;29:746-57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuraoka M, Snowden PB, Nojima T, et al. BCR and endosomal TLR signals synergize to increase AID expression and establish central B cell tolerance. Cell Rep 2017;18:1627-35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paul E, Nelde A, Verschoor A, et al. Follicular exclusion of autoreactive B cells requires Fc&#x3b3;RIIb. Int Immunol 2007;19:365-73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cambier JC, Gauld SB, Merrell KT, et al. B-cell anergy: from transgenic models to naturally occurring anergic B cells? [review]. Nat Rev Immunol 2007;7:633-43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hua Z, Gross AJ, Lamagna C, et al. Requirement for MyD88 signaling in B cells and dendritic cells for germinal center anti-nuclear antibody production in Lyn-deficient mice. J Immunol 2014;192:875-85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merrell KT, Benschop RJ, Gauld SB, et al. Identification of anergic B cells within a wild-type repertoire. Immunity 2006;25:953-62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teague BN, Pan Y, Mudd PA, et al. Cutting edge: transitional T3 B cells do not give rise to mature B cells, have undergone selection, and are reduced in murine lupus. J Immunol 2007;178:7511-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rao DA, Gurish MF, Marshall JL, et al. Pathologically expanded peripheral T helper cell subset drives B cells in rheumatoid arthritis. Nature 2017;542:110-4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jenks SA, Cashman KS, Zumaquero E, et al. Distinct effector B cells induced by unregulated toll-like receptor 7 contribute to pathogenic responses in systemic lupus erythematosus. Immunity 2018;49:725-39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S, Wang J, Kumar V, et al. IL-21 drives expansion and plasma cell differentiation of autoreactive CD11chiT-bet+ B cells in SLE. Nat Commun 2018;9:1758.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miettinen M, Sareneva T, Julkunen I, et al. IFNs activate toll-like receptor gene expression in viral infections. Genes Immun 2001;2:349-55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sir&#xe9;n J, Pirhonen J, Julkunen I, et al. IFN-&#x3b1; regulates TLR-dependent gene expression of IFN-&#x3b1;, IFN-&#x3b2;, IL-28, and IL-29. J Immunol 2005;174:1932-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niewold TB, Kelly JA, Flesch MH, et al. Association of the IRF5 risk haplotype with high serum interferon-&#x3b1; activity in systemic lupus erythematosus patients. Arthritis Rheum 2008;58:2481-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salloum R, Franek BS, Kariuki SN, et al. Genetic variation at the IRF7/PHRF1 locus is associated with autoantibody profile and serum interferon-&#x3b1; activity in lupus patients. Arthritis Rheum 2010;62:553-61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manjarrez-Ordu&#xf1;o N, Marasco E, Chung SA, et al. CSK regulatory polymorphism is associated with systemic lupus erythematosus and influences B-cell signaling and activation. Nat Genet 2012;44:1227-30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai X, James RG, Habib T, et al. A disease-associated PTPN22 variant promotes systemic autoimmunity in murine models. J Clin Invest 2013;123:2024-36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simpfendorfer KR, Armstead BE, Shih A, et al. Autoimmune disease-associated haplotypes of BLK exhibit lowered thresholds for B cell activation and expansion of Ig class-switched B cells. Arthritis Rheumatol 2015;67:2866-76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niewold TB, Swedler WI. Systemic lupus erythematosus arising during interferon-alpha therapy for cryoglobulinemic vasculitis associated with hepatitis C. Clin Rheumatol 2005;24:178-81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yusof MY, Psarras A, El-Sherbiny YM, et al. Prediction of autoimmune connective tissue disease in an at-risk cohort: prognostic value of a novel two-score system for interferon status. Ann Rheum Dis 2018;77:1432-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pelanda R, Schwers S, Sonoda E, et al. Receptor editing in a transgenic mouse model: site, efficiency, and role in B cell tolerance and antibody diversification. Immunity 1997;7:765-75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Y, Zhao S, Qin XY, et al. Altered phenotype and enhanced antibody-producing ability of peripheral B Cells in mice with Cd19-driven Cre expression. Cells 2022;11:700.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menard L, Saadoun D, Isnardi I, et al. The PTPN22 allele encoding an R620W variant interferes with the removal of developing autoreactive B cells in humans. J Clin Invest 2011;121:3635-44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baglaenko Y, Chang NH, Johnson SR, et al. The presence of anti-nuclear antibodies alone is associated with changes in B cell activation and T follicular helper cells similar to those in systemic autoimmune rheumatic disease. Arthritis Res Ther 2018;20:264.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Metzler G, Kolhatkar NS, Rawlings DJ. BCR and co-receptor crosstalk facilitate the positive selection of self-reactive transitional B cells. Curr Opin Immunol 2015;37:46-53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang NH, McKenzie T, Bonventi G, et al. Expanded population of activated antigen-engaged cells within the naive B cell compartment of patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. J Immunol 2008;180:1276-84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qu&#xe1;ch TD, Manjarrez-Ordu&#xf1;o N, Adlowitz DG, et al. Anergic responses characterize a large fraction of human autoreactive naive B cells expressing low levels of surface IgM. J Immunol 2011;186:4640-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yurasov S, Tiller T, Tsuiji M, et al. Persistent expression of autoantibodies in SLE patients in remission. J Exp Med 2006;203:2255-61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Domeier PP, Chodisetti SB, Schell SL, et al. B-cell-intrinsic type 1 interferon signaling is crucial for loss of tolerance and the development of autoreactive B cells. Cell Rep 2018;24:406-18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong EB, Khan TN, Mohan C, et al. The lupus-prone NZM2410/NZW strain-derived Sle1b sublocus alters the germinal center checkpoint in female mice in a B cell-intrinsic manner. J Immunol 2012;189:5667-81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacquemin C, Schmitt N, Contin-Bordes C, et al. OX40 ligand contributes to human lupus pathogenesis by promoting T follicular helper response. Immunity 2015;42:1159-70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim CJ, Lee CG, Jung JY, et al. The transcription factor Ets1 suppresses T follicular helper type 2 cell differentiation to halt the onset of systemic lupus erythematosus. Immunity 2018;49:1034-48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cappione A, Anolik JH, Pugh-Bernard A, et al. Germinal center exclusion of autoreactive B cells is defective in human systemic lupus erythematosus. J Clin Invest 2005;115:3205-16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pieterse E, van der Vlag J. Breaking immunological tolerance in systemic lupus erythematosus. Front Immunol 2014;5:164.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>