<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36802112</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>04</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1756-185X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of rheumatic diseases</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Rheum Dis</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Performance of systemic lupus erythematosus responder index for detecting clinician-rated responders in patients with active systemic lupus erythematosus.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>667</StartPage><EndPage>672</EndPage><MedlinePgn>667-672</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/1756-185X.14606</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Disease activity measures in systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) are critical tools for trial endpoints. We aimed to evaluate the performance of current treatment outcome measures in SLE.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Individuals with active SLE with a clinical SLE Disease Activity Index-2000 (SLEDAI-2K) score of at least 4 were followed up for two or more visits and classified as responders and non-responders based on a physician's judgment of improvement. The treatment outcome measures including SLEDAI-2K responder index-50 (SRI-50), SLE responder index-4 (SRI-4), substituting SLEDAI-2K with SRI-50 in SRI-4 (SRI-4(50)), SLE Disease Activity Score (SLE-DAS) responder index (&#x394;&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;1.72) and the British Isles Lupus Assessment Group (BILAG)-based Composite Lupus Assessment (BICLA) were tested. The performance of those measures was shown by sensitivity, specificity, predictive value, positive likelihood ratio, accuracy, and agreement against a physician-rated improvement.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Twenty-seven patients with active SLE were followed. The total cumulative pair of visits (baseline and follow up) was 48. The overall accuracies (95% confidence interval [CI]) of SRI-50, SRI-4, SRI-4(50), SLE-DAS, and BICLA for detecting responders in all patients were 72.9 (58.2-84.7), 75.0 (60.4-86.4), 72.9 (58.2-84.7), 75.0 (60.4-86.4), and 64.6 (49.5-77.8), respectively. Subgroup analyses of lupus nephritis (23 patients had a pair of visits) found the accuracies (95% CI) of SRI-50, SRI-4, SRI-4(50), SLE-DAS, and BICLA were 82.6 (61.2-95.0), 73.9 (51.6-89.8), 82.6 (61.2-95.0), 82.6 (61.2-95.0), and 78.3 (56.3-92.5), respectively. However, there were no significant differences between the groups (P&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;0.05).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">SRI-4, SRI-50, SRI-4(50), SLE-DAS responder index, and BICLA demonstrated comparable abilities to identify clinician-rated responders in patients with active SLE and lupus nephritis.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 Asia Pacific League of Associations for Rheumatology and John Wiley &amp; Sons Australia, Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Leosuthamas</LastName><ForeName>Pornsawan</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rheumatic Disease Unit, Department of Internal Medicine, Phramongkutklao Hospital and College of Medicine, Bangkok, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Narongroeknawin</LastName><ForeName>Pongthorn</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8202-6746</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rheumatic Disease Unit, Department of Internal Medicine, Phramongkutklao Hospital and College of Medicine, Bangkok, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chaiamnuay</LastName><ForeName>Sumapa</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6056-3559</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rheumatic Disease Unit, Department of Internal Medicine, Phramongkutklao Hospital and College of Medicine, Bangkok, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Asavatanabodee</LastName><ForeName>Paijit</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rheumatic Disease Unit, Department of Internal Medicine, Phramongkutklao Hospital and College of Medicine, Bangkok, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pakchotanon</LastName><ForeName>Rattapol</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9228-5650</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rheumatic Disease Unit, Department of Internal Medicine, Phramongkutklao Hospital and College of Medicine, Bangkok, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Rheum Dis</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101474930</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1756-1841</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008181" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lupus Nephritis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012720" MajorTopicYN="N">Severity of Illness Index</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006113" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">United Kingdom</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">disease activity index</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">systemic lupus erythematosus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">treatment outcome</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>58</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36802112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1756-185X.14606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Bombardier C, Gladman DD, Urowitz MB, Caron D, Chang CH. Derivation of the SLEDAI. A disease activity index for lupus patients. The committee on prognosis studies in SLE. Arthritis Rheum. 1992;35(6):630-640.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gladman DD, Iba&#xf1;ez D, Urowitz MB. Systemic lupus erythematosus disease activity index 2000. J Rheumatol. 2002;29(2):288-291.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petri M, Kim MY, Kalunian KC, et al. Combined oral contraceptives in women with systemic lupus erythematosus. N Engl J Med. 2005;353(24):2550-2558.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Touma Z, Gladman DD, Iba&#xf1;ez D, Urowitz MB. Development and initial validation of the systemic lupus erythematosus disease activity index 2000 responder index 50. J Rheumatol. 2011;38(2):275-284.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jesus D, Matos A, Henriques C, et al. Derivation and validation of the SLE disease activity score (SLE-DAS): a new SLE continuous measure with high sensitivity for changes in disease activity. Ann Rheum Dis. 2019;78(3):365-371.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hay EM, Bacon PA, Gordon C, et al. The BILAG index: a reliable and valid instrument for measuring clinical disease activity in systemic lupus erythematosus. Q J Med. 1993;86(7):447-458.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isenberg DA, Rahman A, Allen E, Farewell V, Akil M, Bruce IN, et al. BILAG 2004. Development and initial validation of an updated version of the British Isles Lupus Assessment Group's disease activity index for patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. Rheumatology (Oxford) 2005;44(7):902-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yee CS, Farewell V, Isenberg DA, et al. The BILAG-2004 index is sensitive to change for assessment of SLE disease activity. Rheumatology (Oxford). 2009;48(6):691-695.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Navarra SV, Guzman RM, Gallacher AE, et al. Efficacy and safety of belimumab in patients with active systemic lupus erythematosus: a randomised, placebo-controlled, phase 3 trial. Lancet. 2011;377(9767):721-731.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furie R, Petri M, Zamani O, et al. A phase III, randomized, placebo-controlled study of belimumab, a monoclonal antibody that inhibits B lymphocyte stimulator, in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Rheum. 2011;63(12):3918-3930.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallace DJ, Kalunian K, Petri MA, et al. Efficacy and safety of epratuzumab in patients with moderate/severe active systemic lupus erythematosus: results from EMBLEM, a phase IIb, randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled, multicentre study. Ann Rheum Dis. 2014;73(1):183-190.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furie RA, Morand EF, Bruce IN, et al. Type I interferon inhibitor anifrolumab in active systemic lupus erythematosus (TULIP-1): a randomised, controlled, phase 3 trial. Lancet Rheumatol. 2019;1(4):e208-e219.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morand EF, Furie R, Tanaka Y, et al. Trial of Anifrolumab in active systemic lupus erythematosus. N Engl J Med. 2019;382(3):211-221.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petri M, Orbai AM, Alarc&#xf3;n GS, et al. Derivation and validation of the systemic lupus international collaborating clinics classification criteria for systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Rheum. 2012;64(8):2677-2686.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Touma Z, Gladman DD, Iba&#xf1;ez D, Taghavi-Zadeh S, Urowitz MB. Systemic lupus erythematosus disease activity index 2000 responder Index-50 enhances the ability of SLE responder index to identify responders in clinical trials. J Rheumatol. 2011;38(11):2395-2399.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yee C-S, Farewell V, Isenberg DA, et al. Revised British Isles lupus assessment group 2004 index: a reliable tool for assessment of systemic lupus erythematosus activity. Arthritis Rheum. 2006;54(10):3300-3305.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furie RA, Petri MA, Wallace DJ, et al. Novel evidence-based systemic lupus erythematosus responder index. Arthritis Rheum. 2009;61(9):1143-1151.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thanou A, Chakravarty E, James JA, Merrill JT. Which outcome measures in SLE clinical trials best reflect medical judgment? Lupus Sci Med. 2014;1(1):e000005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Touma Z, Urowitz MB, Taghavi-Zadeh S, Iba&#xf1;ez D, Gladman DD. Systemic lupus erythematosus disease activity index 2000 responder index 50: sensitivity to response at 6 and 12 months. Rheumatology (Oxford). 2012;51(10):1814-1819.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>