<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36800570</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>22</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-5964</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>102</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>17</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Medicine (Baltimore)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Management of cardiovascular surgery in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus including thromboembolism and multiple organ failure prevention: A retrospective observational study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e32979</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e32979</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e32979</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MD.0000000000032979</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Systemic lupus erythematosus is a chronic autoimmune disease that affects most tissues. Cardiovascular events are critical, life-threatening, long-term complications of systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE). We report our single-center experience of performing cardiovascular surgery in patients with SLE while avoiding postoperative complications. We also suggest a new approach for cardiopulmonary bypass and perioperative management. We applied the antiphospholipid antibody syndrome (APS) severity classification published by the Japan Intractable Disease Information Center to patients with SLE for perioperative management. Patients with Grade III or higher severity are treated with a slightly relaxed version of catastrophic APS therapy. This treatment modality includes glucocorticoids, anticoagulation, intravenous immunoglobulin, and plasma exchange. Between April 2010 and January 2021, 26 patients (2 males, 24 females) with SLE underwent cardiovascular surgery. The mean age was 74.2&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;13.0 years (38-84 years). The primary outcomes were in-hospital mortality and long-term results, and the secondary outcomes were related to bleeding/embolization and coagulation function/platelet count. A subset analysis was performed to examine treatment efficacy in the APS Grade III or higher group. Of the 26 patients, 17 underwent valve surgery, 4 underwent isolated coronary artery bypass grafting, and 5 underwent thoracic aortic aneurysm surgery. There were no in-hospital deaths or associated bleeding/embolic complications. Postoperative antithrombin III decreased in patients who underwent valvular and aortic surgery, and platelet counts recovered to preoperative levels within 7 to 10 days. The 5- and 10-year survival rates were 80.5% and 53.7%, respectively. In addition, there were 10 patients with APS Grade III or higher, but there was no significant difference in the frequency of complications other than platelet recovery after treatment. The surgical outcome of open-heart surgery in patients with SLE was good. Surgical treatment of cardiovascular disease in these patients is difficult and complex. We focused on blood coagulation abnormalities and treated each patient by selecting the best individual treatment protocol according to the severity of the disease, taking into account the risk of bleeding and thrombosis. Management of blood coagulation function in these patients is essential, and careful therapeutic management should be considered during open-heart surgery.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 the Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yamamoto</LastName><ForeName>Taira</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2214-2539</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiovascular Surgery, Juntendo University Nerima Hospital, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Matsushita</LastName><ForeName>Satoshi</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiovascular Surgery, Juntendo University, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Endo</LastName><ForeName>Daisuke</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiovascular Surgery, Juntendo University, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shimada</LastName><ForeName>Akie</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiovascular Surgery, Juntendo University Nerima Hospital, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dohi</LastName><ForeName>Shizuyuki</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiovascular Surgery, Juntendo University Nerima Hospital, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kajimoto</LastName><ForeName>Kan</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiovascular Surgery, Juntendo University Shizuoka Hospital, Shizuoka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yokoyama</LastName><ForeName>Yasutaka</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiovascular Surgery, Toda Chuo Hospital, Saitama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sato</LastName><ForeName>Yuichiro</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiovascular Surgery, Juntendo University, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Machida</LastName><ForeName>Yoichiro</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiovascular Surgery, Juntendo University, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Asai</LastName><ForeName>Tohru</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiovascular Surgery, Juntendo University, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Amano</LastName><ForeName>Atsushi</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiovascular Surgery, Juntendo University, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D064888">Observational Study</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Medicine (Baltimore)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>2985248R</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0025-7974</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000369" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged, 80 and over</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009102" MajorTopicYN="N">Multiple Organ Failure</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016736" MajorTopicYN="Y">Antiphospholipid Syndrome</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013927" MajorTopicYN="Y">Thrombosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006470" MajorTopicYN="N">Hemorrhage</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013923" MajorTopicYN="Y">Thromboembolism</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors have no funding and conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36800570</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9936021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000032979</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005792-202302170-00001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Hersh AO, von Scheven E, Yazdany J, et al. . Differences in long-term disease activity and treatment of adult patients with childhood- and adult-onset systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Rheum. 2009;15:13&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2875186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19116979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sato VA, Marques ID, Goldenstein PT, et al. . Lupus nephritis is more severe in children and adolescents than in older adults. Lupus. 2012;21:978&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22451604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Svenungsson E, Jensen-Urstad K, Heimb&#xfc;rger M, et al. . Risk factors for cardiovascular disease in systemic lupus erythematosus. Circulation. 2001;104:1887&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11602489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lockshin MD. Update on antiphospholipid syndrome. Bull NYU Hosp Jt Dis. 2008;66:195&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18937631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cervera R. Antiphospholipid syndrome. Thromb Res. 2017;151:S43&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28262233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pappalardo F, Franco A, Crescenzi G, et al. . Anticoagulation management in patients undergoing open heart surgery by activated clotting time and whole blood heparin concentration. Perfusion. 2006;21:285&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17201083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verzelloni Sef A, Caliandro F, Sef D, et al. . The use of point-of-care testing in detecting platelet function recovery in a patient treated with prasugrel undergoing urgent surgical revascularization. J Card Surg. 2021;36:4801&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34580922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorki H. The antiphospholipid syndrome and heart valve surgery. Eur J CardioThoracic Surg. 2008;33:168&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18082413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sniecinski RM, Levy JH. Anticoagulation management associated with extracorporeal circulation. Best Pract Res Clin Anaesthesiol. 2015;29:189&#x2013;202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26060030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gravlee GP, Rogers AT, Dudas LM, et al. . Heparin management protocol for cardiopulmonary bypass influences postoperative heparin rebound but not bleeding. Anesthesiology. 1992;76:393&#x2013;401.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1539851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsushita S, Kishida A, Wakamatsu Y, et al. . Factors influencing activated clotting time following heparin administration for the initiation of cardiopulmonary bypass. Gen Thorac Cardiovasc Surg. 2021;69:38&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32656705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shore-Lesserson L, Baker RA, Ferraris VA, et al. . The society of thoracic surgeons, the society of cardiovascular anesthesiologists, and the American society of extracorporeal technology: clinical practice guidelines-anticoagulation during cardiopulmonary bypass. Ann Thorac Surg. 2018;105:650&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29362176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Genzen JR, Fareed J, Hoppensteadt D, et al. Prolonged elevation of plasma argatroban in a cardiac transplant patient with a suspected history of heparin-induced thrombocytopenia with thrombosis. Transfusion. 2010;50:801&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20003049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ota T, Okada K, Kano H, et al. . Cardiopulmonary bypass using nafamostat mesilate for patients with infective endocarditis and recent intracranial hemorrhage. Interact Cardiovasc Thorac Surg. 2007;6:270&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17669840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serrano R, Pons-Estel GJ, Espinosa G, et al. . Long-term follow-up of antiphospholipid syndrome: real-life experience from a single center. Lupus. 2020;29:1050&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32536318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cervera R, Serrano R, Pons-Estel GJ, et al. .; Euro-Phospholipid Project Group (European Forum on Antiphospholipid Antibodies). Morbidity and mortality in the antiphospholipid syndrome during a 10-year period: a multicentre prospective study of 1000 patients. Ann Rheum Dis. 2015;74:1011&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24464962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyakis S, Lockshin MD, Atsumi T, et al. . International consensus statement on an update of the classification criteria for definite antiphospholipid syndrome (APS). J Thromb Haemost. 2006;4:295&#x2013;306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16420554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Japan Intractable Disease Information Center. Antiphospholipid antibody syndrome (designated intractable disease 48).
Available at: https://www.nanbyou.or.jp/entry/4102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sciascia S, Sanna G, Murru V, et al. . GAPSS: the global anti-phospholipid syndrome score. Rheumatology (Oxford). 2013;52:1397&#x2013;403.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23315788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodr&#xed;guez-Pint&#xf3; I, Moitinho M, Santacreu I, et al. .; CAPS Registry Project Group (European Forum on Antiphospholipid Antibodies). Catastrophic antiphospholipid syndrome (CAPS): descriptive analysis of 500 patients from the International CAPS Registry. Autoimmun Rev. 2016;15:1120&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27639837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tektonidou MG, Wang Z, Ward MM. Brief report: Trends in hospitalizations due to acute coronary syndromes and stroke in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus, 1996 to 2012. Arthritis Rheumatol. 2016;68:2680&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5083218</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27273732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld SR, Kasturi S, Costenbader KH. The epidemiology of atherosclerotic cardiovascular disease among patients with SLE: a systematic review. Semin Arthritis Rheum. 2013;43:77&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23422269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manzi S, Meilahn EN, Rairie JE, et al. . Age-specific incidence rates of myocardial infarction and angina in women with systemic lupus erythematosus: comparison with the Framingham study. Am J Epidemiol. 1997;145:408&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9048514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen J, Tang Y, Zhu M, et al. . Heart involvement in systemic lupus erythematosus: a systemic review and meta-analysis. Clin Rheumatol. 2016;35:2437&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27502777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watad A, Tiosano S, Grysman N, et al. . The association between systemic lupus erythematosus and valvular heart disease: an extensive data analysis. Eur J Clin Invest. 2017;47:366&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28295225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abramowitz Y, Jilaihawi H, Chakravarty T, et al. . Porcelain aorta: a comprehensive review. Circulation. 2015;131:827&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25737502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirose K, Kodera S, Daimon M, et al. . Time-dependent changes in porcelain aorta and aortic stenosis in a patient with systemic lupus erythematosus. Int Heart J. 2020;61:1294&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33191339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aguayo E, Dobaria V, Sareh S, et al. . National analysis of coronary artery bypass grafting in autoimmune connective tissue disease. Ann Thorac Surg. 2020;110:2006&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32439392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Onea R, Germain P, Zimmermann A. Coronary microvasculopathy and intracardiac thrombosis in antiphospholipid syndrome. Arch Cardiovasc Dis. 2012;105:461&#x2013;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22958890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azeem T, Vassallo M, Samani NJ. Images in cardiology. Endomyocardial fibrosis associated with antiphospholipid syndrome. Heart. 2000;84:156.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1760912</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10979722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandhu VK, Wei J, Thomson LEJ, et al. . Five-year follow-up of coronary microvascular dysfunction and coronary artery disease in systemic lupus erythematosus: results from a community-based lupus cohort. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken). 2020;72:882&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6832763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31058466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S, Chang Y, Liu C, et al. . Incidence and risk analysis of aortic aneurysm and aortic dissection among patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: a nationwide population-based study in Taiwan. Lupus. 2014;23:665&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24554710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dietrich M, Bois M, Ferrufino R, et al. . A tale of two valves: bioprosthetic aortic valve obstruction in systemic lupus erythematosus and antiphospholipid antibody syndrome. J Cardiothorac Vasc Anesth. 2020;34:3462&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32800619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kolitz T, Shiber S, Sharabi I, et al. . Cardiac manifestations of antiphospholipid syndrome with focus on its primary form. Front Immunol. 2019;10:941.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6522847</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31134062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Camous J, Decrombecque T, Louvain-Quintard V, et al. . Outcomes of patients with antiphospholipid syndrome after pulmonary endarterectomy. Eur J Cardiothorac Surg. 2014;46:116&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24362260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakajima T, Enomoto Y, Ishigaki M, et al. . Perioperative anticoagulation management during aortic valve replacement complicated by antiphospholipid syndrome. J Card Surg. 2017;32:633&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28944492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Endara SA, D&#xe1;valos GA, Fierro CH, et al. . Antiphospholipid syndrome and valvular heart disease, a complex scenario of thrombotic events, a case report. J Cardiothorac Surg. 2020;15:275.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7526220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32993710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pengo V, Ruffatti A, Legnani C, et al. . Clinical course of high-risk patients diagnosed with antiphospholipid syndrome. J Thromb Haemost. 2010;8:237&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19874470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seki T, Shingu Y, Sugiki H, et al. . Anticoagulation management during cardiopulmonary bypass in patients with antiphospholipid syndrome. J Artif Organs. 2018;21:363&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29541945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnaud L, Mathian A, Devilliers H, et al. . Patient-level analysis of five international cohorts further confirms the efficacy of aspirin for the primary prevention of thrombosis in patients with antiphospholipid antibodies. Autoimmun Rev. 2014;14:192&#x2013;200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25461472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahman A. Management of antiphospholipid syndrome. Clin Rheumatol. 2020;39:2111&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32458245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>