<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36827060</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>28</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-5964</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>102</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>22</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Medicine (Baltimore)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The efficacy and safety of cyclosporine in children with systemic lupus erythematosus: A protocol for systematic review and meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e32314</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e32314</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MD.0000000000032314</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Childhood-onset systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) is a rare but severe multisystem autoimmune/inflammatory disease with marked heterogeneity between patients, causing anything from mild to life-threatening disease. We performed a protocol for systematic review and meta-analysis to evaluate the efficacy and safety of cyclosporine in childhood-onset SLE.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This systematic review has been registered in PROSPERO (CRD42022377450), which will be conducted in accordance with Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis Protocols 2015 statement. Only randomized controlled trials will be included.We searched the following databases including PubMed, EMBASE, the Cochrane Library, SinoMed, CNKI, VIP, Wanfang Data and International Clinical Trials Register Search Portal, and Clinical Trials.gov. Two researchers will use the Cochrane systematic evaluation tool to assess the risk of bias independently. Data synthesis will be performed using RevMan V.5.4.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">This study will comprehensively summarize the high-quality trials to determine the efficacy and safety of cyclosporine in the treatment of childhood-onset SLE.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This study may be beneficial to health policymakers, clinicians, and patients with regard to the use of cyclosporine in childhood-onset SLE.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 the Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Xiaohui</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3367-1583</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rheumatology and Immunology, Jiangxi Provincial Children's Hospital, Jiangxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Peng</LastName><ForeName>Yu</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cai</LastName><ForeName>Sufen</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Medicine (Baltimore)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>2985248R</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0025-7974</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>83HN0GTJ6D</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D016572">Cyclosporine</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016572" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cyclosporine</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000078202" MajorTopicYN="N">Systematic Reviews as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015201" MajorTopicYN="N">Meta-Analysis as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012107" MajorTopicYN="N">Research Design</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors have no conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36827060</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000032314</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005792-202302220-00060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Fortuna G, Brennan MT. Systemic lupus erythematosus: epidemiology, pathophysiology, manifestations, and management. Dent Clin North Am. 2013;57:631&#x2013;55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zucchi D, Elefante E, Schiliro D, et al. One year in review 2022: systemic lupus erythematosus. Clin Exp Rheumatol. 2022;40:4&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aringer M, Johnson SR. Classifying and diagnosing systemic lupus erythematosus in the 21st century. Rheumatology (Oxford). 2020;59 (Suppl5):v4&#x2013;v11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwon OC, Lee JS, Ghang B, et al. Predicting eventual development of lupus nephritis at the time of diagnosis of systemic lupus erythematosus. Semin Arthritis Rheum. 2018;48:462&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan A, Sawant T, Deen Z, et al. Systemic lupus erythematosus in the elderly that debuts with an organic manifestation of lupus nephritis. Cureus. 2022;14:e28746.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charras A, Smith E, Hedrich CM. Systemic lupus erythematosus in children and young people. Curr Rheumatol Rep. 2021;23:20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith E, Lythgoe H, Midgley A, et al. Juvenile-onset systemic lupus erythematosus: update on clinical presentation, pathophysiology and treatment options. Clin Immunol. 2019;209:108274.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balci S, Ekinci R, Bayazit AK, et al. Juvenile systemic lupus erythematosus: a single-center experience from southern Turkey. Clin Rheumatol. 2019;38:1459&#x2013;68.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brunner HI, Gladman DD, Ibanez D, et al. Difference in disease features between childhood-onset and adult-onset systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Rheum. 2008;58:556&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papadimitraki ED, Isenberg DA. Childhood- and adult-onset lupus: an update of similarities and differences. Expert Rev Clin Immunol. 2009;5:391&#x2013;403.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mok CC. Calcineurin inhibitors in systemic lupus erythematosus. Best Pract Res Clin Rheumatol. 2017;31:429&#x2013;38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patocka J, Nepovimova E, Kuca K, et al. Cyclosporine A: chemistry and toxicity - a review. Curr Med Chem. 2021;28:3925&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moher D, Shamseer L, Clarke M, et al. Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis Protocols (PRISMA-P) 2015 statement. Syst Rev. 2015;4:1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Altman DG, Gotzsche PC, et al. The cochrane collaboration&#x2019;s tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ. 2011;343:d5928.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atkins D, Best D, Briss PA, et al. Grading quality of evidence and strength of recommendations. BMJ. 2004;328:1490.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trindade VC, Carneiro-Sampaio M, Bonfa E, et al. An update on the management of childhood-onset systemic lupus erythematosus. Paediatr Drugs. 2021;23:331&#x2013;47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aggarwal A, Srivastava P. Childhood onset systemic lupus erythematosus: how is it different from adult SLE?. Int J Rheum Dis. 2015;18:182&#x2013;91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bitencourt N, Kramer J, Bermas BL, et al. Clinical team perspectives on the psychosocial aspects of transition to adult care for patients with childhood-onset systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken). 2021;73:39&#x2013;47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdalla E, Jeyaseelan L, Ullah I, et al. Growth pattern in children with systemic lupus erythematosus. Oman Med J. 2017;32:284&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>