<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36852495</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>12</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2163-8306</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>12</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>CPT: pharmacometrics &amp; systems pharmacology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>CPT Pharmacometrics Syst Pharmacol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Population model-based analysis of the memory B-cell response following belimumab therapy in the treatment of systemic lupus erythematosus.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>462</StartPage><EndPage>473</EndPage><MedlinePgn>462-473</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/psp4.12919</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) is an autoimmune disease characterized by B-cell hyperactivity and breach of tolerance. Autoreactive memory B cells, which have a decreased activation threshold and the ability to survive in absence of antigen, are believed to contribute to chronicity in autoimmune diseases like SLE. Belimumab, the first approved biological treatment of active SLE and lupus nephritis, reduces B cells dependent on B-lymphocyte stimulator protein (BLyS) for survival, whereas memory B cells are spared; several studies reported circulating memory B-cell concentrations increase following BLyS neutralization. This analysis investigated the effect of dose, demographics, and disease status on memory B-cell response after starting belimumab treatment. Population pharmacodynamic models were fitted to a pooled dataset from seven belimumab SLE trials. The optimal model was selected using maximum likelihood methods and was then refit to the data using Bayesian analysis and used to simulate memory B-cell response by belimumab dose and covariate subgroups. At the belimumab approved doses (10&#xa0;mg/kg intravenously every 4&#x2009;weeks, 200&#x2009;mg subcutaneously every week), circulatory memory B cells increase in the first 4-8&#x2009;weeks after belimumab initiation, typically returning to baseline levels over 76&#x2009;weeks. The model analysis suggested belimumab stimulates memory B-cell transition from lymphoid and/or inflamed tissues into the circulation, rather than inhibiting trafficking in the reverse direction. Baseline BLyS and anti-double-stranded deoxyribonucleic acid antibody concentrations were statistically identifiable covariates of memory B-cell response, although their impact on predicting size and response duration was small.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 GSK. CPT: Pharmacometrics &amp; Systems Pharmacology published by Wiley Periodicals LLC on behalf of American Society for Clinical Pharmacology and Therapeutics.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dimelow</LastName><ForeName>Richard</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1246-5705</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>GSK, Clinical Pharmacology Modelling and Simulation, Stevenage, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gillespie</LastName><ForeName>William R</ForeName><Initials>WR</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4560-6482</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Metrum Research Group, Tariffville, Connecticut, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>van Maurik</LastName><ForeName>Andre</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1954-0141</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>GSK, Clinical Pharmacology and Experimental Medicine, Stevenage, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>CPT Pharmacometrics Syst Pharmacol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101580011</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2163-8306</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>73B0K5S26A</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C511911">belimumab</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D007166">Immunosuppressive Agents</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000091245" MajorTopicYN="Y">Memory B Cells</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001499" MajorTopicYN="N">Bayes Theorem</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007166" MajorTopicYN="N">Immunosuppressive Agents</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>R.D. and A.V.M. are employees of GSK and hold stocks and shares in the company. W.R.G. is an employee of Metrum Research Group, and his work on this project was funded by GSK.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36852495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10088083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/psp4.12919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Cancro MP, D'Cruz DP, Khamashta MA. The role of B lymphocyte stimulator (BLyS) in systemic lupus erythematosus. J Clin Invest. 2009;119:1066&#x2010;1073.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2673851</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19411764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackay F, Woodcock SA, Lawton P, et al. Mice transgenic for BAFF develop lymphocytic disorders along with autoimmune manifestations. J Exp Med. 1999;190:1697&#x2010;1710.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2195729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10587360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teng YKO, Bruce IN, Diamond B, et al. Phase III, multicentre, randomised, double&#x2010;blind, placebo&#x2010;controlled, 104&#x2010;week study of subcutaneous belimumab administered in combination with rituximab in adults with systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE): BLISS&#x2010;BELIEVE study protocol. BMJ Open. 2019;9:e025687.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6475247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30898822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mariette X, Roux S, Zhang J, et al. The level of BLyS (BAFF) correlates with the titre of autoantibodies in human Sjogren's syndrome. Ann Rheum Dis. 2003;62:168&#x2010;171.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1754442</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12525388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheema GS, Roschke V, Hilbert DM, Stohl W. Elevated serum B lymphocyte stimulator levels in patients with systemic immune&#x2010;based rheumatic diseases. Arthritis Rheum. 2001;44:1313&#x2010;1319.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11407690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petri M, Stohl W, Chatham W, et al. Association of plasma B lymphocyte stimulator levels and disease activity in systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Rheum. 2008;58:2453&#x2010;2459.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18668552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsushita T, Hasegawa M, Yanaba K, Kodera M, Takehara K, Sato S. Elevated serum BAFF levels in patients with systemic sclerosis: enhanced BAFF signaling in systemic sclerosis B lymphocytes. Arthritis Rheum. 2006;54:192&#x2010;201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16385515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker KP, Edwards BM, Main SH, et al. Generation and characterization of LymphoStat&#x2010;B, a human monoclonal antibody that antagonizes the bioactivities of B lymphocyte stimulator. Arthritis Rheum. 2003;48:3253&#x2010;3265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14613291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>GSK . US highlights of prescribing information 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stohl W, Hiepe F, Latinis KM, et al. Belimumab reduces autoantibodies, normalizes low complement levels, and reduces select B cell populations in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Rheum. 2012;64:2328&#x2010;2337.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3350827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22275291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Struemper H, Kurtinecz M, Edwards L, Freimuth WW, Roth DA, Stohl W. Reductions in circulating B cell subsets and immunoglobulin G levels with long&#x2010;term belimumab treatment in patients with SLE. Lupus Sci Med. 2022;9:e000499.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8823257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35131846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manz RA, Moser K, Burmester GR, Radbruch A, Hiepe F. Immunological memory stabilizing autoreactivity. Curr Top Microbiol Immunol. 2006;305:241&#x2010;257.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16724809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cambridge G, Isenberg DA, Edwards JC, et al. B cell depletion therapy in systemic lupus erythematosus: relationships among serum B lymphocyte stimulator levels, autoantibody profile and clinical response. Ann Rheum Dis. 2008;67:1011&#x2010;1016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17962238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arends EJ, Zlei M, Tipton CM, et al. POS0680 belimumab add&#x2010;on therapy mobilises memory B cells into the circulation of patients with SLE. Ann Rheum Dis. 2021;80:585.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jourdan M, Caraux A, Caron G, et al. Characterization of a transitional preplasmablast population in the process of human B cell to plasma cell differentiation. J Immunol. 2011;187:3931&#x2010;3941.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21918187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palm AE, Henry C. Remembrance of things past: long&#x2010;term B cell memory after infection and vaccination. Front Immunol. 2019;10:1787.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6685390</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31417562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacLennan IC. Germinal centers. Annu Rev Immunol. 1994;12:117&#x2010;139.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8011279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallace DJ, Stohl W, Furie RA, et al. A phase II, randomized, double&#x2010;blind, placebo&#x2010;controlled, dose&#x2010;ranging study of belimumab in patients with active systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Rheum. 2009;61:1168&#x2010;1178.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2758229</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19714604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>clinicaltrials.gov . Phase 2 study of belimumab administered subcutaneously to subjects with systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) 2013. NCT00732940 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brunner HI, Abud&#x2010;Mendoza C, Viola DO, et al. Safety and efficacy of intravenous belimumab in children with systemic lupus erythematosus: results from a randomised, placebo&#x2010;controlled trial. Ann Rheum Dis. 2020;79:1340&#x2010;1348.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7509523</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32699034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stohl W, Schwarting A, Okada M, et al. Efficacy and safety of subcutaneous belimumab in systemic lupus erythematosus: a fifty&#x2010;two&#x2010;week randomized, double&#x2010;blind, Placebo&#x2010;Controlled Study. Arthritis Rheumatol. 2017;69:1016&#x2010;1027.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5434872</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28118533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang F, Bae SC, Bass D, et al. A pivotal phase III, randomised, placebo&#x2010;controlled study of belimumab in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus located in China, Japan and South Korea. Ann Rheum Dis. 2018;77:355&#x2010;363.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5867402</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29295825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furie R, Petri M, Zamani O, et al. A phase III, randomized, placebo&#x2010;controlled study of belimumab, a monoclonal antibody that inhibits B lymphocyte stimulator, in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Rheum. 2011;63:3918&#x2010;3930.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5007058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22127708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ginzler E, Guedes Barbosa LS, D'Cruz D, et al. Phase III/IV, randomized, fifty&#x2010;two&#x2010;week study of the efficacy and safety of belimumab in patients of black African ancestry with systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Rheumatol. 2022;74:112&#x2010;123.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9300099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34164944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanz I, Wei C, Jenks SA, et al. Challenges and opportunities for consistent classification of human B cell and plasma cell populations. Front Immunol. 2019;10:2458.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6813733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31681331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Struemper H, Chen C, Cai W. Population pharmacokinetics of belimumab following intravenous administration in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. J Clin Pharmacol. 2013;53:711&#x2010;720.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23681782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Struemper H, Thapar M, Roth D. Population pharmacokinetic and pharmacodynamic analysis of belimumab administered subcutaneously in healthy volunteers and patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. Clin Pharmacokinet. 2018;57:717&#x2010;728.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5973992</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28887801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dimelow R, Ji B, Struemper H. Pharmacokinetics of belimumab in children with systemic lupus erythematosus. Clin Pharmacol Drug Dev. 2021;10:622&#x2010;633.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8246766</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33245847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gastonguay M. Full Covariate Models as an Alternative to Methods Relying on Statistical Significance for Inferences About Covariate Effects: A Review of Methodology and 42 Case Studies. Population Approach Group in Europe (PAGE) 2011;Abstr. 2229.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carpenter B, Gelman A, Hoffman MD, et al. Stan: a probablistic programming language. J Stat Softw. 2017;76:1&#x2010;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9788645</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36568334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Margossian C, Gillespie WR. Stan functions for Bayesian pharmacometric modeling. J Pharmacokinet Pharmacodyn. 2016;43:S52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Metrum Research Group
. Torsten Version 0.89.0: A pharmacokinetics/pharmacodynamics library for Stan. https://metrumresearchgroup.github.io/Torsten/. Accessed November 24, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman MD, Gelman A. The no&#x2010;U&#x2010;turn sampler: adaptively setting path lengths in Hamiltonian Monte Carlo. J Mach Learn Res. 2011;15:1593&#x2010;1623.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MPI: a message&#x2010;passing interface standard version 3.1. High Performance Computing Center Stuttgart (HLRS); 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewandowski D, Kurowicka D, Joe H. Generating random correlation matrices based on vines and extended onion method. J Multivar Anal. 2009;100:1989&#x2010;2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stohl W, Merrill JT, Looney RJ, et al. Treatment of systemic lupus erythematosus patients with the BAFF antagonist "peptibody" blisibimod (AMG 623/A&#x2010;623): results from randomized, double&#x2010;blind phase 1a and phase 1b trials. Arthritis Res Ther. 2015;17:215.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4545922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26290435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jenks SA, Cashman KS, Woodruff MC, Lee FE, Sanz I. Extrafollicular responses in humans and SLE. Immunol Rev. 2019;288:136&#x2010;148.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6422038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30874345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>