<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36862399</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>31</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2326-5205</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>75</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Arthritis &amp; rheumatology (Hoboken, N.J.)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Arthritis Rheumatol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Involvement of Transcriptional Factor Pbx1 in Peripheral B Cell Homeostasis to Constrain Lupus Autoimmunity.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1381</StartPage><EndPage>1394</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1381-1394</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/art.42487</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">Disruption of B cell homeostasis and subsequent dominance of effector B cell subsets are critical for the development of systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE). Revealing the key intrinsic regulators involved in the homeostatic control of B cells has important therapeutic value for SLE. This study was undertaken to determine the regulatory role of the transcription factor Pbx1 in B cell homeostasis and lupus pathogenesis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">We constructed mice with B cell-specific deletion of Pbx1. T cell-dependent and T cell-independent humoral responses were induced by intraperitoneal injection of nitrophenyl-containing hapten (NP) conjugated to keyhole limpet hemocyanin or NP-Ficoll. The regulatory effects of Pbx1 on autoimmunity were observed in a Bm12-induced lupus murine model. We investigated mechanisms of Pbx1 using RNA sequencing, the cleavage under targets and tagmentation assay, and chromatin immunoprecipitation-quantitative polymerase chain reaction assay. We transduced B cells from SLE patients with plasmids that overexpressed PBX1 to explore the in vitro therapeutic efficacy of PBX1.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Pbx1 was specifically down-regulated in autoimmune B cells and negatively correlated with disease activity. The deficiency of Pbx1 in B cells resulted in excessive humoral responses following immunization. In the Bm12-induced lupus model, mice with B cell-specific Pbx1 deficiency displayed enhancements in germinal center responses, plasma cell differentiation, and autoantibody production. Pbx1-deficient B cells had increased survival and proliferative advantages after activation. Pbx1 regulated genetic programs by directly targeting critical components of the proliferation and apoptosis pathways. In SLE patients, PBX1 expression was negatively correlated with effector B cell expansion; when PBX1 expression was enforced, the survival and proliferative capacity of SLE B cells were attenuated.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">Our study reveals the regulatory function and mechanism of Pbx1 in adjusting B cell homeostasis and highlights Pbx1 as a therapeutic target in SLE.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 American College of Rheumatology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gu</LastName><ForeName>Shuangshuang</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Institute of Rheumatology, Renji Hospital, Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Jinsong</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Institute of Nutrition and Health, Shanghai Institutes for Biological Sciences, University of Chinese Academy of Sciences, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Han</LastName><ForeName>Xiaxia</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Institute of Rheumatology, Renji Hospital, Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ding</LastName><ForeName>Huihua</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7530-8953</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Institute of Rheumatology, Renji Hospital, Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yao</LastName><ForeName>Chao</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Institute of Nutrition and Health, Shanghai Institutes for Biological Sciences, University of Chinese Academy of Sciences, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ye</LastName><ForeName>Zhizhong</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shenzhen Futian Hospital for Rheumatic Diseases, Shenzhen, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yin</LastName><ForeName>Zhihua</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shenzhen Futian Hospital for Rheumatic Diseases, Shenzhen, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hou</LastName><ForeName>Guojun</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Institute of Rheumatology, Renji Hospital, Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jiang</LastName><ForeName>Yang</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Institute of Rheumatology, Renji Hospital, Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Qian</LastName><ForeName>Jie</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Institute of Rheumatology, Renji Hospital, Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Haibo</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Institute of Rheumatology, Renji Hospital, Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, Shanghai, China, and Shenzhen Futian Hospital for Rheumatic Diseases, Shenzhen, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guo</LastName><ForeName>Qiang</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Institute of Rheumatology, Renji Hospital, Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Sheng</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Institute of Rheumatology, Renji Hospital, Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dai</LastName><ForeName>Dai</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Institute of Rheumatology, Renji Hospital, Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shen</LastName><ForeName>Nan</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5875-4417</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Institute of Rheumatology, Renji Hospital, Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, Shanghai, China, Shenzhen Futian Hospital for Rheumatic Diseases, Shenzhen, China, State Key Laboratory of Oncogenes and Related Genes, Shanghai Cancer Institute, Ren Ji Hospital, Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, Shanghai, China, Shanghai Institute of Nutrition and Health, Shanghai Institutes for Biological Sciences, University of Chinese Academy of Sciences, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Shanghai, China, Center of Autoimmune Genomics and Etiology, Division of Human Genetics, Cincinnati Children's Hospital Medical Center, Cincinnati, Ohio, and Department of Pediatrics, University of Cincinnati, Cincinnati, Ohio.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Arthritis Rheumatol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101623795</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2326-5191</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D014157">Transcription Factors</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C481797">Pbx1 protein, mouse</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000075062">Pre-B-Cell Leukemia Transcription Factor 1</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051379" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015551" MajorTopicYN="Y">Autoimmunity</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014157" MajorTopicYN="N">Transcription Factors</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005786" MajorTopicYN="N">Gene Expression Regulation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001402" MajorTopicYN="N">B-Lymphocytes</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000075062" MajorTopicYN="N">Pre-B-Cell Leukemia Transcription Factor 1</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36862399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/art.42487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Sanz I, Lee FE. B cells as therapeutic targets in SLE. Nat Rev Rheumatol 2010;6:326-37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsokos GC, ed. Systemic Lupus Erythematosus: Basic, Applied, and Clinical Aspects. Elsevier/Academic Press; 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wahren-Herlenius M, D&#xf6;rner T. Immunopathogenic mechanisms of systemic autoimmune disease. Lancet 2013;382:819-31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobi AM, Odendahl M, Reiter K, et al. Correlation between circulating CD27high plasma cells and disease activity in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Rheum 2003;48:1332-42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Odendahl M, Jacobi A, Hansen A, et al. Disturbed peripheral B lymphocyte homeostasis in systemic lupus erythematosus. J Immunol 2000;165:5970-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei C, Anolik J, Cappione A, et al. A new population of cells lacking expression of CD27 represents a notable component of the B cell memory compartment in systemic lupus erythematosus. J Immunol 2007;178:6624-33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anolik JH, Barnard J, Cappione A, et al. Rituximab improves peripheral B cell abnormalities in human systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Rheum 2004;50:3580-90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crowley JE, Scholz JL, Quinn WJ III, et al. Homeostatic control of B lymphocyte subsets. Immunol Res 2008;42:75-83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nutt SL, Kee BL. The transcriptional regulation of B cell lineage commitment. Immunity 2007;26:715-25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laidlaw BJ, Cyster JG. Transcriptional regulation of memory B cell differentiation. Nat Rev Immunol 2021;21:209-20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nutt SL, Fairfax KA, Kallies A. BLIMP1 guides the fate of effector B and T cells. Nat Rev Immunol 2007;7:923-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bentham J, Morris DL, Graham DS, et al. Genetic association analyses implicate aberrant regulation of innate and adaptive immunity genes in the pathogenesis of systemic lupus erythematosus. Nat Genet 2015;47:1457-64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harley IT, Kaufman KM, Langefeld CD, et al. Genetic susceptibility to SLE: new insights from fine mapping and genome-wide association studies. Nat Rev Genet 2009;10:285-90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaughn SE, Kottyan LC, Munroe ME, et al. Genetic susceptibility to lupus: the biological basis of genetic risk found in B cell signaling pathways. J Leukoc Biol 2012;92:577-91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morel L. Genetics of SLE: evidence from mouse models. Nat Rev Rheumatol 2010;6:348-57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuda CM, Li S, Liang S, et al. Pre-B cell leukemia homeobox 1 is associated with lupus susceptibility in mice and humans. J Immunol 2012;188:604-14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuda CM, Zeumer L, Sobel ES, et al. Murine lupus susceptibility locus Sle1a requires the expression of two sub-loci to induce inflammatory T cells. Genes Immun 2010;11:542-53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li W, Elshikha AS, Cornaby C, et al. T cells expressing the lupus susceptibility allele Pbx1d enhance autoimmunity and atherosclerosis in dyslipidemic mice. JCI Insight 2020;5:e138274.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sengupta M, Liang S, Potula HH, et al. The SLE-associated Pbx1-d isoform acts as a dominant-negative transcriptional regulator. Genes Immun 2012;13:653-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi SC, Hutchinson TE, Titov AA, et al. The lupus susceptibility gene Pbx1 regulates the balance between follicular helper T cell and regulatory T cell differentiation. J Immunol 2016;197:458-69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hochberg MC. Updating the American College of Rheumatology revised criteria for the classification of systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Rheum 1997;40:1725.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biram A, Shulman Z. Evaluation of B cell proliferation in vivo by EdU incorporation assay. Bio Protoc 2020;10:e3602.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hruz T, Laule O, Szabo G, et al. Genevestigator v3: a reference expression database for the meta-analysis of transcriptomes. Adv Bioinformatics 2008;2008:420747.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanyal M, Tung JW, Karsunky H, et al. B-cell development fails in the absence of the Pbx1 proto-oncogene. Blood 2007;109:4191-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klarquist J, Janssen EM. The bm12 inducible model of systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) in C57BL/6 mice. J Vis Exp 2015;1:e53319.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vinuesa CG, Linterman MA, Yu D, et al. Follicular helper T cells. Annu Rev Immunol 2016;34:335-68.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crotty S. T follicular helper Cell biology: a decade of discovery and diseases. Immunity 2019;50:1132-48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Good-Jacobson KL, Song E, Anderson S, et al. CD80 expression on B cells regulates murine T follicular helper development, germinal center B cell survival, and plasma cell generation. J Immunol 2012;188:4217-25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salek-Ardakani S, Choi YS, Benhnia MR, et al. B cell-specific expression of B7-2 is required for follicular Th cell function in response to vaccinia virus. J Immunol 2011;186:5294-303.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baumjohann D, Preite S, Reboldi A, et al. Persistent antigen and germinal center B cells sustain T follicular helper cell responses and phenotype. Immunity 2013;38:596-605.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herold MJ, McPherson KG, Reichardt HM. Glucocorticoids in T cell apoptosis and function. Cell Mol Life Sci 2006;63:60-72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seki M, Ushiyama C, Seta N, et al. Apoptosis of lymphocytes induced by glucocorticoids and relationship to therapeutic efficacy in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Rheum 1998;41:823-30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller JP, Stadanlick JE, Cancro MP. Space, selection, and surveillance: setting boundaries with BlyS. J Immunol 2006;176:6405-10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaya-Okur HS, Wu SJ, Codomo CA, et al. CUT&amp;Tag for efficient epigenomic profiling of small samples and single cells. Nat Commun 2019;10:1930.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dardaei L, Longobardi E, Blasi F. Prep1 and Meis1 competition for Pbx1 binding regulates protein stability and tumorigenesis. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 2014;111:E896-905.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blasi F, Bruckmann C, Penkov D, et al. A tale of TALE, PREP1, PBX1, and MEIS1: Interconnections and competition in cancer. Bioessays. 2017;39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu S, Zeumer L, Sorensen H, et al. The murine Pbx1-d lupus susceptibility allele accelerates mesenchymal stem cell differentiation and impairs their immunosuppressive function. J Immunol 2015;194:43-55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis KD, Aghaeepour N, Ahn AH, et al. Discovery and validation of biomarkers to aid the development of safe and effective pain therapeutics: challenges and opportunities. Nat Rev Neurol 2020;16:381-400.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jung JG, Shih IM, Park JT, et al. Ovarian cancer chemoresistance relies on the stem cell reprogramming factor PBX1. Cancer Res 2016;76:6351-61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magnani L, Ballantyne EB, Zhang X, et al. PBX1 genomic pioneer function drives Er&#x3b1; signaling underlying progression in breast cancer. PloS Genet 2011;7:e1002368.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shiraishi K, Yamasaki K, Nanba D, et al. Pre-B-cell leukemia transcription factor 1 is a major target of promyelocytic leukemia zinc-finger-mediated melanoma cell growth suppression. Oncogene 2007;26:339-48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ficara F, Murphy MJ, Lin M, et al. Pbx1 regulates self-renewal of long-term hematopoietic stem cells by maintaining their quiescence. Cell Stem Cell 2008;2:484-96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wermuth PJ, Buchberg AM. Meis1-mediated apoptosis is caspase dependent and can be suppressed by coexpression of HoxA9 in murine and human cell lines. Blood 2005;105:1222-30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung EY, Liu J, Homma Y, et al. Interleukin-10 expression in macrophages during phagocytosis of apoptotic cells is mediated by homeodomain proteins Pbx1 and Prep-1. Immunity 2007;27:952-64.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>