<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36884206</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>11</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1534-6307</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>25</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>May</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Current rheumatology reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Curr Rheumatol Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Undifferentiated Connective Tissue Disease: Comprehensive Review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>98</StartPage><EndPage>106</EndPage><MedlinePgn>98-106</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s11926-023-01099-5</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE OF REVIEW">Undifferentiated connective tissue disease (UCTD) is characterized by the presence of clinical symptoms of a systemic autoimmune disease in addition to laboratory evidence of autoimmunity with the patients not fulfilling any of the widely used classification criteria for classic autoimmune diseases. The presence of UCTD as a separate entity versus an early stage of such diseases as systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) or scleroderma has long been debated. Given the uncertainty regarding this condition, we performed a systematic review on the topic.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RECENT FINDINGS">UCTD can be subcategorized as evolving (eUCTD) or stable UCTD (sUCTD) based on its evolution towards a definable autoimmune syndrome. Analyzing the data from six UCTD cohorts published in the literature, we found that 28% of patients have an evolving course with the majority developing SLE or rheumatoid arthritis within 5-6&#xa0;years of the UCTD diagnosis. From the remaining patients, 18% do achieve remission. Published treatment regimens were similar to other mild autoimmune diseases with low-dose prednisone, hydroxychloroquine, and NSAID. One-third of patients did need immune suppressive medications. Importantly, the reported outcomes were excellent with survival rates of more than 90% over 10&#xa0;years. It has to be noted though that as data on patient related outcomes are not available to date, the exact impact of this condition on quality of life is unclear. UCTD is a mild autoimmune condition with generally good outcomes. There is still great uncertainty though regarding diagnosis and management. Going forward, consistent classification criteria are needed to advance UCTD research and eventually provide authoritative guidance on the management of the condition.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer Science+Business Media, LLC, part of Springer Nature.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rubio</LastName><ForeName>Jose</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Rheumatology and Clinical Immunology, Beth Israel Deaconess Medical Center, 110 Francis St, Suite 4B, Boston, MA, 02215, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Clinical Immunology and Rheumatology, University of Alabama at Birmingham, Birmingham, AL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kyttaris</LastName><ForeName>Vasileios C</ForeName><Initials>VC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7652-3826</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Rheumatology and Clinical Immunology, Beth Israel Deaconess Medical Center, 110 Francis St, Suite 4B, Boston, MA, 02215, USA. vkyttari@bidmc.harvard.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA, USA. vkyttari@bidmc.harvard.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Curr Rheumatol Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100888970</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1523-3774</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000074079" MajorTopicYN="Y">Undifferentiated Connective Tissue Diseases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001327" MajorTopicYN="Y">Autoimmune Diseases</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001172" MajorTopicYN="Y">Arthritis, Rheumatoid</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003240" MajorTopicYN="Y">Connective Tissue Diseases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Autoantibodies</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Criteria</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Early SLE</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Undifferentiated connective tissue disease</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36884206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11926-023-01099-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s11926-023-01099-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Papers of particular interest, published recently, have been highlighted as: &#x2022; Of importance &#x2022;&#x2022; Of major importance</Title><Reference><Citation>Antunes M, Scire CA, Talarico R, Alexander T, Avcin T, Belocchi C, et al. Undifferentiated connective tissue disease: state of the art on clinical practice guidelines. RMD Open. 2018;4(Suppl 1):e000786. https://doi.org/10.1136/rmdopen-2018-000786 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/rmdopen-2018-000786</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30886731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alarcon GS, Williams GV, Singer JZ, Steen VD, Clegg DO, Paulus HE, et al. Early undifferentiated connective tissue disease. I. Early clinical manifestation in a large cohort of patients with undifferentiated connective tissue diseases compared with cohorts of well established connective tissue disease. J Rheumatol. 1991;18(9):1332&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1757934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>LeRoy EC, Maricq HR, Kahaleh MB. Undifferentiated connective tissue syndromes. Arthritis Rheum. 1980;23(3):341&#x2013;3. https://doi.org/10.1002/art.1780230312 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/art.1780230312</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7362686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calvo-Alen J, Alarcon GS, Burgard SL, Burst N, Bartolucci AA, Williams HJ. Systemic lupus erythematosus: predictors of its occurrence among a cohort of patients with early undifferentiated connective tissue disease: multivariate analyses and identification of risk factors. J Rheumatol. 1996;23(3):469&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8832985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mosca M, Tavoni A, Neri R, Bencivelli W, Bombardieri S. Undifferentiated connective tissue diseases: the clinical and serological profiles of 91 patients followed for at least 1 year. Lupus. 1998;7(2):95&#x2013;100. https://doi.org/10.1191/096120398678919787 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1191/096120398678919787</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9541093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Danieli MG, Fraticelli P, Salvi A, Gabrielli A, Danieli G. Undifferentiated connective tissue disease: natural history and evolution into definite CTD assessed in 84 patients initially diagnosed as early UCTD. Clin Rheumatol. 1998;17(3):195&#x2013;201. https://doi.org/10.1007/BF01451046 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF01451046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9694051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mosca M, Neri R, Bombardieri S. Undifferentiated connective tissue diseases (UCTD): a review of the literature and a proposal for preliminary classification criteria. Clin Exp Rheumatol. 1999;17(5):615&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10544849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Danieli MG, Fraticelli P, Franceschini F, Cattaneo R, Farsi A, Passaleva A, et al. Five-year follow-up of 165 Italian patients with undifferentiated connective tissue diseases. Clin Exp Rheumatol. 1999;17(5):585&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10544842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cavazzana I, Franceschini F, Belfiore N, Quinzanini M, Caporali R, Calzavara-Pinton P, et al. Undifferentiated connective tissue disease with antibodies to Ro/SSa: clinical features and follow-up of 148 patients. Clin Exp Rheumatol. 2001;19(4):403&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11491495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bodolay E, Csiki Z, Szekanecz Z, Ben T, Kiss E, Zeher M, et al. Five-year follow-up of 665 Hungarian patients with undifferentiated connective tissue disease (UCTD). Clin Exp Rheumatol. 2003;21(3):313&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12846049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Angelis R, Cerioni A, Del Medico P, Blasetti P. Raynaud&#x2019;s phenomenon in undifferentiated connective tissue disease (UCTD). Clin Rheumatol. 2005;24(2):145&#x2013;51. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10067-004-0988-2 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10067-004-0988-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15351873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaz CC, Couto M, Medeiros D, Miranda L, Costa J, Nero P, et al. Undifferentiated connective tissue disease: a seven-center cross-sectional study of 184 patients. Clin Rheumatol. 2009;28(8):915&#x2013;21. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10067-009-1175-2 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10067-009-1175-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19390908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castellino G, Capucci R, Bernardi S, Padovan M, Giacuzzo S, Pivato E, et al. Pregnancy in patients with undifferentiated connective tissue disease: a prospective case-control study. Lupus. 2011;20(12):1305&#x2013;11. https://doi.org/10.1177/0961203311409610 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0961203311409610</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21813586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guerrero LF, Rueda JC, Arciniegas R, Rueda JM. Undifferentiated connective tissue disease in a rheumatology center in Cali, Colombia: clinical features of 94 patients followed for a year. Rheumatol Int. 2013;33(4):1085&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00296-011-2234-y .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00296-011-2234-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22116525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia-Gonzalez M, Rodriguez-Lozano B, Bustabad S, Ferraz-Amaro I. Undifferentiated connective tissue disease: predictors of evolution into definite disease. Clin Exp Rheumatol. 2017;35(5):739&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28770704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x2022; Zucchi D, Tani C, Monacci F, Elefante E, Carli L, Parma A, et al. Pregnancy and undifferentiated connective tissue disease: outcome and risk of flare in 100 pregnancies. Rheumatology (Oxford). 2020;59(6):1335&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.1093/rheumatology/kez440 . This study demonstrates that pregnant UCTD patients have less adverse pregnancy outcomes when compared to individuals with a established CTD. Nonetheless, careful evaluation is suggested given that a minority of patients can still develop complications.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x2022; Radin M, Rubini E, Cecchi I, Foddai SG, Barinotti A, Rossi D, et al. Disease evolution in a long-term follow-up of 104 undifferentiated connective tissue disease patients. Clin Exp Rheumatol. 2022;40(3):575&#x2013;80. https://doi.org/10.55563/clinexprheumatol/7vp1bo . This single center study shows that up to 21% of UCTD patients progress to a definitive disease, results that are in line with our current report.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mosca M, Tani C, Bombardieri S. Undifferentiated connective tissue diseases (UCTD): a new frontier for rheumatology. Best Pract Res Clin Rheumatol. 2007;21(6):1011&#x2013;23. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.berh.2007.09.004 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.berh.2007.09.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18068858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x2022;&#x2022; Sciascia S, Roccatello D, Radin M, Parodis I, Yazdany J, Pons-Estel G, et al. Differentiating between UCTD and early-stage SLE: from definitions to clinical approach. Nat Rev Rheumatol. 2022;18(1):9&#x2013;21. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41584-021-00710-2 . This review provides insight into key differences between UCTD and early SLE stages, additionally authors suggest a nomeclature for the SLE spectrum.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x2022;&#x2022; Drehmel KR, Erickson AR, England BR, Michaud KD, Sayles HR, Hearth-Holmes MP. Applying SLICC and ACR/EULAR systemic lupus erythematosus classification criteria in a cohort of patients with undifferentiated connective tissue disease. Lupus. 2021;30(2):280&#x2013;4. https://doi.org/10.1177/0961203320976939 . This study demonstrates that UCTD patients can be reclassified as SLE (14 - 20%) after adopting the latest SLE criteria.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mosca M, Tani C, Carli L, Della Rossa A, Talarico R, Baldini C, et al. Analysis of the evolution of UCTD to defined CTD after a long term follow-up. Clin Exp Rheumatol. 2013;31(3):471.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23075608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mosca M, Neri R, Bencivelli W, Tavoni A, Bombardieri S. Undifferentiated connective tissue disease: analysis of 83 patients with a minimum followup of 5 years. J Rheumatol. 2002;29(11):2345&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12415590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams HJ, Alarcon GS, Joks R, Steen VD, Bulpitt K, Clegg DO, et al. Early undifferentiated connective tissue disease (CTD). VI. An inception cohort after 10 years: disease remissions and changes in diagnoses in well established and undifferentiated CTD. J Rheumatol. 1999;26(4):816&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10229402</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>James JA, Kim-Howard XR, Bruner BF, Jonsson MK, McClain MT, Arbuckle MR, et al. Hydroxychloroquine sulfate treatment is associated with later onset of systemic lupus erythematosus. Lupus. 2007;16(6):401&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.1177/0961203307078579 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0961203307078579</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17664230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lambers WM, Westra J, Bootsma H, de Leeuw K. From incomplete to complete systemic lupus erythematosus; a review of the predictive serological immune markers. Semin Arthritis Rheum. 2021;51(1):43&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.semarthrit.2020.11.006 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.semarthrit.2020.11.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33360229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iudici M, Irace R, Riccardi A, Cuomo G, Vettori S, Valentini G. Longitudinal analysis of quality of life in patients with undifferentiated connective tissue diseases. Patient Relat Outcome Meas. 2017;8:7&#x2013;13. https://doi.org/10.2147/PROM.S117767 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/PROM.S117767</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28203114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5295807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lambers WM, Westra J, Arends S, Doornbos-van der Meer B, Horvath B, Bootsma H, et al. Persistent low complement levels and increased interferon gene expression are predictive for disease progression in patients with incomplete systemic lupus erythematosus. Joint Bone Spine. 2022;89(5):105381. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jbspin.2022.105381 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jbspin.2022.105381</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35500799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luciano N, Baldini C, Tarantini G, Ferro F, Sernissi F, Varanini V, et al. Ultrasonography of major salivary glands: a highly specific tool for distinguishing primary Sjogren&#x2019;s syndrome from undifferentiated connective tissue diseases. Rheumatology (Oxford). 2015;54(12):2198&#x2013;204. https://doi.org/10.1093/rheumatology/kev253 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/rheumatology/kev253</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26206346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>