<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36897027</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>30</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1096-9071</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>95</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of medical virology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Med Virol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Mendelian randomization analysis suggests no associations of herpes simplex virus infections with systemic lupus erythematosus.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e28649</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e28649</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jmv.28649</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) characterized by immune dysfunction is possibly more vulnerable to herpes simplex virus (HSV) infection. The infection has been intensively considered a common onset and exacerbation of SLE. This study is aimed at elucidating the causal association between SLE and HSV. A bidirectional two-sample Mendelian Randomization (TSMR) analysis was systematically conducted to explore the causal effect of SLE and HSV on each other. The causality was estimated by inverse variance weighted (IVW), MR-Egger and weighted median methods based on the summary-level genome-wide association studies (GWAS) data from a publicly available database. Genetically proxied HSV infection exhibited no causal association with SLE in the forward MR analysis using IVW method (odds ratio [OR]&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.987; 95% confidence interval [CI]: 0.891-1.093; p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.798), nor did HSV-1 IgG (OR&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.241; 95% CI: 0.874-1.762; p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.227) and HSV-2 IgG (OR&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.934; 95% CI: 0.821-1.062; p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.297). Similar null results with HSV infection (OR&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.021; 95% CI: 0.986-1.057; p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.245), HSV-1 IgG (OR&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.003; 95% CI: 0.982-1.024; p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.788) and HSV-2 IgG (OR&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.034; 95% CI: 0.991-1.080; p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.121) were observed in the reverse MR where SLE served as the exposure. Our study demonstrated no causal association between the genetically predicted HSV and SLE.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Authors. Journal of Medical Virology published by Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chang</LastName><ForeName>Min-Jing</ForeName><Initials>MJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8875-9254</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanxi Key Laboratory of Big Data for Clinical Decision, Shanxi Medical University, Taiyuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ministry of Education, Key Laboratory of Cellular Physiology, Shanxi Medical University, Taiyuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Meng-Ting</ForeName><Initials>MT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanxi Key Laboratory of Big Data for Clinical Decision, Shanxi Medical University, Taiyuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Miao-Ran</ForeName><Initials>MR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ministry of Education, Key Laboratory of Cellular Physiology, Shanxi Medical University, Taiyuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Nan</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ministry of Education, Key Laboratory of Cellular Physiology, Shanxi Medical University, Taiyuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Yu-Hui</ForeName><Initials>YH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ministry of Education, Key Laboratory of Cellular Physiology, Shanxi Medical University, Taiyuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Sheng-Xiao</ForeName><Initials>SX</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ministry of Education, Key Laboratory of Cellular Physiology, Shanxi Medical University, Taiyuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rheumatology, Second Hospital of Shanxi Medical University, Taiyuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>He</LastName><ForeName>Pei-Feng</ForeName><Initials>PF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanxi Key Laboratory of Big Data for Clinical Decision, Shanxi Medical University, Taiyuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yu</LastName><ForeName>Qi</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Management, Shanxi Medical University, Taiyuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Med Virol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7705876</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0146-6615</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>56562-79-9</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C015595">P297</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000914">Antibodies, Viral</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D007074">Immunoglobulin G</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="CommentIn"><RefSource>J Med Virol. 2023 Mar;95(3):e28689</RefSource><PMID Version="1">36946496</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057182" MajorTopicYN="N">Mendelian Randomization Analysis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055106" MajorTopicYN="N">Genome-Wide Association Study</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006561" MajorTopicYN="Y">Herpes Simplex</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000914" MajorTopicYN="N">Antibodies, Viral</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007074" MajorTopicYN="N">Immunoglobulin G</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020641" MajorTopicYN="N">Polymorphism, Single Nucleotide</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bidirectional Mendelian randomization</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">genetic association</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">herpes simplex virus (HSV)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">immunoglobulinG (IgG)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE)</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36897027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmv.28649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Whitley RJ, Roizman B. Herpes simplex virus infections. Lancet. 2001;357:1513-1518.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan L, Lu MP, Wang JH, Xu M, Yang SR. Immunological pathogenesis and treatment of systemic lupus erythematosus. World J Pediatr. 2020;16:19-30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durcan L, O'Dwyer T, Petri M. Management strategies and future directions for systemic lupus erythematosus in adults. Lancet. 2019;393:2332-2343.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan Q, Xing X, Lu Z, Li X. Clinical characteristics and risk factors of infection in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: a systematic review and meta-analysis of observational studies. Semin Arthritis Rheum. 2020;50:1022-1039.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quaglia M, Merlotti G, De Andrea M, Borgogna C, Cantaluppi V. Viral infections and systemic lupus erythematosus: new players in an old story. Viruses. 2021;13:277.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iwata S, Tanaka Y. Association of viral infection with the development and pathogenesis of systemic lupus erythematosus. Front Med. 2022;9:849120.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rigante D, Mazzoni MB, Esposito S. The cryptic interplay between systemic lupus erythematosus and infections. Autoimmun Rev. 2014;13:96-102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zandman-Goddard G, Shoenfeld Y, Zandman-Goddard G, Shoenfeld Y. Infections and SLE. Autoimmunity. 2005;38:473-485.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiao J, Zhang SX, Chang MJ, et al. Deep stratification by transcriptome molecular characters for precision treatment of patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. Rheumatology (Oxford). 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>James C, Harfouche M, Welton NJ, et al. Herpes simplex virus: global infection prevalence and incidence estimates, 2016. Bull World Health Organ. 2020;98:315-329.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan C, Luo Z, Li W, et al. Disturbed Yin-Yang balance: stress increases the susceptibility to primary and recurrent infections of herpes simplex virus type 1. Acta Pharm Sin B. 2020;B10:383-398.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akhtar LN, Szpara ML. Viral genetic diversity and its potential contributions to the development and progression of neonatal herpes simplex virus (HSV) disease. Curr Clin Microbiol Rep. 2019;6:249-256.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Criscuolo E, Castelli M, Diotti RA, et al. Cell-to-cell spread blocking activity is extremely limited in the sera of herpes simplex virus 1 (HSV-1)- and HSV-2-Infected subjects. J Virol. 2019;93:e00070-19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fatahzadeh M, Schwartz RA. Human herpes simplex virus infections: epidemiology, pathogenesis, symptomatology, diagnosis, and management. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2007;57:737-763.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharpe NG, Isenberg D, Williams DG, Latchman DS. Elevation of the levels of SmB, B' and D proteins but not that of the La (SS-B) antigen during HSV infections. J Autoimmun. 1989;2:701-708.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Unterholzner L. The interferon response to intracellular DNA: why so many receptors? Immunobiology. 2013;218:1312-1321.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cederblad B, Blomberg S, Vallin H, Perers A, Alm GV, R&#xf6;nnblom L. Patients with systemic lupus erythematosus have reduced numbers of circulating natural interferon-&#x3b1;- producing cells. J Autoimmun. 1998;11:465-470.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Ceuninck F, Duguet F, Aussy A, Laigle L, Moingeon P. IFN-&#x3b1;: a key therapeutic target for multiple autoimmune rheumatic diseases. Drug Discovery Today. 2021;26:2465-2473.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li TH, Lai CC, Wang WH, et al. Risk of severe herpes simplex virus infection in systemic lupus erythematosus: analysis of epidemiology and risk factors analysis in Taiwan. Ann Rheum Dis. 2019;78:941-946.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vista ES, Weisman MH, Ishimori ML, et al. Strong viral associations with SLE among Filipinos. Lupus Sci Med. 2017;4:000214.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ElMelegy T, Radwan A, Herdan O, Rashed H. Does herpes simplex virus have a role in the pathogenesis of systemic lupus erythematosus in Egyptians? Egypt J Immunol. 2022;29:48-56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Us T, Cetin E, Ka&#x15f;ifo&#x11f;lu N, Ka&#x15f;ifo&#x11f;lu T, Akg&#xfc;n Y. Investigation of Epstein-Barr virus and herpes simplex virus markers by serological and molecular methods in patients with rheumatoid arthritis and systemic lupus erythematosus]. Mikrobiyol Nul. 2011;45:677-683.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davey Smith G, Ebrahim S. &#x2018;Mendelian randomization': can genetic epidemiology contribute to understanding environmental determinants of disease? Int J Epidemiol. 2003;32:1-22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mo X, Guo Y, Qian Q, et al. Mendelian randomization analysis revealed potential causal factors for systemic lupus erythematosus. Immunology. 2020;159:279-288.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dan YL, Wang P, Cheng Z, et al. Circulating adiponectin levels and systemic lupus erythematosus: a two-sample Mendelian randomization study. Rheumatology. 2021;60:940-946.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwok MK, Schooling CM. Herpes simplex virus and Alzheimer's disease: a Mendelian randomization study. Neurobiol Aging. 2021;99:101.e11-101.e13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang W, Wu P, Yin R, et al. Mendelian randomization analysis suggests no associations of herpes simplex virus infections with multiple sclerosis. Front Neurosci. 2022;16:817067.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johansson PJ, Hallberg T, Oxelius VA, Grubb A, Blomberg J. Human immunoglobulin class and subclass specificity of Fc receptors induced by herpes simplex virus type 1. J Virol. 1984;50:796-804.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skrivankova VW, Richmond RC, Woolf BAR, et al. Strengthening the reporting of observational studies in epidemiology using Mendelian randomization: the STROBE-MR statement. JAMA. 2021;326:1614-1621.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boef AGC, Dekkers OM, le Cessie S. Mendelian randomization studies: a review of the approaches used and the quality of reporting. Int J Epidemiol. 2015;44:496-511.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scepanovic P, Alanio C, Hammer C, et al. Human genetic variants and age are the strongest predictors of humoral immune responses to common pathogens and vaccines. Genome Med. 2018;10:59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bentham J, Morris DL, Cunninghame Graham DS, et al. Genetic association analyses implicate aberrant regulation of innate and adaptive immunity genes in the pathogenesis of systemic lupus erythematosus. Nature Genet. 2015;47:1457-1464.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burgess S, Thompson SG. Interpreting findings from Mendelian randomization using the MR-Egger method. Eur J Epidemiol. 2017;32:377-389.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowden J, Davey Smith G, Haycock PC, Burgess S. Consistent estimation in Mendelian randomization with some invalid instruments using a weighted median estimator. Genet Epidemiol. 2016;40:304-314.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hemani G, Zheng J, Elsworth B, et al. The MR-base platform supports systematic causal inference across the human phenome. eLife. 2018;7:e34408.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta A, Jogi V, Goyal M, Modi M, Khurana D. Chronic meningitis in systemic lupus erythematosus: an unusual etiology. Ann Indian Acad Neurol. 2014;17:426-428.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L, Liu J, Li M. Herpes simplex virus type 1 encephalitis and unusual retinitis in a patient with systemic lupus erythematosus. Lupus. 2013;22:1403-1408.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Catoggio C, Alvarez-Ur&#xed;a A, Fernandez P, Cervera R, Espinosa G. Catastrophic antiphospholipid syndrome triggered by fulminant disseminated herpes simplex infection in a patient with systemic lupus erythematosus. Lupus. 2012;21:1359-1361.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Decout A, Katz JD, Venkatraman S, Ablasser A. The cGAS-STING pathway as a therapeutic target in inflammatory diseases. Nat Rev Immunol. 2021;21:548-569.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian M, Liu W, Zhang Q, et al. MYSM1 represses innate immunity and autoimmunity through suppressing the cGAS-STING pathway. Cell Rep. 2020;33:108297.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jenks JA, Goodwin ML, Permar SR. The roles of host and viral antibody fc receptors in herpes simplex virus (HSV) and human cytomegalovirus (HCMV) infections and immunity. Front Immunol. 2019;10:2110.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa AS, Agostini S, Guerini FR, Mancuso R, Clerici M, Pandey JP. Relation between FCGRIIB rs1050501 and HSV-1 specific IgG antibodies in Alzheimer's disease. J Transl Med. 2020;18:325.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith KGC, Clatworthy MR. Fc&#x3b3;RIIB in autoimmunity and infection: evolutionary and therapeutic implications. Nat Rev Immunol. 2010;10:328-343.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pincetic A, Bournazos S, DiLillo DJ, et al. Type I and type II Fc receptors regulate innate and adaptive immunity. Nat Immunol. 2014;15:707-716.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reis AD, Mudinutti C, de Freitas Peigo M, et al. Correction to: active human herpesvirus infections in adults with systemic lupus erythematosus and correlation with the SLEDAI score. Adv Rheumatol. 2020;60:47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lino K, Alves LS, Trizzotti N, et al. Evaluation of herpesvirus members on hospital admission in patients with systemic lupus erythematous shows higher frequency of Epstein-Barr virus and its associated renal dysfunction. Jornal Brasileiro de Nefrologia. 2022;44:490-497.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui Y, Yu H, Zheng X, et al. SENP7 potentiates cGAS activation by relieving SUMO-mediated inhibition of cytosolic DNA sensing. PLoS Pathog. 2017;13:e1006156.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Witt MN, Braun GS, Ihrler S, Schmid H. Occurrence of HSV-1-induced pneumonitis in patients under standard immunosuppressive therapy for rheumatic, vasculitic, and connective tissue disease. BMC Pulm Med. 2009;9:22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wood RA, Guthridge L, Thurmond E, et al. Serologic markers of Epstein-Barr virus reactivation are associated with increased disease activity, inflammation, and interferon pathway activation in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. J Transl Autoimmun. 2021;4:100117.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Qu J, Luo L, Xu Z, Zou X. Multigenomics reveals the causal effect of herpes simplex virus in Alzheimer's disease: a two-sample Mendelian randomization study. Front Genet. 2021;12:773725.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>