<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36890668</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>04</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1756-185X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of rheumatic diseases</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Rheum Dis</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Genetic predisposition between coronavirus disease 2019 and rheumatic diseases: A 2-sample Mendelian randomization study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>710</StartPage><EndPage>717</EndPage><MedlinePgn>710-717</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/1756-185X.14624</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The causalities between the coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) and the risk of rheumatic diseases remain unclear. The purpose of this study was to investigate the causal effect of COVID-19 on rheumatic disease occurrence.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Single nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs), acquired from published genome-wide association studies, were used to perform 2-sample Mendelian randomization (MR) on cases diagnosed with COVID-19 (n&#xa0;=&#xa0;13&#x2009;464), rheumatic diseases (n&#xa0;=&#xa0;444&#x2009;199), juvenile idiopathic arthritis (JIA, n&#xa0;=&#xa0;15&#x2009;872), gout (n&#xa0;=&#xa0;69&#xa0;&#x2009;374), systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE, n&#xa0;=&#xa0;3094), ankylosing spondylitis (n&#xa0;=&#xa0;75&#x2009;130), primary biliary cholangitis (PBC, n&#xa0;=&#xa0;11&#x2009;375) and primary Sj&#xf6;gren's syndrome (n&#xa0;=&#xa0;95&#x2009;046). Three MR methods were used in the analysis based on different heterogeneity and pleiotropy using the Bonferroni correction.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The results revealed a causality between COVID-19 and rheumatic diseases with an odds ratio (OR) of 1.010 (95% confidence interval [CI], 1.006-1.013; P&#xa0;=&#xa0;.014). In addition, we observed that COVID-19 was causally associated with an increased risk of JIA (OR 1.517; 95%CI, 1.144-2.011; P&#xa0;=&#xa0;.004), PBC (OR 1.370; 95%CI, 1.149-1.635; P&#xa0;=&#xa0;.005), but a decreased risk of SLE (OR 0.732; 95%CI, 0.590-0.908; P&#xa0;=&#xa0;.004). Using MR, 8 SNPs were identified to associate with COVID-19 and recognized as significant variables. None of them were previously reported in any other diseases.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This is the first study to use MR to explore the impact of COVID-19 on rheumatic diseases. From a genetic perspective, we found that COVID-19 could increase the risk of rheumatic diseases, such as PBC and JIA, but decrease that of SLE, thereby suggesting a potential surge in the disease burden of PBC and JIA following the COVID-19 pandemic.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 Asia Pacific League of Associations for Rheumatology and John Wiley &amp; Sons Australia, Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Quan</LastName><ForeName>Liuliu</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4599-6174</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rheumatology, Peking Union Medical College Hospital, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences &amp; Peking Union Medical College, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tan</LastName><ForeName>Jiangshan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Fuwai Hospital, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences &amp; Peking Union Medical College and National Clinical Research Center of Cardiovascular Diseases, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hua</LastName><ForeName>Lu</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Fuwai Hospital, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences &amp; Peking Union Medical College and National Clinical Research Center of Cardiovascular Diseases, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>You</LastName><ForeName>Xin</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rheumatology, Peking Union Medical College Hospital, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences &amp; Peking Union Medical College, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Rheumatology &amp; Clinical Immunology, Ministry of Education, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Clinical Research Center for Dermatologic and Immunologic Diseases (NCRC-DID), Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>L222085</GrantID><Agency>Haidian Original Frontier Project of Beijing Natural Science Foundation</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Rheum Dis</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101474930</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1756-1841</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020022" MajorTopicYN="N">Genetic Predisposition to Disease</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055106" MajorTopicYN="N">Genome-Wide Association Study</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057182" MajorTopicYN="N">Mendelian Randomization Analysis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058873" MajorTopicYN="N">Pandemics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012216" MajorTopicYN="Y">Rheumatic Diseases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020641" MajorTopicYN="N">Polymorphism, Single Nucleotide</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mendelian randomization</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">coronavirus disease 2019</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">juvenile idiopathic arthritis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">primary biliary cholangitis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">systemic lupus erythematosus</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36890668</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1756-185X.14624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Ji D, Cai W, et al. Clinical characteristics, cause analysis and infectivity of COVID-19 nucleic acid repositive patients: a literature review. J Med Virol. 2021;93(3):1288-1295.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu J, Ji P, Pang J, et al. Clinical characteristics of 3062 COVID-19 patients: a meta-analysis. J Med Virol. 2020;92(10):1902-1914.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zargaran M, Movassaghi S, Seyyedsalehi MS, Zendehdel K, Rostamian A. Outcomes of coronavirus disease 19 patients with a history of rheumatoid arthritis: a retrospective registry-based study in Iran. Int J Rheum Dis. 2022;25(10):1196-1199.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orlandi M, Landini N, Sambataro G, et al. The role of chest CT in deciphering interstitial lung involvement: systemic sclerosis versus COVID-19. Rheumatology (Oxford). 2022;61(4):1600-1609.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baratella E, Ruaro B, Marrocchio C, et al. Interstitial lung disease at high resolution CT after SARS-CoV-2-related acute respiratory distress syndrome according to pulmonary segmental anatomy. J Clin Med. 2021;10(17):3985.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun P, Ren J, Li K, Qie S, Liu Z, Xi J. Clinical characteristics of hospitalized patients with SARS-CoV-2 infection: a single arm meta-analysis. J Med Virol. 2020;92:612-617.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He F, Luo Q, Lei M, et al. Successful recovery of recurrence of positive SARS-CoV-2 RNA in COVID-19 patient with systemic lupus erythematosus: a case report and review. Reumatol Clin. 2020;39(9):2803-2810.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roger G, Pavot A, Bonnet I, Ferlicot S, Mariette X. Phenotypic switch from non-active primary Sj&#xf6;gren's syndrome to severe systemic lupus erythematosus after COVID-19 infection in an elderly man. Joint Bone Spine. 2021;88(6):105228.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fireizen Y, Shahriary C, Imperial ME, Randhawa I, Nianiaris N, Ovunc B. Pediatric P-ANCA vasculitis following COVID-19. Pediatr Pulmonol. 2021;56(10):3422-3424.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naddei R, Alfani R, Bove M, et al. Increased relapse rate during COVID-19 lockdown in an Italian cohort of children with juvenile idiopathic arthritis. Arthritis Care Res. 2023;75(2):326-331.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malek Mahdavi A, Varshochi M, Hajialilo M, Dastgiri S, Khabbazi R, Khabbazi A. Factors associated with COVID-19 and its outcome in patients with rheumatoid arthritis. Reumatol Clin. 2021;40(11):4527-4531.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azkur AK, Akdis M, Azkur D, et al. Immune response to SARS-CoV-2 and mechanisms of immunopathological changes in COVID-19. Allergy. 2020;75(7):1564-1581.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jesenak M, Brndiarova M, Urbancikova I, et al. Immune parameters and COVID-19 infection - associations with clinical severity and disease prognosis. Front Cell Infect Microbiol. 2020;10:364.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davey Smith G, Hemani G. Mendelian randomization: genetic anchors for causal inference in epidemiological studies. Hum Mol Genet. 2014;23(R1):R89-R98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowden J, Holmes MV. Meta-analysis and mendelian randomization: a review. Res Synth Methods. 2019;10(4):486-496.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emdin CA, Khera AV, Kathiresan S. Mendelian randomization. Jama. 2017;318(19):1925-1926.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan JS, Liu NN, Guo TT, Hu S, Hua L. Genetic predisposition to COVID-19 may increase the risk of hypertension disorders in pregnancy: a two-sample mendelian randomization study. Pregnancy Hypertens. 2021;26:17-23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riaz H, Khan MS, Siddiqi TJ, et al. Association between obesity and cardiovascular outcomes: a systematic review and meta-analysis of mendelian randomization studies. JAMA Netw Open. 2018;1(7):e183788.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richmond RC, Hemani G, Tilling K, Davey Smith G, Relton CL. Challenges and novel approaches for investigating molecular mediation. Hum Mol Genet. 2016;25(R2):R149-R156.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawlor DA. Commentary: two-sample mendelian randomization: opportunities and challenges. Int J Epidemiol. 2016;45(3):908-915.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pairo-Castineira E, Clohisey S, Klaric L, et al. Genetic mechanisms of critical illness in COVID-19. Nature. 2021;591(7848):92-98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Locke AE, Kahali B, Berndt SI, et al. Genetic studies of body mass index yield new insights for obesity biology. Nature. 2015;518(7538):197-206.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nazarzadeh M, Pinho-Gomes AC, Bidel Z, et al. Plasma lipids and risk of aortic valve stenosis: a mendelian randomization study. Eur Heart J. 2020;41(40):3913-3920.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martelli J&#xfa;nior H, Gueiros LA, de Lucena EG, Coletta RD. Increase in the number of Sj&#xf6;gren's syndrome cases in Brazil in the COVID-19 era. Oral Dis. 2021;28(Suppl 2):2588-2590.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luther R, Skeoch S, Pauling JD, Curd C, Woodgate F, Tansley S. Increased number of cases of giant cell arteritis and higher rates of ophthalmic involvement during the era of COVID-19. Rheumatol Adv Pract. 2020;4(2):rkaa067.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh B, Kaur P, Maroules M. Autoimmune hepatitis-primary biliary cholangitis overlap syndrome triggered by COVID-19. Eur J Case Rep Intern Med. 2021;8(3):002264.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang KT, Hsu BC, Chen DY. Autoimmune and rheumatic manifestations associated with COVID-19 in adults: an updated systematic review. Front Immuno. 2021;12:645013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharifian-Dorche M, Bahmanyar M, Sharifian-Dorche A, Mohammadi P, Nomovi M, Mowla A. Vaccine-induced immune thrombotic thrombocytopenia and cerebral venous sinus thrombosis post COVID-19 vaccination; a systematic review. J Neurol Sci. 2021;428:117607.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haslak F, Gunalp A, Cebi MN, et al. Early experience of COVID-19 vaccine-related adverse events among adolescents and young adults with rheumatic diseases: a single-center study. Int J Rheum Dis. 2022;25(3):353-363.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohanasundaram K, Santhanam S, Natarajan R, et al. Covid-19 vaccination in autoimmune rheumatic diseases: a multi-center survey from southern India. Int J Rheum Dis. 2022;25(9):1046-1052.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sachinidis A, Garyfallos A. COVID-19 vaccination can occasionally trigger autoimmune phenomena, probably via inducing age-associated B cells. Int J Rheum Dis. 2022;25(1):83-85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirschfield GM, Gershwin ME. The immunobiology and pathophysiology of primary biliary cirrhosis. Annu Rev Pathol. 2013;8:303-330.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartoli A, Gitto S, Sighinolfi P, Cursaro C, Andreone P. Primary biliary cholangitis associated with SARS-CoV-2 infection. J Hepatol. 2021;74(5):1245-1246.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan Z, Chen L, Li J, et al. Clinical features of COVID-19-related liver functional abnormality. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2020;18(7):1561-1566.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarin SK, Choudhury A, Lau GK, et al. Pre-existing liver disease is associated with poor outcome in patients with SARS CoV2 infection; the APCOLIS study (APASL COVID-19 liver injury Spectrum study). Hepatol Int. 2020;14(5):690-700.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia M, Gonzalez P, Li C, et al. Mitophagy enhances oncolytic measles virus replication by mitigating DDX58/RIG-I-like receptor signaling. J Virol. 2014;88(9):5152-5164.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohta A, Nishiyama Y. Mitochondria and viruses. Mitochondrion. 2011;11(1):1-12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harrold LR, Salman C, Shoor S, et al. Incidence and prevalence of juvenile idiopathic arthritis among children in a managed care population, 1996-2009. J Rheumatol. 2013;40(7):1218-1225.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petty RE, Southwood TR, Manners P, et al. International league of associations for rheumatology classification of juvenile idiopathic arthritis: second revision, Edmonton, 2001. J Rheumatol. 2004;31(2):390-392.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boyarchuk O, Predyk L, Yuryk I. COVID-19 in patients with juvenile idiopathic arthritis: frequency and severity. Reumatologia. 2021;59(3):197-199.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohamadian M, Chiti H, Shoghli A, Biglari S, Parsamanesh N, Esmaeilzadeh A. COVID-19: virology, biology and novel laboratory diagnosis. J Gene Med. 2021;23(2):e3303.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khailany RA, Safdar M, Ozaslan M. Genomic characterization of a novel SARS-CoV-2. Gene Rep. 2020;19:100682.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elemam NM, Maghazachi AA, Hannawi S. COVID-19 infection and rheumatoid arthritis: mutual outburst cytokines and remedies. Curr Med Res Opin. 2021;37(6):929-938.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bell LCK, Meydan C, Kim J, et al. Transcriptional response modules characterize IL-1&#x3b2; and IL-6 activity in COVID-19. iScience. 2021;24(1):101896.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGonagle D, Ramanan AV, Bridgewood C. Immune cartography of macrophage activation syndrome in the COVID-19 era. Nat Rev Rheumatol. 2021;17(3):145-157.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khalid MZ, Rogers S, Fatima A, Dawe M, Singh R. A flare of systemic lupus erythematosus disease after COVID-19 infection: a case of lupus cerebritis. Cureus. 2021;13(7):e16104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guven F, Ogul H, Turgut A, Tezcan A, Kantarci M. Leptomeningeal involvement in a patient with systemic lupus erythematosus infected by COVID-19. Joint Bone Spine. 2020;87(5):495.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reiff DD, Meyer CG, Marlin B, Mannion ML. New onset ANCA-associated vasculitis in an adolescent during an acute COVID-19 infection: a case report. BMC Pediatr. 2021;21(1):333.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Y, Han T, Chen J, et al. Clinical and autoimmune characteristics of severe and critical cases of COVID-19. Clin Transl Sci. 2020;13(6):1077-1086.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sokolowska M, Lukasik ZM, Agache I, et al. Immunology of COVID-19: mechanisms, clinical outcome, diagnostics, and perspectives-a report of the European academy of allergy and clinical immunology (EAACI). Allergy. 2020;75(10):2445-2476.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hinks A, Cobb J, Marion MC, et al. Dense genotyping of immune-related disease regions identifies 14 new susceptibility loci for juvenile idiopathic arthritis. Nat Genet. 2013;45(6):664-669.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>