<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36917505</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>01</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-0237</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>38</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>May</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of thoracic imaging</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Thorac Imaging</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Cardiac Magnetic Resonance Imaging T1 and T2 Mapping in Systemic Lupus Erythematosus in Relation to Antimalarial Treatment.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>W33</StartPage><EndPage>W42</EndPage><MedlinePgn>W33-W42</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/RTI.0000000000000703</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Patients with systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) are at risk of cardiac disease including antimalarial-induced cardiomyopathy (AMIC). The purpose of this study is to evaluate cardiac magnetic resonance imaging parametric mapping findings in SLE patients with AMIC and investigate the relationship of T1/T2 mapping to antimalarial (AM) treatment duration.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">All patients with SLE who had undergone cardiac magnetic resonance imaging with T1/T2 mapping for evaluation of suspected cardiac disease between 2018 and 2021 were evaluated and compared with healthy controls. To facilitate comparison between scanners, T1/T2 values were converted to a z -score using scanner-specific local reference values. Patients were classified into 3 groups: AMIC, myocarditis, and other (no AMIC or myocarditis).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Forty-five SLE patients (47&#xb1;17&#xa0;y, 80% female; 8 [18%] with AMIC and 7 [16%] with myocarditis) and 30 healthy controls (39&#xb1;15&#xa0;y, 60% female) were included. Patients with AMIC had higher T1 and T2 compared with controls ( z -score 1.1&#xb1;1.3 vs. 0&#xb1;0.6, P =0.01 and 1.7&#xb1;1.1 vs. 0&#xb1;1.0, P &lt;0.01, respectively) and lower values compared with those with myocarditis (3.7&#xb1;1.6, P &lt;0.01 and 4.0&#xb1;2.0, P &lt;0.01, respectively). T1 correlated negatively with AM treatment duration in patients without AMIC or myocarditis ( r =-0.36, P =0.048) and positively in patients with AMIC ( r =0.92, P =0.001). AM treatment duration did not correlate significantly with T1 in patients with myocarditis or with T2 in any group.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The relationship between T1 and AM treatment duration differed between groups. Native T1 decreases with longer treatment in patients without AMIC or myocarditis, possibility due to glycosphingolipid accumulation. In patients with AMIC, increasing T1 with longer treatment could reflect fibrosis.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shalmon</LastName><ForeName>Tamar</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University Medical Imaging Toronto, Department of Medical Imaging, University of Toronto.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, Tel Aviv Sourasky Medical Center, Tel Aviv, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Thavendiranathan</LastName><ForeName>Paaladinesh</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University Medical Imaging Toronto, Department of Medical Imaging, University of Toronto.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Peter Munk Cardiac Centre, Toronto General Hospital, University Health Network, University of Toronto.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Seidman</LastName><ForeName>Michael A</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory Medicine Program, University Health Network.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wald</LastName><ForeName>Rachel M</ForeName><Initials>RM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University Medical Imaging Toronto, Department of Medical Imaging, University of Toronto.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Peter Munk Cardiac Centre, Toronto General Hospital, University Health Network, University of Toronto.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Karur</LastName><ForeName>Gauri Rani</ForeName><Initials>GR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University Medical Imaging Toronto, Department of Medical Imaging, University of Toronto.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Peter Munk Cardiac Centre, Toronto General Hospital, University Health Network, University of Toronto.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Harvey</LastName><ForeName>Paula J</ForeName><Initials>PJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiology, Department of Medicine, Women's College Hospital, University of Toronto.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Akhtari</LastName><ForeName>Shadi</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiology, Department of Medicine, Women's College Hospital, University of Toronto.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Osuntokun</LastName><ForeName>Tosin</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiology, Department of Medicine, Women's College Hospital, University of Toronto.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tselios</LastName><ForeName>Kostantinos</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Toronto Lupus Clinic, Toronto Western Hospital, Centre for Prognosis Studies in the Rheumatic Diseases, University Health Network, University of Toronto, Toronto, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gladman</LastName><ForeName>Dafna D</ForeName><Initials>DD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Toronto Lupus Clinic, Toronto Western Hospital, Centre for Prognosis Studies in the Rheumatic Diseases, University Health Network, University of Toronto, Toronto, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hanneman</LastName><ForeName>Kate</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3077-2218</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University Medical Imaging Toronto, Department of Medical Imaging, University of Toronto.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Peter Munk Cardiac Centre, Toronto General Hospital, University Health Network, University of Toronto.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Thorac Imaging</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8606160</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0883-5993</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000962">Antimalarials</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D003287">Contrast Media</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009205" MajorTopicYN="Y">Myocarditis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000139" MajorTopicYN="N">chemically induced</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009206" MajorTopicYN="N">Myocardium</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000962" MajorTopicYN="Y">Antimalarials</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019028" MajorTopicYN="N">Magnetic Resonance Imaging, Cine</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008279" MajorTopicYN="N">Magnetic Resonance Imaging</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009202" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cardiomyopathies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010496" MajorTopicYN="N">Pericardium</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011237" MajorTopicYN="N">Predictive Value of Tests</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003287" MajorTopicYN="N">Contrast Media</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36917505</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/RTI.0000000000000703</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005382-202305000-00011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Dima A, Jurcut C, Chasset F, et al. Hydroxychloroquine in systemic lupus erythematosus: overview of current knowledge. Ther Adv Musculoskelet Dis. 2022;14:1759720X211073001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bertsias G, Ioannidis JPA, Boletis J, et al. EULAR recommendations for the management of systemic lupus erythematosus. Report of a Task Force of the EULAR Standing Committee for International Clinical Studies Including Therapeutics. Ann Rheum Dis. 2008;67:195&#x2013;205.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petitdemange A, Felten R, Sibilia J, et al. Prescription strategy of antimalarials in cutaneous and systemic lupus erythematosus: an international survey. Ther Adv Musculoskelet Dis. 2021;13:1759720X211002595.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chatre C, Roubille F, Vernhet H, et al. Cardiac complications attributed to chloroquine and hydroxychloroquine: a systematic review of the literature. Drug Safety. 2018;41:919&#x2013;931.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teixeira RA, Filho MM, Benvenuti LA, et al. Cardiac damage from chronic use of chloroquine: a case report and review of the literature. Arq Bras Cardiol. 2002;79:85&#x2013;88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T&#xf6;nnesmann E, Stroehmann I, Kandolf R, et al. Cardiomyopathy caused by longterm treatment with chloroquine: a rare disease, or a rare diagnosis? J Rheumatol. 2012;39:1099&#x2013;1103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tselios K, Deeb M, Gladman DD, et al. Antimalarial-induced cardiomyopathy: a systematic review of the literature. Lupus. 2018;27:591&#x2013;599.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frustaci A, Morgante E, Antuzzi D, et al. Inhibition of cardiomyocyte lysosomal activity in hydroxychloroquine cardiomyopathy. Int J Cardiol. 2012;157:117&#x2013;119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karur GR, Mathur S, Morel CF, et al. Increased spread of native T1 assessed by MRI is a marker of cardiac involvement in fabry disease. Am J Roentgenol. 2020;216:355&#x2013;361.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Augusto JB, Nordin S, Kozor R, et al. Inflammatory cardiomyopathy in fabry disease. Heart. 2019;105(suppl 3):A1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moon JC, Sheppard M, Reed E, et al. The histological basis of late gadolinium enhancement cardiovascular magnetic resonance in a patient with Anderson-Fabry disease. J Cardiovasc Magn Reson. 2006;8:479&#x2013;482.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joyce E, Fabre A, Mahon N. Hydroxychloroquine cardiotoxicity presenting as a rapidly evolving biventricular cardiomyopathy: key diagnostic features and literature review. Eur Heart J Acute Cardiovasc Care. 2013;2:77&#x2013;83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shalmon T, Thavendiranathan P, Harvey P, et al. Cardiac MRI and clinical follow-up in antimalarial induced cardiomyopathy in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. J Thorac Imaging. 2023. doi: 10.1097/RTI.0000000000000694. [Epub ahead of print].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/RTI.0000000000000694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tijmes FS, Thavendiranathan P, Udell JA, et al. Cardiac MRI assessment of nonischemic myocardial inflammation: state of the art review and update on myocarditis associated with COVID-19 vaccination. Radiol Cardiothorac Imaging. 2021;3:e210252.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caredda G, Bassareo PP, Cau R, et al. Emerging role of cardiac magnetic resonance imaging in diagnosing myocarditis. J Thorac Imag. 2022;37:W12&#x2013;W27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bordonaro V, Larici AR, Franchi P, et al. Imaging of cardiopulmonary involvement in systemic immune-mediated diseases. J Thorac Imag. 2021;36:W35&#x2013;W51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanneman K, Alberdi HV, Karur GR, et al. Antimalarial-induced cardiomyopathy resembles fabry disease on cardiac MRI. JACC Cardiovasc Imaging. 2020;13:879&#x2013;881.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karur GR, Robison S, Iwanochko RM, et al. Use of myocardial T1 mapping at 3.0 T to differentiate anderson-fabry disease from hypertrophic cardiomyopathy. Radiology. 2018;288:172613.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warnica W, Al-Arnawoot A, Stanimirovic A, et al. Clinical impact of cardiac MRI T1 and T2 parametric mapping in patients with suspected cardiomyopathy. Radiology. 2022;305:319&#x2013;326.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanneman K. Myocardial imaging with CMR parametric mapping: clinical applications. Curr Radiol Rep. 2018;6:47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muscogiuri G, Suranyi P, Schoepf UJ, et al. Cardiac magnetic resonance T1-mapping of the myocardium: technical background and clinical relevance. J Thorac Imaging. 2018;33:71&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muthukrishnan P, Roukoz H, Grafton G, et al. Hydroxychloroquine-induced cardiomyopathy: a case report. Circ Heart Fail. 2011;4:e7&#x2013;e8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caforio ALP, Pankuweit S, Arbustini E, et al. Current state of knowledge on aetiology, diagnosis, management, and therapy of myocarditis: a position statement of the European Society of Cardiology Working Group on Myocardial and Pericardial Diseases. Eur Heart J. 2013;34:2636&#x2013;2648; 2648a&#x2013;2648d.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferreira VM, Schulz-Menger J, Holmvang G, et al. Cardiovascular magnetic resonance in nonischemic myocardial inflammation: expert recommendations. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2018;72:3158&#x2013;3176.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gladman DD, Ibanez D, Urowitz MB. Systemic lupus erythematosus disease activity index 2000. J Rheumatol. 2002;29:288&#x2013;291.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruce IN, O&#x2019;Keeffe AG, Farewell V, et al. Factors associated with damage accrual in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: results from the Systemic Lupus International Collaborating Clinics (SLICC) Inception Cohort. Ann Rheum Dis. 2015;74:1706&#x2013;1713.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fronza M, Thavendiranathan P, Karur GR, et al. Cardiac MRI and clinical follow-up in COVID-19 vaccine&#x2013;associated myocarditis. Radiology. 2022;304:E48&#x2013;E49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fronza M, Thavendiranathan P, Chan V, et al. Myocardial injury pattern at MRI in COVID-19 vaccine&#x2013;associated myocarditis. Radiology. 2022;304:553&#x2013;562.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puntmann VO, D&#x2019;Cruz D, Smith Z, et al. Native myocardial T1 mapping by cardiovascular magnetic resonance imaging in subclinical cardiomyopathy in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. Circ Cardiovasc Imaging. 2013;6:295&#x2013;301.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hinojar R, Foote L, Sangle S, et al. Native T1 and T2 mapping by CMR in lupus myocarditis: disease recognition and response to treatment. Int J Cardiol. 2016;222:717&#x2013;726.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson RB, Chow K, Khan A, et al. T(1) mapping with cardiovascular MRI is highly sensitive for Fabry disease independent of hypertrophy and sex. Circ Cardiovasc Imaging. 2013;6:637&#x2013;645.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanneman K, Karur GR, Wasim S, et al. Left ventricular hypertrophy and late gadolinium enhancement at cardiac MRI are associated with adverse cardiac events in Fabry disease. Radiology. 2020;294:42&#x2013;49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roos JM, Aubry M-C, Edwards WD. Chloroquine cardiotoxicity: clinicopathologic features in three patients and comparison with three patients with Fabry disease. Cardiovasc Pathol. 2002;11:277&#x2013;283.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deva DP, Hanneman K, Li Q, et al. Cardiovascular magnetic resonance demonstration of the spectrum of morphological phenotypes and patterns of myocardial scarring in Anderson-Fabry disease. J Cardiovasc Magn Resonance. 2016;18:14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tselios K, Deeb M, Gladman DD, et al. Antimalarial-induced cardiomyopathy in systemic lupus erythematosus: as rare as considered? J Rheumatol. 2019;46:391&#x2013;396.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tett SE. Clinical pharmacokinetics of slow-acting antirheumatic drugs. Clin Pharmacokinet. 1993;25:392&#x2013;407.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanchez-Nino MD, Carpio D, Sanz AB, et al. Lyso-Gb3 activates Notch1 in human podocytes. Hum Mol Genet. 2015;24:5720&#x2013;5732.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanneman K, Karur GR, Wasim S, et al. Prognostic significance of cardiac magnetic resonance imaging late gadolinium enhancement in Fabry disease. Circulation. 2018;138:2579&#x2013;2581.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>