<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36924922</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>25</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1873-0183</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>22</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>May</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Autoimmunity reviews</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Autoimmun Rev</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Treatment of autoimmunity: The impact of disease-modifying therapies in multiple sclerosis and comorbid autoimmune disorders.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>103312</StartPage><MedlinePgn>103312</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.autrev.2023.103312</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S1568-9972(23)00046-0</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>More than 10 disease-modifying therapies (DMT) are approved by the European Medicines Agency (EMA) and the US Food and Drug Administration (FDA) for the treatment of multiple sclerosis (MS) and new therapeutic options are on the horizon. Due to different underlying therapeutic mechanisms, a more individualized selection of DMTs in MS is possible, taking into account the patient's current situation. Therefore, concomitant treatment of various comorbid conditions, including autoimmune mediated disorders such as rheumatoid arthritis, should be considered in MS patients. Because the pathomechanisms of autoimmunity partially overlap, DMT could also treat concomitant inflammatory diseases and simplify the patient's treatment. In contrast, the exacerbation and even new occurrence of several autoimmune diseases have been reported as a result of immunomodulatory treatment of MS. To simplify treatment and avoid disease exacerbation, knowledge of the beneficial and adverse effects of DMT in other autoimmune disorders is critical. Therefore, we conducted a literature search and described the beneficial and adverse effects of approved and currently studied DMT in a large number of comorbid autoimmune diseases, including rheumatoid arthritis, ankylosing spondylitis, inflammatory bowel diseases, cutaneous disorders including psoriasis, Sj&#xf6;gren&#xb4;s syndrome, systemic lupus erythematosus, systemic vasculitis, autoimmune hepatitis, and ocular autoimmune disorders. Our review aims to facilitate the selection of an appropriate DMT in patients with MS and comorbid autoimmune diseases.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 The Authors. Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Konen</LastName><ForeName>Franz Felix</ForeName><Initials>FF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Hannover Medical School, 30625 Hannover, Germany.. Electronic address: konen.felix@mh-hannover.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>M&#xf6;hn</LastName><ForeName>Nora</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Hannover Medical School, 30625 Hannover, Germany.. Electronic address: moehn.nora@mh-hannover.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Witte</LastName><ForeName>Torsten</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rheumatology and Clinical Immunology, Hannover Medical School, 30625 Hannover, Germany.. Electronic address: witte.torsten@mh-hannover.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schefzyk</LastName><ForeName>Matthias</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Allergology and Venerology, Hannover Medical School, 30625 Hannover, Germany.. Electronic address: schefzyk.matthias@mh-hannover.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wiestler</LastName><ForeName>Miriam</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Division of Gastroenterology, Hepatology and Endocrinology, Hannover Medical School, 30625 Hannover, Germany. Electronic address: wiestler.miriam@mh-hannover.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lovric</LastName><ForeName>Svjetlana</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nephrology and Hypertension, Hannover Medical School, 30625 Hannover, Germany. Electronic address: lovric.svjetlana@mh-hannover.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hufendiek</LastName><ForeName>Karsten</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University Eye Hospital, Hannover Medical School, 30625 Hannover, Germany. Electronic address: hufendiek.karsten@mh-hannover.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schwenkenbecher</LastName><ForeName>Philipp</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Hannover Medical School, 30625 Hannover, Germany.. Electronic address: schwenkenbecher.philipp@mh-hannover.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>S&#xfc;hs</LastName><ForeName>Kurt-Wolfram</ForeName><Initials>KW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Hannover Medical School, 30625 Hannover, Germany.. Electronic address: suehs.kurt-wolfram@mh-hannover.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Friese</LastName><ForeName>Manuel A</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Neuroimmunology and Multiple Sclerosis, Center for Molecular Neurobiology Hamburg, University Medical Center Hamburg-Eppendorf, Hamburg 20251, Germany. Electronic address: manuel.friese@zmnh.uni-hamburg.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Klotz</LastName><ForeName>Luisa</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology with Institute of Translational Neurology, University Hospital Muenster, 48149 Muenster, Germany. Electronic address: luisa.klotz@ukmuenster.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pul</LastName><ForeName>Refik</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University Medicine Essen, Essen, Germany; Center for Translational Neuro- and Behavioral Sciences, University Hospital Essen, Essen 45147, Germany. Electronic address: refik.pul@uk-essen.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pawlitzki</LastName><ForeName>Marc</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Medical Faculty, Heinrich Heine University Dusseldorf, 40225 Dusseldorf, Germany. Electronic address: marcguenter.pawlitzki@med.uni-duesseldorf.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hagin</LastName><ForeName>David</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Allergy and Clinical Immunology Unit, Department of Medicine, Tel-Aviv Sourasky Medical Center and Sackler Faculty of Medicine, University of Tel Aviv, 6 Weizmann St., Tel-Aviv 6423906, Israel. Electronic address: Davidha@tlvmc.gov.il.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kleinschnitz</LastName><ForeName>Christoph</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University Medicine Essen, Essen, Germany; Center for Translational Neuro- and Behavioral Sciences, University Hospital Essen, Essen 45147, Germany. Electronic address: christoph.kleinschnitz@uk-essen.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Meuth</LastName><ForeName>Sven G</ForeName><Initials>SG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Medical Faculty, Heinrich Heine University Dusseldorf, 40225 Dusseldorf, Germany. Electronic address: meuth@uni-duesseldorf.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Skripuletz</LastName><ForeName>Thomas</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Hannover Medical School, 30625 Hannover, Germany.. Electronic address: skripuletz.thomas@mh-hannover.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Autoimmun Rev</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101128967</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1568-9972</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009103" MajorTopicYN="Y">Multiple Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015551" MajorTopicYN="N">Autoimmunity</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001327" MajorTopicYN="Y">Autoimmune Diseases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001172" MajorTopicYN="Y">Arthritis, Rheumatoid</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Multiple sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">autoimmune disorders</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">beneficial effects</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">disease-modifying therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">treatment</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of Competing Interest The Authors declare that there is no conflict of interest. FFK received travel grants from Merck and Novartis. NM received honoraria for scientific lectures from Novartis, Merck, and Biogen. TW received honoraria as speaker from Roche and Novartis. MS received honoraria as speaker and for consultation from Almirall and AbbVie. KWS reports honoraria for lectures or travel reimbursements for attending meetings from Biogen, Merck, Bavarian Nordic and Bristol-Myers Squibb as well as research support from Bristol-Myers Squibb. MAF received honoraria as speaker and for consultation from Biogen, Lundbeck, Merck KGaA, Novartis and Roche. His research is funded by the Bundesministerium f&#xfc;r Bildung und Forschung (BMBF), Deutsche Forschungsgemeinschaft (DFG), Landesforschungsf&#xf6;rderung Hamburg, Gemeinn&#xfc;tzige Hertie-Stiftung, Else Kr&#xf6;ner-Fresenius-Stiftung, Deutsche Multiple Sklerose-Gesellschaft, Fritz Thyssen-Stiftung, Werner Otto-Stiftung, Walter und Ilse Rose-Stiftung, Stiftung zur Bek&#xe4;mpfung neuroviraler Erkrankungen and Research Fund of the University Medical Center Hamburg-Eppendorf. LK received compensation for serving on Scientific Advisory Boards for Alexion, Biogen, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Genzyme, Horizon, Janssen, Merck Serono, Novartis, Roche and Viatris. She received speaker honoraria and travel support from Argenx, Bayer, Biogen, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Genzyme, Grifols, Merck Serono, Novartis, Roche, Santhera and Teva. She receives research support from the German Research Foundation, the IZKF M&#xfc;nster, IMF M&#xfc;nster, Biogen, Immunic AG, Novartis and Merck Serono. RP received honoraria for lecturing and consulting from Alexion, Bayer Healthcare, Biogen, Bristol-Mayers Squibb, MedDay, Merck Serono, Mylan, Novartis, Roche, Sanofi Genzyme. He received research funds from Teva, Merck Serono, and Novartis. MP received honoraria for lecturing from Argenx, Biogen, Bayer, Novartis, Hexal, Sanofi and Merck. He received research funding from Novartis and Biogen. His research is funded by the German Multiple Sclerosis Society North Rhine-Westphalia (DMSG). CK received honoraria for lecturing and consulting as well as financial research support from Ablynx, Almirall, Amgen, Bayer Vital, Bristol-Mayers Squibb, Biotronik, Boehringer Ingelheim, Biogen, CSL Behring, Daiichi-Sankyo, Desitin, Eisai, Ever Pharma, Sanofi Genzyme, Merck Serono, Mylan, Medday, Novartis, Pfizer, Roche, Siemens, Stago, and Teva. SGM received honoraria for lecturing and travel expenses for attending meetings from Almirall, Amicus Therapeutics Germany, Bayer Health Care, Biogen, Celgene, Diamed, Genzyme, MedDay Pharmaceuticals, Merck Serono, Novartis, Novo Nordisk, ONO Pharma, Roche, Sanofi-Aventis, Chugai Pharma, QuintilesIMS, and Teva. His research is funded by the German Ministry for Education and Research (BMBF), Bundesinstitut f&#xfc;r Risikobewertung (BfR), Deutsche Forschungsgemeinschaft (DFG), Else Kr&#xf6;ner Fresenius Foundation, Gemeinsamer Bundesausschuss (G-BA), German Academic Exchange Service, Hertie Foundation, Interdisciplinary Center for Clinical Studies (IZKF) Muenster, German Foundation Neurology and by Alexion, Almirall, Amicus Therapeutics Germany, Biogen, Diamed, Fresenius Medical Care, Genzyme, HERZ Burgdorf, Merck Serono, Novartis, ONO Pharma, Roche, and Teva. TS reports honoraria for lectures and travel grants from Alexion, Alnylam Pharmaceuticals, argenx, Bayer Vital, Biogen, Celgene, Centogene, CSL Behring, Euroimmun, Janssen, Merck Serono, Novartis, Pfizer, Roche, Sanofi, Siemens, Sobi, Teva. His research is supported by the German Ministry for Education and Research (BMBF), Bristol-Myers Squibb Foundation for Immuno-Oncology, Claudia von Schilling Foundation for Breast Cancer Research, Else Kr&#xf6;ner Fresenius Foundation, Hannover Biomedical Research School (HBRS), Alnylam Pharmaceuticals, CSL Behring, Novartis, Sanofi Genzyme, VHV Stiftung.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36924922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.autrev.2023.103312</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S1568-9972(23)00046-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>