<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36942901</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>03</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1756-185X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>May</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of rheumatic diseases</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Rheum Dis</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>First-degree relatives of patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: Autoreactivity but not autoimmunity?</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>907</StartPage><EndPage>916</EndPage><MedlinePgn>907-916</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/1756-185X.14669</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) is a disorder with a complex immunopathogenesis. It is well known that the disease begins with immunological alterations and autoantibody appearance in the serum years before clinical onset. As SLE has a strong tendency to familial aggregation, first-degree relatives (FDRs) constitute a group at elevated risk. The current understanding is that external risk factors trigger underlying immune dysregulations, leading to overt disease in those with elevated genetic risk.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This cross-sectional study investigates the degree to which clinical features, external risk factors, and immunological profiles differ in SLE FDRs from healthy individuals and SLE patientts.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Three groups were studied: Lupus patient FDRs (n&#xa0;=&#xa0;56), healthy controls (n&#xa0;=&#xa0;20), and SLE patients (n&#xa0;=&#xa0;20). FDRs and healthy participants completed a detailed clinical questionnaire that included questions regarding smoking and estrogen drug history. All participants were tested for the presence of the following antinuclear autoantibodies (ANAs) against: nRNP/Sm, Sm, Ro60, Ro-52, La, Scl-70, PM-Scl, PM- Scl, Jo-1, CENP B, PCNA, dsDNA, nucleosomes, histones, RibP, AMA M2, DFS70, and eight soluble cytokines, including transforming growth factor-&#x3b2; (TGF-&#x3b2;), vitamin D levels, and antibodies against Epstein-Barr virus (EBV).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Compared with the healthy controls, FDRs had higher titers of ANA, more specific staining immunofluorescent patterns, and more autoantibody specificities. Furthermore, FDRs differed significantly in their TGF-&#x3b2; levels from the other two groups. In FDRs, some clinical features (hair loss, skin, and oral ulcer-like lesions) were associated with higher ANA titers and some (oral ulcer-like lesions) with the anti-Ro60-specific antibody. Interestingly, there was an association between ANA titers and levels of antibodies against EBV only in the FDR group.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">First-degree relatives display unique clinical and immunological profiles, placing them between healthy individuals and SLE patients, with a balance between compensated immune dysregulation and disease-developing potential. A possible association between ANA titer and the number of clinical complaints is observed, which needs to be confirmed in more extensive studies.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 Asia Pacific League of Associations for Rheumatology and John Wiley &amp; Sons Australia, Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Penev</LastName><ForeName>Bogdan</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5005-4259</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine and Therapy Department, Medical Institute of Ministry of Interior, Sofia, Bulgaria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vasilev</LastName><ForeName>Georgi</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6314-6889</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Clinical Immunology, "St Ivan Rilski" University Hospital, Sofia, Bulgaria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Immunology, Medical University of Sofia, Sofia, Bulgaria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Todorova</LastName><ForeName>Ekaterina Ivanova</ForeName><Initials>EI</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1833-838X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Clinical Immunology, "St Ivan Rilski" University Hospital, Sofia, Bulgaria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Immunology, Medical University of Sofia, Sofia, Bulgaria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tumangelova-Yuzeir</LastName><ForeName>Kalina</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6143-7538</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Clinical Immunology, "St Ivan Rilski" University Hospital, Sofia, Bulgaria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Immunology, Medical University of Sofia, Sofia, Bulgaria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kurteva</LastName><ForeName>Ekaterina</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1968-5962</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Clinical Immunology, "St Ivan Rilski" University Hospital, Sofia, Bulgaria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Immunology, Medical University of Sofia, Sofia, Bulgaria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Monov</LastName><ForeName>Simeon</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8074-3768</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rheumatology Department, "St Ivan Rilski" University Hospital, Sofia, Bulgaria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine Department, Medical University of Sofia, Sofia, Bulgaria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kyurkchiev</LastName><ForeName>Dobroslav</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8257-7764</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Clinical Immunology, "St Ivan Rilski" University Hospital, Sofia, Bulgaria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Immunology, Medical University of Sofia, Sofia, Bulgaria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>141/24.06.2020</GrantID><Agency>Medical University of Sofia</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>8366/20.11.19</GrantID><Agency>Medical University of Sofia</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><Agency>"Dr. Anka and Petar Balevi" Association</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Rheum Dis</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101474930</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1756-1841</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D001323">Autoantibodies</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000974">Antibodies, Antinuclear</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D016212">Transforming Growth Factor beta</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003430" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Sectional Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020031" MajorTopicYN="Y">Epstein-Barr Virus Infections</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019226" MajorTopicYN="Y">Oral Ulcer</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004854" MajorTopicYN="N">Herpesvirus 4, Human</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001323" MajorTopicYN="N">Autoantibodies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000974" MajorTopicYN="N">Antibodies, Antinuclear</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016212" MajorTopicYN="N">Transforming Growth Factor beta</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">antinuclear antibodies</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">antinuclear antibody patterns</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">autoimmunity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">first-degree relatives</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">systemic lupus erythematosus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">transforming growth factor-&#x3b2;</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36942901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1756-185X.14669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>McMurray RW, May W. Sex hormones and systemic lupus erythematosus: review and meta-analysis. Arthritis Rheum. 2003;48:2100-2110.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M-odile B, Mikaeloff Y, Hudson M, et al. Combined oral contraceptive use and the risk of systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Rheum. 2009;61:476-481.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costenbader KH, Kim DJ, Peerzada J, et al. Cigarette smoking and the risk of systemic lupus erythematosus: a meta-analysis. Arthritis Rheum. 2004;50:849-857.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bae S-C, Kim S-J, Sung M-K. Impaired antioxidant status and decreased dietary intake of antioxidants in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. Rheumatol Int. 2002;22:238-243.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hiraki LT, Munger KL, Costenbader KH, Karlson EW. Dietary intake of vitamin D during adolescence and risk of adult-onset systemic lupus erythematosus and rheumatoid arthritis. Arthritis Care Res. 2012;64:1829-1836.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>James JA, Kaufman KM, Farris AD, Taylor-Albert E, Lehman TJ, Harley JB. An increased prevalence of Epstein-Barr virus infection in young patients suggests a possible etiology for systemic lupus erythematosus. J Clin Investig. 1997;100:3019-3026.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>James JA, Neas BR, Moser KL, et al. Systemic lupus erythematosus in adults is associated with previous Epstein-Barr virus exposure. Arthritis Rheum. 2001;44:1122-1126.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moon U, Park S, Oh S, et al. Patients with systemic lupus erythematosus have abnormally elevated Epstein-Barr virus load in blood. Arthritis Res Ther. 2004;6:R295-R302.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poole BD, Gross T, Maier S, Harley JB, James JA. Lupus-like autoantibody development in rabbits and mice after immunization with EBNA-1 fragments. J Autoimmun. 2008;31:362-371.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ulff-Moller CJ, Nielsen NM, Rostgaard K, Hjalgrim H, Frisch M. Epstein-Barr virus-associated infectious mononucleosis and risk of systemic lupus erythematosus. Rheumatol. 2010;49:1706-1712.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burdin N, P&#xe9;ronne C, Banchereau J, Rousset F. Epstein-Barr virus transformation induces B lymphocytes to produce human interleukin 10. J Exp Med. 1993;177:295-304.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henderson S, Huen D, Rowe M, Dawson C, Johnson G, Rickinson A. Epstein-Barr virus-coded BHRF1 protein, a viral homologue of Bcl-2, protects human B cells from programmed cell death. Proc Natl Acad Sci. 1993;90:8479-8483.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McClain MT, Rapp EC, Harley JB, et al. Infectious mononucleosis patients temporarily recognize a unique, cross-reactive epitope of Epstein-Barr virus nuclear antigen-1. J Med Virol. 2003;70:253-257.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang I, Quan T, Nolasco H, et al. Defective control of latent Epstein-Barr virus infection in systemic lupus erythematosus. J Immunol. 2004;172:1287-1294.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kong P, Jaredm O, Farida B, et al. Intrinsic T cell defects in systemic autoimmunity. Ann N Y Acad Sci. 2003;987:60-67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodnow CC. Balancing immunity and tolerance: deleting and tuning lymphocyte repertoires. Proc Natl Acad Sci. 1996;93:2264-2271.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aringer M, Costenbader K, Daikh D, et al. European league against rheumatism/American College of Rheumatology Classification Criteria for systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Rheum. 2019;71:1400-1412.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eriksson C, Kokkonen H, Johansson M, Hallmans G, Wadell G, Rantap&#xe4;&#xe4;-Dahlqvist S. Autoantibodies predate the onset of systemic lupus erythematosus in northern Sweden. Arthritis Res Ther. 2011;13:13. doi:10.1186/ar3258</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aho K, Koskela P, M&#xe4;kitalo R, Heli&#xf6;vaara M, Palosuo T. Antinuclear antibodies heralding the onset of systemic lupus erythematosus. J Rheumatol. 1992;19(9):1377-1379.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myckatyn S, Russell A. Outcome of positive antinuclear antibodies in individuals without connective tissue disease. J Rheumatol. 2003;30(4):736-739.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arbuckle MR, McClain MT, Rubertone MV, et al. Development of autoantibodies before the clinical onset of systemic lupus erythematosus. N Engl J Med. 2003;349:1526-1533.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heinlen LD, McClain MT, Merrill J, et al. Clinical criteria for systemic lupus erythematosus precede diagnosis, and associated autoantibodies are present before clinical symptoms. Arthritis Rheum. 2007;56:2344-2351.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munroe ME, Lu R, Zhao YD, et al. Altered type II interferon precedes autoantibody accrual and elevated type I interferon activity prior to systemic lupus erythematosus classification. Ann Rheum Dis. 2016;75(11):2014-2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niewold TB. Interferon alpha as a primary pathogenic factor in human lupus. J Interferon Cytokine Res. 2011;31:887-892.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niewold TB, Hua J, Lehman TJA, Harley JB, Crow MK. High serum IFN-&#x3b1; activity is a heritable risk factor for systemic lupus erythematosus. Genes Immun. 2007;8:492-502.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weckerle CE, Franek BS, Kelly JA, et al. Network analysis of associations between serum interferon-&#x3b1; activity, autoantibodies, and clinical features in systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Rheum. 2011;63:1044-1053.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramos PS, Brown EE, Kimberly RP, Langefeld CD. Genetic factors predisposing to systemic lupus erythematosus and lupus nephritis. Semin Nephrol. 2010;30(2):164-176.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alarc&#xf3;n-Segovia D, Alarc&#xf3;n-Riquelme ME, Cardiel MH, et al. Familial aggregation of systemic lupus erythematosus, rheumatoid arthritis, and other autoimmune diseases in 1,177 lupus patients from the GLADEL cohort. Arthritis Rheum. 2005;52:1138-1147.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>RJ DH, Pillarisetty R, Messner RP, et al. Anti-nucleic acid antibodies in systemic lupus erythematosus patients and their families. Incidence and correlation with lymphocytotoxic antibodies. J Clin Investig. 1975;56:1149-1154.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isenberg DA, Shoenfeld Y, Walport M, et al. Detection of cross-reactive anti-DNA antibody idiotypes in the serum of systemic lupus erythematosus patients and of their relatives. Arthritis Rheum. 1985;28:999-1007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams WM, Isenberg DA. A cross-sectional study of anti-DNA antibodies in the serum and IgG and IgM fraction of healthy individuals, patients with systemic lupus erythematosus and their relatives. Lupus. 1996;5:576-586.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van der Linden M, Westendorp R, Zidane M, Meheus L, Huizinga TW. Autoantibodies within families of patients with systemic lupus erythematosus are not directed against the same nuclear antigens. J Rheumatol. 2001;28(2):284-287.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reichlin M, Harley JB, Lockshin MD. Serologic studies of monozygotic twins with systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Rheum. 1992;35:457-464.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laustrup H, Heegaard NHH, Voss A, Green A, Lillevang ST, Junker P. Autoantibodies and self-reported health complaints in relatives of systemic lupus erythematosus patients: a community based approach. Lupus. 1992;13:792-799.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langkilde H, Voss A, Heegaard N, Laustrup H. Autoantibodies persist in relatives to systemic lupus erythematosus patients during 12&#x2009;years follow-up. Lupus. 2017;26:723-728.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marin GG, Cardiel MH, Cornejo H, et al. Prevalence of antinuclear antibodies in 3 groups of healthy individuals. J Clin Rheumatol. 2009. 15: 325-329.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruner BF, Guthridge JM, Lu R, et al. Comparison of autoantibody specificities between traditional and bead-based assays in a large, diverse collection of patients with systemic lupus erythematosus and family members. Arthritis Rheum. 2012;64:3677-3686.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dinse GE, Parks CG, Weinberg CR, et al. Retracted: increasing prevalence of antinuclear antibodies in the United States. Arthritis Rheum. 2020;72:1026-1035.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, Liu X, Cui J, et al. Epidemiological survey of antinuclear antibodies in healthy population and analysis of clinical characteristics of positive population. J Clin Lab Anal. 2019;33:e22965.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munroe ME, Young KA, Kamen DL, et al. Discerning risk of disease transition in relatives of systemic lupus erythematosus patients utilizing soluble mediators and clinical features. Arthritis Rheum. 2017;69:630-642.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karlson EW, Sanchez-Guerrero J, Wright EA, et al. A connective tissue disease screening questionnaire for population studies. Ann Epidemiol. 1995;5:297-302.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damoiseaux J, Andrade LEC, Carballo OG, et al. Clinical relevance of HEp-2 indirect immunofluorescent patterns: the international consensus on ANA patterns (ICAP) perspective. Ann Rheum Dis. 2019;78:879-889.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willems P, De Langhe E, Westhovens R, et al. Antinuclear antibody as entry criterion for classification of systemic lupus erythematosus: pitfalls and opportunities. Ann Rheum Dis. 2018;78:e76. doi:10.1136/annrheumdis-2018-213821</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leuchten N, Hoyer A, Brinks R, et al. Performance of antinuclear antibodies for classifying systemic lupus erythematosus: a systematic literature review and meta-regression of diagnostic data. Arthritis Care Res. 2018;70:428-438.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slight-Webb S, Lu R, Ritterhouse LL, et al. Autoantibody-positive healthy individuals display unique immune profiles that May regulate autoimmunity. Arthritis Rheum. 2016;68:2492-2502.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuomo L, Cirone M, Di Gregorio AO, et al. Elevated antinuclear antibodies and altered anti-Epstein-Barr virus immune responses. Virus Res. 2015;195:95-99.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vista ES, Weisman MH, Ishimori ML, et al. Strong viral associations with SLE among Filipinos. Lupus Sci Med. 2017;4:e000214.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li ZX, Zeng S, Wu HX, Zhou Y. The risk of systemic lupus erythematosus associated with Epstein-Barr virus infection: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Clin Exp Med. 2019;19:23-36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Besson C, Amiel C, Le-Pendeven C, et al. Positive correlation between Epstein-Barr virus viral load and anti-viral capsid immunoglobulin G titers determined for Hodgkin's lymphoma patients and their relatives. J Clin Microbiol. 2006;44(1):47-50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Theofilopoulos AN, Kono DH, Baccala R. The multiple pathways to autoimmunity. Nat Immunol. 2017;18(7):716-724.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>