<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36961155</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>28</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-5964</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>102</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>24</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Medicine (Baltimore)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Application of the Knowledge, Attitude, and Practice model combined with motivational interviewing for health education in female patients with systemic lupus erythematosus.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e33338</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e33338</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e33338</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MD.0000000000033338</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>To explore the application effect of the Knowledge, Attitude, and Practice (KAP) model combined with motivational interviewing for health education in the chronic disease management of female patients with systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE). In this study, 84 women with SLE who were admitted to a tertiary hospital in Tianjin from July 2021 to April 2022 were enrolled in this study and divided into observation (n&#x2005;=&#x2005;42) and control groups (n&#x2005;=&#x2005;42). The control group received routine health education and treatment for chronic diseases. Based on the control group, the KAP method and questionnaire survey were adopted. Health literacy and compliance in the 2 groups were compared in the first and third months after the intervention. The observation group had a higher total score of health literacy in the third month than the control group. From before the intervention to the first and third months, improvement in the observation group was compared with that in the control group (F&#x2005;=&#x2005;36.543, P&#x2005;6..001; F&#x2005;=&#x2005;4.884, P&#x2005;=&#x2005;.03; F&#x2005;=&#x2005;23.881, P&#x2005;3..001). The observation group had a higher total compliance score in the third month than the control group (t&#x2005;=&#x2005;5.101, P&#x2005;=&#x2005;.007). From before the intervention to the first and third months of the intervention, the improvement in the observation group demonstrated an interaction with the time group compared with that in the control group (F&#x2005;=&#x2005;68.116, P&#x2005;8..001; F&#x2005;=&#x2005;4.884, P&#x2005;=&#x2005;.032; F&#x2005;=&#x2005;24.789, P&#x2005;&lt;&#x2005;.001). Motivational interviewing based on the KAP model is effective in the short-term overall health literacy of female patients with SLE, especially in terms of communication, health improvement, and information acquisition; after 3 months, it can influence and maintain high patient compliance.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 the Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kang</LastName><ForeName>Juan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nursing, Tianjin Medical University, Tianjin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Xinran</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nursing, Tianjin Medical University, Tianjin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kan</LastName><ForeName>Yan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rheumatology and Immunology, Tianjin First Central Hospital, Tianjin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhuang</LastName><ForeName>Shumei</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1442-466</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nursing, Tianjin Medical University, Tianjin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Medicine (Baltimore)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>2985248R</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0025-7974</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D062405" MajorTopicYN="Y">Motivational Interviewing</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007722" MajorTopicYN="N">Health Knowledge, Attitudes, Practice</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006266" MajorTopicYN="N">Health Education</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057220" MajorTopicYN="Y">Health Literacy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors have no funding and conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36961155</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10036024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000033338</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005792-202303240-00026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Zhang W, Tang Z, Shi Y, et al. . Association between gamma-glutamyl transferase, total bilirubin and systemic lupus erythematosus in Chinese women. Front Immunol. 2021;12:682400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8277571</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34276670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L, Luan W, Geng S, et al. . Lack of patient education is risk factor of disease flare in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus in China. BMC Health Serv Res. 2019;19:378.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6567412</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31196083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian XP, Li MT, Zeng XF. Current situation and future development direction of diagnosis and treatment of systemic lupus erythematosus in China: from the 2020 Annual report of Chinese systemic lupus erythematosus. Chin J Intern Med. 2022;61:611&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35673741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Q, Xie L, Wang L, et al. . Readability in printed education materials for Chinese patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: a mixed-method design. BMJ Open. 2020;10:e038091.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7559043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33055117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jolly M, Sequeira W, Block JA, et al. . Sex differences in quality of life in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken). 2019;71:1647&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6202275</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29693320</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mac&#xea;do EA, Appenzeller S, Costallat LT. Gender differences in systemic lupus erythematosus concerning anxiety, depression and quality of life. Lupus. 2016;25:1315&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26989166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holloway L, Humphrey L, Heron L, et al. . Patient-reported outcome measures for systemic lupus erythematosus clinical trials: a review of content validity, face validity and psychometric performance. Health Qual Life Outcomes. 2014;12:116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4223409</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25048687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao RC, Wu L, Shi PL, et al. . The impact of distress disclosure and anxiety on the association between social support and quality of life among Chinese women with systemic lupus erythematosus. Front Psychiatry. 2022;13:893235.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9385970</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35990077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maheswaranathan M, Eudy AM, Barr AC, et al. . Association of health literacy and numeracy with lupus knowledge and the creation of the lupus knowledge assessment test. J Rheumatol. 2022;49:585&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35232802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katz P, Dall&#x2019;Era M, Trupin L, et al. . Impact of limited health literacy on patient-reported outcomes in systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken). 2021;73:110&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7775267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32741118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brolin S, Welin E, L&#xf6;vstr&#xf6;m B, et al. . Exploring the educational needs of patients with systemic vasculitis using the educational needs assessment tool. Rheumatol Adv Pract. 2022;6:rkac062.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9382267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35993015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cutilli CC. Excellence in patient education: evidence-based education that &#x201c;sticks&#x201d; and improves patient outcomes. Nurs Clin North Am. 2020;55:267&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32389259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delis PC. Uncertainty and quality of life in systemic lupus erythematosus: a cross-sectional study. Rehabil Nurs. 2019;44:2&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30601796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lussier MT, Richard C. The motivational interview. Can Fam Physician. 2007;53:1895&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2231481</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18000264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lundahl B, Moleni T, Burke BL, et al. . Motivational interviewing in medical care settings: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Patient Educ Couns. 2013;93:157&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24001658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>En&#xf6; Persson J, Bohman B, Forsberg L, et al. . Proficiency in motivational interviewing among nurses in child health services following workshop and supervision with systematic feedback. PLoS One. 2016;11:e0163624.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5042524</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27685152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stenov V, Wind G, Skinner T, et al. . The potential of a self-assessment tool to identify healthcare professionals&#x2019; strengths and areas in need of professional development to aid effective facilitation of group-based, person-centered diabetes education. BMC Med Educ. 2017;17:166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5604418</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28923042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Engelen MM, van Dulmen S, Nijhuis-van der Sanden MWG, et al. . Self-management support in cardiovascular consultations by advanced practice nurses trained in motivational interviewing: an observational study. Patient Educ Couns. 2020;103:159&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31362901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mifsud JL, Galea J, Garside J, et al. . Motivational interviewing to support modifiable risk factor change in individuals at increased risk of cardiovascular disease: a systematic review and meta-analysis. PLoS One. 2020;15:e0241193.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7657493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33175849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li XX, Du XW, Song W, et al. . Effect of continuous nursing care based on the IKAP theory on the quality of life of patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease: a randomized controlled study. Medicine (Baltim). 2020;99:e19543.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7440075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32176107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maruf FA, Ojukwu CC, Akindele MO. Perception, knowledge, and attitude toward physical activity behaviour: implications for participation among individuals with essential hypertension. High Blood Press Cardiovasc Prev. 2018;25:53&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29082466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Low ESH, Krishnaswamy G, Thumboo J. Comparing the 1997 update of the 1982 American College of Rheumatology (ACR-97) and the 2012 Systemic Lupus International Collaborating Clinics (SLICC-12) criteria for systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) classification: which enables earlier classification of SLE in an urban Asian population? Lupus. 2019;28:11&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30463470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li CH, Liu XY. Recommendations of the European alliance against rheumatism on the health management of women with systemic lupus erythematosus and/or antiphospholipid syndrome. Chin J Rheumatol. 2017;21:143&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun HL. Development and Preliminary Application of Scale on Health Literacy for Patients with Chronic Disease. Fudan University. 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Klerk E, van der Heijde D, van der Tempel H, et al. . Development of a questionnaire to investigate patient compliance with antirheumatic drug therapy. J Rheumatol. 1999;26:2635&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10606375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sutanto B, Singh-Grewal D, McNeil HP, et al. . Experiences and perspectives of adults living with systemic lupus erythematosus: thematic synthesis of qualitative studies. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken). 2013;65:1752&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23609952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu J, Zhang Y, Sun F. Analysis of the status quo and influencing factors of stigma in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. Nurs Pract Res. 2017;14:91&#x2013;3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tincopa MA, Wong J, Fetters M, et al. . Patient disease knowledge, attitudes and behaviours related to non-alcoholic fatty liver disease: a qualitative study. BMJ Open Gastroenterol. 2021;8:e000634.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8246278</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34193468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murugesu L, Heijmans M, Rademakers J, et al. . Challenges and solutions in communication with patients with low health literacy: perspectives of healthcare providers. PLoS One. 2022;17:e0267782.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9067671</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35507632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller LR, Cano A, Wurm LH. A motivational therapeutic assessment improves pain, mood, and relationship satisfaction in couples with chronic pain. J Pain. 2013;14:525&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23523023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young HM, Miyamoto S, Dharmar M, et al. . Nurse coaching and mobile health compared with usual care to improve diabetes self-efficacy for persons with type 2 diabetes: randomized controlled trial. JMIR Mhealth Uhealth. 2020;8:e16665.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7076411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32130184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nissen NK, J&#xf3;nsd&#xf3;ttir M, Spindler H, et al. . Resistance to change: role of relationship and communal coping for coronary heart disease patients and their partners in making lifestyle changes. Scand J Public Health. 2018;46:659&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29400128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beckwith VZ, Beckwith J. Motivational interviewing: a communication tool to promote positive behavior change and optimal health outcomes. NASN Sch Nurse. 2020;35:344&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32338141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaume J, Magill M, Gmel G, et al. . Motivational interviewing technical and relational skills, change talk, and alcohol outcomes-a moderated mediation analysis. J Consult Clin Psychol. 2021;89:707&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34472897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu W, Li T, Cao S, et al. . Influence of nurse-led health education on self-management ability, satisfaction, and compliance of elderly patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease based on knowledge, belief, and practice model. Comput Math Methods Med. 2022;2022:1782955.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9377965</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35979056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parwati NM, Bakta IM, Januraga PP, et al. . A health belief model-based motivational interviewing for medication adherence and treatment success in pulmonary tuberculosis patients. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18:13238.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8701142</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34948846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alonso WW, Kupzyk K, Norman J, et al. . Negative attitudes, self-efficacy, and relapse management mediate long-term adherence to exercise in patients with heart failure. Ann Behav Med. 2021;55:1031&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8489305</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33580663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shenavandeh S, Mani A, Eazadnegahdar M, et al. . Medication adherence of patients with systemic lupus erythematosus and rheumatoid arthritis considering the psychosocial factors, health literacy and current life concerns of patients. Curr Rheumatol Rev. 2021;17:412&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33645485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mallisham SL, Sherrod B. The spirit and intent of motivational interviewing. Perspect Psychiatr Care. 2017;53:226&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27252143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bischof G, Bischof A, Rumpf HJ. Motivational interviewing: an evidence-based approach for use in medical practice. Dtsch Arztebl Int. 2021;118:109&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8200683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33835006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henderson S, Horne M, Hills R, et al. . Cultural competence in healthcare in the community: a concept analysis. Health Soc Care Community. 2018;26:590&#x2013;603.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29516554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>