<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36966601</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>01</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1532-866X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>60</Volume><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Seminars in arthritis and rheumatism</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Semin Arthritis Rheum</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Racial disparities in pregnancy outcomes among women with rheumatic diseases: A systematic literature review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>152193</StartPage><MedlinePgn>152193</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.semarthrit.2023.152193</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0049-0172(23)00033-1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">There is a limited understanding of racial disparities in adverse pregnancy outcomes (APO) among women with rheumatic diseases. The aim of our study was to conduct a systematic literature review to evaluate the impact of race on APO in women with rheumatic diseases.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Databases were searched to find reports of APO stratified by race among women with rheumatic diseases. The initial searches were conducted in July 2020 and updated in March 2021. Of the final included articles, the full text was reviewed, and data was extracted from each study using a standard data abstraction form.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Ten studies with a total of 39,720 patients met our eligibility criteria. There was a greater propensity for APO in racial minorities with rheumatic diseases compared to their White counterparts. Among women with systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE), Black women had the highest odds of APOs, particularly those with a concomitant diagnosis of antiphospholipid syndrome. Pooled meta-analysis could not be done due to multiple factors, including heterogeneity between studies.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">Racial minorities with rheumatic diseases are more prone to APO compared to their White counterparts. One limitation is the lack of standardized criteria for APO, which prohibited direct comparison between studies. There is also a paucity of data looking at APOs among women with rheumatic diseases other than SLE. Further research is needed to explore the drivers of these racial disparities to guide targeted solutions for those in the greatest need.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shen</LastName><ForeName>Gloria</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Washington, Seattle, WA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Swaminathan</LastName><ForeName>Maya</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Rheumatology, Department of Internal Medicine, University of Washington, Seattle, WA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Irvin</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Rheumatology, Department of Internal Medicine, University of Washington, Seattle, WA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Louden</LastName><ForeName>Diana</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University Libraries, University of Washington, Seattle, WA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Feterman</LastName><ForeName>Dominique</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Rheumatology, Department of Internal Medicine, University of Washington, Seattle, WA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tahir</LastName><ForeName>Muhammad Waqas</ForeName><Initials>MW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Hospital Internal Medicine, Mayo Clinic, Jacksonville, FL, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Singh</LastName><ForeName>Namrata</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Rheumatology, Department of Internal Medicine, University of Washington, Seattle, WA, United States. Electronic address: nasingh@uw.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>K23 AR079588</GrantID><Acronym>AR</Acronym><Agency>NIAMS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Semin Arthritis Rheum</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>1306053</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0049-0172</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011247" MajorTopicYN="N">Pregnancy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011256" MajorTopicYN="N">Pregnancy Outcome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016736" MajorTopicYN="Y">Antiphospholipid Syndrome</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012216" MajorTopicYN="Y">Rheumatic Diseases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Preterm birth</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Racial disparities</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Rheumatoid arthritis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Systemic lupus erythematosus</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of Competing Interest The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36966601</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS1886054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10148907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.semarthrit.2023.152193</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0049-0172(23)00033-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Cooper GS, Stroehla BC: The epidemiology of autoimmune diseases. Autoimmun Rev 2003, 2(3):119&#x2013;125.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12848952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell K, Kaul M, Clowse ME: The management of rheumatic diseases in pregnancy. Scand J Rheumatol 2010, 39(2):99&#x2013;108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3724464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20337545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ostensen M: Disease specific problems related to drug therapy in pregnancy. Lupus 2004, 13(9):746&#x2013;750.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15485116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sugawara E, Kato M, Fujieda Y, Oku K, Bohgaki T, Yasuda S, Umazume T, Morikawa M, Watari H, Atsumi T: Pregnancy outcomes in women with rheumatic diseases: a real-world observational study in Japan. Lupus 2019, 28(12):1407&#x2013;1416.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31551035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin JAMPH, Hamilton BE, Osterman MJK, Driscoll AK, Mathews TJ: Births : final data for 2015. In. Edited by (U.S.) NCfHS, 66 edn; 2017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28135188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clowse ME, Grotegut C: Racial and Ethnic Disparities in the Pregnancies of Women With Systemic Lupus Erythematosus. Arthritis care &amp; research 2016, 68(10):1567&#x2013;1572.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26815791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, Boutron I, Hoffmann TC, Mulrow CD, et al.: The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. BMJ 2021, 372.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8005924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33782057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Newcastle-Ottawa Scale (NOS) for assessing the quality of nonrandomised studies in meta-analyses [http://www.ohri.ca/programs/clinical_epi-demiology/oxford.htm]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaplowitz ET, Ferguson S, Guerra M, Laskin CA, Buyon JP, Petri M, Lockshin MD, Sammaritano LR, Branch DW, Merrill JT et al.: Contribution of Socioeconomic Status to Racial/Ethnic Disparities in Adverse Pregnancy Outcomes Among Women With Systemic Lupus Erythematosus. Arthritis care &amp; research 2018, 70(2):230&#x2013;235.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28480528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buyon JP, Kim MY, Salmon JE: Predictors of Pregnancy Outcomes in Patients With Lupus. Ann Intern Med 2016, 164(2):131.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26784479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrade R, Sanchez ML, Alarcon GS, Fessler BJ, Fernandez M, Bertoli AM, Apte M, Vila LM, Arango AM, Reveille JD et al.: Adverse pregnancy outcomes in women with systemic lupus erythematosus from a multiethnic US cohort: LUMINA (LVI) [corrected]. Clin Exp Rheumatol 2008, 26(2):268&#x2013;274.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18565248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vinet E, Clarke AE, Gordon C, Urowitz MB, Hanly JG, Pineau CA, Isenberg D, Rahman A, Wallace D, Alarcon GS et al.: Decreased live births in women with systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis care &amp; research 2011, 63(7):1068&#x2013;1072.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21425248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaharir SS, Maulana SA, Shahril NS, Mohd R, Mustafar R, Said MSM, Rahman RA: Adverse pregnancy outcomes among multi-ethnic systemic lupus erythematosus patients in Malaysia. Lupus 2020, 29(10):1305&#x2013;1313.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32660312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manzano-Gamero V, Pardo-Cabello AJ, Vargas-Hitos JA, Zamora-Pasadas M, Navarrete-Navarrete N, Sabio JM, J&#xe1;imez-G&#xe1;miz L, R&#xed;os-Fernandez R, Ortego-Centeno N, Ayala-Gutierrez MM et al.: Effect of ethnicity on clinical presentation and risk of antiphospholipid syndrome in Roma and Caucasian patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: a multicenter cross-sectional study. Int J Rheum Dis 2018, 21(11):2028&#x2013;2035.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28593703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohamed MA, Goldman C, El-Dib M, Aly H: Maternal juvenile rheumatoid arthritis may be associated with preterm birth but not poor fetal growth. Journal of perinatology : official journal of the California Perinatal Association 2016, 36(4):268&#x2013;271.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26675002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L S, J S, G B, R B, L J-P, C C, N S, K R: Racial and Ethnic Disparities in the Risk of Preterm Birth Among Women with Systemic Lupus Erythematosus or Rheumatoid Arthritis with Varying Reference Groups In., vol. 72. Arthritis Rheumatology; 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C A, L T, P K, Z I, M G, G S, J. Y: Worse Maternal and Fetal Outcomes Among Hospitalized U.S. Pregnant Women with Systemic Lupus Erythematosus (SLE) and Rheumatoid Arthritis (RA). Arthritis Rheumatology 2020, 72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anastasiou C TL, Katz P, Izadi Z, Gianfrancesco M, Schmajuk G, Yazdany J.: Worse Maternal and Fetal Outcomes Among Hospitalized U.S. Pregnant Women with Systemic Lupus Erythematosus (SLE) and Rheumatoid Arthritis (RA) [abstract]. Arthritis Rheumatol 2020; 72 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabih L SJ, Bandoli G, Baer R, Jelliffe-Pawlowski L, Chambers C, Singh N, Ryckman K: Racial and Ethnic Disparities in the Risk of Preterm Birth Among Women with Systemic Lupus Erythematosus or Rheumatoid Arthritis with Varying Reference Groups. Arthritis Rheumatol 2020; 72 2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37099120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feld J, Kibari A, Rozenbaum M, Riskin-Mashiah S, Eder L, Laor A, Rosner I, Ellias M, Zisman D: The fetal outcomes of pregnancies of systemic lupus erythematosus patients in northern Israel. J Matern Fetal Neonatal Med 2015, 28(5):564&#x2013;567.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24844162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mbuli L, Mapiye D, Okpechi I: Lupus nephritis is associated with poor pregnancy outcomes in pregnant SLE patients in Cape Town: a retrospective analysis. Pan Afr Med J 2015, 22:365.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4789183</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27022425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Njagu RS, Eudy AM, Petri M, Gladman DD, Urowitz MB, Balevic S, Clowse ME: 140 Effect of lupus nephritis on pregnancy outcomes in systemic lupus erythematosus: an individual participant meta-analysis. Lupus Science &amp; Medicine 2019, 6(Suppl 1):A102&#x2013;A102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kharbanda R, Naveen R, Misra DP, Gupta L, Agarwal V: Poor maternal and foetal outcomes in women with systemic sclerosis: an interview-based study at a tertiary centre. Rheumatol Int 2021, 41(6):1133&#x2013;1142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33682026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taraborelli M, Ramoni V, Brucato A, Airo P, Bajocchi G, Bellisai F, Biasi D, Blagojevic J, Canti V, Caporali R et al.: Brief report: successful pregnancies but a higher risk of preterm births in patients with systemic sclerosis: an Italian multicenter study. Arthritis Rheum 2012, 64(6):1970&#x2013;1977.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22213060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sampaio-Barros PD, Samara AM, Marques Neto JF: Gynaecologic history in systemic sclerosis. Clin Rheumatol 2000, 19(3):184&#x2013;187.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10870650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gomez-Puerta JA, Barbhaiya M, Guan H, Feldman CH, Alarcon GS, Costenbader KH: Racial/Ethnic variation in all-cause mortality among United States medicaid recipients with systemic lupus erythematosus: a Hispanic and asian paradox. Arthritis &amp; rheumatology (Hoboken, NJ) 2015, 67(3):752&#x2013;760.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4366131</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25590668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bharti B, Lee SJ, Lindsay SP, Wingard DL, Jones KL, Lemus H, Chambers CD: Disease Severity and Pregnancy Outcomes in Women with Rheumatoid Arthritis: Results from the Organization of Teratology Information Specialists Autoimmune Diseases in Pregnancy Project. J Rheumatol 2015, 42(8):1376&#x2013;1382.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25877497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenberg JD, Spruill TM, Shan Y, Reed G, Kremer JM, Potter J, Yazici Y, Ogedegbe G, Harrold LR: Racial and ethnic disparities in disease activity in patients with rheumatoid arthritis. Am J Med 2013, 126(12):1089&#x2013;1098.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4006346</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24262723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>