<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36989451</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>31</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2376-1032</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>29</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of managed care &amp; specialty pharmacy</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Manag Care Spec Pharm</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Prolonged oral corticosteroid treatment in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: An evaluation of 12-month economic and clinical burden.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>365</StartPage><EndPage>377</EndPage><MedlinePgn>365-377</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.18553/jmcp.2023.29.4.365</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText><b>BACKGROUND:</b> Prolonged, high-dose corticosteroid treatment for systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) is associated with substantial health care costs, health care resource utilization (HCRU), and adverse events (AEs). <b>OBJECTIVE:</b> To compare all-cause health care costs, HCRU, and oral corticosteroid (OCS)-related AEs among patients with prevalent OCS use and patients without OCS use. <b>METHODS:</b> This retrospective, longitudinal cohort study (GSK study 214100) used claims data from the IQVIA Real-World Data Adjudicated Claims - US, IQVIA, Inc, database between January 1, 2006, and July 31, 2019, to identify patients with SLE. Patients with at least 1 OCS pharmacy claim during the study period and continuous OCS use during the 6-month pre-index (baseline) period (index date is the date of the first OCS claim following 6 months' continuous use) formed the "prevalent OCS use cohort." This cohort was subdivided based on the level of OCS exposure during the 12-month observation period, ie, the number of 6-month periods of greater than 5 mg/day OCS use (0, 1, or 2). Patients without OCS claims formed the "no OCS use cohort." All patients had continuous enrollment during the baseline and observation periods, had at least 1 inpatient or at least 2 outpatient SLE diagnosis codes during baseline, and were aged at least 5 years at index. A 2-part model, a generalized linear regression model with a negative binomial distribution, and a multivariate logistic regression model were used to compare health care costs, HCRU, and the odds of developing an OCS-related AE between cohorts, respectively. <b>RESULTS:</b> The no OCS use and prevalent OCS use cohorts included 21,517 and 16,209 patients, respectively. Adjusted health care cost differences (95% CI) were significantly lower for the no OCS use cohort vs all prevalent OCS use exposure categories ($5,439 [$4,537-$6,371] vs $17,856 [$16,368-$19,498]), driven by inpatient stays and outpatient visits; HCRU was also significantly lower (adjusted incidence rate ratios vs no OCS use cohort [95% CI]: 1.20 [1.16-1.23] vs 1.47 [1.41-1.52]). Health care costs and HCRU increased with increasing length of OCS exposure. OCS-related AEs occurred more frequently for all prevalent OCS use exposure categories vs the no OCS use cohort (odds ratio [95% CI]: 1.39 [1.25-1.55] vs 2.32 [2.02-2.68]), driven by hematologic/oncologic and immune system-related AEs. The mean (SD) average daily dose of OCS increased with increasing periods of prevalent OCS use (2.5 [1.3], 6.9 [31.1], and 34.6 [1,717.3] mg/day, respectively, for patients with 0, 1, and 2 periods of OCS use). <b>CONCLUSIONS:</b> Prevalent OCS use incurs a substantial clinical and economic burden, highlighting the need for restricted OCS doses and durations. <b>DISCLOSURES:</b> This study (GSK Study 214100) was funded by GSK. GSK was involved in designing the study, contributing to the collection, analysis, and interpretation of the data, supporting the authors in the development of the manuscript, and funding the medical writing assistance. All authors, including those employed by GSK, approved the content of the submitted manuscript and were involved in the decision to submit the manuscript for publication. Dr DerSarkissian, Dr Duh, and Mr Benson are employees of Analysis Group, which received research funding from GSK to conduct this study. Dr Wang, Ms Gu, and Mr Vu are former employees of Analysis Group. Mr Bell is an employee of GSK and holds stocks and shares in the company. Ms Averell and Dr Huang are former employees of GSK and held stocks and shares in the company at the time of the study.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Shirley P</ForeName><Initials>SP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>US Value, Evidence and Outcomes, GSK, Durham, NC.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>DerSarkissian</LastName><ForeName>Maral</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Analysis Group, Inc., Boston, MA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gu</LastName><ForeName>Yuqian M</ForeName><Initials>YM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Analysis Group, Inc., Boston, MA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Duh</LastName><ForeName>Mei Sheng</ForeName><Initials>MS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Analysis Group, Inc., Boston, MA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Min-Jung</ForeName><Initials>MJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Analysis Group, Inc., Boston, MA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Benson</LastName><ForeName>John</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Analysis Group, Inc., Boston, MA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vu</LastName><ForeName>Jensen</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Analysis Group, Inc., Boston, MA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Averell</LastName><ForeName>Carlyne</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>US Value, Evidence and Outcomes, GSK, Durham, NC.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bell</LastName><ForeName>Christopher F</ForeName><Initials>CF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>US Value, Evidence and Outcomes, GSK, Durham, NC.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Manag Care Spec Pharm</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101644425</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2376-0540</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000305">Adrenal Cortex Hormones</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008137" MajorTopicYN="N">Longitudinal Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017048" MajorTopicYN="Y">Health Care Costs</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000305" MajorTopicYN="N">Adrenal Cortex Hormones</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>This study (GSK Study 214100) was funded by GSK. GSK was involved in designing the study, contributing to the collection, analysis, and interpretation of the data, supporting the authors in the development of the manuscript, and funding the medical writing assistance. All authors, including those employed by GSK, approved the content of the submitted manuscript and were involved in the decision to submit the manuscript for publication. Dr DerSarkissian, Dr Duh, and Mr Benson are employees of Analysis Group, which received research funding from GSK to conduct this study. Dr Wang, Ms Gu, and Mr Vu are former employees of Analysis Group. Mr Bell is an employee of GSK and holds stocks and shares in the company. Ms Averell and Dr Huang are former employees of GSK and held stocks and shares in the company at the time of the study.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36989451</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10387938</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18553/jmcp.2023.29.4.365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Gyori N, Giannakou I, Chatzidionysiou K, Magder L, van Vollenhoven RF, Petri M. Disease activity patterns over time in patients with SLE: Analysis of the Hopkins Lupus Cohort. Lupus Sci Med. 2017;4(1):e000192. doi:10.1136/lupus-2016-000192</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5307372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28243457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cojocaru M, Cojocaru IM, Silosi I, Vrabie CD. Manifestations of systemic lupus erythematosus. Maedica (Bucur). 2011;6(4):330-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3391953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22879850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahman MM, Moniruzzan M, Sayeed JB, et al. . 239 Patterns of organ involvement in SLE and their outcome: A real life experience in a lupus clinic. Lupus Sci Med. 2019;6(Suppl 1). doi:10.1136/lupus-2019-lsm.239</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fanouriakis A, Kostopoulou M, Alunno A, et al. . 2019. update of the EULAR recommendations for the management of systemic lupus erythematosus. Ann Rheum Dis. 2019;78(6):736-45. doi:10.1136/annrheumdis-2019-215089</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30926722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon C, Amissah-Arthur MB, Gayed M, et al.; British Society for Rheumatology Standards; Audit and Guidelines Working Group. The British Society for Rheumatology guideline for the management of systemic lupus erythematosus in adults. Rheumatology (Oxford). 2018;57(1):e1-e45. doi:10.1093/rheumatology/kex286</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29029350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sciascia S, Mompean E, Radin M, Roccatello D, Cuadrado MJ. Rate of adverse effects of medium- to high-dose glucocorticoid therapy in systemic lupus erythematosus: A systematic review of randomized control trials. Clin Drug Investig. 2017;37(6):519-24. doi:10.1007/s40261-017-0518-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28357813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thamer M, Hernan MA, Zhang Y, Cotter D, Petri M. Prednisone, lupus activity, and permanent organ damage. J Rheumatol. 2009;36(3):560-4. doi:10.3899/jrheum.080828</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3624968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19208608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Birt JA, Wu J, Griffing K, et al. . Corticosteroid dosing and opioid use are high in patients with SLE and remain elevated after belimumab initiation: A retrospective claims database analysis. Lupus Sci Med. 2020;7(1):e000435. doi:10.1136/lupus-2020-000435</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7759957</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33361460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hammond ER, Desta B, Near AM, Wang X, Jiang M. Frequency, severity and costs of flares increase with disease severity in newly diagnosed systemic lupus erythematosus: A real-world cohort study, United States, 2004-2015. Lupus Sci Med. 2021;8(1):e000504. doi:10.1136/lupus-2021-000504</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8461688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34556546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davidson JE, Fu Q, Rao S, Magder LS, Petri M. Quantifying the burden of steroid-related damage in SLE in the Hopkins Lupus Cohort. Lupus Sci Med. 2018;5(1):e000237. doi:10.1136/lupus-2017-000237</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5950698</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29765616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gladman DD, Urowitz MB, Rahman P, Ibanez D, Tam LS. Accrual of organ damage over time in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. J Rheumatol. 2003;30(9):1955-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12966597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al Sawah S, Zhang X, Zhu B, et al. . Effect of corticosteroid use by dose on the risk of developing organ damage over time in systemic lupus erythematosus-the Hopkins Lupus Cohort. Lupus Sci Med. 2015;2(1):e000066. doi:10.1136/lupus-2014-000066</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4378372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25861455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruiz-Arruza I, Ugarte A, Cabezas-Rodriguez I, Medina JA, Moran MA, Ruiz-Irastorza G. Glucocorticoids and irreversible damage in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. Rheumatology (Oxford). 2014;53(8):1470-6. doi:10.1093/rheumatology/keu148</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24681836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah M, Chaudhari S, McLaughlin TP, et al. . Cumulative burden of oral corticosteroid adverse effects and the economic implications of corticosteroid use in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. Clin Ther. 2013;35(4):486-97. doi:10.1016/j.clinthera.2013.03.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23587268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen SY, Choi CB, Li Q, et al. . Glucocorticoid use in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: Association between dose and health care utilization and costs. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken). 2015;67(8):1086-94. doi:10.1002/acr.22574</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25732795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kabadi S, Yeaw J, Bacani AK, et al. . Healthcare resource utilization and costs associated with long-term corticosteroid exposure in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. Lupus. 2018;27(11):1799-809. doi:10.1177/0961203318790675</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6264911</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30068254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petri M, Bechtel B, Dennis G, et al. . Burden of corticosteroid use in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: Results from a Delphi panel. Lupus. 2014;23(10):1006-13. doi:10.1177/0961203314532699</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24786783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang M, DerSarkissian M, Duh MS, et al. . Clinical and economic burden associated with new oral corticosteroid users with systemic lupus erythematosus in the United States. J Manag Care Spec Pharm. 2021;27(4):S1-152.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garris C, Jhingran P, Bass D, Engel-Nitz NM, Riedel A, Dennis G. Healthcare utilization and cost of systemic lupus erythematosus in a US managed care health plan. J Med Econ. 2013;16(5):667-77. doi:10.3111/13696998.2013.778270</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23425294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Narayanan S, Wilson K, Ogelsby A, Juneau P, Durden E. Economic burden of systemic lupus erythematosus flares and comorbidities in a commercially insured population in the United States. J Occup Environ Med. 2013;55(11):1262-70. doi:10.1097/JOM.0000000000000008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24202242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruperto N, Hanrahan LM, Alarcon GS, et al.; Lupus Foundation of America, Inc. International Flare Consensus Initiative. International consensus for a definition of disease flare in lupus. Lupus. 2011;20(5):453-62. doi:10.1177/0961203310388445</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21148601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murimi-Worstell IB, Lin DH, Kan H, et al. . Healthcare utilization and costs of systemic lupus erythematosus by disease severity in the United States. J Rheumatol. 2021;48(3):385-93. doi:10.3899/jrheum.191187</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32611669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Speyer CB, Li D, Guan H, et al. . Comparison of an administrative algorithm for SLE disease severity to clinical SLE Disease Activity Index scores. Rheumatol Int. 2020;40(2):257-61. doi:10.1007/s00296-019-04477-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6960319</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31784790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon C, Sutcliffe N, Skan J, Stoll T, Isenberg DA. Definition and treatment of lupus flares measured by the BILAG index. Rheumatology (Oxford). 2003;42(11):1372-9. doi:10.1093/rheumatology/keg382</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12810926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarnes E, Crofford L, Watson M, Dennis G, Kan H, Bass D. Incidence and US costs of corticosteroid-associated adverse events: A systematic literature review. Clin Ther. 2011;33(10):1413-32. doi:10.1016/j.clinthera.2011.09.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21999885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diehr P, Yanez D, Ash A, Hornbrook M, Lin DY. Methods for analyzing health care utilization and costs. Annu Rev Public Health. 1999;20:125-44. doi:10.1146/annurev.publhealth.20.1.125</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10352853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Honeycutt AA, Segel JE, Hoerger TJ, Finkelstein EA. Comparing cost-of-illness estimates from alternative approaches: An application to diabetes. Health Serv Res. 2009;44(1):303-20. doi:10.1111/j.1475-6773.2008.00909.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2669634</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19146569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang S, Wang M, DerSarkissian M, et al. . PSY26 healthcare costs, resource utilization, and adverse events associated with long-term oral corticosteroid use in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus in the United States. Value Health. 2021;24(Supplement 1):S233. doi:10.1016/j.jval.2021.04.1164</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen HL, Shen LJ, Hsu PN, Shen CY, Hall SA, Hsiao FY. Cumulative burden of glucocorticoid-related adverse events in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: Findings from a 12-year longitudinal study. J Rheumatol. 2018;45(1):83-9. doi:10.3899/jrheum.160214</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29142034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oinuma K, Harada Y, Nawata Y, et al. . Osteonecrosis in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus develops very early after starting high dose corticosteroid treatment. Ann Rheum Dis. 2001;60(12):1145-8. doi:10.1136/ard.60.12.1145</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1753447</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11709458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rice JB, White AG, Johnson M, et al. . Quantitative characterization of the relationship between levels of extended corticosteroid use and related adverse events in a US population. Curr Med Res Opin. 2018;34(8):1519-27. doi:10.1080/03007995.2018.1474090</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29741130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>