<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">36987604</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>30</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1462-0332</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>62</Volume><Issue>Suppl 1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>29</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Rheumatology (Oxford, England)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Rheumatology (Oxford)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The impact of social determinants of health on the presentation, management and outcomes of systemic lupus erythematosus.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>i10</StartPage><EndPage>i14</EndPage><MedlinePgn>i10-i14</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1093/rheumatology/keac613</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Disparities in SLE rates and outcomes have been attributed to genetic and hormonal factors, cigarette smoking and environmental pollutants. However, a growing body of research indicates that social determinants of health (SDH) also have substantial impact on the disparities that characterize SLE. According to the World Health Organization, SDH are defined as 'the conditions in which people are born, grow, work, live, and age', account for 30-55% of health outcomes, and adversely impact health outcomes among those of low socioeconomic status and stigmatized racial/ethnic groups. We reviewed the impact of key SDH on SLE presentation, management and outcomes, including income, education, neighbourhood factors, healthcare access, discrimination and social support. We found that adverse SDH conditions may lead to more severe SLE with increased morbidity and mortality, and that SDH affect SLE management by dictating the most feasible monitoring and treatment plan for each individual patient based on his or her specific life circumstances (for example, based on health insurance status, distance to nearest provider and/or drug affordability). SDH also have a significant impact on SLE outcomes, with worse disease and psychosocial outcomes associated with lower income level, lower educational attainment, disadvantaged neighbourhoods, lack of health insurance or public health insurance in the USA, travel burden to nearest provider, anti-Black racism and lower social support. Future efforts to improve the management and outcomes of patients with SLE must combat the societal, economic and political forces that perpetuate these inequities.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2023. Published by Oxford University Press on behalf of the British Society for Rheumatology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Williams</LastName><ForeName>Jessica N</ForeName><Initials>JN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Rheumatology, Department of Medicine, Emory University School of Medicine, Atlanta, GA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Drenkard</LastName><ForeName>Cristina</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Rheumatology, Department of Medicine, Emory University School of Medicine, Atlanta, GA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lim</LastName><ForeName>S Sam</ForeName><Initials>SS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Rheumatology, Department of Medicine, Emory University School of Medicine, Atlanta, GA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Rheumatology (Oxford)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100883501</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1462-0324</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004522" MajorTopicYN="N">Educational Status</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D044469" MajorTopicYN="N">Racial Groups</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D064890" MajorTopicYN="Y">Social Determinants of Health</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36987604</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10050938</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/rheumatology/keac613</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">7087228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Izmirly PM, Parton H, Wang L. et al. Prevalence of systemic lupus erythematosus in the united states: estimates from a meta-analysis of the centers for disease control and prevention national lupus registries. Arthritis Rheumatol 2021;73:991&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8169527</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33474834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Division of Population Health, National Center for Chronic Disease Prevention and Health Promotion, Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. https://www.cdc.gov/lupus/features/lupus-awareness/index.htm (15 July 2022, date last accessed).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pons-Estel GJ, Alarc&#xf3;n GS, Scofield L, Reinlib L, Cooper GS.. Understanding the epidemiology and progression of systemic lupus erythematosus. Semin Arthritis Rheum 2010;39:257&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2813992</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19136143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Somers EC, Marder W, Cagnoli P. et al. Population-based incidence and prevalence of systemic lupus erythematosus: the Michigan Lupus Epidemiology and Surveillance program. Arthritis Rheumatol 2014;66:369&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4198147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24504809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim SS, Bayakly AR, Helmick CG. et al. The incidence and prevalence of systemic lupus erythematosus, 2002-2004: the Georgia Lupus Registry. Arthritis Rheumatol 2014;66:357&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4617771</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24504808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izmirly PM, Wan I, Sahl S. et al. The incidence and prevalence of systemic lupus erythematosus in New York County (Manhattan), New York: the Manhattan Lupus Surveillance Program. Arthritis Rheumatol 2017;69:2006&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28891252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helmick CG, Felson DT, Lawrence RC. et al.; National Arthritis Data Workgroup. Estimates of the prevalence of arthritis and other rheumatic conditions in the United States. Part I. Arthritis Rheum 2008;58:15&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18163481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dall&#x2019;Era M, Cisternas MG, Snipes K. et al. The incidence and prevalence of systemic lupus erythematosus in San Francisco County, California: the California Lupus Surveillance Project. Arthritis Rheumatol 2017;69:1996&#x2013;2005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28891237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feldman CH, Hiraki LT, Liu J. et al. Epidemiology and sociodemographics of systemic lupus erythematosus and lupus nephritis among US adults with Medicaid coverage, 2000-2004. Arthritis Rheum 2013;65:753&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3733212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23203603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yen EY, Singh RR.. Brief report: lupus-an unrecognized leading cause of death in young females: a population-based study using nationwide death certificates, 2000-2015. Arthritis Rheumatol 2018;70:1251&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6105528</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29671279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maningding E, Dall&#x2019;Era M, Trupin L, Murphy LB, Yazdany J.. Racial and ethnic differences in the prevalence and time to onset of manifestations of systemic lupus erythematosus: the California lupus surveillance project. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken) 2020;72:622&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6872905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31115180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Contreras G, Lenz O, Pardo V. et al. Outcomes in African Americans and Hispanics with lupus nephritis. Kidney Int 2006;69:1846&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16598205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plantinga L, Lim SS, Patzer R. et al. Incidence of end-stage renal disease among newly diagnosed systemic lupus erythematosus patients: the Georgia lupus registry. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken) 2016;68:357&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4740266</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26239749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clowse ME, Grotegut C.. Racial and ethnic disparities in the pregnancies of women with systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken) 2016;68:1567&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26815791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiani AN, Strand V, Fang H, Jaranilla J, Petri M.. Predictors of self-reported health-related quality of life in systemic lupus erythematosus. Rheumatology (Oxford) 2013;52:1651&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3741477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23681396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim SS, Helmick CG, Bao G. et al. Racial disparities in mortality associated with systemic lupus erythematosus - Fulton and Dekalb counties, Georgia, 2002-2016. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep 2019;68:419&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6542193</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31071073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parks CG, de Souza Espindola Santos A, Barbhaiya M, Costenbader KH.. Understanding the role of environmental factors in the development of systemic lupus erythematosus. Best Pract Res Clin Rheumatol 2017;31:306&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5729939</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29224673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim SS, Drenkard C.. Understanding lupus disparities through a social determinants of health framework: the Georgians organized against lupus research cohort. Rheum Dis Clin North Am 2020;46:613&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32981639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. https://www.who.int/health-topics/social-determinants-of-health#tab=tab_1 (15 July 2022, date last accessed).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams DR, Priest N, Anderson NB.. Understanding associations among race, socioeconomic status, and health: patterns and prospects. Health Psychol 2016;35:407&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4817358</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27018733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeQuattro K, Yelin E.. Socioeconomic status, health care, and outcomes in systemic lupus erythematosus. Rheum Dis Clin North Am 2020;46:639&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32981641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendoza-Pinto C, M&#xe9;ndez-Mart&#xed;nez S, Soto-Santill&#xe1;n P. et al. Socioeconomic status and organ damage in Mexican systemic lupus erythematosus women. Lupus 2015;24:1227&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26085596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoge C, Bowling CB, Lim SS, Drenkard C, Plantinga LC.. Association of poverty income ratio with physical functioning in a cohort of patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. J Rheumatol 2020;47:983&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7334069</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32115428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peschken CA, Katz SJ, Silverman E. et al.; Canadian Network for Improved Outcomes in Systemic Lupus Erythematosus (CaNIOS). The 1000 Canadian faces of lupus: determinants of disease outcome in a large multiethnic cohort. J Rheumatol 2009;36:1200&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19369456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yelin E, Trupin L, Yazdany J.. A prospective study of the impact of current poverty, history of poverty, and exiting poverty on accumulation of disease damage in systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Rheumatol 2017;69:1612&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5529220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28480630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yelin E, Yazdany J, Trupin L.. Relationship between poverty and mortality in systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken) 2018;70:1101&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5882599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28973834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trupin L, Tonner MC, Yazdany J. et al. The role of neighborhood and individual socioeconomic status in outcomes of systemic lupus erythematosus. J Rheumatol 2008;35:1782&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2875144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18634153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooper GS, Treadwell EL, St Clair EW, Gilkeson GS, Dooley MA.. Sociodemographic associations with early disease damage in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Rheum 2007;57:993&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17665464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blomjous BS, Gajadin GRS, Voskuyl AE. et al. Work participation in patients with systematic lupus erythematosus: a systematic review. Rheumatology (Oxford) 2022;61:2740&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9258549</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34792543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alarc&#xf3;n GS, McGwin G Jr, Bastian HM. et al.; LUMINA Study Group. Systemic lupus erythematosus in three ethnic groups. VII [correction of VIII]. Predictors of early mortality in the LUMINA cohort. Arthritis Rheum 2001;45:191&#x2013;202. Erratum in: Arthritis Rheum 2001;45:306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11324784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alarc&#xf3;n GS, McGwin G Jr, Sanchez ML. et al. Systemic lupus erythematosus in three ethnic groups. XIV. Poverty, wealth, and their influence on disease activity. Arthritis Rheum 2004;51:73&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14872458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCormick N, Trupin L, Yelin EH, Katz PP.. Socioeconomic predictors of incident depression in systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken) 2018;70:104&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5617755</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28371529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yelin E, Trupin L, Bunde J, Yazdany J.. Poverty, neighborhoods, persistent stress, and systemic lupus erythematosus outcomes: a qualitative study of the patients' perspective. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken) 2019;71:398&#x2013;405.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6249128</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29781579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>George A, Wong-Pack A, Peschken CA. et al.; 1000 Canadian Faces of Lupus Investigators. Influence of education on disease activity and damage in systemic lupus erythematosus: data from the 1000 Canadian faces of lupus. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken) 2017;69:124&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27110869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng Y, Li M, Zhao J. et al.; CSTAR co-authors. Chinese SLE Treatment and Research Group (CSTAR) registry: VIII. Influence of socioeconomic and geographical variables on disease phenotype and activity in Chinese patients with SLE. Int J Rheum Dis 2018;21:716&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28296238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehat P, Atiquzzaman M, Esdaile JM, Avi&#xd1;a-Zubieta A, De Vera MA.. Medication nonadherence in systemic lupus erythematosus: a systematic review. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken) 2017;69:1706&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28086003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Son MB, Sergeyenko Y, Guan H, Costenbader KH.. Disease activity and transition outcomes in a childhood-onset systemic lupus erythematosus cohort. Lupus 2016;25:1431&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5035166</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27013665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Auerbach C, Beckerman NL.. What social workers in health care should know about lupus: a structural equation model. Health Soc Work 2011;36:269&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22308879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knight AM, Trupin L, Katz P, Yelin E, Lawson EF.. Depression risk in young adults with Juvenile- and adult-onset lupus: twelve years of followup. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken) 2018;70:475&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5700870</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28544568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elera-Fitzcarrald C, Fuentes A, Gonz&#xe1;lez LA. et al. Factors affecting quality of life in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: important considerations and potential interventions. Expert Rev Clin Immunol 2018;14:915&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30266076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartels CM, Rosenthal A, Wang X. et al. Investigating lupus retention in care to inform interventions for disparities reduction: an observational cohort study. Arthritis Res Ther 2020;22:35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7036188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32087763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martz CD, Hunter EA, Kramer MR. et al. Pathways linking census tract typologies with subjective neighborhood disorder and depressive symptoms in the Black Women&#x2019;s Experiences Living with Lupus (BeWELL) Study. Health Place 2021;70:102587.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8328917</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34116496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feldman CH, Costenbader KH, Solomon DH, Subramanian SV, Kawachi I.. Area-level predictors of medication nonadherence among US Medicaid beneficiaries with lupus: a multilevel study. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken) 2019;71:903&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6349545</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30055088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pons-Estel GJ, Saurit V, Alarcon GS. et al. The impact of rural residency on the expression and outcome of systemic lupus erythematosus: data from a multiethnic Latin American cohort. Lupus 2012;21:1397&#x2013;404.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3758687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22941567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gergianaki I, Fanouriakis A, Adamichou C. et al. Is systemic lupus erythematosus different in urban versus rural living environment? Data from the Cretan Lupus Epidemiology and Surveillance Registry. Lupus 2019;28:104&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30522399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdul-Sattar AB, Abou El Magd S.. Association of perceived neighborhood characteristics, socioeconomic status and rural residency with health outcomes in Egyptian patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: one center study. Int J Rheum Dis 2017;20:2045&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24646073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carter EE, Barr SG, Clarke AE.. The global burden of SLE: prevalence, health disparities and socioeconomic impact. Nat Rev Rheumatol 2016;12:605&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27558659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yazdany J, Marafino BJ, Dean ML. et al. Thirty-day hospital readmissions in systemic lupus erythematosus: predictors and hospital- and state-level variation. Arthritis Rheumatol 2014;66:2828&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4180780</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25110993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown EA, Gebregziabher M, Kamen DL, White BM, Williams EM.. Examining racial differences in access to primary care for people living with lupus: use of ambulatory care sensitive conditions to measure access. Ethn Dis 2020;30:611&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7518530</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32989361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown EA, Dismuke-Greer CE, Ramakrishnan V, Faith TD, Williams EM.. Impact of the affordable care act Medicaid expansion on access to care and hospitalization charges for lupus patients. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken) 2020;72:208&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6992496</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31562794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Najjar R, Alexander SA, Hughes GC, Yazdany J, Singh N.. Predictors of thirty-day hospital readmissions in systemic lupus erythematosus in the US: a nationwide study. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken) 2022. doi: 10.1002/acr.24900.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/acr.24900</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9579214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35439363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walunas TL, Jackson KL, Chung AH. et al. Disease outcomes and care fragmentation among patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken) 2017;69:1369&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5447502</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27899012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bitencourt N, Makris UE, Solow EB. et al. Predictors of adverse outcomes in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus transitioning to adult care. Semin Arthritis Rheum 2021;51:353&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33601191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plantinga LC, Drenkard C, Patzer RE. et al. Sociodemographic and geographic predictors of quality of care in United States patients with end-stage renal disease due to lupus nephritis. Arthritis Rheumatol 2015;67:761&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5340148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25692867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devlin A, Waikar SS, Solomon DH. et al. Variation in initial kidney replacement therapy for end-stage renal disease due to lupus nephritis in the United States. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken) 2011;63:1642&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3227771</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22058067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams EM, Ortiz K, Zhang J, Zhou J, Kamen D.. The systemic lupus erythematosus travel burden survey: baseline data among a South Carolina cohort. BMC Res Notes 2016;9:246.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4850711</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27129590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>White AA, Smalls BL, Ba A. et al. The effect of travel burden on depression and anxiety in African American women living with systemic lupus. Healthcare (Basel) 2021;9:1507.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8621308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34828553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams EM, Ortiz K, Flournoy-Floyd M, Bruner L, Kamen D.. Systemic lupus erythematosus observations of travel burden: a qualitative inquiry. Int J Rheum Dis 2015;18:751&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26176174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chae DH, Martz CD, Fuller-Rowell TE. et al. Racial discrimination, disease activity, and organ damage: the Black Women&#x2019;s Experiences Living With Lupus (BeWELL) study. Am J Epidemiol 2019;188:1434&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6670046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31062841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martz CD, Allen AM, Fuller-Rowell TE. et al. Vicarious racism stress and disease activity: the Black Women&#x2019;s Experiences Living with Lupus (BeWELL) Study. J Racial Ethn Health Disparities 2019;6:1044&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7302115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31215018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spears EC, Allen AM, Chung KW. et al. Anticipatory racism stress, smoking and disease activity: the Black women's experiences living with lupus (BeWELL) study. J Behav Med 2021;44:760&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34159500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunter EA, Spears EC, Martz CD. et al. Racism-related stress and psychological distress: Black Women&#x2019;s Experiences Living with Lupus study. J Health Psychol 2021;26:2374&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32228184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu Q, Liu D, Zeng F. et al. [Social support and management strategies for chronic disease in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus]. Zhong Nan Da Xue Xue Bao Yi Xue Ban 2019;44:67&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30837405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jordan J, Thompson NJ, Dunlop-Thomas C, Lim SS, Drenkard C.. Relationships among organ damage, social support, and depression in African American women with systemic lupus erythematosus. Lupus 2019;28:253&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6415670</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30482093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bae SC, Hashimoto H, Karlson EW, Liang MH, Daltroy LH.. Variable effects of social support by race, economic status, and disease activity in systemic lupus erythematosus. J Rheumatol 2001;28:1245&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11414264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng Y, Ye DQ, Pan HF. et al. Influence of social support on health-related quality of life in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. Clin Rheumatol 2009;28:265&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19002545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brennan KA, Creaven AM.. Living with invisible illness: social support experiences of individuals with systemic lupus erythematosus. Qual Life Res 2016;25:1227&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26449351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leung J, Ra J, Baker EA, Kim AHJ.. &#x201c;&#x2026;Not Having the Real Support That We Need&#x201d;: patients&#x2019; experiences with ambiguity of systemic lupus erythematosus and erosion of social support. ACR Open Rheumatol 2019;1:135&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6858040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31773100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazzoni D, Cicognani E.. Problematic social support from patients&#x2019; perspective: the case of systemic lupus erythematosus. Soc Work Health Care 2014;53:435&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24835088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>