<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36987603</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>30</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1462-0332</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>62</Volume><Issue>Suppl 1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>29</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Rheumatology (Oxford, England)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Rheumatology (Oxford)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Improving access to SLE therapies in low and middle-income countries.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>i30</StartPage><EndPage>i35</EndPage><MedlinePgn>i30-i35</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1093/rheumatology/keac530</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>SLE increases disease burden in those affected with it, and that is particularly the case in low- and middle-income countries. The 2019 Addressing Lupus Pillar of Health Advancement project is a multiphase initiative whose objective is to recognize, hierarchize and establish approaches for diligent SLE research, care and access to healthcare. Lack of access to high-cost medications that have been shown to be efficacious in the short term and that potentially reduce damage in SLE is a complex issue. In this review, we highlight opportunities and plans of action to diminish costs and improve access to therapies, which should be recognized and executed, preferably within regional strategies with multiple stakeholders (including supranational organizations, governments, the pharmaceutical industry, medical societies and the general population) connected with and grounded in structured and clear cost-effectiveness analysis.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2023. Published by Oxford University Press on behalf of the British Society for Rheumatology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mendoza-Pinto</LastName><ForeName>Claudia</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Systemic Autoimmune Disease Research Unit, Hospital de Especialidades, Centro M&#xe9;dico Nacional, MAV-Centro de Investigaci&#xf3;n Biom&#xe9;dica de Oriente (CIBIOR), Mexican Institute for Social Security, Puebla, Mexico.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rheumatology and Immunology Department Medicine School Benem&#xe9;rita, Universidad Aut&#xf3;noma de Puebla, Puebla, Mexico.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Etchegaray-Morales</LastName><ForeName>Ivet</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rheumatology and Immunology Department Medicine School Benem&#xe9;rita, Universidad Aut&#xf3;noma de Puebla, Puebla, Mexico.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ugarte-Gil</LastName><ForeName>Manuel F</ForeName><Initials>MF</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1728-1999</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rheumatology Department. Hospital Guillermo Almenara Irigoyen, EsSalud, Lima, Peru.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Grupo Peruano de Estudio de Enfermedades Autoinmunes Sist&#xe9;micas, Universidad Cient&#xed;fica del Sur, Lima, Peru.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Rheumatology (Oxford)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100883501</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1462-0324</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003906" MajorTopicYN="Y">Developing Countries</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003695" MajorTopicYN="N">Delivery of Health Care</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017281" MajorTopicYN="N">Cost of Illness</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SLE</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">access to healthcare</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">low- and middle-income countries</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36987603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10050935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/rheumatology/keac530</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">7087227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Barber MRW, Drenkard C, Falasinnu T. et al. Global epidemiology of systemic lupus erythematosus. Nature Rev Rheumatol 2021;17:515&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8982275</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34345022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demas KL, Costenbader KH.. Disparities in lupus care and outcomes. Curr Opin Rheumatol 2009;21:102&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2774141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19339919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manzi S, Raymond S, Tse K. et al. Global consensus building and prioritisation of fundamental lupus challenges: the ALPHA project. Lupus Sci Med 2019;6:e000342.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6667778</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31413854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tse K, Sangodkar S, Bloch L. et al. The ALPHA Project: establishing consensus and prioritisation of global community recommendations to address major challenges in lupus diagnosis, care, treatment and research. Lupus Sci Med 2021;8:e000433.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7875256</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33563729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braveman P. What are health disparities and health equity? We need to be clear. Public Health Rep 2014;129:5&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3863701</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24385658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Danchenko N, Satia JA, Anthony MS.. Epidemiology of systemic lupus erythematosus: a comparison of worldwide disease burden. Lupus 2006;15:308&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16761508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tiffin N, Hodkinson B, Okpechi I.. Lupus in Africa: can we dispel the myths and face the challenges? Lupus 2014;23:102&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24174511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Global Epidemiology of SLE: still important gaps in our knowledge. Rheumatology (Oxford) 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scherlinger M, Mertz P, Sagez F. et al. Worldwide trends in all-cause mortality of auto-immune systemic diseases between 2001 and 2014. Autoimmun Rev 2020;19:102531.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32234406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez LA, Pons-Estel GJ, Toloza SMA, Ugarte-Gil MF, Alarc&#xf3;n GS.. Understanding risk factors for poor outcomes in a multiethnic longitudinal cohort: the LUMINA (Lupus in Minorities: Nature vs. Nurture) experience (LUMINA LXXXII). Rheum Dis Clin North Am 2021;47:55&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34042054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ward MM, Studenski S.. Clinical manifestations of systemic lupus erythematosus. Identification of racial and socioeconomic influences. Arch Int Med 1990;150:849&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2327845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasitanon N, Fine DM, Haas M, Magder LS, Petri M.. Hydroxychloroquine use predicts complete renal remission within 12 months among patients treated with mycophenolate mofetil therapy for membranous lupus nephritis. Lupus 2006;15:366&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16830883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez M, Alarc&#xf3;n GS, Calvo-Al&#xe9;n J. et al.; LUMINA Study Group. A multiethnic, multicenter cohort of patients with systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) as a model for the study of ethnic disparities in SLE. Arthritis Rheum 2007;57:576&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17471524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ward MM, Pyun E, Studenski S.. Long-term survival in systemic lupus erythematosus. Patient characteristics associated with poorer outcomes. Arthritis Rheum 1995;38:274&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7848319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petri M, Perez-Gutthann S, Longenecker JC, Hochberg M.. Morbidity of systemic lupus erythematosus: role of race and socioeconomic status. Am J Med 1991;91:345&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1951378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker K, Pope J.. Employment and work disability in systemic lupus erythematosus: a systematic review. Rheumatology (Oxford) 2009;48:281&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19153144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pons-Estel BA, Catoggio LJ, Cardiel MH. et al.; Grupo Latinoamericano de Estudio del Lupus (GLADEL). The GLADEL multinational Latin American prospective inception cohort of 1,214 patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: ethnic and disease heterogeneity among &#x201c;hispanics&#x201d;. Medicine 2004;83:1&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14747764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Re&#xe1;tegui-Sokolova C, Ugarte-Gil MF, Harvey GB. et al. Predictors of renal damage in systemic lupus erythematous patients: data from a multiethnic, multinational Latin American lupus cohort (GLADEL). RMD Open 2020;6:e001299.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7859505</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33310863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burling F, Ng J, Thein H. et al. Ethnic, clinical and immunological factors in systemic lupus erythematosus and the development of lupus nephritis: results from a multi-ethnic New Zealand cohort. Lupus 2007;16:830&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17895308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasitanon N, Magder LS, Petri M.. Predictors of survival in systemic lupus erythematosus. Medicine 2006;85:147&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16721257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Studenski S, Allen NB, Caldwell DS, Rice JR, Polisson RP.. Survival in systemic lupus erythematosus. A multivariate analysis of demographic factors. Arthritis Rheum 1987;30:1326&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3435564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alarc&#xf3;n GS, McGwin GJ, Sanchez ML. et al.; The Lumina Study Group. Systemic lupus erythematosus in three ethnic groups. XIV. Poverty, wealth, and their influence on disease activity. Arthritis Rheum 2004;51:73&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14872458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Vollenhoven RF, Navarra SV, Levy RA. et al. Long-term safety and limited organ damage in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus treated with belimumab: a Phase III study extension. Rheumatology (Oxford) 2020;59:281&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7571485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31302695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tektonidou MG, Lewandowski LB, Hu J, Dasgupta A, Ward MM.. Survival in adults and children with systemic lupus erythematosus: a systematic review and Bayesian meta-analysis of studies from 1950 to 2016. Ann Rheum Dis 2017;76:2009&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28794077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klumb EM, Scheinberg M, Souza V. D. et al. The landscape of systemic lupus erythematosus in Brazil: an expert panel review and recommendations. Lupus 2021;30:1684&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8489682</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34255586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
The World Bank. The World Bank in Middle Income Countries. https://www.worldbank.org/en/country/mic/overview (27 June 2022, date last accessed).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Safiri S, Kolahi AA, Cross M. et al. Global, regional, and national burden of other musculoskeletal disorders 1990-2017: results from the Global Burden of Disease Study 2017. Rheumatology (Oxford) 2021;60:855&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32840303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Global Burden of Disease Collaborative Network Global Burden of Disease Study (2018). 2016 results institute for health metrics and evaluation. 2017. http://ghdx.healthdata.org/gbd-results-tool (5 March 2020, date last accessed).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prada SI, P&#xe9;rez AM, Nieto-Aristiz&#xe1;bal I, Tob&#xf3;n GJ.. Increase in direct costs for health systems due to lupus nephritis: the case of Colombia. Einstein (Sao Paulo) 2022;20:eAO6553.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9018061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35476081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meacock R, Dale N, Harrison MJ.. The humanistic and economic burden of systemic lupus erythematosus: a systematic review. Pharmacoeconomics 2013;31:49&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23329592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morel CM, McGuire A, Mossialos E.. The level of income appears to have no consistent bearing on pharmaceutical prices across countries. Health Aff (Millwood) 2011;30:1545&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21821572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Pan American Health Organization. Access to high-cost medicines in the Americas: situation, challenges and perspectives. https://www.paho.org/hq/dmdocuments/2010/High-cost-Med-Tech-Series-No-1-Sep-15-10.pdf (18 May 2022, date last accessed).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flood CM, Gross A.. Litigating the right to health: what can we learn from a comparative law and health care systems approach? Health Hum Rights J 2014;16:E62&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25569725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gavan S, Bruce I, Payne K.. Generating evidence to inform health technology assessment of treatments for SLE: a systematic review of decision-analytic model-based economic evaluations. Lupus Sci Med 2020;7:e000350.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7389518</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32723809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
WHO. Health technology assessment. https://www.who.int/teams/health-product-policy-and-standards/assistive-and-medical-technology/medical-devices/assessment (17 May 2022, date last accessed).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banta D. What is technology assessment? Int J Technol Assess Health Care 2009;25(Suppl 1):7&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19519979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fr&#xf8;nsdal KB, Facey K, Klemp M. et al. Health technology assessment to optimize health technology utilization: using implementation initiatives and monitoring processes. Int J Technol Assess Health Care 2010;26:309&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20584360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oortwijn W, van Oosterhout S, Kapiriri L.. Application of evidence-informed deliberative processes in health technology assessment in low- and middle-income countries. Int J Technol Assess Health Care 2020;36:440&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32715993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conran CA, Moreland LW.. A review of biosimilars for rheumatoid arthritis. Curr Opin Pharmacol 2022;64:102234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35552095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia R, Araujo DV.. The regulation of biosimilars in Latin America. Curr Rheumatol Rep 2016;18:16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26951254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. Lupus Research Studies. https://www.cdc.gov/lupus/funded/lupus-studies.htm (29 May 2022, date last accessed).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoy D, Geere J-A, Davatchi F, Meggitt B, Barrero LH.. A time for action: opportunities for preventing the growing burden and disability from musculoskeletal conditions in low- and middle-income countries. Best Pract Res Clin Rheumatol 2014;28:377&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25481422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
World Health Organization. WHO model list of essential medicine. https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-MHP-HPS-EML-2021.02 (25 May 2022, date last accessed).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
US Food and Drug Administration. 2015&#x2013;2019 Drug Trials Snapshots Summary Report. Five-Year Summary and Analysis of Clinical Trial Participation and Demographics. https://www.fda.gov/media/143592/download (20 May 2022, date last accessed).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Memon R, Asif M, Khoso AB. et al.; Pakistan Institute of Living and Learning (PILL). Recognising values and engaging communities across cultures: towards developing a cultural protocol for researchers. BMC Med Ethics 2021;22:47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8072318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33902560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beard AJ, Sleath B, Blalock SJ. et al. Predictors of rheumatoid arthritis patient-physician communication about medication costs during visits to rheumatologists. Arthritis Care Res 2010;62:632&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20191466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>