<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37003131</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>19</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2213-1582</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>38</Volume><PubDate><Year>2023</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>NeuroImage. Clinical</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Neuroimage Clin</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Abnormal cerebral hemodynamics and blood-brain barrier permeability detected with perfusion MRI in systemic lupus erythematosus patients.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>103390</StartPage><MedlinePgn>103390</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">103390</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.nicl.2023.103390</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S2213-1582(23)00079-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Dynamic susceptibility contrast (DSC) magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) has previously shown alterations in cerebral perfusion in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE). However, the results have been inconsistent, in particular regarding neuropsychiatric (NP) SLE. Thus, we investigated perfusion-based measures in different brain regions in SLE patients with and without NP involvement, and additionally, in white matter hyperintensities (WMHs), the most common MRI pathology in SLE patients.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We included 3&#xa0;T MRI images (conventional and DSC) from 64 female SLE patients and 19 healthy controls (HC). Three different NPSLE attribution models were used: the Systemic Lupus International Collaborating Clinics (SLICC) A model (13 patients), the SLICC B model (19 patients), and the American College of Rheumatology (ACR) case definitions for NPSLE (38 patients). Normalized cerebral blood flow (CBF), cerebral blood volume (CBV) and mean transit time (MTT) were calculated in 26 manually drawn regions of interest and compared between SLE patients and HC, and between NPSLE and non-NPSLE patients. Additionally, normalized CBF, CBV and MTT, as well as absolute values of the blood-brain barrier leakage parameter (K<sub>2</sub>) were investigated in WMHs compared to normal appearing white matter (NAWM) in the SLE patients.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">After correction for multiple comparisons, the most prevalent finding was a bilateral significant decrease in MTT in SLE patients compared to HC in the hypothalamus, putamen, right posterior thalamus and right anterior insula. Significant decreases in SLE compared to HC were also found for CBF in the pons, and for CBV in the bilateral putamen and posterior thalamus. Significant increases were found for CBF in the posterior corpus callosum and for CBV in the anterior corpus callosum. Similar patterns were found for both NPSLE and non-NPSLE patients for all attributional models compared to HC. However, no significant perfusion differences were revealed between NPSLE and non-NPSLE patients regardless of attribution model. The WMHs in SLE patients showed a significant increase in all perfusion-based metrics (CBF, CBV, MTT and K<sub>2</sub>) compared to NAWM.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Our study revealed perfusion differences in several brain regions in SLE patients compared to HC, independently of NP involvement. Furthermore, increased K<sub>2</sub> in WMHs compared to NAWM may indicate blood-brain barrier dysfunction in SLE patients. We conclude that our results show a robust cerebral perfusion, independent from the different NP attribution models, and provide insight into potential BBB dysfunction and altered vascular properties of WMHs in female SLE patients. Despite SLE being most prevalent in females, a generalization of our conclusions should be avoided, and future studies including all sexes are needed.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 The Author(s). Published by Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Salomonsson</LastName><ForeName>T</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Sciences/Radiology, Lund University, Lund, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rumetshofer</LastName><ForeName>T</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Sciences/Radiology, Lund University, Lund, Sweden; Department of Clinical Sciences/Division of Logopedics, Phoniatrics and Audiology, Lund University, Lund, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>J&#xf6;nsen</LastName><ForeName>A</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Sciences Lund/Rheumatology, Lund University, Sk&#xe5;ne University Hospital, Lund, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bengtsson</LastName><ForeName>A A</ForeName><Initials>AA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Sciences Lund/Rheumatology, Lund University, Sk&#xe5;ne University Hospital, Lund, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zervides</LastName><ForeName>K A</ForeName><Initials>KA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Sciences Lund/Rheumatology, Lund University, Sk&#xe5;ne University Hospital, Lund, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nilsson</LastName><ForeName>P</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Sciences Lund/Neurology, Lund University, Sk&#xe5;ne University Hospital, Lund, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Knutsson</LastName><ForeName>M</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Sciences/Radiology, Lund University, Lund, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wirestam</LastName><ForeName>R</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Radiation Physics, Lund University, Lund, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>L&#xe4;tt</LastName><ForeName>J</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Imaging and Physiology, Sk&#xe5;ne University Hospital, Lund, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Knutsson</LastName><ForeName>L</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Radiation Physics, Lund University, Lund, Sweden; Russell H. Morgan Department of Radiology and Radiological Science, Johns Hopkins University School of Medicine, Baltimore, MD, United States; F.M. Kirby Research Center for Functional Brain Imaging, Kennedy Krieger Institute, Baltimore, MD, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sundgren</LastName><ForeName>P C</ForeName><Initials>PC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Sciences/Radiology, Lund University, Lund, Sweden; Department of Medical Imaging and Physiology, Sk&#xe5;ne University Hospital, Lund, Sweden; Lund University Bioimaging Center, Lund University, Lund, Sweden. Electronic address: pia.sundgren@med.lu.se.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Neuroimage Clin</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101597070</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2213-1582</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001812" MajorTopicYN="N">Blood-Brain Barrier</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018810" MajorTopicYN="N">Magnetic Resonance Angiography</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008279" MajorTopicYN="N">Magnetic Resonance Imaging</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020945" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lupus Vasculitis, Central Nervous System</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010477" MajorTopicYN="N">Perfusion</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Blood-brain-barrier</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cerebral perfusion</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dynamic susceptibility contrast</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Systemic lupus erythematosus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">White matter hyperintensities</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of Competing Interest The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>8</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37003131</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10102558</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nicl.2023.103390</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2213-1582(23)00079-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abreu M.R., Jakosky A., Folgerini M., Brenol J.C.T., Xavier R.M., Kapczinsky F. Neuropsychiatric systemic lupus erythematosus: correlation of brain MR imaging, CT, and SPECT. Clin Imaging. 2005;29(3):215&#x2013;221.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15855069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ainiala H., Hietaharju A., Loukkola J., Peltola J., Korpela M., Mets&#xe4;noja R., Auvinen A. Validity of the new American College of Rheumatology criteria for neuropsychiatric lupus syndromes: a population-based evaluation. Arthritis Rheum. 2001;45(5):419&#x2013;423.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11642640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borrelli M., Tamarozzi R., Colamussi P., Govoni M., Trotta F., Lappi S. Evaluation with MR, perfusion MR and cerebral flowSPECT in NPSLE patients. Radiol Med. 2003;105(5&#x2013;6):482&#x2013;489.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12949459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bortoluzzi A., Scir&#xe8; C.A., Govoni M. Attribution of neuropsychiatric manifestations to systemic lupus erythematosus. Front Med (Lausanne). 2018;14(5):68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5861139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29594125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boxerman J.L., Schmainda K.M., Weisskoff R.M. Relative cerebral blood volume maps corrected for contrast agent extravasation significantly correlate with glioma tumor grade, whereas uncorrected maps do not. AJNR Am J Neuroradiol. 2006;27(4):859&#x2013;867.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8134002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16611779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brickman A.M., Zahra A., Muraskin J., Steffener J., Holland C.M., Habeck C., Borogovac A., Ramos M.A., Brown T.R., Asllani I., Stern Y. Reduction in cerebral blood flow in areas appearing as white matter hyperintensities on magnetic resonance imaging. Psychiatry Res. 2009;172(2):117&#x2013;120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2763417</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19324534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bulk M., van Harten T., Kenkhuis B., Inglese F., Hegeman I., van Duinen S., Ercan E., Magro-Checa C., Goeman J., Mawrin C., van Buchem M., Steup-Beekman G., Huizinga T., van der Weerd L., Ronen I. Quantitative susceptibility mapping in the thalamus and basal ganglia of systemic lupus erythematosus patients with neuropsychiatric complaints. Neuroimage Clin. 2021;30</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8053812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33812303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cagnoli P.C., Sundgren P.C., Kairys ANSON, Graft C.C., Clauw D.J., Gebarski STEPHEN, McCUNE W.J., Schmidt-wilcke TOBIAS. Changes in regional brain morphology in neuropsychiatric systemic lupus erythematosus. J Rheumatol. 2012;39(5):959&#x2013;967.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22467931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi J.M., Mackay M., Hoang A., Cheng K., Aranow C., Ivanidze J., et al. Alterations in Blood-Brain Barrier Permeability in Patients with Systemic Lupus Erythematosus. AJNR Am J Neuroradiol. 2019;40(3):470&#x2013;477.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6483727</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30792254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dababneh H., Guerrero W., Wilson K., Mocco J.D. Observation of Mean Transit Time (Mtt) Perfusion Maps on a 320-Detector Row Ct Scanner and its Potential Application in Acute Ischemic Stroke. J Neurol Neurophysiol. 2011;02(04)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dewey B.E., Xu X., Knutsson L., Jog A., Prince J.L., Barker P.B., van Zijl P.C.M., Leigh R., Nyquist P. MTT and Blood-Brain Barrier Disruption within Asymptomatic Vascular WM Lesions. AJNR Am J Neuroradiol. 2021;42(8):1396&#x2013;1402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8367617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34083262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doucet C., Roncarolo F., Tampieri D., Del Pilar C.M. Paradoxically decreased mean transit time in patients presenting with acute stroke. J Comput Assist Tomogr. 2016;40(3):409&#x2013;412.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26953763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emmer B.J., van Osch M.J., Wu O., Steup-Beekman G.M., Steens S.C., Huizinga T.W., van Buchem M.A., van der Grond J. Perfusion MRI in neuro-psychiatric systemic lupus erthemathosus. J Magn Reson Imaging. 2010;32(2):283&#x2013;288.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20677252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisel C.R., Ackerman J.L., Buxton R.B., Garrido L., Belliveau J.W., Rosen B.R., Brady T.J. MR contrast due to microscopically heterogeneous magnetic susceptibility: numerical simulations and applications to cerebral physiology. Magn Reson Med. 1991;17(2):336&#x2013;347.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2062208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gasparovic C.M., Roldan C.A., Sibbitt W.L., Qualls C.R., Mullins P.G., Sharrar J.M., Yamamoto J.J., Bockholt H.J. Elevated cerebral blood flow and volume in systemic lupus measured by dynamic susceptibility contrast magnetic resonance imaging. J Rheumatol. 2010;37(9):1834&#x2013;1843.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3609948</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20551095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giovacchini GIAMPIERO, Mosca MARTA, Manca GIANPIERO, Della porta MAURO, Neri CLAUDIA, Bombardieri STEFANO, Ciarmiello ANDREA, Strauss H.W., Mariani GIULIANO, Volterrani DUCCIO. Cerebral blood flow in depressed patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. J Rheumatol. 2010;37(9):1844&#x2013;1851.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20595265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gladman D., Ginzler E., Goldsmith C., Fortin P., Liang M., Sanchez-Guerrero J., Urowitz M., Bacon P., Bombardieri S., Hanly J., Jones J., Hay E., Symmons D., Isenberg D., Kalunion K., Maddison P., Nived O., Sturfelt G., Petri M., Richter M., Snaith M., Zoma A. The development and initial validation of the Systemic Lupus International Collaborating Clinics/American College of Rheumatology damage index for systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Rheum. 1996;39(3):363&#x2013;369.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8607884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gladman D.D., Iba&#xf1;ez D., Urowitz M.B. Systemic lupus erythematosus disease activity index 2000. J Rheumatol. 2002;29(2):288&#x2013;291.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11838846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanly J.G., McCurdy G., Fougere L., Douglas J.-A., Thompson K. Neuropsychiatric events in systemic lupus erythematosus: attribution and clinical significance. J Rheumatol. 2004;31(11):2156&#x2013;2162.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15517627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanly J.G., Urowitz M.B., Sanchez-Guerrero J., Bae S.C., Gordon C., Wallace D.J., Isenberg D., Alarc&#xf3;n G.S., Clarke A., Bernatsky S., Merrill J.T., Petri M., Dooley M.A., Gladman D., Fortin P.R., Steinsson K., Bruce I., Manzi S., Khamashta M., Zoma A., Aranow C., Ginzler E., Van Vollenhoven R., Font J., Sturfelt G., Nived O., Ramsey-Goldman R., Kalunian K., Douglas J., Thompson K., Farewell V. Neuropsychiatric events at the time of diagnosis of systemic lupus erythematosus: an international inception cohort study. Arthritis Rheum. 2007;56(1):265&#x2013;273.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17195230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanly J.G., Urowitz M.B., Su L., Sanchez-Guerrero J., Bae S.C., Gordon C., Wallace D.J., Isenberg D., Alarc&#xf3;n G.S., Merrill J.T., Clarke A., Bernatsky S., Dooley M.A., Fortin P.R., Gladman D., Steinsson K., Petri M., Bruce I.N., Manzi S., Khamashta M., Zoma A., Font J., Van Vollenhoven R., Aranow C., Ginzler E., Nived O., Sturfelt G., Ramsey-goldman R., Kalunian K., Douglas J., Qiufen Qi K., Thompson K., Farewell V. Short-term outcome of neuropsychiatric events in systemic lupus erythematosus upon enrollment into an international inception cohort study. Arthritis Rheum. 2008;59(5):721&#x2013;729.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4656032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18438902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes M., Sundgren P.C., Fan X., Foerster B., Nan B., Welsh R.C., Williamson J.A., Attwood J., Maly P.V., Chenevert T.L., McCune W., Gebarski S. Diffusion tensor imaging in patients with acute onset of neuropsychiatric systemic lupus erythematosus: a prospective study of apparent diffusion coefficient, fractional anisotropy values, and eigenvalues in different regions of the brain. Acta Radiol. 2007;48(2):213&#x2013;222.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17354144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huisa B.N., Caprihan A., Thompson J., Prestopnik J., Qualls C.R., Rosenberg G.A. Long-Term Blood-Brain Barrier Permeability Changes in Binswanger Disease. Stroke. 2015;46(9):2413&#x2013;2418.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4550546</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26205374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jafari-Khouzani K., Emblem K.E., Kalpathy-Cramer J., Bj&#xf8;rnerud A., Vangel M.G., Gerstner E.R., Schmainda K.M., Paynabar K., Wu O., Wen P.Y., Batchelor T., Rosen B., Stufflebeam S.M. Repeatability of cerebral perfusion using dynamic susceptibility contrast MRI in glioblastoma patients. Transl Oncol. 2015;8(3):137&#x2013;146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4486737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26055170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jenkinson M., Bannister P., Brady M., Smith S. Improved optimization for the robust and accurate linear registration and motion correction of brain images. Neuroimage. 2002;17(2):825&#x2013;841.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12377157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jenkinson M., Smith S. A global optimisation method for robust affine registration of brain images. Med Image Anal. 2001;5(2):143&#x2013;156.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11516708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jennings J.E., Sundgren P.C., Attwood J., McCune J., Maly P. Value of MRI of the brain in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus and neurologic disturbance. Neuroradiology. 2004;46(1):15&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14648006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia J., Xie J., Li H., Wei H., Li X., Hu J., Meng D., Zhang Y., Zhang X. Cerebral blood flow abnormalities in neuropsychiatric systemic lupus erythematosus. Lupus. 2019;28(9):1128&#x2013;1133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31315530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamintsky L., Beyea S.D., Fisk J.D., Hashmi J.A., Omisade A., Calkin C., Bardouille T., Bowen C., Quraan M., Mitnitski A., Matheson K., Friedman A., Hanly J.G. Blood-brain barrier leakage in systemic lupus erythematosus is associated with gray matter loss and cognitive impairment. Ann Rheum Dis. 2020;79(12):1580&#x2013;1587.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33004325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knutsson L., Lindgren E., Ahlgren A., van Osch M.J.P., Bloch K.M., Surova Y., St&#xe5;hlberg F., van Westen D., Wirestam R. Dynamic susceptibility contrast MRI with a prebolus contrast agent administration design for improved absolute quantification of perfusion. Magn Reson Med. 2014;72(4):996&#x2013;1006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24285621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lapointe E., Li D.K.B., Traboulsee A.L., Rauscher A. What Have We Learned from Perfusion MRI in Multiple Sclerosis? AJNR Am J Neuroradiol. 2018;39(6):994&#x2013;1000.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7410640</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29301779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leigh R., Jen S.S., Varma D.D., Hillis A.E., Barker P.B., Herholz K. Arrival time correction for dynamic susceptibility contrast MR permeability imaging in stroke patients. PLoS ONE. 2012;7(12)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3527589</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23285132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luyendijk J., Steens S.C.A., Ouwendijk W.J.N., Steup-Beekman G.M., Bollen E.L.E.M., van der Grond J., Huizinga T.W.J., Emmer B.J., van Buchem M.A. Neuropsychiatric systemic lupus erythematosus: lessons learned from magnetic resonance imaging. Arthritis Rheum. 2011;63(3):722&#x2013;732.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21360502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magro Checa C., Cohen D., Bollen E.L.E.M., van Buchem M.A., Huizinga T.W.J., Steup-Beekman G.M. Demyelinating disease in SLE: is it multiple sclerosis or lupus? Best Pract Res Clin Rheumatol. 2013;27(3):405&#x2013;424.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24238696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marstrand J.R., Garde E., Rostrup E., Ring P., Rosenbaum S., Mortensen E.L., Larsson H.B.W. Cerebral perfusion and cerebrovascular reactivity are reduced in white matter hyperintensities. Stroke. 2002;33(4):972&#x2013;976.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11935046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murayama K., Katada K., Hayakawa M., Toyama H. Shortened mean transit time in CT perfusion with singular value decomposition analysis in acute cerebral infarction: quantitative evaluation and comparison with various CT perfusion parameters. J Comput Assist Tomogr. 2017;41(2):173&#x2013;180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27753725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nikolopoulos D., Fanouriakis A., Boumpas D.T. Update on the pathogenesis of central nervous system lupus. Curr Opin Rheumatol. 2019;31(6):669&#x2013;677.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31415031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oda K., Matsushima E., Okubo Y., Ohta K., Murata Y., Koike R., Miyasaka N., Kato M. Abnormal regional cerebral blood flow in systemic lupus erythematosus patients with psychiatric symptoms. J Clin Psychiatry. 2005;66(07):907&#x2013;913.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16013907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogasawara A., Kakeda S., Watanabe K., Ide S., Ueda I., Murakami Y.u., Moriya J., Futatsuya K., Sato T., Nakayamada S., Saito K., Tanaka Y., Liu T., Wang Y.i., Korogi Y. Quantitative susceptibility mapping in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: detection of abnormalities in normal-appearing basal ganglia. Eur Radiol. 2016;26(4):1056&#x2013;1063.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26228900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ota Y., Srinivasan A., Capizzano A.A., Bapuraj J.R., Kim J., Kurokawa R., Baba A., Moritani T. Central nervous system systemic lupus erythematosus: pathophysiologic, clinical, and imaging features. Radiographics. 2022;42(1):212&#x2013;232.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34990324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papadaki E., Fanouriakis A., Kavroulakis E., Karageorgou D., Sidiropoulos P., Bertsias G., Simos P., Boumpas D.T. Neuropsychiatric lupus or not? Cerebral hypoperfusion by perfusion-weighted MRI in normal-appearing white matter in primary neuropsychiatric lupus erythematosus. Ann Rheum Dis. 2018;77(3):441&#x2013;448.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29259047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papadaki E., Kavroulakis E., Bertsias G., Fanouriakis A., Karageorgou D., Sidiropoulos P., Papastefanakis E., Boumpas D.T., Simos P. Regional cerebral perfusion correlates with anxiety in neuropsychiatric SLE: evidence for a mechanism distinct from depression. Lupus. 2019;28(14):1678&#x2013;1689.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31718491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petri M., Orbai A.-M., Alarc&#xf3;n G.S., Gordon C., Merrill J.T., Fortin P.R., et al. Derivation and validation of the Systemic Lupus International Collaborating Clinics classification criteria for systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Rheum. 2012;64(8):2677&#x2013;2686.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3409311</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22553077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Promjunyakul N., Lahna D., Kaye J.A., Dodge H.H., Erten-Lyons D., Rooney W.D., Silbert L.C. Characterizing the white matter hyperintensity penumbra with cerebral blood flow measures. Neuroimage Clin. 2015;8:224&#x2013;229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4473817</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26106546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren T., Ho R.-C.-M., Mak A. Dysfunctional cortico-basal ganglia-thalamic circuit and altered hippocampal-amygdala activity on cognitive set-shifting in non-neuropsychiatric systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Rheum. 2012;64(12):4048&#x2013;4059.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23165941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sachdev P., Wen W., Shnier R., Brodaty H. Cerebral blood volume in T2-weighted white matter hyperintensities using exogenous contrast based perfusion MRI. J Neuropsychiatry Clin Neurosci. 2004;16(1):83&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14990763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Semmineh N.B., Bell L.C., Stokes A.M., Hu L.S., Boxerman J.L., Quarles C.C. Optimization of Acquisition and Analysis Methods for Clinical Dynamic Susceptibility Contrast MRI Using a Population-Based Digital Reference Object. AJNR Am J Neuroradiol. 2018;39(11):1981&#x2013;1988.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6239921</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30309842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaharir S.S., Osman S.S., Md Rani S.A., Sakthiswary R., Said M.S.M. Factors associated with increased white matter hyperintense lesion (WMHI) load in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) Lupus. 2018;27(1):25&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28467290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen Y.Y., Kao C.H., Ho Y.J., Lee J.K. Regional cerebral blood flow in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. J Neuroimaging. 1999;9(3):160&#x2013;164.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10436758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shin W., Horowitz S., Ragin A., Chen Y., Walker M., Carroll T.J. Quantitative cerebral perfusion using dynamic susceptibility contrast MRI: evaluation of reproducibility and age- and gender-dependence with fully automatic image postprocessing algorithm. Magn Reson Med. 2007;58(6):1232&#x2013;1241.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17969025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith S.M. Fast robust automated brain extraction. Hum Brain Mapp. 2002;17(3):143&#x2013;155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6871816</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12391568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stock A.D., Gelb S., Pasternak O., Ben-Zvi A., Putterman C. The blood brain barrier and neuropsychiatric lupus: new perspectives in light of advances in understanding the neuroimmune interface. Autoimmun Rev. 2017;16(6):612&#x2013;619.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6068398</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28428121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The American College of Rheumatology nomenclature and case definitions for neuropsychiatric lupus syndromes. Arthritis Rheum. 1999 Apr. 42 (4). 599&#x2013;608.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10211873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Unterman A., Nolte J.E.S., Boaz M., Abady M., Shoenfeld Y., Zandman-Goddard G. Neuropsychiatric syndromes in systemic lupus erythematosus: a meta-analysis. Semin Arthritis Rheum. 2011;41(1):1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20965549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Virtanen P., Gommers R., Oliphant T.E., Haberland M., Reddy T., Cournapeau D., et al. SciPy 1.0: fundamental algorithms for scientific computing in Python. Nat Methods. 2020;17(3):261&#x2013;272.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7056644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32015543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang P.I., Cagnoli P.C., McCune W.J., Schmidt-Wilcke T., Lowe S.E., Graft C.C., Gebarski S.S., Chenevert T.L., Khalatbari S., Myles J.D., Watcharotone K., Cronin P., Sundgren P.C. Perfusion-weighted MR Imaging in Cerebral Lupus Erythematosus. Acad Radiol. 2012;19(8):965&#x2013;970.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3641847</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22608862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong S.M., Jansen J.F.A., Zhang C.E., Hoff E.I., Staals J., van Oostenbrugge R.J., Backes W.H. Blood-brain barrier impairment and hypoperfusion are linked in cerebral small vessel disease. Neurology. 2019;92(15):e1669. e1677.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30867275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu O., &#xd8;stergaard L., Weisskoff R.M., Benner T., Rosen B.R., Sorensen A.G. Tracer arrival timing-insensitive technique for estimating flow in MR perfusion-weighted imaging using singular value decomposition with a block-circulant deconvolution matrix. Magn Reson Med. 2003;50(1):164&#x2013;174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12815691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamada K., Gonzalez R.G., &#xd8;Stergaard L., Komili S., Weisskoff R.M., Rosen B.R., et al. Iron-induced susceptibility effect at the globus pallidus causes underestimation of flow and volume on dynamic susceptibility contrast-enhanced MR perfusion images. AJNR Am J Neuroradiol. 2002;23(6):1022&#x2013;1029.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7976913</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12063236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin P., Xiong H., Liu Y.i., Sah ShambhuK, Zeng C., Wang J., Li Y., Hong N. Measurement of the permeability, perfusion, and histogram characteristics in relapsing-remitting multiple sclerosis using dynamic contrast-enhanced MRI with extended Tofts linear model. Neurol India. 2018;66(3):709.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29766930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X., Zhu Z., Zhang F., Shu H., Li F., Dong Y. Diagnostic value of single-photon-emission computed tomography in severe central nervous system involvement of systemic lupus erythematosus: a case-control study. Arthritis Rheum. 2005 Dec 15;53(6):845&#x2013;849.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16342090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhuo Z., Su L.i., Duan Y., Huang J., Qiu X., Haller S., Li H., Zeng X., Liu Y. Different patterns of cerebral perfusion in SLE patients with and without neuropsychiatric manifestations. Hum Brain Mapp. 2020;41(3):755&#x2013;766.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7268026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31650651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zimny A., Szmyrka-Kaczmarek M., Szewczyk P., Bladowska J., Pokryszko-Dragan A., Gruszka E., et al. In vivo evaluation of brain damage in the course of systemic lupus erythematosus using magnetic resonance spectroscopy, perfusion-weighted and diffusion-tensor imaging. Lupus. 2014;23(1):10&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24192079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>