<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37012219</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1756-185X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of rheumatic diseases</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Rheum Dis</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Role of CD19<sup>+</sup> CD5<sup>+</sup> CD1d<sup>+</sup> Bregs in maintaining the Th17/Treg balance in mice with systemic lupus erythematosus complicated with atherosclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1048</StartPage><EndPage>1057</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1048-1057</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/1756-185X.14691</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">In this study, we aimed to investigate Bregs, their regulatory effects on Th17/Treg cell balance, and the release of downstream inflammatory factors in a mouse model of low-density lipoprotein receptor (LDLr)<sup>-/-</sup> &#x2009;+&#x2009;Pristane.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">After the establishment of the mouse model of systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) complicated with atherosclerosis (AS), 8-week-old LDLr<sup>-/-</sup> &#x2009;+&#x2009;Pristane mice (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;10) were included in the SLE&#x2009;+&#x2009;AS group. Furthermore, 8-week-old MRL/lpr and C57 mice were used as the SLE and normal control groups, respectively (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;10 per group). After feeding the mice a high-fat diet for 14&#x2009;weeks, peripheral blood and spleen of mice were collected, and Bregs, Th17, and Treg cells and related inflammatory factors were detected by flow cytometry, enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay, and reverse-transcription polymerase chain reaction.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The number of Bregs and Tregs in spleen lymphocytes of SLE&#x2009;+&#x2009;AS mice significantly decreased compared with the C57 group (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;.05), whereas the number of Th17 cells significantly increased (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;.000). Furthermore, the proportion of Bregs showed a negative correlation with the Th17/Treg ratio (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;.03). Mice in the SLE&#x2009;+&#x2009;AS group showed higher serum interleukin (IL)-10, IL-17, and tumor necrosis factor-&#x3b1; levels than those in the SLE and C57 groups (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;.05). Furthermore, IL-35 and transforming growth factor (TGF)-&#x3b2; expression was reduced in the SLE&#x2009;+&#x2009;AS group compared with the C57 group (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;.05).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The proportion of Breg decreases was negatively associated with increased Th17/Treg which was increased in SLE&#x2009;+&#x2009;AS mice, indicating that Bregs may regulate Th17/Treg cell homeostasis and cytokine release via IL-35 and TGF-&#x3b2; production.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 Asia Pacific League of Associations for Rheumatology and John Wiley &amp; Sons Australia, Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Zhen-Zhen</ForeName><Initials>ZZ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1001-2817</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rheumatology, Guilin Medical University, Guilin, Guangxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Xiao-Huan</ForeName><Initials>XH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Endocrinology and Rheumatology, The First People's Hospital of Linping District, Hangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wei</LastName><ForeName>Si-Ru</ForeName><Initials>SR</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4437-6742</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rheumatology, Guilin Medical University, Guilin, Guangxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Jia</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rheumatology, The Affiliated Hospital of Guilin Medical University, Guilin, Guangxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Ya-Hui</ForeName><Initials>YH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rheumatology, Guilin Medical University, Guilin, Guangxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Wen-Jue</ForeName><Initials>WJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rheumatology, Guilin Medical University, Guilin, Guangxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Hong</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5864-4648</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rheumatology, Guilin Medical University, Guilin, Guangxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mo</LastName><ForeName>Han-You</ForeName><Initials>HY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rheumatology, The Affiliated Hospital of Guilin Medical University, Guilin, Guangxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rheumatology and Immunology, The First Affiliated Hospital of Guangxi Medical University, Nanning, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2021GXNSFAA220006</GrantID><Agency>Guangxi Natural Science Foundation</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>YCSW2022375</GrantID><Agency>Innovation Project of Guangxi Graduate Education</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>81760298</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><Agency>the 139 Program for the High Level Medical Talents in Guangxi Province</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Rheum Dis</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101474930</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1756-1841</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>26HZV48DT1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C009042">pristane</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051379" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D050378" MajorTopicYN="N">T-Lymphocytes, Regulatory</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058504" MajorTopicYN="N">Th17 Cells</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019463" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice, Inbred MRL lpr</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D050197" MajorTopicYN="Y">Atherosclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bregs</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Th17</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Treg</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">atherosclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">systemic lupus erythematosus</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>22</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37012219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1756-185X.14691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Avina-Zubieta JA, To F, Vostretsova K, et al. Risk of myocardial infarction and stroke in newly diagnosed systemic lupus erythematosus: a general population-based study. Arthritis Care Res. 2017;69(6):849-856. doi:10.1002/acr.23018</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tektonidou MG, Kravvariti E, Konstantonis G, Tentolouris N, Sfikakis PP, Protogerou A. Subclinical atherosclerosis in systemic lupus erythematosus: comparable risk with diabetes mellitus and rheumatoid arthritis. Autoimmun Rev. 2017;16(3):308-312. doi:10.1016/j.autrev.2017.01.009</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gustafsson JT, Herlitz Lindberg M, Gunnarsson I, et al. Excess atherosclerosis in systemic lupus erythematosus, a matter of renal involvement: case control study of 281 SLE patients and 281 individually matched population controls. PLoS One. 2017;12(4):e0174572. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0174572</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ci W, Zhao J, Qi W, et al. Characteristics and risk factors of severe coronary artery disease in systemic lupus erythematosus: a multicenter, Chinese rheumatism date center database study. Int J Rheum Dis. 2022;25(10):118. doi:10.1111/1756-185x.14402</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu M, Mo H, Li D, Luo X, Zhang L. Th17/Treg imbalance induced by increased incidence of atherosclerosis in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE). Clin Rheumatol. 2013;32(7):1045-1052. doi:10.1007/s10067-013-2237-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butcher MJ, Filipowicz AR, Waseem TC, et al. Atherosclerosis-driven Treg plasticity results in formation of a dysfunctional subset of plastic IFNgamma+ Th1/Tregs. Circ Res. 2016;119(11):1190-1203. doi:10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.116.309764</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klingenberg R, Gerdes N, Badeau RM, et al. Depletion of FOXP3+ regulatory T cells promotes hypercholesterolemia and atherosclerosis. J Clin Invest. 2013;123(3):1323-1334. doi:10.1172/JCI63891</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilhelm AJ, Rhoads JP, Wade NS, Major AS. Dysregulated CD4+ T cells from SLE-susceptible mice are sufficient to accelerate atherosclerosis in LDLr&#x2212;/&#x2212; mice. Ann Rheum Dis. 2015;74(4):778-785. doi:10.1136/annrheumdis-2013-203759</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Usui F, Kimura H, Ohshiro T, et al. Interleukin-17 deficiency reduced vascular inflammation and development of atherosclerosis in Western diet-induced apoE-deficient mice. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 2012;420(1):72-77. doi:10.1016/j.bbrc.2012.02.117</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yue Q, Jingliang W, Yun Z, et al. Effect of regulatory B cells on subsets of CD4 + T cells in systemic lupus erythematosus. Chinese Journal of Clinicians. 2017;11:1208-1211. doi:10.3877/cma.j.issn.1674-0785.2017.07.033</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han J, Sun L, Fan X, et al. Role of regulatory b cells in neuroimmunologic disorders. J Neurosci Res. 2016;94(8):693-701. doi:10.1002/jnr.23749</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y-H, Mo H-Y, Wei W, et al. Establishment of a new mouse model of systemic lupus erythematosus complicated by atherosclerosis. Int J Clin Exp Med. 2021;14(8):2216-2227.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hong M, Liao Y, Liang J, et al. Immunomodulation of human CD19(+)CD25(high) regulatory B cells via Th17/Foxp3 regulatory T cells and Th1/Th2 cytokines. Hum Immunol. 2019;80(10):863-870. doi:10.1016/j.humimm.2019.05.011</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jung JY, Kim HA, Lee HY, Suh CH. Body mass index and glucocorticoid dose contribute to subclinical atherosclerosis in Korean patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: a prospective 4 year follow-up study. Int J Rheum Dis. 2019;22(8):1410-1418. doi:10.1111/1756-185x.13588</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng Y, Yang M, Wu H, Lu Q. The pathological role of B cells in systemic lupus erythematosus: from basic research to clinical. Autoimmunity. 2020;53(2):56-64. doi:10.1080/08916934.2019.1700232</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koulouri V, Koutsilieris M, Mavragani CP. B cells and atherosclerosis in systemic lupus erythematosus. Expert Rev Clin Immunol. 2019;15(4):417-429. doi:10.1080/1744666x.2019.1571411</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komlosi ZI, Kovacs N, Van De Veen W, et al. Human CD40 ligand-expressing type 3 innate lymphoid cells induce IL-10-producing immature transitional regulatory B cells. J Allergy Clin Immunol. 2018;142(1):178-194 e111. doi:10.1016/j.jaci.2017.07.046</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang RX, Yu CR, Dambuza IM, et al. Interleukin-35 induces regulatory B cells that suppress autoimmune disease. Nat Med. 2014;20(6):633-641. doi:10.1038/nm.3554</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee KM, Stott RT, Zhao G, et al. TGF-beta-producing regulatory B cells induce regulatory T cells and promote transplantation tolerance. Eur J Immunol. 2014;44(6):1728-1736. doi:10.1002/eji.201344062</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang D, Lei L. Interleukin-35 regulates the balance of Th17 and Treg responses during the pathogenesis of connective tissue diseases. Int J Rheum Dis. 2021;24(1):21-27. doi:10.1111/1756-185x.13962</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rei Watanabe NI, Nakashima H, Kuwano Y, et al. Regulatory B cells (B10 cells) have a suppressive role in murine lupus: CD19 and B10 cell deficiency exacerbates systemic autoimmunity. J Immunol. 2010;184(9):4801-4809. doi:10.4049/jimmunol.0902385</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sattler S, Ling GS, Xu D, et al. IL-10-producing regulatory B cells induced by IL-33 (Breg (IL-33)) effectively attenuate mucosal inflammatory responses in the gut. J Autoimmun. 2014;50:107-122. doi:10.1016/j.jaut.2014.01.032</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akdis M, Aab A, Altunbulakli C, et al. Interleukins (from IL-1 to IL-38), interferons, transforming growth factor beta, and TNF-alpha: receptors, functions, and roles in diseases. J Allergy Clin Immunol. 2016;138(4):984-1010. doi:10.1016/j.jaci.2016.06.033</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butz H, Racz K, Hunyady L, et al. Crosstalk between TGF-beta signaling and the microRNA machinery. Trends Pharmacol Sci. 2012;33(7):382-393. doi:10.1016/j.tips.2012.04.003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uzrail AH, Assaf AM, Abdalla SS. Correlations of expression levels of a panel of genes (IRF5, STAT4, TNFSF4, MECP2, and TLR7) and cytokine levels (IL-2, IL-6, IL-10, IL-12, IFN-gamma, and TNF-alpha) with systemic lupus erythematosus outcomes in Jordanian patients. Biomed Res Int. 2019;2019:1703842. doi:10.1155/2019/1703842</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rashad NM, El-Shabrawy RM, Said D, et al. Serum levels of transforming growth factor Beta &#x2212;1 (TGF-&#x3b2;1) as an early No invasive marker for diagnosis of lupus nephritis in systemic lupus erythematosus patients. Egypt J Immunol. 2019;26(1):31-42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye Z, Jiang Y, Sun D, Zhong W, Zhao L, Jiang Z. The plasma interleukin (IL)-35 level and frequency of circulating IL-35(+) regulatory B cells are decreased in a cohort of Chinese patients with new-onset systemic lupus erythematosus. Sci Rep. 2019;9(1):13210. doi:10.1038/s41598-019-49748-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'garra A, Vieira P. Regulatory T cells and mechanisms of immune system control. Nat Med. 2004;10:801-805. doi:10.1038/nm0804-801</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffmann KF, Cheever AW, Wynn TA. IL-10 and the dangers of immune polarization: excessive type 1 and type 2 cytokine responses induce distinct forms of lethal immunopathology in murine schistosomiasis. J Immunol. 2000;164(12):6406-6416. doi:10.4049/jimmunol.164.12.6406</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maynard CL, Weaver CT. Diversity in the contribution of interleukin-10 to T-cell-mediated immune regulation. Immunol Rev. 2008;226:219-233. doi:10.1111/j.1600-065X.2008.00711.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blair PA, Norena LY, Flores-Borja F, et al. CD19(+)CD24(hi)CD38(hi) B cells exhibit regulatory capacity in healthy individuals but are functionally impaired in systemic lupus erythematosus patients. Immunity. 2010;32(1):129-140. doi:10.1016/j.immuni.2009.11.009</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lampropoulou V, Hoehlig K, Roch T, et al. TLR-activated B cells suppress T cell-mediated autoimmunity. J Immunol. 2008;180(7):4763-4773. doi:10.4049/jimmunol.180.7.4763</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>