<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37036168</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>18</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1526-4610</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>63</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Headache</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Headache</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Headache and systemic lupus erythematosus: A narrative review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>461</StartPage><EndPage>471</EndPage><MedlinePgn>461-471</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/head.14501</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">To review the epidemiology, the differential diagnosis, and the clinical and laboratory factors associated with the care management of headaches in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">SLE is a chronic autoimmune disease and in 12%-95% of patients, the nervous system is involved. Headache is a frequently reported, although nonspecific, symptom that may potentially represent serious underlying diagnoses. Primary headaches may also occur in these patients, thereby causing a negative and significant impact on their quality of life.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">This is a narrative review. A literature review was conducted on the PubMed platform using the following terms: (1) headache and (2) lupus. All articles considered relevant were included. No limitations were imposed for the publication date.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Headache is a frequent symptom in patients with SLE. Although its prevalence is similar to the general population, headaches nonetheless tend to have a greater negative impact on these patients. Patients with SLE are more likely to experience headache due to vascular diseases such as cerebral venous sinus thrombosis, stroke, reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome, posterior reversible encephalopathy syndrome, and vasculitis. Aseptic meningitis, neuroinfections, intracranial neoplasms, and intracranial hypertension or hypotension may also be a cause of headache in these patients. Although used in disease activity scores, the concept of lupus headache is controversial.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Headache is a frequent symptom in patients with SLE. An appropriate approach enables the potentially serious conditions, which are the causes of secondary headaches, to be recognized and treated, together with an appropriate diagnosis and treatment of primary headaches.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 American Headache Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>de Oliveira</LastName><ForeName>Igor</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1008-4215</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Postgraduate Program in Neuropsychiatry and Behavioral Sciences, Federal University of Pernambuco (UFPE), Recife, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sampaio Rocha-Filho</LastName><ForeName>Pedro Augusto</ForeName><Initials>PA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5725-2637</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Neuropsychiatry, Centro de Ci&#xea;ncias M&#xe9;dicas, Universidade Federal de Pernambuco (UFPE), Recife, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Headache Clinic, Hospital Universit&#xe1;rio Oswaldo Cruz, Universidade de Pernambuco, Recife, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Headache</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>2985091R</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0017-8748</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054038" MajorTopicYN="Y">Posterior Leukoencephalopathy Syndrome</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006261" MajorTopicYN="N">Headache</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003937" MajorTopicYN="N">Diagnosis, Differential</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">autoimmune diseases</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">headache</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">migraine disorders</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pain</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">secondary headache disorders</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">systemic lupus erythematosus</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37036168</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/head.14501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Kaul A, Gordon C, Crow MK, et al. Systemic lupus erythematosus. Nat Rev Dis Prim. 2016;2:1-21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barber MRW, Drenkard C, Falasinnu T, et al. Global epidemiology of systemic lupus erythematosus. Nat Rev Rheumatol. 2021;17:515-532.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izmirly PM, Parton H, Wang L, et al. Prevalence of systemic lupus erythematosus in the United States: estimates from a meta-analysis of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention National Lupus Registries. Arthritis Rheumatol. 2021;73(6):991-996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsokos G. Systemic lupus erythematosus. N Engl J Med. 2011;365:2110-2121.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwartz N, Stock AD, Putterman C. Neuropsychiatric lupus: new mechanistic insights and future treatment directions. Nat Rev Rheumatol. 2019;15(3):137-152.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuadrado MJ, Sanna G. Headache and systemic lupus erythematosus. Lupus. 2003;12(12):943-946.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tjensvoll AB, G&#xf8;ransson LG, Harboe E, Kval&#xf8;y JT, Omdal R. High headache-related disability in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus and primary Sj&#xf6;gren's syndrome. Eur J Neurol. 2014;21(8):1124-1130.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bertsias GK, Ioannidis JPA, Aringer M, et al. EULAR recommendations for the management of systemic lupus erythematosus with neuropsychiatric manifestations: report of a task force of the EULAR standing committee for clinical affairs. Ann Rheum Dis. 2010;69(12):2074-2082.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Do TP, Remmers A, Schytz HW, et al. Red and orange flags for secondary headaches in clinical practice. Neurology. 2018;92(3):134-144.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanly JG, Urowitz MB, Sanchez-Guerrero J, et al. Neuropsychiatric events at the time of diagnosis of systemic lupus erythematosus: an international inception cohort study. Arthritis Rheum. 2007;56(1):265-273.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romero-Diaz J, Isenberg D, Ramsey-Goldman R. Measures of adult systemic lupus erythematosus: updated version of British Isles Lupus Assessment Group (BILAG 2004), European Consensus Lupus Activity Measurements (ECLAM), Systemic Lupus Activity Measure, Revised (SLAM-R), Systemic Lupus Activity Questionnaire for Population Studies (SLAQ), Systemic Lupus Erythematosus Disease Activity Index 2000 (SLEDAI-2K), and Systemic Lupus International Collaborating Clinics/American College of Rheumatology Damage Index (SDI). Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken). 2011;63(Suppl 11(0 11)):S37-S46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duman T, Demirci S, Uluduz D, et al. Cerebral venous sinus thrombosis as a rare complication of systemic lupus erythematosus: subgroup analysis of the VENOST study. J Stroke Cerebrovasc Dis. 2019;28(12):1-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guraieb-Chah&#xed;n P, Cant&#xfa;-Brito C, Soto-Mota A, et al. Stroke in systemic lupus erythematosus: epidemiology, mechanism, and long-term outcome. Lupus. 2020;29(5):437-445.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung SW, Lee KM, Heo SH, et al. A systemic lupus erythematosus patient with thunderclap headache: reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome. Lupus. 2019;28(7):898-902.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valdez-L&#xf3;pez M, Aguirre-Aguilar E, Vald&#xe9;s-Ferrer SI, et al. Posterior reversible encephalopathy syndrome: a neuropsychiatric manifestation of systemic lupus erythematosus. Autoimmun Rev. 2021;20(2):1-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calle-Botero E, Abril A. Lupus vasculitis. Curr Rheumatol Rep. 2020;22(10):1-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim JM, Kim KJ, Yoon HS, et al. Meningitis in Korean patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: analysis of demographics, clinical features and outcomes; experience from affiliated hospitals of the Catholic University of Korea. Lupus. 2011;20(5):531-536.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yelehe-Okouma M, Czmil-Garon J, Pape E, Petitpain N, Gillet P. Drug-induced aseptic meningitis: a mini-review. Fundam Clin Pharmacol. 2018;32(3):252-260.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han JY, Kim H, Jung SY, Jang EJ, Cho SK, Sung YK. Increased risk of malignancy in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: population-based cohort study in Korea. Arthritis Res Ther. 2021;23(1):1-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim JM, Kwok SK, Ju JH, Kim HY, Park SH. Idiopathic intracranial hypertension as a significant cause of intractable headache in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: a 15-year experience. Lupus. 2012;21(5):542-547.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen-addad DI, Efendizade A, Grigorian A, Hewitt K, Velayudhan V. Spontaneous intracranial hypotension in a patient with systemic lupus erythematosus. Radiol Case Rep. 2019;14:1188-1192.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitsikostas DD, Sfikakis PP, Goadsby PJ. A meta-analysis for headache in systemic lupus erythematosus: the evidence and the myth. Brain. 2004;127(5):1200-1209.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gladman DD, Iba&#xf1;ez D, Urowitz MB. Systemic lupus erythematosus disease activity index 2000. J Rheumatol. 2002;29(2):288-291.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leal Rato M, Bandeira M, Rom&#xe3;o VC, Aguiar de Sousa D. Neurologic manifestations of the antiphospholipid syndrome - an update. Curr Neurol Neurosci Rep. 2021;21(8):41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Postal M, Lapa AT, Reis F, Rittner L, Appenzeller S. Magnetic resonance imaging in neuropsychiatric systemic lupus erythematosus: current state of the art and novel approaches. Lupus. 2017;26:517-521.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bicakci S, Ozbek S, Bicakci K, Aslan K, Kara B, Sarica Y. Recurrent headache and MRI findings in systemic lupus erythematosus. J Natl Med Assoc. 2008;100(3):323-333.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitelaw DA, Hugo F, Spangenberg JJ, Rickman R. Headaches in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: a comparative study. Lupus. 2004;13(7):501-505.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Appenzeller S, Costallat LTL. Clinical implications of migraine in systemic lupus erythematosus: relation to cumulative organ damage. Cephalalgia. 2004;24:1024-1030.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weder-Cisneros ND, T&#xe9;llez-Zenteno JF, Cardiel MH, et al. Prevalence and factors associated with headache in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. Cephalalgia. 2004;24:1031-1044.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lessa B, Santana A, Lima I, Almeida JM, Santiago M. Prevalence and classification of headache in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. Clin Rheumatol. 2006;25(6):850-853.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guimar&#xe3;es Bettero R, Rahal MY, Spadoni Barboza J, Skare TL. Cefaleia no lupus eritematoso sist&#xea;mico: preval&#xea;ncia e condi&#xe7;&#xf5;es associadas. Arq Neuropsiquiatr. 2007;65(4-B):1196-1199.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harboe E, Tjensvoll AB, Maroni S, et al. Neuropsychiatric syndromes in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus and primary Sj&#xf6;gren syndrome: a comparative population-based study. Ann Rheum Dis. 2009;68(10):1541-1546.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tjensvoll AB, Harboe E, G&#xf8;ransson LG, et al. Migraine is frequent in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: a case-control study. Cephalalgia. 2011;31(4):401-408.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katsiari CG, Vikelis M, Paraskevopoulou ES, Sfikakis PP, Mitsikostas DD. Headache in systemic lupus erythematosus vs multiple sclerosis: a prospective comparative study. Headache. 2011;51(9):1398-1407.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vargas-Hitos JA, Sabio JM, Marti&#x144;ez-Egea I, et al. Influence of psychological stress on headache in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. J Rheumatol. 2014;41(3):453-457.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-Nebro A, Palacios-Mu&#xf1;oz R, Gordillo J, et al. Chronic or recurrent headache in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: a case control study. Lupus. 1999;8(2):151-157.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Badry R, Gamal RM. Different types of headache in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. Int J Neurosci. 2015;125(5):357-360.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sfikakis PP, Mitsikostas DD, Manoussakis MN, Foukaneli D, Moutsopoulos HM. Headache in systemic lupus erythematosus: a controlled study. Br J Rheumatol. 1998;37:300-303.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isenberg DA, Meyrick-Thomas D, Snaith ML, Mckeran R, Royston JP, Snaith ML. A study of migraine in systemic lupus erythematosus. Ann Rheum Dis. 1982;41:30-32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Markus HS, Hopkinson N. Migraine and headache in systemic lupus erythematosus and their relationship with antibodies against phospholipids. J Neurol. 1992;239:39-42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanly JG, Urowitz MB, O'Keeffe AG, et al. Headache in systemic lupus erythematosus: results from a prospective, international inception cohort study. Arthritis Rheum. 2013;65(11):2887-2897.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montalb&#xe1;n J, Cervera R, Font JV, et al. Lack of association between anticardiolipin antibodies and migraine in systemic lupus erythematosus. Neurology. 1992;42(3):681-682.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernatsky S, Pineau CA, Lee JL, Clarke AE. Headache, Raynaud's syndrome and serotonin receptor agonists in systemic lupus erythematosus. Lupus. 2006;15(10):671-674.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zobdeh F, Kraiem AB, Attwood MM, et al. Pharmacological treatment of migraine: drug classes, mechanisms of action, clinical trials and new treatments. Br J Pharmacol. 2021;178:4588-4607.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marmura MJ, Silberstein SD, Schwedt TJ. The acute treatment of migraine in adults: the American Headache Society evidence assessment of migraine pharmacotherapies. Headache. 2015;55(1):3-20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khouri C, Jouve T, Blaise S, Carpentier P, Cracowski JL, Roustit M. Peripheral vasoconstriction induced by &#x3b2;-adrenoceptor blockers: a systematic review and a network meta-analysis. Br J Clin Pharmacol. 2016;82(2):549-560.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L, Fu T, Yin R, Zhang Q, Shen B. Prevalence of depression and anxiety in systemic lupus erythematosus: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Psychiatry. 2017;17(1):70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrari MD, Goadsby PJ, Burstein R, et al. Migraine. Nat Rev Dis Prim. 2022;8(1):2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MaassenVanDenBrink A, Meijer J, Villal&#xf3;n CM, Ferrari MD. Wiping out CGRP: potential cardiovascular risks. Trends Pharmacol Sci. 2016;37(9):779-788.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans RW. Raynaud's phenomenon associated with calcitonin gene-related peptide monoclonal antibody antagonists. Headache. 2019;59(8):1360-1364.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanly JG, Inan&#xe7; M. The neurology of lupus. J Neurol Sci. 2021;424:117419.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanly JG. Diagnosis and management of neuropsychiatric SLE. Nat Rev Rheumatol. 2014;10(6):338-347.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang M, Wang Z, Zhang S, et al. Progress in the pathogenesis and treatment of neuropsychiatric systemic lupus erythematosus. J Clin Med. 2022;11(17):4955.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kivity S, Agmon-levin N, Zandman-goddard G, Chapman J. Neuropsychiatric lupus: a mosaic of clinical presentations. BMC Med. 2015;13(43):1-11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grammatikos AP, Tsokos GC. Immunodeficiency and autoimmunity: lessons from systemic lupus erythematosus. Trends Mol Med. 2012;18(2):101-108.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Molooghi K, Sheybani F, Naderi H, Mirfeizi Z, Morovatdar N, Baradaran A. Central nervous system infections in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Lupus Sci Med. 2022;9(1):1-10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang H, Lan L, Qu Y. Differences between central nervous system infection and neuropsychiatric systemic lupus erythematosus in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. J Int Med Res. 2018;46(1):485-491.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang M, Shi X, Gao X, et al. Clinical features of central nervous system infections and experience in differential diagnosis from neuropsychiatric lupus erythematosus in a cohort of 8491 patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Res Ther. 2019;21(189):1-11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen J, Feng X, Wang H, Hua B. Discriminating infectious meningitis versus neuropsychiatric involvement in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: a single-center experience. Clin Rheumatol. 2015;34:365-369.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCaffrey LM, Petelin A, Cunha BA. Systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) cerebritis versus Listeria monocytogenes meningoencephalitis in a patient with systemic lupus erythematosus on chronic corticosteroid therapy: the diagnostic importance of cerebrospinal fluid (CSF) of lactic acid levels. Heart Lung J Acute Crit Care. 2012;41(4):394-397.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Unterman A, Nolte JES, Boaz M, Abady M, Shoenfeld Y, Zandman-Goddard G. Neuropsychiatric syndromes in systemic lupus erythematosus: a meta-analysis. Semin Arthritis Rheum. 2011;41(1):1-11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsukamoto M, Shimamoto M, Terashima T, Seta N. Aseptic meningitis with systemic lupus erythematosus: case report and review of the literature. Arch Rheumatol. 2019;34(1):108-111.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheok L, Lee W, Cheng W, Cheong Y, Teh C. Aseptic meningitis as initial manifestation of systemic lupus erythematosus: case series. Lupus. 2022;31(3):373-377.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sato S, Yashiro M, Asano T, Kobayashi H, Watanabe H, Migita K. Association of anti-triosephosphate isomerase antibodies with aseptic meningitis in patients with neuropsychiatric systemic lupus erythematosus. Clin Rheumatol. 2017;36(7):1655-1659.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L, Chen H, Zhang Y, et al. Clinical characteristics of cerebral venous SinusThrombosis in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: a single-centre experience in China. J Immunol Res. 2015;2015:1-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh RK, Bhoi SK, Kalita J, Misra UK. Cerebral venous sinus thrombosis presenting feature of systemic lupus erythematosus. J Stroke Cerebrovasc Dis. 2017;26(3):518-522.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uthman I, Khalil I, Sawaya R, Taher A. Lupus anticoagulant, factor V Leiden, and methylenetetrahydrofolate reductase gene mutation in a lupus patient with cerebral venous thrombosis. Clin Rheumatol. 2004;23(4):362-363.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao N, Wang ZL, Li MT, et al. Clinical characteristics and risk factors of intracranial hemorrhage in systemic lupus erythematosus. Lupus. 2013;22:453-460.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang YS, Liu CJ, Chen WS, et al. Increased risk of subarachnoid hemorrhage in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: a nationwide population-based study. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken). 2013;65(4):601-606.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torn&#xe9; R, Rodr&#xed;guez-hern&#xe1;ndez A, Bernard T, Arikan F, Vilalta J, Sahuquillo J. Subarachnoid hemorrhage in systemic lupus erythematosus: systematic review and report of three cases. Clin Neurol Neurosurg. 2015;128:17-24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damrongpipatkul U, Oranratanachai K, Kasitanon N. Clinical features, outcome, and associated factors for posterior reversible encephalopathy in Thai patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: a case-control study. Clin Rheumatol. 2018;37:691-702.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merayo-Chalico J, Apodaca E, Barrera-Vargas A, et al. Clinical outcomes and risk factors for posterior reversible encephalopathy syndrome in systemic lupus erythematosus: a multicentric case-control study. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2016;87(3):287-294.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai CC, Chen WS, Chang YS, et al. Clinical features and outcomes of posterior reversible encephalopathy syndrome in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Care Res. 2013;65(11):1766-1774.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leroux G, Sellam J, Costedoat-Chalumeau N, et al. Posterior reversible encephalopathy syndrome during systemic lupus erythematosus: four new cases and review of the literature. Lupus. 2008;17(2):139-147.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zekic T, Benic M, Antulov R, Antoncic I, Novak S. The multifactorial origin of posterior reversible encephalopathy syndrome in cyclophosphamide-treated lupus patients. Rheumatol Int. 2017;37:2105-2114.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fugate JE, Rabinstein AA. Posterior reversible encephalopathy syndrome: clinical and radiological manifestations, pathophysiology, and outstanding questions. Lancet Neurol. 2015;14(9):914-925.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spadaro A, Scott KR, Koyfman A, Long B. Reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome: a narrative review for emergency clinicians. Am J Emerg Med. 2021;50:765-772.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ducros A, Boukobza M, Porcher R, Sarov M, Valade D, Bousser MG. The clinical and radiological spectrum of reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome. A prospective series of 67 patients. Brain. 2007;130(12):3091-3101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shima A, Maki T, Mimura N, et al. A case of reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome associated with anti-phospholipid antibody syndrome and systemic lupus erythematosus. eNeurologicalSci. 2021;24:100351.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodrigues M, Galego O, Costa C, et al. Central nervous system vasculitis in systemic lupus erythematosus: a case series report in a tertiary referral centre. Lupus. 2017;26:1440-1447.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rowshani A, Remans P, Rozemuller A, Tak P. Cerebral vasculitis as a primary manifestation of systemiclupus erythematosus. Ann Rheum Dis. 2005;64:784-786.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song TJ, Lee KH, Li H, et al. Reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome: a comprehensive systematic review. Eur Rev Med Pharmacol Sci. 2021;25:3519-3529.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singhal AB, Hajj-Ali RA, Topcuoglu MA, et al. Reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndromes: analysis of 139 cases. Arch Neurol. 2011;68(8):1005-1012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clarke AE, Pooley N, Marjenberg Z, et al. Risk of malignancy in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: systematic review and meta-analysis. Semin Arthritis Rheum. 2021;51(6):1230-1241.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCullagh K, Castillo M, Zamora C. Headache attributed to non-vascular intracranial disorder: neoplasms, infections, and substance abuse. Neurol Clin. 2022;40(3):531-546.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Villanueva-Meyer JE, Mabray MC, Cha S. Current clinical brain tumor imaging. Clin Neurosurg. 2017;81(3):397-415.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bin AS, Almujaiwel N, Alshakweer W, Alzhrani G. High-grade spheno-orbital meningioma in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: two case reports and literature review. Surg Neurol Int. 2020;11(367):1-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castellino G, Rizzo N, Bernardi S, Trotta F, Govoni M. Meningioma and systemic lupus erythematosus: a matter of pure coincidence? Lupus. 2009;18(7):650-654.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaulen LD, Karschnia P, Dietrich J, Baehring JM. Autoimmune disease-related primary CNS lymphoma: systematic review and meta-analysis. J Neurooncol. 2020;149(1):153-159.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakairi T, Nakasatomi M, Watanabe M, et al. Primary central nervous system lymphoma in a patient with neuropsychiatric systemic lupus erythematosus receiving mycophenolate mofetil: a case report and literature review. Mod Rheumatol Case Rep. 2022;6(1):36-40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ichikawa T, Shimojima Y, Kishida D, Kaneko T, Sekijima Y. Primary central nervous system lymphoma in neuropsychiatric systemic lupus erythematosus: case-based review. Rheumatol Int. 2021;41(5):1009-1017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aringer M, Houssiau F, Gordon C, et al. Adverse events and efficacy of TNF-alpha blockade with infliximab in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: long-term follow-up of 13 patients. Rheumatology (Oxford). 2009;48(11):1451-1454.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hershko AY, Berkun Y, Mevorach D, Rubinow A, Naparstek Y. Increased intracranial pressure related to systemic lupus erythematosus: a 26-year experience. Semin Arthritis Rheum. 2008;38(2):110-115.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barahona-Hernando R, R&#xed;os-Blanco J, M&#xe9;ndez-Mes&#xf3;n I, et al. Idiopathic intracranial hypertension and systemic lupus erythematosus: a case report and review of literature. Lupus. 2009;18:1121-1123.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maloney K. Idiopathic intracranial hypertension as an initial presentation of systemic lupus erythematosus. BMJ Case Rep. 2013;2013:bcr2013010223.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katsuyama E, Sada KE, Tatebe N, et al. Bilateral abducens nerve palsy due to idiopathic intracranial hypertension as an initial manifestation of systemic lupus erythematosus. Intern Med. 2016;55(8):991-994.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mollan SP, Davies B, Silver NC, et al. Idiopathic intracranial hypertension: consensus guidelines on management. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2018;89(10):1088-1100.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Branger P, Ficheux M, Trenec M, Aouba A, Martin SN. Spontaneous intracranial hypotension: a rare cause of headache in systemic lupus erythematosus. Rev Med Interne. 2021;42(8):571-574.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arai H, Yamamoto Y, Maeda Y. SPET/CT imaging in radionuclide cisternography to detect cerebrospinal fluid leakage in spontaneous intracranial hypotension associated with SLE. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging. 2012;39:1225-1226.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ando D, Nakaya I, Watanabe S, Osawa H, Kubo N, Soma J. Spontaneous intracranial hypotension in a case of systemic lupus erythematosus. Japan Coll Rheumatol. 2015;25(4):662-663.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanchez-Garcia M, Gomez-Delgado F, Gomez-Gardu&#xf1;o A, Blanco-Molina A, Fernandez de la Puebla R. Hypertrophic pachymeningitis associated with cerebral spinal fluid hypovolemia as initial presentation of systemic lupus erythematous. Lupus. 2014;23:197-200.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radhakrishnan S, Surendran D, Barathi D, Bammigatti C. Spontaneous intracranial hypotension associated with pachymeningeal enhancement in a patient with systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE): an extremely rare presenting feature. BMJ Case Rep. 2019;12(2):e227780.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bombardier C, Gladman DD, Urowitz MB, et al. Derivation of the SLEDAI: a disease activity index for lupus patients. Arthritis Rheum. 1992;35(6):630-640.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davey R, Bamford J, Emery P. The validity of the inclusion of &#x201c;lupus headache&#x201d; in the systemic lupus erythematosus disease activity index. Arthritis Rheum. 2007;56(8):2813-2814.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lockshin MD. Splitting headache (off). Arthritis Rheum. 2013;65(11):2759-2761.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olesen J. Headache Classification Committee of the International Headache Society (IHS) The International Classification of Headache Disorders, 3rd edition. Cephalalgia. 2018;38:1-211.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kodera T, Tsutsumi T, Oka Y, Takeda T, Shirota Y, Kameoka J. Clinical efficacy of belimumab in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus and headache: a report of two cases. Mod Rheumatol Case Rep. 2022;6(1):25-28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manzi S, S&#xe1;nchez-Guerrero J, Merrill JT, et al. Effects of belimumab, a B lymphocyte stimulator-specific inhibitor, on disease activity across multiple organ domains in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: combined results from two phase III trials. Ann Rheum Dis. 2012;71(11):1833-1838.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>