<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37058724</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>18</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1526-7598</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>136</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>May</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Anesthesia and analgesia</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Anesth Analg</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Comprehensive Management of the Patient With Traumatic Cardiac Injury.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>877</StartPage><EndPage>893</EndPage><MedlinePgn>877-893</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1213/ANE.0000000000006380</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Cardiac injuries are rare but potentially life-threatening, with a significant proportion of victims dying before arrival at the hospital. The in-hospital mortality among patients who arrive in-hospital alive also remains significantly high, despite major advancements in trauma care including the continuous updating of the Advanced Trauma Life Support (ATLS) program. Stab and gunshot wounds due to assault or self-inflicted injuries are the common causes of penetrating cardiac injuries, while motor vehicular accidents and fall from height are attributable causes of blunt cardiac injury. Rapid transport of victim to trauma care facility, prompt recognition of cardiac trauma by clinical evaluation and focused assessment with sonography for trauma (FAST) examination, quick decision-making to perform emergency department thoracotomy, and/or shifting the patient expeditiously to the operating room for operative intervention with ongoing resuscitation are the key components for a successful outcome in cardiac injury victims with cardiac tamponade or exsanguinating hemorrhage. Blunt cardiac injury with arrhythmias, myocardial dysfunction, or cardiac failure may need continuous cardiac monitoring or anesthetic care for operative procedure of other associated injuries. This mandates a multidisciplinary approach working in concert with agreed local protocols and shared goals. An anesthesiologist has a pivotal role to play as a team leader or member in the trauma pathway of severely injured patients. They are not only involved in in-hospital care as a perioperative physician but also participate in the organizational aspects of prehospital trauma systems and training of prehospital care providers/paramedics. There is sparse literature available on the anesthetic management of cardiac injury (penetrating as well as blunt) patients. This narrative review discusses the comprehensive management of cardiac injury patients, focusing on the anesthetic concerns and is guided by our experience in managing cardiac injury cases at Jai Prakash Narayan Apex Trauma Center (JPNATC), All India Institute of Medical Sciences, New Delhi. JPNATC is the only level 1 trauma center in north India, providing services to a population of approximately 30 million with around 9000 operations being performed annually.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 International Anesthesia Research Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gupta</LastName><ForeName>Babita</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Department of Anaesthesiology, Pain Medicine and Critical Care, Jai Prakash Narayan Apex Trauma Center, All India Institute of Medical Sciences, New Delhi, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Singh</LastName><ForeName>Yudhyavir</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Department of Anaesthesiology, Pain Medicine and Critical Care, Jai Prakash Narayan Apex Trauma Center, All India Institute of Medical Sciences, New Delhi, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bagaria</LastName><ForeName>Dinesh</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Trauma Surgery and Critical Care, Jai Prakash Narayan Apex Trauma Center, All India Institute of Medical Sciences, New Delhi, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nagarajappa</LastName><ForeName>Abhishek</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anaesthesiology, Pain Medicine and Critical Care, All India Institute of Medical Sciences, New Delhi, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Anesth Analg</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>1310650</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0003-2999</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014948" MajorTopicYN="Y">Wounds, Gunshot</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000601" MajorTopicYN="N">surgery</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014950" MajorTopicYN="Y">Wounds, Penetrating</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006335" MajorTopicYN="Y">Heart Injuries</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012151" MajorTopicYN="N">Resuscitation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000071956" MajorTopicYN="Y">Myocardial Contusions</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37058724</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1213/ANE.0000000000006380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00000539-202305000-00009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Campbell NC, Thomson SR, Muckart DJ, Meumann CM, Van Middelkoop I, Botha JB. Review of 1198 cases of penetrating cardiac trauma. Br J Surg. 1997;84:1737&#x2013;1740.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thourani VH, Feliciano DV, Cooper WA, et al. Penetrating cardiac trauma at an urban trauma center: a 22-year perspective. Am Surg. 1999;65:811&#x2013;816.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yousef R, Carr JA. Blunt cardiac trauma: a review of the current knowledge and management. Ann Thorac Surg. 2014;98:1134&#x2013;1140.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Veelen MJ, Brodmann Maeder M. Hypothermia in trauma. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18:8719.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morse BC, Mina MJ, Carr JS, et al. Penetrating cardiac injuries: a 36-year perspective at an urban, Level I trauma center. J Trauma Acute Care Surg. 2016;81:623&#x2013;631.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta S, Parida S, Pillai AK, Varadharajan R. Emergency anaesthetic management of penetrating thoracic trauma: combining skill with fortuity. Indian J Anaesth. 2015;59:186&#x2013;187.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canale L, Gill I, Smith C. Cardiac and great vessel trauma. Smith C, ed. In: Trauma Anesthesia. 2nd ed. Cambridge University Press; 2015:482&#x2013;498.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thokchom CS, Laitonjam C, Nongmaithem M, C Arambam N, D Khagokpam H. Management of penetrating cardiac injury in a tertiary hospital in Northeast India. Int J Med Res Rev. 2020;8:45&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Makhadi S, Moeng MS, Ede C, Jassat F, Palweni ST. Penetrating cardiac injuries: outcome of treatment from a level 1 trauma centre in South Africa. Trauma Care. 2022;2:251&#x2013;259.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asensio JA, Murray J, Demetriades D, et al. Penetrating cardiac injuries: a prospective study of variables predicting outcomes. J Am Coll Surg. 1998;186:24&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Connor CJ, Tuman KJ. The intraoperative management of patients with pericardial tamponade. Anesthesiol Clin. 2010;28:87&#x2013;96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mina MJ, Jhunjhunwala R, Gelbard RB, et al. Factors affecting mortality after penetrating cardiac injuries: 10-year experience at urban level I trauma center. Am J Surg. 2017;213:1109&#x2013;1115.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Degiannis E, Loogna P, Doll D, Bonanno F, Bowley DM, Smith MD. Penetrating cardiac injuries: recent experience in South Africa. World J Surg. 2006;30:1258&#x2013;1264.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cowley RA. The resuscitation and stabilization of major multiple trauma patients in a trauma center environment. Clin Med (Northfield IL). 1976;83:16&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gervin AS, Fischer RP. The importance of prompt transport of salvage of patients with penetrating heart wounds. J Trauma. 1982;22:443&#x2013;448.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taghavi S, Maher Z, Goldberg AJ, et al. An eastern association for the surgery of Trauma multicenter trial examining prehospital procedures in penetrating trauma patients. J Trauma Acute Care Surg. 2021;91:130&#x2013;140.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrada P, Callcut RA, Skarupa DJ, et al.; AAST Multi-Institutional Trials Committee. Circulation first - the time has come to question the sequencing of care in the ABCs of trauma; an American Association for the Surgery of Trauma multicenter trial. World J Emerg Surg. 2018;13:8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang HE, Schmicker RH, Daya MR, et al. Effect of a strategy of initial laryngeal tube insertion vs endotracheal intubation on 72-hour survival in adults with out-of-hospital cardiac arrest: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA. 2018;320:769&#x2013;778.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wise R, Faurie M, Malbrain MLNG, Hodgson E. Strategies for intravenous fluid resuscitation in trauma patients. World J Surg. 2017;41:1170&#x2013;1183.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pusateri AE, Moore EE, Moore HB, et al. Association of prehospital plasma transfusion with survival in trauma patients with hemorrhagic shock when transport times are longer than 20 minutes: a post hoc analysis of the PAMPer and COMBAT Clinical Trials. JAMA Surg. 2020;155:e195085.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crombie N, Doughty HA, Bishop JRB, et al.; RePHILL collaborative group. Resuscitation with blood products in patients with trauma-related haemorrhagic shock receiving prehospital care (RePHILL): a multicentre, open-label, randomised, controlled, phase 3 trial. Lancet Haematol. 2022;9:e250&#x2013;e261.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taran S. The scoop and run method of pre-clinical care for trauma victims. Mcgill J Med. 2009;12:73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Surgeons. Committee on trauma. In: Advanced Trauma Life Support: Student Course Manual. 10th ed. American College of Surgeons; 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Navsaria PH, Nicol AJ. Haemopericardium in stable patients after penetrating injury: is subxiphoid pericardial window and drainage enough? A prospective study. Injury. 2005;36:745&#x2013;750.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandal AK, Sanusi M. Penetrating chest wounds: 24 years experience. World J Surg. 2001;25:1145&#x2013;1149.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tyburski JG, Astra L, Wilson RF, Dente C, Steffes C. Factors affecting prognosis with penetrating wounds of the heart. J Trauma. 2000;48:587&#x2013;590.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ivatury RR. The injured heart. Moore EE, Feliciano DV, Mattox KL, eds. In: Trauma. 5th ed. McGraw-Hill; 2004:555&#x2013;568.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreno C, Moore EE, Majure JA, Hopeman AR. Pericardial tamponade: a critical determinant for survival following penetrating cardiac wounds. J Trauma. 1986;26:821&#x2013;825.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duncan AO, Scalea TM, Sclafani SJ, et al. Evaluation of occult cardiac injuries using subxiphoid pericardial window. J Trauma. 1989;29:955&#x2013;960.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamali S, Aydin MT, Akan A, Karatepe O, Sari A, Y&#xfc;ney E. Penetrating cardiac injury: factors affecting outcome. Ulus Travma Acil Cerrahi Derg. 2011;17:225&#x2013;230.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson A, Rott M, Kuchler A, et al. Direct to operating room trauma resuscitation: optimizing patient selection and time-critical outcomes when minutes count. J Trauma Acute Care Surg. 2020;89:160&#x2013;166.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rehn L. Ueber penetrierende herzwunden und herznaht. Arch Klin Chir. 1897;55:315&#x2013;329.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhee PM, Acosta J, Bridgeman A, Wang D, Jordan M, Rich N. Survival after emergency department thoracotomy: review of published data from the past 25 years. J Am Coll Surg. 2000;190:288&#x2013;298.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burlew CL, Moore EE. Resuscitative thoracotomy. Moore EE, Feliciano DV, Mattox KL. eds. In: Trauma, 9th ed. McGraw Hill; 2020. Accessed August 17, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sikka R, Millham FH, Feldman JA. Analysis of occupational exposures associated with emergency department thoracotomy. J Trauma. 2004;56:867&#x2013;872.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winkle JM, Legome E. Initial evaluation and management of penetrating thoracic trauma in adults. 2022. Accessed August 18, 2022. https://www.uptodate.com/contents/initial-evaluation-and-management-of-penetrating-thoracic-trauma-in-adults .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kulshrestha P, Das B, Iyer KS, et al. Cardiac injuries&#x2014;a clinical and autopsy profile. J Trauma. 1990;30:203&#x2013;207.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eckstein M, Henderson SO. Thoracic trauma. Marx JA, Hockberger RS, Walls RM eds. In: Rosen&#x2019;s Emergency Medicine. Vol I. 7th ed. Mosby Elsevier; 2010: 387.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheffy N, Chemsian RV, Grabinsky A, S J. Howell, Anaesthesia considerations in penetrating trauma. Br J Anaesth. 2014;113:276&#x2013;285.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panaro S. Anesthesia for thoracic trauma in adults. 2019. Accessed August 18, 2022. https://www.uptodate.com/contents/anesthesia-for-thoracic-trauma-in-adults .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tantry TP, Kadam D, Shetty P, Adappa KK, Muralishankar B, Shenoy SP. Penetrating abdominal injury in a polytrauma patient: anaesthetic challenges faced. J Anaesthesiol Clin Pharmacol. 2011;27:272&#x2013;274.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dar Rawat J, Goel P, Kunnur SV, Kushwaha B, Kushwaha R. Penetrating injury of pelvis, abdomen and thorax in a child with a trident (Trishula). APSP J Case Rep. 2013;4:3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isenburg S, Jackson N, Karmy-Jones R. Removal of an impaled knife under thoracoscopic guidance. Can Respir J. 2008;15:39&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egan ED, Johnson KB. The influence of hemorrhagic shock on the disposition and effects of intravenous anesthetics: a narrative review. Anesth Analg. 2020;130:1320&#x2013;1330.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Correia M. Anaesthesia for patients with pericardial disease. Aronow WS, Murashita T, eds. In: Inflammatory Heart Diseases [Internet]. IntechOpen; 2019. Accessed August 3, 2022. https://www.intechopen.com/chapters/67335 . doi: 10.5772/intechopen.8254027.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Das S, Forrest K, Howell S. General anaesthesia in elderly patients with cardiovascular disorders: choice of anaesthetic agent. Drugs Aging. 2010;27:265&#x2013;282.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen TL, Huang FY, Lin SY, Chao CC. Hemodynamic response to ketamine and diazepam in dogs with acute cardiac tamponade. Ma Zui Xue Za Zhi. 1989;27:19&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bassett MD, Smith CE. General anesthesia for trauma. Varon AJ, Smith CE, eds. In: Essentials of Trauma Anesthesia. Cambridge University Press; 2012:76&#x2013;94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kakazu C, Lippmann M, Hsu D. Ketamine: a positive-negative anaesthetic agent. Br J Anaesth. 2016;117:267.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carmona P, Mateo E, Casanovas I, et al. Management of cardiac tamponade after cardiac surgery [published correction appears in J Cardiothorac Vasc Anesth. 2012 Aug;26(4):758]. J Cardiothorac Vasc Anesth. 2012;26:302&#x2013;311.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aye T, Milne B. Ketamine anesthesia for pericardial window in a patient with pericardial tamponade and severe COPD. Can J Anaesth. 2002;49:283&#x2013;286.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stollings JL, Diedrich DA, Oyen LJ, Brown DR. Rapid-sequence intubation: a review of the process and considerations when choosing medications. Ann Pharmacother. 2014;48:62&#x2013;76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sikorski RA, Koerner AK, Fouche-Weber LY, Galvagno SM. Choice of general anesthetics for trauma patients. Curr Anesthesiol Rep. 2014;4:225&#x2013;232.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galvagno S. Anesthesia for adult trauma patients. 2021. Accessed July 20, 2022. https://www.uptodate.com/contents/anesthesia-for-adult-trauma-patients .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Vasconcellos K, Sneyd JR. Nitrous oxide: are we still in equipoise? A qualitative review of current controversies. Br J Anaesth. 2013;111:877&#x2013;885.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enlund M, Edmark L, Reven&#xe4;s B. Is nitrous oxide a real gentleman? Acta Anaesthesiol Scand. 2001;45:922&#x2013;923.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myles PS, Leslie K, Chan MT, et al.; ENIGMA Trial Group. Avoidance of nitrous oxide for patients undergoing major surgery: a randomized controlled trial. Anesthesiology. 2007;107:221&#x2013;231.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madhivathanan PR, Corredor C, Smith A. Perioperative implications of pericardial effusions and cardiac tamponade. BJA Educ. 2020;20:226&#x2013;234.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schulman DS, Biondi JW, Matthay RA, Barash PG, Zaret BL, Soufer R. Effect of positive end-expiratory pressure on right ventricular performance. Importance of baseline right ventricular function. Am J Med. 1988;84:57&#x2013;67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panchal AR, Bartos JA, Caba&#xf1;as JG, et al.; Adult Basic and Advanced Life Support Writing Group. Part 3: adult basic and advanced life support: 2020 American Heart Association Guidelines for cardiopulmonary resuscitation and emergency cardiovascular care. Circulation. 2020;142(16_suppl_2):S366&#x2013;S468.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hensley NB, Hogue WC. Anesthesia for emergency surgery after cardiac arrest or traumatic cardiac injury. 2021. Accessed July 18, 2022. https://www.uptodate.com/contents/anesthesia-for-emergency-surgery-after-cardiac-arrest .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Handy J. Lactate&#x2014;the bad boy of metabolism,or simply misunderstood? Curr Anaesth Crit Care. 2006;17:71&#x2013;76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aminiahidashti H, Shafiee S, Zamani Kiasari A, Sazgar M. Applications of end-tidal carbon dioxide (ETCO2) monitoring in emergency department; a narrative review. Emerg (Tehran). 2018;6:e5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thys DM, Brooker RF, Cahalan MK, et al. American Society of Anesthesiologists and Society of Cardiovascular Anesthesiologists task force on transesophageal echocardiography. Practice guidelines for perioperative transesophageal echocardiography. An updated report by the American Society of Anesthesiologists and the Society of Cardiovascular Anesthesiologists task force on transesophageal echocardiography. Anesthesiology. 2010;112:1084&#x2013;1096.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poldermans D, Bax JJ, Boersma E, et al.; Task Force for Preoperative Cardiac Risk Assessment and Perioperative Cardiac Management in Non-cardiac Surgery of European Society of Cardiology (ESC). Guidelines for pre-operative cardiac risk assessment and perioperative cardiac management in non-cardiac surgery: the Task Force for Preoperative Cardiac Risk Assessment and Perioperative Cardiac Management in Non-cardiac Surgery of the European Society of Cardiology (ESC) and endorsed by the European Society of Anaesthesiology (ESA). Eur J Anaesthesiol. 2010;27:92&#x2013;137.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orliaguet G, Ferjani M, Riou B. The heart in blunt trauma. Anesthesiology. 2001;95:544&#x2013;548.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gir&#xf3;n-Arango L, D&#x2019;Empaire PP. Is there a role for transesophageal echocardiography in the perioperative trauma patient? Curr Anesthesiol Rep. 2022;12:210&#x2013;216.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Little WC, Freeman GL. Pericardial disease [published correction appears in Circulation. 2007 Apr 17;115(15):e406. Dosage error in article text]. Circulation. 2006;113:1622&#x2013;1632.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spodick DH. Acute cardiac tamponade. N Engl J Med. 2003;349:684&#x2013;690.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grocott HP, Gulati H, Srinathan S, Mackensen GB. Anesthesia and the patient with pericardial disease. Can J Anaesth. 2011;58:952&#x2013;966.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harrold IM, Seheult JN, Alarcon LH, et al. Hemolytic markers following the transfusion of uncrossmatched, cold-stored, low-titer, group O+ whole blood in civilian trauma patients. Transfusion. 2020;60(suppl 3):S24&#x2013;S30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lamb CM, MacGoey P, Navarro AP, Brooks AJ. Damage control surgery in the era of damage control resuscitation. Br J Anaesth. 2014;113:242&#x2013;249.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shakur H, Roberts I, Bautista R, et al.; CRASH-2 trial collaborators. Effects of tranexamic acid on death, vascular occlusive events, and blood transfusion in trauma patients with significant haemorrhage (CRASH-2): a randomised, placebo-controlled trial. Lancet. 2010;376:23&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klein AA, Bailey CR, Charlton AJ, et al. Association of anaesthetists guidelines: cell salvage for peri-operative blood conservation 2018. Anaesthesia. 2018;73:1141&#x2013;1150.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J, Sun SL, Tian JH, Yang K, Liu R, Li J. Cell salvage in emergency trauma surgery. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2015;1:CD007379.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sagrist&#xe0;-Sauleda J, Angel J, Sambola A, Permanyer-Miralda G. Hemodynamic effects of volume expansion in patients with cardiac tamponade. Circulation. 2008;117:1545&#x2013;1549.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh V, Dwivedi SK, Chandra S, et al. Optimal fluid amount for haemodynamic benefit in cardiac tamponade. Eur Heart J Acute Cardiovasc Care. 2014;3:158&#x2013;164.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sperry JL, Minei JP, Frankel HL, et al. Early use of vasopressors after injury: caution before constriction. J Trauma. 2008;64:9&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richards JE, Harris T, D&#xfc;nser MW, Bouzat P, Gauss T. Vasopressors in trauma: a never event? Anesth Analg. 2021;133:68&#x2013;79.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uchida K, Nishimura T, Hagawa N, et al. The impact of early administration of vasopressor agents for the resuscitation of severe hemorrhagic shock following blunt trauma. BMC Emerg Med. 2020;20:26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spahn DR, Bouillon B, Cerny V, et al. Management of bleeding and coagulopathy following major trauma: an updated European guideline. Crit Care. 2013;17:R76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta B, Garg N, Ramachandran R. Vasopressors: do they have any role in hemorrhagic shock? J Anaesthesiol Clin Pharmacol. 2017;33:3&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu H, Yu L, Yang L, Green MS. Vasoplegic syndrome: an update on perioperative considerations. J Clin Anesth. 2017;40:63&#x2013;71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vahdatpour C, Collins D, Goldberg S. Cardiogenic shock. J Am Heart Assoc. 2019;8:e011991.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao JM, Gao YH, Wei GB, et al. Penetrating cardiac wounds: principles for surgical management. World J Surg. 2004;28:1025&#x2013;1029.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isaza-Restrepo A, Bol&#xed;var-S&#xe1;enz DJ, Tarazona-Lara M, Tovar JR. Penetrating cardiac trauma: analysis of 240 cases from a hospital in Bogota, Colombia. World J Emerg Surg. 2017;12:26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mishra B, Gupta A, Sagar S, Singhal M, Kumar S. Traumatic cardiac injury: experience from a level-1 trauma centre. Chin J Traumatol. 2016;19:333&#x2013;336.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bar I, Papiashvilli M, Jeroukhimov I, Muhanna AY, Alzaanin AA. Strategies in the management of penetrating cardiac trauma based on 14 surviving patients from a strife-ridden area. Indian J Thorac Cardiovasc Surg. 2009;25:23&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Menyar A, Al Thani H, Zarour A, Latifi R. Understanding traumatic blunt cardiac injury. Ann Card Anaesth. 2012;15:287&#x2013;295.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warrington SJ, Mahajan K. Cardiac trauma. [Updated April 13, 2022]. In: StatPearls [Internet]. StatPearls Publishing; 2022. Accessed August 16, 2022. https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK430725/ .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robicsek F. Induced ventricular fibrillation in the management of aortic arch trauma. Ann Thorac Surg. 2002;73:342.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim R, Gill IS, Temes RT, Smith CE. The use of adenosine for repair of penetrating cardiac injuries: a novel method. Ann Thorac Surg. 2001;71:1714&#x2013;1715.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagiwara K, Inoue JI, Matumoto G, Iwase F. Penetrating cardiac injury repaired under &#x201c;intentional cardiac arrest&#x201d; with adenosine triphosphate. Acute Med Surg. 2021;8:e686.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rupprecht H, Ghidau M. Penetrating nail-gun injury of the heart managed by adenosine-induced asystole in the absence of a heart-lung machine. Tex Heart Inst J. 2014;41:429&#x2013;432.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gill I, Lim R, Temes RT. In reply to: Robicsek F. Induced ventricular fibrillation in the management of aortic arch trauma. Ann Thorac Surg. 2002;73:342.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hakuba T, Minato N, Minematsu T, Kamohara K. Surgical management and treatment of a traumatic right atrial rupture. Gen Thorac Cardiovasc Surg. 2008;56:551&#x2013;554.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandell SP. Management of cardiac injury in severely injured patients. Accessed August 16, 2022. https://www.uptodate.com/contents/management-of-cardiac-injury-in-severely-injured-patients/ .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reissman P, Rivkind A, Jurim O, Simon D. Case report: the management of penetrating cardiac trauma with major coronary artery injury&#x2014;Is cardiopulmonary bypass essential? J Trauma. 1992;33:773&#x2013;775.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker JM, Battistella FD, Kraut E, Owings JT, Follette DM. Use of cardiopulmonary bypass to salvage patients with multiple-chamber heart wounds. Arch Surg. 1998;133:855&#x2013;860.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#x2019;Souza RS, Law L. Open heart massage. [Updated July 11, 2022]. In: StatPearls [Internet]. StatPearls Publishing; 2022. https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK537230/ .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soar J, Perkins GD, Abbas G, et al. European resuscitation council guidelines for resuscitation 2010 Section 8. Cardiac arrest in special circumstances: electrolyte abnormalities, poisoning, drowning, accidental hypothermia, hyperthermia, asthma, anaphylaxis, cardiac surgery, trauma, pregnancy, electrocution. Resuscitation. 2010;81:1400&#x2013;1433.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winterhalter M, Piepenbrock T, Leyh RG, et al. Effectiveness and safety of internal rectilinear biphasic versus monophasic defibrillation in patients undergoing cardiac surgery. J Cardiothorac Vasc Anesth. 2005;19:739&#x2013;745.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lamberg JJ, Malhotra AK, McAlevy ME. Intracardiac epinephrine injection during open thoracotomy and circulatory arrest. J Anesthe Clinic Res. 2013;4:341.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prabhakar Y, Goyal A, Khalid N, et al. Pericardial decompression syndrome: a comprehensive review. World J Cardiol. 2019;11:282&#x2013;291.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perez SA, Amastha J, Vincent L, Alfonso CE, de Marchena E. Severe right ventricular failure following pericardiocentesis: a case report of pericardial decompression syndrome. JACC Case Rep. 2021;3:58&#x2013;63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pradhan R, Okabe T, Yoshida K, Angouras DC, DeCaro MV, Marhefka GD. Patient characteristics and predictors of mortality associated with pericardial decompression syndrome: a comprehensive analysis of published cases. Eur Heart J Acute Cardiovasc Care. 2015,4:113&#x2013;120.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ischaki E, Vasileiadis I, Koroneos A, et al. Acute heart failure following decompression of tuberculosis induced pericardial tamponade. Respirat Med CME. 2008;1:87&#x2013;98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan MI, Al Sahali W, Quigley P, McCreery C, Dodd J, O&#x2019;Hanlon R. Pericardiocentesis in cardiac tamponade: a case for &#x201c;Less is More.&#x201d; Int J Case Rep Images. 2020;11:101091Z01MK2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ricarte Bratti JP, Brunette V, Lebon JS, Pellerin M, Lamarche Y. Venoarterial extracorporeal membrane oxygenation support for severe pericardial decompression syndrome: a case report. Crit Care Med. 2020;48:74&#x2013;75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ligero C, Leta R, Bayes-Genis A. Transient biventricular dysfunction following pericardiocentesis. Eur J Heart Fail. 2006;8:102&#x2013;104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernal JM, Pradhan J, Li T, Tchokonte R, Afonso L. Acute pulmonary edema following pericardiocentesis for cardiac tamponade. Can J Cardiol. 2007;23:1155&#x2013;1156.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdelmalek J, Abohelwa MM, Elmassry M, Ansari MM. A case of pericardial decompression syndrome following surgical pericardial fluid drainage. Cureus. 2021;13:e16631.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Attar S, Suter CM, Hankins JR, Sequeira A, McLaughlin JS. Penetrating cardiac injuries. Ann Thorac Surg. 1991;51:711&#x2013;716.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Villegas Lanau MI. Trauma card&#xed;aco penetrante: factores pron&#xf3;sticos. rev. colomb. cir.[online]. 2007, vol. 22, n. 3. ISSN. 2011;7582:148&#x2013;156.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Snow N, Richardson JD, Flint LM Jr. Myocardial contusion: implications for patients with multiple traumatic injuries. Surgery. 1982;92:744&#x2013;750.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh S, Heard M, Pester JM, et al. Blunt cardiac injury. [Updated September 19, 2022]. In: StatPearls [Internet]. StatPearls Publishing; 2022. https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK532267/ .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>EL-Andari R, O&#x2019;Brien D, Bozso SJ, Nagendran J. Blunt cardiac trauma: a narrative review. Mediastinum. 2021;5:28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clancy K, Velopulos C, Bilaniuk JW, et al. Screening for blunt cardiac injury: an Eastern Association for the Surgery of Trauma practice management guideline. J Trauma Acute Care Surg. 2012;73:S301.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Velmahos GC, Karaiskakis M, Salim A, et al. Normal electrocardiography and serum troponin I levels preclude the presence of clinically significant blunt cardiac injury. J Trauma. 2003;54:45&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salim A, Velmahos GC, Jindal A, et al. Clinically significant blunt cardiac trauma: role of serum troponin levels combined with electrocardiographic findings. J Trauma. 2001;50:237&#x2013;243.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tenzer ML. The spectrum of myocardial contusion: a review. J Trauma. 1985;25:620&#x2013;627.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robert E, de La Coussaye JE, Aya AG, et al. Mechanisms of ventricular arrhythmias induced by myocardial contusion: a high-resolution mapping study in left ventricular rabbit heart. Anesthesiology. 2000;92:1132&#x2013;1143.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schultz JM, Trunkey DD. Blunt cardiac injury. Crit Care Clin. 2004;20:57&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sybrandy KC, Cramer MJ, Burgersdijk C. Diagnosing cardiac contusion: old wisdom and new insights. Heart. 2003;89:485&#x2013;489.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellister SA, Dennis BM, Guillamondegui OD. Blunt and penetrating cardiac trauma. Surg Clin North Am. 2017;97:1065&#x2013;1076.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abu-Hmeidan JH, Arrowaili AI, Yousef RS, et al. Coronary artery rupture in blunt thoracic trauma: a case report and review of literature. J Cardiothorac Surg. 2016;11:119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fokin AA, Wycech Knight J, Yoshinaga K, et al. Blunt cardiac injury in patients with sternal fractures. Cureus. 2022;14:e22841.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flancbaum L, Wright J, Siegel JH. Emergency surgery in patients with post-traumatic myocardial contusion. J Trauma. 1986;26:795&#x2013;803.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elie MC. Blunt cardiac injury. Mt Sinai J Med. 2006;73:542&#x2013;552.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shafi S, Elliott AC, Gentilello L. Is hypothermia simply a marker of shock and injury severity or an independent risk factor for mortality in trauma patients? Analysis of a large national trauma registry. J Trauma. 2005;59:1081&#x2013;1085.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin RS, Kilgo PD, Miller PR, Hoth JJ, Meredith JW, Chang MC. Injury-associated hypothermia: an analysis of the 2004 National Trauma Data Bank. Shock. 2005;24:114&#x2013;118.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xf6;sli D, Schn&#xfc;riger B, Candinas D, Haltmeier T. The impact of accidental hypothermia on mortality in trauma patients overall and patients with traumatic brain injury specifically: a systematic review and meta-analysis. World J Surg. 2020;44:4106&#x2013;4117.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsuei BJ, Kearney PA. Hypothermia in the trauma patient. Injury. 2004;35:7&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xf8;reide K. Clinical and translational aspects of hypothermia in major trauma patients: from pathophysiology to prevention, prognosis and potential preservation. Injury. 2014;45:647&#x2013;654.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alam HB, Chen Z, Honma K, et al. The rate of induction of hypothermic arrest determines the outcome in a Swine model of lethal hemorrhage. J Trauma. 2004;57:961&#x2013;969.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhee P, Talon E, Eifert S, et al. Induced hypothermia during emergency department thoracotomy: an animal model. J Trauma. 2000;48:439&#x2013;450.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kutcher ME, Forsythe RM, Tisherman SA. Emergency preservation and resuscitation for cardiac arrest from trauma. Int J Surg. 2016;33:209&#x2013;212.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raedler C, Voelckel WG, Wenzel V, et al. Treatment of uncontrolled hemorrhagic shock after liver trauma: fatal effects of fluid resuscitation versus improved outcome after vasopressin. Anesth Analg. 2004;98:1759&#x2013;1766.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voelckel WG, Raedler C, Wenzel V, et al. Arginine vasopressin, but not epinephrine, improves survival in uncontrolled hemorrhagic shock after liver trauma in pigs. Crit Care Med. 2003;31:1160&#x2013;1165.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cossu AP, Mura P, De Giudici LM, et al. Vasopressin in hemorrhagic shock: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized animal trials. Biomed Res Int. 2014;2014:421291.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poloujadoff MP, Borron SW, Amathieu R, et al. Improved survival after resuscitation with norepinephrine in a murine model of uncontrolled hemorrhagic shock. Anesthesiology. 2007;107:591&#x2013;596.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meier J, Pape A, Loniewska D, et al. Norepinephrine increases tolerance to acute anemia. Crit Care Med. 2007;35:1484&#x2013;1492.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alspaugh DM, Sartorelli K, Shackford SR, Okum EJ, Buckingham S, Osler T. Prehospital resuscitation with phenylephrine in uncontrolled hemorrhagic shock and brain injury. J Trauma. 2000;48:851&#x2013;863.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>