<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37055357</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>17</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2233-4521</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>56</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of preventive medicine and public health = Yebang Uihakhoe chi</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Prev Med Public Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Outcomes of an e-Wellness Program for Lupus Patients in Thailand: A Participatory Action Research Approach.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>154</StartPage><EndPage>163</EndPage><MedlinePgn>154-163</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3961/jpmph.22.491</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) or lupus patients usually experience various physical and psychological challenges. Since the coronavirus disease 2019 pandemic, these challenges have become even harsher. Using the participatory action research approach, this study evaluated how an e-wellness program (eWP) impacted SLE-related knowledge and health behaviors, mental health, and quality of life among lupus patients in Thailand.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A 1-group, pretest-posttest design study was conducted among a purposive sample of lupus patients who were members of Thai SLE Foundation. The 2 main intervention components were: (1) online social support, and (2) lifestyle and stress management workshops. Sixty-eight participants completed all the study requirements, including the Physical and Psychosocial Health Assessment questionnaire.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">After being in the eWP for 3 months, participants' mean score for SLE-related knowledge increased significantly (t=5.3, p&lt;0.001). The increase in sleep hours was statistically significant (Z=-3.1, p&lt;0.01), with the percentage of participants who slept less than 7 hours decreasing from 52.9% to 29.0%. The percentage of participants reporting sun exposure decreased from 17.7% to 8.8%. The participants also reported significantly lower stress (t(66)=-4.4, p&lt;0.001) and anxiety (t(67)=-2.9, p=0.005). The post-eWP quality of life scores for the pain, planning, intimate relationship, burden to others, emotional health, and fatigue domains also improved significantly (p&lt;0.05).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The overall outcomes showed promising results of improved self-care knowledge, health behaviors, mental health status, and quality of life. It is recommended that the SLE Foundation continues to use the eWP model to help the lupus patient community.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ratanasiripong</LastName><ForeName>Nop T</ForeName><Initials>NT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Nursing, California State University, Dominguez Hills, Carson, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cahill</LastName><ForeName>Steven</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Nursing, California State University, Dominguez Hills, Carson, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Crane</LastName><ForeName>Christine</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Nursing, California State University, Dominguez Hills, Carson, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ratanasiripong</LastName><ForeName>Paul</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Education, California State University, Long Beach, Long Beach, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>California State University, Dominguez Hills</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Korea (South)</Country><MedlineTA>J Prev Med Public Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101242972</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1975-8375</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013785" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Thailand</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006293" MajorTopicYN="N">Health Promotion</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011795" MajorTopicYN="N">Surveys and Questionnaires</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Intervention</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Knowledge</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mental health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Qualify of life</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Systemic lupus erythematosus</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>
<b>CONFLICT OF INTEREST</b>
. The authors have no conflicts of interest associated with the material presented in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>22</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37055357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10111100</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3961/jpmph.22.491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">jpmph.22.491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Lupus Foundation of America  What is lupus?  [cited 2022 Oct 21]. Available from:  https://www.lupus.org/resources/what-is-lupus
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gandelman JS, Khan OA, Shuey MM, Neal JE, McNeer E, Dickson A, et al. Increased incidence of resistant hypertension in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: a retrospective cohort study. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken) 2020;72(4):534&#x2013;543.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6745299</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30875459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rees F, Doherty M, Grainge MJ, Lanyon P, Zhang W. The worldwide incidence and prevalence of systemic lupus erythematosus: a systematic review of epidemiological studies. Rheumatology (Oxford) 2017;56(11):1945&#x2013;1961.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28968809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drenkard C, Lim SS. Update on lupus epidemiology: advancing health disparities research through the study of minority populations. Curr Opin Rheumatol. 2019;31(6):689&#x2013;696.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6791519</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31436582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barber MR, Drenkard C, Falasinnu T, Hoi A, Mak A, Kow NY, et al. Global epidemiology of systemic lupus erythematosus. Nat Rev Rheumatol. 2021;17(9):515&#x2013;532.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8982275</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34345022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carter EE, Barr SG, Clarke AE. The global burden of SLE: prevalence, health disparities and socioeconomic impact. Nat Rev Rheumatol. 2016;12(10):605&#x2013;620.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27558659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palavutitotai N, Buppajarntham T, Katchamart W. Etiologies and outcomes of pleural effusions in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. J Clin Rheumatol. 2014;20(8):418&#x2013;421.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25417677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pereira MG, Duarte S, Ferraz A, Santos M, Fontes L. Quality of life in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: the mediator role of psychological morbidity and disease activity. Psychol Health Med. 2020;25(10):1247&#x2013;1257.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32093519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delis PC. Uncertainty and quality of life in systemic lupus erythematosus: a cross-sectional study. Rehabil Nurs. 2019;44(1):2&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30601796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazzoni D, Cicognani E. Positive and problematic support, stress and quality of life in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. Anxiety Stress Coping. 2016;29(5):542&#x2013;551.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26691287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lertwongpaopun W, Tilokskulchai F, Sindhu S, Pattaragan A, Chai-Aroon T. Factors associated with kidney damage among Thais with lupus nephritis. Pac Rim Int J Nurs Res Thail. 2016;20(4):309&#x2013;319.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratanasiripong NT, Ratanasiripong P. Predictive factors of quality of life among systemic lupus erythematosus patients in Thailand: a web-based cross-sectional study. Qual Life Res. 2020;29(9):2415&#x2013;2423.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32270369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Case S, Sinnette C, Phillip C, Grosgogeat C, Costenbader KH, Leatherwood C, et al. Patient experiences and strategies for coping with SLE: a qualitative study. Lupus. 2021;30(9):1405&#x2013;1414.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34013818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandez-Ruiz R, Masson M, Kim MY, Myers B, Haberman RH, Castillo R, et al. Leveraging the United States epicenter to provide insights on COVID-19 in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Rheumatol. 2020;72(12):1971&#x2013;1980.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7941257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32715660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tselios K, Gladman DD, Touma Z, Su J, Anderson N, Urowitz MB. Clinical remission and low disease activity outcomes over 10 years in systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken) 2019;71(6):822&#x2013;828.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30055090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tselios K, Gladman DD, Touma Z, Su J, Anderson N, Urowitz MB. Disease course patterns in systemic lupus erythematosus. Lupus. 2019;28(1):114&#x2013;122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30526328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fangtham M, Kasturi S, Bannuru RR, Nash JL, Wang C. Non-pharmacologic therapies for systemic lupus erythematosus. Lupus. 2019;28(6):703&#x2013;712.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6585401</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30961418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang A, Winquist NW, Wescott AB, Lattie EG, Graham AK. Systematic review of digital and non-digital non-pharmacological interventions that target quality of life and psychological outcomes in adults with systemic lupus erythematosus. Lupus. 2021;30(7):1058&#x2013;1077.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8122052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33779388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>da Hora TC, Lima K, Maciel RR. The effect of therapies on the quality of life of patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: a meta-analysis of randomized trials. Adv Rheumatol. 2019;59(1):34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31358064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nabundit R, Tangvoraphonkchai J. The effects of innovation in providing health information and health game on self-care behaviors for adolescent SLE patients admitted in hospital. J Nurs Sci Health. 2012;35(1):10&#x2013;17. (Thai)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baum F, MacDougall C, Smith D. Participatory action research. J Epidemiol Community Health. 2006;60(10):854&#x2013;857.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2566051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16973531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faul F, Erdfelder E, Lang AG, Buchner A. G*Power 3: a flexible statistical power analysis program for the social, behavioral, and biomedical sciences. Behav Res Methods. 2007;39(2):175&#x2013;191.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17695343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferguson CJ. An effect size primer: a guide for clinicians and researchers. Prof Psychol Res Pract. 2009;40(5):532&#x2013;538.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lovibond SH, Lovibond PF. Manual of the depression anxiety stress scales. 2nd ed. Sydney: Psychology Foundation; 1995. pp. 1&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratanasiripong N, Warawitsaranggoon R, Junda T, Sangchan H, Goo PA, Siripaitoon B, et al. Mental health status and health-related quality of life among systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) patients in Thailand: a multi-site study. J Med Assoc Thai. 2020;103(11):1185&#x2013;1193.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>RWS Life Sciences  LupusQoL scale.  [cited 2022 Oct 18]. Available from  https://lifesciences.rws.com/lupusqol/instrument-information/instrument-scoring
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plichta SB, Kelvin EA. Munro&#x2019;s statistical methods for health care research. 6th ed. Philadelphia: Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins; 2013. pp. 130&#x2013;137.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>United States Agency for International Development (USAID)  International data &amp; economic analysis. Thailand general education.  [cited 2022 Oct 11]. Available from:  https://idea.usaid.gov/cd/thailand/education
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elsayed D, Mesbah S. Effect of health education based intervention on self-care among systemic lupus erythematosus clients. Am J Nurs Res. 2018;6(3):105&#x2013;112.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puccinelli PJ, da Costa TS, Seffrin A, de Lira CA, Vancini RL, Nikolaidis PT, et al. Correction to: reduced level of physical activity during COVID-19 pandemic is associated with depression and anxiety levels: an internet-based survey. BMC Public Health. 2021;21(1):613.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8006646</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33781231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu MC, Koo M. Effects of exercise intervention on health-related quality of life in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: a systematic review and meta-analysis of controlled trials. Healthcare (Basel) 2021;9(9):1215.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8468902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34574989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams EM, Egede L, Faith T, Oates J. Effective self-management interventions for patients with lupus: potential impact of peer mentoring. Am J Med Sci. 2017;353(6):580&#x2013;592.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6249683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28641721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodrigues L, Sim-Sim MM, Sousa L, Faria-Sch&#xfc;tzer DB, Surita FG. Self-concept and body image of people living with lupus: a systematic review. Int J Rheum Dis. 2021;24(11):1339&#x2013;1353.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34314107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jolly M, Peters KF, Mikolaitis R, Evans-Raoul K, Block JA. Body image intervention to improve health outcomes in lupus: a pilot study. J Clin Rheumatol. 2014;20(8):403&#x2013;410.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25417675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polit DF, Beck CT. Nursing research: generating and assessing evidence for nursing practice. 10th ed. Philadelphia: Wolters Kluwer Health; 2017. p. 197.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hewitt CE, Kumaravel B, Dumville JC, Torgerson DJ, Trial attrition study group Assessing the impact of attrition in randomized controlled trials. J Clin Epidemiol. 2010;63(11):1264&#x2013;1270.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20573482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>