<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37070503</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>19</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1610-0387</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>21</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal der Deutschen Dermatologischen Gesellschaft = Journal of the German Society of Dermatology : JDDG</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Dtsch Dermatol Ges</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Lupus erythematosus.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>426</StartPage><EndPage>430</EndPage><MedlinePgn>426-430</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/ddg.15049</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Cutaneous lupus erythematosus can manifest with or without systemic involvement resulting in a broad clinical spectrum. Disease pathogenesis is often characterized by a loss of tolerance to endogenous antigens and a chronic relapsing activation of the innate and adaptive immune system. Research in recent years has expanded our pathogenic understanding of the disease. However, therapeutic options remain limited. Biologics directed against BLyS or the type&#xa0;I interferon receptor can be used for patients with cutaneous involvement and systemic lupus erythematosus, sometimes with an excellent response. Clinical trials are difficult to conduct due to the symptomatic variability of the disease. However, as cutaneous manifestations are increasingly recorded as a primary endpoints, we hope that multiple therapeutic targets will lead to better treatment options for SLE in the near future.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Authors. Journal der Deutschen Dermatologischen Gesellschaft published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of Deutsche Dermatologische Gesellschaft.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>G&#xfc;nther</LastName><ForeName>Claudia</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, University Hospital Carl Gustav Carus, Technische Universit&#xe4;t Dresden, Dresden, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wenzel</LastName><ForeName>J&#xf6;rg</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology and Allergy, University Medical Center, Bonn, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>J Dtsch Dermatol Ges</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101164708</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1610-0379</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008178" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lupus Erythematosus, Cutaneous</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37070503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ddg.15049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Worm M, Zidane M, Eisert L, et&#xa0;al. S2k guideline: Diagnosis and management of cutaneous lupus erythematosus - Part 1: Classification, diagnosis, prevention, activity scores. J Dtsch Dermatol Ges. 2021;19:1236-1247.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Worm M, Zidane M, Eisert L, et&#xa0;al. S2k guideline: Diagnosis and management of cutaneous lupus erythematosus - Part 2: Therapy, risk factors and other special topics. J Dtsch Dermatol Ges. 2021;19:1371-1395.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aringer M, Costenbader K, Daikh D, et&#xa0;al. 2019 European League Against Rheumatism/American College of Rheumatology Classification Criteria for Systemic Lupus Erythematosus. Arthritis Rheumatol. 2019;71:1400-1412.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolf C, Bruck N, Koss S, et&#xa0;al. Janus kinase inhibition in complement component 1 deficiency. J Allergy Clin Immunol. 2020;146:1439-1442. e5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Mayouf SM, Sunker A, Abdwani R, et&#xa0;al. Loss-of-function variant in DNASE1L3 causes a familial form of systemic lupus erythematosus. Nat Genet. 2011; 43: 1186-1188.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gunther C, Kind B, Reijns MA, et&#xa0;al. Defective removal of ribonucleotides from DNA promotes systemic autoimmunity. J Clin Invest. 2015;125:413-424.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gunther C. Research in practice: Disturbance in intracellular nucleic acid metabolism promotes lupus erythematosus. J Dtsch Dermatol Ges. 2021;19:209-213.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gehrke N, Mertens C, Zillinger T, et&#xa0;al. Oxidative damage of DNA confers resistance to cytosolic nuclease TREX1 degradation and potentiates STING-dependent immune sensing. Immunity. 2013;39:482-495.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scholtissek B, Zahn S, Maier J, et&#xa0;al. Immunostimulatory endogenous nucleic acids drive the lesional inflammation in cutaneous lupus erythematosus. J Invest Dermatol. 2017;137:1484-1492.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartok E, Hartmann G. Immune sensing mechanisms that discriminate self from altered self and foreign nucleic acids. Immunity. 2020;53:54-77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang W, Cai Y, Xu W, et&#xa0;al. AIM2 facilitates the apoptotic DNA-induced systemic lupus erythematosus via arbitrating macrophage functional maturation. J Clin Immunol. 2013;33:925-937.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kato Y, Park J, Takamatsu H, et&#xa0;al. Apoptosis-derived membrane vesicles drive the cGAS-STING pathway and enhance type I IFN production in systemic lupus erythematosus. Ann Rheum Dis. 2018;77:1507-1515.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wenzel J. Cutaneous lupus erythematosus: new insights into pathogenesis and therapeutic strategies. Nat Rev Rheumatol. 2019;15:519-532.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wenzel J, Landmann A, Vorwerk G, Kuhn A. High expression of B lymphocyte stimulator in lesional keratinocytes of patients with cutaneous lupus erythematosus. Exp Dermatol. 2018;27:95-97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hansel A, Gunther C, Baran W, et&#xa0;al. Human 6-sulfo LacNAc (slan) dendritic cells have molecular and functional features of an important pro-inflammatory cell type in lupus erythematosus. J Autoimmun. 2013;40:1-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caielli S, Athale S, Domic B, et&#xa0;al. Oxidized mitochondrial nucleoids released by neutrophils drive type I interferon production in human lupus. J Exp Med. 2016;213:697-713.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gunther C. [Genetics of lupus erythematosus]. Hautarzt. 2015;66:121-128.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gunther C, Berndt N, Wolf C, Lee-Kirsch MA. Familial chilblain lupus due to a novel mutation in the exonuclease III domain of 3' repair exonuclease 1 (TREX1). JAMA Dermatol. 2015;151:426-431.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee-Kirsch MA, Chowdhury D, Harvey S, et&#xa0;al. A mutation in TREX1 that impairs susceptibility to granzyme A-mediated cell death underlies familial chilblain lupus. J Mol Med. 2007;85:531-537.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolf C, Rapp A, Berndt N, et&#xa0;al. RPA and Rad51 constitute a cell intrinsic mechanism to protect the cytosol from self DNA. Nat Commun. 2016;7:11752.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berndt N, Wolf C, Fischer K, et&#xa0;al. Photosensitivity and cGAS-Dependent IFN-1 Activation in Patients with Lupus and TREX1 Deficiency. J Invest Dermatol. 2022;142:633-640. e6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zimmermann N, Wolf C, Schwenke R, et&#xa0;al. Assessment of clinical response to Janus kinase inhibition in patients with familial Chilblain lupus and TREX1 mutation. JAMA Dermatol. 2019;155:342-346.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konig N, Fiehn C, Wolf C, et&#xa0;al. Familial Chilblain lupus due to a gain-of-function mutation in STING. Ann Rheum Dis. 2017;76:468-472.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mougiakakos D, Kr&#xf6;nke G, V&#xf6;lkl S, et&#xa0;al. CD19-targeted CAR T cells in refractory systemic lupus erythematosus. N Engl J Med. 2021; 385: 567-569.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morand EF, Furie R, Tanaka Y, et&#xa0;al. Trial of anifrolumab in active systemic lupus erythematosus. N Engl J Med. 2020;382:211-221.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wenzel J, van Holt N, Maier J, et&#xa0;al. JAK1/2 inhibitor ruxolitinib controls a case of chilblain lupus erythematosus. J Invest Dermatol. 2016;136:1281-1283.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morand EF, Tanaka Y, Furie R, et&#xa0;al. POS0190. efficacy and safety of baricitinib in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: results from two randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled, parallel-group, phase 3 studies. Ann Rheum Dis. 2022;81:327-328.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braegelmann C, Niebel D, Wenzel J. Targeted therapies in autoimmune skin diseases. J Invest Dermatol. 2022; 142:969-975. e7.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>