<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37073886</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>20</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1469-493X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>4</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>19</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Cochrane database of systematic reviews</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cochrane Database Syst Rev</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Exercise as adjunctive therapy for systemic lupus erythematosus.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>CD014816</StartPage><MedlinePgn>CD014816</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">CD014816</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/14651858.CD014816.pub2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) is a rare, chronic autoimmune inflammatory disease with a prevalence varying from 4.3 to 150 people in 100,000, or approximately five million people worldwide. Systemic manifestations frequently include internal organ involvement, a characteristic malar rash on the face, pain in joints and muscles, and profound fatigue. Exercise is purported to be beneficial for people with SLE. For this review, we focused on studies that examined all types of structured exercise as an adjunctive therapy in the management of SLE.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES">To evaluate the benefits and harms of structured exercise as adjunctive therapy for adults with SLE compared with usual pharmacological care, usual pharmacological care plus placebo and usual pharmacological care plus non-pharmacological care.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SEARCH METHODS">We used standard, extensive Cochrane search methods. The latest search date was 30 March 2022.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SELECTION CRITERIA">We included randomised controlled trials (RCTs) of exercise as an adjunct to usual pharmacological treatment in SLE compared with placebo, usual pharmacological care alone and another non-pharmacological treatment. Major outcomes were fatigue, functional capacity, disease activity, quality of life, pain, serious adverse events, and withdrawals due to any reason, including any adverse events.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DATA COLLECTION AND ANALYSIS">We used standard Cochrane methods. Our major outcomes were 1. fatigue, 2. functional capacity, 3. disease activity, 4. quality of life, 5. pain, 6. serious adverse events, and 7. withdrawals due to any reason. Our minor outcomes were 8. responder rate, 9. aerobic fitness, 10. depression, and 11. anxiety. We used GRADE to assess certainty of evidence. The primary comparison was exercise compared with placebo.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MAIN RESULTS">We included 13 studies (540 participants) in this review. Studies compared exercise as an adjunct to usual pharmacological care (antimalarials, immunosuppressants, and oral glucocorticoids) with usual pharmacological care plus placebo (one study); usual pharmacological care (six studies); and another non-pharmacological treatment such as relaxation therapy (seven studies). Most studies had selection bias, and all studies had performance and detection bias. We downgraded the evidence for all comparisons because of a high risk of bias and imprecision. Exercise plus usual pharmacological care versus placebo plus usual pharmacological care Evidence from a single small study (17 participants) that compared whole body vibration exercise to whole body placebo vibration exercise (vibrations switched off) indicated that exercise may have little to no effect on fatigue, functional capacity, and pain (low-certainty evidence). We are uncertain whether exercise results in fewer or more withdrawals (very low-certainty evidence). The study did not report disease activity, quality of life, and serious adverse events. The study measured fatigue using the self-reported Functional Assessment of Chronic Illness Therapy - Fatigue (FACIT-Fatigue), scale 0 to 52; lower score means less fatigue. People who did not exercise rated their fatigue at 38 points and those who did exercise rated their fatigue at 33 points (mean difference (MD) 5 points lower, 95% confidence interval (CI) 13.29 lower to 3.29 higher). The study measured functional capacity using the self-reported 36-item Short Form health questionnaire (SF-36) Physical Function domain, scale 0 to 100; higher score means better function. People who did not exercise rated their functional capacity at 70 points and those who did exercise rated their functional capacity at 67.5 points (MD 2.5 points lower, 95% CI 23.78 lower to 18.78 higher). The study measured pain using the SF-36 Pain domain, scale 0 to 100; lower scores mean less pain. People who did not exercise rated their pain at 43 points and those who did exercise rated their pain at 34 points (MD 9 points lower, 95% CI 28.88 lower to 10.88 higher). More participants from the exercise group (3/11, 27%) withdrew from the study than the placebo group (1/10, 10%) (risk ratio (RR) 2.73, 95% CI 0.34 to 22.16). Exercise plus usual pharmacological care versus usual pharmacological care alone The addition of exercise to usual pharmacological care may have little to no effect on fatigue, functional capacity, and disease activity (low-certainty evidence). We are uncertain whether the addition of exercise improves pain (very low-certainty evidence), or results in fewer or more withdrawals (very low-certainty evidence). Serious adverse events and quality of life were not reported. Exercise plus usual care versus another non-pharmacological intervention such as receiving information about the disease or relaxation therapy Compared with education or relaxation therapy, exercise may reduce fatigue slightly (low-certainty evidence), may improve functional capacity (low-certainty evidence), probably results in little to no difference in disease activity (moderate-certainty evidence), and may result in little to no difference in pain (low-certainty evidence). We are uncertain whether exercise results in fewer or more withdrawals (very low-certainty evidence). Quality of life and serious adverse events were not reported.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="AUTHORS' CONCLUSIONS">Due to low- to very low-certainty evidence, we are not confident on the benefits of exercise on fatigue, functional capacity, disease activity, and pain, compared with placebo, usual care, or advice and relaxation therapy. Harms data were not well reported.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 The Cochrane Collaboration. Published by John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Frade</LastName><ForeName>Stephanie</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Health and Wellbeing, University of Southern Queensland, Ipswich, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Behavioural &amp; Health Sciences, Australian Catholic University, Strathfield, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>O'Neill</LastName><ForeName>Sean</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Bone and Joint Research, Kolling Institute, University of Sydney, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Northern Clinical School, Faculty of Medicine and Health, University of Sydney and Department of Rheumatology, Royal North Shore Hospital, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Greene</LastName><ForeName>David</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Behavioural &amp; Health Sciences, Australian Catholic University, Strathfield, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nutter</LastName><ForeName>Elise</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Health and Wellbeing, University of Southern Queensland, Ipswich, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cameron</LastName><ForeName>Melainie</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Health and Wellbeing, University of Southern Queensland, Ipswich, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>PhASRec (Physical activity, sport and recreation), North-west University, Potchefstroom, South Africa.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Health and Behavioural Sciences, University of the Sunshine Coast, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Cochrane Database Syst Rev</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100909747</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1361-6137</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><SupplMeshList><SupplMeshName Type="Disease" UI="C000721270">malar rash</SupplMeshName></SupplMeshList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="UpdateOf"><RefSource>doi: 10.1002/14651858.CD014816</RefSource></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="Y">Exercise</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005221" MajorTopicYN="N">Fatigue</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005081" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise Therapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010146" MajorTopicYN="N">Pain</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>SF: none. SO: none. EN: none. DG: none. MC: none.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37073886</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10115181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD014816.pub2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References to studies included in this review</Title><ReferenceList><Title>Abrah&#xe3;o 2016 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Abrah&#xe3;o MI, Gomiero AB, Peccin MS, Grande AJ, Trevisani VF. Cardiovascular training vs. resistance training for improving quality of life and physical function in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: a randomized controlled trial. Scandinavian Journal of Rheumatology 2016;45:197-201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26525835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Avaux 2016 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Avaux M, Hoellinger P, Nieuwland-Husson S, Fraselle V, Depresseux G, Houssiau FA. Effects of two different exercise programs on chronic fatigue in lupus patients. International Journal of Clinical and Laboratory Medicine 2016;71(6):403-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27377292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Benatti 2015 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Benatti FB, Miossi R, Passareli M, Nakandakare ER, Perandini L, Lima FR, et al. The effects of exercise on lipid profile in systemic lupus erythematosus and healthy individuals: a randomized trial. Rheumatology International 2015;35(1):61-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24972700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Benatti 2018 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Benatti FB, Miyake CN, Dantas WS, Zambelli VO, Shinjo SK, Pereira RM, et al. Exercise increases insulin sensitivity and skeletal muscle AMPK expression in systemic lupus erythematosus: a randomized controlled trial. Frontiers in Immunology 2018;9(906):1-10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5934440</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29755474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Bostrom 2016 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Bostrom C, Elfving B, Dupre B, Opava CH, Lundberg IE, Jansson E. Effects of a one-year physical activity programme for women with systemic lupus erythematosus &#x2013; a randomized controlled study. Lupus 2016;25(6):602-16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26768748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Daltroy 1995 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Daltroy LH, Robb-Nicholson C, Iversen MD, Wright EA, Liang MH. Effectiveness of minimally supervised home aerobic training in patients with systemic rheumatic disease. British Journal of Rheumatology 1995;34(11):1064-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8542209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Dos Reis&#x2010;Neto 2013 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Dos Reis-Neto ET, Da Silva AE, Monteiro CM, De Camargo LM, Sato EI. Supervised physical exercise improves endothelial function in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. Rheumatology 2013;52(12):2187-95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23970541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Hashemi 2022 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Hashemi S, Habibagahi Z, Heidari M, Abdollahpour-Alitappeh M, Karimic MH. Effects of combined aerobic and anaerobic exercise training on cytokine profiles in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE): a randomized controlled trial. Transplant Immunology 2022;70:1-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34922023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Kao 2021 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Kao VP, Wen HJ, Pan YJ, Pai CS, Tsai ST, Su KY. Combined aerobic and resistance training improves physical and executive functions in women with systemic lupus erythematosus. Lupus 2021;30(6):946-55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33657920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Keramiotou 2020 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Keramiotou K, Anagnostou C, Kataxaki E, Galanos A, Sfikakis PP, Tektonidou MG. The impact of upper limb exercise on function, daily activities and quality of life in systemic lupus erythematosus: a pilot randomised controlled trial. Rheumatic and Musculoskeletal Diseases 2020;6(1):1-10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6999688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31958285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Lopes&#x2010;Souza 2021 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Lopes-Souza P, Dionello CF, Bernardes-Oliveira CL, Moreira-Marconi E, Marchon RM, Teixeira-Silva Y, et al. Effects of 12-week whole-body vibration exercise on fatigue, functional ability and quality of life in women with systemic lupus erythematosus: a randomized controlled trial. Journal of Bodywork &amp; Movement Therapies 2021;27:191-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34391233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Miossi 2012 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Miossi R, Benatti FB, Pinto AL, Lima FR, Borba EF, Prado DM, et al. Using exercise training to counterbalance chronotropic incompetence and delayed heart rate recovery in systemic lupus erythematosus: a randomized trial. Arthritis Care &amp; Research 2012;64(8):1159-66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22438298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Tench 2003 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Tench CM, McCarthy J, McCurdie I, White PD, D'Cruz DP. Fatigue in systemic lupus erythematosus: a randomized controlled trial of exercise. British Society for Rheumatology 2003;42:1050-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12730519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>References to studies excluded from this review</Title><ReferenceList><Title>Abrahao 2009 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Abrahao MI, Montenegro-Rodrigues R, Marangoni RG, Peccin S, Trevisani VFM. Impact of physical activity program in systemic lupus erythematosus. Accession Number: 70373838. In: Arthritis and Rheumatism. Vol. 10. 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abrah&#xe3;o MI, Gomiero AB, Peccin MS, Grande AJ, Trevisani VF. Cardiovascular training vs. resistance training for improving quality of life and physical function in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: a randomized controlled trial. Scandinavian Journal of Rheumatology 2016;45:197-201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26525835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Ahn 2015 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Ahn GE, Chmiel JS, Dunlop DD, Helenowski IB, Semanik PA, Song J, et al. Self-reported and objectively measured physical activity in adults with systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Care &amp; Research 2015;67(5):701-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4370811</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25251755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Barnes 2010 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Barnes JN, Nualnim N, Sugawara J, Tanaka H. Habitual exercise is associated with reduced arterial stiffness in systemic lupus erythematosus. Faseb Journal 2010;24(11):1194-200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21833040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Bogdanovic 2015 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Bogdanovic G, Stojanovich L, Djokovic A, Stanisavljevic N. Physical activity program is helpful for improving quality of life in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. Journal of Experimental Medicine 2015;237(3):193-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26490344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Bostrom 2013 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Bostrom C. Exercise therapy in systemic lupus erythematosus. Annals of the Rheumatic Diseases 2013;71:39.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Cenedeze 2016 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Cenedeze MA, Benatti FB, Lima F, Borba E, Bonfa E, Sa-Pinto AL, et al. Effects of acute aerobic exercise on leukocyte inflammatory gene expression in systemic lupus erythematosus. Exercise Immunology Review 2016;22:64-80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26859426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Chapman 2020 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Chapman M, Gupta S, Chu J, Naqi M, Manna Z, Mazhar MA, et al. Aerobic exercise improves fatigue and quality of life in women with systemic lupus erythematosus (preliminary analysis). Arthritis &amp; Rheumatology 2020;72(Suppl 10):1.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Clarke&#x2010;Jenssen 2005 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Clarke-Jenssen AC, Fredriksen PM, Lilleby V, Mengshoelz AM. Effects of supervised aerobic exercise in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: a pilot study. Arthritis &amp; Rheumatism (Arthritis Care &amp; Research) 2005;53(2):308-12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15818657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Da Silva 2013 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Da Silva AE, Dos Reis-Neto ET, Da Silva NP, Sato EI. The effect of acute physical exercise on cytokine levels in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. Lupus 2013;22(14):1479-83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24135080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>De Carvalho 2005 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>De Carvalho MR, Sato EI, Tebexreni AS, Heidecher RT, Schenkman S, Neto TL. Effects of supervised cardiovascular training program on exercise tolerance, aerobic capacity, and quality of life in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis &amp; Rheumatism 2005;53(6):838-44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16342102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Gavilan&#x2010;Carrera 2020 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Gavilan-Carrera B, Vargas-Hitos JA, Morillas-de-Laguno P, Rosales-Castillo A, Sola-Rodriguez S, Callejas-Rubio JL, et al. Effects of 12-week aerobic exercise on patient-reported outcomes in women with systemic lupus erythematosus. Disability and Rehabilitation 2020;44(10):1863-71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32878503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Gordon 2017 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Gordon BB, Kaufman K, Hicks ST, Norfleet JA, Cleveland RJ, Callahan LF, et al. Walk SLE &#x2013; a pilot study exploring Walk with Ease (WWE), a self-directed walking program, in lupus patients. Arthritis and Rheumatology 2017;69:Suppl 10.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Haglo 2021 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Haglo H, Wang ED, Berg OK, Hoff J, Helgerud J. Smartphone-assisted high-intensity interval training in inflammatory rheumatic disease patients: randomized controlled trial. JMIR mHealth and uHealth 2021;9(10):1-16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8569541</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34673536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Hasni 2021 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Hasni S, Chapman M, Feng R, Ahmad A, Gupta S, Naqi M, et al. A 12-week aerobic exercise training program in women with systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) improves fatigue, mitochondrial dysfunction and associated interferon gene signature [abstract]. Arthritis and Rheumatology 2021;73:Suppl 10.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Isenberg 1981 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Isenberg DA, Crisp AJ, Morrow WJ, Newham D, Snaith ML. Variation in circulating immune-complex levels with diet, exercise, and sleep &#x2013; a comparison between normal controls and patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. Annals of the Rheumatic Diseases 1981;40(5):466-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1000782</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6895450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Mak 2020 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Mak A. Physical exercise and systemic lupus erythematosus. Rheumatology 2020;59(5):921-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31691830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Martinez 2021 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Martinez J, Chan L, Hasni S, Keyser R, Chin L. Effects of aerobic exercise training on fatigability in women with systemic lupus erythematosus. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise 2021;53(8):438.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Martinez&#x2010;Rosales 2020 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Martinez-Rosales E, Sola-Rodriguez S, Vargas-Hitos JA, Gavilan-Carrera B, Rosales-Castillo A, Hernandez-Martinez A, et al. Heart rate variability in women with systemic lupus erythematosus: association with health-related parameters and effects of aerobic exercise. International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health 2020;17(24):1-14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7766283</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33352985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soriano-Maldonado A, Morillas-de-Laguno P, Sabio JM, Gavilan-Carrera B, Rosales-Castillo A, Montalban-Mendez C, et al. Effects of 12-week aerobic exercise on arterial stiffness, inflammation, and cardiorespiratory fitness in women with systemic lupus erythematosus: non-randomized controlled trial. Journal of Clinical Medicine 2018;7(12):1-17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6306776</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30477218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Perandini 2014 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Perandini LA, Sales-De-Oliveira D, Mello SB, Camara NO, Benatti FB, Lima FR, et al. Exercise training can attenuate the inflammatory milieu in women with systemic lupus erythematosus. Journal of Applied Physiology 2014;117(6):639-47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25038103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Ramsey&#x2010;Goldman&#xa0;2000 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Ramsey-Goldman R, Schilling EM, Dunlop D, Langman C, Greenland P, Thomas RJ, et al. A pilot study on the effects of exercise in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Care and Research 2000;13(5):262-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14635294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Sheikh 2019 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Sheikh SZ, Kaufman K, Gordon BB, Hicks S, Love A, Walker J, et al. Evaluation of the self-directed format of Walk With Ease in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: the Walk-SLE Pilot Study. Lupus 2019;28(6):764-70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31042128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Sieczkowska 2022 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Sieczkowska SM, Astley C, Marques IG, Iraha AY, Franco TC, Ihara BP, et al. A home-based exercise program during COVID-19 pandemic: perceptions and acceptability of juvenile systemic lupus erythematosus and juvenile idiopathic arthritis adolescents. Lupus 2022;31(4):443-56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8914298</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35264025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Soriano&#x2010;Maldonado 2018 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Soriano-Maldonado A, Morillas-de-Laguno P, Sabio JM, Gavilan-Carrera B, Rosales-Castillo A, Montalban-Mendez C, et al. Effects of 12-week aerobic exercise on arterial stiffness, inflammation, and cardiorespiratory fitness in women with systemic lupus erythematosus: non-randomized controlled trial. Journal of Clinical Medicine 2018;7(12):1-17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6306776</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30477218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Tench 2002 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Tench C, Bentley D, Vleck V, McCurdie I, White P, D'Cruz D. Aerobic fitness, fatigue, and physical disability in systemic lupus erythematosus. Journal of Rheumatology 2002;29(3):474-81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11908559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Youssef 2021 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Youssef MK. Effect of training on health outcome including fatigue, depression and quality of life in patients with systemic lupus erythromatosus. Beni-Suef University Journal of Basic and Applied Sciences 2021;10(90):1-8.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Yuen 2011 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Yuen HK, Holthaus K, Kamen DL, Sword DO, Breland HL. Using Wii Fit to reduce fatigue among African American women with systemic lupus erythematosus: a pilot study. Lupus 2011;20(12):1293-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3311128</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21700656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Zeppieri&#x2010;Caruana&#xa0;2018 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Zeppieri-Caruana M. Improved quality of life and decreased symptoms of lupus with diet, exercise, and functional medicine [abstract]. Arthritis and Rheumatology 2018;70(Suppl 9):-.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>References to studies awaiting assessment</Title><ReferenceList><Title>Boedecker 2020 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Boedecker SC, Philippi KF, Neuberger E, Schmidt S, Pfirrmann D, Haller N, et al. Twelve-week internet-based individualized exercise program in adults with systemic lupus erythematosus: protocol for a randomized controlled trial. Journal of Medical Internet Research Protocols 2020;9(11):1-11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7671835</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33141101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Additional references</Title><ReferenceList><Title>Abrah&#xe3;o 2016</Title><Reference><Citation>Abrah&#xe3;o MI, Gomiero AB, Peccin MS, Grande AJ, Trevisani VF. Cardiovascular training vs. resistance training for improving quality of life and physical function in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: a randomized controlled trial. Scandinavian Journal of Rheumatology 2016;45:197-201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26525835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Ali 2018</Title><Reference><Citation>Ali A, Sayyed Z, Ameer MA, Arif AW, Kiran F, Iftikhar A, et al. Systemic lupus erythematosus: an overview of the disease pathology and its management. Cureus 2018;10:1-13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6235637</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30443458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Askanase 2012</Title><Reference><Citation>Askanase A, Shum K, Mitnick H. Systemic lupus erythematosus: an overview. Social Work in Health Care 2012;51(7):576-86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22905974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Bogdanovic 2015</Title><Reference><Citation>Bogdanovic G, Stojanovich L, Djokovic A, Stanisavljevic N. Physical activity program is helpful for improving quality of life in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. Tohoku Journal of Experimental Medicine 2015;237:193-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26490344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Bossingham&#xa0;2003</Title><Reference><Citation>Bossingham D. Systemic lupus erythematosus in the far north of Queensland. Lupus 2003;12(4):327-31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12729060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Bostr&#xf6;m 2016</Title><Reference><Citation>Bostr&#xf6;m C, Elfving B, Dupr&#xe9; B, Opava CH, Lundberg IE, Jansson E. Effects of a one-year physical activity programme for women with systemic lupus erythematosus &#x2013; a randomized controlled study. Lupus 2016;25:602-16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26768748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Brunner 2010</Title><Reference><Citation>Brunner HI, Higgins GC, Klein-Gitelman MS. Minimal clinically important differences of disease activity indices in childhood-onset systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Care &amp; Research (Hoboken) 2010;62(7):950-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2916727</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20589695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Button 2013</Title><Reference><Citation>Button KS, Ioannidis JP, Mokrysz C, Nosek BA, Flint J, Robinson ES, et al. Power failure: why small sample size undermines the reliability of neuroscience. Nature Reviews. Neuroscience 2013;14(5):365-76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23571845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Campbell 2020</Title><Reference><Citation>Campbell M, McKenzie JE, Sowden A, Katikireddi SV, Brennan SE, Ellis S, et al. Synthesis Without Meta-analysis (SWiM) in systematic reviews: reporting guideline. BMJ 2020;368:1-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7190266</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31948937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Carvalho 2005</Title><Reference><Citation>Carvalho MR, Sato EI, Tebexreni AS, Heidecher RT, Schenkman S, Neto TL. Effects of supervised cardiovascular training program on exercise tolerance, aerobic capacity, and quality of life in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis and Rheumatism 2005;53(6):838-44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16342102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Da Hora 2019</Title><Reference><Citation>Da Hora TC, Lima K, Maciel RR. The effect of therapies on the quality of life of patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: a meta-analysis of randomized trials. Advance Rheumatology 2019;59(34):1-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31358064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Deeks 2020</Title><Reference><Citation>Deeks JJ, Higgins JP, Altman DG. Chapter 10: Analysing data and undertaking meta-analyses. In: Higgins JP, Thomas J, Chandler J, Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, et al, editor(s). Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions Version 6.1 (updated September 2020). Cochrane, 2020. Available from training.cochrane.org/handbook/archive/v6.1.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Del Pino&#x2010;Sedeno&#xa0;2016</Title><Reference><Citation>Del Pino-Sedeno T, Trujillo-Martin MM, Ruiz-Irastorza G, Cuellar-Pompa L, Pascual-Medina AM, Serrano-Aguilar P, et al. Effectiveness of nonpharmacologic interventions for decreasing fatigue in adults with systemic lupus erythematosus: a systematic review. Arthritis Care &amp; Research 2016;68(1):141-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26238554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Dos Reis&#x2010;Neto&#xa0; 2013</Title><Reference><Citation>Dos Reis-Neto ET, Da Silva AE, Monteiro CM, De Camargo LM, Sato EI. Supervised physical exercise improves endothelial function in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. Rheumatology 2013;52:2187-95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23970541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Doward 2009</Title><Reference><Citation>Doward LC, McKenna SP, Whalley D, Tennant A, Griffiths B, Emery P, et al. The development of the L-QoL: a quality-of-life instrument specific to systemic lupus erythematosus. Annals of the Rheumatic Diseases 2009;68:196-200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18385276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>FACIT group</Title><Reference><Citation>FACIT group. The Functional Assessment of Chronic Illness Therapy &#x2013; Fatigue (FACIT-F) scale: summary of development and validation. www.facit.org/FACITOrg/Questionnaires (accessed prior to 1 October 2021).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Fanouriakis 2019</Title><Reference><Citation>Fanouriakis A, Kostopoulou M, Alunno A, Aringer M, Bajema I, Boletis JN, et al. 2019 update of the EULAR recommendations for the management of systemic lupus erythematosus. Annals of the Rheumatic Diseases 2019;78:736-45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30926722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Furie 2009</Title><Reference><Citation>Furie RA, Petri MA, Wallace DJ, Ginzler EM, Merrill JT, Stohl W, et al. Novel evidence-based systemic lupus erythematosus responder index. Arthritis &amp; Rheumatology 2009;61(9):1143-51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2748175</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19714615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Ghogomu 2014</Title><Reference><Citation>Ghogomu EA, Maxwell LJ, Buchbinder R, Rader T, Pardo Pardo J, Johnston RV, et al. Updated method guidelines for Cochrane Musculoskeletal Group systematic reviews and meta-analyses. Journal of Rheumatology 2014;41(2):194-205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24293581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Goligher 2008</Title><Reference><Citation>Goligher EC, Pouchot J, Brant R, Kherani RB, Avi&#xf1;a-Zubieta JA, Lacaille D, et al. Minimal clinically important difference for 7 measures of fatigue in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. Journal of Rheumatology 2008;35:635-42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18322987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>GRADEpro GDT [Computer program]</Title><Reference><Citation>GRADEpro GDT. Hamilton (ON): McMaster University (developed by Evidence Prime), 2015. Available from www.gradepro.org.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Gu 2020</Title><Reference><Citation>Gu C, Zhao R, Zhang X, Gu Z, Zhou W, Guo J, et al. A meta-analysis of secondary osteoporosis in systemic lupus erythematosus: prevalence and risk factors. Archives of Osteoporosis 2020;15(1):1-12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31802295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Hay 1993</Title><Reference><Citation>Hay EM, Bacon PA, Gordon C, Isenberg DA, Maddison P, Snaith ML, et al. The BILAG index: a reliable and valid instrument for measuring clinical disease activity in systemic lupus erythematosus. Quarterly Journal of Medicine 1993;86(7):447-58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8210301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Higgins 2011</Title><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Altman DG, Sterne JA. Chapter 8: Assessing risk of bias in included studies. In: Higgins JP, Green S, editor(s). Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions Version 5.1.0 (updated March 2011). The Cochrane Collaboration, 2011. Available from training.cochrane.org/handbook/archive/v5.1/.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Higgins 2020a</Title><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Li T, Deeks JJ. Chapter 6: Choosing effect measures and computing estimates of effect. In: Higgins JP, Thomas J, Chandler J, Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, Welch VA, editor(s). Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions Version 6.1 (updated September 2020). Cochrane, 2020. Available from training.cochrane.org/handbook/archive/v6.1.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Higgins 2020b</Title><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Eldridge S, Li T. Chapter 23: Including variants on randomized trials. In: Higgins JP, Thomas J, Chandler J, Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, et al, editor(s). Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions Version 6.1 (updated September 2020). Cochrane, 2020. Available from training.cochrane.org/handbook/archive/v6.1.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Isenberg 2000</Title><Reference><Citation>Isenberg DA, Gordon C, BILAG Group, British Isles Lupus Assessment Group. From BILAG to BLIPS &#x2013; disease activity assessment in lupus past, present and future. Lupus 2000;9(9):651-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11199918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Kelley 2015</Title><Reference><Citation>Kelley GA, Kelley KS, Hootman JM. Effects of exercise on depression in adults with arthritis: a systematic review with meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Arthritis Research Therapy 2015;17(1):1-22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4467075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25645739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Lai 2011</Title><Reference><Citation>Lai J-S, Beaumont JL, Ogale S, Brunetta P, Cella D. Validation of the Functional Assessment of Chronic Illness Therapy &#x2013; Fatigue scale in patients with moderately to severely active systemic lupus erythematosus, participating in a clinical trial. Journal of Rheumatology 2011;38(4):672-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21239746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Leong &#xa0;2005</Title><Reference><Citation>Leong KP, Kong KO, Thong BY, Koh ET, Lian TY, Teh CL, et al. Development and preliminary validation of a Systemic Lupus Erythematosus-specific Quality-Of-Life instrument (SLEQOL). Rheumatology 2005;44:1267&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15797980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Leung 2011</Title><Reference><Citation>Leung YY, Zhu TY, Tam LS, Kun EW, Li EK. Minimal important difference and responsiveness to change of the SF-36 in patients with psoriatic arthritis receiving tumor necrosis factor-alpha blockers. Journal of Rheumatology 2011;38(9):2077-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21885524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Lu 2021</Title><Reference><Citation>Lu M-C, Koo M. Effects of exercise intervention on health-related quality of life in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: a systematic review and meta-analysis of controlled trials. Healthcare (Basel) 2021;9(1215):1-15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8468902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34574989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Manzi 1997</Title><Reference><Citation>Manzi S, Meilahn EN, Rairie JE, Conte CG, Medsger TA Jr, Jansen-McWilliams L, et al. Age-specific incidence rates of myocardial infarction and angina in women with systemic lupus erythematosus: comparison with the Framingham Study. American Journal of Epidemiology 1997;145(5):408-15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9048514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Margiotta 2018</Title><Reference><Citation>Margiotta DP, Basta F, Dolcini G, Batani V, Lo Vullo M, Vernuccio A, et al. Physical activity and sedentary behavior in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. PLOS One 2018;13(3):1-16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5837187</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29505598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>McElhone 2007</Title><Reference><Citation>McElhone K, Abbott J, Shelmerdine J, Bruce IN, Ahmad Y, Gordon C, et al. Development and validation of a disease-specific health-related quality of life measure, the LupusQol, for adults with systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis &amp; Rheumatology 2007;57:972&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17665467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>McElhone 2010</Title><Reference><Citation>McElhone K, Abbott J, Gray J, Williams A, Teh LS. Patient perspective of systemic lupus erythematosus in relation to health-related quality of life concepts: a qualitative study. Lupus 2010;19:1640-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20709719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>McElhone&#xa0;2016</Title><Reference><Citation>McElhone K, Abbott J, Sutton C, Mullen M, Lanyon P, Rahman A, et al. Sensitivity to change and minimal important differences of the LupusQoL in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Care &amp; Research 2016;68:1505-13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5053261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26816223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>McKenzie 2021</Title><Reference><Citation>McKenzie JE, Brennan SE, Ryan RE, Thomson HJ, Johnston RV. Chapter 9: Summarizing study characteristics and preparing for synthesis. In: Higgins JP, Thomas J, Chandler J, Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, et al, editor(s). Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions Version 6.2 (updated February 2021). Cochrane, 2021. Available from training.cochrane.org/handbook/archive/v6.2.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Metsios&#xa0;2020</Title><Reference><Citation>Metsios GS, Moe RH, Kitas GD. Exercise and inflammation. Best Practice Research &amp; Clinical Rheumatology 2020;34(2):1-12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32249021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Miossi 2012</Title><Reference><Citation>Miossi R, Benatti FB, L&#xfa;ciade de S&#xe1; Pinto A, Lima FR, Borba EF, Prado DM, et al. Using exercise training to counter balance chronotropic incompetence and delayed heart rate recovery in systemic lupus erythematosus: a randomized trial. Arthritis Care &amp; Research 2012;64:1159-66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22438298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Neill 2006</Title><Reference><Citation>Neill J, Belan I, Ried K. Effectiveness of non-pharmacological interventions for fatigue in adults with multiple sclerosis, rheumatoid arthritis, or systemic lupus erythematosus: a systematic review. Journal Advance Nursing 2006;56(6):617-35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17118041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Nikpour 2014</Title><Reference><Citation>Nikpour M, Bridge JA, Richter S. A systematic review of prevalence, disease characteristics and management of systemic lupus erythematosus in Australia: identifying areas of unmet need. Internal Medicine Journal 2014;44(12a):1170-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25169712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Nordin 2016</Title><Reference><Citation>Nordin A, Taft C, Lundgren-Nilsson A, Dencker A. Minimal important differences for fatigue patient reported outcome measures &#x2013; a systematic review. BMC Medical Research Methodology 2016;16(62):1-16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4937582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27387456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>O'Dwyer 2017</Title><Reference><Citation>O'Dwyer T, Durcan L, Wilson F. Exercise and physical activity in systemic lupus erythematosus: a systematic review with meta-analyses. Seminars in Arthritis and Rheumatism 2017;47(2):204-15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28477898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Page 2020</Title><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, Higgins JP, Sterne JA. Chapter 13: Assessing risk of bias due to missing results in a synthesis. In: Higgins JP, Thomas J, Chandler J, Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, et al, editor(s). Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions Version 6.1 (updated September 2020). Cochrane, 2020. Available from training.cochrane.org/handbook/archive/v6.1.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Page 2021</Title><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, Moher D, Bossuyt PM, Boutron I, Hoffmann TC, Mulrow CD, et al. PRISMA 2020 explanation and elaboration: updated guidance and exemplars for reporting systematic reviews. BMJ 2021;372:1-36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8005925</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33781993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Perandini 2012</Title><Reference><Citation>Perandini LA, De Sa-Pinto AL, Roschel H, Benatti FB, Lima FR, Bonfa E, et al. Exercise as a therapeutic tool to counteract inflammation and clinical symptoms in autoimmune rheumatic diseases. Autoimmunity Reviews 2012;12(2):218-24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22776785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Pescatello 2014</Title><Reference><Citation>Pescatello LS. ACSM's Guidelines for Exercise Testing and Prescription. 9th edition. Philadelphia (PA): Wolters Kluwer/Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins Health, 2014.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Petri 1999</Title><Reference><Citation>Petri M, Buyon J, Kim M. Classification and definition of major flares in SLE clinical trials. Lupus 1999;8(8):685-91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10568907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Petri 2005</Title><Reference><Citation>Petri M, Kim MY, Kalunian KC, Grossman J, Hahn BH, Sammaritano LR, et al, OC-SELENA Trial. Combined oral contraceptives in women with systemic lupus erythematosus. New England Journal of Medicine 2005;353(24):2550-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16354891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>PRISMA Group 2009</Title><Reference><Citation>Moher D, Liberati A, Tetzlaff J, Altman DG, The PRISMA Group. Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic Reviews and Meta-Analyses: the PRISMA statement. BMJ 2009;339:b2535.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3090117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21603045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Ramsey&#x2010;Goldman 2000</Title><Reference><Citation>Ramsey-Goldman R, Schilling EM, Dunlop D, Langman C, Greenland P, Thomas RJ, et al. A pilot study on the effects of exercise in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Care &amp; Research 2000;13(5):262-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14635294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>RevMan Web 2022 [Computer program]</Title><Reference><Citation>Review Manager Web (RevMan Web). Version 4.12.0. The Cochrane Collaboration, 2022. Available at revman.cochrane.org.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Robb&#x2010;Nicholson 1989</Title><Reference><Citation>Robb-Nicholson LC, Daltroy L, Eaton H, Gall V, Wright E, Hartley LH, et al. Effects of aerobic conditioning in lupus fatigue: a pilot study. British Journal of Rheumatology 1989;28:500-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2590802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Schoenfeld 2013</Title><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld R, Kasturi S, Costenbader KH. The epidemiology of atherosclerotic cardiovascular disease among patients with SLE: a systematic review. Seminars in Arthritis and Rheumatism 2013;43(1):77-95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23422269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Sch&#xfc;nemann 2020a</Title><Reference><Citation>Sch&#xfc;nemann HJ, Vist GE, Higgins JP, Santesso N, Deeks JJ, Glasziou P, et al. Chapter 15: Interpreting results and drawing conclusions. In: Higgins JP, Thomas J, Chandler J, Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, et al, editor(s). Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions Version 6.1 (updated September 2020). Cochrane, 2020. Available from training.cochrane.org/handbook/archive/v6.1.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Sch&#xfc;nemann 2022b</Title><Reference><Citation>Sch&#xfc;nemann HJ, Vist GE, Higgins JP, Santesso N, Deeks JJ, Glasziou P, et al, on behalf of the Cochrane GRADEing Methods Group. Chapter 15: Interpreting results and drawing conclusions. In: Higgins JP, Thomas J, Chandler J, Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, et al, editor(s). Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions Version 6.1 (updated September 2020). Cochrane, 2020. Available from training.cochrane.org/handbook/archive/v6.1.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Segasothy 2001</Title><Reference><Citation>Segasothy M, Phillips PA. Systemic lupus erythematosus in Aborigines and Caucasians in central Australia: a comparative study. Lupus 2001;10:439-44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11434580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Sieczkowskaa 2020</Title><Reference><Citation>Sieczkowskaa SM, Coimbrab DR, Vilarinoa GT, Andrade A. Effects of resistance training on the health-related quality of life of patients with rheumatic diseases: systematic review with meta-analysis and meta-regression. Seminars in Arthritis and Rheumatism 2020;50(2):342-53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31548048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Slade 2016</Title><Reference><Citation>Slade S, Dionne CE, Underwood M, Buchbinder R. Consensus on Exercise Reporting Template (CERT): explanation and elaboration statement. British Journal of Sports Medicine 2016;50:1428-37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27707738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Sutanto 2013</Title><Reference><Citation>Sutanto B, Singh-Grewal D, McNeil HP, O'Neill S, Craig JC, Jones J, et al. Experiences and perspectives of adults living with systemic lupus erythematosus: thematic synthesis of qualitative studies. Arthritis Care &amp; Research 2013;65(11):1752-65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23609952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Sveaas 2017</Title><Reference><Citation>Sveaas SH, Smedslund G, Birger HK, Dagfinrud H. Effect of cardiorespiratory and strength exercises on disease activity in patients with inflammatory rheumatic diseases: a systematic review and meta-analysis. British Journal of Sports Medicine 2017;51:1065-72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28455366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Tench&#xa0;2003</Title><Reference><Citation>Tench CM, McCarthy J, McCurdie I, White PD, D'Cruz DP. Fatigue in systemic lupus erythematosus: a randomized controlled trial of exercise. Rheumatology 2003;42(9):1050-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12730519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Wu 2017</Title><Reference><Citation>Wu M-L, Yu K-H, Tsai J-C. The effectiveness of exercise in adults with systemic lupus erythematosus: a systematic review and meta-analysis to guide evidence-based practice. Worldviews on Evidence-Based Nursing 2017;14(4):306-15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28432856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Yorganci 2020</Title><Reference><Citation>Yorganci E, Evans CJ, Johnson H, Barclay S, Murtagh FE, Yi D, et al. Understanding usual care in randomised controlled trials of complex interventions: a multi-method approach. Palliative Medicine 2020;34(5):667-79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7238505</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32081088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Yuen 2014</Title><Reference><Citation>Yuen HK, Cunningham MA. Optimal management of fatigue in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: a systematic review. Therapeutics and Clinical Risk Management 2014;10:775-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4199565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25328393</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>References to other published versions of this review</Title><ReferenceList><Title>Frade 2021</Title><Reference><Citation>Frade S, O'Neill S, Greene D, Cameron M. Exercise as adjunctive therapy for systemic lupus erythematosus. Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews 2021, Issue 10. Art. No: CD014816. [DOI: 10.1002/14651858.CD014816]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD014816</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10115181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37073886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>