<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37072893</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2163-0763</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>95</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The journal of trauma and acute care surgery</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Trauma Acute Care Surg</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Contemporary management and outcomes of penetrating colon injuries: Validation of the 2020 AAST Colon Organ Injury Scale.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>213</StartPage><EndPage>219</EndPage><MedlinePgn>213-219</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/TA.0000000000003969</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION">The American Association for the Surgery of Trauma Colon Organ Injury Scale (OIS) was updated in 2020 to include a separate OIS for penetrating colon injuries and included imaging criteria. In this multicenter study, we describe the contemporary management and outcomes of penetrating colon injuries and hypothesize that the 2020 OIS system correlates with operative management, complications, and outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">This was a retrospective study of patients presenting to 12 Level 1 trauma centers between 2016 and 2020 with penetrating colon injuries and Abbreviated Injury Scale score of &lt;3 in other body regions. We assessed the association of the new OIS with surgical management and clinical outcomes and the association of OIS imaging criteria with operative criteria. Bivariate analysis was done with &#x3c7; 2 , analysis of variance, and Kruskal-Wallis, where appropriate. Multivariable models were constructed in a stepwise selection fashion.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">We identified 573 patients with penetrating colon injuries. Patients were young and predominantly male; 79% suffered a gunshot injury, 11% had a grade V destructive injury, 19% required &#x2265;6 U of transfusion, 24% had an Injury Severity Score of &gt;15, and 42% had moderate-to-large contamination. Higher OIS was independently associated with a lower likelihood of primary repair, higher likelihood of resection with anastomosis and/or diversion, need for damage-control laparotomy, and higher incidence of abscess, wound infection, extra-abdominal infections, acute kidney injury, and lung injury. Damage control was independently associated with diversion and intra-abdominal and extra-abdominal infections. Preoperative imaging in 152 (27%) cases had a low correlation with operative findings ( &#x3ba; coefficient, 0.13).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">This is the largest study to date of penetrating colon injuries and the first multicenter validation of the new OIS specific to these injuries. While imaging criteria alone lacked strong predictive value, operative American Association for the Surgery of Trauma OIS colon grade strongly predicted type of interventions and outcomes, supporting use of this grading scale for research and clinical practice.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="LEVEL OF EVIDENCE">Prognostic and Epidemiological; Level III.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zeineddin</LastName><ForeName>Ahmad</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Department of Surgery (A.Z.), Howard University Hospital, Washington, DC; Department of Surgery (A.Z., N.K.D., R.A.K.), Shock Trauma Center, University of Maryland School of Medicine, Baltimore, Maryland; Department of Surgery (M.A., K.M.S.), Yale University, New Haven, Connecticut; Department of Surgery (G.J., B.M.), University of New Mexico Health Science Center, Albuquerque, New Mexico; Department of Surgery (M.C., A.C.S.), College of Medicine, University of Florida, Jacksonville, Florida; Department of Surgery (B.S.R., M.L.M.), University Hospitals Cleveland Medical Center, Cleveland, Ohio; Department of Surgery (N.D.M., C.L.J.), University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania; Department of Surgery (D.L., K.K.), Community Regional Medical Center, UCSF Fresno, Fresno, California; Department of Surgery (C.R.H., N.L.W.), Denver Health, Denver, Colorado; Department of Surgery (J.A.P.-Z., H.M.A.K.), Massachusetts General Hospital and Harvard Medical School, Boston, Massachusetts; Department of Surgery (W.A.M., L.N.H.), University of California San Diego Health, San Diego; Department of Surgery (G.T.T., K.B.S.), Scripps Memorial Hospital, La Jolla; and Department of Surgery (K.L.S.), Stanford University, Stanford, California.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tominaga</LastName><ForeName>Gail T</ForeName><Initials>GT</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Crandall</LastName><ForeName>Marie</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Almeida</LastName><ForeName>Mariana</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schuster</LastName><ForeName>Kevin M</ForeName><Initials>KM</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jawad</LastName><ForeName>Ghassan</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maqbool</LastName><ForeName>Baila</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sheffield</LastName><ForeName>Abby C</ForeName><Initials>AC</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dhillon</LastName><ForeName>Navpreet K</ForeName><Initials>NK</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Radow</LastName><ForeName>Brandon S</ForeName><Initials>BS</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moorman</LastName><ForeName>Matthew L</ForeName><Initials>ML</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Martin</LastName><ForeName>Niels D</ForeName><Initials>ND</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jacovides</LastName><ForeName>Christina L</ForeName><Initials>CL</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lowry</LastName><ForeName>Debra</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kaups</LastName><ForeName>Krista</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Horwood</LastName><ForeName>Chelsea R</ForeName><Initials>CR</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Werner</LastName><ForeName>Nicole L</ForeName><Initials>NL</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Proa&#xf1;o-Zamudio</LastName><ForeName>Jefferson A</ForeName><Initials>JA</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kaafarani</LastName><ForeName>Haytham M A</ForeName><Initials>HMA</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Marshall</LastName><ForeName>William A</ForeName><Initials>WA</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Haines</LastName><ForeName>Laura N</ForeName><Initials>LN</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schaffer</LastName><ForeName>Kathryn B</ForeName><Initials>KB</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Staudenmayer</LastName><ForeName>Kristan L</ForeName><Initials>KL</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kozar</LastName><ForeName>Rosemary A</ForeName><Initials>RA</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016448">Multicenter Study</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Trauma Acute Care Surg</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101570622</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2163-0755</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014950" MajorTopicYN="Y">Wounds, Penetrating</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000601" MajorTopicYN="N">surgery</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011379" MajorTopicYN="N">Prognosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014948" MajorTopicYN="Y">Wounds, Gunshot</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000601" MajorTopicYN="N">surgery</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015601" MajorTopicYN="N">Injury Severity Score</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000007" MajorTopicYN="Y">Abdominal Injuries</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000601" MajorTopicYN="N">surgery</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003106" MajorTopicYN="N">Colon</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000601" MajorTopicYN="N">surgery</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013898" MajorTopicYN="Y">Thoracic Injuries</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37072893</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/TA.0000000000003969</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">01586154-990000000-00341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Stone HH, Fabian TC. Management of perforating colon trauma. Randomization between primary closure and exteriorization. Ann Surg . 1979;190(4):430&#x2013;436.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pasquale M, Fabian TC. Practice management guidelines for trauma from the Eastern Association for the Surgery of Trauma. J Trauma . 1998;44(6):941&#x2013;947.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demetriades D, Murray JA, Chan L, Ordo&#xf1;ez C, Bowley D, Nagy KK, Cornwell EE 3rd, Velmahos GC, Mu&#xf1;oz N, Hatzitheofilou C, et al. Penetrating colon injuries requiring resection: diversion or primary anastomosis? An AAST prospective multicenter study. J Trauma . 2001;50(5):765&#x2013;775.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nelson R, Singer M. Primary repair for penetrating colon injuries. Cochrane Database Syst Rev . 2003;(3):CD002247.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cullinane DC, Jawa RS, Como JJ, Moore AE, Morris DS, Cheriyan J, Guillamondegui OD, Goldberg SR, Petrey L, Schaefer GP, et al. Management of penetrating intraperitoneal colon injuries: a meta-analysis and practice management guideline from the Eastern Association for the Surgery of Trauma. J Trauma Acute Care Surg . 2019;86(3):505&#x2013;515.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weinberg JA, Griffin RL, Vandromme MJ, Melton SM, George RL, Reiff DA, Kerby JD, Rue LW 3rd. Management of colon wounds in the setting of damage control laparotomy: a cautionary tale. J Trauma . 2009;67(5):929&#x2013;935.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ordo&#xf1;ez CA, Pino LF, Badiel M, S&#xe1;nchez AI, Loaiza J, Ballestas L, Puyana JC. Safety of performing a delayed anastomosis during damage control laparotomy in patients with destructive colon injuries. J Trauma . 2011;71(6):1512&#x2013;1517.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Georgoff P, Perales P, Laguna B, Holena D, Reilly P, Sims C. Colonic injuries and the damage control abdomen: does management strategy matter? J Surg Res . 2013;181(2):293&#x2013;299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dubose JJ, Scalea TM, Holcomb JB, Shrestha B, Okoye O, Inaba K, Bee TK, Fabian TC, Whelan J, Ivatury RR. Open abdominal management after damage-control laparotomy for trauma: a prospective observational American Association for the Surgery of Trauma multicenter study. J Trauma Acute Care Surg . 2013;74(1):113&#x2013;120.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anjaria DJ, Ullmann TM, Lavery R, Livingston DH. Management of colonic injuries in the setting of damage-control laparotomy: one shot to get it right. J Trauma Acute Care Surg . 2014;76(3):594&#x2013;600.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tatebe LC, Jennings A, Tatebe K, Handy A, Prajapati P, Smith M, Do T, Ogola GO, Gandhi RR, Duane TM, et al. Traumatic colon injury in damage control laparotomy &#x2014; a multicenter trial: is it safe to do a delayed anastomosis? J Trauma Acute Care Surg . 2017;82(4):742&#x2013;749.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore EE, Cogbill TH, Malangoni MA, Jurkovich GJ, Champion HR, Gennarelli TA, McAninch JW. Organ injury scaling, II: Pancreas, duodenum, small bowel, colon, and rectum. J Trauma . 1990;30(11):1427&#x2013;1429.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tominaga GT, Crandall M, Cribari C, Zarzaur BL, Bernstein M, Kozar RA. Organ injury scaling 2020 update: bowel and mesentery. J Trauma Acute Care Surg . 2021;91(3):e73&#x2013;e77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchao DP, Lewis MR, Strickland M, Benjamin ER, Wong MD, Demetriades D. Destructive colon injuries requiring resection: is colostomy ever indicated? J Trauma Acute Care Surg . 2022;92(6):1039&#x2013;1046.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller PR, Fabian TC, Croce MA, Magnotti LJ, Elizabeth Pritchard F, Minard G, Stewart RM. Improving outcomes following penetrating colon wounds: application of a clinical pathway. Ann Surg . 2002;235(6):775&#x2013;781.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demetriades D, Murray JA, Chan LS, Ordo&#xf1;ez C, Bowley D, Nagy KK, Cornwell EE 3rd, Velmahos GC, Mu&#xf1;oz N, Hatzitheofilou C, et al. Handsewn versus stapled anastomosis in penetrating colon injuries requiring resection: a multicenter study. J Trauma . 2002;52(1):117&#x2013;121.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharpe JP, Magnotti LJ, Weinberg JA, Parks NA, Maish GO, Shahan CP, Fabian TC, Croce MA. Adherence to a simplified management algorithm reduces morbidity and mortality after penetrating colon injuries: a 15-year experience. J Am Coll Surg . 2012;214(4):591&#x2013;597.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldberg SR, Henning J, Wolfe LG, Duane TM. Practice patterns for the use of antibiotic agents in damage control laparotomy and its impact on outcomes. Surg Infect (Larchmt) . 2017;18(3):282&#x2013;286.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeineddin A, Crandall M, Tominaga GT, Kozar RA. Validation of the American Association for the Surgery of Trauma Organ Injury Scale for penetrating colon injuries. Am Surg . 2022;88(7):1563&#x2013;1565.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>