<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37126423</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1540-8175</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>40</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Echocardiography (Mount Kisco, N.Y.)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Echocardiography</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Value of Autostrain LV in the study of left ventricular systolic function and synchronization in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>760</StartPage><EndPage>767</EndPage><MedlinePgn>760-767</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/echo.15562</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">There are relatively few studies investigating cardiac structural and functional abnormalities associated with systemic lupus erythematous (SLE). The long-term prognosis of SLE patients is closely related to the cardiovascular events caused by SLE. Accordingly, it is necessary to assess early myocardial systolic function and synchrony.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Overall, 90 patients with SLE were randomly selected from our outpatient and inpatient clinics and divided according to SLE Disease Activity Index (SLE-DAI-2000) scores: group A, stable (scores 0-4); group B, mildly active stage (scores 5-9); and group C, moderately active stage (scores &#x2265;10). Each group included 30 patients. Further, 30 sex- and age-matched healthy individuals who were referred for check-ups at the same period were selected as controls (group D). The minimum age for entry into the group was 17&#xa0;years old. Autostrain LV and three-dimensional quantitative analysis (3DQA) were applied to obtain left ventricular systolic function parameters, information on strain parameters, and correlations between parameters. Simultaneity parameters measured by Autostrain LV and 3DQA were tested for reproducibility.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">A two-by-two comparison of groups A-C showed that as the disease activity score increased, AP4LS%, AP2LS%, AP3LS%, and the LV mean overall longitudinal strain all gradually decreased, while LV longitudinal strain peak time standard deviation (Tls-SD) gradually increased, with all differences being statistically significant (p&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;.05). In groups A-C compared with controls, Tmsv-17-SD, Tmsv-17-Dif, Tmsv-17-SD%, and Tmsv-17-Dif% were all significantly prolonged (p&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;.05). Further, Tls-SD was positively correlated with Tmsv-17-SD and Tmsv-17-Dif, and there was good agreement between Autostrain and 3DQA for the measurement of left ventricular synchrony indexes, with Tmsv-17-Dif having the best repeatability (intraobserver interclass correlation coefficient (ICC)&#xa0;=&#xa0;.979; interobserver ICC&#xa0;=&#xa0;.848, p&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;.01).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">Autostrain LV can accurately detect changes in left ventricular myocardial strain in patients with SLE early in the disease, with simple operation. The 3DQA technique can quantitatively evaluate left ventricular systolic synchronization in patients with SLE, and Autostrain LV synchronization index measurements correlate significantly with 3DQA. Both methods are reproducible, but 3DQA is more sensitive to left ventricular synchronous motion changes.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Wanqing</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0771-7253</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ultrasound, The First Affiliated Hospital of Jinzhou Medical University, Jinzhou, Liaoning, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ge</LastName><ForeName>Lili</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ultrasound, The First Affiliated Hospital of Jinzhou Medical University, Jinzhou, Liaoning, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Yuhong</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0056-8862</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ultrasound, The First Affiliated Hospital of Jinzhou Medical University, Jinzhou, Liaoning, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>Yuhong LI</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Echocardiography</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8511187</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0742-2822</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018487" MajorTopicYN="Y">Ventricular Dysfunction, Left</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015203" MajorTopicYN="N">Reproducibility of Results</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016277" MajorTopicYN="N">Ventricular Function, Left</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006321" MajorTopicYN="N">Heart</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006337" MajorTopicYN="N">Heart Murmurs</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">automatic strain quantification</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">strain</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">synchronization</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">systemic lupus erythematosus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">three-dimensional quantitative analysis</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37126423</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/echo.15562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Hussain K, Gauto-Mariotti E, Cattoni HM, et&#xa0;al. A meta-analysis and systematic review of valvular heart disease in systemic lupus erythematosus and its association with antiphospholipid antibodies. J Clin Rheumatol. 2021;27:e525-e532.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tincani A, Rebaioli CB, Taglietti M, et&#xa0;al. Heart involvement in systemic lupus erythematosus, anti-phospholipid syndrome and neonatal lupus. Rheumatology (Oxford). 2006; 45(suppl 4):8-13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miner JJ, Kim AH. Cardiac manifestations of systemic lupus erythematosus. Rheum Dis Clin North Am. 2014;40:51-60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mavrogeni S, Koutsogeorgopoulou L, Dimitroulas T, et&#xa0;al. Complementary role of cardiovascular imaging and laboratory indices in early detection of cardiovascular disease in systemic lupus erythematosus. Lupus. 2017;26:227-236.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang F, Chen Y, Wu L, et&#xa0;al. Left heart function evaluation of patients with essential hypertension and paroxysmal atrial fibrillation by two-dimensional speckle tracking imaging combined with real-time three-dimensional ultrasound imaging. J Thorac Dis. 2021;13:322-333.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kitano T, Nabeshima Y, Negishi K, et&#xa0;al. Prognostic value of automated longitudinal strain measurements in asymptomatic aortic stenosis. Heart. 2020;107(7):578-584.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawakami H, Wright L, Nolan M, et&#xa0;al. Feasibility, reproducibility, and clinical implications of the novel fully automated assessment for global longitudinal strain. J Am Soc Echocardiogr. 2021;34(2):136-145.e2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elshafey WEH, Al Khoufi EA, Elmelegy EK. Effects of sacubitril/valsartan treatment on left ventricular myocardial torsion mechanics in patients with heart failure reduced ejection fraction 2D speckle tracking echocardiography. J Cardiovasc Echogr. 2021;31:59-67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muraru D, Spadotto V, Cecchetto A, et&#xa0;al. New speckle-tracking algorithm for right ventricular volume analysis from three-dimensional echocardiographic data sets: validation with cardiac magnetic resonance and comparison with the previous analysis tool. Eur Heart J Cardiovasc Imaging. 2016;17:1279-1289.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abraham NS, Hlatky MA, Antman EM, et&#xa0;al. ACCF/ACG/AHA 2010 Expert Consensus Document on the concomitant use of proton pump inhibitors and thienopyridines: a focused update of the ACCF/ACG/AHA 2008 expert consensus document on reducing the gastrointestinal risks of antiplatelet therapy and NSAID use: a report of the American College of Cardiology Foundation Task Force on Expert Consensus Documents. Circulation. 2010;122:2619-2633.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siller-Matula JM, Spiel AO, Lang IM, et&#xa0;al. Effects of pantoprazole and esomeprazole on platelet inhibition by clopidogrel. Am Heart J. 2009;157:148.e141-145.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li M, Zhao Y, Zhang Z, et&#xa0;al. 2020 Chinese guidelines for the diagnosis and treatment of systemic lupus erythematosus. Rheumatol Immunol Res. 2020;1(1):5-23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park DJ, Takahashi Y, Kang JH, et&#xa0;al. Anti-N-methyl-D-aspartate receptor antibodies are associated with fibromyalgia in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: a case-control study. Clin Exp Rheumatol. 2017;35(suppl 105):54-60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He J, Zhang X, Wei Y, et&#xa0;al. Low-dose interleukin-2 treatment selectively modulates CD4(+) T cell subsets in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. Nat Med. 2016;22:991-993.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azhar AS, Awlia OM, Muzaffer MA. Cardiovascular complications in paediatric-onset systemic lupus erythematosus in Saudi Arabian patients. Clin Exp Rheumatol. 2017;35:535-541.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x3001; Ramkumar S, Yang H, Wang Y, et&#xa0;al. Association of the active and passive components of left atrial deformation with left ventricular function. J Am Soc Echocardiogr. 2017;30:659-666.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koestenberger M, Friedberg MK, Ravekes W, et&#xa0;al. Non-invasive imaging for congenital heart disease: recent innovations in transthoracic echocardiography. J Clin Exp Cardiolog. 2012; suppl 8:2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaw JL, Ishimori ML, Sandhu V, et&#xa0;al. Myocardial tissue characterization with native myocardial T1 mapping in SLE patients with chest pain. J Cardiovasc Magn Reson. 2016;18:1-2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld SR, Kasturi S, Costenbader KH. The epidemiology of atherosclerotic cardiovascular disease among patients with SLE: a systematic review. Semin Arthritis Rheum. 2013;43:77-95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kjaergaard J, Snyder EM, Hassager C, et&#xa0;al. Impact of preload and afterload on global and regional right ventricular function and pressure: a quantitative echocardiography study. J Am Soc Echocardiogr. 2006;19:515-521.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collier P, Phelan D, Klein A. A test in context: myocardial strain measured by speckle-tracking echocardiography. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2017;69(8):1043-1056.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Li M, Liu Y, et&#xa0;al. Baseline characteristics and risk factors of pulmonary arterial hypertension in systemic lupus erythematosus patients. Medicine. 2016;95(10):e2761.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qian J, Wang Y, Huang C, et&#xa0;al. Survival and prognostic factors of systemic lupus erythematosus-associated pulmonary arterial hypertension: a PRISMA-compliant systematic review and meta-analysis. Autoimmun Rev. 2016;15(3):250-257.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hara H, Hasegawa H, Iwanaga M, et&#xa0;al. A case of the syndrome of inappropriate secretion of antidiuretic hormone (SIADH) associated with lupus erythematosus in the central nervous system. CEN Case Rep. 2013;2(1):17-22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Q, Deng Q, Huang J, et&#xa0;al. Evaluation of left ventricular mechanical dyssynchrony in patients with heart failure after myocardial infarction by real-time three-dimensional echocardiography. Saudi Med J. 2012;33:256-261.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wislowska M, Dere&#x144; D, Kochma&#x144;ski M, et&#xa0;al. Systolic and diastolic heart function in SLE patients. Rheumatol Int. 2009;29:1469-1476.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Divard G, Abbas R, Chenevier-Gobeaux C, et&#xa0;al. High-sensitivity cardiac troponin T is a biomarker for atherosclerosis in systemic lupus erythematous patients: a cross-sectional controlled study. Arthritis Res Ther. 2017;19(1):132.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&lt;"Periodical"&gt;31&lt;/number&gt;Sun X, Zhao B, Chen Y, et&#xa0;al. Preliminary results analysis for left ventricular systolic function in normal fetuses by automated cardiac motion quantitation. J Matern Fetal Neonatal Med. 2021;34(16):2701-2709.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buss SJ, Wolf D, Korosoglou G, et&#xa0;al. Myocardial left ventricular dysfunction in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: new insights from tissue Doppler and strain imaging. J Rheumatol. 2010;37:79-86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Villuendas R, Mart&#xed;nez-Morillo M, Junc&#xe0; G, et&#xa0;al. Usefulness of cardiac screening in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus and anti-Ro/SSA antibodies. Lupus. 2021;30:1596-1602.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan L, Lu MP, Wang JH, et&#xa0;al. Immunological pathogenesis and treatment of systemic lupus erythematosus. World J Pediatr. 2020;16:19-30.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>