<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37147022</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>08</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2053-8790</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>10</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>May</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Lupus science &amp; medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Lupus Sci Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Belimumab versus anifrolumab in adults with systemic lupus erythematosus: an indirect comparison of clinical response at 52 weeks.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e000907</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1136/lupus-2023-000907</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">To generate comparative efficacy evidence of belimumab versus anifrolumab in SLE that can inform treatment practices.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">The SLE Responder Index (SRI)-4 response at 52 weeks of belimumab versus anifrolumab was evaluated with an indirect treatment comparison. The evidence base consisted of randomised trials that were compiled through a systemic literature review.A feasibility assessment was performed to comprehensively compare the eligible trials and to determine the most appropriate indirect treatment comparison analysis method. A multilevel network meta-regression (ML-NMR) was implemented that adjusted for differences across trials in four baseline characteristics: SLE Disease Activity Index-2K, anti-double-stranded DNA antibody positive, low complement (C)3 and low C4. Additional analyses were conducted to explore if the results were robust to different sets of baseline characteristics included for adjustment, alternative adjustment methods and changes to the trials included in the evidence base.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">The ML-NMR included eight trials: five belimumab trials (BLISS-52, BLISS-76, NEA, BLISS-SC, EMBRACE) and three anifrolumab trials (MUSE, TULIP-1, TULIP-2). Belimumab and anifrolumab were comparable in terms of SRI-4 response (OR (95% credible interval), 1.04 (0.74-1.45)), with the direction of the point estimate slightly favouring belimumab. Belimumab had a 0.58 probability of being the more effective treatment. The results were highly consistent across all analysis scenarios.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Our results suggest that the SRI-4 response of belimumab and anifrolumab are similar at 52 weeks in the general SLE population, but the level of uncertainty around the point estimate means we cannot rule out the possibility of a clinically meaningful benefit for either treatment. It remains to be seen if specific groups of patients could derive a greater benefit from anifrolumab or from belimumab, and there is certainly an unmet need to identify robust predictors towards more personalised selection of available biological agents in SLE.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; Author(s) (or their employer(s)) 2023. Re-use permitted under CC BY-NC. No commercial re-use. See rights and permissions. Published by BMJ.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Neupane</LastName><ForeName>Binod</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Evidence Synthesis, Modeling &amp; Simulation, Evidera, St-Laurent, Quebec, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shukla</LastName><ForeName>Pragya</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Evidence Synthesis, Modeling &amp; Simulation, Evidera, St-Laurent, Quebec, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Slim</LastName><ForeName>Mahmoud</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Evidence Synthesis, Modeling &amp; Simulation, Evidera, St-Laurent, Quebec, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Neurosciences "Federico Ol&#xf3;riz", University of Granada, Granada, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Martin</LastName><ForeName>Amber</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Evidence Synthesis, Modeling &amp; Communication, Evidera, Waltham, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Petri</LastName><ForeName>Michelle</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1441-5373</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Rheumatology, Johns Hopkins University School of Medicine, Baltimore, Maryland, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bertsias</LastName><ForeName>George K</ForeName><Initials>GK</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5299-1406</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rheumatology, Clinical Immunology and Allergy, University of Crete School of Medicine, Crete, Greece.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Alfred H J</ForeName><Initials>AHJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Rheumatology, Department of Medicine, Washington University School of Medicine, Saint Louis, Missouri, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fanouriakis</LastName><ForeName>Antonis</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2696-031X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>First Department of Propaedeutic Internal Medicine, "Laikon" General Hospital, National Kapodistrian University of Athens Medical School, Athens, Greece.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Levy</LastName><ForeName>Roger A</ForeName><Initials>RA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6393-6031</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Specialty Care, Global Medical Affairs, GSK, Collegeville, Pennsylvania, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chauhan</LastName><ForeName>Deven</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Value Evidence and Outcomes, GSK, Brentford, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ballew</LastName><ForeName>Nick</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3507-0028</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Value Evidence and Outcomes, GSK, Collegeville, Pennsylvania, USA nick.g.ballew@gsk.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>P30 AR073752</GrantID><Acronym>AR</Acronym><Agency>NIAMS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>UL1 TR002345</GrantID><Acronym>TR</Acronym><Agency>NCATS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Lupus Sci Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101633705</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2053-8790</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>73B0K5S26A</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C511911">belimumab</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>38RL9AE51Q</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C582345">anifrolumab</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D061067">Antibodies, Monoclonal, Humanized</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012720" MajorTopicYN="N">Severity of Illness Index</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D061067" MajorTopicYN="N">Antibodies, Monoclonal, Humanized</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Antirheumatic Agents</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Biological Products</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Outcome Assessment, Health Care</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Therapeutics</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Competing interests: BN, PS, MS and AM are employees of Evidera, a part of Thermo Fisher Scientific. MP has received grant/research support from AstraZeneca, Aurinia, Eli Lilly, Exagen, GSK, Janssen and Thermo Fisher. MP has also received consulting fees from the BPR Scientific Advisory Committee, Alexion, Amgen, AnaptysBio, Argenx, AstraZeneca, Aurinia, AxDev, Biogen, Boston Pharmaceuticals, Caribou Biosciences, CVS Health, Eli Lilly, Gilead Biosciences, GSK, Idorsia Pharmaceuticals, Janssen, Kezar Life Sciences, Kira Pharmaceuticals, Momenta Pharmaceuticals, Nimbus Lakshmi, Proviant, Sanofi, SinoMab and UCB. MP has received speakers&#x2019; fees from Aurinia, MedShr and Arthros-FocusMedEd, and has received consulting fees for participation in a data safety monitoring board or advisory board for EMD Serono, Emergent Biosolutions, IQVIA and PPD Development. GKB has received consulting fees from Pfizer, Lilly and Novartis, and has received honorary fees from GSK, AstraZeneca, Pfizer, Novartis, Aenorasis, AbbVie and Lilly. GKB has also received a research grant from Pfizer. AHJK has received research support to Washington University from the National Institute of Arthritis and Musculoskeletal and Skin Diseases (grant number P30 AR073752), National Center for Advancing Translational Sciences (grant number UL1 TR002345), Leona M. and Harry B. Helmsley Charitable Trust, Rheumatology Research Foundation, and National Multiple Sclerosis Society, GSK, and Foghorn Therapeutics. AHJK has performed consultancy for Alexion Pharmaceuticals, ANI Pharmaceuticals, AstraZeneca, Aurinia Pharmaceuticals, Exagen Diagnostics, GSK, Kypha and Pfizer unrelated to this work. AHJK has received payment or honoraria (for lectures, presentations, speakers bureaus, manuscript writing or educational events) from AstraZeneca, Aurinia Pharmaceuticals, Exagen Diagnostics and GSK. AHJK has participated on a data safety monitoring board or advisory board for National Institutes of Health/National Institute of Arthritis and Musculoskeletal and Skin Diseases. AHJK has been a board member for the Rheumatology Research Foundation Scientific Advisory Board and the Lupus Foundation of America-Heartland Chapter, and president of the St Louis Rheumatology Association. AHJK is the inventor of patent number 11029318 with Kypha unrelated to this work. The funders had no role in the decision to publish or preparation of this manuscript. The content is solely the responsibility of the authors and does not necessarily represent the official views of Washington University, its affiliated academic health care centers, or the National Institutes of Health. AF has received honoraria and consulting fees from GSK, Aenorasis and AstraZeneca. AF has been a paid speaker for AbbVie, Amgen, Pfizer, Lilly, Genesis-Pharma, Novartis, UCB and Boehringer-Ingelheim. RAL, DC and NB are employees of GSK and hold stocks and shares in GSK.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37147022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10186457</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/lupus-2023-000907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10/1/e000907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Kaul A, Gordon C, Crow MK, et al. . Systemic lupus erythematosus. Nat Rev Dis Primers 2016;2:16039. 10.1038/nrdp.2016.39</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrdp.2016.39</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27306639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fanouriakis A, Kostopoulou M, Alunno A, et al. . 2019 update of the EULAR recommendations for the management of systemic lupus erythematosus. Ann Rheum Dis 2019;78:736&#x2013;45. 10.1136/annrheumdis-2019-215089</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/annrheumdis-2019-215089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30926722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill DD, Eudy AM, Egger PJ, et al. . Impact of systemic lupus erythematosus disease activity, hydroxychloroquine and NSAID on the risk of subsequent organ system damage and death: analysis in a single US medical centre. Lupus Sci Med 2021;8:e000446. 10.1136/lupus-2020-000446</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/lupus-2020-000446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8039259</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33832976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>GSK . Benlysta us prescribing information. Available: https://gskpro.com/content/dam/global/hcpportal/en_US/Prescribing_Information/Benlysta/pdf/BENLYSTA-PI-MG-IFU.PDF [Accessed Jul 2022].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levy RA, Gonzalez-Rivera T, Khamashta M, et al. . 10 years of belimumab experience: what have we learnt? Lupus 2021;30:1705&#x2013;21. 10.1177/09612033211028653</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/09612033211028653</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8564244</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34238087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Navarra SV, Guzm&#xe1;n RM, Gallacher AE, et al. . Efficacy and safety of belimumab in patients with active systemic lupus erythematosus: a randomised, placebo-controlled, phase 3 trial. Lancet 2011;377:721&#x2013;31. 10.1016/S0140-6736(10)61354-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(10)61354-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21296403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furie R, Petri M, Zamani O, et al. . A phase III, randomized, placebo-controlled study of belimumab, a monoclonal antibody that inhibits B lymphocyte stimulator, in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Rheum 2011;63:3918&#x2013;30. 10.1002/art.30613</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/art.30613</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5007058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22127708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stohl W, Schwarting A, Okada M, et al. . Efficacy and safety of subcutaneous belimumab in systemic lupus erythematosus: a fifty-two-week randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled study. Arthritis Rheumatol 2017;69:1016&#x2013;27. 10.1002/art.40049</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/art.40049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5434872</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28118533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang F, Bae S-C, Bass D, et al. . A pivotal phase III, randomised, placebo-controlled study of belimumab in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus located in China, Japan and South Korea. Ann Rheum Dis 2018;77:355&#x2013;63. 10.1136/annrheumdis-2017-211631</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/annrheumdis-2017-211631</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5867402</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29295825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riggs JM, Hanna RN, Rajan B, et al. . Characterisation of anifrolumab, a fully human anti-interferon receptor antagonist antibody for the treatment of systemic lupus erythematosus. Lupus Sci Med 2018;5:e000261. 10.1136/lupus-2018-000261</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/lupus-2018-000261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5890856</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29644082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morand EF, Furie R, Tanaka Y, et al. . Trial of anifrolumab in active systemic lupus erythematosus. N Engl J Med 2020;382:211&#x2013;21. 10.1056/NEJMoa1912196</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1912196</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31851795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furie R, Khamashta M, Merrill JT, et al. . Anifrolumab, an anti-interferon-&#x3b1; receptor monoclonal antibody, in moderate-to-severe systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis &amp; Rheumatology 2017;69:376&#x2013;86. 10.1002/art.39962</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/art.39962</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5299497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28130918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furie RA, Morand EF, Bruce IN, et al. . Type I interferon inhibitor anifrolumab in active systemic lupus erythematosus (TULIP-1): a randomised, controlled, phase 3 trial. The Lancet Rheumatology 2019;1:e208&#x2013;19. 10.1016/S2665-9913(19)30076-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2665-9913(19)30076-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dias S, Sutton AJ, Ades AE, et al. . Evidence synthesis for decision making 2: a generalized linear modeling framework for pairwise and network meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Med Decis Making 2013;33:607&#x2013;17. 10.1177/0272989X12458724</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0272989X12458724</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3704203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23104435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salanti G, Higgins JPT, Ades AE, et al. . Evaluation of networks of randomized trials. Stat Methods Med Res 2008;17:279&#x2013;301. 10.1177/0962280207080643</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0962280207080643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17925316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillippo DM, Ades AE, Dias S, et al. . Methods for population-adjusted indirect comparisons in health technology appraisal. Med Decis Making 2018;38:200&#x2013;11. 10.1177/0272989X17725740</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0272989X17725740</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5774635</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28823204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillippo DM, Dias S, Ades AE, et al. . Multilevel network meta-regression for population-adjusted treatment comparisons. J R Stat Soc Ser A Stat Soc 2020;183:1189&#x2013;210. 10.1111/rssa.12579</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/rssa.12579</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7362893</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32684669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruce IN, Golam S, Steenkamp J, et al. . Indirect treatment comparison of anifrolumab efficacy versus belimumab in adults with systemic lupus erythematosus. J Comp Eff Res 2022;11:765&#x2013;77. 10.2217/cer-2022-0040</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2217/cer-2022-0040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35546484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ballew N, Mian A, Levy RA, et al. . Letter to the editor: indirect treatment comparison of anifrolumab efficacy versus belimumab in adults with systemic lupus erythematosus. J Comp Eff Res 2023;12:e220106. 10.2217/cer-2022-0106</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2217/cer-2022-0106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10288950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36515082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillippo DM, Dias S, Ades AE, et al. . Assessing the performance of population adjustment methods for anchored indirect comparisons: a simulation study. Stat Med 2020;39:4885&#x2013;911. 10.1002/sim.8759</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/sim.8759</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8690023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33015906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Remiro-Az&#xf3;car A, Heath A, Baio G. Methods for population adjustment with limited access to individual patient data: a review and simulation study. Res Synth Methods 2021;12:750&#x2013;75. 10.1002/jrsm.1511</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jrsm.1511</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34196111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Remiro-Az&#xf3;car A, Heath A, Baio G. Parametric G-computation for compatible indirect treatment comparisons with limited individual patient data. Res Synth Methods 2022;13:716&#x2013;44. 10.1002/jrsm.1565</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jrsm.1565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9790405</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35485582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cochrane . Cochrane Handbook for systematic reviews of interventions. Available: https://training.cochrane.org/handbook/current [Accessed Oct 2022].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9715291</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35352103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, et al. . The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. BMJ 2021;372:n71. 10.1136/bmj.n71</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.n71</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8005924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33782057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cope S, Zhang J, Saletan S, et al. . A process for assessing the feasibility of a network meta-analysis: a case study of everolimus in combination with hormonal therapy versus chemotherapy for advanced breast cancer. BMC Med 2014;12:93. 10.1186/1741-7015-12-93</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1741-7015-12-93</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4077675</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24898705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ginzler E, Guedes Barbosa LS, D&#x2019;Cruz D, et al. . Phase III/IV, randomized, fifty-two-week study of the efficacy and safety of belimumab in patients of black African ancestry with systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Rheumatol 2022;74:112&#x2013;23. 10.1002/art.41900</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/art.41900</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9300099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34164944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillippo DM. Multinma: Bayesian network meta-analysis of individual and aggregate data. R package version 0.5.0. Available: https://zenodo.org/record/7033094#.Y8bhAHb7Q2w [Accessed Oct 2022].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Signorovitch JE, Sikirica V, Erder MH, et al. . Matching-adjusted indirect comparisons: a new tool for timely comparative effectiveness research. Value Health 2012;15:940&#x2013;7. 10.1016/j.jval.2012.05.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jval.2012.05.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22999145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillippo DM, Ades T, Dias S, et al. . Nice dsu technical support document 18: methods for population-adjusted indirect comparisons in submissions to NICE. Available: https://research-information.bris.ac.uk/ws/portalfiles/portal/94868463/Population_adjustment_TSD_FINAL.pdf [Accessed Oct 2022].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ballew N, Mian A, Levy RA, et al. . Letter to the editor: indirect treatment comparison of anifrolumab efficacy versus belimumab in adults with systemic lupus erythematosus. J Comp Eff Res 2023;12. 10.2217/cer-2022-0106</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2217/cer-2022-0106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10288950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36515082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruce IN, Golam S, Steenkamp J, et al. . Letter in reply: indirect treatment comparison of anifrolumab efficacy versus belimumab in adults with systemic lupus erythematosus. J Comp Eff Res 2023;12:e220192. 10.2217/cer-2022-0192</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2217/cer-2022-0192</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10288956</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36515083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillippo DM, Dias S, Ades AE, et al. . Validating the assumptions of population adjustment: application of multilevel network meta-regression to a network of treatments for plaque psoriasis. Med Decis Making 2023;43:53&#x2013;67. 10.1177/0272989X221117162</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0272989X221117162</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9742635</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35997006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy C-L, Yee C-S, Gordon C, et al. . From BILAG to BILAG-based combined lupus assessment-30 years on. Rheumatology (Oxford) 2016;55:1357&#x2013;63. 10.1093/rheumatology/kev387</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/rheumatology/kev387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26589244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furie R, Wang L, Illei G, et al. . Systemic Lupus Erythematosus (SLE) Responder Index response is associated with global benefit for patients with SLE. Lupus 2018;27:955&#x2013;62. 10.1177/0961203318758506</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0961203318758506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29460699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thanou A, Chakravarty E, James JA, et al. . Which outcome measures in SLE clinical trials best reflect medical judgment? Lupus Sci Med 2014;1:e000005. 10.1136/lupus-2013-000005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/lupus-2013-000005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4225744</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25396057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Vollenhoven R, Askanase AD, Bomback AS, et al. . Conceptual framework for defining disease modification in systemic lupus erythematosus: a call for formal criteria. Lupus Sci Med 2022;9:e000634. 10.1136/lupus-2021-000634</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/lupus-2021-000634</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8961173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35346982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>