<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37147860</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>04</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1556-4029</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>68</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of forensic sciences</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Forensic Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Ballistic impact of hollow-point ammunition on porcine bone.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1121</StartPage><EndPage>1132</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1121-1132</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/1556-4029.15273</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Identifying failure mechanisms in skeletal tissue allows a deeper understanding of the effects of specific projectile impacts on bone. While ballistic trauma in flat bones is largely researched, knowledge of how long bones react to gunshot impacts is limited in the literature. The impacts of deforming ammunition appear to produce higher levels of fragmentation; however, these have not been studied in depth. This study compares the damage to femora bone by HP 0.357 and 9&#x2009;mm projectiles constructed with both full and semi-metal jackets. Impact experiments were undertaken on a single-stage light gas gun involving the use of a high-speed video camera and full reconstruction of the bones to ascertain fracture patterns occurring in the femora. Higher degrees of fragmentation are likened to the presence of semi-jacketed HP projectiles than jacketed HP projectiles. The observations of external facing beveled edges are believed to be associated with the increased separation of the jacket and lead core of projectiles. Additionally, experimentation has shown that the amount of kinetic energy lost postimpact is likely related to the presence or the absence of a metal jacket on an HP projectile. The observed data, therefore, suggest that the composition, rather than the configuration, of a projectile affects the type and extent of the damage.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Authors. Journal of Forensic Sciences published by Wiley Periodicals LLC on behalf of American Academy of Forensic Sciences.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Watson</LastName><ForeName>Kayla E</ForeName><Initials>KE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cranfield Forensic Institute, Cranfield University, Defence Academy of the United Kingdom, Shrivenham, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Henwood</LastName><ForeName>Bailey J</ForeName><Initials>BJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cranfield Forensic Institute, Cranfield University, Defence Academy of the United Kingdom, Shrivenham, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hewins</LastName><ForeName>Katherine</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cranfield Forensic Institute, Cranfield University, Defence Academy of the United Kingdom, Shrivenham, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Roberts</LastName><ForeName>Andrew</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Technical Services, Cranfield University, Defence Academy of the United Kingdom, Shrivenham, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hazael</LastName><ForeName>Rachael</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cranfield Forensic Institute, Cranfield University, Defence Academy of the United Kingdom, Shrivenham, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>Cranfield University</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Forensic Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0375370</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0022-1198</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013552" MajorTopicYN="N">Swine</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005389" MajorTopicYN="Y">Firearms</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D044709" MajorTopicYN="N">Forensic Ballistics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014948" MajorTopicYN="Y">Wounds, Gunshot</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D050723" MajorTopicYN="Y">Fractures, Bone</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001842" MajorTopicYN="N">Bone and Bones</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ballistic trauma</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bone trauma</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">firearms</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fracture analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hollow point</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">jacketed bullet</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37147860</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1556-4029.15273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>DiMaio VJM. Gunshot wounds: practical aspects of firearms, ballistics and forensic techniques. 3rd ed. CRC Press; 2016. p. 14-23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berryman HE. A systematic approach to the interpretation of gunshot trauma to the cranium. Forensic Sci Int. 2019;301:306-17. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.forsciint.2019.05.019</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fragkouli K, Hakeem EA, Bulut O, Simmons T. The effect of range and ammunition type on fracture patterns in porcine postcranial flat bones. J Forensic Leg Med. 2018;53:1-12. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jflm.2017.10.004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langley NR. An anthropological analysis of gunshot wounds to the chest. J Forensic Sci. 2007;52(3):532-7. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1556-4029.2007.00413.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ubelaker DH. The remains of Dr. Carl Austin Weiss: anthropological analysis. J Forensic Sci. 1996;41(1):60-79. https://doi.org/10.1520/JFS13898J</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Penn-Barwell JG, Brown KV, Fries CA. High velocity gunshot injuries to the extremities: management on and off the battlefield. Curr Rev Musculoskelet Med. 2015;8(3):312-7. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12178-015-9289-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gitajn L, Perdue P, Hardcastle J, O'Toole RV. Location of civilian ballistic femoral fracture indicates likelihood of arterial injury. Injury. 2014;45:1637-42. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.injury.2014.05.020</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galloway A, Zephro L. Skeletal trauma analysis of the lower extremity. In: Rich J, Dean DE, Powers RH, editors. Forensic medicine of the lower extremity: human identification and trauma analysis of the thigh, leg and foot. The Human Press Inc; 2005. p. 253-77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henwood BJ, Oost TS, Fairgrieve SI. Bullet caliber and type categorization from gunshot wounds in sus scrofa [Linnaeus] long bone. J Forensic Sci. 2019;64(4):1139-44. https://doi.org/10.1111/1556-4029.14004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paschall A, Ross AH. Bone mineral density and wounding capacity of handguns: implications of estimation of caliber. Int J Leg Med. 2017;131:161-6. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00414-016-1420-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hide S's. Soft-nosed vs solid alloy bullet. https://www.snipershide.com/shooting/threads/soft-nosed-vs-solid-alloy-bullet-pros-cons.6956534/. Accessed August 19, 2022</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith O, Symes S, Berryman H, LeVaughn M. Characteristic features of entrance wounds from hollow-point bullets. J Forensic Sci. 1993;38(2):323-6. https://doi.org/10.1520/JFS13411J</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kneubuehl BP. Wound ballistics of bullets and fragments. In: Kneubuehl BP, editor. Wound ballistics: basics and applications. 3rd ed. Berlin/Heidelberg, Germany: Springer-Verlag; 2008. p. 163-252.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rickman JM, Smith MJ. Scanning electron microscope analysis of gunshot defects to bone: underutilized source of information on ballistic trauma. J Forensic Sci. 2014;59(6):1473-86. https://doi.org/10.1111/1556-4029.12522</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harger JH, Huelke DF. Femoral fractures produced by projectiles: the effects of mass and diameter on target damage. J Biomech. 1970;3:487-93. https://doi.org/10.1016/0021-9290[70]90058-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huelke DF, Harger JH, Buege LJ, Dingman HG, Harger DR. An experimental study in bio-ballistics: femoral fractures produced by projectiles. J Biomech. 1968;1:97-105. https://doi.org/10.1016/0021-9290[68]90012-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huelke DF, Harger JH, Buege LJ, Dingman HG. An experimental study in bio-ballistics: femoral fractures produced by projectiles-II shaft impacts. J Biomech. 1986;1:313-21. https://doi.org/10.1016/0021-9290[68]90025-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galloway A. Broken bones: anthropological analysis of blunt force trauma. Charles C Thomas Publisher, LTD.; 1999. p. 52-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen H, Kugel C, May H, Medlej B, Stein D, Slon V, et al. The influence of impact direction and axial loading on the bone fracture pattern. Forensic Sci Int. 2017;277:197-206. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.forsciint.2017.05.015</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowyer GW, Rossiter ND. Management of gunshot wounds of the limbs. J Bone Jt Surg. 1997;79-B(6):1031-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hillier ML, Bell LS. Differentiating human bone from animal bone: a review of histological methods. J Forensic Sci. 2017;52(2):249-63. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1556-4029.2006.00368.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quatrehomme G, Is&#xe7;an MY. Analysis of beveling in gunshot entrance wounds. Forensic Sci Int. 1998;92:45-60. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0379-0738[98]00030-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coe JI. External beveling of entrance wounds by handguns. American J Forensic Med Path. 1982;3(3):215-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peterson BL. External beveling of cranial gunshot entrance wounds. J Forensic Sci. 1991;36(5):1592-5. https://doi.org/10.1520/JFS13181J</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amadasi A, Mazzarelli D, Merli D, Brandone A, Cattaneo C. Characteristics and frequency of chipping effects in near-contact gunshot wounds. J Forensic Sci. 2017;62(3):786-90. https://doi.org/10.1111/1556-4029.13312</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spitz WU. Injury by gunfire: part I. gunshot wounds. In: Spitz WU, Fisher RS, editors. Medicolegal investigation of death: guidelines for the application of pathology to crime investigation. 4th ed. Charles C Thomas Publisher Ltd.; 1980. p. 216-94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behrensmeyer AK. Taphonomic and ecologic information from bone weathering. Paleobiology. 1978;4(2):150-62. https://doi.org/10.1017/S0094837300005820</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thurner PJ, Erickson B, Jungmann R, Schriock Z, Weaver JC, Fantner GE, et al. High-speed photography of compressed human trabecular bone correlates whitening to microscopic damage. Eng Fract Mech. 2007;74:1928-41. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.engfracmech.2006.05.024</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szab&#xf3; ME, Zekonyte J, Katsamenis OL, Taylor M, Thurner PJ. Similar damage initiation but different failure behaviour in trabecular and cortical bone tissue. J Mech Behav Biomed Mat. 2011;4:1787-96. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmbbm.2011.05.036</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hornady Manufacturing, Inc. XTP&#xae; Extreme Terminal Performance. https://www.hornady.com/bullets/handgun/38-cal-357-158-gr-xtp#!/. Accessed April 15, 2020</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bullets S. 9mm 125 GR. JHP. https://www.sierrabullets.com/product/9-mm-355-125-gr-jhp/. Accessed April 15, 2020</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaye B, Randall C, Walsh D, Hansma P. The effects of freezing on the mechanical properties of bone. Open Bone J. 2012;4:14-9. https://doi.org/10.2174/1876525401204010014</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hale A, Ross A. The impact of freezing on bone mineral density: implications for forensic research. J Forensic Sci. 2017;62(2):339-404. https://doi.org/10.1111/1556-4029.13273</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The R Foundation. The R project for statistical computing [computer program]. 4.0.2 version. https://www.r-project.org. Accessed April 24, 2023</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hart G. Fracture pattern interpretation in the skull: differentiating blunt trauma from ballistics trauma using concentric fractures. J&#xa0;Forensic Sci. 2005;50(6):1276-81. https://doi.org/10.1520/JFS2004219</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>