<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37140198</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1756-185X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of rheumatic diseases</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Rheum Dis</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Immunosuppression for the treatment of pulmonary hypertension in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: A&#xa0;systematic review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1022</StartPage><EndPage>1028</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1022-1028</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/1756-185X.14706</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To conduct a systematic review with meta-analysis to determine the effects of immunosuppression on Group 1 Pulmonary Arterial Hypertension in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We searched Medline, Embase, Web of Science, Clinicaltrials.gov, and Cochrane Central Register of Controlled Trials (CENTRAL) with a search strategy developed by a medical librarian. We included retrospective, cross-sectional, case-control, prospective studies, and randomized controlled trials (RCTs) in our analysis and only included studies that contained data for patients with SLE. We included any immunosuppressive agents (including but not limited to cyclophosphamide, glucocorticoids, mycophenolate mofetil, azathioprine, and rituximab) We assessed for risk of bias and certainty of evidence. Outcomes included hemodynamics (as measured by pulmonary arterial hypertension), functional status, 6&#x2009;minute walk test (6MWT), quality of life, mortality, and serious adverse events.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">We included three studies. One RCT and two single-arm interventional observational studies. The RCT had a high risk of bias whereas the two single-arm interventional studies were graded as fair quality. Meta-analysis could not be conducted because of insufficient data. The RCT showed significant improvements in hemodynamics (as measured by pulmonary arterial pressures) and functional status. One observational study showed improvements in hemodynamics, functional status, and 6MWT. There were insufficient data for serious adverse events, mortality, and quality of life.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Despite a high prevalence and with a poor prognosis, there is a paucity of data for the role of immunosuppression in the treatment of Group 1 Pulmonary Arterial Hypertension in SLE. More high-quality studies are needed, especially to investigate serious adverse events and quality of life.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 Asia Pacific League of Associations for Rheumatology and John Wiley &amp; Sons Australia, Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bruera</LastName><ForeName>Sebastian</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3027-9287</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Section of Immunology, Allergy and Rheumatology, Baylor College of Medicine, Houston, Texas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sreedhar</LastName><ForeName>Arsha</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Emergency Medicine, McGovern Medical School, Houston, Texas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Agarwal</LastName><ForeName>Sandeep K</ForeName><Initials>SK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Section of Immunology, Allergy and Rheumatology, Baylor College of Medicine, Houston, Texas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Muthukumar</LastName><ForeName>Varsha</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of General Medicine, Baylor College of Medicine, Houston, Texas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Geng</LastName><ForeName>Yimin</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Medical Library, The University of Texas MD Anderson Cancer Center, Houston, Texas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lopez-Olivo</LastName><ForeName>Maria A</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Services Research, The University of Texas MD Anderson Cancer Center, Houston, Texas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Rheum Dis</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101474930</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1756-1841</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D007166">Immunosuppressive Agents</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006976" MajorTopicYN="Y">Hypertension, Pulmonary</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000081029" MajorTopicYN="Y">Pulmonary Arterial Hypertension</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007166" MajorTopicYN="N">Immunosuppressive Agents</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000139" MajorTopicYN="N">chemically induced</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007165" MajorTopicYN="N">Immunosuppression Therapy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D064887" MajorTopicYN="N">Observational Studies as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">infections</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pulmonary hypertension</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">systemic lupus erythematosus</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37140198</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1756-185X.14706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Chen H-A, Hsu T-C, Yang S-C, et al. Incidence and survival impact of pulmonary arterial hypertension among patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: a nationwide cohort study. Arthritis Res Ther. 2019;21:82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qian J, Li M, Zhang X, et al. Long-term prognosis of patients with systemic lupus erythematosus-associated pulmonary arterial hypertension: CSTAR-PAH cohort study. Eur Respir J. 2019;53:1800081.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qian J, Wang Y, Huang C, et al. Survival and prognostic factors of systemic lupus erythematosus-associated pulmonary arterial hypertension: a PRISMA-compliant systematic review and meta-analysis. Autoimmun Rev. 2016;15:250-257.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGoon MD, Miller DP. REVEAL: a contemporary US pulmonary arterial hypertension registry. Eur Respir Rev. 2012;21:8-18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tselios K, Gladman DD, Urowitz MB. Systemic lupus erythematosus and pulmonary arterial hypertension: links, risks, and management strategies. Open Access Rheumatol. 2017;9:1-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P&#xe9;rez-Pe&#xf1;ate GM, R&#xfa;a-Figueroa I, Juli&#xe1;-Serd&#xe1; G, et al. Pulmonary arterial hypertension in systemic lupus erythematosus: prevalence and predictors. J Rheumatol. 2016;43:323-329.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia YK, Tu SH, Hu YH, et al. Pulmonary hypertension in systemic lupus erythematosus: a systematic review and analysis of 642 cases in Chinese population. Rheumatol Int. 2013;33:1211-1217.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhala A. Pulmonary arterial hypertension in systemic lupus erythematosus: current status and future direction. Clin Dev Immunol. 2012;2012:854941.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bazan IS, Mensah KA, Rudkovskaia AA, et al. Pulmonary arterial hypertension in the setting of scleroderma is different than in the setting of lupus: a review. Respir Med. 2018;134:42-46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyamichi-Yamamoto S, Fukumoto Y, Sugimura K, et al. Intensive immunosuppressive therapy improves pulmonary hemodynamics and long-term prognosis in patients with pulmonary arterial hypertension associated with connective tissue disease. Circ J. 2011;75:2668-2674.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson SR, Granton JT. Pulmonary hypertension in systemic sclerosis and systemic lupus erythematosus. Eur Respir Rev. 2011;20:277-286.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JPT, James Thomas, Chandler J, Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, Welch VA (eds). Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions version 6.3: Cochrane. 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, et al. The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. BMJ. 2021;372:n71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen HH, Lin CH, Hsieh TY, Chen DY, Ying JC, Chao WC. Factors associated with incident severe pulmonary arterial hypertension in systemic autoimmune rheumatic diseases: a nationwide study. Rheumatology (Oxford). 2021;60:5351-5361.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasuoka H, Shirai Y, Tamura Y, Takeuchi T, Kuwana M. Predictors of favorable responses to immunosuppressive treatment in pulmonary arterial hypertension associated with connective tissue disease. Circ J. 2018;82:546-554.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu C, Chen J, Gao Y, Deng B, Liu K. Endothelin receptor antagonists for pulmonary arterial hypertension. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2021;3:Cd004434.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guyatt GH, Oxman AD, Vist GE, et al. GRADE: an emerging consensus on rating quality of evidence and strength of recommendations. BMJ. 2008;336:924-926.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell M, McKenzie JE, Sowden A, et al. Synthesis without meta-analysis (SWiM) in systematic reviews: reporting guideline. BMJ. 2020;368:l6890.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez-Lopez L, Cardona-Mu&#xf1;oz EG, Celis A, et al. Therapy with intermittent pulse cyclophosphamide for pulmonary hypertension associated with systemic lupus erythematosus. Lupus. 2004;13:105-112.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kommireddy S, Bhyravavajhala S, Kurimeti K, et al. Pulmonary arterial hypertension in systemic lupus erythematosus may benefit by addition of immunosuppression to vasodilator therapy: an observational study. Rheumatology (Oxford). 2015;54:1673-1679.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hernandez-Sanchez J, Harlow L, Church C, et al. Clinical trial protocol for TRANSFORM-UK: a therapeutic open-label study of tocilizumab in the treatment of pulmonary arterial hypertension. Pulm Circ. 2018;8:2045893217735820.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiaohong W. Clinical research on treatment of pulmonary arterial hypertension associated with connective tissue disease by Mycophenolate mofetil. International Clinical Trials Registry Platform ID - ChiCTR-TRC-14004894 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding Y, Qian J, Zhang S, et al. Immunosuppressive therapy in patients with connective tissue disease-associated pulmonary arterial hypertension: a systematic review. Int J Rheum Dis. 2022;25:982-990.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>