<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37145055</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>08</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1307-7945</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>29</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>May</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Ulusal travma ve acil cerrahi dergisi = Turkish journal of trauma &amp; emergency surgery : TJTES</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Ulus Travma Acil Cerrahi Derg</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The correlation between hemostatic blood parameters and sepsis in patients with gunshot wounds referred to a training and research hospital.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>605</StartPage><EndPage>612</EndPage><MedlinePgn>605-612</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.14744/tjtes.2023.37734</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">War injuries are different among the causes of trauma compared to cases in normal life. Patients with multi-trauma due to war injury are prone to develop infective complications such as sepsis or septic shock. Septic complications are one of the leading causes of late death in multi-trauma patients. Prompt, appropriate, and effective management of sepsis has been shown to prevent multiorgan dysfunction and improve mortality and clinical outcomes. However, there is no ideal biomarker to predict sepsis. The aim of this study was to determine whether there is a correlation between hemostatic blood parameters and sepsis in patients with gunshot wounds (GSW).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This descriptive study was conducted as a retrospective analysis of patients who were referred to the adult emergency department of a training and research hospital between October 1, 2016, and December 31, 2017, with a diagnosis of GSW and who developed sepsis (n=56) and did not develop sepsis (n=56) during follow-up. Demographic data such as age, sex, and blood parameters obtained from the hospital information system in the emergency department were recorded for each case. The statistical difference in hemostatic blood parameters between the two groups with and without sepsis was evaluated with Statistical Package for the Social Sciences 20.0 program.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The mean age of the patients was 26.9&#xb1;6.67. All of the patients were male. Of the patients who developed sepsis, 57% (n=32) were injured with improvised explosive devices (IEDs), 30% (n=17) were injured with firearms and when the anatomical injury sites were analyzed, 64% (n=36) had multiple injuries. In patients who did not develop sepsis, 48% (n=27) had IED, 43% (n=24) had GSW and 48% (n=27) had multiple injuries and 32% (n=18) had extremity injuries. Among the hemostatic blood parameters, platelet count (PLT), PTZ, INR, and Ca values showed a statistically significant difference between patients with and without sepsis, and when analyzed with the receiver operating characteristics curve, PTZ and INR showed the best diagnostic performance compared to the tested values.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Increased PTZ and INR values and decreased Ca and PLT values in patients with GSW may alert clinicians to sepsis and direct them to initiate or change antibiotic therapy.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Can</LastName><ForeName>Derya</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dr. Derya Can Clinic, Ankara-T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ery&#x131;lmaz</LastName><ForeName>Mehmet</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of General Surgery, University of Health Sciences, G&#xfc;lhane Training and Research Hospital, Ankara-T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><VernacularTitle>Ate&#x15f;li silah yaralanmas&#x131; nedeniyle bir e&#x11f;itim ve ara&#x15f;t&#x131;rma hastanesine sevk edilen yaral&#x131;lar&#x131;n hemostatik kan parametreleri ile sepsis tablolar&#x131; aras&#x131;ndaki korelasyon.</VernacularTitle></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Turkey</Country><MedlineTA>Ulus Travma Acil Cerrahi Derg</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101274231</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1306-696X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D006490">Hemostatics</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014948" MajorTopicYN="Y">Wounds, Gunshot</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000601" MajorTopicYN="N">surgery</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006490" MajorTopicYN="Y">Hemostatics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018805" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sepsis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009104" MajorTopicYN="Y">Multiple Trauma</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006761" MajorTopicYN="N">Hospitals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement><b>Conflict of Interest:</b> None declared.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37145055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10277328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14744/tjtes.2023.37734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Baykan N, Durukan P, Salt O, Yakar S, Kantar Y, Kaymaz ND, et al. Examination of geriatric trauma patients presenting to the emergency department. Phnx Med J. 2022;4:22&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pekdemir M, Cete Y, Eray O, Atilla R, Cevik AA, Topuzo&#x11f;lu A. Determination of the epidemiological characteristics of the trauma patients. Ulus Travma Derg. 2000;6:250&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11813481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soto JM, Zhang Y, Huang JH, Feng DX. An overview of the American trauma system. Chin J Traumatol. 2018;21:77&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5911730</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29605432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atescelik M, Gurger M. Evaluation of patients applied to emergency department with penetrating trauma. Konuralp Med J. 2014;6:40&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turgut K, Gur A, Guven T, Oguzturk H. Evaluation of factors related to mortality caused by firearm injury:A retrospective analysis from Malatya, Turkey. Arch Iran Med. 2019;22:80&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30980643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meral O, Saglam C, Gullupinar B, Akturk OE, Beden S, Parlak I. Investigation of firearm injury cases presented to training and research hospital's emergency service. Ulus Travma Acil Cerrahi Derg. 2020;26:74&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31942730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ertekin A. Analysis of patients admitted to the emergency department with gunshot wounds. J Surg Med. 2021;5:482&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eitze S, Fleischmann-Struzek C, Betsch C, Reinhart K. The vaccination 60+study group Determinants of sepsis knowledge:A representative survey of the elderly population in Germany. Crit Care. 2018;22:273.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6204268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30368239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dugani S, Veillard J, Kissoon N. Reducing the global burden of sepsis. CMAJ. 2017;189:E2&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5224944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28246252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aslankoc R, Gumral N, Cevik D. Investigation of knowledge and perceptions of health professionals about sepsis. Med J SDU. 2021;28:309&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gursoy C, Yasar E, Eyupoglu G, Demirbilek SG. 90-day mortality and readmission rates of after sepsis and septic shock in intensive care unit. Med J Mugla Sitki Kocman Univ. 2019;6:81&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glen J, Constanti M, Brohi K. Guideline Development Group. Assessment and initial management of major trauma:Summary of NICE guidance. BMJ. 2016;353:i3051.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27333868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan M, Lu Y, Jiang H, Zhang L. The diagnostic accuracy of procalcitonin and C-reactive protein for sepsis: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Cell Biochem. 2019;120:5852&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30417415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ongen-Ipek B, Sitar ME, Karadeniz A. The relationship between sepsis and procalcitonin in intensive care patients. Maltepe Med J. 2019;11:51&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#x131;l&#x131;c S. ROC analysis in clinical decision making. J Mood Disorders. 2013;3:135&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stinner DJ, Edwards D. Surgical management of musculoskeletal trauma. Surg Clin North Am. 2017;97:1119&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28958361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saylam N, Uyan&#x131;k B, Buz M, Buyukyilmaz T, Demir Y, Gursoy DA. Gunshot injuries due to terror. Anatolian J Emerg Med. 2019;2:18&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wafaisade A, Lefering R, Bouillon B, Sakka SG, Thamm OC, Paffrath T, et al. Epidemiology and risk factors of sepsis after multiple trauma: An analysis of 29,829 patients from the Trauma Registry of the German Society for Trauma Surgery. Crit Care Med. 2011;39:621&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21242798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pfeifer R, Tarkin IS, Rocos B, Pape HC. Patterns of mortality and causes of death in polytrauma patients--has anything changed? Injury. 2009;40:907&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19540488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar A, Roberts D, Wood KE, Light B, Parrillo JE, Sharma S, et al. Duration of hypotension before initiation of effective antimicrobial therapy is the critical determinant of survival in human septic shock. Crit Care Med. 2006;34:1589&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16625125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Biomarker Definitions Working Group. Biomarkers and surrogate endpoints: Preferred definitions and conceptual framework. Clin Pharmacol Ther. 2001;69:89&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11240971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Regnier MA, Raux M, Le Manach Y, Asencio Y, Gaillard J, Devilliers C, et al. Prognostic significance of blood lactate and lactate clearance in trauma patients. Anesthesiology. 2012;117:1276&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23168430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jo S, Lee JB, Jin YH, Jeong T, Yoon J, Choi SJ, et al. Comparison of the trauma and injury severity score and modified early warning score with rapid lactate lever (the ViEWS-L score) in blunt trauma patients. Eur J Emerg Med. 2014;21:199&#x2013;205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23628928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Odom SR, Howell MD, Silva GS, Nielsen VM, Gupta A, Shapiro NI, et al. Lactate clearance as a predictor of mortality in trauma patients. J Trauma Acute Care Surg. 2013;74:999&#x2013;1004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23511137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen SQ, Mwakalindile E, Booth JS, Hogan V, Morgan J, Prickett CT, et al. Automated electronic medical record sepsis detection in the emergency department. PeerJ. 2014;2:e343.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3994640</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24765577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim MH, Ahn JY, Song JE, Choi H, Ann HW, Kim JK, et al. The C-reactive protein/albumin ratio as an independent predictor of mortality in patients with severe sepsis or septic shock treated with early goal-directed therapy. PLoS One. 2015;10:e0132109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4497596</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26158725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singer AJ, Taylor M, Domingo A, Ghazipura S, Khorasonchi A, Thode HC., Jr Diagnostic characteristics of a clinical screening tool in combination with measuring bedside lactate level in emergency department patients with suspected sepsis. Acad Emerg Med. 2014;21:853&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25155163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sonmez DU, Dirol H, Erdo&#x11f;an A. The effect of fluid balance on outcomes in patients with sepsis;experience of a tertiary hospital. Pamukkale Med J. 2022;15:87&#x2013;94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pierrakos C, Vincent JL. Sepsis biomarkers: A review. Crit Care. 2010;14:R15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2875530</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20144219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wanner GA, Keel M, Steckholzer U, Beier W, Stocker R, Ertel W. Relationship between procalcitonin plasma levels and severity of injury, sepsis, organ failure, and mortality in injured patients. Crit Care Med. 2000;28:950&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10809265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Connor E, Venkatesh B, Mashongonyika C, Lipman J, Hall J, Thomas P. Serum procalcitonin and C-reactive protein as markers of sepsis and outcome in patients with neurotrauma and subarachnoid haemorrhage. Anaesth Intensive Care. 2004;32:465&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15675205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egger G, Aigner R, Glasner A, Hofer HP, Mitterhammer H, Zelzer S. Blood polymorphonuclear leukocyte migration as a predictive marker for infections in severe trauma: Comparison with various inflammation parameters. Intensive Care Med. 2004;30:331&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14727016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hensler T, Sauerland S, Lefering R, Nagelschmidt M, Bouillon B, Andermahr J, et al. The clinical value of procalcitonin and neopterin in predicting sepsis and organ failure after major trauma. Shock. 2003;20:420&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14560105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castelli GP, Pognani C, Cita M, Stuani A, Sgarbi L, Paladini R. Procalcitonin, C-reactive protein, white blood cells and SOFA score in ICU: Diagnosis and monitoring of sepsis. Minerva Anestesiol. 2006;72:69&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16407808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keel M, H&#xe4;rter L, Reding T, Sun LK, Hersberger M, Seifert B, et al. Pancreatic stone protein is highly increased during posttraumatic sepsis and activates neutrophil granulocytes. Crit Care Med. 2009;37:1642&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19325491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fran&#xe7;ois B, Trimoreau F, Vignon P, Fixe P, Praloran V, Gastinne H. Thrombocytopenia in the sepsis syndrome: Role of hemophagocytosis and macrophage colony-stimulating factor. Am J Med. 1997;103:114&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9274894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aydemir H, Piskin N, Akduman D, Kokturk F, Aktas E. Platelet and mean platelet volume kinetics in adult patients with sepsis. Platelets. 2015;26:331&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22731700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vanderschueren S, De Weerdt A, Malbrain M, Vankersschaever D, Frans E, Wilmer A, et al. Thrombocytopenia and prognosis in intensive care. Crit Care Med. 2000;28:1871&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10890635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacLeod JB, Lynn M, McKenney MG, Cohn SM, Murtha M. Early coagulopathy predicts mortality in trauma. J Trauma. 2003;55:39&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12855879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brohi K, Cohen MJ, Davenport RA. Acute coagulopathy of trauma: Mechanism, identification and effect. Curr Opin Crit Care. 2007;13:680&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17975390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simmons RL, Collins JA, Heisterkamp CA, Mills DE, Andren R, Phillips LL. Coagulation disorders in combat casualties I. Acute changes after wounding. II. Effects of massive transfusion. 3. Post-resuscitative changes. Ann Surg. 1969;169:455&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1387454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5774736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Counts RB, Haisch C, Simon TL, Maxwell NG, Heimbach DM, Carrico CJ. Hemostasis in massively transfused trauma patients. Ann Surg. 1979;190:91&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1344465</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">464685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossaint R, Bouillon B, Cerny V, Coats TJ, Duranteau J, Fernandez-Mondejar E, et al. Management of bleeding following major trauma: An updated European guideline. Crit Care. 2010;14:R52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2887168</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20370902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zivin JR, Gooley T, Zager RA, Ryan MJ. Hypocalcemia: A pervasive metabolic abnormality in the critically ill. Am J Kidney Dis. 2001;37:689&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11273867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goyal A, Anastasopoulou C, Ngu M, Singh S. In: StatPearls Treasure. Island, FL: StatPearls Publishing; 2022. Hypocalcemia.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28613662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vivien B, Langeron O, Morell E, Devilliers C, Carli PA, Coriat P, et al. Early hypocalcemia in severe trauma. Crit Care Med. 2005;33:1946&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16148464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>