<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">37150935</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>31</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1532-6535</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>114</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Clinical pharmacology and therapeutics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Clin Pharmacol Ther</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Pharmacokinetics and Pharmacokinetic/Pharmacodynamic Properties of Rozibafusp Alfa, a Bispecific Inhibitor of BAFF and ICOSL: Analyses of Phase I Clinical Trials.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>371</StartPage><EndPage>380</EndPage><MedlinePgn>371-380</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/cpt.2929</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Rozibafusp alfa (AMG 570) is a first-in-class bispecific IgG2-peptide fusion designed to inhibit inducible T-cell costimulator ligand (ICOSL) and B-cell activating factor (BAFF). The pharmacokinetics (PK) and pharmacodynamics (PD) of rozibafusp alfa were investigated in two randomized, placebo-controlled clinical studies: a phase Ia single ascending-dose study (7-700&#x2009;mg subcutaneously (s.c.)) in healthy subjects and a phase Ib multiple ascending-dose study (70-420&#x2009;mg s.c. every 2&#x2009;weeks (q2w)) in patients with rheumatoid arthritis. Rozibafusp alfa exhibited nonlinear PK and dose-related and reversible dual-target engagement. Maximal reduction of na&#xef;ve B cells from baseline (&gt;&#x2009;40%), reflective of BAFF inhibition, was achieved with rozibafusp alfa exposure (area under the concentration-time curve from time 0 to time infinity (AUC<sub>inf</sub> ) and AUC within a dosing interval from day 0 to day 14 (AUC<sub>tau</sub> )) above 51 and 57&#x2009;days&#x2022;&#x3bc;g/mL for the single-dose (&#x2265;&#x2009;70&#x2009;mg) and multiple-dose studies (&#x2265;&#x2009;70&#x2009;mg q2w), respectively. ICOSL receptor occupancy on circulating B cells, a surrogate PD end point for ICOSL inhibition, was directly related to drug concentration. PK/PD analysis showed &gt;&#x2009;90% RO at rozibafusp alfa &#x2265;&#x2009;22.2&#x2009;&#x3bc;g/mL (&#x2265;&#x2009;420-mg single dose or &#x2265;&#x2009;210&#x2009;mg q2w multiple dose), with saturation occurring at higher drug concentrations. These results informed the design and dose selection of a phase IIb study assessing the safety and efficacy of rozibafusp alfa in patients with active systemic lupus erythematosus.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Authors. Clinical Pharmacology &amp; Therapeutics published by Wiley Periodicals LLC on behalf of American Society for Clinical Pharmacology and Therapeutics.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abuqayyas</LastName><ForeName>Lubna</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5188-1010</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Pharmacology, Modeling, and Simulation, Amgen Inc., Thousand Oaks, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Po-Wei</ForeName><Initials>PW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Pharmacology, Modeling, and Simulation, Amgen Inc., Thousand Oaks, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dos Santos</LastName><ForeName>Marcia Teixeira</ForeName><Initials>MT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Biomarkers, Amgen Inc., Thousand Oaks, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Parnes</LastName><ForeName>Jane R</ForeName><Initials>JR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Early Development, Amgen Inc., Thousand Oaks, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Doshi</LastName><ForeName>Sameer</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Pharmacology, Modeling, and Simulation, Amgen Inc., Thousand Oaks, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dutta</LastName><ForeName>Sandeep</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Pharmacology, Modeling, and Simulation, Amgen Inc., Thousand Oaks, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Houk</LastName><ForeName>Brett E</ForeName><Initials>BE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Pharmacology, Modeling, and Simulation, Amgen Inc., Thousand Oaks, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D017426">Clinical Trial, Phase I</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Clin Pharmacol Ther</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0372741</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0009-9236</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D053264">B-Cell Activating Factor</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D060945">Inducible T-Cell Co-Stimulator Ligand</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019540" MajorTopicYN="N">Area Under Curve</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001172" MajorTopicYN="Y">Arthritis, Rheumatoid</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053264" MajorTopicYN="N">B-Cell Activating Factor</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000037" MajorTopicYN="N">antagonists &amp; inhibitors</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004305" MajorTopicYN="N">Dose-Response Relationship, Drug</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D060945" MajorTopicYN="N">Inducible T-Cell Co-Stimulator Ligand</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000037" MajorTopicYN="N">antagonists &amp; inhibitors</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37150935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cpt.2929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Smulski, C.R. &amp; Eibel, H. BAFF and BAFF-receptor in B cell selection and survival. Front. Immunol. 9, 2285 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi, Y.S. et al. ICOS receptor instructs T follicular helper cell versus effector cell differentiation via induction of the transcriptional repressor Bcl6. Immunity 34, 932-946 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, M. et al. Development of an ICOSL and BAFF bispecific inhibitor AMG 570 for systemic lupus erythematosus treatment. Clin. Exp. Rheumatol. 37, 906-914 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benlysta Prescribing Information, 2021. GlaxoSmithKline LLC: Durham, North Carolina, USA (revised July 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Navarra, S.V. et al. Efficacy and safety of belimumab in patients with active systemic lupus erythematosus: a randomised, placebo-controlled, phase 3 trial. Lancet 377, 721-731 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furie, R. et al. A phase III, randomized, placebo-controlled study of belimumab, a monoclonal antibody that inhibits B lymphocyte stimulator, in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Rheum. 63, 3918-3930 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, S.P., Snedecor, S.J., Nanji, S., Lloyd, E. &amp; Bell, C.F. Real-world effectiveness of belimumab in systemic lupus erythematosus: a systematic literature review. Rheumatol. Ther. 9, 975-991 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sullivan, B.A. et al. Inducible T-cell co-stimulator ligand (ICOSL) blockade leads to selective inhibition of anti-KLH IgG responses in subjects with systemic lupus erythematosus. Lupus. Sci. Med. 3, e000146 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng, L.E. et al. Brief report: a randomized, double-blind, parallel-group, placebo-controlled, multiple-dose study to evaluate AMG 557 in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus and active lupus arthritis. Arthritis Rheumatol. 70, 1071-1076 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Efficacy and safety of AMG 570 in subjects with active systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE). ClinicalTrials.gov identifier: NCT04058028. Updated August 12, 2022. &lt;https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04058028?term=AMG570&amp;cond=Systemic+Lupus+Erythematosus&amp;draw=2&amp;rank=2&gt;. Accessed September 7, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abuqayyas, L. et al. Safety and biological activity of rozibafusp alfa, a bispecific inhibitor of inducible costimulator ligand and B cell activating factor, in patients with rheumatoid arthritis: results of a phase 1b, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, multiple ascending dose study. A.C.R. Open. Rheumatol. 4, 903-911 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimamoto, G., Gegg, C., Boone, T. &amp; Qu&#xe9;va, C. Peptibodies: a flexible alternative format to antibodies. MAbs 4, 586-591 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stohl, W. et al. Treatment of systemic lupus erythematosus patients with the BAFF antagonist "peptibody" blisibimod (AMG 623/A-623): results from randomized, double-blind phase 1a and phase 1b trials. Arthritis Res. Ther. 17, 215 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furie, R.A. et al. PEARL-SC study: a phase 2, randomised, placebo-controlled clinical trial of blisibimod, an inhibitor of B cell activating factor, in patients with moderate-to-severe systemic lupus erythematosus, the PEARL-SC study. Ann. Rheum. Dis. 74, 1667-1675 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng, L.E. et al. Safety, pharmacokinetics and pharmacodynamics of a single dose of a bispecific ICOSL and BAFF inhibitor, AMG 570, in healthy subjects. Ann. Rheum. Dis. 77(suppl2), 1418 [abstract AB0521] (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng, L.E. et al. Development and first-in-human characterization of an ICOSL and BAFF bispecific inhibitor AMG 570 for SLE treatment. Arthritis Rheumatol. 70(suppl10), abstract 2671 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dutta, S. &amp; Reed, R.C. Functional half-life is a meaningful descriptor of steady-state pharmacokinetics of an extended-release formulation of a rapidly cleared drug: as shown by once-daily divalproex-ER. Clin. Drug Investig. 26, 681-690 (2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallace, D.J. et al. A phase II, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, dose-ranging study of belimumab in patients with active systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Rheum. 61, 1168-1178 (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, P.-W., Abuqayyas, L., Dutta, S., Houk, B.E. &amp; Doshi, S. Population pharmacokinetics of rozibafusp alfa, a bispecific IgG2 peptide antibody conjugate targeting T-cell and B-cell activity, following SC administration in healthy subjects and rheumatoid arthritis patients. ACoPP11. 2, ISSN:2688-3953 [abstr TUE-064] &lt;https://chrisrackauckas.com/assets/Posters/ACoP11_Poster_Abstracts_2020.pdf&gt; (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai, W.W., Fiscella, M., Chen, C., Zhong, Z.J., Freimuth, W.W. &amp; Subich, D.C. Bioavailability, pharmacokinetics, and safety of belimumab administered subcutaneously in healthy subjects. Clin. Pharmacol. Drug Dev. 2, 349-357 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Struemper, H., Chen, C. &amp; Cai, W. Population pharmacokinetics of belimumab following intravenous administration in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. J. Clin. Pharmacol. 53, 711-720 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stohl, W. Therapeutic targeting of the BAFF/APRIL axis in systemic lupus erythematosus. Expert Opin. Ther. Targets 18, 473-489 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng, R., Jin, F., Prabhu, S. &amp; Iyer, S. Monoclonal antibodies: what are the pharmacokinetic and pharmacodynamic considerations for drug development? Expert Opin. Drug Metab. Toxicol. 8, 141-160 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ovacik, M. &amp; Lin, K. Tutorial on monoclonal antibody pharmacokinetics and its considerations in early development. Clin. Transl. Sci. 11, 540-552 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas, V.A. &amp; Balthasar, J.P. Understanding inter-individual variability in monoclonal antibody disposition. Antibodies. (Basel). 8, 56 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramsk&#xf6;ld, D. et al. B cell alterations during BAFF inhibition with belimumab in SLE. EBioMedicine 40, 517-527 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobi, A.M. et al. Effect of long-term belimumab treatment on B cells in systemic lupus erythematosus: extension of a phase II, double-blind, placebo-controlled, dose-ranging study. Arthritis Rheum. 62, 201-210 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Witcher, J. et al. Pharmacokinetics and safety of single doses of tabalumab in subjects with rheumatoid arthritis or systemic lupus erythematosus. Br. J. Clin. Pharmacol. 81, 908-917 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stohl, W. et al. Efficacy and safety of belimumab in patients with rheumatoid arthritis: a phase II, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, dose-ranging study. J. Rheumatol. 40, 579-589 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, J. et al. First-in-human study of the safety, tolerability, pharmacokinetics, and pharmacodynamics of ALPN-101, a dual CD28/ICOS antagonist, in healthy adult subjects. Clin. Transl. Sci. 14, 1314-1326 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wise, L.M. &amp; Stohl, W. The safety of belimumab for the treatment of systemic lupus erythematosus. Expert Opin. Drug Saf. 18, 1133-1144 (2019).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>