<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37156255</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1474-547X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>401</Volume><Issue>10391</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jun</Month><Day>03</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Lancet (London, England)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Lancet</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Incidence, prevalence, and co-occurrence of autoimmune disorders over time and by age, sex, and socioeconomic status: a population-based cohort study of 22 million individuals in the UK.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1878</StartPage><EndPage>1890</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1878-1890</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/S0140-6736(23)00457-9</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0140-6736(23)00457-9</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">A rise in the incidence of some autoimmune disorders has been described. However, contemporary estimates of the overall incidence of autoimmune diseases and trends over time are scarce and inconsistent. We aimed to investigate the incidence and prevalence of 19 of the most common autoimmune diseases in the UK, assess trends over time, and by sex, age, socioeconomic status, season, and region, and we examine rates of co-occurrence among autoimmune diseases.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">In this UK population-based study, we used linked primary and secondary electronic health records from the Clinical Practice Research Datalink (CPRD), a cohort that is representative of the UK population in terms of age and sex and ethnicity. Eligible participants were men and women (no age restriction) with acceptable records, approved for Hospital Episodes Statistics and Office of National Statistics linkage, and registered with their general practice for at least 12 months during the study period. We calculated age and sex standardised incidence and prevalence of 19 autoimmune disorders from 2000 to 2019 and used negative binomial regression models to investigate temporal trends and variation by age, sex, socioeconomic status, season of onset, and geographical region in England. To characterise co-occurrence of autoimmune diseases, we calculated incidence rate ratios (IRRs), comparing incidence rates of comorbid autoimmune disease among individuals with a first (index) autoimmune disease with incidence rates in the general population, using negative binomial regression models, adjusted for age and sex.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="FINDINGS">Among the 22&#x2009;009&#x2009;375 individuals included in the study, 978&#x2009;872 had a new diagnosis of at least one autoimmune disease between Jan 1, 2000, and June 30, 2019 (mean age 54&#xb7;0 years [SD 21&#xb7;4]). 625&#x2009;879 (63&#xb7;9%) of these diagnosed individuals were female and 352&#x2009;993 (36&#xb7;1%) were male. Over the study period, age and sex standardised incidence rates of any autoimmune diseases increased (IRR 2017-19 vs 2000-02 1&#xb7;04 [95% CI 1&#xb7;00-1&#xb7;09]). The largest increases were seen in coeliac disease (2&#xb7;19 [2&#xb7;05-2&#xb7;35]), Sjogren's syndrome (2&#xb7;09 [1&#xb7;84-2&#xb7;37]), and Graves' disease (2&#xb7;07 [1&#xb7;92-2&#xb7;22]); pernicious anaemia (0&#xb7;79 [0&#xb7;72-0&#xb7;86]) and Hashimoto's thyroiditis (0&#xb7;81 [0&#xb7;75-0&#xb7;86]) significantly decreased in incidence. Together, the 19 autoimmune disorders examined affected 10&#xb7;2% of the population over the study period (1&#x2009;912&#x2009;200 [13&#xb7;1%] women and 668&#x2009;264 [7&#xb7;4%] men). A socioeconomic gradient was evident across several diseases, including pernicious anaemia (most vs least deprived area IRR 1&#xb7;72 [1&#xb7;64-1&#xb7;81]), rheumatoid arthritis (1&#xb7;52 [1&#xb7;45-1&#xb7;59]), Graves' disease (1&#xb7;36 [1&#xb7;30-1&#xb7;43]), and systemic lupus erythematosus (1&#xb7;35 [1&#xb7;25-1&#xb7;46]). Seasonal variations were observed for childhood-onset type 1 diabetes (more commonly diagnosed in winter) and vitiligo (more commonly diagnosed in summer), and regional variations were observed for a range of conditions. Autoimmune disorders were commonly associated with each other, particularly Sj&#xf6;gren's syndrome, systemic lupus erythematosus, and systemic sclerosis. Individuals with childhood-onset type 1 diabetes also had significantly higher rates of Addison's disease (IRR 26&#xb7;5 [95% CI 17&#xb7;3-40&#xb7;7]), coeliac disease (28&#xb7;4 [25&#xb7;2-32&#xb7;0]), and thyroid disease (Hashimoto's thyroiditis 13&#xb7;3 [11&#xb7;8-14&#xb7;9] and Graves' disease 6&#xb7;7 [5&#xb7;1-8&#xb7;5]), and multiple sclerosis had a particularly low rate of co-occurrence with other autoimmune diseases.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="INTERPRETATION">Autoimmune diseases affect approximately one in ten individuals, and their burden continues to increase over time at varying rates across individual diseases. The socioeconomic, seasonal, and regional disparities observed among several autoimmune disorders in our study suggest environmental factors in disease pathogenesis. The inter-relations between autoimmune diseases are commensurate with shared pathogenetic mechanisms or predisposing factors, particularly among connective tissue diseases and among endocrine diseases.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="FUNDING">Research Foundation Flanders.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Conrad</LastName><ForeName>Nathalie</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health and Primary Care, Katholieke Universiteit Leuven, Leuven, Leuven Belgium; Institute of Cardiovascular and Medical Sciences, University of Glasgow, Glasgow, UK; Deep Medicine, Nuffield Department of Women's and Reproductive Health, University of Oxford, Oxford, UK. Electronic address: nathalie.conrad@kuleuven.be.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Misra</LastName><ForeName>Shivani</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, Department of Metabolism, Digestion and Reproduction, Imperial College London, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Verbakel</LastName><ForeName>Jan Y</ForeName><Initials>JY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health and Primary Care, Katholieke Universiteit Leuven, Leuven, Leuven Belgium; Nuffield Department of Primary Care Health Sciences, University of Oxford, Oxford, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Verbeke</LastName><ForeName>Geert</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Interuniversity Institute for Biostatistics and Statistical Bioinformatics (I-BioStat), Hasselt University and Katholieke Universiteit Leuven, Leuven, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Molenberghs</LastName><ForeName>Geert</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Interuniversity Institute for Biostatistics and Statistical Bioinformatics (I-BioStat), Hasselt University and Katholieke Universiteit Leuven, Leuven, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Taylor</LastName><ForeName>Peter N</ForeName><Initials>PN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Infection and Immunity, Cardiff University School of Medicine, Cardiff, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mason</LastName><ForeName>Justin</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, National Heart &amp; Lung Institute, Imperial College London, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sattar</LastName><ForeName>Naveed</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Medical Veterinary and Life Sciences, University of Glasgow, Glasgow, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McMurray</LastName><ForeName>John J V</ForeName><Initials>JJV</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Cardiovascular and Medical Sciences, University of Glasgow, Glasgow, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McInnes</LastName><ForeName>Iain B</ForeName><Initials>IB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Medical Veterinary and Life Sciences, University of Glasgow, Glasgow, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khunti</LastName><ForeName>Kamlesh</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Diabetes Research Centre, University of Leicester, Leicester, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cambridge</LastName><ForeName>Geraldine</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rheumatology, Division of Medicine, University College London, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Lancet</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>2985213R</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0140-6736</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015994" MajorTopicYN="N">Incidence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012859" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sjogren's Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015331" MajorTopicYN="N">Cohort Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003922" MajorTopicYN="Y">Diabetes Mellitus, Type 1</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015995" MajorTopicYN="N">Prevalence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000752" MajorTopicYN="Y">Anemia, Pernicious</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002446" MajorTopicYN="Y">Celiac Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001327" MajorTopicYN="Y">Autoimmune Diseases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012923" MajorTopicYN="N">Social Class</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006111" MajorTopicYN="Y">Graves Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004739" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">England</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013966" MajorTopicYN="Y">Thyroiditis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>Declaration of interests NC is funded by a personal fellowship from the Research Foundation Flanders (grant number 12ZU922N) and declares royalties from Oxford University Innovation. SM is funded by a Wellcome Trust Career Development Award (223024/Z/21/Z) and is supported by the NIHR Imperial Biomedical Research Centre. IBM declares honoraria from AbbVie; grant support paid to his university from AstraZeneca and Eli Lilly; participation on data safety monitoring boards or advisory boards of AstraZeneca, Bristol Myers Squibb, Eli Lilly, Novartis, Janssen, GlaxoSmithKline, AbbVie, Cabaletta, Compugen, Causeway, Gilead, Moonlake, Reflexion, UCB, and XinThera; patents from Novartis; leadership roles with Evelo, Versus Arthritis, and Greater Glasgow and Clyde Health Board; and stock or stock options with Evelo, Compugen, and Cabaletta. JJVM has received funding to his institution from Amgen and Cytokinetics for his participation in the Steering Committee for the ATOMIC-HF, COSMIC-HF, and GALACTIC-HF trials and meetings and other activities related to these trials; has received payments through Glasgow University from work on clinical trials, consulting, and other activities from Alnylam, Amgen, AstraZeneca, Bayer, Boehringer Ingelheim, Bristol Myers Squibb, Cardurion, Dal-Cor, GlaxoSmithKline, Ionis, KBP Biosciences, Novartis, Pfizer, and Theracos; and has received personal lecture fees from the Corpus, Abbott, Hikma, Sun Pharmaceuticals, Medscape/Heart.Org, Radcliffe Cardiology, Alkem Metabolics, Eris Lifesciences, Lupin, ProAdWise Communications, Servier Director, and Global Clinical Trial Partners. NS declares consulting fees or speaker honoraria, or both, from Abbott Laboratories, Afimmune, Amgen, AstraZeneca, Boehringer Ingelheim, Eli Lilly, Hanmi Pharmaceuticals, Janssen, Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme, Novartis, Novo Nordisk, Pfizer, Roche Diagnostics, and Sanofi; and grant support paid to his university from AstraZeneca, Boehringer Ingelheim, Novartis, and Roche Diagnostics. KK is supported by the National Institute for Health Research (NIHR) Applied Research Collaboration East Midlands and the NIHR Leicester Biomedical Research Centre. KK has also acted as a consultant, speaker, or received grants for investigator-initiated studies for AstraZeneca, Abbott, Amgen, Napp, Bayer, Novartis, Novo Nordisk, Sanofi-Aventis, Lilly, Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme, Boehringer Ingelheim, Oramed Pharmaceuticals, and Applied Therapeutics. PNT declares personal consulting fees from Immunovant and leadership roles in the Society for Endocrinology and British Thyroid Association. All other authors declare no competing interests. The views expressed are those of the authors and not necessarily those of the funder.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37156255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(23)00457-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0140-6736(23)00457-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>