<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37159002</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2163-0763</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>95</Volume><Issue>2S Suppl 1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The journal of trauma and acute care surgery</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Trauma Acute Care Surg</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Profile of injuries in recent warfare.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>S79</StartPage><EndPage>S87</EndPage><MedlinePgn>S79-S87</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/TA.0000000000004034</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">The epidemiology of French military severe trauma patients injured during recent military operations remains poorly described, even if French operations, casualties sustained, and care rendered in a different trauma system are distinct from others. This study aimed at describing the characteristics of these patients upon arrival at hospital in France and during hospital stay.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">This 5-year retrospective cohort study included all French military servicemen injured during military operations and admitted to the intensive care unit. Data on the characteristics upon arrival at the Percy hospital in France and during hospital stay were obtained from a national civilian trauma registry.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Of 1,990 military trauma patients injured in military operations, 39 were finally admitted to the intensive care unit of the Percy hospital and included in the analysis. Traumas were related to battle injuries and nonbattle injuries in 27 and 12 patients, respectively. Ninety-eight wounds were described: torso (n = 32), limbs (n = 32), head and neck (n = 25), and spine (n = 9). The mechanism of injury was explosion in 19 patients, gunshot wound in 8 patients, motor vehicular crash in 7 patients, or other mechanisms in 5 patients. The median Injury Severity Score was 25.5 (interquartile range, 14-34).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">This study highlights the small number of military severe trauma patients injured in recent warfare and their characteristics. The use of dedicated systemic military trauma registries could improve the specific epidemiological knowledge on recent warfare and help better prepare for future conflicts that may include major engagements and large-scale combat operations.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="LEVEL OF EVIDENCE">Prognostic and Epidemiological; Level V.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 The Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chiniard</LastName><ForeName>Thomas</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Department of Anesthesiology and Intensive Care (T.C., M.B., P.P.), Percy Military Teaching Hospital, Clamart; French Military Medical Service Academy (T.C., M.B., S.T., P.P.), &#xc9;cole du Val-de-Gr&#xe2;ce, Paris; Defense Health Department (S.D.), French Surgeon General Office, Arcueil; Military Medical Service Operational Center (K.B.); Paris Firefighters Brigade (S.T.), Paris; and French Special Operations Forces Medical Component Command (P.P.), Villacoublay, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Boutonnet</LastName><ForeName>Mathieu</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Duron</LastName><ForeName>Sandrine</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bertho</LastName><ForeName>Kilian</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Travers</LastName><ForeName>St&#xe9;phane</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pasquier</LastName><ForeName>Pierre</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Trauma Acute Care Surg</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101570622</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2163-0755</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014948" MajorTopicYN="Y">Wounds, Gunshot</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000601" MajorTopicYN="N">surgery</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008887" MajorTopicYN="Y">Military Medicine</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007362" MajorTopicYN="N">Intensive Care Units</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015601" MajorTopicYN="N">Injury Severity Score</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008889" MajorTopicYN="Y">Military Personnel</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012042" MajorTopicYN="N">Registries</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37159002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10389621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/TA.0000000000004034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">01586154-990000000-00364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Centre interarm&#xe9;es de concepts, de doctrines et d'exp&#xe9;rimentations. Doctrine interarm&#xe9;es DIA-4.0.10_SOUTMED-OPS (2014) relative au soutien m&#xe9;dical aux engagements op&#xe9;rationnels. Effective July 31, 2014. Available at: https://www.irsem.fr/data/files/irsem/documents/document/file/68/20140731_np_cicde_dia-4-0-10-soutmed-ops.pdf. Accessed February 22, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luft A Corcostegui SP Millet M Gillard J Boissier J Rondy P, et al. . Aeromedical evacuations within the French Armed Forces: analysis of 2,129 patients. Mil Med. 2020;185(3&#x2013;4):468&#x2013;476.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31642486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ponsin P Swiech A Poyat C Alves F Jacques AE Franchin M, et al. . Strategic air medical evacuation of critically ill patients involving an intensive care physician: a retrospective analysis of 16 years of mission data. Injury. 2020;52(5):1176&#x2013;1182.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33082029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pr&#xe9;cloux P B&#xe9;rend M Petitjeans F Lamblin A Loh&#xe9;as D Wey PF, et al. . &#xc9;volution de la strat&#xe9;gie de prise en charge des bless&#xe9;s de guerre au Role 1. Concepts p&#xe9;dagogiques et int&#xe9;r&#xea;ts d&#x2019;un registre des soins d&#x2019;urgence au combat. M&#xe9;decine Arm&#xe9;es. 2011;39(5):387&#x2013;393.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howard JT, Kotwal RS, Santos-Lazada AR, Martin MJ, Stockinger ZT. Reexamination of a battlefield trauma Golden hour policy. J Trauma Acute Care Surg. 2018;84(1):11&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29266051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pasquier P, de Rudnicki S, Donat N, Auroy Y, Merat S. Epidemiology of war injuries, about two conflicts: Iraq and Afghanistan. Ann Fr Anesth Reanim. 2011;30(11):819&#x2013;827.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21981845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haus-Cheymol R Bouguerra C Mayorg E Nivoix P Prat N Verret C, et al. . Blessures par arme &#xe0; feu et engins explosifs dans les arm&#xe9;es. R&#xe9;sultats de la surveillance &#xe9;pid&#xe9;miologique de 2004 &#xe0; 2008. M&#xe9;decine Arm&#xe9;es. 2011;39(1):89&#x2013;96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glenn MA Martin KD Monzon D Nettles W Rodriquez VM Lovasz D, et al. . Implementation of a combat casualty trauma registry. J Trauma Nurs. 2008;15(4):181&#x2013;184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19092507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eastridge BJ Costanzo G Jenkins D Spott MA Wade C Greydanus D, et al. . Impact of joint theater trauma system initiatives on battlefield injury outcomes. Am J Surg. 2009;198(6):852&#x2013;857.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19969141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Owens BD, Kragh JF, Jr., Wenke JC, Macaitis J, Wade CE, Holcomb JB. Combat wounds in operation Iraqi freedom and operation enduring freedom. J Trauma. 2008;64(2):295&#x2013;299.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18301189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelly JF Ritenour AE McLaughlin DF Bagg KA Apodaca AN Mallak CT, et al. . Injury severity and causes of death from operation Iraqi freedom and operation enduring freedom: 2003&#x2013;2004 versus 2006. J Trauma. 2008;64(2 Suppl):S21&#x2013;S26. discussion S26-27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18376168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffmann C Poyat C Alhanati L Haus-Cheymol R de Rudnicki S Bouix-Picasso J, et al. . French military deaths in Afghanistan: a retrospective analysis of 450 combat casualties between 2010 and 2012. BMJ Mil Health. 2021;167(2):140.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32817240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beranger F Lesquen HD Aoun O Roqueplo C Meyrat L Natale C, et al. . Management of war-related vascular wounds in French role 3 hospital during the Afghan campaign. Injury. 2017;48(9):1906&#x2013;1910.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28622832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Lesquen H Beranger F Berbis J Boddaert G Poichotte A Pons F, et al. . Challenges in war-related thoracic injury faced by French military surgeons in Afghanistan (2009&#x2013;2013). Injury. 2016;47(9):1939&#x2013;1944.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27418455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmitt J Boutonnet M Goutorbe P Raynaud L Carfantan C Luft A, et al. . Acute respiratory distress syndrome in the forward environment. Retrospective analysis of acute respiratory distress syndrome cases among French Army war casualties. J Trauma Acute Care Surg. 2020;89(2S Suppl 2):S207&#x2013;S212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32102034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonnet S, Gonzalez F, Poichotte A, Duverger V, Pons F. Lessons learned from the experience of visceral military surgeons in the French role 3 Medical Treatment Facility of Kabul (Afghanistan): an extended skill mix required. Injury. 2012;43(8):1301&#x2013;1306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22440530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbier O, Malgras B, Versier G, Pons F, Rigal S, Ollat D. French surgical experience in the role 3 medical treatment facility of KaIA (Kabul International Airport, Afghanistan): the place of the orthopedic surgery. Orthop Traumatol Surg Res. 2014;100(6):681&#x2013;685.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25193622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robert J, Tourtier JP, Vitalis V, Coste S, Gaspard W, Bourrilhon C. Air medical-evacuated battle injuries: French Army 2001 to 2014 in Afghanistan. Air Med J. 2017;36(6):327&#x2013;331.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29132596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dagain A Aoun O Bordes J Roqueplo C Joubert C Esnault P, et al. . Management of war-related ballistic craniocerebral injuries in a French role 3 hospital during the Afghan campaign. World Neurosurg. 2017;102:6&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28254598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dagain A Aoun O Sellier A Desse N Joubert C Beucler N, et al. . Acute neurosurgical management of traumatic brain injury and spinal cord injury in French armed forces during deployment. Neurosurg Focus. 2018;45(6):E9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30544305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schweizer MA, Janak JC, Stockinger ZT, Monchal T. Description of trauma among French service members in the Department of Defense Trauma Registry: understanding the nature of trauma and the care provided. Mil Med Res. 2019;6(1):7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6391821</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30813959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Travers S Carfantan C Luft A Aigle L Pasquier P Martinaud C, et al. . Five years of prolonged field care: prehospital challenges during recent French military operations. Transfusion. 2019;59(S2):1459&#x2013;1466.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30980759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carfantan C Goudard Y Butin C Duron-Martinaud S Even JP Anselme A, et al. . Forward Medevac during Serval and Barkhane operations in Sahel: a registry study. Injury. 2017;48(1):58&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27829492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu&#xe9;not P Beauchamps V Madec S Carfantan C Boutonnet M Bareau L, et al. . Fixed wing tactical aircraft for air medical evacuation in Sahel. Air Med J. 2019;38(5):350&#x2013;355.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31578973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malgras B, Barbier O, Petit L, Rigal S, Pons F, Pasquier P. Surgical challenges in a new theater of modern warfare: the French role 2 in Gao, Mali. Injury. 2016;47(1):99&#x2013;103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26264878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dubost C, Goudard Y, Soucanye de Landevoisin E, Contargyris C, Evans D, Pauleau G. Combat casualties from two current conflicts with the Seventh French Forward Surgical Team in Mali and Central African Republic in 2014. J R Army Med Corps. 2016;162(6):450&#x2013;455.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26826192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kandel M. U.S. Strategy in Africa, Etude de l'IRSEM n&#xb0;36. 2014. Available at: https://www.irsem.fr/publications-de-l-irsem/etudes.html. Accessed May 31, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamada SR Rosa A Gauss T Desclefs JP Raux M Harrois A, et al. . Development and validation of a pre-hospital &#xab; red flag &#xbb; alert for activation of intra-hospital haemorrhage control response in blunt trauma. Crit Care. 2018;22(1):113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5935988</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29728151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maegele M Lefering R Yucel N Tjardes T Rixen D Paffrath T, et al. . Early coagulopathy in multiple injury: an analysis from the German Trauma Registry on 8724 patients. Injury. 2007;38(3):298&#x2013;304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17214989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dorgalaleh A, Favaloro EJ, Bahraini M, Rad F. Standardization of prothrombin time/international normalized ratio (PT/INR). Int J Lab Hematol. 2021;43(1):21&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32979036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poyat C, Boutonnet M, Pel&#xe9;e de Saint Maurice G, Ausset S, Daban JL, Blot RM. Profil des bless&#xe9;s de guerre Fran&#xe7;ais en Afghanistan: exp&#xe9;rience du service de sant&#xe9; des arm&#xe9;es sur la p&#xe9;riode 2001&#x2013;2010. Anesth R&#xe9;animation. 2017;3(5):403&#x2013;412.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson PC, Foster M, Fries A, Jeffery SLA. Military trauma care in Birmingham: observational study of care requirements and resource utilisation. Injury. 2014;45(1):44&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22999185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brewster CT Forbes K Handford C Scallan N Eskell M Hettiaratchy S, et al. . Planning for UK terror attacks: analysis of blast and ballistic injuries. Injury. 2021;52(5):1221&#x2013;1226.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33454061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brethauer SA Chao A Chambers LW Green DJ Brown C Rhee P, et al. . Invasion vs insurgency: US Navy/Marine Corps forward surgical care during Operation Iraqi Freedom. Arch Surg. 2008;143(6):564&#x2013;569.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18559749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eastridge BJ Hardin M Cantrell J Oetjen-Gerdes L Zubko T Mallak C, et al. . Died of wounds on the battlefield: causation and implications for improving combat casualty care. J Trauma. 2011;71(1 Suppl):S4&#x2013;S8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21795876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eastridge BJ Mabry RL Seguin P Cantrell J Tops T Uribe P, et al. . Death on the battlefield (2001-2011): implications for the future of combat casualty care. J Trauma Acute Care Surg. 2012;73(6 Suppl 5):S431&#x2013;S437.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23192066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazuchowski EL Kotwal RS Janak JC Howard JT Harcke HT Montgomery HR, et al. . Mortality review of US Special Operations Command battle-injured fatalities. J Trauma Acute Care Surg. 2020;88(5):686&#x2013;695.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32039975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janak J Stockinger Z Mazuchowski E Kotwal R Sosnov J Montgomery H, et al. . Military preventable death conceptual framework: a systematic approach for reducing battlefield mortality. Mil Med. 2018;183(suppl 2):15&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30189080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kotwal RS Staudt AM Mazuchowski EL Gurney JM Shackelford SA Butler FK, et al. . A US military Role 2 forward surgical team database study of combat mortality in Afghanistan. J Trauma Acute Care Surg. 2018;85(3):603&#x2013;612.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29851907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pidcoke HF Aden JK Mora AG Borgman MA Spinella PC Dubick MA, et al. . Ten-year analysis of transfusion in Operation Iraqi Freedom and Operation Enduring Freedom: increased plasma and platelet use correlates with improved survival. J Trauma Acute Care Surg. 2012;73(6 suppl 5):S445&#x2013;S452.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23192068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poller L. International normalized ratios (INR): the first 20 years. J Thromb Haemost. 2004;2(6):849&#x2013;860.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15140114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fr&#xf6;hlich M Mutschler M Caspers M Nienaber U J&#xe4;cker V Driessen A, et al. . Trauma-induced coagulopathy upon emergency room arrival: still a significant problem despite increased awareness and management? Eur J Trauma Emerg Surg. 2019;45(1):115&#x2013;124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29170791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peltan ID, Vande Vusse LK, Maier RV, Watkins TR. An international normalized ratio-based definition of acute traumatic coagulopathy is associated with mortality, venous thromboembolism, and multiple organ failure after injury. Crit Care Med. 2015;43(7):1429&#x2013;1438.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4512212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25816119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tribble DR Li P Warkentien TE Lloyd BA Schnaubelt ER Ganesan A, et al. . Impact of operational theater on combat and noncombat trauma-related infections. Mil Med. 2016;181(10):1258&#x2013;1268.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5123796</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27753561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah S, Spinella PC, Muszynski JA. Immunologic effects of trauma and transfusion. J Trauma Acute Care Surg. 2017;82(6S suppl 1):S50&#x2013;S56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28333832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moyer JD Hamada SR Josse J Auliard O Gauss T, Traumabase Group . Trauma reloaded: trauma registry in the era of data science. Anaesth Crit care Pain Med. 2021;40(2):100827.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33741513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore L Champion H O&#x2019;Reilly G Leppaniemi A Cameron P Palmer C, et al. . Impact of trauma system structure on injury outcomes: a systematic review protocol. Syst Rev. 2017;6(1):12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5251247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28109306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gauss T Balandraud P Frandon J Abba J Ageron FX Albaladejo P, et al. . Strategic proposal for a national trauma system in France. Anaesth Crit Care Pain Med. 2019;38(2):121&#x2013;130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29857186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deming WE. Opportunities in mathematical statistics, with special reference to sampling and quality control. Science. 1943;97(2514):209&#x2013;214.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17780136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peduzzi P, Concato J, Kemper E, Holford TR, Feinstein AR. A simulation study of the number of events per variable in logistic regression analysis. J Clin Epidemiol. 1996;49(12):1373&#x2013;1379.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8970487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>