<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37179450</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1521-4141</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>53</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of immunology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Immunol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Interferon-&#x3b1; regulates abnormally increased expression of RSAD2 in Th17 and Tfh cells in systemic lupus erythematosus patients.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e2350420</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e2350420</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/eji.202350420</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) is a chronic autoimmune disease that often involves abnormal activation of regulatory IFN genes and regulation of B cells by CD4<sup>+</sup> T cells. Radical S-adenosyl methionine domain containing 2 (RSAD2) is a viral suppressor protein regulated by type I IFN, and it has been proven to play an important regulatory role in SLE. However, the mechanism by which RSAD2 participates in the pathogenesis of SLE is unclear. In this study, we observed higher expression levels of RSAD2 in CD4<sup>+</sup> T-cell subsets from the peripheral blood of SLE patients than in those from healthy controls by bioinformatics analysis and validation experiments. We analyzed the expression of RSAD2 in CD4<sup>+</sup> T cells of patients with SLE and other autoimmune diseases. In addition, we found that the expression of RSAD2 in CD4<sup>+</sup> T cells might be regulated by IFN-&#x3b1;, and RSAD2 significantly affected the differentiation of Th17 cells and T follicular helper (Tfh) cells. Our findings underlined that RSAD2 may promote B-cell activation by promoting the differentiation of Th17 and Tfh cells in SLE patients, a process that is regulated by IFN-&#x3b1;.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 Wiley-VCH GmbH.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xin</LastName><ForeName>Yue</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Second Xiangya Hospital, Hunan Key Laboratory of Medical Epigenomics, Central South University, Hunan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>He</LastName><ForeName>Zhenghao</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Second Xiangya Hospital, Hunan Key Laboratory of Medical Epigenomics, Central South University, Hunan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mei</LastName><ForeName>Yang</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Second Xiangya Hospital, Hunan Key Laboratory of Medical Epigenomics, Central South University, Hunan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Xi</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Second Xiangya Hospital, Hunan Key Laboratory of Medical Epigenomics, Central South University, Hunan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Zhidan</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Second Xiangya Hospital, Hunan Key Laboratory of Medical Epigenomics, Central South University, Hunan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Mingming</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Second Xiangya Hospital, Hunan Key Laboratory of Medical Epigenomics, Central South University, Hunan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Ming</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8560-0421</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Second Xiangya Hospital, Hunan Key Laboratory of Medical Epigenomics, Central South University, Hunan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Haijing</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Second Xiangya Hospital, Hunan Key Laboratory of Medical Epigenomics, Central South University, Hunan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Immunol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>1273201</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0014-2980</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D016898">Interferon-alpha</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 1.3.-</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C444427">RSAD2 protein, human</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 1.3.-</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D044925">Oxidoreductases Acting on CH-CH Group Donors</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058504" MajorTopicYN="N">Th17 Cells</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016898" MajorTopicYN="N">Interferon-alpha</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000084522" MajorTopicYN="N">T Follicular Helper Cells</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016176" MajorTopicYN="N">T-Lymphocyte Subsets</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006377" MajorTopicYN="N">T-Lymphocytes, Helper-Inducer</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D044925" MajorTopicYN="Y">Oxidoreductases Acting on CH-CH Group Donors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bioinformatics analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Biomarkers</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">RSAD2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Systemic lupus erythematosus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">T follicular helper cells</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37179450</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/eji.202350420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Gatto, M., Zen, M., Ghirardello, A., Bettio, S., Bassi, N., Iaccarino, L., Punzi, L. et&#xa0;al., Emerging and critical issues in the pathogenesis of lupus. Autoimmun. Rev. 2013. 12: 523-536.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, H., Deng, Y., Feng, Y., Long, D., Ma, K., Wang, X., Zhao, M. et&#xa0;al., Epigenetic regulation in B-cell maturation and its dysregulation in autoimmunity. Cell Mol Immunol. 2018. 15: 676-684.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simpson, N., Gatenby, P. A., Wilson, A., Malik, S., Fulcher, D. A., Tangye, S. G., Manku, H. et&#xa0;al., Expansion of circulating T cells resembling follicular helper T cells is a fixed phenotype that identifies a subset of severe systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Rheum. 2010. 62: 234-244.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao, X., Li, C., Yang, J., Wang, G., Li, C. and Xia, Y. Differences in frequency and regulation of T follicular helper cells between newly diagnosed and chronic pediatric immune thrombocytopenia. Blood Cells Mol. Dis. 2016. 61: 26-36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsu, H. C., Yang, P., Wang, J., Wu, Q., Myers, R., Chen, J., Yi, J. et&#xa0;al., Interleukin 17-producing T helper cells and interleukin 17 orchestrate autoreactive germinal center development in autoimmune BXD2 mice. Nat. Immunol. 2008. 9: 166-175.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, X., Wu, H., Qiu, H., Yang, H., Deng, Y., Zhao, M., Luo, H. et&#xa0;al. The expression of Bcl-6 in circulating follicular helper-like T cells positively correlates with the disease activity in systemic lupus erythematosus. Clin. Immunol. 2016. 173: 161-170.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song, G., Bazer, F. W. and Spencer, T. E. Pregnancy and interferon tau regulate RSAD2 and IFIH1 expression in the ovine uterus. Reproduction. 2007. 133: 285-295.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia-Romo, G. S., Caielli, S., Vega, B., Connolly, J., Allantaz, F., Xu, Z., Punaro, M. et&#xa0;al., Netting neutrophils are major inducers of type I IFN production in pediatric systemic lupus erythematosus. Sci. Transl. Med. 2011. 3: 73ra20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raterman, H. G., Vosslamber, S., de Ridder, S., Nurmohamed, M. T., Lems, W. F., Boers, M., van de Wiel, M. et&#xa0;al., The interferon type I signature towards prediction of non-response to rituximab in rheumatoid arthritis patients. Arthritis Res. Ther. 2012. 14: R95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sezin, T., Vorobyev, A., Sadik, C. D., Zillikens, D., Gupta, Y. and Ludwig, R. J. Gene expression analysis reveals novel shared gene signatures and candidate molecular mechanisms between pemphigus and systemic lupus erythematosus in CD4(+) T cells. Front. Immunol. 2017. 8: 1992.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan, H., Zhao, G., Ren, D., Liu, F., Dong, G. and Hou, Y. Gender differences of B cell signature related to estrogen-induced IFI44L/BAFF in systemic lupus erythematosus. Immunol. Lett. 2017. 181: 71-78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ota, M., Nagafuchi, Y., Hatano, H., Ishigaki, K., Terao, C., Takeshima, Y., Yanaoka, H. et&#xa0;al., Dynamic landscape of immune cell-specific gene regulation in immune-mediated diseases. Cell. 2021. 184: 3006-3021.e17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Y. F., Zhang, Y., Lin, Z., Zhang, H., Wang, T. Y., Cao, Y., Morris, D. L. et&#xa0;al., Identification of 38 novel loci for systemic lupus erythematosus and genetic heterogeneity between ancestral groups. Nat. Commun. 2021. 12: 772.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bodis, G., Toth, V. and Schwarting, A. Role of human leukocyte antigens (HLA) in autoimmune diseases. Rheumatol Ther. 2018. 5: 5-20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fanouriakis, A., Tziolos, N. andBertsias, G., Boumpas DT. Update &#x3bf;n the diagnosis and management of systemic lupus erythematosus. Ann. Rheum. Dis. 2021. 80: 14-25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu, H., Cong, J. P. and Shenk, T. Use of differential display analysis to assess the effect of human cytomegalovirus infection on the accumulation of cellular RNAs: induction of interferon-responsive RNAs. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA 1997. 94: 13985-13990.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chyuan, I. T., Tzeng, H. T. and Chen, J. Y. Signaling pathways of type I and type III interferons and targeted therapies in systemic lupus erythematosus. Cells 2019. 8: 963.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garrett-Sinha, L. A., John, S. and Gaffen, S. L.. IL-17 and the Th17 lineage in systemic lupus erythematosus. Curr. Opin. Rheumatol. 2008. 20: 519-525.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qu, N., Xu, M., Mizoguchi, I., Furusawa, J., Kaneko, K., Watanabe, K., Mizuguchi, J. et&#xa0;al., Pivotal roles of T-helper 17-related cytokines, IL-17, IL-22, and IL-23, in inflammatory diseases. Clin. Dev. Immunol. 2013. 2013: 968549.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, D., Guo, B., Wu, H., Tan, L., Chang, C. and Lu, Q. Interleukin-17 in systemic lupus erythematosus: a comprehensive review. Autoimmunity 2015. 48: 353-361.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, Z. M., Yang, X. Q., Zhu, F. H., He, S. J., Tang, W. and Zuo, J. P., Artemisinin analogue SM934 attenuate collagen-induced arthritis by suppressing T follicular helper cells and T helper 17 cells. Sci. Rep. 2016. 6: 38115.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gitlin, A. D., Mayer, C. T., Oliveira, T. Y., Shulman, Z., Jones, M. J., Koren, A. and Nussenzweig, M. C. Humoral immunity. T cell help controls the speed of the cell cycle in germinal center B cells. Science 2015. 349: 643-646.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell, D. J., Kim, C. H. and Butcher, E. C. Separable effector T cell populations specialized for B cell help or tissue inflammation. Nat. Immunol. 2001. 2: 876-881.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, X., Lindwall, E., Gauthier, C., Lyman, J., Spencer, N., Alarakhia, A., Fraser, A. et&#xa0;al., Circulating CXCR5+CD4+helper T cells in systemic lupus erythematosus patients share phenotypic properties with germinal center follicular helper T cells and promote antibody production. Lupus. 2015. 24: 909-917.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panwar, B., Schmiedel, B. J., Liang, S., White, B., Rodriguez, E., Kalunian, K., McKnight, A. J. et&#xa0;al., Multi-cell type gene coexpression network analysis reveals coordinated interferon response and cross-cell type correlations in systemic lupus erythematosus. Genome Res. 2021. 31: 659-676.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nehar-Belaid, D., Hong, S., Marches, R., Chen, G., Bolisetty, M., Baisch, J., Walters, L. et&#xa0;al., Mapping systemic lupus erythematosus heterogeneity at the single-cell level. Nat. Immunol. 2020. 21: 1094-1106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, H., Deng, Y., Long, D., Yang, M., Li, Q., Feng, Y., Chen, Y. et&#xa0;al., The IL-21-TET2-AIM2-c-MAF pathway drives the T follicular helper cell response in lupus-like disease. Clin. Transl. Med. 2022. 12: e781.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>