<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37186611</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>17</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1932-6203</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PloS one</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PLoS One</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Validation and the associated factors of the Malay version of systemic lupus erythematosus-specific health-related quality of life questionnaires (SLEQoL and LupusQoL).</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e0285461</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e0285461</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e0285461</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1371/journal.pone.0285461</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES">To assess the reliability and validity of two disease-specific questionnaires that assess the quality of life (QoL) among patients with Systemic Lupus Erythematosus (SLE); SLEQoL and LupusQoL in Malay language. This study also identified the factors affecting each domain of the questionnaires.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">This cross-sectional study was conducted from June 2021 until April 2022, and SLE patients were recruited to complete the SLEQoL, LupusQoL and Short Form Health Survey (SF-36) in Malay language. Disease activity were recorded using the modified SLE Disease Activity Index (M- SLEDAI) and British Isles Lupus Assessment Group 2004 (BILAG-2004) index. Presence of organ damage was determined using the SLICC Damage index. Cronbach's alpha was calculated to determine internal consistency while exploratory factor analysis was done to determine the construct validity. Concurrent validity was evaluated using correlation with SF-36. Multiple linear regression analysis was deployed to determine the factors affecting each domain of SLEQoL and LupusQoL.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">A total of 125 subjects were recruited. The Cronbach's &#x3b1; value for the Malay-SLEQoL (M-SLEQoL) and Malay-LupusQOL (M-LupusQoL) was 0.890 and 0.944 respectively. Exploratory factor analysis found formation of similar number of components with the original version of questionnaires and all items have good factor loading of &gt;0.4. Both instruments also had good concurrent validity with SF-36. M-SLEQoL had good correlations with BILAG-2004 and M-SLEDAI scores. Musculoskeletal (MSK) involvement was independently associated with lower M-SLEQoL in physical function, activity and symptom domains. Meanwhile, MSK and NPSLE were associated with fatigue in M-LupusQoL.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">Both M-SLEQoL and M-LupusQoL are reliable and valid as disease -specific QoL instruments for Malaysian patients. The M-Lupus QoL has better discriminative validity compared to the M-SLEQoL. SLE patients with MSK involvement are at risk of poor QoL in multiple domains including physical function, activity, symptoms and fatigue.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2023 Ahmad Pouzi et al. This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ahmad Pouzi</LastName><ForeName>Nur Aqeelah</ForeName><Initials>NA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, Universiti Kebangsaan Malaysia, Jalan Yaacob Latiff, Cheras, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shaharir</LastName><ForeName>Syahrul Sazliyana</ForeName><Initials>SS</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9068-8114</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, Universiti Kebangsaan Malaysia, Jalan Yaacob Latiff, Cheras, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mohd Tamil</LastName><ForeName>Azmi</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1657-3351</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health, Faculty of Medicine, Universiti Kebangsaan Malaysia, Jalan Yaacob Latiff, Cheras, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mustafar</LastName><ForeName>Ruslinda</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, Universiti Kebangsaan Malaysia, Jalan Yaacob Latiff, Cheras, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ahmad Maulana</LastName><ForeName>Suhaida</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Department, Hospital Tengku Ampuan Rahimah, Klang, Selangor, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mageswaren</LastName><ForeName>Eashwary</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Department, Hospital Tengku Ampuan Rahimah, Klang, Selangor, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wan Ghazali</LastName><ForeName>Wan Syamimee</ForeName><Initials>WS</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7872-4581</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, School of Medical Sciences, Health Campus, Universiti Sains Malaysia, Kubang Kerian, Kelantan, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PLoS One</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101285081</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1932-6203</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="Y">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015203" MajorTopicYN="N">Reproducibility of Results</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003430" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Sectional Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008296" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Malaysia</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012720" MajorTopicYN="N">Severity of Illness Index</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011795" MajorTopicYN="N">Surveys and Questionnaires</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007802" MajorTopicYN="N">Language</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005221" MajorTopicYN="N">Fatigue</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37186611</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10184909</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0285461</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PONE-D-22-32067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Carter EE, Barr SG, Clarke AE. The global burden of SLE: prevalence, health disparities and socioeconomic impact. Nature Reviews Rheumatology. 2016;12(10):605&#x2013;20. doi: 10.1038/nrrheum.2016.137</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrrheum.2016.137</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27558659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hyphantis T, Palieraki K, Voulgari PV, Tsifetaki N, Drosos AA. Coping with health-stressors and defence styles associated with health-related quality of life in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. Lupus. 2011;20(9):893&#x2013;903. Epub 2011/05/13. doi: 10.1177/0961203311398264 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0961203311398264</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21562019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McElhone K, Abbott J, Teh LS. A review of health related quality of life in systemic lupus erythematosus. Lupus. 2006;15(10):633&#x2013;43. Epub 2006/11/24. doi: 10.1177/0961203306071710 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0961203306071710</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17120589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strand V, Gladman D, Isenberg D, Petri M, Smolen J, Tugwell P. Endpoints: consensus recommendations from OMERACT IV. Outcome Measures in Rheumatology. Lupus. 2000;9(5):322&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1191/096120300678828424 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1191/096120300678828424</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10878722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guidance for industry: patient-reported outcome measures: use in medical product development to support labeling claims: draft guidance. Health Qual Life Outcomes. 2006;4:79. Epub 20061011. doi: 10.1186/1477-7525-4-79 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1477-7525-4-79</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1629006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17034633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>European Medicines Agency: Guideline on clinical investigation of medicinal products for the treatment of systemic lupus erythematosus and lupus nephritis. In: (CHMP) CfMPfHu, editor. 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izadi Z, Gandrup J, Katz PP, Yazdany J. Patient-reported outcome measures for use in clinical trials of SLE: a review. Lupus Science &amp; Medicine. 2018;5(1):e000279. doi: 10.1136/lupus-2018-000279</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/lupus-2018-000279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6109821</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30167315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sararaks S, Azman AB, Low LL, Rugayah B, Aziah AM, Hooi LN, et al.. Validity and reliability of the SF-36: the Malaysian context. Med J Malaysia. 2005;60(2):163&#x2013;79. Epub 2005/08/24. .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16114157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yazdany J. Health-related quality of life measurement in adult systemic lupus erythematosus: Lupus Quality of Life (LupusQoL), Systemic Lupus Erythematosus-Specific Quality of Life Questionnaire (SLEQOL), and Systemic Lupus Erythematosus Quality of Life Questionnaire (L-QoL). Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken). 2011;63 Suppl 11(0 11):S413&#x2013;S9. doi: 10.1002/acr.20636 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/acr.20636</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3437754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22588761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toloza SM, Jolly M, Alarc&#xf3;n GS. Quality-of-life measurements in multiethnic patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: cross-cultural issues. Curr Rheumatol Rep. 2010;12(4):237&#x2013;49. doi: 10.1007/s11926-010-0110-5 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11926-010-0110-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20461481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McElhone K, Abbott J, Shelmerdine J, Bruce IN, Ahmad Y, Gordon C, et al.. Development and validation of a disease-specific health-related quality of life measure, the LupusQol, for adults with systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Rheum. 2007;57(6):972&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1002/art.22881 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/art.22881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17665467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leong KP, Kong KO, Thong BY, Koh ET, Lian TY, Teh CL, et al.. Development and preliminary validation of a systemic lupus erythematosus-specific quality-of-life instrument (SLEQOL). Rheumatology (Oxford). 2005;44(10):1267&#x2013;76. Epub 20050329. doi: 10.1093/rheumatology/keh605 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/rheumatology/keh605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15797980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kong KO, Ho HJ, Howe HS, Thong BY, Lian TY, Chng HH, et al.. Cross-cultural adaptation of the Systemic Lupus Erythematosus Quality of Life Questionnaire into Chinese. Arthritis Rheum. 2007;57(6):980&#x2013;5. doi: 10.1002/art.22911 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/art.22911</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17665463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasitanon N, Wangkaew S, Puntana S, Sukitawut W, Leong KP, Louthrenoo W. The reliability, validity and responsiveness of the Thai version of Systemic Lupus Erythematosus Quality of Life (SLEQOL-TH) instrument. Lupus. 2013;22(3):289&#x2013;96. Epub 20130128. doi: 10.1177/0961203312474702 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0961203312474702</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23358871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aziz MM, Galal MAA, Elzohri MH, El-Nouby F, Leong KP. Cross-cultural adaptation and validation of Systemic Lupus Erythematosus Quality of Life questionnaire into Arabic. Lupus. 2018;27(5):780&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1177/0961203317747714 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0961203317747714</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29308728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elera-Fitzcarrald C, Fuentes A, Gonz&#xe1;lez LA, Burgos PI, Alarc&#xf3;n GS, Ugarte-Gil MF. Factors affecting quality of life in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: important considerations and potential interventions. Expert Rev Clin Immunol. 2018;14(11):915&#x2013;31. Epub 20181008. doi: 10.1080/1744666X.2018.1529566 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/1744666X.2018.1529566</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30266076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hochberg MC. Updating the American College of Rheumatology revised criteria for the classification of systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Rheum. 1997;40(9):1725. doi: 10.1002/art.1780400928 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/art.1780400928</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9324032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petri M, Orbai AM, Alarc&#xf3;n GS, Gordon C, Merrill JT, Fortin PR, et al.. Derivation and validation of the Systemic Lupus International Collaborating Clinics classification criteria for systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Rheum. 2012;64(8):2677&#x2013;86. doi: 10.1002/art.34473 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/art.34473</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3409311</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22553077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costello AB, Osborne J. Best Practices in Exploratory Factor Analysis: Four Recommendations for Getting the Most From Your Analysis. Practical Assessment, Research &amp; Evaluation. 2005;10:1&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isenberg DA, Rahman A, Allen E, Farewell V, Akil M, Bruce IN, et al.. BILAG 2004. Development and initial validation of an updated version of the British Isles Lupus Assessment Group&#x2019;s disease activity index for patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. Rheumatology (Oxford). 2005;44(7):902&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1093/rheumatology/keh624 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/rheumatology/keh624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15814577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gyori N, Giannakou I, Chatzidionysiou K, Magder L, van Vollenhoven RF, Petri M. Disease activity patterns over time in patients with SLE: analysis of the Hopkins Lupus Cohort. Lupus Sci Med. 2017;4(1):e000192. Epub 2017/03/01. doi: 10.1136/lupus-2016-000192 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/lupus-2016-000192</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5307372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28243457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yee CS, Cresswell L, Farewell V, Rahman A, Teh LS, Griffiths B, et al.. Numerical scoring for the BILAG-2004 index. Rheumatology (Oxford). 2010;49(9):1665&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1093/rheumatology/keq026 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/rheumatology/keq026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2919194</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20181671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gladman D, Ginzler E, Goldsmith C, Fortin P, Liang M, Urowitz M, et al.. The development and initial validation of the Systemic Lupus International Collaborating Clinics/American College of Rheumatology damage index for systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Rheum. 1996;39(3):363&#x2013;9. Epub 1996/03/01. doi: 10.1002/art.1780390303 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/art.1780390303</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8607884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Revicki D. Internal Consistency Reliability. In: Michalos AC, editor. Encyclopedia of Quality of Life and Well-Being Research. Dordrecht: Springer Netherlands; 2014. p. 3305&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohamad Adam B. H Y, &amp; Lee KY. A Step By Step Guide To Questionnaire Validation Research: Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia: Institute for Clinical Research, NIH MY; 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Musa AF, Yasin MSM, Smith J, Yakub MA, Nordin RB. The Malay version of SF-36 health survey instrument: testing data quality, scaling assumptions, reliability and validity in post-coronary artery bypass grafting (CABG) surgery patients at the National Heart Institute (Institut Jantung Negara&#x2014;IJN), Kuala Lumpur. Health and Quality of Life Outcomes. 2021;19(1):50. doi: 10.1186/s12955-020-01658-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12955-020-01658-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7874445</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33563262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abu Bakar F, Sazliyana Shaharir S, Mohd R, Mohamed Said MS, Rajalingham S, Wei Yen K. Burden of Systemic Lupus Erythematosus on Work Productivity and Daily Living Activity: A Cross-Sectional Study Among Malaysian Multi-Ethnic Cohort. Arch Rheumatol. 2020;35(2):205&#x2013;13. Epub 2020/08/28. doi: 10.46497/ArchRheumatol.2020.7405 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.46497/ArchRheumatol.2020.7405</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7406156</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32851369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abu Bakar F, Shaharir SS, Mohd R, Kamaruzaman L, Mohamed Said MS. Work disability in a multi-ethnic Malaysian systemic lupus erythematosus cohort: A cross-sectional study. Int J Rheum Dis. 2019;22(6):1002&#x2013;7. Epub 2019/04/11. doi: 10.1111/1756-185X.13572 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1756-185X.13572</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30968556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saddki N, Mohamad H, Yusof N, Mohamad D, Mokhtar N, Wan bakar Wz. Validity and reliability of the Malay version of Sleep Apnea Quality of Life Index&#x2014;preliminary results. Health and quality of life outcomes. 2013;11:100. doi: 10.1186/1477-7525-11-100</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1477-7525-11-100</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3710083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23786866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guadagnoli E, Velicer WF. Relation of sample size to the stability of component patterns. Psychological Bulletin. 1988;103:265&#x2013;75. doi: 10.1037/0033-2909.103.2.265</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/0033-2909.103.2.265</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3363047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abu Bakar F, Shaharir SS, Mohd R, Kamaruzaman L, Mohamed Said MS. Work disability in a multi-ethnic Malaysian systemic lupus erythematosus cohort: A cross-sectional study. International Journal of Rheumatic Diseases. 2019;22(6):1002&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1111/1756-185X.13572</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1756-185X.13572</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30968556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fischin J, Chehab G, Richter JG, Fischer-Betz R, Winkler-Rohlfing B, Willers R, et al.. Factors associated with pain coping and catastrophising in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: a cross-sectional study of the LuLa-cohort. Lupus Sci Med. 2015;2(1):e000113. Epub 20151112. doi: 10.1136/lupus-2015-000113 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/lupus-2015-000113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4654099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26629351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahieu M, Yount S, Ramsey-Goldman R. Patient-Reported Outcomes in Systemic Lupus Erythematosus. Rheum Dis Clin North Am. 2016;42(2):253&#x2013;63. Epub 2016/03/17. doi: 10.1016/j.rdc.2016.01.001 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rdc.2016.01.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4853651</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27133488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yee CS, McElhone K, Teh LS, Gordon C. Assessment of disease activity and quality of life in systemic lupus erythematosus&#x2014;New aspects. Best Pract Res Clin Rheumatol. 2009;23(4):457&#x2013;67. doi: 10.1016/j.berh.2009.01.007 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.berh.2009.01.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19591777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jolly M, Pickard AS, Wilke C, Mikolaitis RA, Teh LS, McElhone K, et al.. Lupus-specific health outcome measure for US patients: the LupusQoL-US version. Ann Rheum Dis. 2010;69(1):29&#x2013;33. doi: 10.1136/ard.2008.094763 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/ard.2008.094763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19126561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez-Rodr&#xed;guez V, Peralta-Ram&#xed;rez MI, Navarrete-Navarrete N, Callejas-Rubio JL, Santos Ruiz AM, Khamashta M. [Adaptation and validation of the Spanish version of a disease-specific quality of life measure in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: the Lupus quality of life]. Med Clin (Barc). 2010;134(1):13&#x2013;6. Epub 20090731. doi: 10.1016/j.medcli.2009.04.045 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.medcli.2009.04.045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19647276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freire EA, Bruscato A, Leite DR, Sousa TT, Ciconelli RM. Translation into Brazilian Portuguese, cultural adaptation and validatation of the systemic lupus erythematosus quality of life questionnaire (SLEQOL). Acta Reumatol Port. 2010;35(3):334&#x2013;9. .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20975636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conti F, Perricone C, Reboldi G, Gawlicki M, Bartosiewicz I, Pacucci V, et al.. Validation of a disease-specific health-related quality of life measure in adult Italian patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: LupusQoL-IT. Lupus. 2014;23(8):743&#x2013;51. doi: 10.1177/0961203314524466 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0961203314524466</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24569393</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S-l, Wu B, Leng L, Bucala R, Lu L-j. Validity of LupusQoL-China for the Assessment of Health Related Quality of Life in Chinese Patients with Systemic Lupus Erythematosus. PLoS One. 2013;8(5):e63795. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0063795</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0063795</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3662722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23717486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devilliers H, Amoura Z, Besancenot JF, Bonnotte B, Pasquali JL, Wahl D, et al.. LupusQoL-FR is valid to assess quality of life in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. Rheumatology (Oxford). 2012;51(10):1906&#x2013;15. Epub 20120722. doi: 10.1093/rheumatology/kes165 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/rheumatology/kes165</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22826305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Etchegaray-Morales I, M&#xe9;ndez-Mart&#xed;nez S, Jim&#xe9;nez-Hern&#xe1;ndez C, Mendoza-Pinto C, Alonso-Garc&#xed;a NE, Montiel-Jarqu&#xed;n A, et al.. Factors Associated with Health-Related Quality of Life in Mexican Lupus Patients Using the LupusQol. PLoS One. 2017;12(1):e0170209. Epub 20170123. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0170209 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0170209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5256863</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28114336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hosseini N, Bonakdar ZS, Gholamrezaei A, Mirbagher L. Linguistic Validation of the LupusQoL for the Assessment of Quality of Life in Iranian Patients with Systemic Lupus Erythematosus. Int J Rheumatol. 2014;2014:151530. doi: 10.1155/2014/151530 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2014/151530</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4172886</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25313310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carri&#xf3;n-Nessi FS, Marcano-Rojas MV, Romero Arocha SR, Mendoza Mill&#xe1;n DL, Forero-Pe&#xf1;a DA, Antuarez-Magallanes AW, et al.. Impact of demographic, clinical, and treatment compliance characteristics on quality of life of Venezuelan patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. BMC Rheumatology. 2022;6(1):2. doi: 10.1186/s41927-021-00232-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s41927-021-00232-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8725562</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34983688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Louthrenoo W, Kasitanon N, Morand E, Kandane-Rathnayake R. Comparison of performance of specific (SLEQOL) and generic (SF36) health-related quality of life questionnaires and their associations with disease status of systemic lupus erythematosus: a longitudinal study. Arthritis Res Ther. 2020;22(1):8. Epub 20200110. doi: 10.1186/s13075-020-2095-4 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13075-020-2095-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6954627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31924267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piga M, Congia M, Gabba A, Figus F, Floris A, Mathieu A, et al.. Musculoskeletal manifestations as determinants of quality of life impairment in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. Lupus. 2018;27(2):190&#x2013;8. Epub 20170615. doi: 10.1177/0961203317716319 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0961203317716319</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28618891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Natalucci F, Ceccarelli F, Cipriano E, Perricone C, Olivieri G, Pirone C, et al.. Joint involvement influences quality of life in systemic lupus erythematosus patients. Lupus. 2021;30(3):478&#x2013;83. Epub 20201215. doi: 10.1177/0961203320979039 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0961203320979039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33323011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orcan F. Exploratory and Confirmatory Factor Analysis: Which One to Use First? E&#x11f;itimde ve Psikolojide &#xd6;l&#xe7;me ve De&#x11f;erlendirme Dergisi. 2018:414&#x2013;21. doi: 10.21031/epod.394323</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21031/epod.394323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>