<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37183087</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>12</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1879-0267</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>54</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Injury</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Injury</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A global perspective on gun violence injuries.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>110763</StartPage><MedlinePgn>110763</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.injury.2023.04.050</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0020-1383(23)00392-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION AND DEFINITIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Civilian gunshot violence is a growing public health issue on a global scale. Treatment of patients with gunshot injuries is based on algorithms derived from military studies, but the distinct differences in weaponry, energy of injury, timing and type of care, and environment translate to a gap in knowledge. With a focus on non-accidental gunshot trauma and excluding suicide etiologies, we propose to build a collaborative research group to address important questions focused on best practices for gunshot injury patients.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PRE-HOSPITAL CARE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">There are important differences in the care of gunshot victims across the globe; some countries provide advanced interventions in the field and others deliver basic support until transport to a higher level of care in hospital. Some simple interventions include the use of extremity tourniquets and intravenous fluid support; others to consider are tranexamic acid, whole blood, and hemostatic agents.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="ACUTE TREATMENT" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Control of exsanguinating hemorrhage is a key priority for gunshot injuries. Military doctrine has evolved to prioritize exsanguination over airway or breathing as the critical first step. The X-ABC protocol focuses on exsanguinating hemorrhage, then standard evaluation of Airway, Breathing and Circulation (ABCs) to enhance survival in trauma patients. The timing of bony stabilization, in terms of damage-control vs definitive care, needs further study in this population, as does use of antibiotics for bony extremity injuries. Finally, recognition of the mental health effects of gun trauma, including post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD), anxiety disorders, substance abuse and depression is important in advocating for prevention such as implementation of social support and specific interventions.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DEFINITIVE CARE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The need for abdominal closure after exploratory laparotomy, definitive fracture treatment, and other treatment all contribute to length of stay for gunshot injured patients. Optimizing stabilization allows earlier mobilization and decreases nosocomial complications. Nerve injuries are often a source of long-term disability and their evaluation and treatment require further investigation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESOURCES AND ETHICS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">There are growing numbers of mass-casualty gunshot events, which require consideration of how to organize and use resources for treatment, including staff, operating room access, blood products, and order of treatment. Drills and planning for incident command hierarchy and communication are key to optimizing resource utilization. The ethics of choosing treatment priorities and resources are important considerations as well.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023. Published by Elsevier Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wolf</LastName><ForeName>Jennifer Moriatis</ForeName><Initials>JM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedic Surgery, Hand Surgery Fellowship, University of Chicago Medicine, 5841 S. Maryland Avenue, Room P211, Chicago, IL 60637, USA. Electronic address: jwolf@bsd.uchicago.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mathieu</LastName><ForeName>Laurent</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Hand and Upper Extremity Surgery, Edouard Herriot Hospital, 5 place d'Arsonval, Lyon 69003, France; Department of Surgery, French Military Health Service Academy, Ecole du Val-de-Gr&#xe2;ce, Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tintle</LastName><ForeName>Scott</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedic Surgery, Walter Reed National Military Medical Center, MD, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wilson</LastName><ForeName>Kenneth</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Trauma Surgery, Department of Surgery, University of Chicago Medicine, 5841 S. Maryland Avenue, Chicago, IL 60637, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Luria</LastName><ForeName>Shai</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hand and Microvascular Surgery, Hadassah University Hospital, Kiryat Hadassah, POB 12000, Jerusalem 91120, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vandentorren</LastName><ForeName>Stephanie</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Direction Scientifique et International, Sant&#xe9; Publique France, INSERM UMR 1219, Bordeaux Population Health Research Center, PHARes Team, University of Bordeaux, Bordeaux, France; Centre National de Ressources et de R&#xe9;silience Lille-Paris (CN2R), Lille, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Boussaud</LastName><ForeName>Marie</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Percy Military Hospital, 101 Avenue Henri Barbusse, Clamart 92140, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Strelzow</LastName><ForeName>Jason</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedic Surgery, Hand Surgery Fellowship, University of Chicago Medicine, 5841 S. Maryland Avenue, Room P211, Chicago, IL 60637, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Injury</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0226040</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0020-1383</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000078402" MajorTopicYN="Y">Gun Violence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058734" MajorTopicYN="N">Exsanguination</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014948" MajorTopicYN="Y">Wounds, Gunshot</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D050723" MajorTopicYN="Y">Fractures, Bone</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014754" MajorTopicYN="N">Violence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Civilian</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ethics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Firearms</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fracture</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Gunshot</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Military</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nerve</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of Competing Interest Wolf &#x2013; stock, Unify Medical, Inc; board member, American Society for Surgery of the Hand; Associate Editor, JBJS Reviews Mathieu &#x2013; nothing to declare Tintle &#x2013; board member, Society of Military Orthopaedic Surgeons; board member, American Society for Reconstructive Microsurgery Wilson &#x2013; nothing to declare Vandentorren - nothing to declare Luria &#x2013; nothing to declare Strelzow &#x2013; Consultant, Acumed, OrthoXel; Associate Editor, Journal of Hand Surgery, JBJS Reviews</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>59</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37183087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.injury.2023.04.050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0020-1383(23)00392-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>