<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37204055</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>17</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1521-4141</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>53</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of immunology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Immunol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Persistently active interferon-&#x3b3; pathway and expansion of T-bet<sup>+</sup> B cells in a subset of patients with childhood-onset systemic lupus erythematosus.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e2250319</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e2250319</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/eji.202250319</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) is an autoimmune disease causing significant morbidity and mortality, despite important improvements in its management in the last decades. The objective of this work is to investigate the role of IFN-&#x3b3; in the pathogenesis of childhood-onset systemic lupus erythematosus (cSLE), evaluating the crosstalk between IFN-&#x3b1; and IFN-&#x3b3; and the expression of T-bet, a transcription factor induced by IFN-&#x3b3;, in B cells of patients with cSLE. Expression levels of both IFN-&#x3b1; and IFN-&#x3b3;-induced genes were upregulated in patients with cSLE. We found increased serum levels of CXCL9 and CXCL10 in patients with cSLE. Type I IFN score decreased with initiation of immunosuppressive treatment; conversely, type II IFN score and levels of CXCL9 were not significantly affected by immunosuppressive treatment. Type II IFN score and CXCL9 were significantly higher in patients with lupus nephritis. We observed the expansion of a population of na&#xef;ve B cells expressing T-bet in a cluster of patients with cSLE. IFN-&#x3b3;, but not IFN-&#x3b1;, induced the expression of T-bet in B cells. Our data suggest that IFN-&#x3b3; is hyperactive in cSLE, especially in patients with lupus nephritis, and it is not modulated by therapy. Our data reinforce the potential of IFN-&#x3b3; as a therapeutic target in SLE.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Authors. European Journal of Immunology published by Wiley-VCH GmbH.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moneta</LastName><ForeName>Gian Marco</ForeName><Initials>GM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Rheumatology, Ospedale Pediatrico Bambino Ges&#xf9; IRCCS, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bracaglia</LastName><ForeName>Claudia</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Rheumatology, Ospedale Pediatrico Bambino Ges&#xf9; IRCCS, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Caiello</LastName><ForeName>Ivan</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Rheumatology, Ospedale Pediatrico Bambino Ges&#xf9; IRCCS, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Farroni</LastName><ForeName>Chiara</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>B Cell Physiopathology Unit, Ospedale Pediatrico Bambino Ges&#xf9;, IRCCS, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pires Marafon</LastName><ForeName>Denise</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Rheumatology, Ospedale Pediatrico Bambino Ges&#xf9; IRCCS, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Carlomagno</LastName><ForeName>Raffella</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Rheumatology, SickKids Hospital, Toronto, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hiraki</LastName><ForeName>Linda</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Rheumatology, SickKids Hospital, Toronto, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vivarelli</LastName><ForeName>Marina</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Nephrology and Dialysis, Department of Pediatric Subspecialties, Ospedale Pediatrico Bambino Ges&#xf9; IRCCS, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gianviti</LastName><ForeName>Alessandra</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Nephrology and Dialysis, Department of Pediatric Subspecialties, Ospedale Pediatrico Bambino Ges&#xf9; IRCCS, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Carbogno</LastName><ForeName>Simone</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Rheumatology, Ospedale Pediatrico Bambino Ges&#xf9; IRCCS, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ferlin</LastName><ForeName>Walter</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Light Chain Bioscience - Novimmune SA, Plan-Les-Ouates Geneva, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>de Min</LastName><ForeName>Cristina</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Novimmune, Geneva, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Silverman</LastName><ForeName>Earl</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Rheumatology, SickKids Hospital, Toronto, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Carsetti</LastName><ForeName>Rita</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>B Cell Physiopathology Unit, Ospedale Pediatrico Bambino Ges&#xf9;, IRCCS, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>De Benedetti</LastName><ForeName>Fabrizio</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Rheumatology, Ospedale Pediatrico Bambino Ges&#xf9; IRCCS, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Marasco</LastName><ForeName>Emiliano</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Rheumatology, Ospedale Pediatrico Bambino Ges&#xf9; IRCCS, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Immunol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>1273201</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0014-2980</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>82115-62-6</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D007371">Interferon-gamma</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D014157">Transcription Factors</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D007370">Interferon Type I</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007371" MajorTopicYN="N">Interferon-gamma</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008181" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lupus Nephritis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014157" MajorTopicYN="N">Transcription Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007370" MajorTopicYN="Y">Interferon Type I</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">IFN-&#x3b3;</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SLE</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">T-bet+ B cells</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lupus nephritis</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37204055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/eji.202250319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Tsokos, G. C., Systemic lupus erythematosus. N. Engl. J. Med. 2011. 365(22):2110-2121.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crow, M. K., Type I interferon in the pathogenesis of lupus. J. Immunol. 2014. 192(12):5459-5468.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Theofilopoulos, A. N., Koundouris, S., Kono, D. H. and Lawson, B. R., The role of IFN-gamma in systemic lupus erythematosus: a challenge to the Th1/Th2 paradigm in autoimmunity. Arthritis Res. 2001. 3(3):136-141.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bennett, L., Palucka, A. K., Arce, E., Cantrell, V., Borvak, J., Banchereau, J. and Pascual, V., Interferon and granulopoiesis signatures in systemic lupus erythematosus blood. J. Exp. Med. 2003. 197(6):711-723.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baechler, E. C., Batliwalla, F. M., Karypis, G., Gaffney, P. M., Ortmann, W. A., Espe, K. J., Shark, K. B. et&#xa0;al., Interferon-inducible gene expression signature in peripheral blood cells of patients with severe lupus. Proc. Nat. Acad. Sci. USA. 2003. 100(5):2610-2615.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han, G. M., Chen, S. L., Shen, N., Ye, S., Bao, C. D. and Gu, Y. Y., Analysis of gene expression profiles in human systemic lupus erythematosus using oligonucleotide microarray. Genes Immun. 2003. 4(3):177-186.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crow, M. K., Kirou, K. A. and Wohlgemuth, J., Microarray analysis of interferon-regulated genes in SLE. Autoimmunity. 2003. 36(8):481-490.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiche, L., Jourde-Chiche, N., Whalen, E., Presnell, S., Gersuk, V., Dang, K., Anguiano, E. et&#xa0;al., Modular transcriptional repertoire analyses of adults with systemic lupus erythematosus reveal distinct type I and type II interferon signatures. Arthritis Rheumatol. 2014. 66(6):1583-1595.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munroe, M. E., Lu, R., Zhao, Y. D., Fife, D. A., Robertson, J. M., Guthridge, J. M., Niewold, T. B. et&#xa0;al., Altered type II interferon precedes autoantibody accrual and elevated type I interferon activity prior to systemic lupus erythematosus classification. Ann. Rheum. Dis. 2016. 75(11):2014-2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knox, J. J., Buggert, M., Kardava, L., Seaton, K. E., Eller, M. A., Canaday, D. H., Robb, M. L. et&#xa0;al., T-bet+ B cells are induced by human viral infections and dominate the HIV gp140 response. JCI Insight. 2017. 2(8):e92943.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keller, B., Strohmeier, V., Harder, I., Unger, S., Payne, K. J., Andrieux, G., Boerries, M. et&#xa0;al., The expansion of human T-bet(high)CD21(low) B cells is T cell dependent. Sci. Immunol. 2021. 6(64):eabh0891.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jenks, S. A., Cashman, K. S., Zumaquero, E., Marigorta, U. M., Patel, A. V., Wang, X., Tomar, D. et&#xa0;al., Distinct effector B cells induced by unregulated Toll-like receptor 7 contribute to pathogenic responses in systemic lupus erythematosus. Immunity 2018. 49(4):725-739.e6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zumaquero, E., Stone, S. L., Scharer, C. D., Jenks, S. A., Nellore, A., Mousseau, B., Rosal-Vela, A. et&#xa0;al., IFN&#x3b3; induces epigenetic programming of human T-bet(hi) B cells and promotes TLR7/8 and IL-21 induced differentiation. Elife. 2019. 8:e41641.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rubtsov, A. V., Rubtsova, K., Fischer, A., Meehan, R. T., Gillis, J. Z., Kappler, J. W. and Marrack, P., Toll-like receptor 7 (TLR7)-driven accumulation of a novel CD11c&#x207a; B-cell population is important for the development of autoimmunity. Blood. 2011. 118(5):1305-1315.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hao, Y., O'Neill, P., Naradikian, M. S., Scholz, J. L. and Cancro, M. P., A B-cell subset uniquely responsive to innate stimuli accumulates in aged mice. Blood. 2011. 118(5):1294-304.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Obeng-Adjei, N., Portugal, S., Holla, P., Li, S., Sohn, H., Ambegaonkar, A., Skinner, J. et&#xa0;al., Malaria-induced interferon-&#x3b3; drives the expansion of Tbethi atypical memory B cells. PLoS Pathog. 2017. 13(9):e1006576.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naradikian, M. S., Myles, A., Beiting, D. P., Roberts, K. J., Dawson, L., Herati, R. S., Bengsch, B. et&#xa0;al., Cutting edge: IL-4, IL-21, and IFN-&#x3b3; interact to govern T-bet and CD11c expression in TLR-activated B cells. J. Immunol. 2016. 197(4):1023-1028.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rice, G. I., Forte, G. M., Szynkiewicz, M., Chase, D. S., Aeby, A., Abdel-Hamid, M.S., Ackroyd, S. et&#xa0;al., Assessment of interferon-related biomarkers in Aicardi-Gouti&#xe8;res syndrome associated with mutations in TREX1, RNASEH2A, RNASEH2B, RNASEH2C, SAMHD1, and ADAR: a case-control study. Lancet Neurol. 2013. 12(12):1159-1169.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bracaglia, C., de Graaf, K., Pires Marafon, D., Guilhot, F., Ferlin, W., Prencipe, G., Caiello, I. et&#xa0;al., Elevated circulating levels of interferon-&#x3b3; and interferon-&#x3b3;-induced chemokines characterise patients with macrophage activation syndrome complicating systemic juvenile idiopathic arthritis. Ann. Rheum. Dis. 2017. 76(1):166-172.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moneta, G. M., Pires Marafon, D., Marasco, E., Rosina, S., Verardo, M., Fiorillo, C., Minetti, C. et&#xa0;al., Muscle expression of type I and type II interferons is increased in juvenile dermatomyositis and related to clinical and histologic features. Arthritis Rheumatol. 2019. 71(6):1011-1021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Padovan, E., Spagnoli, G. C., Ferrantini, M. and Heberer, M., IFN-alpha2a induces IP-10/CXCL10 and MIG/CXCL9 production in monocyte-derived dendritic cells and enhances their capacity to attract and stimulate CD8+ effector T cells. J. Leukocyte Biol. 2002. 71(4):669-676.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Landolt-Marticorena, C., Bonventi, G., Lubovich, A., Ferguson, C., Unnithan, T., Su, J., Gladman, D. D. et&#xa0;al., Lack of association between the interferon-alpha signature and longitudinal changes in disease activity in systemic lupus erythematosus. Ann. Rheum. Dis. 2009. 68(9):1440-1446.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petri, M., Fu, W., Ranger, A., Allaire, N., Cullen, P., Magder, L. S., Zhang, Y. et&#xa0;al., Association between changes in gene signatures expression and disease activity among patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. BMC Med. Genet. 2019. 12(1):4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yee, C. S., Farewell, V., Isenberg, D. A., Griffiths, B., Teh, L. S., Bruce, I. N., Ahmad, Y. et&#xa0;al., The BILAG-2004 index is sensitive to change for assessment of SLE disease activity. Rheumatology 2009. 48(6):691-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rubtsova, K., Rubtsov, A. V., Thurman, J. M., Mennona, J. M. and Kappler, J. W., Marrack P. B cells expressing the transcription factor T-bet drive lupus-like autoimmunity. J. Clin. Invest. 2017. 127(4):1392-1404.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Domeier, P. P., Chodisetti, S. B., Soni, C., Schell, S. L., Elias, M. J., Wong, E. B., Cooper, T. K. et&#xa0;al., IFN-&#x3b3; receptor and STAT1 signaling in B cells are central to spontaneous germinal center formation and autoimmunity. J. Exp. Med. 2016. 213(5):715-732.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson, S. W., Jacobs, H. M., Arkatkar, T., Dam, E. M., Scharping, N. E., Kolhatkar, N. S., Hou, B. et&#xa0;al., B cell IFN-&#x3b3; receptor signaling promotes autoimmune germinal centers via cell-intrinsic induction of BCL-6. J. Exp. Med. 2016. 213(5):733-750.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tipton, C. M., Fucile, C. F., Darce, J., Chida, A., Ichikawa, T., Gregoretti, I., Schieferl, S. et&#xa0;al., Diversity, cellular origin and autoreactivity of antibody-secreting cell population expansions in acute systemic lupus erythematosus. Nat. Immunol. 2015. 16(7):755-765.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarkar, M. K., Hile, G. A., Tsoi, L. C., Xing, X., Liu, J., Liang, Y., Berthier, C. C. et&#xa0;al., Photosensitivity and type I IFN responses in cutaneous lupus are driven by epidermal-derived interferon kappa. Ann. Rheum. Dis. 2018. 77(11):1653-1664.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fava, A., Buyon, J., Mohan, C., Zhang, T., Belmont, H. M., Izmirly, P., Clancy, R. et&#xa0;al., Integrated urine proteomics and renal single-cell genomics identify an IFN-&#x3b3; response gradient in lupus nephritis. JCI Insight 2020. 5(12).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boedigheimer, M. J., Martin, D. A., Amoura, Z., S&#xe1;nchez-Guerrero, J., Romero-Diaz, J., Kivitz, A., Aranow, C. et&#xa0;al., Safety, pharmacokinetics and pharmacodynamics of AMG 811, an anti-interferon-&#x3b3; monoclonal antibody, in SLE subjects without or with lupus nephritis. Lupus Sci. Med. 2017. 4(1):e000226.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malkiel, S., Jeganathan, V., Wolfson, S., Manjarrez Ordu&#xf1;o, N., Marasco, E., Aranow, C., Aranow, C. et&#xa0;al., Checkpoints for autoreactive B cells in the peripheral blood of lupus patients assessed by flow cytometry. Arthritis Rheumatol. 2016. 68(9):2210-2220.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suurmond, J., Atisha-Fregoso, Y., Marasco, E., Barlev, A. N., Ahmed, N., Calderon, S. A., Wong, M. Y. et&#xa0;al., Loss of an IgG plasma cell checkpoint in patients with lupus. J. Allergy Clin. Immunol. 2019. 143(4):1586-1597.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banchereau, R., Hong, S., Cantarel, B., Baldwin, N., Baisch, J., Edens, M., Cepika, A. M. et&#xa0;al., Personalized immunomonitoring uncovers molecular networks that stratify lupus patients. Cell 2016. 165(3):551-565.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobi, A. M., Odendahl, M., Reiter, K., Bruns, A., Burmester, G. R., Radbruch, A., Valet, G. et&#xa0;al., Correlation between circulating CD27high plasma cells and disease activity in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Rheum. 2003. 48(5):1332-1342.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knox, J. J., Cosma, G. L., Betts, M. R. and McLane, L. M., Characterization of T-bet and eomes in peripheral human immune cells. Front. Immunol. 2014. 5:217.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson, J. L., Rosenthal, R. L., Knox, J. J., Myles, A., Naradikian, M. S., Madej, J., Kostiv, M. et&#xa0;al., The transcription factor T-bet resolves memory B cell subsets with distinct tissue distributions and antibody specificities in mice and humans. Immunity 2020. 52(5):842-855.e6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karnell, J. L., Kumar, V., Wang, J., Wang, S., Voynova, E. and Ettinger, R., Role of CD11c(+) T-bet(+) B cells in human health and disease. Cell. Immunol. 2017. 321:40-45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cossarizza, A., Chang, H. D., Radbruch, A., Abrignani, S., Addo, R., Akdis, M., Andr&#xe4;, I. et&#xa0;al., Guidelines for the use of flow cytometry and cell sorting in immunological studies (third edition). Eur. J. Immunol. 2021. 51(12):2708-3145.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bendixen, M. T., Compositional perceptual mapping using chi-squared trees analysis and correspondence analysis. J. Market. Manage. 1995. 11:571-581.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>