<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37224030</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>26</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1165-158X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>69</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>28</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cellular and molecular biology (Noisy-le-Grand, France)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cell Mol Biol (Noisy-le-grand)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Inflammatory mediators and immune function in different stages of systemic lupus erythematosus.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>150</StartPage><EndPage>156</EndPage><MedlinePgn>150-156</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.14715/cmb/2023.69.2.25</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This study aimed to study the relationship between the expression levels of inflammatory mediators IL-36&#x3b2; and IL-36R and disease symptoms, laboratory indices and somatic immune function in Systemic Lupus Erythematosus (SLE) of different stages. In this research 70 patients with SLE who were treated in public hospitals from February 2020 to December 2021 were randomly divided into the stable group (n=35) and active group (n=35), and serum IL-36 was measured in the two groups &#x3b2; and IL-36R concentration with the standard curve of Enzyme-Linked Immunosorbent Assay (ELISA) to analyze IL-36&#x3b2; and IL-36R concentrations. 36&#x3b2; and IL-36R concentrations were analyzed in relation to the Disease activity score of systemic lupus erythematosus (SLEDAI), disease duration, typical symptoms of SLE and experimental characteristics. Results showed that the differences in IL-36&#x3b2; and IL-36R concentrations between the stable and active groups overall and for each disease duration group were tiny. There was no significant correlation between serum IL-36&#x3b2; and IL-36R concentrations and SLEDAI scores in stable and active patients, and a negative correlation between them and disease duration. Serum inflammatory mediator IL-36R concentrations were significantly higher in patients with mucosal ulcers and the difference was statistically significant. differences in IL-36&#x3b2; concentrations were statistically significant only for indicators of decreased erythrocyte count and IL-36R concentrations were statistically significant for indicators of decreased erythrocyte count, decreased haemoglobin and decreased lymphocytes The differences were huge and tiny in C4 decline, anti-dsDNA, and urinary routine protein. There was a significant positive correlation between IL-36&#x3b2; and IL-36R concentrations in patients with stable and active SLE, with correlation coefficients of 0.448 and 0.452 respectively. The differences in IL-36&#x3b2; and IL-36R concentrations between the stable and active groups were tiny for patients in the stable and active groups as a whole and for all disease groups. The differences in the number of each inflammatory mediator positive cells in the epidermal stratum corneum and superficial dermis between patients in the stable and active groups were tiny. In conclusion, IL-36&#x3b2; and IL-36R proteins in SLE patients are expressed in immune cells as well as epithelial cells of patients, indicating that these two inflammatory mediators may be one of the early signals that activate the immune system of SLE patients and trigger the immune response of patients; the onset of SLE may be associated with the inflammatory response induced by IL-36&#x3b2; and IL-36R.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Lixiu</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rheumatology, Ningde Municipal Hospital of Ningde Normal University, Ningde, 352100, China. aries5285107@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Sujuan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathology, Ningde Municipal Hospital of Ningde Normal University, Ningde, 352100, China. zhousujuan2179@126.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lin</LastName><ForeName>Ye</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rheumatology, Ningde Municipal Hospital of Ningde Normal University, Ningde, 352100, China. lyquke1@hotmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ye</LastName><ForeName>Zhen</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rheumatology, Ningde Municipal Hospital of Ningde Normal University, Ningde, 352100, China. yezhien573989040@126.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tang</LastName><ForeName>Yirong</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rheumatology, Ningde Municipal Hospital of Ningde Normal University, Ningde, 352100, China. zntyr@126.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Renli</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rheumatology, Ningde Municipal Hospital of Ningde Normal University, Ningde, 352100, China. rlc@medmail.com.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>France</Country><MedlineTA>Cell Mol Biol (Noisy-le-grand)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9216789</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0145-5680</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D018836">Inflammation Mediators</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004797" MajorTopicYN="N">Enzyme-Linked Immunosorbent Assay</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004847" MajorTopicYN="Y">Epithelial Cells</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018836" MajorTopicYN="N">Inflammation Mediators</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007109" MajorTopicYN="N">Immunity</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37224030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14715/cmb/2023.69.2.25</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>