<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37257084</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2163-0763</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>95</Volume><Issue>2S Suppl 1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The journal of trauma and acute care surgery</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Trauma Acute Care Surg</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Operative management and outcomes of colorectal injuries after gunshot wounds in the deployed military setting versus civilian trauma centers.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>S60</StartPage><EndPage>S65</EndPage><MedlinePgn>S60-S65</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/TA.0000000000004016</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION">Colon and rectal injuries have been diverted at higher rates in military trauma compared with civilian injuries. However, in the last few years, there has been a shift to more liberal primary anastomosis in wartime injuries. The purpose of this study was to compare the management and outcomes in colorectal gunshot wounds (GSWs) between military and civilian settings.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">The study included Department of Defense Trauma Registry and Trauma Quality Improvement Program database patients who sustained colorectal GSWs, during the period 2013 to 2016. Department of Defense Trauma Registry patients were propensity score matched 1:3 based on age, sex, grade of colorectal injury, and extra-abdominal Abbreviated Injury Scale. Patients without signs of life, transfers from an outside hospital, and nonspecific colorectal Organ Injury Scale were excluded. Operative management and outcomes were compared between the two groups. Subanalysis was performed on the military cohort to identify any differences in the use primary repair, colectomy, or fecal diversion based upon military affiliation or North Atlantic Treaty Organization status.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Overall, there were 2,693 patients with colorectal GSWs; 60 patients in the military group were propensity score matched with 180 patients in the civilian group. Overall, colectomy was the most common procedure performed (72.1%) and was used more frequently in the military group (83.3% vs. 68.3%; p &lt; 0.05). However, the rate of fecal diversion was similar in the two groups (23.3% vs. 27.8%; p = 0.500). Among those in the military group, no difference was seen in primary repair, colectomy, or fecal diversion based upon military affiliation or North Atlantic Treaty Organization status. The rates of in-hospital compilations and mortality were similar between the military and civilian groups.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">The severity of GSW colorectal injuries in military and civilian trauma was comparable. There was no significant difference in terms of fecal diversion, mortality, and complications between groups. Military personnel are treated similarly regardless of affiliation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="LEVEL OF EVIDENCE">Therapeutic/Care Management; Level III.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 The Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dilday</LastName><ForeName>Joshua</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Division of Trauma and Surgical Critical Care (J.D., N.O., S.B., D.D.), LAC+USC Medical Center, University of Southern California, Los Angeles, California; Division of Trauma and Surgical Critical Care (E.R.B.), Grady Memorial Hospital, Atlanta, Georgia; and Defense Health Agency (S.S.), Colorado Springs, Colorado.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Owattanapanich</LastName><ForeName>Natthida</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Benjamin</LastName><ForeName>Elizabeth R</ForeName><Initials>ER</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Biswas</LastName><ForeName>Subarna</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shackelford</LastName><ForeName>Stacy</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Demetriades</LastName><ForeName>Demetrios</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Trauma Acute Care Surg</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101570622</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2163-0755</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014948" MajorTopicYN="Y">Wounds, Gunshot</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000601" MajorTopicYN="N">surgery</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008889" MajorTopicYN="Y">Military Personnel</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014193" MajorTopicYN="N">Trauma Centers</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015179" MajorTopicYN="Y">Colorectal Neoplasms</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015601" MajorTopicYN="N">Injury Severity Score</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37257084</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10389307</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/TA.0000000000004016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">01586154-990000000-00378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Office of the Surgeon General, Circular Letter No 178, October 23, 1943. Available at: https://achh.army.mil/history/book-wwii-standarizedcare-cl178l. Accessed January 30, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stone HH, Fabian TC. Management of perforating colon trauma: randomization between primary closure and exteriorization. Ann Surg. 1979;190(4):430&#x2013;436.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1344502</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">384941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chappuis CW, Frey DJ, Dietzen CD, Panetta TP, Buechter KJ, Cohn I, Jr. Management of penetrating colon injuries. A prospective randomized trial. Ann Surg. 1991;213(5):492&#x2013;497; discussion 7-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1358480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2025069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sasaki LS, Allaben RD, Golwala R, Mittal VK. Primary repair of colon injuries: a prospective randomized study. J Trauma. 1995;39(5):895&#x2013;901.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7474005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez RP, Falimirski ME, Holevar MR. Further evaluation of colostomy in penetrating colon injury. Am Surg. 2000;66(4):342&#x2013;346; discussion 6-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10776870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cullinane DC Jawa RS Como JJ Moore AE Morris DS Cheriyan J, et al. . Management of penetrating intraperitoneal colon injuries: a meta-analysis and practice management guideline from the Eastern Association for the Surgery of Trauma. J Trauma Acute Care Surg. 2019;86(3):505&#x2013;515.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30789470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demetriades D Murray JA Chan L Ordo&#xf1;ez C Bowley D Nagy KK, et al. . Penetrating colon injuries requiring resection: diversion or primary anastomosis? An AAST prospective multicenter study. J Trauma. 2001;50(5):765&#x2013;775.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11371831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watson JDB, Aden JK, Engel JE, Rasmussen TE, Glasgow SC. Risk factors for colostomy in military colorectal trauma: a review of 867 patients. Surgery. 2014;155(6):1052&#x2013;1061.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24856125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duncan JE Corwin CH Sweeney WB Dunne JR Denobile JW Perdue PW, et al. . Management of colorectal injuries during operation iraqi freedom: patterns of stoma usage. J Trauma. 2008;64(4):1043&#x2013;1047.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18404073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damage Control Laparotomy In: Cubano MA, Butler FK. eds. Emergency War Surgery - 4th ed. Ft. Sam Houston, TX: Borden Institute; 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cho SD, Kiraly LN, Flaherty SF, Herzig DO, Lu KC, Schreiber MA. Management of colonic injuries in the combat theater. Dis Colon Rectum. 2010;53(5):728&#x2013;734.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20389206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greer LT, Gillern SM, Vertrees AE. Evolving colon injury management: a review. Am Surg. 2013;79(2):119&#x2013;127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23336650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hudolin T, Hudolin I. The role of primary repair for colonic injuries in wartime. Br J Surg. 2005;92(5):643&#x2013;647.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15800953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steele SR Wolcott KE Mullenix PS Martin MJ Sebesta JA Azarow KS, et al. . Colon and rectal injuries during Operation Iraqi Freedom: are there any changing trends in management or outcome? Dis Colon Rectum. 2007;50(6):870&#x2013;877.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17468976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller PR, Chang MC, Hoth JJ, Holmes JH, 4th, Meredith JW. Colonic resection in the setting of damage control laparotomy: is delayed anastomosis safe? Am Surg. 2007;73(6):606&#x2013;609; discussion 9-10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17658099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stewart RM, Fabian TC, Croce MA, Pritchard FE, Minard G, Kudsk KA. Is resection with primary anastomosis following destructive colon wounds always safe? Am J Surg. 1994;168(4):316&#x2013;319.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7943586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murray JA Demetriades D Colson M Song Z Velmahos GC Cornwell EE 3rd, et al. . Colonic resection in trauma: colostomy versus anastomosis. J Trauma. 1999;46(2):250&#x2013;254.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10029029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tatebe LC Jennings A Tatebe K Handy A Prajapati P Smith M, et al. . Traumatic colon injury in damage control laparotomy&#x2014;a multicenter trial: is it safe to do a delayed anastomosis? J Trauma Acute Care Surg. 2017;82(4):742&#x2013;749.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28323788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang MH, Wong JSH, Chia CLK, Lee DJK. Meta-analysis on surgical management of colonic injuries in trauma: to divert or to anastomose? Eur J Trauma Emerg Surg. 2021;47(5):1381&#x2013;1388.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33394062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller PR Fabian TC Croce MA Magnotti LJ Pritchard FE Minard G, et al. . Improving outcomes following penetrating colon wounds: application of a clinical pathway. Ann Surg. 2002;235(6):775&#x2013;781.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1422506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12035033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Talving P Chouliaras K Eastman A Lauerman M Teixeira PG DuBose J, et al. . Discontinuity of the bowel following damage control operation revisited: a multi-institutional study. World J Surg. 2017;41(1):146&#x2013;151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27541027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glasgow SC, Steele SR, Duncan JE, Rasmussen TE. Epidemiology of modern battlefield colorectal trauma: a review of 977 coalition casualties. J Trauma Acute Care Surg. 2012;73(6 Suppl 5):S503&#x2013;S508.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23192077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>