<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37263647</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0315-162X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>50</Volume><Issue>7 Suppl 1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Journal of rheumatology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Rheumatol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Canadian Rheumatology Association Meeting Quebec City Convention Centre Quebec City, Quebec, Canada February 8-11, 2023.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>7</StartPage><EndPage>100</EndPage><MedlinePgn>7-100</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3899/jrheum.2023-0216</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The 77th Annual Meeting of the Canadian Rheumatology Association was held both in person at the Quebec City Convention Centre in Quebec City, Quebec, Canada, and virtually on February 8-11, 2023. The program consisted of presentations covering original research, symposia, awards, and lectures. Highlights of the meeting include the following 2023 Award Winners: Distinguished Rheumatologist, Gilles Boire; Distinguished Investigator, Murray Baron; Distinguished Teacher-Educator, Janet Pope; Emerging Investigator, Lihi Eder; Emerging Teacher-Educator, Steven Thomson; Ian Watson Award for the Best Abstract on SLE Research by a Trainee, Laura Whittall-Garcia; Phil Rosen Award for the Best Abstract on Clinical or Epidemiology Research by a Trainee, Timothy Kwok; Best Abstract on Research by a Rheumatology Resident, Mats Junek; Best Abstract on Basic Science Research by a Trainee, Marie-H&#xe9;l&#xe8;ne Normand; Best Abstract by a Post-Graduate Research Trainee, Leah Flatman; Best Abstract on Quality Care Initiatives in Rheumatology, Amanda Steiman; Best Abstract by a Medical Student, Shakeel Subdar; Best Abstract by an Undergraduate Student, Jeremiah Tan; Best Abstract by a Rheumatology Post-Graduate Research Trainee, Nicole Andersen; Best Abstract on Research by Young Faculty, Alexandra Legge; Best Abstract on Spondyloarthritis Research, Patricia Remalante-Rayco; Practice Reflection Award, Gold, Carrie Ye and Janet Roberts; Practice Reflection Award, Silver, Lillian Lim. Lectures and other events included: Keynote Lecture by Fiona Rawle: Communicating Science to Patients: Complexities &amp; Caveats; Keynote Address by Murray Baron, Distinguished Investigator Awardee: New Outcome Measures for Systemic Sclerosis; State of the Art Lecture by John Isaacs: Precision Medicine in RA - The Precision Gap; Dunlop-Dottridge Lecture by Rae Yeung: What's in a Name? That Which We Call JIA, By Any Other Name, Would It Still Be the Same Childhood Arthritis?; and the Great Debate: Be it Resolved that Canadians With New Inflammatory Arthritis Should Have Access to All Therapeutic Options at Disease Onset to Induce Remission. Arguing for: Cory Baillie and Anne MacLeod, and against: Michelle Batthish and Louis Bessette. Topics including rheumatoid arthritis, systemic lupus erythematosus, systemic sclerosis, Sj&#xf6;gren syndrome, psoriatic arthritis, spondyloarthritis, vasculitis, osteoarthritis, fibromyalgia, and their respective diagnoses, treatments, and outcomes are reflected in the abstracts, which we are pleased to publish in this issue of <i>The Journal of Rheumatology</i>.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 by The Journal of Rheumatology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><CollectiveName>Canadian Rheumatology Association</CollectiveName></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Canada</Country><MedlineTA>J Rheumatol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7501984</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0315-162X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012219" MajorTopicYN="Y">Rheumatology</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011792" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Quebec</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002170" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Canada</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015535" MajorTopicYN="Y">Arthritis, Psoriatic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D025241" MajorTopicYN="Y">Spondylarthritis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37263647</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3899/jrheum.2023-0216</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">jrheum.2023-0216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>