<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37283176</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>11</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1477-0962</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>32</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Lupus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Lupus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Post-COVID-19 depression and anxiety in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>974</StartPage><EndPage>982</EndPage><MedlinePgn>974-982</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/09612033231181663</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This study aimed to evaluate depression and anxiety in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) in the post-coronavirus disease-2019 (COVID-19) period and their potential association with the disease activity and related organ damage.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PATIENTS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This is a case-control study including 120 adult Egyptian patients with SLE: sixty patients with SLE who were proven previously to be positive for severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus-2 (SARS-CoV-2) by polymerase chain reaction (PCR) and recovered during the 3&#xa0;months prior to the study were included in the case group and an equal number of age- and sex-matched patients with SLE and no evidence of SARS-CoV-2 infection were included in the control group. Patients' clinical history was collected, and they underwent clinical evaluation, including SLE disease activity, damage assessment, and psychological assessment.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The mean depression and anxiety scores were significantly higher in cases than in the control group. Both scores showed a significant positive correlation with age, disease duration, the Systemic Lupus International Collaborating Clinics/American College of Rheumatology (SLICC/ACR) Damage Index for SLE (SDI), and SLE disease activity index (SLEDAI) and a significant negative correlation with education years. Hierarchical multivariate regression analyses revealed that COVID-19 infection was a predictor for severe depression and moderate-to-severe anxiety.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Patients with SLE, who are already vulnerable to physiological stressors, are especially predisposed to more risk of anxiety and depression when they are contracted with COVID-19 disease. Furthermore, anxiety and depression are associated with SLE activity and damage scores, and COVID-19 infection is a significant predictor for their severity. These results suggest that healthcare providers should give special attention to the mental health of SLE patients, especially during the COVID-19 pandemic.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abd El-Khalik</LastName><ForeName>Dina M</ForeName><Initials>DM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1002-050X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Rheumatology Division, Ain Shams University Faculty of Medicine, Cairo, Egypt.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">68792</Identifier></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Rheumatology Division, Armed Forces College of Medicine, Cairo, Egypt.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">533144</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Eltohamy</LastName><ForeName>Mohamed</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Armed Forces College of Medicine, Cairo, Egypt.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">533144</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Lupus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9204265</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0961-2033</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003863" MajorTopicYN="N">Depression</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016022" MajorTopicYN="N">Case-Control Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058873" MajorTopicYN="N">Pandemics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001007" MajorTopicYN="N">Anxiety</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012720" MajorTopicYN="N">Severity of Illness Index</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Systemic lupus erythematosus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anxiety</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">depression</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The author(s) declared no potential conflicts of interest with respect to the research, authorship, and/or publication of this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37283176</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10251064</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/09612033231181663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Parks CG, Santos A, Barbhaiya M, et al.Understanding the role of environmental factors in the development of systemic lupus erythematosus. Best Pract Res Clin Rheumatol 2017; 31: 306&#x2013;320.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5729939</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29224673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali A, Sayyed Z, Ameer MA, et al.Systemic lupus erythematosus: an overview of the disease pathology and its management. Cureus 2018; 10: e3288.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6235637</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30443458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaul A, Gordon C, Crow MK, et al.Systemic lupus erythematosus. Nat Rev Dis Primers 2016; 2: 1&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27306639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petri M, Kawata AK, Fernandes AW, et al.Impaired health status and the effect of pain and fatigue on functioning in clinical trial patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. J Rheumatol 2013; 40: 1865&#x2013;1874.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24085548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zamora-Racaza G, Azizoddin DR, Ishimori ML, et al.Role of psychosocial reserve capacity in anxiety and depression in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. Int J Rheum Dis 2018; 21: 850&#x2013;858.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28261991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Figueiredo-Braga M, Cornaby C, Cortez A, et al.Depression and anxiety in systemic lupus erythematosus: the crosstalk between immunological, clinical, and psychosocial factors. Medicine (Baltimore) 2018; 97: e11376.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6076116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29995777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zucchi D, Tani C, Elefante E, et al.Impact of first wave of SARS-CoV-2 infection in patients with Systemic Lupus Erythematosus: weighting the risk of infection and flare. PLoS One 2021; 16: e0245274.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7806138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33439910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kastritis E, Kitas GD, Vassilopoulos D, et al.Systemic autoimmune diseases, anti-rheumatic therapies, COVID-19 infection risk and patient outcomes. Rheumatol Int 2020; 40: 1353&#x2013;1360.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7353833</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32654078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathian A, Mahevas M, Rohmer J, et al.Clinical course of coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) in a series of 17 patients with systemic lupus erythematosus under long-term treatment with hydroxychloroquine. Ann Rheum Dis 2020; 79: 837&#x2013;839.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32332072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bozzalla Cassione E, Zanframundo G, Biglia A, et al.COVID-19 infection in a northern-Italian cohort of systemic lupus erythematosus assessed by telemedicine. Ann Rheum Dis 2020; 7: 1382&#x2013;1383.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32398281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang C, Pan R, Wan X, et al.Immediate psychological responses and associated factors during the initial stage of the 2019 coronavirus disease (COVID-19) epidemic among the general population in China. Int J Environ Res Public Health 2020; 1: 1729.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7084952</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32155789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santos-Ruiz A, Montero-L&#xf3;pez E, Ortego-Centeno N, et al.Effect of COVID-19 confinement on the mental status of patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. Med Clin (Barc) 2021; 156(8): 379&#x2013;385.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7846210</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33632510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hochberg MC. Updating the American College of Rheumatology revised criteria for the classification of systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Rheum 1997; 40: 1725.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9324032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Interim CDC. Guidance on duration of isolation and precautions for adults with COVID-19, 2021. https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/hcp/duration-isolation.html</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gladman DD, Iba&#xf1;ez D, Urowitz MB. Systemic lupus erythematosus disease activity index 2000. J Rheumatol 2002; 29(2): 288&#x2013;291.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11838846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gladman D, Ginzler E, Goldsmith C, et al.The development and initial validation of the Systemic Lupus International Collaborating Clinics/American College of Rheumatology damage index for systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Rheum 1996; 39: 363&#x2013;369.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8607884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamilton M. A rating scale for depression. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 1960; 23: 56&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC495331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14399272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamilton M. The assessment of anxiety states by rating. Br J Med Psychol 1959; 32: 50&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13638508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedhazur EJ. Multiple regression in behavioral research: an explanation and prediction. New York: Holt, Rinehrat and Winston, 1997.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L, Fu T, Yin R, et al.Prevalence of depression and anxiety in systemic lupus erythematosus: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Psychiatry 2017; 17: 70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5310017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28196529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spihlman AP, Gadi N, Wu SC, et al.COVID-19 and systemic lupus erythematosus: focus on immune response and therapeutics. Front Immunol 2020; 11: 2861.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7661632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33193418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vabret N, Britton GJ, Gruber C, et al.Sinai immunology review project. Immunology of COVID-19: current state of the science. Immunity 2020; 52: 910&#x2013;941.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7200337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32505227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salari N, Hosseinian-Far A, Jalali R, et al.Prevalence of stress, anxiety, depression among the general population during the COVID-19 pandemic: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Glob Health 2020; 16: 57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7338126</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32631403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tee CA, Salido EO, Reyes PWC, et al.Psychological state and associated factors during the 2019 coronavirus disease (COVID-19) pandemic among Filipinos with rheumatoid arthritis or systemic lupus erythematosus. Open Access Rheumatol 2020; 12: 215&#x2013;222.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7520098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33061689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasturi S, Price LL, Paushkin V, et al.Impact of the first wave of the COVID-19 pandemic on systemic lupus erythematosus patients: results from a multi-center prospective cohort. Lupus 2021; 30: 1747&#x2013;1755.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8560554</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34284676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quartuccio L, Marchi GD, Azzolina D, et al.Psychological effects of lockdown measures for the COVID-19 outbreak in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. JMDH 2021; 14: 1475&#x2013;1488.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8216740</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34168460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weckerle CE, Niewold TB. The unexplained female predominance of systemic lupus erythematosus: clues from genetic and cytokine studies. Clin Rev Allergy Immunol 2011; 40: 9&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2891868</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20063186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rubio J, krishfield S, Kyttaris V. COVID-19 impact among patients with systemic lupus erythematosus [abstract]. Arthritis Rheumatol 2021; 73(suppl 10).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8568617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33982889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramirez GA, Argolini LM, Bellocchi C, et al.Impact of the COVID-19 pandemic in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus throughout one year. Clin Immunol 2021; 231: 108845.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8405598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34478882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fei Y, Shi X, Gan F, et al.Death causes and pathogens analysis of systemic lupus erythematosus during the past 26 years. Clin Rheumatol 2014; 33: 57&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24046218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alharthy A, Faqihi F, Nasim N, et al.COVID-19 in a patient with a flare of systemic lupus erythematosus: a rare case-report. Respir Med Case Rep 2020; 31: 101252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7557168</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33078093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khalid MZ, Rogers S, Fatima A, et al.A flare of systemic lupus erythematosus disease after COVID-19 infection: a case of lupus cerebritis. Cureus 2021; 13(7): e16104. doi:10.7759/cureus.16104. Available from:https://www.cureus.com/articles/61861-a-flare-of-systemic-lupus-erythematosus-disease-after-covid-19-infection-a-case-of-lupus-cerebritis</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.16104</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8325872</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34350072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tharwat S, Zohdy S. Challenges of Egyptian patients with systemic lupus erythematosus during covid-19 pandemic. Ann Rheum Dis 2021; 80: 917&#x2013;917.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raghavan S, Gonakoti S, Asemota IR, et al.A case of systemic lupus erythematosus flare triggered by severe coronavirus disease 2019. J Clin Rheumatol 2020; 26: 234&#x2013;235.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7493768</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32826658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kondo Y, Kaneko Y, Oshige T, et al.Exacerbation of immune thrombocytopenia triggered by COVID-19 in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. Ann Rheum Dis 2021; 80: e77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32759254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayden A, Vyas-Lahar A, Rella V, et al.Severe refractory thrombocytopenia in a woman positive for coronavirus disease 2019 with lupus and antiphospholipid syndrome. Lupus 2020; 29(11): 1472&#x2013;1474.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32640936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandez-Ruiz R, Paredes JL, Niewold TB. COVID-19 in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: lessons learned from the inflammatory disease. Transl Res 2021; 232: 13&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7749645</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33352298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention . Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19). [Internet]. 2020. Available from:https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/need-extra-precautions/people-with-medical-conditions.html</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ornell F, Schuch JB, Sordi AO, et al.Pandemic fear&#x201d; and COVID-19: mental health burden and strategies. Braz J Psychiatry 2020; 42: 232&#x2013;235.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7236170</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32267343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai R, Liu S, Zhao Y A, et al.Depressive and anxiety disorders in systemic lupus erythematosus patients without major neuropsychiatric manifestations. J Immunol Res 2016; 2016: e2829018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5056298</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27747246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen B, Tan W, Feng G, et al.The correlations of disease activity, socioeconomic status, quality of life, and depression/anxiety in Chinese patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. Clin Dev Immunol 2013; 2013: 270878.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3705842</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23864877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratanasiripong NT, Ratanasiripong P. Predictive factors of quality of life among systemic lupus erythematosus patients in Thailand: a web-based cross-sectional study. Qual Life Res 2020; 29(9): 2415&#x2013;2423.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32270369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maneeton B, Maneeton N, Louthrenoo W. Prevalence and predictors of depression in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: a cross-sectional study. Neuropsychiatr Dis Treat 2013; 9: 799&#x2013;804.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3678948</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23766649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khedr EM, Gamal RM, Rashad SM, et al.Impact of depression on quality of life in systemic lupus erythematosus patients. Egypt J Neurol Psychiatr Neurosurg 2021; 57: 88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moldovan I, Katsaros E, Carr FN, et al.The Patient Reported Outcomes in Lupus (PATROL) study: role of depression in health-related quality of life in a Southern California lupus cohort. Lupus 2011; 20: 1285&#x2013;1292.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21813589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>