<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37302272</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>22</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1095-9157</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>139</Volume><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of autoimmunity</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Autoimmun</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Autoantibodies against the NineTeen complex and U5 RNP in systemic sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>103056</StartPage><MedlinePgn>103056</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.jaut.2023.103056</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0896-8411(23)00065-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>ObjectiveMultiple spliceosome components are known autoantigens in systemic sclerosis (SSc). Here we aim to identify new and characterize rare anti-spliceosomal autoantibodies in patients with SSc without known autoantibody specificity. MethodsSera that precipitated spliceosome subcomplexes, as detected by immunoprecipitation-mass spectrometry (IP-MS), were identified from a database of 106 patients with SSc without known autoantibody specificity. New autoantibody specificities were confirmed with immunoprecipitation-western blot. The IP-MS pattern of new anti-spliceosomal autoantibodies was compared with anti-U1 RNP-positive sera of patients with different systemic autoimmune rheumatic diseases and anti-SmD-positive sera of patients with systemic lupus erythematosus (n&#xa0;=&#xa0;24). ResultsThe NineTeen Complex (NTC) was identified and confirmed as new spliceosomal autoantigen in one patient with SSc. U5 RNP, as well as additional splicing factors, were precipitated by the serum of another patient with SSc. The IP-MS patterns of anti-NTC and anti-U5 RNP autoantibodies were distinct from those of anti-U1 RNP- and anti-SmD-positive sera. Furthermore, there was no difference in IP-MS patterns between a limited number of anti-U1 RNP-positive sera of patients with different systemic autoimmune rheumatic diseases. ConclusionAnti-NTC autoantibodies are a new anti-spliceosomal autoantibody specificity, here first identified in a patient with SSc. Anti-U5 RNP autoantibodies are a distinct but rare anti-spliceosomal autoantibody specificity. All major spliceosomal subcomplexes have now been described as target of autoantibodies in systemic autoimmune diseases.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vulsteke</LastName><ForeName>Jean-Baptiste</ForeName><Initials>JB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>KU Leuven, Department of Development and Regeneration, Skeletal Biology and Engineering Research Center, Leuven, Belgium; Rheumatology, University Hospitals Leuven, Leuven, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Smith</LastName><ForeName>Vanessa</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ghent University, Department of Internal Medicine, Ghent, Belgium; Unit for Molecular Immunology and Inflammation, VIB Inflammation Research Center (IRC), Ghent, Belgium; Rheumatology, Ghent University Hospital, Ghent, Belgium; European Reference Network on Rare and Complex Connective Tissue and Musculoskeletal Diseases (ERN ReCONNET), Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bonroy</LastName><ForeName>Carolien</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ghent University, Department of Diagnostic Sciences, Ghent, Belgium; Laboratory Medicine, Ghent University Hospital, Ghent, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lenaerts</LastName><ForeName>Jan L</ForeName><Initials>JL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rheumatology, University Hospitals Leuven, Leuven, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Derua</LastName><ForeName>Rita</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>KU Leuven, Department of Cellular and Molecular Medicine, Laboratory of Protein Phosphorylation and Proteomics, Leuven, Belgium; KU Leuven, SyBioMa, Leuven, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wuyts</LastName><ForeName>Wim A</ForeName><Initials>WA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>KU Leuven, Department of Chronic Diseases and Metabolism, Laboratory of Respiratory Diseases and Thoracic Surgery, Belgium; Unit for Interstitial Lung Diseases, Respiratory Medicine, University Hospitals Leuven, Leuven, Belgium; European Reference Network on Rare Respiratory Diseases (ERN LUNG), Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Blockmans</LastName><ForeName>Daniel</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>KU Leuven, Department of Microbiology, Immunology and Transplantation, Laboratory for Clinical Infectious and Inflammatory Disorders, Leuven, Belgium; General Internal Medicine, University Hospitals Leuven, Leuven, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>De Haes</LastName><ForeName>Petra</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>KU Leuven, Department of Microbiology, Immunology and Transplantation, Leuven, Belgium; Dermatology, University Hospitals Leuven, Leuven, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Piette</LastName><ForeName>Yves</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ghent University, Department of Internal Medicine, Ghent, Belgium; Rheumatology, Ghent University Hospital, Ghent, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>De Langhe</LastName><ForeName>Ellen</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>KU Leuven, Department of Development and Regeneration, Skeletal Biology and Engineering Research Center, Leuven, Belgium; European Reference Network on Rare and Complex Connective Tissue and Musculoskeletal Diseases (ERN ReCONNET), Belgium; European Reference Network on Rare Immunodeficiency, Autoinflammatory and Autoimmune Diseases (ERN RITA), Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bossuyt</LastName><ForeName>Xavier</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>KU Leuven, Department of Microbiology, Immunology and Transplantation, Clinical and Diagnostic Immunology, Leuven, Belgium; Laboratory Medicine, University Hospitals Leuven, Leuven, Belgium. Electronic address: xavier.bossuyt@uzleuven.be.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Autoimmun</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8812164</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0896-8411</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D001323">Autoantibodies</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000974">Antibodies, Antinuclear</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D001324">Autoantigens</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001323" MajorTopicYN="N">Autoantibodies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017381" MajorTopicYN="N">Spliceosomes</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012595" MajorTopicYN="Y">Scleroderma, Systemic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000974" MajorTopicYN="N">Antibodies, Antinuclear</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001324" MajorTopicYN="N">Autoantigens</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012216" MajorTopicYN="Y">Rheumatic Diseases</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>Declaration of competing interest VS: grants: Janssen. WW: grants: Roche, Boehringer Ingelheim, Galapagos. PDH: payment or honoraria for lectures: Actelion/Janssen-Cilag, Amgen, Novartis, UCB; support for attending meetings: Amgen. EDL: payment or honoraria for lectures: Actelion, Lilly; support for attending meetings: Pfizer, Boehringer Ingelheim, Lilly, MSD, participation on advisory board: AC Immune, Boehringer Ingelheim, Amgen, Astra Zeneca, GSK, Novartis, Otsuka. Leadership role: co-president of the Working Group Rare Diseases, Belgian Royal Society of Rheumatology. XB: payment or honoraria for lectures: Werfen, Thermo Fisher Scientific, participation on advisory board: Werfen, Thermo Fisher Scientific. All abovementioned interests were outside the scope of the current work. CB, JL, RD, DB and YP have no competing interests to declare. Total spectral count per protein (row) as precipitated by each individual serum (column). HC healthy control, ID protein identification, MW molecular weight. The specific proteins are highlighted in color (corresponding to the colors in supplemental figure 1 and 2).</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37302272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaut.2023.103056</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0896-8411(23)00065-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>