<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37308717</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>21</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1573-6628</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>27</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Maternal and child health journal</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Matern Child Health J</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Health Related Quality of Life in Juvenile-Onset Systemic Lupus Erythematosus: A Questionnaire-Based Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1578</StartPage><EndPage>1588</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1578-1588</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s10995-023-03680-x</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This study aimed to evaluate health related quality of life (HRQOL) in Egyptian children with systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) using 3 different tools.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">In this questionnaire-based study, 100 children with SLE were included. HRQOL was assessed using the Pediatric Quality of Life Inventory Generic Core Scales (PedsQL&#x2122; 4.0 GCS), PedsQL&#x2122; 3.0 Rheumatology Module (PedsQL3-RM) and the Simple Measure of the Impact of Lupus Erythematosus in Youngsters (SMILEY). SLE disease activity index (SLEDAI) was used to evaluate activity and SLE International Collaborating Clinics/ American College of Rheumatology Damage Index (SDI) was used to evaluate chronic damage.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">All mean scores of PedsQL<sup>TM</sup>4.0 GCS domains in SLE patients were lower than published normative data and previously published results of Egyptian healthy controls (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001). All mean scores of PedsQL-3RM domains were significantly lower than published normative data except for the treatment and pain and hurt domains (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.1, 0.2 respectively). SMILEY scores were low and the lowest domain scores was "Burden of SLE". Longer duration of illness, higher cumulative steroid doses, higher SLEDAI and SDI scores and presence of obesity were associated with lower scores for all 3 tools (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION FOR PRACTICE" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The Arabic copies of PedsQL&#x2122; 4.0 GCS, PedsQL3-RM and SMILEY are easily used for Arabic speaking subjects and easily interpreted by physician and can be implemented for frequent monitoring of SLE HRQOL. Controlling the disease activity and using lowest doses of steroids and other immunosuppressive drugs are the corner stone strategies for improving HRQOL in SLE children.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Eid</LastName><ForeName>Riham</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2193-9028</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pediatric Nephrology Unit, Faculty of Medicine, Mansoura University Children's Hospital, Mansoura University, Mansoura, 35561, Egypt. rihameid@mans.edu.eg.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hammad</LastName><ForeName>Ayman</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pediatric Nephrology Unit, Faculty of Medicine, Mansoura University Children's Hospital, Mansoura University, Mansoura, 35561, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Korkor</LastName><ForeName>Mai S</ForeName><Initials>MS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pediatric Nephrology Unit, Faculty of Medicine, Mansoura University Children's Hospital, Mansoura University, Mansoura, 35561, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fathy</LastName><ForeName>Aya A</ForeName><Initials>AA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Public Health and Community Department, Faculty of Medicine, Mansoura University, Mansoura, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abd El-Ghafaar</LastName><ForeName>Dena M</ForeName><Initials>DM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rheumatology, Rehabilitation and Physical Medicine Department, Faculty of Medicine, Mansoura University, Mansoura, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rakha</LastName><ForeName>Shaimaa</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pediatric Cardiology Unit, Faculty of Medicine, Mansoura University Children's Hospital, Mansoura University, Mansoura, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hamdy</LastName><ForeName>Nashwa</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pediatric Nephrology Unit, Faculty of Medicine, Mansoura University Children's Hospital, Mansoura University, Mansoura, 35561, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Matern Child Health J</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9715672</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1092-7875</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="Y">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011795" MajorTopicYN="N">Surveys and Questionnaires</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009765" MajorTopicYN="N">Obesity</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013997" MajorTopicYN="N">Time Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012720" MajorTopicYN="N">Severity of Illness Index</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><OtherAbstract Type="plain-language-summary" Language="eng"><AbstractText>This is the first study to evaluate HRQOL scores in Egyptian children with SLE which were found to be lower than published data with long disease duration, high cumulative disease activity, use of steroids and presence of obesity are the main influential factors related to low QoL scores. Generic and disease specific questionnaires are easily used for Arabic speaking subjects and easily interpreted by physician and can be implemented for frequent monitoring of SLE HRQOL. Controlling the disease activity and using lowest doses of steroids and other immunosuppressive drugs are the corner stone strategies for improving HRQOL in SLE children.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></OtherAbstract><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Children</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Egypt</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Lupus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of life</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declared no potential conflicts of interest concerning the research, authorship, and/or publication of this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37308717</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10359351</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10995-023-03680-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s10995-023-03680-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Brunner HI, Giannini EH. Health-related quality of life in children with rheumatic diseases. Current Opinion in Rheumatology. 2003;15(5):602&#x2013;612. doi: 10.1097/00002281-200309000-00014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00002281-200309000-00014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12960488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brunner HI, Klein-Gitelman MS, Miller MJ, Trombley M, Baldwin N, Kress A, Johnson AL, Barron AC, Griffin TA, Passo MH, Lovell DJ. Health of children with chronic arthritis: Relationship of different measures and the quality of parent proxy reporting. Arthritis and Rheumatism. 2004;51(5):763&#x2013;773. doi: 10.1002/art.20689.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/art.20689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15478144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brunner HI, Gladman DD, Iba&#xf1;ez D, Urowitz MD, Silverman ED. Difference in disease features between childhood-onset and adult-onset systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis and Rheumatism. 2008;58(2):556&#x2013;562. doi: 10.1002/art.23204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/art.23204</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18240232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brunner HI, Higgins GC, Wiers K, Lapidus SK, Olson JC, Onel K, Punaro M, Ying J, Klein-Gitelman MS, Seid M. Health-related quality of life and its relationship to patient disease course in childhood-onset systemic lupus erythematosus. The Journal of Rheumatology. 2009;36(7):1536&#x2013;1545. doi: 10.3899/jrheum.081164.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3899/jrheum.081164</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19487266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duffy CM. Measurement of health status, functional status, and quality of life in children with juvenile idiopathic arthritis: Clinical science for the pediatrician. Pediatric Clinics of North America. 2005;52(2):359&#x2013;v. doi: 10.1016/j.pcl.2005.01.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pcl.2005.01.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15820372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duffy CM, Arsenault L, Duffy KN, Paquin JD, Strawczynski H. The juvenile arthritis quality of life questionnaire&#x2013;development of a new responsive index for juvenile rheumatoid arthritis and juvenile spondyloarthritides. The Journal of Rheumatology. 1997;24(4):738&#x2013;746.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9101511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eesa NN, Abdel Nabi H, Owaidy RE, Khalifa I, Radwan AR, NourEl-Din AM, Amer MA, ElShereef RR, Hassan E, Ismail F, El-Gazzar II, Khalil NM, Moshrif AH, Abualfadl E, Tharwat S, Fathi HM, Abd Elazeem MI, El-Shebini E, Samy N, Noshy N, El-Bahnasawy AS, Abdalla AM, Abousehly OS, Mohamed EF, Nasef SI, Elsaman AM, ElKhalifa M, Salem MN, Abaza NM, Fathy HM, Abdel Salam N, El-Saadany HM, El-Najjar AR, El-Hammady DH, Hammam N, Mohammed RH, Gheita TA, Egyptian College of Rheumatology (ECR) SLE Study Group Systemic lupus erythematosus children in Egypt: Homeland spectrum amid the global situation. Lupus. 2021;30(13):2135&#x2013;2143. doi: 10.1177/09612033211043010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/09612033211043010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34528835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eid R, Fathy AA, Hamdy N. Health-related quality of life in Egyptian children with nephrotic syndrome. Quality of Life Research. 2020;29(8):2185&#x2013;2196. doi: 10.1007/s11136-020-02438-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11136-020-02438-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32016684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eid R, Hammad A, Abdelsalam M, Fathy AA, Abd-El Ghafaar DM, Elmarghany EB, El-Hanafy AA, Mostafa N, Niazey NA, Korkor MS, Hamdy N. Tumor necrosis factor receptor II and PTPN22 genes polymorphisms and the risk of systemic lupus erythematosus in Egyptian children. Lupus. 2021;30(9):1449&#x2013;1458. doi: 10.1177/09612033211020359.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/09612033211020359</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34080911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elmougy A, Sarhan A, Hammad A, El-Refaey A, Zedan M, Eid R, Laimon W, Elrahman AA, Elhussieni F, El-Sherbeny E, Bakr A. Erratum to: Lupus nephritis in Egyptian children: A 16-year experience. Journal of Nephrology. 2015;28(1):131. doi: 10.1007/s40620-014-0170-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40620-014-0170-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25585826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Ziny MA, Al-Tonbary YA, Salama OS, Bakr A, Al-Marsafawy H, Elsharkawy AA. Low bone mass in children with malignant lymphoma. Pediatric Hematology and Oncology. 2007;24(8):577&#x2013;585. doi: 10.1080/08880010701640275.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/08880010701640275</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18092248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gladman D, Ginzler E, Goldsmith C, Fortin P, Liang M, Urowitz M, Bacon P, Bombardieri S, Hanly J, Hay E, Isenberg D, Jones J, Kalunian K, Maddison P, Nived O, Petri M, Richter M, Sanchez-Guerrero J, Snaith M, Sturfelt G, Symmons D, Zoma A. The development and initial validation of the Systemic Lupus International Collaborating Clinics/American College of Rheumatology damage index for systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis and Rheumatism. 1996;39(3):363&#x2013;369. doi: 10.1002/art.1780390303.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/art.1780390303</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8607884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gladman DD, Iba&#xf1;ez D, Urowitz MB. Systemic lupus erythematosus disease activity index 2000. The Journal of Rheumatology. 2002;29(2):288&#x2013;291.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11838846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hersh AO, von Scheven E, Yazdany J, Panopalis P, Trupin L, Julian L, Hersh AO, von Scheven E, Yazdany J, Panopalis P, Trupin L, Julian L, Katz P, Criswell LA, Yelin E. Differences in long-term disease activity and treatment of adult patients with childhood- and adult-onset systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis and Rheumatism. 2009;61(1):13&#x2013;20. doi: 10.1002/art.24091.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/art.24091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2875186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19116979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hochberg MC. Updating the American College of Rheumatology revised criteria for the classification of systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis and Rheumatism. 1997;40(9):1725. doi: 10.1002/art.1780400928.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/art.1780400928</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9324032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Houghton KM, Tucker LB, Potts JE, McKenzie DC. Fitness, fatigue, disease activity, and quality of life in pediatric lupus. Arthritis and Rheumatism. 2008;59(4):537&#x2013;545. doi: 10.1002/art.23534.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/art.23534</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18383417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones, J. T., Nelson, S. L., Wootton, J., Liberio, B., Greenler, A. J., Huggins, J. L., Huggins, J. L., Schanberg, L. E., &amp; Brunner, H. (2013). Level and Determinants of Health-Related Quality of Life in Childhood-Onset Systemic Lupus Erythematosus, [Abstract 844]: 2013 ACR/ARHP Annual Meeting.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levy DM, Peschken CA, Tucker LB, Ch&#xe9;deville G, Huber AM, Pope JE, Canadian Network for Improved Outcomes in SLE (CaNIOS) 1000 Faces Investigators, &amp; Silverman, E. D Association of health-related quality of life in childhood-onset systemic lupus erythematosus with ethnicity: results from a multiethnic multicenter Canadian cohort. Arthritis Care &amp; Research. 2014;66(12):1767&#x2013;1774. doi: 10.1002/acr.22363.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/acr.22363</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4229486</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24821613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Massias JS, Smith EM, Al-Abadi E, Armon K, Bailey K, Ciurtin C, Davidson J, Gardner-Medwin J, Haslam K, Hawley DP, Leahy A, Leone V, McErlane F, Mewar D, Modgil G, Moots R, Pilkington C, Ramanan AV, Rangaraj S, Riley P, Sridhar A, Wilkinson N, Beresford MW, Hedrich CM. Clinical and laboratory phenotypes in juvenile-onset systemic lupus erythematosus across ethnicities in the UK. Lupus. 2021;30(4):597&#x2013;607. doi: 10.1177/0961203320984251.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0961203320984251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7967896</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33413005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller ML, LeBovidge J, Feldman B. Health-related quality of life in children with arthritis. Rheumatic Diseases Clinics of North America. 2002;28(3):493&#x2013;vi. doi: 10.1016/s0889-857x(02)00019-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0889-857x(02)00019-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12380367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mina R, Brunner HI. Pediatric lupus&#x2013;are there differences in presentation, genetics, response to therapy, and damage accrual compared with adult lupus? Rheumatic Diseases Clinics of North America. 2010;36(1):53&#x2013;viii. doi: 10.1016/j.rdc.2009.12.012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rdc.2009.12.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2837537</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20202591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moorthy LN, Peterson M, Onel KB, Harrison MJ, Lehman TJ. Quality of life in children with systemic lupus erythematosus. Current Rheumatology Reports. 2005;7(6):447&#x2013;452. doi: 10.1007/s11926-005-0049-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11926-005-0049-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16303104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moorthy LN, Peterson MG, Baratelli M, Harrison MJ, Onel KB, Chalom EC, Haines K, Hashkes PJ, Lehman TJ. Simple Measure of The Impact of Lupus Erythematosus In Youngsters (SMILEY): Validity, internal consistency and test-retest reliability. Arthritis and Rheumatism. 2006;54(9):S162.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moorthy LN, Peterson MG, Baratelli M, Harrison MJ, Onel KB, Chalom EC, Haines K, Hashkes PJ, Lehman TJ. Multicenter validation of a new quality of life measure in pediatric lupus. Arthritis and Rheumatism. 2007;57(7):1165&#x2013;1173. doi: 10.1002/art.22988.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/art.22988</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17907234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moorthy LN, Peterson MG, Hassett AL, Baratelli M, Chalom EC, Hashkes PJ, Hong S, Reiff A, Lehman TJ. Relationship between health-related quality of life and SLE activity and damage in children over time. Lupus. 2009;18(7):622&#x2013;629. doi: 10.1177/0961203308101718.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0961203308101718</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19433463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moorthy LN, Saad-Magalh&#xe3;es C, Sato JO, Len CA, Vasco MB, Appenzeller S, Marini R, Oliveira SK, Rodrigues M, Sztajnbok F, Almeida RG, Jesus AA, Campos LM, Silva CA, Peterson MG, Hassett AL, Weiss E, Verma S, Dahodwala MQ, Lehman TJ. Validation of the Portuguese Simple Measure of Impact of Lupus Erythematosus in Youngsters (SMILEY) in Brazil. Lupus. 2013;22(2):190&#x2013;197. doi: 10.1177/0961203312470185.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0961203312470185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23257403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moorthy LN, Baldino ME, Kurra V, Puwar D, Llanos A, Peterson MG, Hassett AL, Lehman TJ, International SMILEY&#xa9; Collaborative group Relationship between health-related quality of life, disease activity and disease damage in a prospective international multicenter cohort of childhood onset systemic lupus erythematosus patients. Lupus. 2017;26(3):255&#x2013;265. doi: 10.1177/0961203316659546.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0961203316659546</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27496901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petty RE, Cassidy JT. Systemic lupus erythematosus. In: Cassidy JT, Petty RE, editors. Textbook of pediatric rheumatology. 4. WB Saunders; 2001. pp. 396&#x2013;449.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Putera AM, Irwanto I, Maramis MM, Prasetyo RV, Soemyarso NA, Noer MS. Effect of mental health problems on the quality of life in children with lupus nephritis. Neuropsychiatric Disease and Treatment. 2020;16:1583&#x2013;1593. doi: 10.2147/NDT.S250373.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/NDT.S250373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7326200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32617005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ravelli A, Ruperto N, Martini A. Outcome in juvenile onset systemic lupus erythematosus. Current Opinion in Rheumatology. 2005;17(5):568&#x2013;573. doi: 10.1097/01.bor.0000169364.69066.1e.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/01.bor.0000169364.69066.1e</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16093835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogers J, Sagcal-Gironella ACP, Rosillo P, Ramirez AA, Banuelos R, de Guzman MM. A single center review of health-related quality of life in children with systemic lupus erythematosus using the pediatric quality of life inventory version 4.0 generic core scale. Arthritis &amp; Rheumatology. 2017;69(4):223&#x2013;224.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruperto N, Buratti S, Duarte-Salazar C, Pistorio A, Reiff A, Bernstein B, Maldonado-Vel&#xe1;zquez MR, Beristain-Manterola R, Maeno N, Takei S, Falcini F, Lepore L, Spencer CH, Pratsidou-Gertsi P, Martini A, Ravelli A. Health-related quality of life in juvenile-onset systemic lupus erythematosus and its relationship to disease activity and damage. Arthritis and Rheumatism. 2004;51(3):458&#x2013;464. doi: 10.1002/art.20412.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/art.20412</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15188334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stevens B, Rodriguez M, Rakestraw A, O&#x2019;neil K. SAT0477 quality of life in subjects with pre-pubertal onset systemic lupus erythematosus. Annals of the Rheumatic. 2019;78:1326&#x2013;1327.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thumboo J, Strand V. Health-related quality of life in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: An update. Annals of the Academy of Medicine, Singapore. 2007;36(2):115&#x2013;122. doi: 10.47102/annals-acadmedsg.V36N2p115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.47102/annals-acadmedsg.V36N2p115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17364078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varni JW, Burwinkle TM, Seid M, Skarr D. The PedsQL 4.0 as a pediatric population health measure: feasibility, reliability, and validity. Ambulatory Pediatrics: the Official Journal of the Ambulatory Pediatric Association. 2003;3(6):329&#x2013;341. doi: 10.1367/1539-4409(2003)003&lt;0329:tpaapp&gt;2.0.co;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1367/1539-4409(2003)003&lt;0329:tpaapp&gt;2.0.co;2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14616041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varni JW, Seid M, Kurtin PS. PedsQL 4.0: reliability and validity of the pediatric quality of life inventory version 4.0 generic core scales in healthy and patient populations. Medical Care. 2001;39(8):800&#x2013;812. doi: 10.1097/00005650-200108000-00006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005650-200108000-00006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11468499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varni JW, Seid M, Smith Knight T, Burwinkle T, Brown J, Szer IS. The PedsQL in pediatric rheumatology: Reliability, validity, and responsiveness of the pediatric quality of life inventory generic core scales and rheumatology module. Arthritis and Rheumatism. 2002;46(3):714&#x2013;725. doi: 10.1002/art.10095.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/art.10095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11920407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wright FV, Law M, Crombie V, Goldsmith CH, Dent P. Development of a self-report functional status index for juvenile rheumatoid arthritis. The Journal of Rheumatology. 1994;21(3):536&#x2013;544.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8006899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>