<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">37312878</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>21</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2167-8359</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>11</Volume><PubDate><Year>2023</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PeerJ</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PeerJ</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Triptoquinone A and B exercise a therapeutic effect in systemic lupus erythematosus by regulating NLRC3.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e15395</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e15395</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e15395</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7717/peerj.15395</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The autoimmune disorder systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) is multifaceted, with limited therapeutic alternatives and detrimental side effects, particularly on bones and joints. This research endeavors to examine the curative potential and underlying mechanisms of in addressing SLE-associated bone and joint complications. Triptoquinone A and triptoquinone B, constituents of <i>Tripterygium wilfordii</i> polyglycoside tablets (TGTs), exhibit antioxidant and anti-inflammatory attributes; nonetheless, its function in SLE therapy remains elusive. This investigation delves into the role of oxidative stress in systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) and probes the prospective remedial effects of triptoquinone A and triptoquinone B on inflammation and cartilage deterioration in SLE-affected joints. Employing bioinformatics analyses, differentially expressed genes (DEGs) and protein-protein interactions were discerned in SLE, rheumatoid arthritis (RA), and osteoarthritis (OA) datasets. Enrichment analyses unveiled shared genes implicated in immune system regulation and toll-like receptor signaling pathways, among others. Subsequent examination of triptoquinone A and triptoquinone B revealed their capacity to diminish NLRC3 expression in chondrocytes, resulting in decreased pro-inflammatory cytokine levels and cartilage degradation enzyme expression. Suppression of NLRC3 augmented the protective effects of triptoquinone A and B, implying that targeting NLRC3 may constitute a potential therapeutic strategy for inflammation and cartilage degeneration-associated conditions in SLE patients. Our discoveries indicate that triptoquinone A and triptoquinone B may impede SLE progression via the NLRC3 axis, offering potential benefits for SLE-affected bone and joint health.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9;2023 Xu et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Qinyao</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rheumatology and Immunology, The First Affiliated Hospital of Anhui Medical University, Hefei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Xiangzhi</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rheumatology and Immunology, The First Affiliated Hospital of Anhui Medical University, Hefei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ge</LastName><ForeName>Shangqing</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rheumatology and Immunology, The First Affiliated Hospital of Anhui Medical University, Hefei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Chang</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Laboratory, The First Affiliated Hospital of Anhui Medical University, Hefei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lv</LastName><ForeName>Yuanfan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, School Hospital of Anhui Medical University, Hefei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shuai</LastName><ForeName>Zongwen</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rheumatology and Immunology, The First Affiliated Hospital of Anhui Medical University, Hefei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PeerJ</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101603425</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2167-8359</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D036341">Intercellular Signaling Peptides and Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C503285">NLRC3 protein, human</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>142950-86-5</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C100591">triptoquinone A</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D004224">Diterpenes</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001327" MajorTopicYN="Y">Autoimmune Diseases</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D036341" MajorTopicYN="N">Intercellular Signaling Peptides and Proteins</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011446" MajorTopicYN="N">Prospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004224" MajorTopicYN="Y">Diterpenes</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Apoptosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Chondrocytes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Inflammation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">NLRC3</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Oxidative stress</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Triptoquinone</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare there are no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37312878</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10259444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7717/peerj.15395</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">15395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abu Bakar F, Shaharir SS, Mohd R, Kamaruzaman L, Mohamed Said MS. Work disability in a multi-ethnic Malaysian systemic lupus erythematosus cohort: a cross-sectional study. International Journal of Rheumatic Diseases. 2019;22(6):1002&#x2013;1007. doi: 10.1111/1756-185X.13572.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1756-185X.13572</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30968556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ameer MA, Chaudhry H, Mushtaq J, Khan OS, Babar M, Hashim T, Zeb S, Tariq MA, Patlolla SR, Ali J, Hashim SN, Hashim S. An overview of systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) pathogenesis, classification, and management. Cureus. 2022;14(10):e30330. doi: 10.7759/cureus.30330.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.30330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9662848</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36407159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baeck C, Wehr A, Karlmark KR, Heymann F, Vucur M, Gassler N, Huss S, Klussmann S, Eulberg D, Luedde T, Trautwein C, Tacke F. Pharmacological inhibition of the chemokine CCL2 (MCP-1) diminishes liver macrophage infiltration and steatohepatitis in chronic hepatic injury. Gut. 2012;61(3):416&#x2013;426. doi: 10.1136/gutjnl-2011-300304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/gutjnl-2011-300304</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21813474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker K, Pope J. Employment and work disability in systemic lupus erythematosus: a systematic review. Rheumatology. 2008;48(3):281&#x2013;284. doi: 10.1093/rheumatology/ken477.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/rheumatology/ken477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19153144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bauer JW, Baechler EC, Petri M, Batliwalla FM, Crawford D, Ortmann WA, Espe KJ, Li W, Patel DD, Gregersen PK, Behrens TW. Elevated serum levels of interferon-regulated chemokines are biomarkers for active human systemic lupus erythematosus. PLOS Medicine. 2006;3(12):e491. doi: 10.1371/journal.pmed.0030491.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pmed.0030491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1702557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17177599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bauer JW, Petri M, Batliwalla FM, Koeuth T, Wilson J, Slattery C, Panoskaltsis-Mortari A, Gregersen PK, Behrens TW, Baechler EC. Interferon-regulated chemokines as biomarkers of systemic lupus erythematosus disease activity: a validation study. Arthritis &amp; Rheumatology. 2009;60(10):3098&#x2013;3107. doi: 10.1002/art.24803.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/art.24803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2842939</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19790071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Broeren MGA, de Vries M, Bennink MB, Arntz OJ, Blom AB, Koenders MI, van Lent PLEM, van der Kraan PM, van den Berg WB, van de Loo FAJ. Disease-regulated gene therapy with anti-inflammatory interleukin-10 under the control of the CXCL10 promoter for the treatment of rheumatoid arthritis. Human Gene Therapy. 2016;27(3):244&#x2013;254. doi: 10.1089/hum.2015.127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/hum.2015.127</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26711533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao Z, Du K, Liu J, Tang W. Synthesis of triptoquinone H and its C-5 epimer via efficient asymmetric dearomative cyclization. Tetrahedron. 2016;72(14):1782&#x2013;1786. doi: 10.1016/j.tet.2016.02.043.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tet.2016.02.043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceccarelli F, Perricone C, Cipriano E, Massaro L, Natalucci F, Capalbo G, Leccese I, Bogdanos D, Spinelli FR, Alessandri C, Valesini G, Conti F. Joint involvement in systemic lupus erythematosus: from pathogenesis to clinical assessment. Seminars in Arthritis and Rheumatism. 2017;47(1):53&#x2013;64. doi: 10.1016/j.semarthrit.2017.03.022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.semarthrit.2017.03.022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28465078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cen X, Zhu G, Yang J, Yang J, Guo J, Jin J, Nandakumar KS, Yang W, Yin H, Liu S, Cheng K. TLR1/2 specific small-molecule agonist suppresses leukemia cancer cell growth by stimulating cytotoxic T lymphocytes. Advanced Science. 2019;6(10):1802042. doi: 10.1002/advs.201802042.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/advs.201802042</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6523386</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31131189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen F, Ma YL, Ding H, Chen BP. Effects of tripterygium wilfordii glycosides on regulatory T cells and Th17 in an IgA nephropathy rat model. Genetics and Molecular Research. 2015;14(4):14900&#x2013;14907. doi: 10.4238/2015.November.18.55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4238/2015.November.18.55</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26600551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y, Luo Z, Lin J, Qi B, Sun Y, Li F, Guo C, Lin W, Kang X, He X, Wang Q, Chen S, Chen J. Exploring the potential mechanisms of melilotus officinalis (L.) Pall. in chronic muscle repair patterns using single cell receptor-ligand marker analysis and molecular dynamics simulations. Disease Markers. 2022a;2022:1&#x2013;11. doi: 10.1155/2022/9082576.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2022/9082576</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9177293</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35692879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y, Luo Z, Sun Y, Li F, Han Z, Qi B, Lin J, Lin W-W, Yao M, Kang X, Huang J, Sun C, Ying C, Guo C, Xu Y, Chen J, Chen S. Exercise improves choroid plexus epithelial cells metabolism to prevent glial cell-associated neurodegeneration. Frontiers in Pharmacology. 2022b;13:1010785. doi: 10.3389/fphar.2022.1010785.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphar.2022.1010785</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9523215</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36188600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chin C-H, Chen S-H, Wu H-H, Ho C-W, Ko M-T, Lin C-Y. CytoHubba: identifying hub objects and sub-networks from complex interactome. BMC Systems Biology. 2014;8(S4):S11. doi: 10.1186/1752-0509-8-S4-S11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1752-0509-8-S4-S11</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4290687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25521941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duan S, Xu X, Wang J, Huang L, Peng J, Yu T, Zhou Y, Cheng K, Liu S. TLR1/2 agonist enhances reversal of HIV-1 latency and promotes NK cell-induced suppression of HIV-1-infected autologous CD4+ T cells. Journal of Virology. 2021;95(17):e00816-21. doi: 10.1128/JVI.00816-21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JVI.00816-21</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8354220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34133900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisch KM, Gamini R, Alvarez-Garcia O, Akagi R, Saito M, Muramatsu Y, Sasho T, Koziol JA, Su AI, Lotz MK. Identification of transcription factors responsible for dysregulated networks in human osteoarthritis cartilage by global gene expression analysis. Osteoarthritis and Cartilage. 2018;26(11):1531&#x2013;1538. doi: 10.1016/j.joca.2018.07.012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.joca.2018.07.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6245598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30081074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu Y, Zhan X, Wang Y, Jiang X, Liu M, Yang Y, Huang Y, Du X, Zhong X, Li L, Ma L, Hu S. NLRC 3 expression in dendritic cells attenuates CD 4 + T cell response and autoimmunity. EMBO Journal. 2019;38(16):e101397. doi: 10.15252/embj.2018101397.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15252/embj.2018101397</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6694220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31290162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gris D, Ye Z, Iocca HA, Wen H, Craven RR, Gris P, Huang M, Schneider M, Miller SD, Ting JP-Y. NLRP3 plays a critical role in the development of experimental autoimmune encephalomyelitis by mediating Th1 and Th17 responses. The Journal of Immunology. 2010;185(2):974&#x2013;981. doi: 10.4049/jimmunol.0904145.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4049/jimmunol.0904145</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3593010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20574004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasni SA, Gupta S, Davis M, Poncio E, Temesgen-Oyelakin Y, Carlucci PM, Wang X, Naqi M, Playford MP, Goel RR, Li X, Biehl AJ, Ochoa-Navas I, Manna Z, Shi Y, Thomas D, Chen J, Biancotto A, Apps R, Cheung F, Kotliarov Y, Babyak AL, Zhou H, Shi R, Stagliano K, Tsai WL, Vian L, Gazaniga N, Giudice V, Lu S, Brooks SR, MacKay M, Gregersen P, Mehta NN, Remaley AT, Diamond B, O&#x2019;Shea JJ, Gadina M, Kaplan MJ. Phase 1 double-blind randomized safety trial of the janus kinase inhibitor tofacitinib in systemic lupus erythematosus. Nature Communications. 2021;12(1):3391. doi: 10.1038/s41467-021-23361-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-021-23361-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8185103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34099646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hosen N, Park CY, Tatsumi N, Oji Y, Sugiyama H, Gramatzki M, Krensky AM, Weissman IL. CD96 is a leukemic stem cell-specific marker in human acute myeloid leukemia. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America. 2007;104(26):11008&#x2013;11013. doi: 10.1073/pnas.0704271104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.0704271104</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1904175</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17576927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu S, Du X, Huang Y, Fu Y, Yang Y, Zhan X, He W, Wen Q, Zhou X, Zhou C, Zhong X-P, Yang J, Xiong W, Wang R, Gao Y, Ma L. NLRC3 negatively regulates CD4+ T cells and impacts protective immunity during mycobacterium tuberculosis infection. PLOS Pathogens. 2018;14(8):e1007266. doi: 10.1371/journal.ppat.1007266.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.ppat.1007266</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6122840</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30133544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang J, Lin W, Sun Y, Wang Q, He S, Han Z, Lu L, Kang X, Chen Y, Guo H, Cui Z, Sun C, Go K, Wu J, Yao M, Cao M, Xu Y. Quercetin targets VCAM1 to prevent diabetic cerebrovascular endothelial cell injury. Frontiers in Aging Neuroscience. 2022;14:944195. doi: 10.3389/fnagi.2022.944195.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnagi.2022.944195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9475220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36118693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isenberg D, Furie R, Jones NS, Guibord P, Galanter J, Lee C, McGregor A, Toth B, Rae J, Hwang O, Desai R, Lokku A, Ramamoorthi N, Hackney JA, Miranda P, Souza VA, Jaller-Raad JJ, Maura Fernandes A, Garcia Salinas R, Chinn LW, Townsend MJ, Morimoto AM, Tuckwell K. Efficacy, safety, and pharmacodynamic effects of the Bruton&#x2019;s tyrosine kinase inhibitor fenebrutinib (GDC-0853) in systemic lupus erythematosus: results of a phase II, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Arthritis &amp; Rheumatology. 2021;73(10):1835&#x2013;1846. doi: 10.1002/art.41811.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/art.41811</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34042314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jabbari N, Eftekhari Z, Roodbari NH, Parivar K. Evaluation of encapsulated eugenol by chitosan nanoparticles on the aggressive model of rheumatoid arthritis. International Immunopharmacology. 2020;85:106554. doi: 10.1016/j.intimp.2020.106554.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.intimp.2020.106554</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32447218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang J, Li M, Luan P, Jiang D, Chen Y, Xu X, Yu Q, Xu Y, Su Q, Peng W, Jian W. NLRC3 silencing accelerates the invasion of hepatocellular carcinoma cell via IL-6/JAK2/STAT3 pathway activation. Cell Biology International. 2020;44(10):2053&#x2013;2064. doi: 10.1002/cbin.11414.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cbin.11414</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32584509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang X, Sun Y, Yi B, Jiang C, Yan X, Chen B, Lu L, Shi F, Luo Y, Chen Y, Wang Q, Shi R. Based on network pharmacology and molecular dynamics simulations, baicalein, an active ingredient of yiqi qingre ziyin method, potentially protects patients with atrophic rhinitis from cognitive impairment. Frontiers in Aging Neuroscience. 2022;14:880794. doi: 10.3389/fnagi.2022.880794.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnagi.2022.880794</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9226445</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35754951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loetscher M, Loetscher P, Brass N, Meese E, Moser B. Lymphocyte-specific chemokine receptor CXCR3: regulation, chemokine binding and gene localization. European Journal of Immunology. 1998;28(11):3696&#x2013;3705. doi: 10.1002/(SICI)1521-4141(199811)28:11&lt;3696::AID-IMMU3696&gt;3.0.CO;2-W.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/(SICI)1521-4141(199811)28:11&lt;3696::AID-IMMU3696&gt;3.0.CO;2-W</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9842912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li H, Wu R, Yu H, Zheng Q, Chen Y. Bioactive herbal extracts of traditional chinese medicine applied with the biomaterials: for the current applications and advances in the musculoskeletal system. Frontiers in Pharmacology. 2021;12:778041. doi: 10.3389/fphar.2021.778041.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphar.2021.778041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8581265</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34776987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li K, Du Y, Li L, Wei D-Q. Bioinformatics approaches for anti-cancer drug discovery. CDT. 2019;21(1):3&#x2013;17. doi: 10.2174/1389450120666190923162203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/1389450120666190923162203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31549592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu L, Kang X, Yi B, Jiang C, Yan X, Chen B, Sun Y, Shi F, Luo Y, Chen Y, Shi R. Exploring the mechanism of yiqi qingre ziyin method in regulating neuropeptide expression for the treatment of atrophic rhinitis. Disease Markers. 2022;2022:1&#x2013;12. doi: 10.1155/2022/4416637.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2022/4416637</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8923799</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35299869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandrekar P, Ambade A, Lim A, Szabo G, Catalano D. An essential role for monocyte chemoattractant protein-1 in alcoholic liver injury: regulation of proinflammatory cytokines and hepatic steatosis in mice. Hepatology. 2011;54(6):2185&#x2013;2197. doi: 10.1002/hep.24599.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hep.24599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3342822</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21826694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer D, Seth S, Albrecht J, Maier MK, Pasquier L. du, Ravens I, Dreyer L, Burger R, Gramatzki M, Schwinzer R, Kremmer E, Foerster R, Bernhardt G. CD96 interaction with CD155 via its first ig-like domain is modulated by alternative splicing or mutations in distal ig-like domains. Journal of Biological Chemistry. 2009;284(4):2235&#x2013;2244. doi: 10.1074/jbc.M807698200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1074/jbc.M807698200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19056733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moritoki H, Hisayama T, Kida K, Kondoh W, Inoue S, Takaishi Y. Inhibition by triptoquinone-A of LPS- and IL-1 &#x3b2;-primed induction of no synthase in rat thoracic aorta. Life Sciences. 1996;59(3):PL49&#x2013;PL54. doi: 10.1016/0024-3205(96)00283-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0024-3205(96)00283-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8699928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moulton VR, Suarez-Fueyo A, Meidan E, Li H, Mizui M, Tsokos GC. Pathogenesis of human systemic lupus erythematosus: a cellular perspective. Trends in Molecular Medicine. 2017;23(7):615&#x2013;635. doi: 10.1016/j.molmed.2017.05.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.molmed.2017.05.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5650102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28623084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ostrov BE. Immunotherapeutic biologic agents in autoimmune and autoinflammatory diseases. Immunological Investigations. 2015;44(8):777&#x2013;802. doi: 10.3109/08820139.2015.1093912.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/08820139.2015.1093912</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26575464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pandey K, Nimisha An overview on promising nanotechnological approaches for the treatment of psoriasis. NANOTEC. 2020;14(2):102&#x2013;118. doi: 10.2174/1872210514666200204124130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/1872210514666200204124130</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32013854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shao W-H, Shu DH, Zhen Y, Hilliard B, Priest SO, Cesaroni M, Ting JP-Y, Cohen PL. Prion-like aggregation of mitochondrial antiviral signaling protein in lupus patients is associated with increased levels of type I interferon: mavs aggregation and type I IFN IN LUPUS. Arthritis &amp; Rheumatology. 2016;68(11):2697&#x2013;2707. doi: 10.1002/art.39733.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/art.39733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5079845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27110677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen H-H, Yang Y-X, Meng X, Luo X-Y, Li X-M, Shuai Z-W, Ye D-Q, Pan H-F. NLRP3: a promising therapeutic target for autoimmune diseases. Autoimmunity Reviews. 2018;17(7):694&#x2013;702. doi: 10.1016/j.autrev.2018.01.020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.autrev.2018.01.020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29729449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sierra JA, Gilchrist K, Tabares-Guevara JH, Betancur-Galvis L, Ramirez-Pineda JR, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Cardenete MA. Semisynthetic abietic and dehydroabietic acid derivatives and triptoquinone epimers interfere with LPS-triggered activation of dendritic cells. Molecules. 2022;27(19):6684. doi: 10.3390/molecules27196684.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules27196684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9571164</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36235219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith CK, Kaplan MJ. The role of neutrophils in the pathogenesis of systemic lupus erythematosus. Current Opinion in Rheumatology. 2015;27(5):448&#x2013;453. doi: 10.1097/BOR.0000000000000197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/BOR.0000000000000197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26125102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spada R, Rojas JM, Barber DF. Recent findings on the role of natural killer cells in the pathogenesis of systemic lupus erythematosus. Journal of Leukocyte Biology. 2015;98(4):479&#x2013;487. doi: 10.1189/jlb.4RU0315-081RR.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1189/jlb.4RU0315-081RR</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26216938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang H, Hosein A, Mattioli-Belmonte M. Traditional chinese medicine and orthopedic biomaterials: host of opportunities from herbal extracts. Materials Science and Engineering: C. 2021;120:111760. doi: 10.1016/j.msec.2020.111760.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.msec.2020.111760</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33545901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tao P, Ji J, Gu S, Wang Q, Xu Y. Progress in the mechanism of autophagy and traditional chinese medicine herb involved in dementia. Frontiers in Pharmacology. 2022;12:825330. doi: 10.3389/fphar.2021.825330.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphar.2021.825330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8886436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35242028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Woude D, van der Helm-van Mil AHM. Update on the epidemiology, risk factors, and disease outcomes of rheumatoid arthritis. Best Practice &amp; Research Clinical Rheumatology. 2018;32(2):174&#x2013;187. doi: 10.1016/j.berh.2018.10.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.berh.2018.10.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30527425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vargas-Lagos C, Mart&#xed;nez D, Oyarz&#xfa;n R, Avenda&#xf1;o Herrera R, Y&#xe1;&#xf1;ez AJ, Pontigo JP, Vargas-Chacoff L. High doses of francisella noatunensis induces an immune response in Eleginops Maclovinus. Fish &amp; Shellfish Immunology. 2019;90:1&#x2013;11. doi: 10.1016/j.fsi.2019.04.023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fsi.2019.04.023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31015063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Miao M, Qu L, Cui Y, Zhang Y. Protective effects of geniposide against Tripterygium glycosides (TG)-induced liver injury and its mechanisms. The Journal of Toxicological Sciences. 2016;41(1):165&#x2013;173. doi: 10.2131/jts.41.165.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2131/jts.41.165</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26763404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S, Hu D, Wang C, Tang X, Du M, Gu X, Suo J, Hu M, Fang R, Zhu X, Zhang X, Du A, Suo X, Liu X. Transcriptional profiling of innate immune responses in sheep PBMCs induced by haemonchus contortus soluble extracts. Parasites Vectors. 2019;12(1):182. doi: 10.1186/s13071-019-3441-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13071-019-3441-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6482558</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31023355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S, Li R, He S, He L, Zhao H, Deng X, Chen Z. Tripterygium wilfordii glycosides upregulate the new anti-inflammatory cytokine IL-37 through ERK1/2 and P38 MAPK signal pathways. Evidence-Based Complementary and Alternative Medicine. 2017;2017:1&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1155/2017/9148523.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2017/9148523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong CK, Wong PTY, Tam LS, Li EK, Chen DP, Lam CWK. Activation profile of toll-like receptors of peripheral blood lymphocytes in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. Clinical and Experimental Immunology. 2009;159(1):11&#x2013;22. doi: 10.1111/j.1365-2249.2009.04036.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2249.2009.04036.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2802691</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19843090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu H, Chang C, Lu Q. The epigenetics of lupus erythematosus. In: Chang C, Lu Q, editors. Epigenetics in allergy and autoimmunity. Vol. 1253. Springer Singapore; Singapore: 2020. pp. 185&#x2013;207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-981-15-3449-2_7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32445096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H, Wu Z-Y, Yang Y-Y, Yang F-Q, Li S-P. Recent applications of immobilized biomaterials in herbal analysis. Journal of Chromatography A. 2019a;1603:216&#x2013;230. doi: 10.1016/j.chroma.2019.06.059.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chroma.2019.06.059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31277949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang W, Shao Z, Fu R, Wang H, Li L, Liu H. Expressions of CD96 and CD123 in bone marrow cells of patients with myelodysplastic syndromes. Clinical Laboratory. 2015;61(10):1429&#x2013;1434. doi: 10.7754/Clin.Lab.2015.141240.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7754/Clin.Lab.2015.141240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26642704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Chen Y, Gu T, Xu Q, Zhu G, Chen G. Effects of Salmonella Enterica serovar enteritidis infection on egg production and the immune response of the laying duck Anas Platyrhynchos. PeerJ. 2019b;7:e6359. doi: 10.7717/peerj.6359.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7717/peerj.6359</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6348949</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30701142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou X, Zhang P, Zhang C, Zhu Z. Promotion of bone formation by naringin in a titanium particle-induced diabetic murine calvarial osteolysis model: promotion of bone formation by naringin. Journal of Orthopaedic Research. 2010;28(4):451&#x2013;456. doi: 10.1002/jor.21002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jor.21002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19824055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu H, Mi W, Luo H, Chen T, Liu S, Raman I, Zuo X, Li Q-Z. Whole-genome transcription and DNA methylation analysis of peripheral blood mononuclear cells identified aberrant gene regulation pathways in systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Research &amp; Therapy. 2016;18(1):162. doi: 10.1186/s13075-016-1050-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13075-016-1050-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4942934</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27412348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ziaei S, Halaby R. Immunosuppressive, anti-inflammatory and anti-cancer properties of triptolide: a mini review. Avicenna Journal of Phytomedicine. 2016;6(2):149&#x2013;164. doi: 10.22038/ajp.2016.6329.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.22038/ajp.2016.6329</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4877967</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27222828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>