<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37317623</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1756-185X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of rheumatic diseases</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Rheum Dis</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Identification of potent target and its mechanism of action of Tripterygium wilfordii Hook F in the treatment of lupus nephritis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1529</StartPage><EndPage>1539</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1529-1539</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/1756-185X.14780</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="AIM" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The Chinese anti-rheumatic herbal remedy Tripterygium wilfordii Hook F (TWHF) has been widely shown to be effective in treating lupus nephritis (LN), but the therapeutic targets and mechanisms of action are still unclear. In this study, we aimed to combine mRNA expression profile analysis and network pharmacology analysis to screen the pathogenic genes and pathways involved in LN and to explore the potential targets of TWHF in the treatment of LN.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">The mRNA expression profiles of LN patients were used to screen differentially expressed genes (DEGs) and to predict associated pathogenic pathways and networks via the Ingenuity Pathway Analysis database. Through molecular docking, we predicted the mechanism by which TWHF interacts with candidate targets.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 351 DEGs were screened from the glomeruli of LN patients and were mainly concentrated in the role of pattern recognition receptors in the recognition of bacteria and viruses and interferon signaling pathways. A total of 130 DEGs were screened from the tubulointerstitium of LN patients, which were concentrated in the interferon signaling pathway. TWHF might be effective in treating LN by hydrogen bonding to regulate the functions of 24 DEGs (including HMOX1, ALB, and CASP1), which are mainly concentrated in the B-cell signaling pathway.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The mRNA expression profile of renal tissue from LN patients revealed a large number of DEGs. TWHF has been shown to interact with the DEGs (including HMOX1, ALB and CASP1) through hydrogen bonding to treat LN.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Authors. International Journal of Rheumatic Diseases published by Asia Pacific League of Associations for Rheumatology and John Wiley &amp; Sons Australia, Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cai</LastName><ForeName>Bin</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rheumatology and Immunology, Shanghai Changzheng Hospital, Naval Medical University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lu</LastName><ForeName>Hongjuan</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rheumatology and Immunology, Shanghai Changzheng Hospital, Naval Medical University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ye</LastName><ForeName>Qianyi</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rheumatology and Immunology, Shanghai Changzheng Hospital, Naval Medical University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xiao</LastName><ForeName>Qingqing</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Shanghai Chest Hospital, Shanghai Jiaotong University School of Medicine, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Xin</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rheumatology and Immunology, Shanghai Changzheng Hospital, Naval Medical University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Huji</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8588-118X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rheumatology and Immunology, Shanghai Changzheng Hospital, Naval Medical University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, Tsinghua University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Peking-Tsinghua Center for Life Sciences, Tsinghua University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2018AAA0100300</GrantID><Agency>China Ministry of Science and Technology</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>82271852</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>82201981</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>31821003</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>shslczdzk02602</GrantID><Agency>Shanghai Municipal Key Clinical Specialty Fund</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2020YCXYJ-QN04</GrantID><Agency>the Innovative Clinical Research Project of Shanghai Changzheng Hospital</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Rheum Dis</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101474930</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1756-1841</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>9008-11-1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D007372">Interferons</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D012333">RNA, Messenger</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D004365">Drugs, Chinese Herbal</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008181" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lupus Nephritis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D029757" MajorTopicYN="N">Tripterygium</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D062105" MajorTopicYN="N">Molecular Docking Simulation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007372" MajorTopicYN="N">Interferons</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012333" MajorTopicYN="N">RNA, Messenger</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004365" MajorTopicYN="Y">Drugs, Chinese Herbal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ingenuity Pathway Analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Tripterygium wilfordii Hook F</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lupus nephritis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">molecular docking</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">network pharmacology</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37317623</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1756-185X.14780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Durcan L, O'Dwyer T, Petri M. Management strategies and future directions for systemic lupus erythematosus in adults. Lancet. 2019;393(10188):2332-2343.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bultink IEM, de Vries F, van Vollenhoven RF, Lalmohamed A. Mortality, causes of death and influence of medication use in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus vs matched controls. Rheumatology (Oxford). 2021;60(1):207-216.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohan C, Putterman C. Genetics and pathogenesis of systemic lupus erythematosus and lupus nephritis. Nat Rev Nephrol. 2015;11(6):329-341.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anders HJ, Saxena R, Zhao MH, Parodis I, Salmon JE, Mohan C. Lupus nephritis. Nat Rev Dis Primers. 2020;6(1):7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh JA, Hossain A, Kotb A, et al. Treatments for lupus nephritis: a systematic review and network metaanalysis. J Rheumatol. 2016;43(10):1801-1815.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh JA, Hossain A, Kotb A, Wells G. Risk of serious infections with immunosuppressive drugs and glucocorticoids for lupus nephritis: a systematic review and network meta-analysis. BMC Med. 2016;14(1):137.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emadi A, Jones RJ, Brodsky RA. Cyclophosphamide and cancer: golden anniversary. Nat Rev Clin Oncol. 2009;6(11):638-647.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Wong YK, Liao F. What has traditional Chinese medicine delivered for modern medicine? Expert Rev Mol Med. 2018;20:e4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tao X, Fan F, Hoffmann V, et al. Effective therapy for nephritis in (NZB x NZW)F1 mice with triptolide and tripdiolide, the principal active components of the Chinese herbal remedy Tripterygium wilfordii Hook F. Arthritis Rheum. 2008;58(6):1774-1783.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tao X, Lipsky PE. The Chinese anti-inflammatory and immunosuppressive herbal remedy Tripterygium wilfordii Hook F. Rheum Dis Clin North Am. 2000;26(1):29-50, viii.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan K, Li X, Lu Q, et al. Application and mechanisms of triptolide in the treatment of inflammatory diseases - a review. Front Pharmacol. 2019;10:1469.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu W, Fu W, Wei X, Yang Y, Lu C, Liu Z. A network pharmacology study on the active ingredients and potential targets of Tripterygium wilfordii Hook for treatment of rheumatoid arthritis. Evid Based Complement Alternat Med. 2019;2019:5276865.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Z, Chen B, Chen S, et al. Applications of network pharmacology in traditional Chinese medicine research. Evid Based Complement Alternat Med. 2020;2020:1646905.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berthier CC, Bethunaickan R, Gonzalez-Rivera T, et al. Cross-species transcriptional network analysis defines shared inflammatory responses in murine and human lupus nephritis. J Immunol. 2012;189(2):988-1001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen CD, Frach K, Schlondorff D, Kretzler M. Quantitative gene expression analysis in renal biopsies: a novel protocol for a high-throughput multicenter application. Kidney Int. 2002;61(1):133-140.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berthier CC, Zhang H, Schin M, et al. Enhanced expression of Janus kinase-signal transducer and activator of transcription pathway members in human diabetic nephropathy. Diabetes. 2009;58(2):469-477.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R software R Core Team. R: A language and environment for statistical computing. R Foundation for Statistical Computing; 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shannon P, Markiel A, Ozier O, et al. Cytoscape: a software environment for integrated models of biomolecular interaction networks. Genome Res. 2003;13(11):2498-2504.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chin CH, Chen SH, Wu HH, Ho CW, Ko MT, Lin CY. cytoHubba: identifying hub objects and sub-networks from complex interactome. BMC Syst Biol. 2014;8(Suppl 4):S11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bethunaickan R, Berthier CC, Zhang W, Kretzler M, Davidson A. Comparative transcriptional profiling of 3 murine models of SLE nephritis reveals both unique and shared regulatory networks. PLoS One. 2013;8(10):e77489.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren J, Catalina MD, Eden K, et al. Selective histone deacetylase 6 inhibition normalizes B cell activation and germinal center formation in a model of systemic lupus erythematosus. Front Immunol. 2019;10:2512.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boezio B, Audouze K, Ducrot P, Taboureau O. Network-based approaches in pharmacology. Mol Inform. 2017;36(10).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berger SI, Iyengar R. Network analyses in systems pharmacology. Bioinformatics. 2009;25(19):2466-2472.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Li XJ. Network pharmacology and drug discovery. Sheng Li Ke Xue Jin Zhan. 2011;42(4):241-245.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding M, Ma W, Wang X, et al. A network pharmacology integrated pharmacokinetics strategy for uncovering pharmacological mechanism of compounds absorbed into the blood of Dan-Lou tablet on coronary heart disease. J Ethnopharmacol. 2019;242:112055.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterner RM, Hartono SP, Grande JP. The pathogenesis of lupus nephritis. J Clin Cell Immunol. 2014;5(2):205-228.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almaani S, Meara A, Rovin BH. Update on lupus nephritis. Clin J Am Soc Nephrol. 2017;12(5):825-835.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalunian KC. Interferon-targeted therapy in systemic lupus erythematosus: is this an alternative to targeting B and T cells? Lupus. 2016;25(10):1097-1101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dorner T, Furie R. Novel paradigms in systemic lupus erythematosus. Lancet. 2019;393(10188):2344-2358.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riggs JM, Hanna RN, Rajan B, et al. Characterisation of anifrolumab, a fully human anti-interferon receptor antagonist antibody for the treatment of systemic lupus erythematosus. Lupus Sci Med. 2018;5(1):e000261.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oni L, Wright RD, Marks S, Beresford MW, Tullus K. Kidney outcomes for children with lupus nephritis. Pediatr Nephrol. 2021;36(6):1377-1385.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vukelic M, Li Y, Kyttaris VC. Novel treatments in lupus. Front Immunol. 2018;9:2658.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morand EF, Furie R, Tanaka Y, et al. Trial of anifrolumab in active systemic lupus erythematosus. N Engl J Med. 2020;382(3):211-221.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deeks ED. Anifrolumab: first approval. Drugs. 2021;81(15):1795-1802.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adamichou C, Georgakis S, Bertsias G. Cytokine targets in lupus nephritis: current and future prospects. Clin Immunol. 2019;206:42-52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayoub I, Nelson J, Rovin BH. Induction therapy for lupus nephritis: the highlights. Curr Rheumatol Rep. 2018;20(10):60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy G, Isenberg DA. New therapies for systemic lupus erythematosus - past imperfect, future tense. Nat Rev Rheumatol. 2019;15(7):403-412.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gatto M, Zen M, Iaccarino L, Doria A. New therapeutic strategies in systemic lupus erythematosus management. Nat Rev Rheumatol. 2019;15(1):30-48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tao X, Fan F, Hoffmann V, Longo NS, Lipsky PE. Therapeutic impact of the ethyl acetate extract of Tripterygium wilfordii Hook F on nephritis in NZB/W F1 mice. Arthritis Res Ther. 2006;8(1):R24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo C, Fu R, Zhou M, et al. Pathogenesis of lupus nephritis: RIP3 dependent necroptosis and NLRP3 inflammasome activation. J Autoimmun. 2019;103:102286.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fanouriakis A, Kostopoulou M, Alunno A, et al. 2019 update of the EULAR recommendations for the management of systemic lupus erythematosus. Ann Rheum Dis. 2019;78(6):736-745.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang F, Bae SC, Bass D, et al. A pivotal phase III, randomised, placebo-controlled study of belimumab in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus located in China, Japan and South Korea. Ann Rheum Dis. 2018;77(3):355-363.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song J, Zhao L, Li Y. Comprehensive bioinformatics analysis of mRNA expression profiles and identification of a miRNA-mRNA network associated with lupus nephritis. Lupus. 2020;29(8):854-861.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kong J, Li L, Zhimin L, et al. Potential protein biomarkers for systemic lupus erythematosus determined by bioinformatics analysis. Comput Biol Chem. 2019;83:107135.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tseng TC, Huang DY, Lai LC, et al. Dual immuno-renal targeting of 7-benzylidenenaltrexone alleviates lupus nephritis via FcgammaRIIB and HO-1. J Mol Med (Berl). 2018;96(5):413-425.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takeda Y, Takeno M, Iwasaki M, et al. Chemical induction of HO-1 suppresses lupus nephritis by reducing local iNOS expression and synthesis of anti-dsDNA antibody. Clin Exp Immunol. 2004;138(2):237-244.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kahlenberg JM, Kaplan MJ. The inflammasome and lupus: another innate immune mechanism contributing to disease pathogenesis? Curr Opin Rheumatol. 2014;26(5):475-481.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>