<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37335171</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>25</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2163-0763</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>95</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The journal of trauma and acute care surgery</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Trauma Acute Care Surg</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Long-term physical and mental health outcomes of pediatric firearm-injured victims: A prospective cohort study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e31</StartPage><EndPage>e35</EndPage><MedlinePgn>e31-e35</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/TA.0000000000004090</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Firearms are a leading cause of injury among US youth. There is little research describing outcomes after pediatric firearm injuries, particularly past 1 year.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">This study aimed to assess long-term physical and mental health outcomes among nonfatal firearm versus motor vehicle collision (MVC)-injured victims and versus a standard population.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">We retrospectively identified firearm and MVC-injured pediatric patients seen at one of our four trauma centers (January 2008 to October 2020) and prospectively assessed outcomes using validated patient-reported outcome measures. Eligible patients were English speaking, injured &#x2265;5 months before study start, younger than 18 years at time of injury, and 8 years or older at study start. All firearm patients were included; MVC patients were matched 1:1 with firearm patients for Injury Severity Score (dichotomized &lt;15 or &#x2265;15), age range (&#xb1;1 year), and year of injury. We conducted structured interviews of patients and parents using validated tools (Patient-Reported Outcomes Measurement Information System tools, Children's Impact of Event Scale for younger than 18 years and parent proxies). Patient-Reported Outcomes Measurement Information System scores are reported on a T score metric (mean [SD], 50 [10]); higher scores indicate more of the measured domain. We used paired t tests, Wilcoxon signed-rank tests, and McNemar's test to compare demographics, clinical characteristics, and outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">There were 24 participants in each of the MVC and firearm-injured groups. Compared with MVC-injured patients, firearm-injured patients younger than 18 years had similar scores, and firearm-injured patients 18 years or older had higher anxiety scores (59.4 [8.3] vs. 51.2 [9.4]). Compared with a standard population, patients younger than 18 years had worse global health scores (mean [SD], 43.4 [9.7]), and participants 18 years or older reported increased fatigue (mean [SD], 61.1 [3.3]) and anxiety (mean [SD], 59.4 [8.3]).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">Long-term effects of firearm-injured patients were poorer than matched MVC and the standard population in few domains. Further study in a larger, prospectively recruited cohort is warranted to better characterize physical and mental health outcomes.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Haasz</LastName><ForeName>Maya</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Section of Emergency Medicine, Department of Pediatrics (M.H., A.D., J.L., L.A.), Children's Hospital Colorado, University of Colorado School of Medicine, Aurora, Colorado; Department of Surgery (J.S.), Louisiana State University Health Sciences Center, Baton Rouge, Lousiana; Department of Pediatric Surgery (M.N.), Children's Hospital Colorado; Section of Pediatric Surgery, Department of Surgery (R.P.), Children's Hospital Colorado; Division of Cardiology (C.K.), and Adult and Child Center for Outcomes Research and Delivery Science (C.K.), University of Colorado School of Medicine, Aurora; Department of Surgery (T.S.), UCHealth Memorial Hospital, Colorado Springs; Section of Pediatric Surgery, Department of Surgery (J.Z.), Children's Hospital Colorado, University of Colorado School of Medicine, Aurora, Colorado; Denver University (W.A.), Denver, Colorado; and Section of Hospital Medicine, Department of Pediatrics (L.A.), Children's Hospital of Colorado, University of Colorado School of Medicine, Aurora, Colorado.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dulchavsky</LastName><ForeName>Alexandria</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stevens</LastName><ForeName>Jenny</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nolan</LastName><ForeName>Margo</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Leonard</LastName><ForeName>Jan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Phillips</LastName><ForeName>Ryan</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Knoepke</LastName><ForeName>Christopher</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schroeppel</LastName><ForeName>Thomas</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zuk</LastName><ForeName>Jeannie</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abbey</LastName><ForeName>William</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ambroggio</LastName><ForeName>Lilliam</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>UL1 TR002535</GrantID><Acronym>TR</Acronym><Agency>NCATS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Trauma Acute Care Surg</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101570622</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2163-0755</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005389" MajorTopicYN="Y">Firearms</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011446" MajorTopicYN="N">Prospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014948" MajorTopicYN="Y">Wounds, Gunshot</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017063" MajorTopicYN="N">Outcome Assessment, Health Care</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>8</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37335171</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/TA.0000000000004090</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">01586154-202310000-00024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Goldstick JE, Cunningham RM, Carter PM. Current causes of death in children and adolescents in the United States. N Engl J Med . 2022;386(20):1955&#x2013;1956.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrews AL, Killings X, Oddo ER, Gastineau KAB, Hink AB. Pediatric firearm injury mortality epidemiology. Pediatrics . 2022;149(3):e2021052739.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stevens J, Pickett K, Reppucci ML, Nolan M, Moulton SL. National trends in pediatric firearm and automobile fatalities. J Pediatr Surg . 2023;58(1):130&#x2013;135.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Injury Data Visualization Tools. WISQARS. CDC. Cited July 19, 2022. Available at: https://wisqars.cdc.gov/data/non-fatal/home . Accessed July 10, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oddo ER, Simpson AN, Maldonado L, Hink AB, Andrews AL. Mental health care utilization among children and adolescents with a firearm injury. JAMA Surg . 2023;158(1):29&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oddo ER, Maldonado L, Hink AB, Simpson AN, Andrews AL. Increase in mental health diagnoses among youth with nonfatal firearm injuries. Acad Pediatr . 2021;21(7):1203&#x2013;1208.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pulcini CD, Goyal MK, Hall M, Gruhler De Souza H, Chaudhary S, Alpern ER, et al. Nonfatal firearm injuries: utilization and expenditures for children pre- and postinjury. Acad Emerg Med . 2021;28(8):840&#x2013;847.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vella MA, Warshauer A, Tortorello G, Fernandez-Moure J, Giacolone J, Chen B, et al. Long-term functional, psychological, emotional, and social outcomes in survivors of firearm injuries. JAMA Surg . 2020;155(1):51&#x2013;59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herrera-Escobar JP, de Jager E, McCarty JC, Lipsitz S, Haider AH, Salim A, et al. Patient-reported outcomes at 6 to 12 months among survivors of firearm injury in the United States. Ann Surg . 2021;274(6):e1247&#x2013;e1251.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cunningham RM, Carter PM, Ranney ML, Walton M, Zeoli AM, Alpern ER, et al. Prevention of firearm injuries among children and adolescents: consensus-driven research agenda from the Firearm Safety Among Children and Teens (FACTS) consortium. JAMA Pediatr . 2019;173(8):780&#x2013;789.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forrest CB, Tucker CA, Ravens-Sieberer U, Pratiwadi R, Moon J, Teneralli RE, et al. Concurrent validity of the PROMIS &#xae; pediatric global health measure. Qual Life Res . 2016;25(3):739&#x2013;751.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips R, Shahi N, Bensard D, Meier M, Shirek G, Goldsmith A, et al. Guns, scalpels, and sutures: the cost of gunshot wounds in children and adolescents. J Trauma Acute Care Surg . 2020;89(3):558&#x2013;564.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris PA, Taylor R, Minor BL, Elliott V, Fernandez M, O&#x2019;Neal L, et al. The REDCap consortium: Building an international community of software platform partners. J Biomed Inform . 2019;95:103208.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>PROMIS Scoring Manuals. Cited January 16, 2023. Available at: https://www.healthmeasures.net/promis-scoring-manuals . Accessed July 2, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>PROMIS. Cited January 16, 2023. Available at: https://www.healthmeasures.net/index.php?option=com_content&amp;view=category&amp;layout=blog&amp;id=147&amp;Itemid=806 . Accessed September 19, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thissen D, Liu Y, Magnus B, Quinn H, Gipson DS, Dampier C, et al. Estimating minimally important difference (MID) in PROMIS pediatric measures using the scale-judgment method. Qual Life Res . 2016;25(1):13&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kroenke K, Baye F, Lourens SG. Comparative responsiveness and minimally important difference of common anxiety measures. Med Care . 2019;57(11):890&#x2013;897.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yost KJ, Eton DT, Garcia SF, Cella D. Minimally important differences were estimated for six patient-reported outcomes measurement information system&#x2014;cancer scales in advanced-stage cancer patients. J Clin Epidemiol . 2011;64(5):507&#x2013;516.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perrin S, Meiser-Stedman R, Smith P. The Children's Revised Impact of Event Scale (CRIES): validity as a screening instrument for PTSD. Behav Cogn Psychother . 2005;33(4):487&#x2013;498.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Child Revised Impact of Events Scale (CRIES). Cited January 16, 2023. Available at: https://www.corc.uk.net/outcome-experience-measures/child-revised-impact-of-events-scale-cries/ . Accessed April 17, 2020.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>