<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37368557</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>29</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1538-8662</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>48</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jul</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Nurse practitioner</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Nurse Pract</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Systemic lupus erythematosus: An approach to pharmacologic interventions.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>37</StartPage><EndPage>46</EndPage><MedlinePgn>37-46</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/01.NPR.0000000000000071</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Drug therapy for patients with systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) aims to decrease symptom severity. Pharmacologic interventions are divided into four categories: antimalarials, glucocorticoids (GCs), immunosuppressants (ISs), and biological agents. Hydroxychloroquine, the most commonly used antimalarial treatment for this disease, is a mainstay in treating all patients with SLE. The multitude of adverse reactions of GCs has led clinicians to minimize their dosages or discontinue them whenever possible. To speed up the discontinuation or minimization of GCs, ISs are used for their steroid-sparing properties. Furthermore, certain ISs such as cyclophosphamide are recommended as maintenance agents to prevent flares and reduce the reoccurrence and severity of the disease state. Biological agents are recommended when other treatment options have failed due to intolerance or inefficacy. This article presents pharmacologic approaches for managing SLE in patients based on clinical practice guidelines and data from randomized controlled trials.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>El Hussein</LastName><ForeName>Mohamed Toufic</ForeName><Initials>MT</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wong</LastName><ForeName>Cayla</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Nurse Pract</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7603663</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0361-1817</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>4QWG6N8QKH</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D006886">Hydroxychloroquine</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000962">Antimalarials</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D007166">Immunosuppressive Agents</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D005938">Glucocorticoids</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D001685">Biological Factors</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000139" MajorTopicYN="N">chemically induced</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006886" MajorTopicYN="N">Hydroxychloroquine</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000962" MajorTopicYN="Y">Antimalarials</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007166" MajorTopicYN="N">Immunosuppressive Agents</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005938" MajorTopicYN="N">Glucocorticoids</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001685" MajorTopicYN="N">Biological Factors</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37368557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/01.NPR.0000000000000071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00006205-202307000-00009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Mistry P, Kaplan MJ. Cell death in the pathogenesis of systemic lupus erythematosus and lupus nephritis. Clin Immunol . 2017;185:59&#x2013;73. doi:10.1016/j.clim.2016.08.010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izmirly PM, Parton H, Wang L, et al. Prevalence of systemic lupus erythematosus in the United States: estimates from a meta-analysis of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention National Lupus Registries. Arthritis Rheumatol . 2021;73(6):991&#x2013;996. doi:10.1002/art.41632.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon C, Amissah-Arthur M-B, Gayed M, et al. The British Society for Rheumatology guideline for the management of systemic lupus erythematosus in adults. Rheumatology (Oxford) . 2018;57(1):e1&#x2013;e45. doi:10.1093/rheumatology/kex286.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Catalina MD, Owen KA, Labonte AC, Grammer AC, Lipsky PE. The pathogenesis of systemic lupus erythematosus: harnessing big data to understand the molecular basis of lupus. J Autoimmun . 2020;110:102359. doi:10.1016/j.jaut.2019.102359.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pisetsky DS. The central role of nucleic acids in the pathogenesis of systemic lupus erythematosus. F1000Res . 2019;8:368. doi:10.12688/f1000research.17959.1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fanouriakis A, Tziolos N, Bertsias G, Boumpas DT. Update on the diagnosis and management of systemic lupus erythematosus. Ann Rheum Dis . 2020;80(1):14&#x2013;25. doi:10.1136/annrheumdis-2020-218272.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiang H-Y, Guo Z-A, Wu T-W, Peng T-R. Efficacy and safety of belimumab therapy in systemic lupus erythematosus: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Lupus . 2022;31(6):666&#x2013;673. doi:10.1177/09612033221090888.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aringer M, Costenbader K, Daikh D, et al. 2019 European League Against Rheumatism/American College of Rheumatology classification criteria for systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Rheumatol . 2019;71(9):1400&#x2013;1412. doi:10.1002/art.40930.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fanouriakis A, Kostopoulou M, Alunno A, et al. 2019 update of the EULAR recommendations for the management of systemic lupus erythematosus. Ann Rheum Dis . 2019;78(6):736&#x2013;745. doi:10.1136/annrheumdis-2019-215089.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruperto N, Hanrahan LM, Alarc&#xf3;n GS, et al. International consensus for a definition of disease flare in lupus. Lupus . 2010;20(5):453&#x2013;462. doi:10.1177/0961203310388445.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keeling SO, Alabdurubalnabi Z, Avina-Zubieta A, et al. Canadian Rheumatology Association recommendations for the assessment and monitoring of systemic lupus erythematosus. J Rheumatol . 2018;45(10):1426&#x2013;1439. doi:10.3899/jrheum.171459.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Rheumatology Ad Hoc Committee on Systemic Lupus Erythematosus Guidelines. Guidelines for referral and management of systemic lupus erythematosus in adults. Arthritis Rheum . 1999;42(9):1785&#x2013;1796.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MDCalc. Systemic Lupus Erythematosus Disease Activity Index 2000 (SLEDAI-2K). 2023. www.mdcalc.com/calc/10099/systemic-lupus-erythematosus-disease-activity-index-2000-sledai-2k .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dima A, Jurcut C, Chasset F, Felten R, Arnaud L. Hydroxychloroquine in systemic lupus erythematosus: overview of current knowledge. Ther Adv Musculoskelet Dis . 2022;14. doi:10.1177/1759720x211073001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Felten R, Lipsker D, Sibilia J, Chasset F, Arnaud L. The history of lupus throughout the ages. J Am Acad Dermatol . 2020;87(6):1361&#x2013;1369. doi:10.1016/j.jaad.2020.04.150.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruiz-Irastorza G, Ramos-Casals M, Brito-Zeron P, Khamashta MA. Clinical efficacy and side effects of antimalarials in systemic lupus erythematosus: a systematic review. Ann Rheum Dis . 2010;69(1):20&#x2013;28. doi:10.1136/ard.2008.101766.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souza Botelho M, Bolfi F, Leite RGOF, et al. Systematic review and meta-analysis of the safety of chloroquine and hydroxychloroquine from randomized controlled trials on malarial and non-malarial conditions. Syst Rev . 2021;10(1):294. doi:10.1186/s13643-021-01835-x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ponticelli C, Moroni G. Hydroxychloroquine in systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE). Expert Opin Drug Saf . 2016;16(3):411&#x2013;419. doi:10.1080/14740338.2017.1269168.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zahr N, Urien S, Funck-Brentano C, et al. Evaluation of hydroxychloroquine blood concentrations and effects in childhood-onset systemic lupus erythematosus. Pharmaceuticals (Basel) . 2021;14(3):273. doi:10.3390/ph14030273.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garg S, Unnithan R, Hansen KE, Costedoat-Chalumeau N, Bartels CM. Clinical significance of monitoring hydroxychloroquine levels in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken) . 2021;73(5):707&#x2013;716. doi:10.1002/acr.24155.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Telek HH, Yesilirmak N, Sungur G, Ozdemir Y, Yesil NK, Ornek F. Retinal toxicity related to hydroxychloroquine in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus and rheumatoid arthritis. Doc Ophthalmol . 2017;135(3):187&#x2013;194. doi:10.1007/s10633-017-9607-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edington FLB, Gadellha SR, Santiago MB. Safety of treatment with chloroquine and hydroxychloroquine: a ten-year systematic review and meta-analysis. Eur J Intern Med . 2021;88:63&#x2013;72. doi:10.1016/j.ejim.2021.03.028.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoque MR, Avi&#xf1;a-Zubieta JA, De Vera MA, Qian Y, Esdaile JM, Xie H. Impact of antimalarial adherence on mortality among patients with newly diagnosed systemic lupus erythematosus: a population-based cohort study. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken) . 2022;74(7):1089&#x2013;1097. doi:10.1002/acr.24550.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh JA, Hossain A, Kotb A, Wells G. Risk of serious infections with immunosuppressive drugs and glucocorticoids for lupus nephritis: a systematic review and network meta-analysis. BMC Med . 2016;14(1):137. doi:10.1186/s12916-016-0673-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun T, Wang J, Zhang R, Li Y. A systematic review and meta-analysis: effects of glucocorticoids on rheumatoid arthritis and systemic lupus erythematosus. Ann Palliat Med . 2021;10(7):7977&#x2013;7991. doi:10.21037/apm-21-1485.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee YH, Song GG. Comparative efficacy and safety of tacrolimus, mycophenolate mofetil, azathioprine, and cyclophosphamide as maintenance therapy for lupus nephritis. Z Rheumatol . 2017;76(10):904&#x2013;912. doi:10.1007/s00393-016-0186-z.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yap DY, Chan TM. What is the ideal duration of maintenance therapy for lupus nephritis. Expert Rev Clin Immunol . 2022;18(5):425&#x2013;427. doi:10.1080/1744666x.2022.2056020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee JS, Oh JS, Kim Y-G, Lee C-K, Yoo B, Hong S. Methotrexate-related toxicity in patients with rheumatoid arthritis and renal dysfunction. Rheumatol Int . 2020;40(5):765&#x2013;770. doi:10.1007/s00296-020-04547-y.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russell MD, Dey M, Flint J, et alBritish Society for Rheumatology guideline on prescribing drugs in pregnancy and breastfeeding: immunomodulatory anti-rheumatic drugs and corticosteroids [published correction appears in Rheumatology (Oxford) . 2023;62(5):2021]. Rheumatology (Oxford). 2023;62(4):e48&#x2013;e88. doi:10.1093/rheumatology/keac551.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaballo BG, Ahmed AE, Nur MM, Khalid IO, Abu-Aisha H. Mycophenolate mofetil versus azathioprine for maintenance treatment of lupus nephritis. Saudi J Kidney Dis Transpl . 2016;27(4):717&#x2013;725. doi:10.4103/1319-2442.185233.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendonca S, Gupta D, Ali S, Gupta P. Mycophenolate mofetil or cyclophosphamide in indian patients with lupus nephritis: which is better? A single-center experience. Saudi J Kidney Dis Transpl . 2017;28(5):1069&#x2013;1077. doi:10.4103/1319-2442.215147.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cobo-Ib&#xe1;&#xf1;ez T, Loza-Santamar&#xed;a E, Pego-Reigosa JM, et al. Efficacy and safety of rituximab in the treatment of non-renal systemic lupus erythematosus: a systematic review. Semin Arthritis Rheum . 2014;44(2):175&#x2013;185. doi:10.1016/j.semarthrit.2014.04.002.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>