<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37417720</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>10</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1943-278X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>53</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Suicide &amp; life-threatening behavior</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Suicide Life Threat Behav</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>When safe firearm storage isn't enough: Examining risk profiles among firearm suicide decedents.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>655</StartPage><EndPage>665</EndPage><MedlinePgn>655-665</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/sltb.12971</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION">Suicide is a leading cause of death in the United States, and firearms are the most frequently used suicide method. Research suggests risk for firearm suicide increases with greater access to firearms (e.g., storing loaded or unlocked). Although safe firearm storage is promoted as a means of risk reduction, no studies have explored factors differentiating firearm suicide decedents who stored firearms safely vs. those who stored unsafely prior to death.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Utilizing data from the National Violent Death Reporting System, the current study aimed to determine which factors distinguish firearm suicide decedents who stored firearms safely vs. those who stored unsafely. The current sample included decedents for whom data were available on whether the firearm used in the suicide was stored loaded or unloaded (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;4269) and unlocked or locked (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;6273) prior to their death.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Results revealed using a long gun in the suicide (as opposed to a handgun) was associated with five times greater odds of storing unloaded prior to death, suggesting this safe firearm storage practice alone does not mitigate risk among all long gun owners.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">These findings indicate a need to increase suicide prevention efforts within the long gun owning community.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Published 2023. This article is a U.S. Government work and is in the public domain in the USA.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Houtsma</LastName><ForeName>Claire</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3455-5325</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Southeast Louisiana Veterans Health Care System, New Orleans, Louisiana, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>South Central Mental Illness Research, Education and Clinical Center, New Orleans, Louisiana, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Louisiana State University Health Sciences Center, New Orleans, Louisiana, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Raines</LastName><ForeName>Amanda M</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Southeast Louisiana Veterans Health Care System, New Orleans, Louisiana, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>South Central Mental Illness Research, Education and Clinical Center, New Orleans, Louisiana, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Louisiana State University Health Sciences Center, New Orleans, Louisiana, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>IK2 CX001978</GrantID><Acronym>CX</Acronym><Agency>CSRD VA</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013486">Research Support, U.S. Gov't, Non-P.H.S.</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Suicide Life Threat Behav</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7608054</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0363-0234</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014481" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">United States</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005389" MajorTopicYN="Y">Firearms</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014948" MajorTopicYN="Y">Wounds, Gunshot</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013405" MajorTopicYN="Y">Suicide</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000092864" MajorTopicYN="N">Suicide Prevention</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">firearms</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">loaded</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">locked</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">suicide prevention</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">unloaded</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">unlocked</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37417720</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sltb.12971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Anestis, M. D., Bandel, S. L., Butterworth, S. E., Bond, A. E., Daruwala, S. E., &amp; Bryan, C. J. (2020). Suicide risk and firearm ownership and storage behavior in a large military sample. Psychiatry Research, 291, 1-5. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.psychres.2020.113277</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anestis, M. D., Bryan, C. J., Capron, D. W., &amp; Bryan, A. O. (2021). Lethal means counseling, distribution of cable locks, and safe firearm storage practices among the Mississippi National Guard: A factorial randomized controlled trial, 2018-2020. American Journal of Public Health, 111(2), 309-317. https://doi.org/10.2105/ajph.2020.306019</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anestis, M. D., Daruwala, S., &amp; Capron, D. W. (2019). Firearm ownership, means safety, and suicidality. Suicide and Life-Threatening Behavior, 49(4), 1044-1057. https://doi.org/10.1111/sltb.12509</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anestis, M. D., Khazem, L. R., &amp; Anestis, J. C. (2017). Differentiating suicide decedents who died using firearms from those who died using other methods. Psychiatry Research, 252, 23-28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barber, C. W., &amp; Miller, M. J. (2014). Reducing a suicidal person's access to lethal means of suicide: A research agenda. American Journal of Preventive Medicine, 47(3), S264-S272. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.amepre.2014.05.028</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Betz, M. E., Rooney, L. A., Barnard, L. M., Siry-Bove, B. J., Brandspigel, S., McCarthy, M., Simeon, K., Meador, L., Rivara, F. P., Rowhani-Rahbar, A., &amp; Knoepke, C. E. (2022). Voluntary, temporary, out-of-home firearm storage: A qualitative study of stakeholder views. Suicide and Life-Threatening Behavior, 52(4), 655-667. https://doi.org/10.1111/sltb.12850</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bond, A. E., Karnick, A. T., Bandel, S. L., Capron, D. W., &amp; Anestis, M. D. (2022). Demographic differences in the type of firearm and location of bodily injury in firearm suicide decedents. Death Studies. https://doi.org/10.1080/07481187.2022.2144547</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butterworth, S. E., Daruwala, S. E., &amp; Anestis, M. D. (2020). The role of reason for firearm ownership in beliefs about firearms and suicide, openness to means safety, and current firearm storage. Suicide and Life-Threatening Behavior, 50(3), 617-630. https://doi.org/10.1111/sltb.12619</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carter, P. M., Losman, E., Roche, J. S., Malani, P. N., Kullgren, J. T., Solway, E., Kirch, M., Singer, D., Walton, M. A., Zeoli, A. M., &amp; Cunningham, R. M. (2022). Firearm ownership, attitudes, and safe storage practices among a nationally representative sample of older U.S. adults age 50 to 80. Preventive Medicine, 156, 1-10. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ypmed.2022.106955</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>CDC. (2018). National Violent Death Reporting System (NVDRS) coding manual revised [Online]. https://www.cdc.gov/injury/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>CDC. (2022). Web-based injury statistics query and reporting system: Fatal injury reports 1981-2020. https://wisqars.cdc.gov/fatal-reports</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, H., Cohen, P., &amp; Chen, S. (2010). How big is a big odds ratio? Interpreting the magnitudes of odds ratios in epidemiological studies. Communications in Statistics-Simulation and Computation&#xae;, 39(4), 860-864.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daruwala, S. E., Butterworth, S. E., &amp; Anestis, M. D. (2018). Openness to firearm storage safety as a suicide prevention tool among those exposed to suicide: The role of perceived closeness to the suicide decedent. Psychiatry Research, 269, 437-443. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.psychres.2018.08.050</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dempsey, C. L., Benedek, D. M., Zuromski, K. L., Riggs-Donovan, C., Ng, T. H. H., Nock, M. K., Kessler, R. C., &amp; Ursano, R. J. (2019). Association of firearm ownership, use, accessibility, and storage practices with suicide risk among US Army soldiers. JAMA Network Open, 2(6), e195383. https://doi.org/10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2019.5383</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fowler, K. A., Jack, S. P., Lyons, B. H., Betz, C. J., &amp; Petrosky, E. (2018). Surveillance for violent deaths-National violent death reporting system, 18 states, 2014. MMWR Surveillance summaries, 67(2), 1-36. https://doi.org/10.15585/mmwr.ss6702a1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horn, A., Grossman, D. C., Jones, W., &amp; Berger, L. (2003). Community based program to improve firearm storage practices in rural Alaska. Injury Prevention, 9(3), 231-234.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joiner, T. E. (2005). Why people die by suicide. Harvard University Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kellermann, A. L., Rivara, F. P., Somes, G., Reay, D. T., Francisco, J., Banton, J. G., Prodzinski, J., Fligner, C., &amp; Hackman, B. B. (1992). Suicide in the home in relation to gun ownership. New England Journal of Medicine, 327(7), 467-472. https://doi.org/10.1056/nejm199208133270705</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klonsky, E. D., &amp; May, A. M. (2015). The three-step theory (3ST): A new theory of suicide rooted in the &#x201c;ideation-to-action&#x201d; framework. International Journal of Cognitive Therapy, 8(2), 114-129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mann, J. J., &amp; Michel, C. A. (2016). Prevention of firearm suicide in the United States: What works and what is possible. American Journal of Psychiatry, 173(10), 969-979. https://doi.org/10.1176/appi.ajp.2016.16010069</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller, M., Barber, C., White, R. A., &amp; Azrael, D. (2013). Firearms and suicide in the United States: Is risk independent of underlying suicidal behavior? American Journal of Epidemiology, 178(6), 946-955. https://doi.org/10.1093/aje/kwt197</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morgan, E. R., Gomez, A., &amp; Rowhani-Rahbar, A. (2018). Firearm ownership, storage practices, and suicide risk factors in Washington state, 2013-2016. American Journal of Public Health, 108(7), 882-888. https://doi.org/10.2105/ajph.2018.304403</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National-Geographic. (2022). United States regions. National Geographic. https://education.nationalgeographic.org/resource/united-states-regions</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parker, K., Horowitz, J., Igielnik, R., Oliphant, B., &amp; Brown, A. (2017). America's complex relationship with guns: An in-depth look at the attitudes and experiences of U.S. adults. Pew Research Center. https://www.pewresearch.org/social-trends/wp-content/uploads/sites/3/2017/06/Guns-Report-FOR-WEBSITE-PDF-6-21.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ranganathan, P., Pramesh, C., &amp; Aggarwal, R. (2017). Common pitfalls in statistical analysis: Logistic regression. Perspectives in Clinical Research, 8(3), 148-151.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simonetti, J. A., Azrael, D., &amp; Miller, M. (2019). Firearm storage practices and risk perceptions among a nationally representative sample of U.S. veterans with and without self-harm risk factors. Suicide and Life-Threatening Behavior, 49(3), 653-664. https://doi.org/10.1111/sltb.12463</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simonetti, J. A., Azrael, D., Rowhani-Rahbar, A., &amp; Miller, M. (2018). Firearm storage practices among American veterans. American Journal of Preventive Medicine, 55(4), 445-454. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.amepre.2018.04.014</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simonetti, J. A., Rowhani-Rahbar, A., King, C., Bennett, E., &amp; Rivara, F. P. (2018). Evaluation of a community-based safe firearm and ammunition storage intervention. Injury Prevention, 24(3), 218-223. https://doi.org/10.1136/injuryprev-2016-042292</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simonetti, J. A., Simeona, C., Gallagher, C., Bennett, E., Rivara, F., &amp; Rowhani-Rahbar, A. (2019). Preferences for firearm locking devices and device features among participants in a firearm safety event. Western Journal of Emergency Medicine, 20(4), 552-556. https://doi.org/10.5811/westjem.2019.5.42727</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>True, G., Facundo, R., Houtsma, C., Raines, A. M., Asher, A., &amp; Constans, J. I. (2020). Veteran-informed safety intervention and outreach network (VISION): A public health approach to preventing firearm suicides [Conference&#xa0;presentation]. Annual conference on the science of dissemination and implementation. National Institutes of Health and Academy Health, Washington, D.C.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uspal, N. G., Strelitz, B., Cappetto, K., Tsogoo, A., Jensen, J., Rutman, L. E., Schloredt, K., Bradford, M. C., Bennett, E., &amp; Paris, C. A. (2021). Impact of a firearm safety device distribution intervention on storage practices after an emergent mental health visit. Academic Pediatrics, 21(7), 1209-1217.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams, J. (2023). The best trigger locks for multiple gun types. Revolar. https://revolar.com/best-trigger-locks/</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>