<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37485575</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>04</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1440-1797</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>28</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Nephrology (Carlton, Vic.)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Nephrology (Carlton)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Anti-C1q antibodies in lupus nephritis children with glomerular microthrombosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>485</StartPage><EndPage>494</EndPage><MedlinePgn>485-494</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/nep.14194</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="AIM" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Glomerular microthrombosis (GMT) was a common vascular lesion in patients with lupus nephritis (LN). The objective of this study was to investigate the relationship between serum anti-beta2-glycoprotein I antibodies (a-&#x3b2;2GP1) and anti-complement 1q antibodies (a-C1q) antibodies and to investigate the possible mechanism of GMT in children with LN.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">The subjects were 191 children with LN diagnosed by renal biopsy in our hospital from January 2017 to January 2020. The patients were divided into GMT group and non-GMT group. The clinical manifestations, laboratory tests, renal pathology, prognosis of the two groups and the relationship between a-&#x3b2;2GP1 and a-C1q antibodies were observed.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">In 191 children with LN, 52 cases (27.23%) presented with GMT. The value of C3, haemoglobin (Hb), estimate glomerular filtration rate (eGFR) and anticardiolipin antibody (ACA) in GMT group were lower than that of non-GMT group (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;.05, p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;.01). The value of serum creatinine (Scr), 24&#x2009;h proteinuria (PRO), urine red blood cells (RBC), N-acetyl-&#x3b2;-d-glucosidase (NAG) and retinol-binding protein (RBP), a-C1q, a-&#x3b2;2GP1, Systemic Lupus Erythematosus Disease Activity Index (SLEDAI) and renal histopathological activity index (AI) score in GMT group were higher than that of non-GMT group (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;.05, p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;.01). The positive proportions of serum a-C1q and a-&#x3b2;2GP1 in GMT group were higher than those in non-GMT group (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;.05). According to Spearman correlation analysis, a-C1q was positively correlated with AI score, SLEDAI, a-&#x3b2;2GP1, GMT, LN-III and LN-IV. Hb, eGFR and a-C1q Ab were associated with the formation of GMT in children with LN. The complete proteinuria remission and renal survival in GMT group were significantly lower than those in non-GMT group (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;.05, p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;.01).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">LN children with GMT had more severe clinical manifestations and renal pathologic damages, and poor outcome. Serum a-C1q level was positively correlated with a-&#x3b2;2GP1, and a-&#x3b2;2GP1 may be involved in the formation of GMT in children with LN, which might involve in the activation of complement classical pathway.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 Asian Pacific Society of Nephrology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Pei</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8313-8950</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Paediatrics, Jinling Hospital, School of Medicine, Nanjing University, Nanjing, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Xiao</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Paediatrics, Jinling Hospital, School of Medicine, Nanjing University, Nanjing, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fang</LastName><ForeName>Xiang</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Paediatrics, Jinling Hospital, School of Medicine, Nanjing University, Nanjing, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Chao</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Paediatrics, Jinling Hospital, School of Medicine, Nanjing University, Nanjing, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gao</LastName><ForeName>Chunlin</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Paediatrics, Jinling Hospital, School of Medicine, Nanjing University, Nanjing, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xia</LastName><ForeName>Zhengkun</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1443-9009</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Paediatrics, Jinling Hospital, School of Medicine, Nanjing University, Nanjing, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2018M643888</GrantID><Agency>China Postdoctoral Foundation</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>BE2017719</GrantID><Agency>Grant from Clinical Advanced Techniques, Primary Research &amp; Development Plan of Jiangsu Province</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>BK20190251</GrantID><Agency>Natural Science Foundation and Youth Fund Plan of Jiangsu Province</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>CXTDA2017022</GrantID><Agency>Pediatric Medical Innovation Team of Jiangsu Province</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2018K089B</GrantID><Agency>Postdoctoral Fund of Jiangsu Province</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Australia</Country><MedlineTA>Nephrology (Carlton)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9615568</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1320-5358</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D001323">Autoantibodies</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008181" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lupus Nephritis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007678" MajorTopicYN="N">Kidney Glomerulus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001323" MajorTopicYN="N">Autoantibodies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007668" MajorTopicYN="N">Kidney</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013927" MajorTopicYN="Y">Thrombosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011507" MajorTopicYN="N">Proteinuria</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anti-beta2-glycoprotein I antibodies</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anti-complement 1q antibodies</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">children</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">glomerular microthrombosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lupus nephritis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">renal biopsy</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37485575</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/nep.14194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Kamphuis S, Silverman ED. Prevalence and burden of pediatric-onset systemic lupus erythematosus. Nat Rev Rheumatol. 2010;6(9):538-546.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levy DM, Kamphuis S. Systemic lupus erythematosus in children and adolescents. Pediatr Clin North Am. 2021;59(2):345-364.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hiraki LT, Benseler SM, Tyrrell PN, Hebert D, Harvey E, Silverman ED. Clinical and laboratory characteristics and long-term outcome of pediatric systemic lupus erythematosus: a longitudinal study. J Pediatr. 2008;152(4):550-556.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wenderfer SE, Eldin KW. Lupus nephritis. Pediatr Clin North Am. 2019;66(1):87-99.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marks SD, Sebire NJ, Pilkington C, Tullus K. Clinicopathological correlations of paediatric lupus nephritis. Pediatr Nephrol. 2007;22(1):77-83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding Y, Tan Y, Qu Z, Yu F. Renal microvascular lesions in lupus nephritis. Ren Fail. 2019;42(1):19-29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen D, Koopmans M, Kremer Hovinga IC, et al. Potential for glomerular C4d as an indicator of thrombotic microangiopathy in lupus nephritis. Arthritis Rheum. 2008;58:2460-2469.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen Y, Chen XW, Sun CY, Dai M, Yan YC, Yang CD. Association between anti-beta2 glycoprotein I antibodies and renal glomerular C4d deposition in lupus nephritis patients with glomerular microthrombosis: a prospective study of 155 cases. Lupus. 2010;19(10):1195-1203.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pattanashetti N, Anakutti H, Ramachandran R, et al. Effect of thrombotic microangiopathy on clinical outcomes in indian patients with lupus nephritis. Kidney Int Rep. 2017;2(5):844-849.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iba T, Levy JH. Inflammation and thrombosis: roles of neutrophils, platelets and endothelial cells and their interactions in thrombus formation during sepsis. J Thromb Haemost. 2018;16(2):231-241.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng H, Chen Y, Ao W, et al. Antiphospholipid antibody profiles in lupus nephritis with glomerular microthrombosis a prospective study of 124 cases. Arthritis Res Ther. 2009;11(3):R93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Y, Chen P, Li Y. Association between antiphospholipid antibodies and factor bb in lupus nephritis patients with glomerular microthrombosis. Int J Rheum Dis. 2019;22(12):2185-2190.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franklyn K, Lau CS, Navarra SV, et al. Definition and initial validation of a lupus low disease activity state (LLDAS). Ann Rheum Dis. 2016;75(9):1615-1621.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gulati G, Bennett MR, Abulaban K, et al. Prospective validation of a novel renal activity index of lupus nephritis. Lupus. 2017;26(9):927-936.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Revision Committee of the Guidelines for the Prevention and Treatment of Hypertension in China. Guidelines for the prevention and treatment of hypertension in China (revised version 2018). Prevent Treat Cardio-Cereb-Vasc Dis. 2019;19(1):20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weening JJ, D'Agati VD, Schwartz MM, et al. The classification of glomerulonephritis in systemic lupus erythematosus revisited. J Am Soc Nephrol. 2004;15(2):241-250.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song K, Liu X, Liu J, et al. Analysis of clinical and laboratory characteristics and pathology of lupus nephritis-based on 710 renal biopsies in China. Clin Rheumatol. 2020;39(11):3353-3363.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen DN, Fan L, Wu YX, Zhou Q, Chen W, Yu XQ. A predictive model for estimation risk of proliferative lupus nephritis. Chin Med J (Engl). 2018;131(11):1275-1281.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bomback AS. An update on therapies for proliferative lupus nephritis: how certain can we Be about the evidence? Am J Kidney Dis. 2018;72(5):758-760.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hiromura K, Ikeuchi H, Kayakabe K, et al. Clinical and histological features of lupus nephritis in Japan: a cross-sectional analysis of the Japan renal biopsy registry (J-RBR). Nephrology (Carlton). 2017;22(11):885-891.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nossent J, Raymond W, Kang A, Wong D, Ognjenovic M, Chakera A. The current role for clinical and renal histological findings as predictor for outcome in Australian patients with lupus nephritis. Lupus. 2018;27(11):1838-1846.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atehort&#xfa;a L, Rojas M, V&#xe1;squez GM, Casta&#xf1;o D. Endothelial alterations in systemic lupus erythematosus and rheumatoid arthritis: potential effect of monocyte interaction. Mediators Inflamm. 2017;2017:9680729.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Potlukova E, Kralikova P. Complement component c1q and anti-c1q antibodies in theory and in clinical practice. Scand J Immunol. 2008;67(5):423-430.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jayakanthan K, Gupta AN, Mathew J, Ravindran R, Mahasampth G, Danda D. Clinical utility of anti-C1q antibody in primary and secondary vasculitic conditions. Int J Health Sci (Qassim). 2017;11(5):3-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stojan G, Petri M. Anti-C1q in systemic lupus erythematosus. Lupus. 2016;25(8):873-877.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bassyouni IH, Gamal S, Talaat RM, Siam I. Autoantibodies against complement C1q in patients with Behcet's disease: association with vascular involvement. Mod Rheumatol. 2014;24(2):316-320.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marto N, Bertolaccini ML, Calabuig E, Hughes GR, Khamashta MA. Anti-C1q antibodies in nephritis: correlation between titres and renal disease activity and positive predictive value in systemic lupus erythematosus. Ann Rheum Dis. 2005;64(3):444-448.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kozyro I, Perahud I, Sadallah S, et al. Clinical value of autoantibodies against C1q in children with glomerulonephritis. Pediatrics. 2006;117(5):1663-1668.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moroni G, Quaglini S, Radice A, et al. The value of a panel of autoantibodies for predicting the activity of lupus nephritis at time of renal biopsy. J Immunol Res. 2015;2015:106904.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang QY, Yu F, Tan Y, et al. Anti-C1q antibodies and IgG subclass distribution in sera from Chinese patients with lupus nephritis. Nephrol Dial Transplant. 2009;24(1):172-178.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haddon DJ, Diep VK, Price JV, Limb C, Utz PJ, Balboni I. Autoantigen microarrays reveal autoantibodies associated with proliferative nephritis and active disease in pediatric systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Res Ther. 2015;17(1):162.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emad G, Al-Barshomy SM. Anti-C1q antibodies in lupus nephritis and their correlation with the disease activity. Saudi J Kidney Dis Transpl. 2020;31(2):342-352.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yap DYH, Thong KM, Yung S, Tang C, Ma BMY, Chan TM. Antiphospholipid antibodies in patients with lupus nephritis: clinical correlations and associations with long-term outcomes. Lupus. 2019;28(12):1460-1467.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loizou S, Samarkos M, Norsworthy PJ, Cazabon JK, Walport MJ, Davies KA. Significance of anticardiolipin and anti-beta (2)-glycoprotein I antibodies in lupus nephritis. Rheumatology (Oxford). 2000;39(9):962-968.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tektonidou MG, Sotsiou F, Nakopoulou L, Vlachoyiannopoulos PG, Moutsopoulos HM. Antiphospholipid syndrome nephropathy in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus and antiphospholipid antibodies: prevalence, clinical associations, and long-term outcome. Arthritis Rheum. 2004;50(8):2569-2579.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tedesco F, Borghi MO, Gerosa M, et al. Pathogenic role of complement in antiphospholipid syndrome and therapeutic implications. Front Immunol. 2018;9:1388.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding X, Chen C, Zhang J, Lu G. Antiphospholipid antibodies in patients with proliferative and membranous lupus nephritis. Clin Rheumatol. 2020;39(5):1531-1535.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>