<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">37488248</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>21</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1476-5470</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>24</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Genes and immunity</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Genes Immun</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Transmission disequilibrium analysis of whole genome data in childhood-onset systemic lupus erythematosus.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>200</StartPage><EndPage>206</EndPage><MedlinePgn>200-206</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41435-023-00214-x</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Childhood-onset systemic lupus erythematosus (cSLE) patients are unique, with hallmarks of Mendelian disorders (early-onset and severe disease) and thus are an ideal population for genetic investigation of SLE. In this study, we use the transmission disequilibrium test (TDT), a family-based genetic association analysis that employs robust methodology, to analyze whole genome sequencing data. We aim to identify novel genetic associations in an ancestrally diverse, international cSLE cohort. Forty-two cSLE patients and 84 unaffected parents from 3 countries underwent whole genome sequencing. First, we performed TDT with single nucleotide variant (SNV)-based (common variants) using PLINK 1.9, and gene-based (rare variants) analyses using Efficient and Parallelizable Association Container Toolbox (EPACTS) and rare variant TDT (rvTDT), which applies multiple gene-based burden tests adapted for TDT, including the burden of rare variants test. Applying the GWAS standard threshold (5.0&#x2009;&#xd7;&#x2009;10<sup>-8</sup>) to common variants, our SNV-based analysis did not return any genome-wide significant SNVs. The rare variant gene-based TDT analysis identified many novel genes significantly enriched in cSLE patients, including HNRNPUL2, a DNA repair protein, and DNAH11, a ciliary movement protein, among others. Our approach identifies several novel SLE susceptibility genes in an ancestrally diverse childhood-onset lupus cohort.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023. This is a U.S. Government work and not under copyright protection in the US; foreign copyright protection may apply.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vazzana</LastName><ForeName>Kathleen M</ForeName><Initials>KM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Lupus Genomics and Global Health Disparities Unit, Systemic Autoimmunity Branch, National Institute of Arthritis and Musculoskeletal and Skin Diseases, National Institutes of Health, Bethesda, MD, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Arnold Palmer Hospital for Children, Orlando, FL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Musolf</LastName><ForeName>Anthony M</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Computational and Statistical Genomics Branch, National Human Genome Research Institute, National Institutes of Health, Baltimore, MD, 22124, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bailey-Wilson</LastName><ForeName>Joan E</ForeName><Initials>JE</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9153-2920</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Computational and Statistical Genomics Branch, National Human Genome Research Institute, National Institutes of Health, Baltimore, MD, 22124, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hiraki</LastName><ForeName>Linda T</ForeName><Initials>LT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Rheumatology, Department of Pediatrics, The Hospital for Sick Children, University of Toronto, Toronto, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Silverman</LastName><ForeName>Earl D</ForeName><Initials>ED</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Rheumatology, Department of Pediatrics, The Hospital for Sick Children, University of Toronto, Toronto, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Scott</LastName><ForeName>Christiaan</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3874-1704</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Paediatric Rheumatology, Red Cross War Memorial Children's Hospital and University of Cape Town, Cape Town, South Africa.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dalgard</LastName><ForeName>Clifton L</ForeName><Initials>CL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The American Genome Center, Department of Anatomy, Physiology &amp; Genetics, Uniformed Services University, Bethesda, MD, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hasni</LastName><ForeName>Sarfaraz</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4164-8837</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Program, Systemic Autoimmunity Branch, National Institute of Arthritis and Musculoskeletal and Skin Diseases, National Institutes of Health, Bethesda, MD, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Deng</LastName><ForeName>Zuoming</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biodata Mining and Discovery Section, Office of Science and Technology, National Institute of Arthritis and Musculoskeletal and Skin Diseases, National Institutes of Health, Bethesda, MD, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kaplan</LastName><ForeName>Mariana J</ForeName><Initials>MJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Systemic Autoimmunity Branch, National Institute of Arthritis and Musculoskeletal and Skin Diseases, National Institutes of Health, Bethesda, MD, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lewandowski</LastName><ForeName>Laura B</ForeName><Initials>LB</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4253-2545</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Lupus Genomics and Global Health Disparities Unit, Systemic Autoimmunity Branch, National Institute of Arthritis and Musculoskeletal and Skin Diseases, National Institutes of Health, Bethesda, MD, USA. laura.lewandowski@nih.gov.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>Z99 AR999999</GrantID><Acronym>ImNIH</Acronym><Agency>Intramural NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>ZIA AR041214</GrantID><Acronym>ImNIH</Acronym><Agency>Intramural NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Genes Immun</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100953417</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1466-4879</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015810" MajorTopicYN="Y">Linkage Disequilibrium</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055106" MajorTopicYN="N">Genome-Wide Association Study</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015894" MajorTopicYN="N">Genome, Human</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017668" MajorTopicYN="N">Age of Onset</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014644" MajorTopicYN="N">Genetic Variation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors have no conflicts of interest to declare. KV, LBL, SH, ZD, CD, and MK were funded by the National Institute of Arthritis Musculoskeletal and Skin Diseases Intramural research program. AMM and JEBW were funded by the National Human Genome Research Institute Intramural research program of the National Institutes of Health. LH was funded by US Department of Defense Idea Award and a Canada Research Chair Tier 2 Award.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37488248</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS1923826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10529982</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41435-023-00214-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41435-023-00214-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>AlE&#x2019;ed A, Vega-Fernandez P, Muscal E, Hinze CH, Tucker LB, Appenzeller S, et al. Challenges of diagnosing cognitive dysfunction with neuropsychiatric systemic lupus erythematosus in childhood. Arthritis Care Res. 2017;69:1449&#x2013;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5476521</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27992660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ardoin SP, Schanberg LE. Lessons from SLE: children are not little adults. Nat Rev Rheumatol. 2012;8:444&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22782004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vazzana KM, Daga A, Goilav B, Ogbu EA, Okamura DM, Park C, et al. Principles of pediatric lupus nephritis in a prospective contemporary multi-center cohort. Lupus. 2021;30:1660&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10461610</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34219529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewandowski LB, Schanberg LE Chapter 22 - Systemic lupus erythematosus in children. In: Lahita RG, Costenbader KH, Bucala R, Manzi S, Khamashta MA, editors. Lahita&#x2019;s Systemic Lupus Erythematosus (Sixth Edition). San Diego: Academic Press; 2021. p. 365&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brunner HI, Gladman DD, Iba&#xf1;ez D, Urowitz MD, Silverman ED. Difference in disease features between childhood-onset and adult-onset systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Rheum. 2008;58:556&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18240232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Livingston B, Bonner A, Pope J. Differences in clinical manifestations between childhood-onset lupus and adult-onset lupus: a meta-analysis. Lupus. 2011;20:1345&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21951943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hiraki LT, Silverman ED. Genomics of systemic lupus erythematosus: insights gained by studying monogenic young-onset systemic lupus erythematosus. Rheum Dis Clin North Am. 2017;43:415&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28711143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hiraki LT, Feldman CH, Liu J, Alarcon GS, Fischer MA, Winkelmayer WC, et al. Prevalence, incidence, and demographics of systemic lupus erythematosus and lupus nephritis from 2000 to 2004 among children in the US Medicaid beneficiary population. Arthritis Rheum. 2012;64:2669&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3564552</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22847366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lo MS. Monogenic lupus. Curr Rheumatol Rep. 2016;18:71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27812953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deafen D, Escalante A, Weinrib L, Horwitz D, Bachman B, Roy&#x2010;Burman P, et al. A revised estimate of twin concordance in systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Rheum. 1992;35:311&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1536669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sestak AL, Shaver TS, Moser KL, Neas BR, Harley JB. Familial aggregation of lupus and autoimmunity in an unusual multiplex pedigree. J Rheumatol. 1999;26:1495&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10405936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Webber D, Cao J, Dominguez D, Gladman DD, Levy DM, Ng L, et al. Association of systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) genetic susceptibility loci with lupus nephritis in childhood-onset and adult-onset SLE. Rheumatol (Oxf). 2020;59:90&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31236574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong M, Tsao BP. Current topics in human SLE genetics. Springe Semin Immunopathol. 2006;28:97&#x2013;107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16941108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bentham J, Morris DL, Cunninghame Graham DS, Pinder CL, Tombleson P, Behrens TW, et al. Genetic association analyses implicate aberrant regulation of innate and adaptive immunity genes in the pathogenesis of systemic lupus erythematosus. Nat Genet. 2015;47:1457&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4668589</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26502338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dominguez D, Kamphuis S, Beyene J, Wither J, Harley JB, Blanco I, et al. Relationship between genetic risk and age of diagnosis in systemic lupus erythematosus. J Rheumatol. 2021;48:852&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33060314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Omarjee O, Picard C, Frachette C, Moreews M, Rieux-Laucat F, Soulas-Sprauel P, et al. Monogenic lupus: dissecting heterogeneity. Autoimmun Rev. 2019;18:102361.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31401343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Misztal MC, Liao F, Couse M, Cao J, Dominguez D, Lau L, et al. Genome-Wide Sequencing Identified Rare Genetic Variants for Childhood-Onset Monogenic Lupus. J Rheumatol. 2023;50:671&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36379578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bryan AR, Wu EY. Complement deficiencies in systemic lupus erythematosus. Curr Allergy Asthma Rep. 2014;14:448.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24816552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee-Kirsch MA, Chowdhury D, Harvey S, Gong M, Senenko L, Engel K, et al. A mutation in TREX1 that impairs susceptibility to granzyme A-mediated cell death underlies familial chilblain lupus. J Mol Med (Berl, Ger). 2007;85:531&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17440703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Mayouf SM, Sunker A, Abdwani R, Abrawi SA, Almurshedi F, Alhashmi N, et al. Loss-of-function variant in DNASE1L3 causes a familial form of systemic lupus erythematosus. Nat Genet. 2011;43:1186&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22019780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown GJ, Ca&#xf1;ete PF, Wang H, Medhavy A, Bones J, Roco JA, et al. TLR7 gain-of-function genetic variation causes human lupus. Nature. 2022;605:349&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9095492</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35477763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batu ED, Kosukcu C, Taskiran E, Sahin S, Akman S, S&#xf6;zeri B, et al. Whole exome sequencing in early-onset systemic lupus erythematosus. J Rheumatol. 2018;45:1671&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30008451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tirosh I, Spielman S, Barel O, Ram R, Stauber T, Paret G, et al. Whole exome sequencing in childhood-onset lupus frequently detects single gene etiologies. Pediatr Rheumatol. 2019;17:52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6668194</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31362757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ewens WJ, Spielman RS. The transmission/disequilibrium test: history, subdivision, and admixture. Am J Hum Genet. 1995;57:455.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1801556</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7668272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogers AJ, Weiss ST. Epidemiologic and population genetic studies. Clinical and Translational Science: Elsevier; 2017. p. 313&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbosa FB, Cagnin NF, Simioni M, Farias AA, Torres FR, Molck MC, et al. Ancestry informative marker panel to estimate population stratification using genome-wide human array. Ann Hum Genet. 2017;81:225&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28895130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shriner D, Adeyemo A, Ramos E, Chen G, Rotimi CN. Mapping of disease-associated variants in admixed populations. Genome Biol. 2011;12:223.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3219963</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21635713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laird NM, Lange C. Family-based designs in the age of large-scale gene-association studies. Nat Rev Genet. 2006;7:385&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16619052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sillanp&#xe4;&#xe4; MJ. Overview of techniques to account for confounding due to population stratification and cryptic relatedness in genomic data association analyses. Heredity (Edinb). 2011;106:511&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3183892</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20628415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J, Lewinger JP, Gilliland FD, Gauderman WJ, Conti DV. Confounding and heterogeneity in genetic association studies with admixed populations. Am J Epidemiol. 2013;177:351&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3626055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23334005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsuchiya N, Kawasaki A, Tsao B, Komata T, Grossman J, Tokunaga K. Analysis of the association of HLA-DRB1, TNF&#x3b1; promoter and TNFR2 (TNFRSF1B) polymorphisms with SLE using transmission disequilibrium test. Genes Immun. 2001;2:317&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11607787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacob CO, Reiff A, Armstrong DL, Myones BL, Silverman E, Klein-Gitelman M, et al. Identification of novel susceptibility genes in childhood-onset systemic lupus erythematosus using a uniquely designed candidate gene pathway platform. Arthritis Rheum. 2007;56:4164&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18050247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hernandez RD, Uricchio LH, Hartman K, Ye C, Dahl A, Zaitlen N. Ultrarare variants drive substantial cis heritability of human gene expression. Nat Genet. 2019;51:1349&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6730564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31477931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hochberg MC. Updating the American College of Rheumatology revised criteria for the classification of systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Rheum. 1997;40:1725.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9324032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gladman DD, Ibanez D, Urowitz MB. Systemic lupus erythematosus disease activity index 2000. J Rheumatol. 2002;29:288&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11838846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altschul SF, Gish W, Miller W, Myers EW, Lipman DJ. Basic local alignment search tool. J Mol Biol. 1990;215:403&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2231712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKenna A, Hanna M, Banks E, Sivachenko A, Cibulskis K, Kernytsky A, et al. The Genome Analysis Toolkit: a MapReduce framework for analyzing next-generation DNA sequencing data. Genome Res. 2010;20:1297&#x2013;303.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2928508</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20644199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Purcell S, Neale B, Todd-Brown K, Thomas L, Ferreira MAR, Bender D, et al. PLINK: a tool set for whole-genome association and population-based linkage analyses. Am J Hum Genet. 2007;81:559&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1950838</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17701901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Team RC. R: A language and environment for statistical computing. R Foundation for Statistical Computing. Vienna, Austria: R Foundation for Statistical Computing; 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gogarten SM, Sofer T, Chen H, Yu C, Brody JA, Thornton TA, et al. Genetic association testing using the GENESIS R/Bioconductor package. Bioinforma (Oxf, Engl). 2019;35:5346&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7904076</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31329242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altshuler DM, Gibbs RA, Peltonen L, Altshuler DM, Gibbs RA, Peltonen L, et al. Integrating common and rare genetic variation in diverse human populations. Nature. 2010;467:52&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3173859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20811451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alexander DH, Novembre J, Lange K. Fast model-based estimation of ancestry in unrelated individuals. Genome Res. 2009;19:1655&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2752134</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19648217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He Z, O&#x2019;Roak BJ, Smith JD, Wang G, Hooker S, Santos-Cortez RL, et al. Rare-variant extensions of the transmission disequilibrium test: application to autism exome sequence data. Am J Hum Genet. 2014;94:33&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3882934</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24360806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Risch N, Merikangas K. The future of genetic studies of complex human diseases. Sci (N. Y, NY) 1996;273:1516&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8801636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pe&#x2019;er I, Yelensky R, Altshuler D, Daly MJ. Estimation of the multiple testing burden for genomewide association studies of nearly all common variants. Genet Epidemiol. 2008;32:381&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18348202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang HM
EPACTS (efficient and parallelizable association container toolbox). 2012. https://genome.sph.umich.edu/wiki/EPACTS.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Auer PL, Wang G, Leal SM. Testing for rare variant associations in the presence of missing data. Genet Epidemiol. 2013;37:529&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4459641</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23757187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li B, Leal SM. Methods for detecting associations with rare variants for common diseases: application to analysis of sequence data. Am J Hum Genet. 2008;83:311&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2842185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18691683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Price AL, Kryukov GV, de Bakker PI, Purcell SM, Staples J, Wei L-J, et al. Pooled association tests for rare variants in exon-resequencing studies. Am J Hum Genet. 2010;86:832&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3032073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20471002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee S, Abecasis GR, Boehnke M, Lin X. Rare-variant association analysis: study designs and statistical tests. Am J Hum Genet. 2014;95:5&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4085641</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24995866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu HH, Lee JH, Wang LC, Yang YH, Chiang BL. Neuropsychiatric manifestations in pediatric systemic lupus erythematosus: a 20-year study. Lupus. 2006;15:651&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17120591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gkirtzimanaki K, Kabrani E, Nikoleri D, Polyzos A, Blanas A, Sidiropoulos P, et al. IFN&#x3b1; impairs autophagic degradation of mtDNA promoting autoreactivity of SLE monocytes in a STING-dependent fashion. Cell Rep. 2018;25:921&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6218203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30355498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alarc&#xf3;n&#x2010;Segovia D, Alarc&#xf3;n&#x2010;Riquelme ME, Cardiel MH, Caeiro F, Massardo L, Villa AR, et al. Familial aggregation of systemic lupus erythematosus, rheumatoid arthritis, and other autoimmune diseases in 1177 lupus patients from the GLADEL cohort. Arthritis Rheumatol. 2005;52:1138&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15818688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Budarf ML, Goyette P, Boucher G, Lian J, Graham RR, Claudio JO, et al. A targeted association study in systemic lupus erythematosus identifies multiple susceptibility alleles. Genes Immun. 2011;12:51&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20962850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bronson PG, Komorowski LK, Ramsay PP, May SL, Noble J, Lane JA, et al. Analysis of maternal&#x2013;offspring HLA compatibility, parent&#x2010;of&#x2010;origin effects, and non-inherited maternal antigen effects for HLA&#x2013;DRB1 in systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Rheum. 2010;62:1712&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2948464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20191587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moser KL, Kelly JA, Lessard CJ, Harley JB. Recent insights into the genetic basis of systemic lupus erythematosus. Genes Immun. 2009;10:373&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3144759</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19440199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peschken CA. Health disparities in systemic lupus erythematosus. Rheum Dis Clin. 2020;46:673&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32981644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pullmann R Jr, Bonilla E, Phillips PE, Middleton FA, Perl A. Haplotypes of the HRES-1 endogenous retrovirus are associated with development and disease manifestations of systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Rheum. 2008;58:532&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18240231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu JL, Zhang FY, Liang YH, Xiao FL, Zhang SQ, Cheng YL, et al. Association between the PD1. 3A/G polymorphism of the PDCD1 gene and systemic lupus erythematosus in European populations: a meta&#x2010;analysis. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol. 2009;23:425&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19220647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polo Sophie E, Blackford Andrew N, Chapman JR, Baskcomb L, Gravel S, Rusch A, et al. Regulation of DNA-end resection by hnRNPU-like proteins promotes DNA double-strand break signaling and repair. Mol Cell. 2012;45:505&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3550743</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22365830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang H, Wang Y, Ai M, Wang H, Duan Z, Wang H, et al. Long noncoding RNA CRNDE stabilized by hnRNPUL2 accelerates cell proliferation and migration in colorectal carcinoma via activating Ras/MAPK signaling pathways. Cell Death Dis. 2017;8:e2862.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5520914</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28594403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calender A, Rollat Farnier PA, Buisson A, Pinson S, Bentaher A, Lebecque S, et al. Whole exome sequencing in three families segregating a pediatric case of sarcoidosis. BMC Med Genom. 2018;11:23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5839022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29510755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knowles MR, Leigh MW, Carson JL, Davis SD, Dell SD, Ferkol TW, et al. Mutations of DNAH11 in patients with primary ciliary dyskinesia with normal ciliary ultra-structure. Thorax. 2012;67:433&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3739700</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22184204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schultz R, Elenius V, Lukkarinen H, Saarela T. Two novel mutations in the DNAH11 gene in primary ciliary dyskinesia (CILD7) with considerable variety in the clinical and beating cilia phenotype. BMC Med Genet. 2020;21:1&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7690114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33243178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiong Y, Xia H, Yuan L, Deng S, Ding Z, Deng H. Identification of compound heterozygous DNAH11 variants in a Han-Chinese family with primary ciliary dyskinesia. J Cell Mol Med. 2021;25:9028&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8435457</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34405951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsyklauri O, Niederlova V, Forsythe E, Prasai A, Drobek A, Kasparek P, et al. Bardet&#x2013;Biedl syndrome ciliopathy is linked to altered hematopoiesis and dysregulated self-tolerance. EMBO Rep. 2021;22:e50785.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7857422</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33426789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cassioli C, Baldari CT. A ciliary view of the immunological synapse. Cells. 2019;8:789.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6721628</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31362462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alagramam KN, Miller ND, Adappa ND, Pitts DR, Heaphy JC, Yuan H, et al. Promoter, alternative splice forms, and genomic structure of protocadherin 15. Genomics. 2007;90:482&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2043478</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17706913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Albertin CB, Simakov O, Mitros T, Wang ZY, Pungor JR, Edsinger-Gonzales E, et al. The octopus genome and the evolution of cephalopod neural and morphological novelties. Nature. 2015;524:220&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4795812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26268193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X, Su H, Bradley A. Molecular mechanisms governing Pcdh-gamma gene expression: evidence for a multiple promoter and cis-alternative splicing model. Genes Dev. 2002;16:1890&#x2013;905.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC186422</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12154121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haas CS, Creighton CJ, Pi X, Maine I, Koch AE, Haines GK, et al. Identification of genes modulated in rheumatoid arthritis using complementary DNA microarray analysis of lymphoblastoid B cell lines from disease-discordant monozygotic twins. Arthritis Rheum. 2006;54:2047&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16804865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng Y, Zhao K, Oros Klein K, Shao X, Fritzler MJ, Hudson M, et al. Thousands of CpGs show DNA methylation differences in ACPA-positive individuals. Genes. 2021;12:1349.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8472734</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34573331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murthy SE, Dubin AE, Whitwam T, Jojoa-Cruz S, Cahalan SM, Mousavi SAR, et al. OSCA/TMEM63 are an evolutionarily conserved family of mechanically activated ion channels. Elife. 2018;7:e41844.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6235560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30382938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan H, Helman G, Murthy SE, Ji H, Crawford J, Kubisiak T, et al. Heterozygous variants in the mechanosensitive ion channel TMEM63A result in transient hypomyelination during infancy. Am J Hum Genet. 2019;105:996&#x2013;1004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6848986</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31587869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaiser FM, Gruenbacher S, Oyaga MR, Nio E, Jaritz M, Sun Q, et al. Biallelic PAX5 mutations cause hypogammaglobulinemia, sensorimotor deficits, and autism spectrum disorder. J Exp Med. 2022;219:e20220498.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9372349</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35947077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morris DL, Taylor KE, Fernando MM, Nititham J, Alarc&#xf3;n-Riquelme ME, Barcellos LF, et al. Unraveling multiple MHC gene associations with systemic lupus erythematosus: model choice indicates a role for HLA alleles and non-HLA genes in Europeans. Am J Hum Genet. 2012;91:778&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3487133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23084292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sirikong M, Tsuchiya N, Chandanayingyong D, Bejrachandra S, Suthipinittharm P, Luangtrakool K, et al. Association of HLA-DRB1*1502-DQB1*0501 haplotype with susceptibility to systemic lupus erythematosus in Thais. Tissue Antigens. 2002;59:113&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12028537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langefeld CD, Ainsworth HC, Cunninghame Graham DS, Kelly JA, Comeau ME, Marion MC, et al. Transancestral mapping and genetic load in systemic lupus erythematosus. Nat Commun. 2017;8:16021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5520018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28714469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang SH, Athanasopoulos V, Ellyard JI, Chuah A, Cappello J, Cook A, et al. Functional rare and low frequency variants in BLK and BANK1 contribute to human lupus. Nat Commun. 2019;10:2201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6525203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31101814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niewold TB. Advances in lupus genetics. Curr Opin Rheumatol. 2015;27:440&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4540605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26218512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warrier V, Toro R, Chakrabarti B, B&#xf8;rglum AD, Grove J, Hinds DA, et al. Genome-wide analyses of self-reported empathy: correlations with autism, schizophrenia, and anorexia nervosa. Transl Psychiatry. 2018;8:35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5845860</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29527006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howe AS, Buttensch&#xf8;n HN, Bani-Fatemi A, Maron E, Otowa T, Erhardt A, et al. Candidate genes in panic disorder: meta-analyses of 23 common variants in major anxiogenic pathways. Mol Psychiatry. 2016;21:665&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26390831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>