<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37496262</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1756-185X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of rheumatic diseases</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Rheum Dis</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Meta-analysis of effectiveness and safety of glucocorticoid combined with hydroxychloroquine in the treatment of systemic lupus erythematosus rash.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1686</StartPage><EndPage>1696</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1686-1696</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/1756-185X.14791</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Many studies have found that glucocorticoid (GC) combined with hydroxychloroquine (HCQ) has a good clinical effect in the treatment of systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) rash, but there is no relevant systematic evaluation at present. The purpose of this study was to systematically evaluate and analyze the effectiveness and safety of GC combined with HCQ in the treatment of SLE rash.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Randomized controlled trials of GC combined with HCQ in the treatment of SLE rash were collected through computer retrieval of Cochrane Library, PubMed, Embase, CNKI, China Science and Technology Journal Database (VIP), Wanfang Data Knowledge Service Platform (Wanfang), and China Biology Medicine disc (CBM) since the establishment of the database. The main outcome indicators included clinical total effective rate, adverse reactions, SLE disease activity index (SLEDAI) score, erythrocyte sedimentation rate (ESR), C-reactive protein (CRP), and complement 3 (C3). A meta-analysis was conducted using Review Manager 5.3 software.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 11 studies involving 809 patients (406 in the test group and 403 in the control group) were included in this article. The meta-analysis results showed that compared with the single use of GC, GC combined with HCQ could improve the clinical total effective rate in the treatment of SLE rash (odds ratio [OR]&#x2009;=&#x2009;4.27, 95% confidence interval [CI] 2.50-7.30, p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;.00001), and reduce the occurrence of adverse reactions (OR&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.26, 95% CI 0.15-0.44, p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;.00001); effectively reduce SLEDAI score (mean difference [MD]&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.88, 95% CI 1.66-2.10, p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;.00001) and ESR level (MD&#x2009;=&#x2009;7.92, 95% CI 5.66-10.19, p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;.00001); increase C3 level after treatment (MD&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.36, 95% CI 0.32-0.41, p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;.00001); and reduce CRP level (MD&#x2009;=&#x2009;3.22, 95% CI 2.87-3.58, p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;.00001), with statistically significant differences.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Compared with the use of GC alone, GC combined with HCQ can improve the clinical effectiveness of SLE rash treatment, with a low incidence of adverse reactions and good clinical safety. However, the number and quality of studies included in this article were not high, so the findings need to be further verified by high-quality, multicenter randomized controlled trials.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 Asia Pacific League of Associations for Rheumatology and John Wiley &amp; Sons Australia, Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liang</LastName><ForeName>Siping</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4548-6932</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Guangzhou University of Chinese Medicine, Guangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wei</LastName><ForeName>Zhiming</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Guangzhou University of Chinese Medicine, Guangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fang</LastName><ForeName>Hanjun</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The First Affiliated Hospital of Guangzhou University of Chinese Medicine, Guangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guan</LastName><ForeName>Tong</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The First Affiliated Hospital of Guangzhou University of Chinese Medicine, Guangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Rheum Dis</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101474930</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1756-1841</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>4QWG6N8QKH</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D006886">Hydroxychloroquine</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D005938">Glucocorticoids</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006886" MajorTopicYN="N">Hydroxychloroquine</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005938" MajorTopicYN="N">Glucocorticoids</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000139" MajorTopicYN="N">chemically induced</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005076" MajorTopicYN="Y">Exanthema</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000139" MajorTopicYN="N">chemically induced</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015337" MajorTopicYN="N">Multicenter Studies as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">glucocorticoid</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hydroxychloroquine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">meta-analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rash</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">systemic lupus erythematosus</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37496262</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1756-185X.14791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Chinese Rheumatology Association. National Clinical Research Center for dermatologic and immunologic diseases, Chinese systemic lupus erythematosus treatment and research group. Zhonghua Nei Ke Za Zhi. 2020;59(3):172-185.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ugarte-Gil MF, Gonz&#xe1;lez LA, Alarc&#xf3;n GS. Lupus: the new epidemic. Lupus. 2019;28(9):1031-1050.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Reshaid K, Al-Bader S, Sallam H-T. A self-limited facial rash in a lupus patient: the case of primary facial Raynaud's phenomenon. Case Rep Dermatol. 2021;13(2):366-371.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li M, Zhang W, Leng X, et al. Chinese SLE treatment and research group (CSTAR) registry: I. Major clinical characteristics of Chinese patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. Lupus. 2013;22(11):1192-1199.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu Q, Long H, Chow S, et al. Guideline for the diagnosis, treatment and long-term management of cutaneous lupus erythematosus. J Autoimmun. 2021;123:102707.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun J. Meta-analysis of the effectiveness and safety of glucocorticoid for the treatment of IgA kidney disease. J Healthc Eng. 2022;2022:5466331.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akhavan PS, Su J, Lou W, Gladman DD, Urowitz MB, Fortin PR. The early protective effect of hydroxychloroquine on the risk of cumulative damage in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. J Rheumatol. 2013;40:831-841.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, et al. Updated guidance for trusted systematic reviews: a new edition of the Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of interventions. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2019;(10):ED000142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu LJ. Observation on the efficacy of glucocorticoid combined with hydroxychloroquine in the treatment of systemic lupus erythematosus rash. Jilin Med J. 2010;31(4):495-496.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pu YT. Hydroxychloroquine with rash glucocorticoid in the treatment of systemic lupus erythematosus: analysis of 26 cases. World Latest Med Inform. 2013;21:192-205.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X. Efficacy of glucocorticoid combined with hydroxychloroquine in the treatment of systemic lupus erythematosus rash. Diet Health. 2017;4(22):69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li SY, Deng DH. Study on the clinical value of glucocorticoid combined with hydroxychloroquine in the treatment of systemic lupus erythematosus rash. J Panzhihua Univ. 2018;35(5):38-40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xing MM. Study on the effect of glucocorticoid combined with hydroxychloroquine sulfate in the treatment of systemic lupus erythematosus rash. Contemp Med Symp. 2018;16(19):164-165.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hao LX, Zhao LP, Mao GG. Clinical effect of hydroxychloroquine combined with low-dose hormone in the treatment of facial lupus erythematosus. World's Latest Med Inform Abs. 2020;20(14):120-121.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu L, Shu C, Fan ZG. Effect of glucocorticoid combined with hydroxychloroquine on the rehabilitation of systemic lupus erythematosus rash. Reflex Ther Rehabil Med. 2020;29(4):101-102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ying Y. Analysis of the effect of glucocorticoid combined with hydroxychloroquine in the treatment of systemic lupus erythematosus rash. Diet Health. 2021;29:86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin R, Miao HN, Ling W. Analysis of the effect of glucocorticoid combined with hydroxychloroquine in the treatment of systemic lupus erythematosus rash. Reflexol Rehabil Med. 2022;3(1):126-128, 142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu S. Clinical effect of glucocorticoid combined with hydroxychloroquine in the treatment of systemic lupus erythematosus rash. China Modern Med. 2022;29(1):36-38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yue M. Observation on the efficacy of glucocorticoids combined with hydroxychloroquine in the treatment of systemic lupus erythematosus. Dermatol Sex Transm Dis. 2018;40(6):834-835.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basta F, Fasola F, Triantafyllias K, Schwarting A. Systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) therapy: the old and the new. Rheumatol Ther. 2020;7(3):433-446.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaul A, Gordon C, Crow MK, et al. Systemic lupus erythematosus. Nat Rev Dis Primers. 2016;2:16039.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bodis G, Toth V, Schwarting A. Role of human leukocyte antigens (HLA) in autoimmune diseases. Rheumatol Ther. 2018;5:5-20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsokos GC, Lo MS, Costa Reis P, Sullivan KE. New insights into the immunopathogenesis of systemic lupus erythematosus. Nat Rev Rheumatol. 2016;12:716-730.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herzum A, Gasparini G, Cozzani E, Burlando M, Parodi A. Atypical and rare forms of cutaneous lupus erythematosus: the importance of the diagnosis for the best management of patients. Dermatology. 2022;238(2):195-204.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Obermoser G, Zelger B, Zelger B. Lupus erythematodes - ein klinisch-pathologisch heterogenes Krankheitsbild [lupus erythematosus-a clinico-pathological heterogeneous disease]. Pathologe. 2020;41(4):334-343.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fanouriakis A, Kostopoulou M, Alunno A, et al. 2019 update of the EULAR recommendations for the management of systemic lupus erythematosus. Ann Rheum Dis. 2019;78:736-745.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dima A, Jurcut C, Chasset F, Felten R, Arnaud L. Hydroxychloroquine in systemic lupus erythematosus: overview of current knowledge. Ther Adv Musculoskelet Dis. 2022;14:1759720X211073001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pakchotanon R, Gladman DD, Su J, Urowitz MB. More consistent antimalarial intake in first 5&#x2009;years of disease is associated with better prognosis in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. J Rheumatol. 2018;45:90-94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim JW, Lee JH, Kim HJ. Use of hydroxychloroquine in dermatology: a multicenter retrospective study in Korea. J Dermatol. 2022;49(1):173-178.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alarc&#xf3;n GS, McGwin G, Bertoli AM, et al. Effect of hydroxychloroquine on the survival of patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: data from LUMINA, a multiethnic US cohort (LUMINA L). Ann Rheum Dis. 2007;66:1168-1172.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>