<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37543816</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>07</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-5964</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>102</Volume><Issue>31</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>04</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Medicine (Baltimore)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Intestinal perforation with systemic lupus erythematosus: A systematic review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e34415</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e34415</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e34415</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MD.0000000000034415</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Intestinal perforation (IP) is a rare complication of systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE), and the timely diagnosis and treatment of IP are necessary to prevent death. In this study, the clinical features of IP in SLE were described in an attempt to enhance its understanding to reduce mortality. The clinical data of IP in SLE from 1984 to 2022 were retrospectively collected. A total of 18 patients were enrolled, and data on clinical symptoms, preoperative evaluation, surgical procedures, and postoperative outcomes were collected and retrospectively analyzed. The analysis included 15 females and 3 males, with a mean age of 49.2 years. Fifteen patients (83.3%) had a history of the disease for &gt;5 years, and the SLE disease activity index score of 1 (5.6%) patient was &lt;5 points and that of 17 (94.4%) patients was &gt;10 points. A total of 9 (50%), 5 (27.7%), 3 (16.7%), and 1 (5.6%) patient had lesions in the rectum, colon, ileum, and both ileum and appendix, respectively. The cause of perforation in 12 (66.7%) patients was lupus mesenteric vasculitis and in 3 (16.7%) patients was chronic inflammation. Seven (38.9%) patients had other immune system diseases. All patients were treated with steroids and surgical treatment. However, 5 patients died after surgery. A disease duration of &gt;5 years, SLE disease activity index score of &gt;10, nonstandard use of steroids, and concomitant presence of other immune system diseases are the possible risk factors of IP in SLE. The most common site of perforation was the rectum, which was caused by lupus mesenteric vasculitis. The results suggest that the key to successfully manage such cases is early diagnosis, aggressive resuscitation, antibiotics, steroid therapy, and prompt surgical intervention.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 the Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Ya Lan</ForeName><Initials>YL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology, The Affiliated Hospital of Hebei University, Baoding, P.R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Meng</LastName><ForeName>Jie</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology, The Affiliated Hospital of Hebei University, Baoding, P.R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Cong</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Hepatobiliary Surgery, The Affiliated Hospital of Hebei University, Baoding, P.R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Medicine (Baltimore)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>2985248R</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0025-7974</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007416" MajorTopicYN="Y">Intestinal Perforation</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000601" MajorTopicYN="N">surgery</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012307" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014657" MajorTopicYN="Y">Vasculitis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors have no funding and conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37543816</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10402941</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000034415</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005792-202308040-00059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Chng HH, Tan BE, Teh CL. Major gastrointestinal manifestations in lupus patients in Asia: lupus enteritis, intestinal pseudo-obstruction, and protein-losing gastroenteropathy. Lupus. 2010;12:1404&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20947549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu CG, Hu Z, Jin XD. Clinical analysis of systemic lupus erythematosus with intestinal perforation. West China Med. 2014;29:1116&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie XY, Zhang YD. A case of maintenance hemodialysis with rectal perforation in SLE patients. Prac J Med Pharm. 2020;37:37&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gong SH. Rare manifestations of systemic lupus erythematosus: a report of 7 cases and literature review. Fuzhou Fujian Med Univ. 2016;5:13&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mei TH. Misdiagnosis of intestinal perforation in systemic lupus erythematosus: a case report. Chongqing Med. 1986;15:60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao YH, Jiang YH, Liao LQ, et al. . Systemic lupus erythematosus with rectal perforation: a case report. Chin J Bases Clin Genera Surg. 2011;18:693.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang YH, Chen S, Gu YY. Report of 5 cases of systemic lupus erythematosus with Mesenteri cvasculitis. Chin J Dig. 2002;22:56&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bourikas LA, Tzardi M, Hatzidakis A, et al. . Small bowel perforation due to non-Hodgkin-lymphoma in a patient with ulcerative colitis and systemic lupus erythematosus. Dig Liver Dis. 2008;40:144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17950679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shrestha BM, Shrestha S, Kharel S, et al. . Ilealperforation as an initial manifestation of systemic lupus erythematosus: a case report. Int J Surg Case Rep. 2021;87:106409.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8461371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34555679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mansoor AC, Jemshad A, Musambil M. Systemic lupus erythematosus presenting as rectal ulcer and longitudinal myelopathy. Int J Rheum Dis. 2017;20:1818&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26218011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang Y, Di Re A, El Khoury T. A rare case of lupus-related gastrointestinal vasculitis presenting as rectal gangrene. J Surg Case Rep. 2019;4:1&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6486653</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31044066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohara M, Takahashi H, Suzuki C, et al. . A case of lupus erythematosus profundus followed by systemic lupus erythematosus presenting with severe intestinal involvement. Nihon Rinsho Meneki Gakkai Kaishi. 2007;30:48&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17332705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teramoto J, Takahashi Y, Katsuki S, et al. . Systemic lupus erythematosus with a giant rectal ulcer and perforation. Intern Med. 1999;38:643&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10440500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu Y, Zhu T, Wang Y, et al. . Systemic lupus erythematosus with intestinal perforation: a case report. Exp Ther Med. 2015;10:1234&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4533166</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26622471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Latif E, Musthafa S, Ahmed A, et al. . Stercoral perforation of sigmoid colon in systemic lupus erythematosus: a rare cause of peritonitis. Cureus. 2020;12:e9495.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7458703</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32879819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strasser C, Wolf EM, Kornprat P, et al. . Opportunistic cytomegalovirus infection causing colonic perforation in a patient with systemic lupus erythematosus. Lupus. 2012;21:449&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22020267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Rheumatology AdHoc Committee on Systemic Lupus Erythematosus Guidelines. Guidelines for referral and management of systemic lupus erythematosus in adults. Arthritis Rheum. 1999;42:1785&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10513791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu AM. International Classification of Diseases Ninth Edition Clinical Revision Surgery and Operation. Shanxi Science and Technology Press; 2011:42&#x2013;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bombardier C, Gladman DD, Urowitz MB, et al. . Derivation of the SLEDAI: a disease activity index for lupus patients. Arthritis Rheum. 1992;35:630&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1599520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen L, He Q, Luo M, et al. . Clinical features of lupus enteritis: a single-center retrospective study. Orphanet J Rare Dis. 2021;16:396&#x2013;404.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8474739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34565417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Medina F, Ayala A, Jara LJ, et al. . Acute abdomen in systemic lupus erythematosus: the importance of early laparotomy. Am J Med. 1997;103:100&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9274892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mok CC. Investigations and management of gastrointestinal and hepatic manifestations of systemic lupus erythematosus. Best Pract Res Clin Rheumatol. 2005;19:741&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16150401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ju JH, Min JK, Jung CK, et al. . Lupus mesenteric vasculitis can cause acute abdominal pain in patients with SLE. Nat Rev Rheumatol. 2009;5:273&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19412194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z, Wu C, Ruan F, et al. . A case of systemic lupus erythematosus with rectal necrosis. Lupus. 2020;29:1&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31924142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reissman P, Weiss EG, Teoh TA, et al. . Gangrenous ischemic colitis of the rectum: a rare complication of systemic lupus erythematosus. Am J Gastroenterol. 1994;89:2234&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7977248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>