<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">37555846</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>10</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2573-7732</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>7</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>ImmunoHorizons</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Immunohorizons</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Disease in the Pld4thss/thss Model of Murine Lupus Requires TLR9.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>577</StartPage><EndPage>586</EndPage><MedlinePgn>577-586</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4049/immunohorizons.2300058</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Phospholipase D4 (PLD4) is an endolysosomal exonuclease of ssRNA and ssDNA, rather than a phospholipase as its name suggests. Human polymorphisms in the PLD4 gene have been linked by genome-wide association studies to systemic sclerosis, rheumatoid arthritis, and systemic lupus erythematosus. However, B6.129 Pld4-/- mice develop features of a distinct disease, macrophage activation syndrome, which is reversed in mice mutated in TLR9. In this article, we compare a Pld4 null mutant identified on the BALB/c background, Pld4thss/thss, which has distinct phenotypes: short stature, thin hair, and features of systemic lupus erythematosus. All phenotypes analyzed were largely normalized in Pld4thss/thssTlr9-/- mice. Thus, Pld4thss/thss represents a rare model in which mouse lupus etiology is TLR9 dependent. Compared with PLD4-deficient B6 mice, Pld4thss/thss mice had elevated levels of serum IgG, IgG anti-dsDNA autoantibodies, BAFF, and IFN-&#x3b3; and elevated B cell numbers. Overall, the data suggest that PLD4 deficiency can lead to a diverse array of rheumatological abnormalities depending upon background-modifying genes, and that these diseases of PLD4 deficiency are largely driven by TLR9 recognition of ssDNA.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 The Authors.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gavin</LastName><ForeName>Amanda L</ForeName><Initials>AL</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9921-4225</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Immunology and Microbiology, The Scripps Research Institute, La Jolla, CA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Blane</LastName><ForeName>Tanya R</ForeName><Initials>TR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Immunology and Microbiology, The Scripps Research Institute, La Jolla, CA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Thinnes</LastName><ForeName>Therese C</ForeName><Initials>TC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Immunology and Microbiology, The Scripps Research Institute, La Jolla, CA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gerlt</LastName><ForeName>Emma</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9720-1957</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of California, Merced, Merced, CA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Marshak-Rothstein</LastName><ForeName>Ann</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2136-8130</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Massachusetts Medical School, Worcester, MA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Deli</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Immunology and Microbiology, The Scripps Research Institute, La Jolla, CA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Life Sciences Institute, Zhejiang University, Hangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nemazee</LastName><ForeName>David</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4769-6311</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Immunology and Microbiology, The Scripps Research Institute, La Jolla, CA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R01 AI142945</GrantID><Acronym>AI</Acronym><Agency>NIAID NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R56 AG070775</GrantID><Acronym>AG</Acronym><Agency>NIA NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>RF1 AG070775</GrantID><Acronym>AG</Acronym><Agency>NIA NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Immunohorizons</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101708159</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2573-7732</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 3.1.-</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D005092">Exonucleases</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D007074">Immunoglobulin G</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 3.1.-</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D010740">Phospholipases</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 3.1.-</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C557622">PLD4 protein, mouse</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D051217">Toll-Like Receptor 9</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C495370">Tlr9 protein, mouse</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051379" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005092" MajorTopicYN="N">Exonucleases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055106" MajorTopicYN="N">Genome-Wide Association Study</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007074" MajorTopicYN="N">Immunoglobulin G</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010740" MajorTopicYN="N">Phospholipases</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051217" MajorTopicYN="Y">Toll-Like Receptor 9</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>Competing interests. The authors have no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>56</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37555846</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS1924444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10441812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4049/immunohorizons.2300058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">265827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Nadeau JH 2001. Modifier genes in mice and humans. Nat. Rev. Genet 2: 165&#x2013;174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11256068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sittig LJ, Carbonetto P, Engel KA, Krauss KS, Barrios-Camacho CM, and Palmer AA 2016. Genetic Background Limits Generalizability of Genotype-Phenotype Relationships. Neuron 91: 1253&#x2013;1259.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5033712</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27618673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mullis MN, Matsui T, Schell R, Foree R, and Ehrenreich IM 2018. The complex underpinnings of genetic background effects. Nat Commun 9: 3548&#x2013;3557.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6141565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30224702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishimura H, Nose M, Hiai H, Minato N, and Honjo T 1999. Development of lupus-like autoimmune diseases by disruption of the PD-1 gene encoding an ITIM motif-carrying immunoreceptor. Immunity 11: 141&#x2013;151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10485649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishimura H, Okazaki T, Tanaka Y, Nakatani K, Hara M, Matsumori A, Sasayama S, Mizoguchi A, Hiai H, Minato N, and Honjo T 2001. Autoimmune dilated cardiomyopathy in PD-1 receptor-deficient mice. Science 291: 319&#x2013;322.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11209085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsuo T, Hashimoto M, Sakaguchi S, Sakaguchi N, Ito Y, Hikida M, Tsuruyama T, Sakai K, Yokoi H, Shirakashi M, Tanaka M, Ito H, Yoshifuji H, Ohmura K, Fujii T, and Mimori T 2019. Strain-Specific Manifestation of Lupus-like Systemic Autoimmunity Caused by Zap70 Mutation. J. Immunol 202: 3161&#x2013;3172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31019063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bossaller L, Christ A, Pelka K, Nundel K, Chiang PI, Pang C, Mishra N, Busto P, Bonegio RG, Schmidt RE, Latz E, and Marshak-Rothstein A 2016. TLR9 Deficiency Leads to Accelerated Renal Disease and Myeloid Lineage Abnormalities in Pristane-Induced Murine Lupus. J. Immunol 197: 1044&#x2013;1053.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5266544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27354219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bolland S, and Ravetch JV 2000. Spontaneous autoimmune disease in Fc(gamma)RIIB-deficient mice results from strain-specific epistasis. Immunity 13: 277&#x2013;285.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10981970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gavin AL, Huang D, Huber C, Martensson A, Tardif V, Skog PD, Blane TR, Thinnes TC, Osborn K, Chong HS, Kargaran F, Kimm P, Zeitjian A, Sielski RL, Briggs M, Schulz SR, Zarpellon A, Cravatt B, Pang ES, Teijaro J, de la Torre JC, O&#x2019;Keeffe M, Hochrein H, Damme M, Teyton L, Lawson BR, and Nemazee D 2018. PLD3 and PLD4 are single-stranded acid exonucleases that regulate endosomal nucleic-acid sensing. Nat. Immunol 19: 942&#x2013;953.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6105523</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30111894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akizuki S, Ishigaki K, Kochi Y, Law SM, Matsuo K, Ohmura K, Suzuki A, Nakayama M, Iizuka Y, Koseki H, Ohara O, Hirata J, Kamatani Y, Matsuda F, Sumida T, Yamamoto K, Okada Y, Mimori T, and Terao C 2019. PLD4 is a genetic determinant to systemic lupus erythematosus and involved in murine autoimmune phenotypes. Ann. Rheum. Dis 78: 509&#x2013;518.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30679154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okada Y, Terao C, Ikari K, Kochi Y, Ohmura K, Suzuki A, Kawaguchi T, Stahl EA, Kurreeman FA, Nishida N, Ohmiya H, Myouzen K, Takahashi M, Sawada T, Nishioka Y, Yukioka M, Matsubara T, Wakitani S, Teshima R, Tohma S, Takasugi K, Shimada K, Murasawa A, Honjo S, Matsuo K, Tanaka H, Tajima K, Suzuki T, Iwamoto T, Kawamura Y, Tanii H, Okazaki Y, Sasaki T, Gregersen PK, Padyukov L, Worthington J, Siminovitch KA, Lathrop M, Taniguchi A, Takahashi A, Tokunaga K, Kubo M, Nakamura Y, Kamatani N, Mimori T, Plenge RM, Yamanaka H, Momohara S, Yamada R, Matsuda F, and Yamamoto K 2012. Meta-analysis identifies nine new loci associated with rheumatoid arthritis in the Japanese population. Nat. Genet 44: 511&#x2013;516.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22446963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terao C, Ohmura K, Kawaguchi Y, Nishimoto T, Kawasaki A, Takehara K, Furukawa H, Kochi Y, Ota Y, Ikari K, Sato S, Tohma S, Yamada R, Yamamoto K, Kubo M, Yamanaka H, Kuwana M, Tsuchiya N, Matsuda F, and Mimori T 2013. PLD4 as a novel susceptibility gene for systemic sclerosis in a Japanese population. Arthritis Rheum 65: 472&#x2013;480.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23124809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langenmayer MC, Jung S, Majzoub-Altweck M, Trefz FM, Seifert C, Knubben-Schweizer G, Fries R, Hermanns W, and Gollnick NS 2018. Zinc Deficiency-Like Syndrome in Fleckvieh Calves: Clinical and Pathological Findings and Differentiation from Bovine Hereditary Zinc Deficiency. J Vet Intern Med 32: 853&#x2013;859.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5866964</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29424482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langenmayer MC, Jung S, Fux R, Wittlinger C, Tschoner T, Majzoub-Altweck M, Knubben-Schweizer G, Fries R, Hermanns W, and Trefz FM 2022. Macrophages in dermal disease progression of phospholipase D4-deficient Fleckvieh calves. Vet. Pathol 59: 319&#x2013;327.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34856834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gavin AL, Huang D, Blane TR, Thinnes TC, Murakami Y, Fukui R, Miyake K, and Nemazee D 2021. Cleavage of DNA and RNA by PLD3 and PLD4 limits autoinflammatory triggering by multiple sensors. Nat Commun 12: 5874&#x2013;5887.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8497607</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34620855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackay F, Silveira PA, and Brink R 2007. B cells and the BAFF/APRIL axis: fast-forward on autoimmunity and signaling. Curr. Opin. Immunol 19: 327&#x2013;336.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17433868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leadbetter EA, Rifkin IR, Hohlbaum AM, Beaudette BC, Shlomchik MJ, and Marshak-Rothstein A 2002. Chromatin-IgG complexes activate B cells by dual engagement of IgM and Toll-like receptors. Nature 416: 603&#x2013;607.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11948342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pisitkun P, Deane JA, Difilippantonio MJ, Tarasenko T, Satterthwaite AB, and Bolland S 2006. Autoreactive B cell responses to RNA-related antigens due to TLR7 gene duplication. Science 312: 1669&#x2013;1672.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16709748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Subramanian S, Tus K, Li QZ, Wang A, Tian XH, Zhou J, Liang C, Bartov G, McDaniel LD, Zhou XJ, Schultz RA, and Wakeland EK 2006. A Tlr7 translocation accelerates systemic autoimmunity in murine lupus. Proc.Natl.Acad.Sci.U.S.A 103: 9970&#x2013;9975.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1502563</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16777955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christensen SR, Shupe J, Nickerson K, Kashgarian M, Flavell RA, and Shlomchik MJ 2006. Toll-like receptor 7 and TLR9 dictate autoantibody specificity and have opposing inflammatory and regulatory roles in a murine model of lupus. Immunity 25: 417&#x2013;428.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16973389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson SW, Scharping NE, Kolhatkar NS, Khim S, Schwartz MA, Li QZ, Hudkins KL, Alpers CE, Liggitt D, and Rawlings DJ 2014. Opposing impact of B cell-intrinsic TLR7 and TLR9 signals on autoantibody repertoire and systemic inflammation. J. Immunol 192: 4525&#x2013;4532.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4041708</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24711620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fillatreau S, Manfroi B, and Dorner T 2021. Toll-like receptor signalling in B cells during systemic lupus erythematosus. Nat Rev Rheumatol 17: 98&#x2013;108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7747191</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33339987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desnues B, Macedo AB, Roussel-Queval A, Bonnardel J, Henri S, Demaria O, and Alexopoulou L 2014. TLR8 on dendritic cells and TLR9 on B cells restrain TLR7-mediated spontaneous autoimmunity in C57BL/6 mice. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 111: 1497&#x2013;1502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3910605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24474776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soni C, Perez OA, Voss WN, Pucella JN, Serpas L, Mehl J, Ching KL, Goike J, Georgiou G, Ippolito GC, Sisirak V, and Reizis B 2020. Plasmacytoid Dendritic Cells and Type I Interferon Promote Extrafollicular B Cell Responses to Extracellular Self-DNA. Immunity 52: 1022&#x2013;1038 e1027.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7306002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32454024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu P, Wellmann U, Kunder S, Quintanilla-Martinez L, Jennen L, Dear N, Amann K, Bauer S, Winkler TH, and Wagner H 2006. Toll-like receptor 9-independent aggravation of glomerulonephritis in a novel model of SLE. Int. Immunol 18: 1211&#x2013;1219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16798839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lartigue A, Courville P, Auquit I, Francois A, Arnoult C, Tron F, Gilbert D, and Musette P 2006. Role of TLR9 in anti-nucleosome and anti-DNA antibody production in lpr mutation-induced murine lupus. J. Immunol 177: 1349&#x2013;1354.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16818796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santiago-Raber ML, Dunand-Sauthier I, Wu T, Li QZ, Uematsu S, Akira S, Reith W, Mohan C, Kotzin BL, and Izui S 2010. Critical role of TLR7 in the acceleration of systemic lupus erythematosus in TLR9-deficient mice. J. Autoimmun 34: 339&#x2013;348.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19944565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nickerson KM, Christensen SR, Shupe J, Kashgarian M, Kim D, Elkon K, and Shlomchik MJ 2010. TLR9 regulates TLR7- and MyD88-dependent autoantibody production and disease in a murine model of lupus. J. Immunol 184: 1840&#x2013;1848.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4098568</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20089701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beutler B, Jiang Z, Georgel P, Crozat K, Croker B, Rutschmann S, Du X, and Hoebe K 2006. GENETIC ANALYSIS OF HOST RESISTANCE: Toll-Like Receptor Signaling and Immunity at Large. Annu. Rev. Immunol 24: 353&#x2013;389.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16551253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heinz LX, Lee J, Kapoor U, Kartnig F, Sedlyarov V, Papakostas K, Cesar-Razquin A, Essletzbichler P, Goldmann U, Stefanovic A, Bigenzahn JW, Scorzoni S, Pizzagalli MD, Bensimon A, Muller AC, King FJ, Li J, Girardi E, Mbow ML, Whitehurst CE, Rebsamen M, and Superti-Furga G 2020. TASL is the SLC15A4-associated adaptor for IRF5 activation by TLR7&#x2013;9. Nature 581: 316&#x2013;322.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7610944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32433612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mouchess ML, Arpaia N, Souza G, Barbalat R, Ewald SE, Lau L, and Barton GM 2011. Transmembrane mutations in Toll-like receptor 9 bypass the requirement for ectodomain proteolysis and induce fatal inflammation. Immunity 35: 721&#x2013;732.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3230302</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22078797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sisirak V, Sally B, D&#x2019;Agati V, Martinez-Ortiz W, Ozcakar ZB, David J, Rashidfarrokhi A, Yeste A, Panea C, Chida AS, Bogunovic M, Ivanov II, Quintana FJ, Sanz I, Elkon KB, Tekin M, Yalcinkaya F, Cardozo TJ, Clancy RM, Buyon JP, and Reizis B 2016. Digestion of Chromatin in Apoptotic Cell Microparticles Prevents Autoimmunity. Cell 166: 88&#x2013;101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5030815</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27293190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zou W, Schwartz H, Endres S, Hartmann G, and Bar-Shavit Z 2002. CpG oligonucleotides: novel regulators of osteoclast differentiation. FASEB J 16: 274&#x2013;282.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11874977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krisher T, and Bar-Shavit Z 2014. Regulation of osteoclastogenesis by integrated signals from toll-like receptors. J. Cell. Biochem 115: 2146&#x2013;2154.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25079212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ota M, Duong BH, Torkamani A, Doyle CM, Gavin AL, Ota T, and Nemazee D 2010. Regulation of the B cell receptor repertoire and self-reactivity by BAFF. J. Immunol 185: 4128&#x2013;4136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3263398</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20817867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harigai M, Kawamoto M, Hara M, Kubota T, Kamatani N, and Miyasaka N 2008. Excessive production of IFN-gamma in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus and its contribution to induction of B lymphocyte stimulator/B cell-activating factor/TNF ligand superfamily-13B. J. Immunol 181: 2211&#x2013;2219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18641361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mills RE, Lam VC, Tan A, Cresalia N, Oksenberg N, Zikherman J, Anderson M, Weiss A, and Hermiston ML 2015. Unbiased modifier screen reveals that signal strength determines the regulatory role murine TLR9 plays in autoantibody production. J. Immunol 194: 3675&#x2013;3686.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4503364</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25769918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sindhava VJ, Oropallo MA, Moody K, Naradikian M, Higdon LE, Zhou L, Myles A, Green N, Nundel K, Stohl W, Schmidt AM, Cao W, Dorta-Estremera S, Kambayashi T, Marshak-Rothstein A, and Cancro MP 2017. A TLR9-dependent checkpoint governs B cell responses to DNA-containing antigens. J. Clin. Invest 127: 1651&#x2013;1663.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5409796</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28346226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isnardi I, Ng YS, Srdanovic I, Motaghedi R, Rudchenko S, von Bernuth H, Zhang SY, Puel A, Jouanguy E, Picard C, Garty BZ, Camcioglu Y, Doffinger R, Kumararatne D, Davies G, Gallin JI, Haraguchi S, Day NK, Casanova JL, and Meffre E 2008. IRAK-4- and MyD88-dependent pathways are essential for the removal of developing autoreactive B cells in humans. Immunity 29: 746&#x2013;757.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2666307</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19006693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gies V, Schickel JN, Jung S, Joublin A, Glauzy S, Knapp AM, Soley A, Poindron V, Guffroy A, Choi JY, Gottenberg JE, Anolik JH, Martin T, Soulas-Sprauel P, Meffre E, and Korganow AS 2018. Impaired TLR9 responses in B cells from patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. JCI Insight 3: 1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5922279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29515028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nickerson KM, Christensen SR, Cullen JL, Meng W, Luning Prak ET, and Shlomchik MJ 2013. TLR9 promotes tolerance by restricting survival of anergic anti-DNA B cells, yet is also required for their activation. J. Immunol 190: 1447&#x2013;1456.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3563726</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23296704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azulay-Debby H, Edry E, and Melamed D 2007. CpG DNA stimulates autoreactive immature B cells in the bone marrow. Eur. J. Immunol 37: 1463&#x2013;1475.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17474151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohyagi H, Onai N, Sato T, Yotsumoto S, Liu J, Akiba H, Yagita H, Atarashi K, Honda K, Roers A, Muller W, Kurabayashi K, Hosoi-Amaike M, Takahashi N, Hirokawa M, Matsushima K, Sawada K, and Ohteki T 2013. Monocyte-derived dendritic cells perform hemophagocytosis to fine-tune excessive immune responses. Immunity 39: 584&#x2013;598.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24035363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Z, Ohto U, Shibata T, Krayukhina E, Taoka M, Yamauchi Y, Tanji H, Isobe T, Uchiyama S, Miyake K, and Shimizu T 2016. Structural Analysis Reveals that Toll-like Receptor 7 Is a Dual Receptor for Guanosine and Single-Stranded RNA. Immunity 45: 737&#x2013;748.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27742543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanji H, Ohto U, Shibata T, Taoka M, Yamauchi Y, Isobe T, Miyake K, and Shimizu T 2015. Toll-like receptor 8 senses degradation products of single-stranded RNA. Nat. Struct. Mol. Biol 22: 109&#x2013;115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25599397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>