<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37577878</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>13</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1473-5733</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>34</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Blood coagulation &amp; fibrinolysis : an international journal in haemostasis and thrombosis</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Blood Coagul Fibrinolysis</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Reduced ADAMTS13 activity and high D-dimer levels are associated with thrombosis in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>432</StartPage><EndPage>438</EndPage><MedlinePgn>432-438</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MBC.0000000000001247</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Patients with systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) have an increased risk of vascular thrombosis compared to the general population. Therefore, biomarkers for predicting the risk of thrombosis in patients with SLE are needed.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">In the present study, a total of 66 patients with SLE (22 with and 44 without a history of thrombosis) were enrolled. The cases with thrombosis and the controls without thrombosis were matched for age (&#xb1; 5&#x200a;years) and sex. We assessed ADAMTS13 activity, D-dimer levels, and antiphospholipid antibodies. Clinical manifestations, SLE disease activity, classical risk factors, and medical history were collected.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">ADAMTS13 activity was significantly reduced, and D-dimer levels were significantly increased in patients with SLE with a history of thrombosis compared with those in patients without thrombosis. Receiver operating characteristic curve analysis revealed a good correlation between reduced ADAMTS13 activity and a history of thrombosis. Reduced ADAMTS13 activity was correlated with increased D-dimer levels only in the thrombotic group.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Reduced ADAMTS13 activity and high D-dimer levels are associated with thrombosis and may serve as prognostic markers for thrombosis in patients with SLE.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Penglong</LastName><ForeName>Tipparat</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Haematology Unit, Department of Pathology, Faculty of Medicine.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Boontanvansom</LastName><ForeName>Anuchit</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Immunology and Virology Unit, Department of Pathology, Faculty of Medicine.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Viboonjuntra</LastName><ForeName>Pongtep</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Haematology Unit, Department of Internal Medicine.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Siripaitoon</LastName><ForeName>Boonjing</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Allergy and Rheumatology Unit, Department of Internal Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, Prince of Songkla University, Hat Yai, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Blood Coagul Fibrinolysis</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9102551</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0957-5235</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C036309">fibrin fragment D</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D005338">Fibrin Fibrinogen Degradation Products</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D017152">Antibodies, Antiphospholipid</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 3.4.24.87</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C099604">ADAMTS13 protein, human</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 3.4.24.87</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000071120">ADAMTS13 Protein</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013927" MajorTopicYN="Y">Thrombosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005338" MajorTopicYN="N">Fibrin Fibrinogen Degradation Products</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017152" MajorTopicYN="N">Antibodies, Antiphospholipid</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000071120" MajorTopicYN="N">ADAMTS13 Protein</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37577878</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MBC.0000000000001247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00001721-990000000-00097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Mok CC, Tang SS, To CH, Petri M. Incidence and risk factors of thromboembolism in systemic lupus erythematosus: a comparison of three ethnic groups. Arthritis Rheum 2005; 52:2774&#x2013;2782.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romero-D&#xed;az J, Garc&#xed;a-Sosa I, S&#xe1;nchez-Guerrero J. Thrombosis in systemic lupus erythematosus and other autoimmune diseases of recent onset. J Rheumatol 2009; 36:68&#x2013;75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang ER, Pineau CA, Bernatsky S, Neville C, Clarke AE, Fortin PR. Risk for incident arterial or venous vascular events varies throughout systemic lupus erythematosus. J Rheumatol 2006; 33:1780&#x2013;1784.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cervera R, Khamashta MA, Font J, et al. Morbidity and mortality in systemic lupus erythematosus during a 10-year period: a comparison of early and late manifestations in a cohort of 1000 patients. Medicine (Baltimore) 2003; 82:299&#x2013;308.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Afeltra A, Vadacca M, Conti L, et al. Thrombosis in systemic lupus erythematosus: congenital and acquired risk factors. Arthritis Rheu 2005; 53:452&#x2013;459.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Love PE, Santoro SA. Antiphospholipid antibodies: anticardiolipin and the lupus anticoagulant in systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) and in non-SLE disorders. Prevalence and clinical significance. Ann Intern Med 1990; 112:682&#x2013;698.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amoroso A, Mitterhofer AP, Del Porto F, et al. Antibodies to anionic phospholipids and antibeta2-GPI: association with thrombosis and thrombocytopenia in systemic lupus erythematosus. Hum Immunol 2003; 64:265&#x2013;273.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wahl DG, Guillemin F, de Maistre E, Perret C, Lecompte T, Thibaut G. Risk for venous thrombosis related to antiphospholipid antibodies in systemic lupus erythematosus&#x2014;a meta-analysis. Lupus 1997; 6:467&#x2013;473.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackworth-Young CG. Antiphospholipid syndrome: multiple mechanisms. Clin Exp Immunol 2004; 136:393&#x2013;401.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pengo V, Ruffatti A, Legnani C, et al. Incidence of a first thromboembolic event in asymptomatic carriers of high-risk antiphospholipid antibody profile: a multicenter prospective study. Blood 2011; 118:4714&#x2013;4718.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stein PD, Hull RD, Patel KC, et al. D-dimer for the exclusion of acute venous thrombosis and pulmonary embolism: a systematic review. Ann Intern Med 2004; 140:589&#x2013;602.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qaseem A, Snow V, Barry P, et al. Current diagnosis of venous thromboembolism in primary care: a clinical practice guideline from the American Academy of Family Physicians and the American College of Physicians. Ann Fam Med 2007; 5:57&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eichinger S, Minar E, Bialonczyk C, et al. D-dimer levels and risk of recurrent venous thromboembolism. JAMA 2003; 290:1071&#x2013;1074.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shrivastava S, Ridker PM, Glynn RJ, et al. D-dimer, factor VIII coagulant activity, low-intensity warfarin and the risk of recurrent venous thromboembolism. J Thromb Haemost 2006; 4:1208&#x2013;1214.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu H, Birmingham DJ, Rovin B, et al. D-dimer level and the risk for thrombosis in systemic lupus erythematosus. Clin J Am Soc Nephrol 2008; 3:1628&#x2013;1636.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiang Y, de Groot R, Crawley JT, Lane DA. Mechanism of von Willebrand factor scissile bond cleavage by a disintegrin and metalloproteinase with a thrombospondin type 1 motif, member 13 (ADAMTS13). PNAS 2011; 108:11602&#x2013;11607.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin-Rodriguez S, Reverter JC, T&#xe0;ssies D, et al. Reduced ADAMTS13 activity is associated with thrombotic risk in systemic lupus erythematosus. Lupus 2015; 24:1143&#x2013;1149.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hochberg MC. Updating the American College of Rheumatology revised criteria for the classification of systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Rheum 1997; 40:1725.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uribe AG, Vil&#xe1; LM, McGwin G Jr, Sanchez ML, Reveille JD, Alarc&#xf3;n GS. The Systemic Lupus Activity Measure-revised, the Mexican Systemic Lupus Erythematosus Disease Activity Index (SLEDAI), and a modified SLEDAI-2K are adequate instruments to measure disease activity in systemic lupus erythematosus. J Rheumatol 2004; 31:1934&#x2013;1940.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devreese KMJ, de Groot PG, de Laat B, et al. Guidance from the Scientific and Standardization Committee for lupus anticoagulant/antiphospholipid antibodies of the International Society on Thrombosis and Haemostasis: update of the guidelines for lupus anticoagulant detection and interpretation. J Thromb Haemost 2020; 18:2828&#x2013;2839.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ichkawa Y, Wada H, Ezaki M, et al. Elevated D-dimer levels predict a poor outcome in critically ill patients. Clin Appl Thromb Hemost 2020; 26:1076029620973084.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Broder A, Putterman C. Hydroxychloroquine use is associated with lower odds of persistently positive antiphospholipid antibodies and/or lupus anticoagulant in systemic lupus erythematosus. J Rheumatol 2013; 40:30&#x2013;33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mannucci PM, Vanoli M, Forza I, Canciani MT, Scorza R. Von Willebrand factor cleaving protease (ADAMTS-13) in 123 patients with connective tissue diseases (systemic lupus erythematosus and systemic sclerosis). Haematologica 2003; 88:914&#x2013;918.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rieger M, Mannucci PM, Kremer Hovinga JA, et al. ADAMTS13 autoantibodies in patients with thrombotic microangiopathies and other immunomediated diseases. Blood 2005; 106:1262&#x2013;1267.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner N, Nolasco L, Tao Z, Dong JF, Moake J. Human endothelial cells synthesize and release ADAMTS-13. J Thromb Haemost 2006; 4:1396&#x2013;1404.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>