<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37611146</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>12</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1744-6880</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>33</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Pharmacogenetics and genomics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Pharmacogenet Genomics</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Genetic polymorphisms effect on cyclophosphamide's tolerability and clinical efficacy in Egyptian patients with lupus nephritis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>172</StartPage><EndPage>180</EndPage><MedlinePgn>172-180</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/FPC.0000000000000506</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES">Many studies were conducted to determine the association between genetic polymorphisms in CYP2B6 c.516G&gt;T and cyclophosphamide (CYC) efficacy or toxicity, no studies were focused on both clinical efficacy and toxicity of CYC. This study aimed to investigate the relationship between the CYP2B6 c.516G&gt;T polymorphism (rs 3745274) and 17 different parameters related to CYC efficacy and tolerability in Egyptian patients with lupus nephritis (LN).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">A prospective cohort study on 142 LN patients with a mean age of 36.26 was conducted at Kasr Al Ainy School of Medicine, Cairo University, Egypt after the exclusion of 14 patients due to receiving an interacting medication with CYC. All clinical parameters related to CYC efficacy or toxicity were recorded and compared between the different genotypes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">There was a statistically significant difference between different genotypes in 11 out of 13 of the studied efficacy-related parameters. Many of the studied clinical parameters revealed that CYC's efficacy was associated with the presence of the T allele. There was a statistically significant difference between different genotypes in hepatotoxicity, diarrhea, and blood-related toxicities.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">To our knowledge, this study is the first study that focused on studying 17 different parameters related to CYC efficacy and tolerability. Our findings paint a picture of the function that CYP2B6 polymorphisms play in Egyptian LN patients. Pre-treatment evaluation of CYP2B6 rs 3745274 may account for some individual differences in treatment response.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abuelsoud</LastName><ForeName>Nermeen N</ForeName><Initials>NN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacy Practice and Clinical Pharmacy, College of Pharmacy, Egyptian Russian University.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>El Khateeb</LastName><ForeName>Engy M</ForeName><Initials>EM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical and Chemical Pathology, Kasr Al Aini School of Medicine, Cairo University, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Pharmacogenet Genomics</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101231005</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1744-6872</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 1.14.14.1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D065702">Cytochrome P-450 CYP2B6</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>8N3DW7272P</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D003520">Cyclophosphamide</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008181" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lupus Nephritis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004534" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Egypt</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D065702" MajorTopicYN="N">Cytochrome P-450 CYP2B6</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011446" MajorTopicYN="N">Prospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003520" MajorTopicYN="N">Cyclophosphamide</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011110" MajorTopicYN="N">Polymorphism, Genetic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37611146</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/FPC.0000000000000506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">01213011-990000000-00035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Attia D, Eissa M, Samy L, Khattab R. Influence of glutathione S transferase A1 gene polymorphism (-69C &gt; T, rs3957356) on intravenous cyclophosphamide efficacy and side effects: a case-control study in Egyptian patients with lupus nephritis. Clin Rheumatol 2021; 40:753&#x2013;762.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crow MK. Etiology and pathogenesis of systemic lupus erythematosus. In: Firestein GS, Budd RC, Gabriel SE, Mcinnes LB, O&#x2019;Dell JR, ., editors. Kelley and Firestein&#x2019;s textbook of rheumatology, 10th ed. Elsevier, Philadelphia; 2017. pp. 1329&#x2013;1344</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mok CC. Mycophenolate mofetil for lupus nephritis: an update. Expert Rev Clin Immunol 2015; 11:1353&#x2013;1364.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korbet SM, Schwartz MM, Evans J, Lewis EJ; Collaborative Study Group. Severe lupus nephritis: racial differences in presentation and outcome. J Am Soc Nep 2007; 18:244&#x2013;254.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Serafi I, Afsharian P, Moshfegh A, Hassan M, Terelius Y. Cytochrome P450 oxidoreductase influences CYP2B6 activity in cyclophosphamide bioactivation. PLoS One 2015; 10:e0141979.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mok CC. Con: Cyclophosphamide for the treatment of lupus nephritis. Nephrol Dial Transplant 2016; 31:1053&#x2013;1057.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emadi A, Jones RJ, Brodsky RA. Cyclophosphamide and cancer: golden anniversary. Nat Rev Clin Oncol 2009; 6:638&#x2013;647.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Preissner SC, Hoffmann MF, Preissner R, Dunkel M, Gewiess A, Preissner S. Polymorphic cytochrome P450 enzymes (CYPs) and their role in personalized therapy. PLoS One 2013; 8:e82562.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Illei GG, Austin HA, Crane M, Collins L, Gourley MF, Yarboro CH, et al. Combination therapy with pulse cyclophosphamide plus pulse methylprednisolone improves long-term renal outcome without adding toxicity in patients with lupus nephritis. Ann Intern Med 2001; 135:248&#x2013;257.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mok CC, Lau CS, Wong WS. Risk factors for ovarian failure in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus receiving cyclophosphamide therapy. Arthritis Rheum 1998; 41:831&#x2013;837.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mok CC, Yap DY, Navarra SV, Liu Z, Zhao M, Lu L, et al.; Asian Lupus Nephritis Network (ALNN). Overview of lupus nephritis management guidelines and perspective from Asia. Nephrology (Carlton) 2014; 19:11&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ginzler EM, Dooley MA, Aranow C, Kim MY, Buyon J, Merrill JT, et al. Mycophenolate mofetil or intravenous cyclophosphamide for lupus nephritis. N Engl J Med 2005; 353:2219&#x2013;2228.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Contreras G, Pardo V, Leclercq B, Lenz O, Tozman E, O&#x2019;Nan P, et al. Sequential therapies for proliferative lupus nephritis. N Engl J Med 2004; 350:971&#x2013;980.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinto N, Ludeman SM, Dolan ME. Drug focus: Pharmacogenetic studies related to cyclophosphamide-based therapy. Pharmacogenomics 2009; 10:1897&#x2013;1903.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martinez-Bravo MJ, Calder&#x20d;n-Cabrera C, M&#xe1;rquez-Malaver FJ, Rodrigue&#x17a; N, Guijarro M, Espigado I, et al. Mismatch on glutathione s-transferase T1 increases the risk of graft-versus-host disease and mortality after allogeneic stem cell transplantation. Biol Blood Marrow Transplant 2014; 20:1356&#x2013;1362.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bachanova V, Shanley R, Malik F, Chauhan L, Lamba V, Weisdorf DJ, et al. Cytochrome P450 2B6*5 increases relapse after cyclophosphamide-containing conditioning and autologous transplantation for lymphoma. Biol Blood Marrow Transplant 2015; 21:944&#x2013;948.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hochberg MC. Updating the American College of Rheumatology revised criteria for the classification of systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Rheum 1997; 40:1725&#x2013;1734.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petri M, Orbai A, Alarc&#xf3;n G, Gordon C, Merrill JT, Fortin PR, et al. Derivation and validation of systemic lupus international collaborating clinics classification criteria for systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Rheum 2012; 64:2677&#x2013;2686.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bombardier C, Gladman DD, Urowitz MB, Caron D, Chang CH. Derivation of the SLEDAI. A disease activity index for lupus patients. The committee on prognosis studies in SLE. Arthritis Rheum 1992; 35:630&#x2013;640.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim JH, Cheong HS, Park BL, Kim LH, Shin HJ, Na HS, et al. Direct sequencing and comprehensive screening of genetic polymorphisms on CYP2 family genes (CYP2A6, CYP2B6, CYP2C8, and CYP2E1) in five ethnic populations. Arch Pharm Res 2014; 38:115&#x2013;128.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shu W, Guan S, Yang X, Liang L, Li J, Chen Z, et al. Genetic markers in CYP2C19 and CYP2B6 for prediction of cyclophosphamide&#x2019;s 4- hydroxylation, efficacy and side effects in Chinese patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. Br J Clin Pharmacol 2015; 81:327&#x2013;340.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ariyoshi N, Ohara M, Kaneko M, Afuso S, Kumamoto T, Nakamura H, et al. Q172H replacement overcomes effects on the metabolism of cyclophosphamide and efavirenz caused by CYP2B6 variant with Arg262. Drug Metab Dispos 2011; 39:2045&#x2013;2048.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang TKH, Weber GF, Crespi CL, Waxman DJ. Differential activation of cyclophosphamide and ifosphamide by cytochromes P-450 2B and 3A in human liver microsomes. Cancer Res 1993; 53:5629&#x2013;5637.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bray J, Sludden J, Griffin MJ, Cole M, Verrill M, Jamieson D, et al. Influence of pharmacogenetics on response and toxicity in breast cancer patients treated with doxorubicin and cyclophosphamide. Br J Cancer 2010; 102:1003&#x2013;1009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lang T, Klein K, Fischer J, Nussler AK, Neuhaus P, Hofmann U, et al. Extensive genetic polymorphism in the human CYP2B6 gene with impact on expression and function in human liver. Pharmacogenetics 2001; 11:399&#x2013;415.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jinno H, Tanaka-Kagawa T, Ohno A, Makino Y, Matsushima E, Hanioka N, et al. Functional characterization of cytochrome P4502B6 allelic variants. Drug Metab Dispos 2003; 31:398&#x2013;403.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie HJ, Yasar U, Lundgren S, Griskevicius L, Terelius Y, Hassan M, Rane A.Role of polymorphic human CYP2B6 in cyclophosphamide bioactivation. Pharmacogenomics J 2003; 3:53&#x2013;61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie H, Griskevicius L, Stahle L, Hassan Z, Yasar U, Rane A, et al. Pharmacogenetics of cyclophosphamide in patients with hematological malignancies. Eur J Pharm Sci 2006; 27:54&#x2013;61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakajima M, Komagata S, Fujiki Y, Kanada Y, Ebi H, Itoh K, et al. Genetic polymorphisms of CYP2B6 affect the pharmacokinetics/pharmacodynamics of cyclophosphamide in Japanese cancer patients. Pharmacogenet Genomics 2007; 17:431&#x2013;445.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekhart C, Doodeman VD, Rodenhuis S, Smits PH, Beijnen JH, Huitema AD. Influence of polymorphisms of drug metabolizing enzymes (CYP2B6, CYP2C9, CYP2C19, CYP3A4, CYP3A5, GSTA1, GSTP1, ALDH1A1 and ALDH3A1) on the pharmacokinetics of cyclophosphamide and 4-hydroxycyclophosphamide. Pharmacogenet Genomics 2008; 18:515&#x2013;523.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veal G, Cole M, Chinnaswamy G, Sludden J, Jamieson D, Errington J, et al. Cyclophosphamide pharmacokinetics and pharmacogenetics in children with B-cell non-Hodgkin&#x2019;s lymphoma. Eur J Cancer 2016; 55:56&#x2013;64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mu&#xf1;iz P, Andr&#xe9;s-Zayas C, Carbonell D, Chicano M, Bail&#xe9;n R, Oarbeascoa G, et al. Association between gene polymorphisms in cyclophosphamide metabolism pathway with complications after haploidentical hematopoietic stem cell transplantation. Front Immunol 2022; 13:1002959.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson GG, Lin K, Cox TF, Oates M, Sibson DR, Eccles R, et al. CYP2B6*6 is an independent determinant of inferior response to fludarabine plus cyclophosphamide in chronic lymphocytic leukemia. Blood 2013; 122:4253&#x2013;4258.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Labib RM, Abdelrahim MEA, Elnadi E, Hesham RM, Yassin D. CYP2B6rs2279343 is associated with improved survival of pediatric rhabdomyosarcoma treated with cyclophosphamide. PLoS One 2016; 11:e0158890.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhong S, Huang M, Yang X, Liang L, Wang Y, Romkes M, et al. Relationship of glutathione S-transferase genotypes with side-effects of pulsed cyclophosphamide therapy in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. Br J Clin Pharmacol 2006; 62:457&#x2013;472.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rocha V, Porcher R, Fernandes JF, Filion A, Bittencourt H, Silva W, et al. Association of drug metabolism gene polymorphisms with toxicities, graft-versus-host disease and survival after HLA-identical sibling hematopoietic stem cell transplantation for patients with leukemia. Leukemia 2009; 23:545&#x2013;556.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brummaier T, Pohanka E, Studnicka-Benke A, Pieringer H. Using cyclophosphamide in inflammatory rheumatic diseases. Eur J Intern Med 2013; 24:590&#x2013;596.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le Guenno G, Mahr A, Pagnoux C, Dhote R, Guillevin L; French Vasculitis Study Group. Incidence and predictors of urotoxic adverse events in cyclophosphamide-treated patients with systemic necrotizing vasculitides. Arthritis Rheum 2011; 63:1435&#x2013;1445.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>