<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37610115</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>24</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2376-1032</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>29</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of managed care &amp; specialty pharmacy</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Manag Care Spec Pharm</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Clinical and economic characterization of mild, moderate, and severe systemic lupus erythematosus: Real-world observation across payer channels in the United States.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1010</StartPage><EndPage>1020</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1010-1020</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.18553/jmcp.2023.29.9.1010</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText><b>BACKGROUND:</b> Systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) is a chronic autoimmune disease affecting as many as 322,000 people in the United States. Because of heterogeneity in both disease course and clinical manifestations, it is critical to identify a prevalent SLE population that includes patients with moderate or severe disease. Additionally, differences in the clinical and economic burden of SLE may exist across payer channels, yet to date this has not been reported in any previous studies. <b>OBJECTIVE:</b> To characterize the clinical and economic burden of SLE across disease severity and payer channels. <b>METHODS:</b> This retrospective study included patients from Merative MarketScan Commercial, Medicare Supplemental, and Medicaid databases from 2013 to 2020 (Commercial/Medicare) or 2013 to 2019 (Medicaid), with at least 1 inpatient or at least 2 outpatient SLE claims and no invalid steroid claims. The index date was a random SLE claim with at least 12 months of disease history. Patients were continuously enrolled 1 year pre-index (baseline) and 1 year post-index and classified with mild, moderate, or severe disease using a published algorithm. Baseline demographics, clinical characteristics, flares, and utilization/costs were compared across disease severity. <b>RESULTS:</b> 22,385 Commercial, 2,035 Medicare, and 8,083 Medicaid patients had SLE. Most Medicaid patients (51.1%) had severe disease. Comorbidity scores increased with disease severity (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.001). 30.7% of Commercial, 34.1% Medicare, and 51.3% Medicaid patients had opioids, which increased with disease severity (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.001). All-cause costs ranged from 1.8- to 2.3-fold for moderate vs mild and 4.2- to 6.5-fold for severe vs mild. Outpatient medical costs accounted for the highest proportion of all-cause costs, except Medicaid patients with severe disease, for whom inpatient costs were highest. Mean (SD) SLE-related annual costs were $23,030 (43,304) vs $1,738 (4,427) in severe vs mild for Commercial, $12,264 (31,896) vs $2,024 (4,998) for Medicare, and $7,572 (27,719) vs $787 (3,797) for Medicaid (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.001). For patients with severe disease in Medicaid, 16.5% and 60.1% had inpatient and emergency department (ED) visits, respectively, vs 10.3% and 26.5% Commercial vs 10.6% and 24.6% Medicare. Mean [SD] flares per year in the baseline period increased from 2.5 [1.7] in mild to 4.6 [1.9] in severe for Commercial, 3.2 [1.9] to 5.0 [2.1] for Medicare, and 2.0 [1.6] to 4.5 [2.0] for Medicaid. <b>CONCLUSIONS:</b> Patients with severe SLE experienced more comorbidities, flares, and utilization/costs. Outpatient costs were the largest driver of all-cause costs for Commercial and Medicare (and Medicaid for mild to moderate SLE). Medicaid beneficiaries had the highest rate of severe SLE, highest use of ED and inpatient services, and highest oral corticosteroid and opioid use but the lowest utilization of disease-modifying treatments. Results demonstrate an unmet need in SLE treatment, especially among patients with moderate to severe disease or Medicaid coverage. <b>DISCLOSURES:</b> This study was funded by AstraZeneca. Drs Wu and Bryant are current employees of AstraZeneca and may own stock and/or options. At the time of the study, Ms Perry and Mr Tkacz were employed by IBM Watson Health, which received funding from AstraZeneca to conduct this study.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Sandra Sze-Jung</ForeName><Initials>SS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>AstraZeneca, Wilmington, DE.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Perry</LastName><ForeName>Allison</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>IBM Watson Health, Cambridge, MA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tkacz</LastName><ForeName>Joseph</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>IBM Watson Health, Cambridge, MA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bryant</LastName><ForeName>Gary</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>AstraZeneca, Wilmington, DE.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Manag Care Spec Pharm</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101644425</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2376-0540</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014481" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">United States</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006278" MajorTopicYN="Y">Medicare</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008484" MajorTopicYN="N">Medicaid</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007297" MajorTopicYN="N">Inpatients</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37610115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10508840</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18553/jmcp.2023.29.9.1010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Cojocaru M, Cojocaru IM, Silosi I, et al. . Manifestations of systemic lupus erythematosus. Maedica (Bucur). 2011;6(4):330-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3391953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22879850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stojan G, Petri M. Epidemiology of systemic lupus erythematosus: An update. Curr Opin Rheumatol. 2018;30(2):144-50. doi:10.1097/BOR.0000000000000480</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6026543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29251660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Carrasco M, Mendoza Pinto C, Sol&#xed;s Poblano JC, et al. . Systemic lupus erythematosus. In: Anaya JM, Shoenfeld Y, Rojas-Villarraga A, et al., eds. Autoimmunity: From bench to bedside. El Rosario University Press; 2013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29087650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bello GA, Brown MA, Kelly JA, et al. . Development and validation of a simple lupus severity index using ACR criteria for classification of SLE. Lupus Sci Med. 2016;3(1):e000136. doi:10.1136/lupus-2015-000136</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4800735</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27026812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yildirim-Toruner C, Diamond B. Current and novel therapeutics in the treatment of systemic lupus erythematosus. J Allergy Clin Immunol. 2011;127(2):303-12; quiz 13-4. doi:10.1016/j.jaci.2010.12.1087</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3053574</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21281862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah M, Chaudhari S, McLaughlin TP, et al. . Cumulative burden of oral corticosteroid adverse effects and the economic implications of corticosteroid use in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. Clin Ther. 2013;35(4):486-97. doi:10.1016/j.clinthera.2013.03.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23587268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Birt JA, Wu J, Griffing K, et al. . Corticosteroid dosing and opioid use are high in patients with SLE and remain elevated after belimumab initiation: A retrospective claims database analysis. Lupus Sci Med. 2020;7(1) doi:10.1136/lupus-2020-000435</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7759957</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33361460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Somers EC, Lee J, Hassett AL, et al. . Prescription opioid use in patients with and without systemic lupus erythematosus &#x2013; Michigan Lupus Epidemiology and Surveillance Program, 2014-2015. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2019;68(38):819-24. doi:10.15585/mmwr.mm6838a2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6762189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31557148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murimi-Worstell IB, Lin DH, Kan H, et al. . Healthcare utilization and costs of systemic lupus erythematosus by disease severity in the United States. J Rheumatol. 2021;48(3):385-93. doi:10.3899/jrheum.191187</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32611669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang M, Near AM, Desta B, et al. . Disease and economic burden increase with systemic lupus erythematosus severity 1 year before and after diagnosis: A real-world cohort study, United States, 2004-2015. Lupus Sci Med. 2021;8(1) doi:10.1136/lupus-2021-000503</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8442098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34521733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hammond ER, Desta B, Near AM, et al. . Frequency, severity and costs of flares increase with disease severity in newly diagnosed systemic lupus erythematosus: A real-world cohort study, United States, 2004-2015. Lupus Sci Med. 2021;8(1) doi:10.1136/lupus-2021-000504</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8461688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34556546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garris C, Shah M, Farrelly E. The prevalence and burden of systemic lupus erythematosus in a medicare population: Retrospective analysis of medicare claims. Cost Eff Resour Alloc. 2015;13:9. doi:10.1186/s12962-015-0034-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4445996</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26019689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elixhauser A, Steiner C, Harris DR, et al. . Comorbidity measures for use with administrative data. Med Care. 1998;36(1):8-27. doi:10.1097/00005650-199801000-00004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9431328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ward MM. Development and testing of a systemic lupus-specific risk adjustment index for in-hospital mortality. J Rheumatol. 2000;27(6):1408-13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10852262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garris C, Jhingran P, Bass D, et al. . Healthcare utilization and cost of systemic lupus erythematosus in a US managed care health plan. J Med Econ. 2013;16(5):667-77. doi:10.3111/13696998.2013.778270</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23425294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furst DE, Clarke A, Fernandes AW, et al. . Resource utilization and direct medical costs in adult systemic lupus erythematosus patients from a commercially insured population. Lupus. 2013;22(3):268-78. doi:10.1177/0961203312474087</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23340996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li T, Carls GS, Panopalis P, et al. . Long-term medical costs and resource utilization in systemic lupus erythematosus and lupus nephritis: A five-year analysis of a large medicaid population. Arthritis Rheum. 2009;61(6):755-63. doi:10.1002/art.24545</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19479688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwarting A, Friedel H, Garal-Pantaler E, et al. . The burden of systemic lupus erythematosus in Germany: Incidence, prevalence, and healthcare resource utilization. Rheumatol Ther. 2021;8(1):375-93. doi:10.1007/s40744-021-00277-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7991067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33544369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>