<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">37682181</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>11</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-5964</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>102</Volume><Issue>36</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>08</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Medicine (Baltimore)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Survival and prognosis analysis of systemic lupus erythematosus patients with pulmonary hypertension: A systematic review and meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e34947</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e34947</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e34947</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MD.0000000000034947</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The study aimed to evaluate survival rates and prognosis in systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) patients with pulmonary hypertension (PH) using meta-analysis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">PubMed, EMBASE, Cochrane central register of controlled trials, China National Knowledge Infrastructure, China Science and Technology Journal Database, Wan-Fang Database, and Chinese biomedical database were searched. Information and data were screened and extracted by 2 researchers. The obtained data were analyzed using the R software meta package. Quality assessment was conducted using Newcastle-Ottawa Scale. The causes of heterogeneity were analyzed using subgroup analysis and sensitivity analysis. Publication bias was evaluated using Begger funnel plots and Egger test.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The search strategy yielded a total of 21 studies involving 875 patients included in the final analysis. The pooled 1-, 3- and 5-year survival rates of patients with SLE-PH were 0.9020 (95%CI: 0.8576; 0.9397), 0.8363 (96%CI: 0.7813; 0.8852), 0.7301 (95%CI: 0.6327; 0.8181). The 1-, 3- and 5-year survival rates of echocardiography subgroup were 0.9000 (95%CI: 0.8480; 0.9551), 0.8435 (95%CI: 0.7744; 0.9187), 0.6795 (95%CI: 0.5746; 0.8035), respectively; and there were 0.9174 (95%CI: 0.8951; 0.9402), 0.8529 (95%CI: 0.8255; 0.8812), 0.7757 (95%CI: 0.7409; 0.8121) at right heart catheterization subgroup in the meantime. Multivariate analysis for predicting mortality in SLE-PH patients revealed that diminishing left ventricular ejection fraction, New York Heart Association classification, lupus nephritis, lower cardiac index, and higher red blood cell distribution width level were significantly associated with a higher mortality rate. Treatment with huge doses of cyclophosphamide, tricuspid annular plane systolic excursion/pulmonary artery systolic pressure, and Raynaud phenomenon signaled favorable outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The 1-, 3-, and 5-year survival rates of SLE-PH patients in recent years (0.9020, 0.8363, 0.7301) were estimated in this study. SLE-PH patients diagnosed by echocardiography have a worse long-term prognosis than those diagnosed by right heart catheterization. Studies after 2015 have shown significantly better survival than earlier studies.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 the Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Jianguo</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shandong University of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Jinan, Shandong, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Fuyu</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shandong University of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Jinan, Shandong, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Xinpeng</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Affiliated Hospital of Shandong University of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Jinan, Shandong, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sun</LastName><ForeName>Yuying</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shandong University of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Jinan, Shandong, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lun</LastName><ForeName>Xueping</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shandong University of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Jinan, Shandong, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cao</LastName><ForeName>Jiaojiao</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shandong University of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Jinan, Shandong, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fan</LastName><ForeName>Bing</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0000-5218-0339</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Affiliated Hospital of Shandong University of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Jinan, Shandong, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Medicine (Baltimore)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>2985248R</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0025-7974</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006976" MajorTopicYN="Y">Hypertension, Pulmonary</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013318" MajorTopicYN="N">Stroke Volume</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016277" MajorTopicYN="N">Ventricular Function, Left</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011379" MajorTopicYN="N">Prognosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors have no funding and conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37682181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10489205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000034947</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005792-202309080-00059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ruopp NF, Cockrill BA. Diagnosis and treatment of pulmonary arterial hypertension: a review. JAMA. 2022;327:1379&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35412560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frost A, Badesch D, Gibbs JSR, et al. . Diagnosis of pulmonary hypertension. Eur Respir J. 2019;53:1801904.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6351333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30545972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiriakidou M, Ching CL. Systemic lupus erythematosus. Ann Intern Med. 2020;172:IITC81&#x2013;ITC96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32479157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stojan G, Petri M. Epidemiology of systemic lupus erythematosus: an update. Curr Opin Rheumatol. 2018;30:144&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6026543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29251660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung SM, Lee CK, Lee EY, et al. . Clinical aspects of pulmonary hypertension in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus and in patients with idiopathic pulmonary arterial hypertension. Clin Rheumatol. 2006;25:866&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16496078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hochberg MC. Updating the American College of Rheumatology revised criteria for the classification of systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Rheum. 1997;40:1725.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9324032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan EM, Cohen AS, Fries JF, et al. . The 1982 revised criteria for the classification of systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Rheum. 1982;25:1271&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7138600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gali&#xe8; N, Humbert M, Vachiery JL, et al. . 2015 ESC/ERS Guidelines for the diagnosis and treatment of pulmonary hypertension: the joint task force for the diagnosis and treatment of pulmonary hypertension of the European Society of Cardiology (ESC) and the European Respiratory Society (ERS): endorsed by: Association for European Paediatric and Congenital Cardiology (AEPC), International Society for Heart and Lung Transplantation (ISHLT). Eur Heart J. 2016;37:67&#x2013;119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26320113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwarzer G, Carpenter JR, R&#xfc;cker G. Meta-Analysis with R. Switzerland: Springer International Publishing; 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen DY, Liang LQ, Zhan ZP, et al. . An initial study of potential clinical factors associated with prognosis in systemic lupus erythematosus with pulmonary arteria. China Clin Prac Med. 2008;2:6&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qu JG, Qian JY, Huang C, et al. . Association of red blood cell distribution width with prognosis in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus associated pulmonary arterial hypertension. Chin J Allerg Clin Immunol. 2021;15:7&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan LJ, Li SS, Wang Y, et al. . Characteristics and survival analysis of patients with connective tissus diseases-associated pulmonary arterial hypertension. J Zhengzhou Univ (Med Sci). 2022;57:609&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang JL, Ren ZF, Luo H. Clinical characteristics and prognostic risk factors of connective tissue disorders associated pulmonary arterial hypertension. J Chongqing Med Univ. 2022;47:745&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren YL, Ding X, Zhang L. Characteristics and prognosis of pulmonary arterial hypertension in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. J Today Health. 2014;13:29&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen K, Kearney K, Strange G, et al. . Baseline characteristics and long-term survival of systemic lupus erythematosus-associated pulmonary arterial hypertension: a PHSANZ registry analysis. Respirology. 2021;26(SUPPL 2):136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan J, Lei L, Zhao C, et al. . Clinical characteristics and survival of patients with three major connective tissue diseases associated with pulmonary hypertension: a study from China. Exp Therap Med. 2021;22:3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8280713</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34306194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hao YJ, Jiang X, Zhou W, et al. . Connective tissue disease-associated pulmonary arterial hypertension in Chinese patients. Eur Respir J. 2014;44:963&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24791829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Condliffe R, Kiely DG, Peacock AJ, et al. . Connective tissue disease-associated pulmonary arterial hypertension in the modern treatment era. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2009;179:151&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18931333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim JS, Kim D, Joo YB, et al. . Factors associated with development and mortality of pulmonary hypertension in systemic lupus erythematosus patients. Lupus. 2018;27:1769&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30028258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen HA, Hsu TC, Yang SC, et al. . Incidence and survival impact of pulmonary arterial hypertension among patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: a nationwide cohort study. Arthr Res Ther. 2019;21:82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6438012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30917868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qian J, Li M, Zhang X, et al. . Long-term prognosis of patients with systemic lupus erythematosus-associated pulmonary arterial hypertension: CSTAR-PAH cohort study. Eur Respir J. 2019;53:800081.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30635295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo X, Lai J, Wang H, et al. . Predictive value of non-invasive right ventricle to pulmonary circulation coupling in systemic lupus erythematosus patients with pulmonary arterial hypertension. Eur Heart J Cardiovasc Imag. 2021;22:111&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31872222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hachulla E, Jais X, Cinquetti G, et al. . Pulmonary arterial hypertension associated with systemic lupus erythematosus: results from the french pulmonary hypertension registry. Chest. 2018;153:143&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28851621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Min HK, Lee JH, Jung SM, et al. . Pulmonary hypertension in systemic lupus erythematosus: an independent predictor of patient survival. Korean J Intern Med. 2015;30:232&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4351331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25750566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cefle A, Inanc M, Sayarlioglu M, et al. . Pulmonary hypertension in systemic lupus erythematosus: relationship with antiphospholipid antibodies and severe disease outcome. Rheumatol Int. 2011;31:183&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20012052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y, Guo L, Li Y, et al. . Severe pulmonary arterial hypertension secondary to lupus in the emergency department: proactive intense care associated with a better short-term survival. Int J Rheum Dis. 2015;18:331&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24946184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang KY, Jeon CH, Choi SJ, et al. . Survival and prognostic factors in patients with connective tissue disease-associated pulmonary hypertension diagnosed by echocardiography: results from a Korean nationwide registry. Int J Rheum Dis. 2017;20:1227&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26214170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Funauchi M, Shimadzu H, Tamaki C, et al. . Survival study by organ disorders in 306 Japanese patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: results from a single center. Rheumatol Int. 2007;27:243&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16944153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang JFYLYZX, Author A, Guangdong Provincial People&#x2019;s H, et al. . The prognosis of two distinct clinical phenotypes of SLE-PAH. Ann Rheum Dis. 2020;79(Suppl 1):1063.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Humbert M, Kovacs G, Hoeper MM, et al. . 2022 ESC/ERS Guidelines for the diagnosis and treatment of pulmonary hypertension. Eur Heart J. 2022;43:3618&#x2013;731.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36017548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qian J, Wang Y, Huang C, et al. . Survival and prognostic factors of systemic lupus erythematosus-associated pulmonary arterial hypertension: a PRISMA-compliant systematic review and meta-analysis. Autoimmun Rev. 2016;15:250&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26640159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher MR, Forfia PR, Chamera E, et al. . Accuracy of Doppler echocardiography in the hemodynamic assessment of pulmonary hypertension. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2009;179:615&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2720125</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19164700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galie N, Hoeper MM, Humbert M, et al. . Guidelines for the diagnosis and treatment of pulmonary hypertension: The Task Force for the Diagnosis and Treatment of Pulmonary Hypertension of the European Society of Cardiology (ESC) and the European Respiratory Society (ERS), endorsed by the International Society of Heart and Lung Transplantation (ISHLT). Eur Heart J. 2009;30:2493&#x2013;537.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19713419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Working Group on Pulmonary Vascular Diseases of Chinese Society of Cardiology of Chinese Medical Association, Editorial Board of Chinese Journal of Cardiology. Chinese guidelines for the diagnosis and treatment of pulmonary hypertension 2018. Chin J Cardiol. 2018;46:933&#x2013;64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hassoun PM. Pulmonary arterial hypertension. N Engl J Med. 2021;385:2361&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34910865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vonk MC, Vandecasteele E, van Dijk AP. Pulmonary hypertension in connective tissue diseases, new evidence and challenges. Eur J Clin Invest. 2021;51:e13453.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7988614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33216992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lang RM, Badano LP, Mor-Avi V, et al. . Recommendations for cardiac chamber quantification by echocardiography in adults: an update from the American Society of Echocardiography and the European Association of Cardiovascular Imaging. J Am Soc Echocardiogr. 2015;28:1&#x2013;39.e14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25559473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrara F, Zhou X, Gargani L, et al. . Echocardiography in pulmonary arterial hypertension. Curr Cardiol Rep. 2019;21:22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30828743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xfc;bbe-Tena C, Gallegos-Nava S, M&#xe1;rquez-Velasco R, et al. . Pulmonary hypertension in systemic lupus erythematosus: echocardiography-based definitions predict 6-year survival. Rheumatology (Oxford, England). 2014;53:1256&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24599923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#x2019;Alto M, Bossone E, Opotowsky AR, et al. . Strengths and weaknesses of echocardiography for the diagnosis of pulmonary hypertension. Int J Cardiol. 2018;263:177&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29655950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>