<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">31336405</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1460-9568</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>50</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2019</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The European journal of neuroscience</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Neurosci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>In vitro evidence consistent with an interaction between wild-type and mutant SOD1 protein associated with canine degenerative myelopathy.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>3896</StartPage><EndPage>3905</EndPage><MedlinePgn>3896-3905</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/ejn.14526</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Canine degenerative myelopathy (DM) is a progressive neurological disorder that may be considered to be a large animal model for specific forms of the fatal human disease, familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (fALS). DM is associated with a c118G&gt;A mutation of the superoxide dismutase 1 (Sod1) gene, and a significant proportion of cases are inherited in an autosomal recessive manner in contrast to the largely, but not exclusively, dominant mode of inheritance in fALS. The consensus view is that these Sod1/SOD1 mutations result in a toxic gain of function but the mechanisms remain unclear. Here we used an in vitro neuroblastoma cell line transfection system to monitor wild-type and mutant forms of SOD1 fusion proteins containing either a Cherry or an enhanced green fluorescent protein (EGFP) tag. These fusion proteins retained SOD1 enzymatic activity on a native gel assay system. We demonstrate that SOD1 aggregate density is significantly higher in DM transfectants compared to wild-type. In addition, we show by co-immunoprecipitation and confocal microscopy, evidence for a potential interaction between wild-type and mutant forms of SOD1 in co-transfected cells. While in vitro studies have shown SOD1 heterodimer formation in fALS models, this is the first report for DM SOD1. Therefore, despite for the majority of cases there is a difference in the mode of inheritance between fALS and DM, a similar interaction between wild-type and mutant SOD1 forms can occur. Clarifying the role of SOD1 in DM may also be of benefit to understanding the role of SOD1 in fALS.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2019 Federation of European Neuroscience Societies and John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Qi</LastName><ForeName>Yao</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Veterinary Medicine, College of Medical, Veterinary and Life Science, University of Glasgow, Scotland, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Montague</LastName><ForeName>Paul</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Infection, Immunity and Inflammation, College of Medical, Veterinary and Life Science (MVLS), University of Glasgow, Glasgow, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Loney</LastName><ForeName>Colin</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MRC, Centre for Virus Research, MVLS, University of Glasgow, Glasgow, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Campbell</LastName><ForeName>Clare</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Infection, Immunity and Inflammation, College of Medical, Veterinary and Life Science (MVLS), University of Glasgow, Glasgow, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shafie</LastName><ForeName>Intan N F</ForeName><Initials>INF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Veterinary Clinical Studies, Faculty of Veterinary Medicine, University Putra Malaysia, Serdang, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Anderson</LastName><ForeName>Thomas J</ForeName><Initials>TJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Veterinary Medicine, College of Medical, Veterinary and Life Science, University of Glasgow, Scotland, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McLaughlin</LastName><ForeName>Mark</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5317-2090</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Veterinary Medicine, College of Medical, Veterinary and Life Science, University of Glasgow, Scotland, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>MC_UU_12014/6</GrantID><Acronym>MRC_</Acronym><Agency>Medical Research Council</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2019</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>France</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Neurosci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8918110</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0953-816X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C000606290">SOD1 protein, human</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C485184">enhanced green fluorescent protein</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>147336-22-9</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D049452">Green Fluorescent Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 1.15.1.1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D013482">Superoxide Dismutase</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 1.15.1.1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000072105">Superoxide Dismutase-1</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><SupplMeshList><SupplMeshName Type="Disease" UI="C531617">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis 1</SupplMeshName></SupplMeshList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="Y">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002460" MajorTopicYN="N">Cell Line</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004195" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Models, Animal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004285" MajorTopicYN="N">Dogs</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D049452" MajorTopicYN="N">Green Fluorescent Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009154" MajorTopicYN="N">Mutation</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="Y">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013118" MajorTopicYN="N">Spinal Cord Diseases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013482" MajorTopicYN="N">Superoxide Dismutase</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="Y">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000072105" MajorTopicYN="N">Superoxide Dismutase-1</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="Y">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">aggregates</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">canine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cell toxicity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fALS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">superoxide dismutase</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2018</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2019</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2019</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31336405</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ejn.14526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Andersen, P. M., Nilsson, P., Ala-Hurula, V., Keranen, M. L., Tarvainen, I., Haltia, T., &#x2026; Marklund, S. L. (1995). Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis associated with homozygosity for an Asp90Ala mutation in CuZn-superoxide dismutase. Nature Genetics, 10, 61-66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Averill, D. R. Jr (1973). Degenerative myelopathy in the aging German Shepherd dog: Clinical and pathologic findings. Journal of the American Veterinary Medical Association, 162, 1045-1051.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Awano, T., Johnson, G. S., Wade, C. M., Katz, M. L., Johnson, G. C., Taylor, J. F., &#x2026; Coates, J. R. (2009). Genome-wide association analysis reveals a SOD1 mutation in canine degenerative myelopathy that resembles amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 106, 2794-2799.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banci, L., Bertini, I., Cantini, F., Kozyreva, T., Massagni, C., Palumaa, P., &#x2026; Zovo, K. (2012). Human superoxide dismutase 1 (hSOD1) maturation through interaction with human copper chaperone for SOD1 (hCCS). Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 109, 13555-13560.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brotherton, T. E., Li, Y., &amp; Glass, J. D. (2013). Cellular toxicity of mutant SOD1 protein is linked to an easily soluble, non-aggregated form in vitro. Neurobiology of Diseases, 49, 49-56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bunton-Stasyshyn, R. K., Saccon, R. A., Fratta, P., &amp; Fisher, E. M. (2015). SOD1 function and its implications for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis pathology: new and renascent themes. Neuroscientist, 21, 519-529.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coates, J. R., &amp; Wininger, F. A. (2010). Canine degenerative myelopathy. Veterinary Clinics of North America: Small Animal Practice, 40, 929-950.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crisp, M. J., Beckett, J., Coates, J. R., &amp; Miller, T. M. (2013). Canine degenerative myelopathy: Biochemical characterization of superoxide dismutase 1 in the first naturally occurring non-human amyotrophic lateral sclerosis model. Experimental Neurology, 248, 1-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Draper, Z., Windley, C., Maile, R. J., &amp; Piercy, R. (2016). Species-specific differences in cellular aggregation and localisation of virally transduced mutant and normal canine and equine superoxide dismutase 1 (sod1) proteins. Journal of Veterinary Internal Medicine, 30(6), p1929-p1955.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gertsman, I., Wuu, J., McAlonis-Downes, M., Ghassemian, M., Ling, K., Rigo, F., &#x2026; Da, C. S. (2019). An endogenous peptide marker differentiates SOD1 stability and facilitates pharmacodynamic monitoring in SOD1 amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. JCI Insight, 4, e122768.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griffiths, I. R., &amp; Duncan, I. D. (1975). Chronic degenerative radiculomyelopathy in the dog. Journal of Small Animal Practice, 16, 461-471.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hand, C. K., Mayeux-Portas, V., Khoris, J., Briolotti, V., Clavelou, P., Camu, W., &amp; Rouleau, G. A. (2001). Compound heterozygous D90A and D96N SOD1 mutations in a recessive amyotrophic lateral sclerosis family. Annals of Neurology, 49, 267-271.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helson, L., Das, S. K., &amp; Hajdu, S. I. (1975). Human neuroblastoma in nude mice. Cancer Research, 35, 2594-2599.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iannitti, T., Scarrott, J. M., Likhite, S., Coldicott, I. R. P., Lewis, K. E., Heath, P. R., &#x2026; Azzouz, M. (2018). Translating SOD1 gene silencing toward the clinic: A highly efficacious, off-target-free, and biomarker-supported strategy for fALS. Molecular Therapy - Nucleic Acids, 12, 75-88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ivansson, E. L., Megquier, K., Kozyrev, S. V., Muren, E., Korberg, I. B., Swofford, R., &#x2026; Lindblad-Toh, K. (2016). Variants within the SP110 nuclear body protein modify risk of canine degenerative myelopathy. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 113, E3091-E3100.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnston, P. E., Barrie, J. A., McCulloch, M. C., Anderson, T. J., &amp; Griffiths, I. R. (2000). Central nervous system pathology in 25 dogs with chronic degenerative radiculomyelopathy. Veterinary Record, 146, 629-633.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kobatake, Y., Sakai, H., Tsukui, T., Yamato, O., Kohyama, M., Sasaki, J., &#x2026; Kamishina, H. (2017). Localization of a mutant SOD1 protein in E40K-heterozygous dogs: Implications for non-cell-autonomous pathogenesis of degenerative myelopathy. Journal of the Neurological Sciences, 372, 369-378.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLaughlin, M., Barrie, J. A., Karim, S., Montague, P., Edgar, J. M., Kirkham, D., &#x2026; Griffiths, I. R. (2006). Processing of PLP in a model of Pelizaeus-Merzbacher disease/SPG2 due to the rumpshaker mutation. Glia, 53, 715-722.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLaughlin, M., Hunter, D. J., Thomson, C. E., Yool, D., Kirkham, D., Freer, A. A., &amp; Griffiths, I. R. (2002). Evidence for possible interactions between PLP and DM20 within the myelin sheath. Glia, 39, 31-36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakamae, S., Kobatake, Y., Suzuki, R., Tsukui, T., Kato, S., Yamato, O., &#x2026; Kamishina, H. (2015). Accumulation and aggregate formation of mutant superoxide dismutase 1 in canine degenerative myelopathy. Neuroscience, 303, 229-240.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nardone, R., Holler, Y., Taylor, A. C., Lochner, P., Tezzon, F., Golaszewski, S., &#x2026; Trinka, E. (2016). Canine degenerative myelopathy: A model of human amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Zoology (Jena), 119, 64-73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogawa, M., Uchida, K., Park, E. S., Kamishina, H., Sasaki, J., Chang, H. S., &#x2026; Nakayama, H. (2011). Immunohistochemical observation of canine degenerative myelopathy in two Pembroke Welsh Corgi dogs. Journal of Veterinary Medical Science, 73, 1275-1279.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogawa, M., Uchida, K., Yamato, O., Inaba, M., Uddin, M. M., &amp; Nakayama, H. (2014). Neuronal loss and decreased GLT-1 expression observed in the spinal cord of Pembroke Welsh Corgi dogs with canine degenerative myelopathy. Veterinary Pathology, 51, 591-602.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orrell, R. W. (2000). Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Copper/zinc superoxide dismutase (SOD1) gene mutations. Neuromuscular Disorders, 10, 63-68.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pasinelli, P., &amp; Brown, R. H. (2006). Molecular biology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Insights from genetics. Nature Reviews Neuroscience, 7, 710-723.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pfahler, S., Bachmann, N., Fechler, C., Lempp, C., Baumgartner, W., &amp; Distl, O. (2014). Degenerative myelopathy in a SOD1 compound heterozygous Bernese mountain dog. Animal Genetics, 45, 309-310.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pickles, S., &amp; Vande, V. C. (2012). Misfolded SOD1 and ALS: Zeroing in on mitochondria. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis, 13, 333-340.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proctor, E. A., Fee, L., Tao, Y., Redler, R. L., Fay, J. M., Zhang, Y., &#x2026; Dokholyan, N. V. (2016). Nonnative SOD1 trimer is toxic to motor neurons in a model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 113, 614-619.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prudencio, M., Durazo, A., Whitelegge, J. P., &amp; Borchelt, D. R. (2009). Modulation of mutant superoxide dismutase 1 aggregation by co-expression of wild-type enzyme. Journal of Neurochemistry, 108, 1009-1018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prudencio, M., Durazo, A., Whitelegge, J. P., &amp; Borchelt, D. R. (2010). An examination of wild-type SOD1 in modulating the toxicity and aggregation of ALS-associated mutant SOD1. Human Molecular Genetics, 19, 4774-4789.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prudencio, M., Hart, P. J., Borchelt, D. R., &amp; Andersen, P. M. (2009). Variation in aggregation propensities among ALS-associated variants of SOD1: Correlation to human disease. Human Molecular Genetics, 18, 3217-3226.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qualls, D. A., Crosby, K., Brown, H., &amp; Borchelt, D. R. (2013). An analysis of interactions between fluorescently-tagged mutant and wild-type SOD1 in intracellular inclusions. PLoS ONE, 8, e83981.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rakhit, R., &amp; Chakrabartty, A. (2006). Structure, folding, and misfolding of Cu, Zn superoxide dismutase in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Biochimica et Biophysica Acta, 1762, 1025-1037.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reaume, A. G., Elliott, J. L., Hoffman, E. K., Kowall, N. W., Ferrante, R. J., Siwek, D. F., &#x2026; Snider, W. D. (1996). Motor neurons in Cu/Zn superoxide dismutase-deficient mice develop normally but exhibit enhanced cell death after axonal injury. Nature Genetics, 13, 43-47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shafie, I. N., McLaughlin, M., Burchmore, R., Lim, M. A., Montague, P., Johnston, P. E., &#x2026; Anderson, T. J. (2014). The chaperone protein clusterin may serve as a cerebrospinal fluid biomarker for chronic spinal cord disorders in the dog. Cell Stress and Chaperones, 19, 311-320.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shelton, G. D., Johnson, G. C., O'Brien, D. P., Katz, M. L., Pesayco, J. P., Chang, B. J., &#x2026; Coates, J. R. (2012). Degenerative myelopathy associated with a missense mutation in the superoxide dismutase 1 (SOD1) gene progresses to peripheral neuropathy in Pembroke Welsh corgis and boxers. Journal of the Neurological Sciences, 318, 55-64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stevens, J.C., Chia, R., Hendriks, W.T., Bros-Facer, V., van Minnen, J., Martin, J.E., &#x2026; Fisher, E.M. (2010). Modification of superoxide dismutase 1 (SOD1) properties by a GFP tag-implications for research into amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). PLoS ONE, 5, e9541.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, L., Deng, H. X., Grisotti, G., Zhai, H., Siddique, T., &amp; Roos, R. P. (2009). Wild-type SOD1 overexpression accelerates disease onset of a G85R SOD1 mouse. Human Molecular Genetics, 18, 1642-1651.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weichert, A., Besemer, A. S., Liebl, M., Hellmann, N., Koziollek-Drechsler, I., Ip, P., &#x2026; Clement, A. M. (2014). Wild-type Cu/Zn superoxide dismutase stabilizes mutant variants by heterodimerization. Neurobiology of Diseases, 62, 479-488.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weydert, C. J., &amp; Cullen, J. J. (2010). Measurement of superoxide dismutase, catalase and glutathione peroxidase in cultured cells and tissue. Nature Protocols, 5, 51-66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wininger, F. A., Zeng, R., Johnson, G. S., Katz, M. L., Johnson, G. C., Bush, W. W., &#x2026; Coates, J. R. (2011). Degenerative myelopathy in a Bernese Mountain Dog with a novel SOD1 missense mutation. Journal of Veterinary Internal Medicine, 25, 1166-1170.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Witan, H., Gorlovoy, P., Kaya, A. M., Koziollek-Drechsler, I., Neumann, H., Behl, C., &amp; Clement, A. M. (2009). Wild-type Cu/Zn superoxide dismutase (SOD1) does not facilitate, but impedes the formation of protein aggregates of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis causing mutant SOD1. Neurobiology of Diseases, 36, 331-342.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Witan, H., Kern, A., Koziollek-Drechsler, I., Wade, R., Behl, C., &amp; Clement, A. M. (2008). Heterodimer formation of wild-type and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-causing mutant Cu/Zn-superoxide dismutase induces toxicity independent of protein aggregation. Human Molecular Genetics, 17, 1373-1385.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, G., Ayers, J. I., Roberts, B. L., Brown, H., Fromholt, S., Green, C., &amp; Borchelt, D. R. (2015). Direct and indirect mechanisms for wild-type SOD1 to enhance the toxicity of mutant SOD1 in bigenic transgenic mice. Human Molecular Genetics, 24, 1019-1035.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng, R., Coates, J. R., Johnson, G. C., Hansen, L., Awano, T., Kolicheski, A., &#x2026; Johnson, G. S. (2014). Breed distribution of SOD1 alleles previously associated with canine degenerative myelopathy. Journal of Veterinary Internal Medicine, 28, 515-521.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu, C., Beck, M. V., Griffith, J. D., Deshmukh, M., &amp; Dokholyan, N. V. (2018). Large SOD1 aggregates, unlike trimeric SOD1, do not impact cell viability in a model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 115, 4661-4665.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>