<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">31330055</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-4598</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>60</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2019</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Muscle &amp; nerve</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Muscle Nerve</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Parameters derived from compound muscle action potential scan for discriminating amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-related denervation.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>400</StartPage><EndPage>408</EndPage><MedlinePgn>400-408</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/mus.26644</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION">The objective of this study was to determine compound muscle action potential (CMAP) scan parameters and MScanFit motor unit number estimation (MUNE) in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) and to compare the results in the abductor pollicis brevis (APB) to those in the abductor digiti minimi (ADM).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">CMAP scans were recorded from the APB and ADM in 35 patients with ALS and 21 controls. MScanFit MUNE, neurophysiological index (NI), step%, returner%, and D50 were calculated.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">CMAP scan parameters including the returner%, MScanFit MUNE, and NI can distinguish ALS with high sensitivity and specificity. The electrophysiological parameters, with the exception of D50 (the number of largest consecutive differences of recorded responses generating 50% of maximum CMAP), showed more pronounced changes in the APB than in the ADM, even though most of the patients had normal APB/ADM amplitude ratios.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION">CMAP scan parameters and MScanFit MUNE can be used in the evaluation of denervation and reinnervation and may herald the "split hand" in ALS.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2019 Wiley Periodicals, Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sirin</LastName><ForeName>N Gorkem</ForeName><Initials>NG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Istanbul Faculty of Medicine, Istanbul University, Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oguz Akarsu</LastName><ForeName>Emel</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Istanbul Faculty of Medicine, Istanbul University, Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kocasoy Orhan</LastName><ForeName>Elif</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Istanbul Faculty of Medicine, Istanbul University, Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Erbas</LastName><ForeName>Bahar</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Istanbul Faculty of Medicine, Istanbul University, Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Artug</LastName><ForeName>Tugrul</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Electrical and Electronics Engineering, Istanbul Arel University, Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dede</LastName><ForeName>H Ozlem</ForeName><Initials>HO</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Istanbul Faculty of Medicine, Istanbul University, Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Baslo</LastName><ForeName>M Baris</ForeName><Initials>MB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Istanbul Faculty of Medicine, Istanbul University, Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Idrisoglu</LastName><ForeName>Halil A</ForeName><Initials>HA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Istanbul Faculty of Medicine, Istanbul University, Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oge</LastName><ForeName>A Emre</ForeName><Initials>AE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Istanbul Faculty of Medicine, Istanbul University, Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2019</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Muscle Nerve</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7803146</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0148-639X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000200" MajorTopicYN="N">Action Potentials</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016022" MajorTopicYN="N">Case-Control Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006225" MajorTopicYN="Y">Hand</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000294" MajorTopicYN="Y">innervation</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009416" MajorTopicYN="N">Nerve Regeneration</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CMAP scan</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">MScanFit MUNE</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nerve excitability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">split hand</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">stimulus-response curve</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2019</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2019</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31330055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.26644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Gooch CL, Doherty TJ, Chan KM, et al. Motor unit number estimation: a technology and literature review. Muscle Nerve. 2014;50(6):884-893.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Barkhaus PE, Nandedkar SD, Swash M. Motor unit number estimation (MUNE): where are we now? Clin Neurophysiol. 2018;129(8):1507-1516.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Costa J, Swash M. Clinical trials in ALS: a review of the role of clinical and neurophysiological measurements. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord. 2005;6(4):202-212.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olney RK, Lomen-Hoerth C. Motor unit number estimation (MUNE): how may it contribute to the diagnosis of ALS? Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord. 2000;1(Suppl 2):S41-S44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gooch CL. The canaries in the coal mine: mune and munix in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 2017;56(2):183-184.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blok JH, Ruitenberg A, Maathuis EM, Visser GH. The electrophysiological muscle scan. Muscle Nerve. 2007;36(4):436-446.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henderson RD, Ridall GR, Pettitt AN, McCombe PA, Daube JR. The stimulus-response curve and motor unit variability in normal subjects and subjects with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 2006;34(1):34-43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maathuis EM, Drenthen J, van Doorn PA, Visser GH, Blok JH. The CMAP scan as a tool to monitor disease progression in ALS and PMA. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2013;14(3):217-223.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sleutjes BT, Montfoort I, Maathuis EM, et al. CMAP scan discontinuities: automated detection and relation to motor unit loss. Clin Neurophysiol. 2014;125(2):388-395.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Heyden J, van der Meer P, Birnie E, et al. Decreased excitability of the distal motor nerve of young patients with type 1 diabetes mellitus. Pediatr Diabetes. 2013;14(7):519-525.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobsen AB, Bostock H, Tankisi H. CMAP scan MUNE (MScan)-a novel motor unit number estimation (MUNE) method. J Vis Exp. 2018;136.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobsen AB, Bostock H, Tankisi H. Following disease progression in motor neuron disorders with 3 MUNE methods. Muscle Nerve. 2019;59(1):82-87.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bostock H. Estimating motor unit numbers from a CMAP scan. Muscle Nerve. 2016;53(6):889-896.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Swash M. Sensitivity of electrophysiological tests for upper and lower motor neuron dysfunction in ALS: a six-month longitudinal study. Muscle Nerve. 2010;41(2):208-211.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Swash M. Can selection of rapidly progressing patients shorten clinical trials in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis? Arch Neurol. 2006;63(4):557-560.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Scotto M, Lopes A, Swash M. Quantitating progression in ALS. Neurology. 2005;64(10):1783-1785.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheah BC, Vucic S, Krishnan AV, Boland RA, Kiernan MC. Neurophysiological index as a biomarker for ALS progression: validity of mixed effects models. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2011;12(1):33-38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Escorcio-Bezerra ML, Abrahao A, Nunes KF, et al. Motor unit number index and neurophysiological index as candidate biomarkers of presymptomatic motor neuron loss in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 2018;58(2):204-212.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S, Rutkove SB. Neurophysiological biomarkers in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Curr Opin Neurol. 2018;31(5):640-647.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilbourn AJ. The &#x2018;split hand syndrome&#x2019;. Muscle Nerve. 2000;23(1):138.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuwabara S, Mizobuchi K, Ogawara K, Hattori T. Dissociated small hand muscle involvement in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis detected by motor unit number estimates. Muscle Nerve. 1999;22(7):870-873.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Dengler R, Eisen A, et al. Electrodiagnostic criteria for diagnosis of ALS. Clin Neurophysiol. 2008;119(3):497-503.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum JM, Stambler N, Malta E, et al. The ALSFRS-R: a revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. BDNF ALS Study Group (Phase III). J Neurol Sci. 1999;169(1-2):13-21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vanhoutte EK, Faber CG, van Nes SI, et al. Modifying the Medical Research Council grading system through Rasch analyses. Brain. 2012;135(Pt 5):1639-1649.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hermans G, Clerckx B, Vanhullebusch T, et al. Interobserver agreement of Medical Research Council sum-score and handgrip strength in the intensive care unit. Muscle Nerve. 2012;45(1):18-25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bromberg MB. Consensus. In: Bromberg MB, ed. Motor Unit Number Estimation. Supplements to Clinical Neurophysiology. Vol 55. St Louis, MO: Elsevier; 2003:335-338.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuwabara S, Sonoo M, Komori T, et al. Dissociated small hand muscle atrophy in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: frequency, extent, and specificity. Muscle Nerve. 2008;37(4):426-430.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maathuis EM, Henderson RD, Drenthen J, et al. Optimal stimulation settings for CMAP scan registrations. J Brachial Plex Peripher Nerve Inj. 2012;7(1):4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drenthen J, Maathuis EM, Visser GH, van Doorn PA, Blok JH, Jacobs BC. Limb motor nerve dysfunction in Miller Fisher syndrome. J Peripher Nerv Syst. 2013;18(1):25-29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maathuis EM, Drenthen J, Visser GH, Blok JH. Reproducibility of the CMAP scan. J Electromyogr Kinesiol. 2011;21(3):433-437.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanai K, Shibuya K, Sato Y, et al. Motor axonal excitability properties are strong predictors for survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2012;83(7):734-738.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanai K, Kuwabara S, Misawa S, et al. Altered axonal excitability properties in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: impaired potassium channel function related to disease stage. Brain. 2006;129(Pt 4):953-962.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S, Kiernan MC. Axonal excitability properties in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Neurophysiol. 2006;117(7):1458-1466.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mogyoros I, Kiernan MC, Burke D, Bostock H. Strength-duration properties of sensory and motor axons in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain. 1998;121(Pt 5):851-859.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shibuya K, Misawa S, Nasu S, et al. Split hand syndrome in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: different excitability changes in the thenar and hypothenar motor axons. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2013;84(9):969-972.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai HJ, Chiang YW, Lee MJ. Motor and sensory axon excitability properties from the median and ulnar nerves and the effects of age on these properties. J Clin Neurophysiol. 2015;32(4):357-363.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murray JE, Jankelowitz SK. A comparison of the excitability of motor axons innervating the APB and ADM muscles. Clin Neurophysiol. 2011;122(11):2290-2293.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daube JR. Estimating the number of motor units in a muscle. J Clin Neurophysiol. 1995;12(6):585-594.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown WF, Milner-Brown HS. Some electrical properties of motor units and their effects on the methods of estimating motor unit numbers. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 1976;39(3):249-257.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hales JP, Lin CS, Bostock H. Variations in excitability of single human motor axons, related to stochastic properties of nodal sodium channels. J Physiol. 2004;559(Pt 3):953-964.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garg N, Howells J, Yiannikas C, et al. Motor unit remodelling in multifocal motor neuropathy: the importance of axonal loss. Clin Neurophysiol. 2017;128(10):2022-2028.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobsen AB, Kristensen RS, Witt A, et al. The utility of motor unit number estimation methods versus quantitative motor unit potential analysis in diagnosis of ALS. Clin Neurophysiol. 2018;129(3):646-653.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobsen AB, Bostock H, Fuglsang-Frederiksen A, et al. Reproducibility and sensitivity to motor unit loss in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, of a novel MUNE method: MScanFit MUNE. Clin Neurophysiol. 2017;128(7):1380-1388.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thakore NJ, Lapin BR, Pioro EP, Pooled Resource Open-Access ALSCTC. Trajectories of impairment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: insights from the Pooled Resource Open-Access ALS Clinical Trials cohort. Muscle Nerve. 2018;57(6):937-945.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McComas AJ, Fawcett PR, Campbell MJ, Sica RE. Electrophysiological estimation of the number of motor units within a human muscle. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 1971;34(2):121-131.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hansen S, Ballantyne JP. A quantitative electrophysiological study of motor neurone disease. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 1978;41(9):773-783.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bae JS, Sawai S, Misawa S, Kanai K, Isose S, Kuwabara S. Differences in excitability properties of FDI and ADM motor axons. Muscle Nerve. 2009;39(3):350-354.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cengiz B, Mercan M, Kuruoglu R. Spinal excitability changes do not influence the mechanisms of split-hand syndrome in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 2018;58(4):503-508.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weber M, Eisen A, Stewart H, Hirota N. The split hand in ALS has a cortical basis. J Neurol Sci. 2000;180(1-2):66-70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eisen A, Kuwabara S. The split hand syndrome in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2012;83(4):399-403.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim DG, Hong YH, Shin JY, et al. Split-hand phenomenon in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a motor unit number index study. Muscle Nerve. 2016;53(6):885-888.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schelhaas HJ, van de Warrenburg BP, Kremer HP, Zwarts MJ. The &#x2018;split hand&#x2019; phenomenon: evidence of a spinal origin. Neurology. 2003;61(11):1619-1620.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menon P, Kiernan MC, Vucic S. ALS pathophysiology: insights from the split-hand phenomenon. Clin Neurophysiol. 2014;125(1):186-193.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menon P, Kiernan MC, Vucic S. Cortical dysfunction underlies the development of the split-hand in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. PLoS One. 2014;9(1):e87124.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mogyoros I, Kiernan MC, Burke D. Strength-duration properties of human peripheral nerve. Brain. 1996;119(Pt 2):439-447.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Priori A, Cinnante C, Pesenti A, et al. Distinctive abnormalities of motor axonal strength-duration properties in multifocal motor neuropathy and in motor neurone disease. Brain. 2002;125(Pt 11):2481-2490.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Lopes A, Scotto M, Swash M. Reproducibility of neurophysiological and myometric measurement in the ulnar nerve-abductor digiti minimi system. Muscle Nerve. 2001;24(10):1391-1395.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menon P, Kiernan MC, Yiannikas C, Stroud J, Vucic S. Split-hand index for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Neurophysiol. 2013;124(2):410-416.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>