<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">31361627</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1473-6551</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>32</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2019</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Current opinion in neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Curr Opin Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Epidemiology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: an update of recent literature.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>771</StartPage><EndPage>776</EndPage><MedlinePgn>771-776</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/WCO.0000000000000730</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE OF REVIEW">The cause of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) remains unknown for most of the patients with the disease. Epidemiologic studies can help describe disease burden and examine its potential risk factors, providing thereby evidence base for future mechanistic studies. With this review, we aimed to provide a summary of epidemiologic studies published during the past 18 months, which studied the incidence and risk factors for ALS.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RECENT FINDINGS">An increasing incidence and prevalence of ALS continue to be reported from different parts of the world. Several previously studied risk factors are confirmed as causally related to ALS by Mendelian randomization analysis. The previously known prognostic indicators for ALS appear to be the same across populations.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUMMARY">Provided with the increasing number of patients diagnosed with ALS and the improved societal awareness of the disease, more resources should be allocated to the research and care of ALS. Population-based studies, especially population-based disease registers, should be the priorities in ALS research, and more data from outside Europe are needed in gaining a better global perspective of the disease.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Longinetti</LastName><ForeName>Elisa</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Epidemiology and Biostatistics, Karolinska Institutet, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fang</LastName><ForeName>Fang</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Curr Opin Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9319162</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1350-7540</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="Y">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005060" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Europe</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015994" MajorTopicYN="N">Incidence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015995" MajorTopicYN="N">Prevalence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012307" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31361627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6735526</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/WCO.0000000000000730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Longinetti E, Regodon Wallin A, Samuelsson K, et al. The Swedish motor neuron disease quality registry. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2018; 19:528&#x2013;537.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30296856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palese F, Sartori A, Verriello L, et al. Epidemiology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in Friuli-Venezia Giulia, North-Eastern Italy, 2002&#x2013;2014: a retrospective population-based study. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2019; 20:90&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30430867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benjaminsen E, Alstadhaug KB, Gulsvik M, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in Nordland County, Norway, 2000&#x2013;2015: prevalence, incidence, and clinical features. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2018; 19:522&#x2013;527.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30265157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jun KY, Park J, Oh KW, et al. Epidemiology of ALS in Korea using nationwide big data. J Neurol, Neurosurg, Psychiatry 2019; 90:395&#x2013;403.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6581156</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30409890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turgut N, Birgili O, Varol SaraCoglu G, et al. An epidemiologic investigation of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in Thrace, Turkey, 2006&#x2013;2010. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2019; 20:100&#x2013;106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30468083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou S, Zhou Y, Qian S, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in Beijing: epidemiologic features and prognosis from 2010 to 2015. Brain Behav 2018; 8:e01131.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6236245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30338660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leighton DJ, Newton J, Stephenson LJ, et al. Changing epidemiology of motor neurone disease in Scotland. J Neurol 2019; 266:817&#x2013;825.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30805795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rose L, McKim D, Leasa D, et al. Trends in incidence, prevalence, and mortality of neuromuscular disease in Ontario, Canada: a population-based retrospective cohort study (2003&#x2013;2014). PLoS One 2019; 14:e0210574.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6435115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30913206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim HJ, Oh KW, Kwon MJ, et al. Identification of mutations in Korean patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis using multigene panel testing. Neurobiol Aging 2016; 37:209.e9&#x2013;209.e16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26601740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwon MJ, Baek W, Ki CS, et al. Screening of the SOD1, FUS, TARDBP, ANG, and OPTN mutations in Korean patients with familial and sporadic ALS. Neurobiol Aging 2012; 33:1017.e17&#x2013;1017.e23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22244934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nelson LM, Topol B, Kaye W, et al. Estimation of the prevalence of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in the United States using national administrative healthcare data from 2002 to 2004 and capture-recapture methodology. Neuroepidemiology 2018; 51:149&#x2013;157.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6250049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30092573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehta P, Kaye W, Raymond J, et al. Prevalence of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: United States. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep 2018; 67:1285&#x2013;1289.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6289079</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30462626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakken O, Lindstrom JC, Tysnes OB, Holmoy T. Assessing amyotrophic lateral sclerosis prevalence in Norway from 2009 to 2015 from compulsory nationwide health registers. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2018; 19:303&#x2013;310.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29271248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhattacharya R, Harvey RA, Abraham K, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis among patients with a Medicare Advantage prescription drug plan: prevalence, survival and patient characteristics. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2019; 20:251&#x2013;259.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30892090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ingre C, Roos PM, Piehl F, et al. Risk factors for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Epidemiol 2015; 7:181&#x2013;193.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4334292</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25709501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Marchi F, Sarnelli MF, Solara V, et al. Depression and risk of cognitive dysfunctions in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neurol Scand 2019; 139:438&#x2013;445.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30712314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dickerson AS, Hansen J, Kioumourtzoglou MA, et al. Study of occupation and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in a Danish cohort. Occup Environ Med 2018; 75:630&#x2013;638.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6445390</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29941657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dorst J, Chen L, Rosenbohm A, et al. Prognostic factors in ALS: a comparison between Germany and China. J Neurol 2019; 266:1516&#x2013;1525.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30923935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goutman SA, Boss J, Patterson A, et al. High plasma concentrations of organic pollutants negatively impact survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol, Neurosurg, Psychiatry 2019; 90:907&#x2013;912.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6625908</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30760645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hodgkinson VL, Lounsberry J, Mirian A, et al. Provincial differences in the diagnosis and care of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Can J Neurol Sci 2018; 45:652&#x2013;659.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30430962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karanevich AG, Weisbrod LJ, Jawdat O, et al. Using automated electronic medical record data extraction to model ALS survival and progression. BMC Neurol 2018; 18:205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6295028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30547800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim JM, Park JH, Kim HS, et al. Epidemiology and diagnostic process of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis as distinct from myelopathy: 5-year cohort study of whole-population in South Korea. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2018; 19:547&#x2013;554.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30421999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moglia C, Calvo A, Grassano M, et al. Early weight loss in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: outcome relevance and clinical correlates in a population-based cohort. J Neurol, Neurosurg, Psychiatry 2019; 90:666&#x2013;673.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30630957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peters S, Visser AE, D&#x2019;Ovidio F, et al. Electric shock and extremely low-frequency magnetic field exposure and the risk of ALS: Euro-MOTOR. Am J Epidemiol 2019; 188:796&#x2013;805.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30649156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qadri S, Langefeld CD, Milligan C, et al. Racial differences in intervention rates in individuals with ALS: a case-control study. Neurology 2019; 92:e1969&#x2013;e1974.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6511079</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30918092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan M, Zaldivar Vaillant T, McLaughlin RL, et al. Comparison of the clinical and genetic features of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis across Cuban, Uruguayan and Irish clinic-based populations. J Neurol, Neurosurg, Psychiatry 2019; 90:659&#x2013;665.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30846540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korner S, Kammeyer J, Zapf A, et al. Influence of environment and lifestyle on incidence and progress of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in a German ALS population. Aging Dis 2019; 10:205&#x2013;216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6457054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31011473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#x2019;Ovidio F, Rooney JP, Visser AE, et al. Association between alcohol exposure and the risk of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in the Euro-MOTOR study. J Neurol, Neurosurg, Psychiatry 2019; 90:11&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30076269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luna J, Diagana M, Ait Aissa L, et al. Clinical features and prognosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in Africa: the TROPALS study. J Neurol, Neurosurg, Psychiatry 2019; 90:20&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30242088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimizu T, Nakayama Y, Matsuda C, et al. Prognostic significance of body weight variation after diagnosis in ALS: a single-centre prospective cohort study. J Neurol 2019; 266:1412&#x2013;1420.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30868220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seelen M, Toro Campos RA, Veldink JH, et al. Long-term air pollution exposure and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in Netherlands: a population-based case-control study. Environ Health Perspect 2017; 125:097023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5915195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29989551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pupillo E, Bianchi E, Chio A, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and food intake. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2018; 19:267&#x2013;274.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29268633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardiman O, Al-Chalabi A, Brayne C, et al. The changing picture of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: lessons from European registers. J Neurol, Neurosurg, Psychiatry 2017; 88:557&#x2013;563.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28285264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Camu W, Khoris J, Moulard B, et al. Genetics of familial ALS and consequences for diagnosis: French ALS Research Group. J Neurol Sci 1999; 165 Suppl 1:S21&#x2013;S26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10448977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Logroscino G, Marin B, Piccininni M, et al. Referral bias in ALS epidemiological studies. PLoS One 2018; 13:e0195821.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5901916</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29659621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehta PR, Jones AR, Opie-Martin S, et al. Younger age of onset in familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis is a result of pathogenic gene variants, rather than ascertainment bias. J Neurol, Neurosurg, Psychiatry 2019; 90:268&#x2013;271.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6518463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30270202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agrawal M, Biswas A. Molecular diagnostics of neurodegenerative disorders. Front Mol Biosci 2015; 2:54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4585189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26442283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, Miller RG, Swash M, Munsat TL. El Escorial revisited: revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord 2000; 1:293&#x2013;299.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11464847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renton AE, Chio A, Traynor BJ. State of play in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis genetics. Nat Neurosci 2014; 17:17&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4544832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24369373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen PM, Al-Chalabi A. Clinical genetics of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: what do we really know? Nat Rev Neurol 2011; 7:603&#x2013;615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21989245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Couratier P, Corcia P, Lautrette G, et al. Epidemiology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a review of literature. Rev Neurol 2016; 172:37&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26727307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belbasis L, Bellou V, Evangelou E. Environmental risk factors and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: an umbrella review and critical assessment of current evidence from systematic reviews and meta-analyses of observational studies. Neuroepidemiology 2016; 46:96&#x2013;105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26731747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardiman O, Al-Chalabi A, Chio A, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat Rev Dis Primers 2017; 3:17071.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28980624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng P, Zhou X. Causal effects of blood lipids on amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a Mendelian randomization study. Human Mol Genet 2019; 28:688&#x2013;697.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6360326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30445611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bandres-Ciga S, Noyce AJ, Hemani G, et al. Shared polygenic risk and causal inferences in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol 2019; 85:470&#x2013;481.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6450729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30723964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhan Y, Fang F. Smoking and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a Mendelian randomization study. Ann Neurol 2019; 85:482&#x2013;484.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30786056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dickerson AS, Hansen J, Gredal O, Weisskopf MG. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and exposure to diesel exhaust in a Danish Cohort. Am J Epidemiol 2018; 187:1613&#x2013;1622.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6070035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29590300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dickerson AS, Hansen J, Specht AJ, et al. Population-based study of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and occupational lead exposure in Denmark. Occup Environ Med 2019; 76:208&#x2013;214.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6433465</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30705111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Visser AE, D&#x2019;Ovidio F, Peters S, et al. Multicentre, population-based, case-control study of particulates, combustion products and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis risk. J Neurol, Neurosurg, Psychiatry 2019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30850472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aberg M, Nyberg J, Robertson J, et al. Risk factors in Swedish young men for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in adulthood. J Neurol 2018; 265:460&#x2013;470.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5834569</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29285652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdulla MN, Sokrab TE, el Tahir A, et al. Motor neurone disease in the tropics: findings from Sudan. East Afr Med J 1997; 74:46&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9145578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radhakrishnan K, Ashok PP, Sridharan R, Mousa ME. Descriptive epidemiology of motor neuron disease in Benghazi, Libya. Neuroepidemiology 1986; 5:47&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3489194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osuntokun BO, Adeuja AO, Bademosi O. The prognosis of motor neuron disease in Nigerian Africans: a prospective study of 92 patients. Brain: J Neurol 1974; 97:385&#x2013;394.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4434185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>