<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">31377555</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2213-1582</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>24</Volume><PubDate><Year>2019</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>NeuroImage. Clinical</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Neuroimage Clin</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>MRI cortical feature of bulbar impairment in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>101934</StartPage><MedlinePgn>101934</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">101934</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.nicl.2019.101934</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S2213-1582(19)30284-0</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The decline of voluntary bulbar functions such as speech and swallowing are among the clinical manifestations of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) influencing a worst prognosis. Differential diagnosis between the contribution of upper motor neuron (UMN) and lower motor neuron degeneration to the bulbar impairment is often hard. Thinning and T2* hypointensity of the primary motor cortex have been recently suggested as possible MRI markers of UMN impairment in ALS patients, but little research has purposely targeted the orofacial region of the primary motor cortex (fM1). With the aim of finding an MRI marker of UMN impairment responsible for bulbar dysfunction, we investigated the T2* signal intensity of fM1 and the relationship with bulbar impairment in ALS patients. Fifty-five ALS patients were examined with 3&#x202f;T MRI. Their fM1 was evaluated both qualitatively in terms of T2* signal intensity and quantitatively by measuring its magnetic susceptibility with Quantitative Susceptibility Mapping (QSM). Bulbar functions were assessed clinically, by neurological examination and using the items 1-3 of the ALSFRS-R, and with neurophysiological tests. The marked hypointensity of fM1 was detected in 25% of ALS patients, including all patients with bulbar onset, and was 74% sensitive, 100% specific and 91% accurate in diagnosing functional bulbar impairment. Such hypointensity involved the middle and ventral part of fM1 and was usually visible in both hemispheres. The magnetic susceptibility was significantly higher in patients with marked fM1 hypointensity than in the other patients (p&#x202f;&#x2264;&#x202f;.001). The relationship with clinical and neurophysiological data suggests that such feature could be a marker of UMN degeneration for voluntary bulbar functions.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2019 The Authors. Published by Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Donatelli</LastName><ForeName>Graziella</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Imago7 Research Foundation, Pisa, Italy; Neuroradiology Unit, Azienda Ospadaliero-Universitaria Pisana, Pisa, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Caldarazzo Ienco</LastName><ForeName>Elena</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurology Unit, Department of Clinical and Experimental Medicine, University of Pisa, Pisa, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Costagli</LastName><ForeName>Mauro</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Imago7 Research Foundation, Pisa, Italy; Laboratory of Medical Physics and Magnetic Resonance, IRCCS Stella Maris, Pisa, Italy. Electronic address: mcostagli@imago7.eu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Migaleddu</LastName><ForeName>Gianmichele</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Translational Research and New Technologies in Medicine and Surgery, University of Pisa, Pisa, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cecchi</LastName><ForeName>Paolo</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neuroradiology Unit, Azienda Ospadaliero-Universitaria Pisana, Pisa, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Siciliano</LastName><ForeName>Gabriele</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurology Unit, Department of Clinical and Experimental Medicine, University of Pisa, Pisa, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cosottini</LastName><ForeName>Mirco</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neuroradiology Unit, Azienda Ospadaliero-Universitaria Pisana, Pisa, Italy; Department of Translational Research and New Technologies in Medicine and Surgery, University of Pisa, Pisa, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2019</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Neuroimage Clin</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101597070</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2213-1582</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="Y">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015331" MajorTopicYN="N">Cohort Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003679" MajorTopicYN="N">Deglutition</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005500" MajorTopicYN="N">Follow-Up Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008279" MajorTopicYN="N">Magnetic Resonance Imaging</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009044" MajorTopicYN="N">Motor Cortex</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="Y">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2018</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2019</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2019</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31377555</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6698695</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nicl.2019.101934</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2213-1582(19)30284-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Adachi Y., Sato N., Saito Y., Kimura Y., Nakata Y., Ito K., Kamiya K., Matsuda H., Tsukamoto T., Ogawa M. Usefulness of SWI for the detection of iron in the motor cortex in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J. Neuroimaging. 2015;25:443&#x2013;451.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24888543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed A., Simmons Z. Pseudobulbar affect: prevalence and management. Ther. Clin. Risk Manag. 2013;9:483&#x2013;489.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3849173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24348042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arwas N., Leshno A., Gotkine M. The palmomental reflex predicts earlier corticobulbar involvement in ALS. Amyotroph. Lateral Scler. Frontotemporal Degener. 2018;19:1&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30299162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bede P., Hardiman O. Lessons of ALS imaging: pitfalls and future directions - a critical review. Neuroimage Clin. 2014;4:436&#x2013;443.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3950559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24624329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bede P., Bokde A., Elamin M., Byrne S., McLaughlin R.L., Jordan N., Hampel H., Gallagher L., Lynch C., Fagan A.J., Pender N., Hardiman O. Grey matter correlates of clinical variables in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS): a neuroimaging study of ALS motor phenotype heterogeneity and cortical focality. J. Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatry. 2013;84:766&#x2013;773.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23085933</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks B.R., Miller R.G., Swash M., Munsat T.L., World Federation of Neurology Research Group on Motor Neuron Diseases El Escorial revisited: revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph. Lateral Scler. Other Motor Neuron Disord. 2000;1:293&#x2013;299.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11464847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brownell B., Oppenheimer D.R., Hughes J.T. The central nervous system in motor neurone disease. J. Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatry. 1970;33:338&#x2013;357.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC493478</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5431724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cattaneo L., Pavesi G. The facial motor system. Neurosci. Biobehav. Rev. 2014;38:135&#x2013;159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24239732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum J.M., Stambler N., Malta E., Fuller C., Hilt D., Thurmond B., Nakanishi A. The ALSFRS-R: a revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. BDNF ALS Study Group (phase III) J. Neurol. Sci. 1999;169:13&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10540002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2; A., Calvo A., Moglia C., Mazzini L., Mora G., PARALS Study Group Phenotypic heterogeneity of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a population based study. J. Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatry. 2011;82:740&#x2013;746.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21402743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cosottini M., Frosini D., Pesaresi I., Donatelli G., Cecchi P., Costagli M., Biagi L., Ceravolo R., Bonuccelli U., Tosetti M. Comparison of 3T and 7T susceptibility-weighted angiography of the substantia nigra in diagnosing Parkinson disease. AJNR Am. J. Neuroradiol. 2015;36:461&#x2013;466.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25376811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cosottini M., Donatelli G., Costagli M., Caldarazzo Ienco E., Frosini D., Pesaresi I., Biagi L., Siciliano G., Tosetti M. High-resolution 7T MR imaging of the motor cortex in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. AJNR Am. J. Neuroradiol. 2016;37:455&#x2013;461.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26680464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costagli M., Donatelli G., Biagi L., Caldarazzo Ienco E., Siciliano G., Tosetti M., Cosottini M. Magnetic susceptibility in the deep layers of the primary motor cortex in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuroimage Clin. 2016;12:965&#x2013;969.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5153607</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27995062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M., Dengler R., Eisen A., England J.D., Kaji R., Kimura J., Mills K., Mitsumoto H., Nodera H., Shefner J., Swash M. Electrodiagnostic criteria for diagnosis of ALS. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2008;119:497&#x2013;503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18164242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donatelli G., Retico A., Caldarazzo Ienco E., Cecchi P., Costagli M., Frosini D., Biagi L., Tosetti M., Siciliano G., Cosottini M. Semiautomated evaluation of the primary motor cortex in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis at 3T. AJNR Am. J. Neuroradiol. 2018;39:63&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7410679</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29122765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eisen A., Swash M. Clinical neurophysiology of ALS. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2001;112:2190&#x2013;2201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11738189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filippi M., Agosta F., Abrahams S., Fazekas F., Grosskreutz J., Kalra S., Kassubek J., Silani V., Turner M.R., Masdeu J.C., European Federation of Neurological Societies EFNS guidelines on the use of neuroimaging in the management of motor neuron diseases. Eur. J. Neurol. 2010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3154636</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20136647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huynh W., Simon N.G., Grosskreutz J., Turner M.R., Vucic S., Kiernan M.C. Assessment of the upper motor neuron in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2016;127:2643&#x2013;2660.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27291884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawamata T., Akiyama H., Yamada T., McGeer P.L. Immunologic reactions in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis brain and spinal cord tissue. Am. J. Pathol. 1992;140:691&#x2013;707.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1886170</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1347673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiernan M.C., Vucic S., Cheah B.C., Turner M.R., Eisen A., Hardiman O., Burrell J.R., Zoing M.C. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet. 2011;377:942&#x2013;955.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21296405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xf6;rner S., Kollewe K., Fahlbusch M., Zapf A., Dengler R., Krampfl K., Petri S. Onset and spreading patterns of upper and lower motor neuron symptoms in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 2011;43:636&#x2013;642.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21484822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xfc;hnlein P., Gdynia H.-J., Sperfeld A.-D., Lindner-Pfleghar B., Ludolph A.C., Prosiegel M., Riecker A. Diagnosis and treatment of bulbar symptoms in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat. Clin. Pract. Neurol. 2008;4:366&#x2013;374.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18560390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwan J.Y., Jeong S.Y., van Gelderen P., Deng H.-X., Quezado M.M., Danielian L.E., Butman J.A., Chen L., Bayat E., Russell J., Siddique T., Duyn J.H., Rouault T.A., Floeter M.K. Iron accumulation in deep cortical layers accounts for MRI signal abnormalities in ALS: correlating 7 tesla MRI and pathology. PLoS One. 2012;7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3328441</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22529995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawyer T., Netsky M.G. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. AMA Arch. Neurol. Psychiatr. 1953;69:171&#x2013;192.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13007227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leigh P.N., Abrahams S., Al-Chalabi A., Ampong M.-A., Goldstein L.H., Johnson J., Lyall R., Moxham J., Mustfa N., Rio A., Shaw C., Willey E., King's MND Care and Research Team The management of motor neurone disease. J. Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatry. 2003;74(Suppl. 4):iv32&#x2013;iv47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1765641</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14645465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Logroscino G., Traynor B.J., Hardiman O., Chio A., Couratier P., Mitchell J.D., Swingler R.J., Beghi E., EURALS Descriptive epidemiology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: new evidence and unsolved issues. J. Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatry. 2008;79:6&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18079297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazziotta J.C., Toga A.W., Evans A., Fox P., Lancaster J. A probabilistic atlas of the human brain: theory and rationale for its development. The International Consortium for Brain Mapping (ICBM) NeuroImage. 1995;2:89&#x2013;101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9343592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Owen G., Mulley G.P. The palmomental reflex: a useful clinical sign? J. Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatry. 2002;73:113&#x2013;115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1738000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12122165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pallebage-Gamarallage M., Foxley S., Menke R.A.L., Huszar I.N., Jenkinson M., Tendler B.C., Wang C., Jbabdi S., Turner M.R., Miller K.L., Ansorge O. Dissecting the pathobiology of altered MRI signal in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a post mortem whole brain sampling strategy for the integration of ultra-high-field MRI and quantitative neuropathology. BMC Neurosci. 2018;19</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5848544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29529995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Penfield W., Boldrey E. Somatic motor and sensory representation in the cerebral cortex of man as studied by electrical stimulation. Brain. 1937;60:389&#x2013;443.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Penfield W., Rasmussen T. Macmillan; 1950. The Cerebral Cortex of Man.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saberi S., Stauffer J.E., Schulte D.J., Ravits J. Neuropathology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and its variants. Neurol. Clin. 2015;33:855&#x2013;876.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4628785</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26515626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schott J.M., Rossor M.N. The palmomental reflex: stop scratching around! Pract. Neurol. 2016;16:500&#x2013;501.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28120789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuster C., Kasper E., Machts J., Bittner D., Kaufmann J., Benecke R., Teipel S., Vielhaber S., Prudlo J. Focal thinning of the motor cortex mirrors clinical features of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and their phenotypes: a neuroimaging study. J. Neurol. 2013;260:2856&#x2013;2864.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23996101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sorar&#xf9;, G., Ermani, M., Logroscino, G., Palmieri, A., D' Ascenzo, C., Orsetti, V., Volpe, M., Cima, V., Zara, G., Pegoraro, E., Angelini, C., 2010. Natural history of upper motor neuron-dominant ALS. Amyotroph. Lateral Scler. 11, 424&#x2013;429. doi:10.3109/17482960903300867.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/17482960903300867</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19929748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swash M. Why are upper motor neuron signs difficult to elicit in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis? J. Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatry. 2012;83:659&#x2013;662.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22496581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsuchiya K., Ikeda K., Mimura M., Takahashi M., Miyazaki H., Anno M., Shiotsu H., Akabane H., Niizato K., Uchihara T., Tominaga I., Nakano I. Constant involvement of the Betz cells and pyramidal tract in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with dementia: a clinicopathological study of eight autopsy cases. Acta Neuropathol. 2002;104:249&#x2013;259.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12172910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Urban P.P., Vogt T., Hopf H.C. Corticobulbar tract involvement in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. A transcranial magnetic stimulation study. Brain. 1998;121(Pt 6):1099&#x2013;1108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9648545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>V&#xe1;zquez-Costa J.F., Maz&#xf3;n M., Carreres-Polo J., Herv&#xe1;s D., P&#xe9;rez-Tur J., Mart&#xed;-Bonmat&#xed; L., Sevilla T. Brain signal intensity changes as biomarkers in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neurol. Scand. 2018;137:262&#x2013;271.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29082510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S., Nicholson G.A., Kiernan M.C. Cortical hyperexcitability may precede the onset of familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain. 2008;131:1540&#x2013;1550.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18469020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walhout R., Westeneng H.-J., Verstraete E., Hendrikse J., Veldink J.H., van den Heuvel M.P., van den Berg L.H. Cortical thickness in ALS: towards a marker for upper motor neuron involvement. J. Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatry. 2015;86:288&#x2013;294.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25121571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wijesekera L.C., Leigh P.N. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Orphanet J. Rare Dis. 2009;4(3)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2656493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19192301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yousry T.A., Schmid U.D., Alkadhi H., Schmidt D., Peraud A., Buettner A., Winkler P. Localization of the motor hand area to a knob on the precentral gyrus. A new landmark. Brain. 1997;120(Pt 1):141&#x2013;157.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9055804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zoccolella S., Beghi E., Palagano G., Fraddosio A., Samarelli V., Lamberti P., Lepore V., Serlenga L., Logroscino G. Signs and symptoms at diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a population-based study in southern Italy. Eur. J. Neurol. 2006;13:789&#x2013;792.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16834713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>