<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">31400058</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1522-2586</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>51</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of magnetic resonance imaging : JMRI</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Magn Reson Imaging</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Facial nerve atrophy in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Evaluation with fast imaging employing steady-state acquisition (FIESTA).</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>757</StartPage><EndPage>766</EndPage><MedlinePgn>757-766</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jmri.26890</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">In amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS), motor neurons in the brainstem markedly deplete, whereas sensory neurons are less severely affected.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE">To determine whether facial nerve (FN) measurement on 3D fast imaging employing steady-state acquisition (FIESTA) is useful for ALS diagnosis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="STUDY TYPE">Retrospective.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUBJECTS">Fifteen ALS patients and 16 controls.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="FIELD STRENGTH/SEQUENCE">3T FIESTA MR.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="ASSESSMENT">The cross-sectional area of the FN and cochlear nerve (CN) were measured, and the FN/CN ratio (FCR) was assessed. For qualitative assessment, the FN cross-sectional area was compared with that of the CN and the following scores were assigned: score 1 (large), the FN is larger than the CN; score 2 (almost equal), the size difference between the FN and CN is within 10%; score 3 (small), the FN is smaller than the CN (10-50%); score 4 (significantly small), size of the FN is less than half the size of the CN.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="STATISTICAL TESTS">The differences in FCR between the ALS patients and the controls were tested using the Wilcoxon Mann-Whitney U-test. For the qualitative and quantitative assessments, we performed a receiver operating characteristic analysis for the diagnosis of ALS with an abnormal finding as score 3 or 4.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">The mean FCR was significantly smaller for ALS patients (0.71&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.17) than for controls (0.95&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.08) (P &lt; 0.001) and the area under the curve was 0.93. When an FN score was 3 or 4, indicative of FN atrophy, the sensitivity and specificity values of FIESTA for discriminating ALS patients from controls were 93.3% (14/15) and 90.0% (18/20), respectively.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DATA CONCLUSION">The FN atrophy revealed on FIESTA, which may reflect lower motor neuron impairment in ALS, allowed us to distinguish ALS patients from controls with a high degree of accuracy.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="LEVEL OF EVIDENCE">3 Technical Efficacy: Stage 2 J. Magn. Reson. Imaging 2020;51:757-766.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2019 International Society for Magnetic Resonance in Medicine.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Miyata</LastName><ForeName>Mari</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8837-9593</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, University of Occupational and Environmental Health, School of Medicine, Kitakyushu, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kakeda</LastName><ForeName>Shingo</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Diagnostic Radiology, Hirosaki University Graduate School of Medicine 5 Zaifu-cho, Hirosaki, Aomori, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hashimoto</LastName><ForeName>Tomoyo</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8132-5592</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of Occupational and Environmental Health, School of Medicine, Kitakyushu, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ide</LastName><ForeName>Satoru</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, University of Occupational and Environmental Health, School of Medicine, Kitakyushu, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Okada</LastName><ForeName>Kazumasa</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of Occupational and Environmental Health, School of Medicine, Kitakyushu, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Adachi</LastName><ForeName>Hiroaki</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of Occupational and Environmental Health, School of Medicine, Kitakyushu, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Korogi</LastName><ForeName>Yukunori</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, University of Occupational and Environmental Health, School of Medicine, Kitakyushu, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2019</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Magn Reson Imaging</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9105850</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1053-1807</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001284" MajorTopicYN="N">Atrophy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005154" MajorTopicYN="Y">Facial Nerve</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D021621" MajorTopicYN="N">Imaging, Three-Dimensional</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008279" MajorTopicYN="N">Magnetic Resonance Imaging</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cochlear nerve</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">facial nerve</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fast imaging employing steady-state acquisition</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2019</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31400058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmri.26890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Turner MR, Swash M. The expanding syndrome of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A clinical and molecular odyssey. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2015;86:667-673.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jang JS, Bae JS. AWAJI criteria are not always superior to the previous criteria: A meta-analysis. Muscle Nerve 2015;51:822-829.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campanari ML, Bourefis AR, Kabashi E. Diagnostic challenge and neuromuscular junction contribution to ALS pathogenesis. Front Neurol 2019;10:68.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L, Ulug AM, Zimmerman RD, et al. The diagnostic utility of FLAIR imaging in clinically verified amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Magn Reson Imaging 2003;17:521-527.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waragai M. MRI and clinical features in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuroradiol J 1997;39:847-851.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamada K, Kakeda S, Ohnari N, et al. Signal intensity of motor and sensory cortices on T2-weighted and FLAIR images: Intraindividual comparison of 1.5 T and 3T MRI. Eur Radiol 2008;18:2949-2955.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowen BC, Pattany PM, Bradley WG, et al. MR imaging and localized proton spectroscopy of the precentral gyrus in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Am J Neuroradiol 2000;21:647-658.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham J, Papadakis N, Evans J, et al. Diffusion tensor imaging for the assessment of upper motor neuron integrity in ALS. Neurol 2004;63:2111-2119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sach M, Winkler G, Glauche V, et al. Diffusion tensor MRI of early upper motor neuron involvement in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain 2004;127:340-350.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dyck PJ, Stevens JC, Mulder DW, et al. Frequency of nerve fiber degeneration of peripheral motor and sensory neurons in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Morphometry of deep and superficial peroneal nerves. Neurology 1975;25:781-781.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heads T, Pollock M, Robertson A, et al. Sensory nerve pathology in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathol 1991;82:316-320.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawamura Y, Dyck PJ, Shimono M, et al. Morphometric comparison of the vulnerability of peripheral motor and sensory neurons in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neuropathol Exp Neurol 1981;40:667-675.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haacke EM, Wielopolski PA, Tkach JA, et al. Steady-state free precession imaging in the presence of motion: Application for improved visualization of the cerebrospinal fluid. Radiology 1990;175:545-552.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsuchiya K, Aoki C, Hachiya J. Evaluation of MR cisternography of the cerebellopontine angle using a balanced fast-field-echo sequence: Preliminary findings. Eur Radiol 2004;14:239-242.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung HW, Chen CY, Zimmerman RA, et al. T2-Weighted fast MR imaging with true FISP versus HASTE: Comparative efficacy in the evaluation of normal fetal brain maturation. Am J Roentgenol 2000;175:1375-1380.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jayakumar PN, Kovoor JM, Srikanth SG, et al. 3D steady-state MR cisternography in CSF rhinorrhoea. Acta Radiol 2001;42:582-584.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks B, Miller R, Swash M, et al. World Federation of Neurology Research Group on Motor Neuron Diseases. El Escorial revisited: Revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord 2000;1:293-299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Dengler R, Eisen A, et al. Electrodiagnostic criteria for diagnosis of ALS. Clin Neurophysiol 2008;119:497-503.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naguib NN, Hey C, Shaaban MS, et al. Assessment of the cochlear nerve to facial nerve size ratio using MR multiplanar reconstruction of the internal auditory canal in patients presenting with acquired long-standing hearing loss. Br J Radiol 2017;90:20160870.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Youden WJ. Index for rating diagnostic tests. Cancer 1950;3:32-35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Landis JR, Koch GG. The measurement of observer agreement for categorical data. Biometrics 1977;33:159-174.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dietrich O, Reiser MF, Schoenberg SO. Artifacts in 3-T MRI: Physical background and reduction strategies. Eur J Radiol 2008;65:29-35</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ludolph A, Drory V, Hardiman O, et al. A revision of the El Escorial criteria-2015. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2015;16:291-292.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang WS, Hyun SM, Lim HK, et al. Normative diameters and effects of aging on the cochlear and facial nerves in normal-hearing Korean ears using 3.0-Tesla magnetic resonance imaging. Laryngoscope 2012;122:1109-1114.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kennedy WR, Alter M, Sung JH. Progressive proximal spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy of late onset: A sex-linked recessive trait. Neurology 1968;18:671-680.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kakeda S, Yoneda T, Ide S, et al. Zebra sign of precentral gyri in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A novel finding using phase difference enhanced (PADRE) imaging-initial results. Eur Radiol 2016;26:4173-4183.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grams AE, Kraff O, Kalkmann J, et al. Magnetic resonance imaging of cranial nerves at 7 Tesla. Clin Neuroradiol 2013;23:17-23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerganov VM, Giordano M, Samii M, et al. Diffusion tensor imaging-based fiber tracking for prediction of the position of the facial nerve in relation to large vestibular schwannomas. J Neurosurg 2011;115:1087-1093.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heros RC, Bhatia R. Editorial: Vestibular schwannoma the facial nerve. J Neurosurg 2012;116:695-696.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li H, Wang L, Hao S, et al. Identification of the facial nerve in relation to vestibular schwannoma using preoperative diffusion tensor tractography and intraoperative tractography-integrated neuronavigation system. World Neurosurg 2017;107:669-677.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taoka T, Hirabayashi H, Nakagawa H, et al. Displacement of the facial nerve course by vestibular schwannoma: Preoperative visualization using diffusion tensor tractography. J Magn Reson Imaging 2006;24:1005-1010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moon HC, You ST, Baek HM, et al. 7.0 Tesla MRI tractography in patients with trigeminal neuralgia. Magn Reson Imaging. 2018;54:265-270.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henssen DJHA, Mollink J, Kurt E, et al. Ex vivo visualization of the trigeminal pathways in the human brainstem using 11.7T diffusion MRI combined with microscopy polarized light imaging. Brain Struct Funct 2019;224:159-170.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>