<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">31412164</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>07</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1601-183X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>19</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Genes, brain, and behavior</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Genes Brain Behav</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Novel behavioural characteristics of the superoxide dismutase 1 G93A (SOD1<sup>G93A</sup> ) mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis include sex-dependent phenotypes.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e12604</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e12604</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/gbb.12604</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) involves the rapid degeneration of upper and lower motor neurons leading to weakening and paralysis of voluntary movements. Mutations in copper-zinc superoxide dismutase 1 (SOD1) are a known genetic cause of ALS, and the SOD1 <sup>G93A</sup> mouse has been used extensively to investigate molecular mechanisms in ALS. In recent years, evidence suggests that ALS and frontotemporal dementia form a spectrum disorder ranging from motor to cognitive dysfunctions. Thus, we tested male and female SOD1 <sup>G93A</sup> mice for the first time before the onset of debilitating motor impairments in behavioural domains relevant to both ALS and frontotemporal dementia. SOD1 <sup>G93A</sup> males displayed reduced locomotion, exploration and increased anxiety-like behaviours compared with control males. Intermediate-term spatial memory was impaired in SOD1 <sup>G93A</sup> females, whereas long-term spatial memory deficits as well as lower acoustic startle response, and prepulse inhibition were identified in SOD1 <sup>G93A</sup> mice of both sexes compared with respective controls. Interestingly, SOD1 <sup>G93A</sup> males exhibited an increased conditioned cue freezing response. Nosing behaviours were also elevated in both male and female SOD1 <sup>G93A</sup> when assessed in social paradigms. In conclusion, SOD1 <sup>G93A</sup> mice exhibit a variety of sex-specific behavioural deficits beyond motor impairments supporting the notion of an ALS-frontotemporal spectrum disorder. Thus, SOD1 <sup>G93A</sup> mice may represent a useful model to test the efficacy of therapeutic interventions on clinical symptoms in addition to declining motor abilities.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2019 John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd and International Behavioural and Neural Genetics Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kreilaus</LastName><ForeName>Fabian</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, Western Sydney University, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guerra</LastName><ForeName>Stefan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, Western Sydney University, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Masanetz</LastName><ForeName>Rebecca</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medical and Life Sciences, Hochschule Furtwangen University, Villingen-Schwenningen, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Menne</LastName><ForeName>Victoria</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Psychology, Technische Universit&#xe4;t Braunschweig, Braunschweig, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yerbury</LastName><ForeName>Justin</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Illawarra Health and Medical Research Institute, Wollongong, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Chemistry and Molecular Bioscience, Faculty of Science, Medicine and Health, University of Wollongong, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Karl</LastName><ForeName>Tim</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9904-8482</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, Western Sydney University, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neuroscience Research Australia (NeuRA), New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medical Sciences, University of New South Wales, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2019</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Genes Brain Behav</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101129617</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1601-183X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C000606290">SOD1 protein, human</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 1.15.1.1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C109415">SOD1 G93A protein</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 1.15.1.1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D013482">Superoxide Dismutase</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 1.15.1.1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000072105">Superoxide Dismutase-1</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001007" MajorTopicYN="N">Anxiety</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004195" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Models, Animal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005106" MajorTopicYN="N">Exploratory Behavior</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057180" MajorTopicYN="N">Frontotemporal Dementia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008124" MajorTopicYN="N">Locomotion</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051379" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008822" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice, Transgenic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009046" MajorTopicYN="N">Motor Neurons</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009154" MajorTopicYN="N">Mutation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010641" MajorTopicYN="N">Phenotype</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013216" MajorTopicYN="N">Reflex, Startle</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012737" MajorTopicYN="N">Sex Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013116" MajorTopicYN="N">Spinal Cord</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013482" MajorTopicYN="N">Superoxide Dismutase</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="Y">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000072105" MajorTopicYN="N">Superoxide Dismutase-1</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">acoustic startle response</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">behaviour</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cognitive dysfunction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">frontotemporal dementia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">motor neuron disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mouse model</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">prepulse inhibition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">spatial memory</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">superoxide dismutase-1</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2019</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2019</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31412164</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/gbb.12604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Ferrante RJ, Browne SE, Shinobu LA, et al. Evidence of increased oxidative damage in both sporadic and familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurochem. 1997;69(5):2064-2074.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barber SC, Shaw PJ. Oxidative stress in ALS: key role in motor neuron injury and therapeutic target. Free Radic Biol Med. 2010 March 1;48(5):629-641.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Q, Johnson JL, Agar NY, Agar JN. Protein aggregation and protein instability govern familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patient survival. PLoS Biol. 2008 Jul 29;6(7):e170.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piao Y-S, Wakabayashi K, Kakita A, et al. Neuropathology with clinical correlations of sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: 102 autopsy cases examined between 1962 and 2000. Brain Pathol. 2003;13(1):10-22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ciryam P, Lambert-Smith IA, Bean DM, et al. Spinal motor neuron protein supersaturation patterns are associated with inclusion body formation in ALS. Proc Natl Acad Sci. 2017;114(20):E3935-E3943.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yerbury JJ, Ooi L, Blair IP, Ciryam P, Dobson CM, Vendruscolo M. The metastability of the proteome of spinal motor neurons underlies their selective vulnerability in ALS. Neurosci Lett. 2019 June 21;704:89-94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner MR, Rabiner EA, Hammers A, et al. [11C]-WAY100635 PET demonstrates marked 5-HT1A receptor changes in sporadic ALS. Brain. 2005 Apr;128(Pt 4):896-905.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Przedborski S, Dhawan V, Donaldson DM, et al. Nigrostriatal dopaminergic function in familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients with and without copper/zinc superoxide dismutase mutations. Neurology. 1996 Dec;47(6):1546-1551.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vogels OJM, Veltman J, Oyen WJG, Horstink MWIM. Decreased striatal dopamine D2 receptor binding in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) and multiple system atrophy (MSA): D2 receptor down-regulation versus striatal cell degeneration. J Neurol Sci. 2000 November 1;180(1):62-65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abrahams S, Goldstein LH, Suckling J, et al. Frontotemporal white matter changes in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol. 2005 March 01;252(3):321-331.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Usman U, Choi C, Camicioli R, et al. Mesial prefrontal cortex degeneration in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a high-field proton MR spectroscopy study. Am J Neuroradiol. 2011;32(9):1677-1680.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Machts J, Loewe K, Kaufmann J, et al. Basal ganglia pathology in ALS is associated with neuropsychological deficits. Neurology. 2015 Oct 13;85(15):1301-1309.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudharshan N, Hanstock C, Hui B, Pyra T, Johnston W, Kalra S. Degeneration of the mid-cingulate cortex in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis detected in vivo with MR spectroscopy. Am J Neuroradiol. 2011;32(2):403-407.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abrahams S, Leigh PN, Harvey A, Vythelingum GN, Grise D, Goldstein LH. Verbal fluency and executive dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). Neuropsychologia. 2000;38(6):734-747.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abrahams S, Leigh PN, Goldstein LH. Cognitive change in ALS: a prospective study. Neurology. 2005 Apr 12;64(7):1222-1226.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeJesus-Hernandez M, Mackenzie Ian R, Boeve Bradley F, et al. Expanded GGGGCC Hexanucleotide repeat in noncoding region of C9ORF72 causes chromosome 9p-linked FTD and ALS. Neuron. 2011 October 20;72(2):245-256.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strong MJ, Abrahams S, Goldstein LH, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis - frontotemporal spectrum disorder (ALS-FTSD): revised diagnostic criteria. Amyotroph Lat Scl Frontotemp Degen. 2017 May;18(3-4):153-174.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parton MJ, Broom W, Andersen PM, et al. D90A-SOD1 mediated amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a single founder for all cases with evidence for a Cis-acting disease modifier in the recessive haplotype. Hum Mutat. 2002;20(6):473.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner BJ, Talbot K. Transgenics, toxicity and therapeutics in rodent models of mutant SOD1-mediated familial ALS. Prog Neurobiol. 2008;85(1):94-134.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosen DR, Siddiquef T, Patterson D, et al. Mutations in Cu/Zn superoxide dismutase gene are associated with familial amyotrophic. Nature. 1993;362:4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Synofzik M, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Santiago R, Maetzler W, Sch&#xf6;ls L, Andersen PM. The human G93A SOD1 phenotype closely resembles sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2010;81(7):764-767.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gurney ME, Pu H, Chiu AY, et al. Motor neuron degeneration in mice that express a human Cu, Zn superoxide dismutase mutation. Science. 1994;264(5166):1772-1775.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zang D, Cheema S. Degeneration of corticospinal and bulbospinal systems in the superoxide dismutase 1 G93A G1H transgenic mouse model of familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurosci Lett. 2002 Oct 31;332(2):99-102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acevedo-Arozena A, Kalmar B, Essa S, et al. A comprehensive assessment of the SOD1G93A low-copy transgenic mouse, which models human amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Dis Model Mech. 2011 Sep;4(5):686-700.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stam NC, Nithianantharajah J, Howard ML, Atkin JD, Cheema SS, Hannan AJ. Sex-specific behavioural effects of environmental enrichment in a transgenic mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Eur J Neurosci. 2008;28(4):717-723.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCombe PA, Henderson RD. Effects of gender in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Gend Med. 2010 Dec;7(6):557-570.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi CI, Lee YD, Gwag BJ, Cho SI, Kim SS, Suh-Kim H. Effects of estrogen on lifespan and motor functions in female hSOD1 G93A transgenic mice. J Neurol Sci. 2008 May 15;268(1-2):40-47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karl T, Pabst R, von Horsten S. Behavioral phenotyping of mice in pharmacological and toxicological research. Exp Toxicol Pathol. 2003 Jul;55(1):69-83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shang K, Talmage DA, Karl T. Parent-of-origin effects on schizophrenia-relevant behaviours of type III neuregulin 1 mutant mice. Behav Brain Res. 2017 August 14;332:250-258.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taglialatela G, Hogan D, Zhang W-R, Dineley KT. Intermediate- and long-term recognition memory deficits in Tg2576 mice are reversed with acute calcineurin inhibition. Behav Brain Res. 2009 June 8;200(1):95-99.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stough S, Shobe JL, Carew TJ. Intermediate-term processes in memory formation. Curr Opin Neurobiol. 2006 December 1;16(6):672-678.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olaya JC, Heusner CL, Matsumoto M, Shannon Weickert C, Karl T. Schizophrenia-relevant behaviours of female mice overexpressing neuregulin 1 type III. Behav Brain Res. 2018 November 1;353:227-235.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moy SS, Nadler JJ, Perez A, et al. Sociability and preference for social novelty in five inbred strains: an approach to assess autistic-like behavior in mice. Genes Brain Behav. 2004;3(5):287-302.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng D, Low JK, Logge W, Garner B, Karl T. Novel behavioural characteristics of female APPSwe/PS1&#x394;E9 double transgenic mice. Behav Brain Res. 2014 March 1;260:111-118.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paylor R, Crawley JN. Inbred strain differences in prepulse inhibition of the mouse startle response. Psychopharmacology. 1997 July 01;132(2):169-180.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Owen EH, Logue SF, Rasmussen DL, Wehner JM. Assessment of learning by the Morris water task and fear conditioning in inbred mouse strains and F1 hybrids: implications of genetic background for single gene mutations and quantitative trait loci analyses. Neuroscience. 1997 August 11;80(4):1087-1099.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dere E, Huston JP, De Souza Silva MA. The pharmacology, neuroanatomy and neurogenetics of one-trial object recognition in rodents. Neurosci Biobehav Rev. 2007;31(5):673-704.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Llano Lopez L, Hauser J, Feldon J, Gargiulo PA, Yee BK. Evaluating spatial memory function in mice: a within-subjects comparison between the water maze test and its adaptation to dry land. Behav Brain Res. 2010 May 1;209(1):85-92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quarta E, Bravi R, Scambi I, Mariotti R, Minciacchi D. Increased anxiety-like behavior and selective learning impairments are concomitant to loss of hippocampal interneurons in the presymptomatic SOD1(G93A) ALS mouse model. J Comp Neurol. 2015 Aug 1;523(11):1622-1638.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pulvirenti L, Berrier R, Kreifeldt M, Koob GK. Modulation of locomotor activity by NMDA receptors in the nucleus accumbens core and shell regions of the rat. Brain Res. 1994 November 21;664(1):231-236.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pijnenburg AJJ, Honig WMM, Van Rossum JM. Inhibition of d-amphetamine-induced locomotor activity by injection of haloperidol into the nucleus accumbens of the rat. Psychopharmacologia. 1975 January 1, 1975;41(2):87-95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singer CA, Figueroa-Masot XA, Batchelor RH, Dorsa DM. The mitogen-activated protein kinase pathway mediates estrogen neuroprotection after glutamate toxicity in primary cortical neurons. J Neurosci. 1999;19(7):2455-2463.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Culmsee C, Vedder H, Ravati A, et al. Neuroprotection by estrogens in a mouse model of focal cerebral ischemia and in cultured neurons: evidence for a receptor-independent antioxidative mechanism. J Cereb Blood Flow Metab. 1999 Nov;19(11):1263-1269.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Temel Y, Blokland A, Lim LW. Deactivation of the parvalbumin-positive interneurons in the hippocampus after fear-like behaviour following electrical stimulation of the dorsolateral periaqueductal gray of rats. Behav Brain Res. 2012 August 1;233(2):322-325.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang RJ, Mozhui K, Karlsson RM, Cameron HA, Williams RW, Holmes A. Variation in mouse basolateral amygdala volume is associated with differences in stress reactivity and fear learning. Neuropsychopharmacology. 2008 Oct;33(11):2595-2604.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lul&#xe9; D, Diekmann V, Anders S, et al. Brain responses to emotional stimuli in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). J Neurol. 2007 April 01;254(4):519-527.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson VER, Cairns NJ, Leigh PN. Involvement of the amygdala, dentate and hippocampus in motor neuron disease. J Neurol Sci. 1995 May 1;129:75-78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawashima T, Doh-ura K, Kikuchi H, Iwaki T. Cognitive dysfunction in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis is associated with spherical or crescent-shaped ubiquitinated intraneuronal inclusions in the parahippocampal gyrus and amygdala, but not in the neostriatum. Acta Neuropathol. 2001 November 01;102(5):467-472.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinkhardt EH, van Elst LT, Ludolph AC, Kassubek J. Amygdala size in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis without dementia: an in vivostudy using MRI volumetry. BMC Neurol. 2006 December 25;6(1):48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sgobio C, Trabalza A, Spalloni A, et al. Abnormal medial prefrontal cortex connectivity and defective fear extinction in the presymptomatic G93A SOD1 mouse model of ALS. Genes Brain Behav. 2008 Jun;7(4):427-434.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koss DJ, Robinson L, Drever BD, et al. Mutant Tau knock-in mice display frontotemporal dementia relevant behaviour and histopathology. Neurobiol Dis. 2016 Jul;91:105-123.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morgan MA, Pfaff DW. Effects of estrogen on activity and fear-related behaviors in mice. Hormones Behav. 2001 December 1;40(4):472-482.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vignola A, Guzzo A, Calvo A, et al. Anxiety undermines quality of life in ALS patients and caregivers. Eur J Neurol. 2008;15(11):1231-1236.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurt A, Nijboer F, Matuz T, K&#xfc;bler A. Depression and anxiety in individuals with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. CNS Drugs. 2007 April 01;21(4):279-291.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spalloni A, Geracitano R, Berretta N, et al. Molecular and synaptic changes in the hippocampus underlying superior spatial abilities in pre-symptomatic G93A+/+ mice overexpressing the human Cu/Zn superoxide dismutase (Gly93 --&gt; ALA) mutation. Exp Neurol. 2006 Feb;197(2):505-514.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cha CI, Chung YH, Shin C-m, et al. Immunocytochemical study on the distribution of nitrotyrosine in the brain of the transgenic mice expressing a human Cu/Zn SOD mutation. Brain Res. 2000 January 17;853(1):156-161.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung YH, Joo KM, Nam RH, et al. Decreased expression of calretinin in the cerebral cortex and hippocampus of SOD1G93A transgenic mice. Brain Res. 2005 February 21;1035(1):105-109.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takeda T, Uchihara T, Arai N, Mizutani T, Iwata M. Progression of hippocampal degeneration in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with or without memory impairment: distinction from Alzheimer disease. Acta Neuropathol. 2009 Jan;117(1):35-44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mantovan MC, Baggio L, Barba GD, et al. Memory deficits and retrieval processes in ALS1. Eur J Neurol. 2003;10(3):221-227.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geracitano R, Paolucci E, Prisco S, et al. Altered long-term corticostriatal synaptic plasticity in transgenic mice overexpressing human CU/ZN superoxide dismutase (GLY(93)--&gt;ALA) mutation. Neuroscience. 2003;118(2):399-408.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woolley DG, Laeremans A, Gantois I, et al. Homologous involvement of striatum and prefrontal cortex in rodent and human water maze learning. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2013 Feb 19;110(8):3131-3136.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sano H, Nagai Y, Miyakawa T, Shigemoto R, Yokoi M. Increased social interaction in mice deficient of the striatal medium spiny neuron-specific phosphodiesterase 10A2. J Neurochem. 2008 Apr;105(2):546-556.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanda K, Nishi A, Matsuo N, et al. Abnormal social behavior, hyperactivity, impaired remote spatial memory, and increased D1-mediated dopaminergic signaling in neuronal nitric oxide synthase knockout mice. Mol Brain. 2009 June 18;2(1):19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palmiter RD. Dopamine signaling in the dorsal striatum is essential for motivated behaviors: lessons from dopamine-deficient mice. Ann N Y Acad Sci. 2008;1129:35-46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beninger RJ. The role of dopamine in locomotor activity and learning. Brain Research Reviews. 1983 October 1;6(2):173-196.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kostic V, Gurney ME, Deng H-X, Siddique T, Epstein CJ, Przedborski S. Midbrain dopaminergic neuronal degeneration in a transgenic mouse model of familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol. 1997;41(4):497-504.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radakovic R, Stephenson L, Colville S, Swingler R, Chandran S, Abrahams S. Multidimensional apathy in ALS: validation of the dimensional apathy scale. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2016;87(6):663.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caga J, Hsieh S, Highton-Williamson E, et al. Apathy and its impact on patient outcome in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol. 2018 January 01;265(1):187-193.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J, Forkstam C, Engel JA, Svensson L. Role of dopamine in prepulse inhibition of acoustic startle. Psychopharmacology. 2000 April 01;149(2):181-188.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dulawa SC, Gross C, Stark KL, Hen R, Geyer MA. Knockout mice reveal opposite roles for serotonin 1A and 1B receptors in prepulse inhibition. Neuropsychopharmacology. 2000 Jun 2000;22(6):650-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner BJ, Lopes EC, Cheema SS. The serotonin precursor 5-hydroxytryptophan delays neuromuscular disease in murine familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord. 2003 Sep;4(3):171-176.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miquel E, Cassina A, Martinez-Palma L, et al. Modulation of astrocytic mitochondrial function by dichloroacetate improves survival and motor performance in inherited amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. PLoS One. 2012;7(4):e34776.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naumenko N, Pollari E, Kurronen A, et al. Gender-specific mechanism of synaptic impairment and its prevention by GCSF in a mouse model of ALS. Front Cell Neurosci. 2011;5:26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riar AK, Burstein SR, Palomo GM, Arreguin A, Manfredi G, Germain D. Sex specific activation of the ERalpha axis of the mitochondrial UPR (UPRmt) in the G93A-SOD1 mouse model of familial ALS. Hum Mol Genet. 2017 Apr 1;26(7):1318-1327.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cario-Toumaniantz C, Loirand G, Ferrier L, Pacaud P. Non-genomic inhibition of human P2X7 purinoceptor by 17beta-oestradiol. J Physiol. 1998;508(Pt 3):659-666.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cervetto C, Frattaroli D, Maura G, Marcoli M. Motor neuron dysfunction in a mouse model of ALS: gender-dependent effect of P2X7 antagonism. Toxicology. 2013 Sep 6;311(1-2):69-77.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>