<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">31438881</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2019</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>25</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2377</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>19</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2019</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>22</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Intentions of Canadian health professionals towards recommending exercise for people living with ALS.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>204</StartPage><MedlinePgn>204</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">204</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12883-019-1426-z</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">To provide a nationwide overview of the attitudes, social pressure, perceived ability and intentions of health professionals toward exercise prescription for people living with ALS (pALS).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">An online survey of physician and non-physician health professionals (HPs) working in academic ALS clinics across Canada.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The response rate was 48% (84/176) with 30% of respondents identifying as physicians, 63% as other HPs and the remainder as administrative or research personnel. Respondents were sharply divided in their intentions to provide exercise counsel: 24% unlikely and 45% likely. Respondents with low intentions were HPs that considered this activity outside their scope of practice. Measures of intention and attitude were more positive for flexibility compared to strength and aerobic exercise. Perceptions of social pressure and ability to provide exercise counsel were significantly correlated with intention across the three exercise modes in all respondents. Qualitative themes identified as barriers to exercise prescription were lack of confidence or competence (31% physicians, 32% HP), patient tolerance (30% HP), lack of evidence (22% physicians) and lack of infrastructure (22% physicians).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">While "lack of evidence" for the benefit of exercise was a deterrent for physicians, the larger issue for all respondents was building competence and confidence in exercise prescription for pALS.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jones</LastName><ForeName>Kelvin E</ForeName><Initials>KE</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4764-7031</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Kinesiology, Sport, and Recreation, University of Alberta, Edmonton, Canada. kejones@ualberta.ca.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neuroscience and Mental Health Institute, University of Alberta, Edmonton, Canada. kejones@ualberta.ca.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Berry</LastName><ForeName>Tanya R</ForeName><Initials>TR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Kinesiology, Sport, and Recreation, University of Alberta, Edmonton, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Merali</LastName><ForeName>Aaliya S</ForeName><Initials>AS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Kinesiology, Sport, and Recreation, University of Alberta, Edmonton, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bello-Haas</LastName><ForeName>Vanina Dal</ForeName><Initials>VD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Rehabilitation Science, McMaster University, Hamilton, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>201003JNM-225975-MOV</GrantID><Agency>CIHR Neuromuscular Research Partnership</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2019</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100968555</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2377</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000534" MajorTopicYN="Y">rehabilitation</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001291" MajorTopicYN="Y">Attitude of Health Personnel</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002170" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Canada</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005081" MajorTopicYN="Y">Exercise Therapy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006282" MajorTopicYN="Y">Health Personnel</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D033182" MajorTopicYN="N">Intention</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011795" MajorTopicYN="N">Surveys and Questionnaires</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise prescription</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Motor neuron disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">National survey</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Scope of practice</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Theory of Planned Behavior</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2019</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2019</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31438881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6706893</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12883-019-1426-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12883-019-1426-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Dal Bello-Haas V, Krivickas LS, American College of Sports Medicine. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. 3rd ed In: Durstine JL, of Sports Medicine AC, et al., editors. ACSM&#x2019;s exercise management for persons with chronic diseases and disabilities, Ch 44. Champaign: Human Kinetics: 2009. p. 419&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huisman MH, Seelen M, de Jong SW, Dorresteijn KR, van Doormaal PT, van der Kooi, et al. Lifetime physical activity and the risk of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatr. 2013;84(9):976&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23418211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beghi E, Logroscino G, Chio A, Hardiman O, Millul A, Mitchell D, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, physical exercise, trauma and sports: results of a population-based pilot case-control study. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Off Publ World Fed Neurol Res Group Mot Neuron Dis. 2010;11(3):289&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3513269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20433412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chio A, Benzi G, Dossena M, Mutani R, Mora G. Severely increased risk of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis among Italian professional football players. Brain J Neurol. 2005;128(Pt 3):472&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15634730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner MR, Wicks P, Brownstein CA, Massagli MP, Toronjo M, Talbot K, et al. Concordance between site of onset and limb dominance in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatr. 2011;82(8):853&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20562391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scarmeas N, Shih T, Stern Y, Ottman R, Rowland LP. Premorbid weight, body mass, and varsity athletics in ALS. Neurology. 2002;59(5):773&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12221178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Felmus MT, Patten BM, Swanke L. Antecedent events in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology. 1976;26(2):167&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">946326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harwood CA, McDermott CJ, Shaw PJ. Physical activity as an exogenous risk factor in motor neuron disease (MND): a review of the evidence. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Off Publ World Fed Neurol Res Group Mot Neuron Dis. 2009;10(4):191&#x2013;204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19263258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallo V, Vanacore N, Bueno-de Mesquita HB, Vermeulen R, Brayne C, Pearce N, et al. Physical activity and risk of Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis in a prospective cohort study. Eur J Epidemiol. 2016;31(3):255&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4820490</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26968841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamidou B, Couratier P, Besancon C, Nicol M, Preux PM, Marin B. Epidemiological evidence that physical activity is not a risk factor for ALS. Eur J Epidemiol. 2014;29(7):459&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24986107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pupillo E, Messina P, Giussani G, Logroscino G, Zoccolella S, Chio A, et al. Physical activity and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a European population-based case-control study. Ann Neurol. 2014;75(5):708&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24706338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eaglehouse YL, Talbott EO, Chang Y, Kuller LH. Participation in Physical Activity and Risk for Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Mortality Among Postmenopausal Women. JAMA Neurol. 2016;73(3):329&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6044440</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26783702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang F, Hallmarker U, James S, Ingre C, Michaelsson K, Ahlbom A, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis among cross-country skiers in Sweden. Eur J Epidemiol. 2016;31(3):247&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26220522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dal Bello-Haas V, Florence JM. Therapeutic exercise for people with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis or motor neuron disease. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2013;(5). 10.1002/14651858.CD005229.pub3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6769061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23728653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lunetta C, Lizio A, Sansone VA, Cellotto NM, Maestri E, Bettinelli M, et al.Strictly monitored exercise programs reduce motor deterioration in ALS: preliminary results of a randomized controlled trial. J Neurol. 2015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26477027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clawson LL, Cudkowicz M, Krivickas L, Brooks BR, Sanjak M, Allred P, et al. A randomized controlled trial of resistance and endurance exercise in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2018;19(3&#x2013;4):250&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29191052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Mouse Tumor Biology Database. 2016. http://tumor.informatics.jax.org/cancer/_links.html. Accessed 30 July 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner MR. Increased premorbid physical activity and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: born to run rather than run to death, or a seductive myth? J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatr. 2013;84(9):304935.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23447649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berra K, Rippe J, Manson JE. Making physical activity counseling a priority in clinical practice: the time for action is now. Jama. 2015;314(24):2617&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26662069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>AuYoung M, Linke SE, Pagoto S, Buman MP, Craft LL, Richardson CR, et al. Integrating Physical Activity in Primary Care Practice. Am J Med. 2016;129(10):1022&#x2013;1029.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26953063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ajzen I. The theory of planned behavior. Organ Behav Hum Decis Process. 1991;50(2):179&#x2013;211.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krivickas LS. Exercise in neuromuscular disease. J Clin Neuromuscul Dis. 2003;5(1):29&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19078719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kortteisto T, Kaila M, Komulainen J, M&#xe4;ntyranta T, Rissanen P. Healthcare professionals&#x2019; intentions to use clinical guidelines: a survey using the theory of planned behaviour. Implement Sci. 2010;5(1):51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2902417</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20587021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rashidian A, Russell I. Intentions and statins prescribing: can the Theory of Planned Behaviour explain physician behaviour in following guideline recommendations? J Eval Clin Pract. 2011;17(4):749&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21545379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fonteyn M, Fisher A. Use of think aloud method to study nurses&#x2019; reasoning and decision making in clinical practice settings. J Neurosci Nurs J Am Assoc Neurosci Nurses. 1995;27(2):124&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7622950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johansson G. Westerterp KR.Assessment of the physical activity level with two questions: validation with doubly labeled water. Int J Obes (2005) 2008;32(6):1031&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18392036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Field AP. ISM introducing statistical methods. Thousand Oaks: Sage: Andy Field; 2005. Discovering statistics using SPSS: (and sex, drugs and rock&#x2019;n&#x2019;roll)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dunn OJ. Multiple Comparisons Using Rank Sums. Technometrics. 1964;6(3):241.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. A power primer. Psychol Bull. 1992;112(1):155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19565683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller R, Jackson C, Kasarskis E, England J, Forshew D, Johnston W, et al. Practice parameter update: the care of the patient with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: multidisciplinary care, symptom management, and cognitive/behavioral impairment (an evidence-based review): report of the Quality Standards Subcommittee of the American Academy of Neurology. Neurology. 2009;73(15):1227&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2764728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19822873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen P, Abrahams S, Borasio G, De Carvalho M, Chio A, Van Damme P, et al. EFNS task force on diagnosis and management of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: EFNS guidelines on the clinical management of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (MALS)&#x2013;revised report of an EFNS task force. Eur J Neurol. 2012;19(3):360&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21914052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drory VE, Goltsman E, Reznik JG, Mosek A, Korczyn AD. The value of muscle exercise in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Sci. 2001;191(1-2):133&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11677004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dal Bello-Haas V, Florence J, Kloos A, Scheirbecker J, Lopate G, Hayes S, et al. A randomized controlled trial of resistance exercise in individuals with ALS. Neurology. 2007;68(23):2003&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17548549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnsen B, Pugdahl K, Fuglsang-Frederiksen A, Kollewe K, Paracka L, Dengler R, et al. Diagnostic criteria for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A multicentre study of inter-rater variation and sensitivity. Clin Neurophysiol. 2019;130(2):307&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30573424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nair KPS, Marsden J. The management of spasticity in adults. Bmj. 2014;349:g4737.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25096594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katalinic OM, Harvey LA, Herbert RD, Moseley AM, Lannin NA, Schurr K. Stretch for the treatment and prevention of contractures. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2010:(9). 10.1002/14651858.CD007455.pub2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20824861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harvey KOHRMALN LA, Schurr K. Stretch for the treatment and prevention of contractures. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2017;1. 10.1002/14651858.CD007455.pub3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6464268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28146605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwarzer R. Modeling health behavior change: How to predict and modify the adoption and maintenance of health behaviors. Appl Psychol. 2008;57(1):1&#x2013;29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braga ACM, Pinto A, Pinto S, de Carvalho M. The role of moderate aerobic exercise as determined by cardiopulmonary exercise testing in ALS. Neurol Res Int. 2018;2018:10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5832023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29666705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunter GR, McCarthy JP, Bamman MM. Effects of resistance training on older adults. Sports Med. 2004;34(5):329&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15107011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>