<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">31472253</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>28</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1095-9572</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>202</Volume><PubDate><Year>2019</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>15</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>NeuroImage</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Neuroimage</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Differential tractography as a track-based biomarker for neuronal injury.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>116131</StartPage><MedlinePgn>116131</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.neuroimage.2019.116131</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S1053-8119(19)30722-0</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Diffusion MRI tractography has been used to map the axonal structure of the human brain, but its ability to detect neuronal injury is yet to be explored. Here we report differential tractography, a new type of tractography that utilizes repeat MRI scans and a novel tracking strategy to map the exact segment of fiber pathways with a neuronal injury. We examined differential tractography on multiple sclerosis, Huntington's disease, amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, and epileptic patients. The results showed that the affected pathways shown by differential tractography matched well with the unique clinical symptoms of the patients, and the false discovery rate of the findings could be estimated using a sham setting to provide a reliability measurement. This novel approach enables a quantitative and objective method to monitor neuronal injury in individuals, allowing for diagnostic and prognostic evaluation of brain diseases.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2019 Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yeh</LastName><ForeName>Fang-Cheng</ForeName><Initials>FC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurological Surgery, University of Pittsburgh School of Medicine, Pittsburgh, PA, United States; Department of Bioengineering, University of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, PA, United States. Electronic address: frank.yeh@pitt.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zaydan</LastName><ForeName>Islam M</ForeName><Initials>IM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of Pittsburgh School of Medicine, Pittsburgh, PA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Suski</LastName><ForeName>Valerie R</ForeName><Initials>VR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of Pittsburgh School of Medicine, Pittsburgh, PA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lacomis</LastName><ForeName>David</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of Pittsburgh School of Medicine, Pittsburgh, PA, United States; Live Like Lou Center for ALS Research, University of Pittsburgh School of Medicine, Pittsburgh, PA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Richardson</LastName><ForeName>R Mark</ForeName><Initials>RM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurological Surgery, University of Pittsburgh School of Medicine, Pittsburgh, PA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maroon</LastName><ForeName>Joseph C</ForeName><Initials>JC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurological Surgery, University of Pittsburgh School of Medicine, Pittsburgh, PA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Barrios-Martinez</LastName><ForeName>Jessica</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurological Surgery, University of Pittsburgh School of Medicine, Pittsburgh, PA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R56 MH113634</GrantID><Acronym>MH</Acronym><Agency>NIMH NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2019</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Neuroimage</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9215515</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1053-8119</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D015415">Biomarkers</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="Y">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015415" MajorTopicYN="N">Biomarkers</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D056324" MajorTopicYN="N">Diffusion Tensor Imaging</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000592" MajorTopicYN="Y">standards</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004827" MajorTopicYN="N">Epilepsy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="Y">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006816" MajorTopicYN="N">Huntington Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="Y">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009103" MajorTopicYN="N">Multiple Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="Y">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009474" MajorTopicYN="N">Neurons</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="Y">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Differential tractography</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Diffusion MRI</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Epilepsy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fiber tracking</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Huntington&#x2019;s disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Imaging biomarker</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Multiple sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neuronal injury</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2019</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2019</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31472253</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS1539376</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6919327</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuroimage.2019.116131</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S1053-8119(19)30722-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abhinav K, Yeh FC, El-Dokla A, Ferrando LM, Chang YF, Lacomis D, Friedlander RM, Fernandez-Miranda JC, 2014. Use of diffusion spectrum imaging in preliminary longitudinal evaluation of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: development of an imaging biomarker. Front Hum Neurosci 8, 270.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4010737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24808852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashburner J, Friston KJ, 2000. Voxel-based morphometry--the methods. Neuroimage 11, 805&#x2013;821.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10860804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basser PJ, Mattiello J, LeBihan D, 1994. Estimation of the effective self-diffusion tensor from the NMR spin echo. J Magn Reson B 103, 247&#x2013;254.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8019776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Budde MD, Xie M, Cross AH, Song SK, 2009. Axial diffusivity is the primary correlate of axonal injury in the experimental autoimmune encephalomyelitis spinal cord: a quantitative pixelwise analysis. J Neurosci 29, 2805&#x2013;2813.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2673458</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19261876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Callaghan PT, 1991. Principles of Nuclear Magnetic Resonance Microscopy. Oxford University Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filippini N, Douaud G, Mackay CE, Knight S, Talbot K, Turner MR, 2010. Corpus callosum involvement is a consistent feature of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology 75, 1645&#x2013;1652.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2974368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21041787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glasser MF, Smith SM, Marcus DS, Andersson JL, Auerbach EJ, Behrens TE, Coalson TS, Harms MP, Jenkinson M, Moeller S, Robinson EC, Sotiropoulos SN, Xu J, Yacoub E, Ugurbil K, Van Essen DC, 2016. The Human Connectome Project&#x2019;s neuroimaging approach. Nat Neurosci 19, 1175&#x2013;1187.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6172654</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27571196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henf J, Grothe MJ, Brueggen K, Teipel S, Dyrba M, 2018. Mean diffusivity in cortical gray matter in Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease: The importance of partial volume correction. Neuroimage Clin 17, 579&#x2013;586.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5702878</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29201644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huisman TA, Schwamm LH, Schaefer PW, Koroshetz WJ, Shetty-Alva N, Ozsunar Y, Wu O, Sorensen AG, 2004. Diffusion tensor imaging as potential biomarker of white matter injury in diffuse axonal injury. AJNR Am J Neuroradiol 25, 370&#x2013;376.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15037457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loewe K, Machts J, Kaufmann J, Petri S, Heinze HJ, Borgelt C, Harris JA, Vielhaber S, Schoenfeld MA, 2017. Widespread temporo-occipital lobe dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Sci Rep 7, 40252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5220336</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28067298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maier-Hein KH, Neher PF, Houde JC, Cote MA, Garyfallidis E, Zhong J, Chamberland M, Yeh FC, Lin YC, Ji Q, Reddick WE, Glass JO, Chen DQ, Feng Y, Gao C, Wu Y, Ma J, Renjie H, Li Q, Westin CF, Deslauriers-Gauthier S, Gonzalez JOO, Paquette M, St-Jean S, Girard G, Rheault F, Sidhu J, Tax CMW, Guo F, Mesri HY, David S, Froeling M, Heemskerk AM, Leemans A, Bore A, Pinsard B, Bedetti C, Desrosiers M, Brambati S, Doyon J, Sarica A, Vasta R, Cerasa A, Quattrone A, Yeatman J, Khan AR, Hodges W, Alexander S, Romascano D, Barakovic M, Auria A, Esteban O, Lemkaddem A, Thiran JP, Cetingul HE, Odry BL, Mailhe B, Nadar MS, Pizzagalli F, Prasad G, Villalon-Reina JE, Galvis J, Thompson PM, Requejo FS, Laguna PL, Lacerda LM, Barrett R, Dell&#x2019;Acqua F, Catani M, Petit L, Caruyer E, Daducci A, Dyrby TB, Holland-Letz T, Hilgetag CC, Stieltjes B, Descoteaux M, 2017. The challenge of mapping the human connectome based on diffusion tractography. Nat Commun 8, 1349.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5677006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29116093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melonakos ED, Shenton ME, Rathi Y, Terry DP, Bouix S, Kubicki M, 2011. Voxel-based morphometry (VBM) studies in schizophrenia-can white matter changes be reliably detected with VBM? Psychiatry Res 193, 65&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3382976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21684124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raffelt DA, Tournier JD, Smith RE, Vaughan DN, Jackson G, Ridgway GR, Connelly A, 2017. Investigating white matter fibre density and morphology using fixel-based analysis. Neuroimage 144, 58&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5182031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27639350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rovira A, Wattjes MP, Tintore M, Tur C, Yousry TA, Sormani MP, De Stefano N, Filippi M, Auger C, Rocca MA, Barkhof F, Fazekas F, Kappos L, Polman C, Miller D, Montalban X, group, M.s., 2015. Evidence-based guidelines: MAGNIMS consensus guidelines on the use of MRI in multiple sclerosis-clinical implementation in the diagnostic process. Nat Rev Neurol 11, 471&#x2013;482.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26149978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schilling KG, Yeh FC, Nath V, Hansen C, Williams O, Resnick S, Anderson AW, Landman BA, 2019. A fiber coherence index for quality control of B-table orientation in diffusion MRI scans. Magn Reson Imaging 58, 82&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6401245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30682379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song SK, Sun SW, Ramsbottom MJ, Chang C, Russell J, Cross AH, 2002. Dysmyelination revealed through MRI as increased radial (but unchanged axial) diffusion of water. Neuroimage 17, 1429&#x2013;1436.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12414282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song SK, Yoshino J, Le TQ, Lin SJ, Sun SW, Cross AH, Armstrong RC, 2005. Demyelination increases radial diffusivity in corpus callosum of mouse brain. Neuroimage 26, 132&#x2013;140.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15862213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tabrizi SJ, Langbehn DR, Leavitt BR, Roos RA, Durr A, Craufurd D, Kennard C, Hicks SL, Fox NC, Scahill RI, Borowsky B, Tobin AJ, Rosas HD, Johnson H, Reilmann R, Landwehrmeyer B, Stout JC, investigators, T.-H., 2009. Biological and clinical manifestations of Huntington&#x2019;s disease in the longitudinal TRACK-HD study: cross-sectional analysis of baseline data. Lancet Neurol 8, 791&#x2013;801.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3725974</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19646924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tabrizi SJ, Reilmann R, Roos RA, Durr A, Leavitt B, Owen G, Jones R, Johnson H, Craufurd D, Hicks SL, Kennard C, Landwehrmeyer B, Stout JC, Borowsky B, Scahill RI, Frost C, Langbehn DR, investigators, T.-H., 2012. Potential endpoints for clinical trials in premanifest and early Huntington&#x2019;s disease in the TRACK-HD study: analysis of 24 month observational data. Lancet Neurol 11, 42&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22137354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Wang Q, Haldar JP, Yeh FC, Xie M, Sun P, Tu TW, Trinkaus K, Klein RS, Cross AH, Song SK, 2011. Quantification of increased cellularity during inflammatory demyelination. Brain 134, 3590&#x2013;3601.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3235568</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22171354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wattjes MP, Rovira A, Miller D, Yousry TA, Sormani MP, de Stefano MP, Tintore M, Auger C, Tur C, Filippi M, Rocca MA, Fazekas F, Kappos L, Polman C, Frederik B, Xavier M, group, M.s., 2015. Evidence-based guidelines: MAGNIMS consensus guidelines on the use of MRI in multiple sclerosis--establishing disease prognosis and monitoring patients. Nat Rev Neurol 11, 597&#x2013;606.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26369511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wedeen VJ, Rosene DL, Wang R, Dai G, Mortazavi F, Hagmann P, Kaas JH, Tseng WY, 2012. The geometric structure of the brain fiber pathways. Science 335, 1628&#x2013;1634.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3773464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22461612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Werring DJ, Clark CA, Barker GJ, Thompson AJ, Miller DH, 1999. Diffusion tensor imaging of lesions and normal-appearing white matter in multiple sclerosis. Neurology 52, 1626&#x2013;1632.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10331689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Werring DJ, Toosy AT, Clark CA, Parker GJ, Barker GJ, Miller DH, Thompson AJ, 2000. Diffusion tensor imaging can detect and quantify corticospinal tract degeneration after stroke. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 69, 269&#x2013;272.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1737065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10896709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woo CW, Krishnan A, Wager TD, 2014. Cluster-extent based thresholding in fMRI analyses: pitfalls and recommendations. Neuroimage 91, 412&#x2013;419.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4214144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24412399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeh FC, Panesar S, Barrios J, Fernandes D, Abhinav K, Meola A, Fernandez-Miranda JC, 2019. Automatic Removal of False Connections in Diffusion MRI Tractography Using Topology-Informed Pruning (TIP). Neurotherapeutics 16, 52&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6361061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30218214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeh FC, Tseng WY, 2011. NTU-90: a high angular resolution brain atlas constructed by q-space diffeomorphic reconstruction. Neuroimage 58, 91&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21704171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeh FC, Verstynen TD, Wang Y, Fernandez-Miranda JC, Tseng WY, 2013. Deterministic diffusion fiber tracking improved by quantitative anisotropy. PLoS ONE 8, e80713.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3858183</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24348913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeh FC, Vettel JM, Singh A, Poczos B, Grafton ST, Erickson KI, Tseng WI, Verstynen TD, 2016. Quantifying Differences and Similarities in Whole-Brain White Matter Architecture Using Local Connectome Fingerprints. PLoS Comput Biol 12, e1005203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5112901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27846212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeh FC, Wedeen VJ, Tseng WY, 2010. Generalized q-sampling imaging. IEEE Trans Med Imaging 29, 1626&#x2013;1635.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20304721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang F, Wu W, Ning L, McAnulty G, Waber D, Gagoski B, Sarill K, Hamoda HM, Song Y, Cai W, Rathi Y, O&#x2019;Donnell LJ, 2018. Suprathreshold fiber cluster statistics: Leveraging white matter geometry to enhance tractography statistical analysis. Neuroimage 171, 341&#x2013;354.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5857470</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29337279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Fang T, Wang Y, Guo X, Alarefi A, Wang J, Jiang T, Zhang J, 2017. Occipital cortical gyrification reductions associate with decreased functional connectivity in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain Imaging Behav 11, 1&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26780240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>