<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">31495915</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>01</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-4598</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>60</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2019</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Muscle &amp; nerve</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Muscle Nerve</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Taking the eye road: A new access method for powered mobility in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>493</StartPage><EndPage>495</EndPage><MedlinePgn>493-495</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/mus.26696</ELocationID><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Geronimo</LastName><ForeName>Andrew M</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7754-3754</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, Penn State College of Medicine, Hershey, Pennsylvania.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016421">Editorial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016420">Comment</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Muscle Nerve</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7803146</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0148-639X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><SupplMeshList><SupplMeshName Type="Disease" UI="C565957">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis 2, Juvenile</SupplMeshName></SupplMeshList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="CommentOn"><RefSource>Muscle Nerve. 2019 Nov;60(5):513-519</RefSource><PMID Version="1">31397910</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016059" MajorTopicYN="N">Range of Motion, Articular</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014910" MajorTopicYN="Y">Wheelchairs</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2019</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2019</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31495915</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.26696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Woods B, Watson N. A short history of powered wheelchairs. Assist Technol. 2003;15:164-180.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor DM. US Census Bureau 2018 report: Americans with disabilities. https://www.census.gov/content/dam/Census/library/publications/2018/demo/p70-152.pdf. Accessed August 18, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Committee on the Use of Selected Assistive Products and Technologies in Eliminating or Reducing the Effects of Impairments. The Promise of Assistive Technology to Enhance Activity and Work Participation. Washington, DC: National Academies Press; 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sonenblum SE, Sprigle S, Harris FH, Maurer CL. Characterization of power wheelchair use in the home and community. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2008;89:486-491.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finlayson M, Van Denend T. Experiencing the loss of mobility: perspectives of older adults with MS. Disabil Rehabil. 2003;25:1168-1180.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trail M, Nelson N, Van JN, Appel S, Lai EC. Wheelchair use by patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a survey of user characteristics and selection preferences. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2001;82:98-102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ward AL, Hammond S, Holsten S, Bravver E, Brooks BR. Power wheelchair use in persons with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: changes over time. Assist Technol. 2015;27:238-245.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ward AL, Sanjak M, Duffy K, et al. Power wheelchair prescription, utilization, satisfaction, and cost for patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: preliminary data for evidence-based guidelines. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2010;91:268-272.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simpson RC, LoPresti EF, Cooper RA. How many people would benefit from a smart wheelchair? J Rehabil Res Dev. 2008;45:53-72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elliott M, Malvar H, Maassel L, et al. Eye-controlled, power wheelchair performs well for ALS patients. Muscle Nerve. 2019;60:513-519.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henderson GI, Dolan MJ, Geggie CJ. A review and appraisal of clinically prevalent control devices for electrically powered wheelchairs. Technol Disabil. 2013;25:221-232.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dolan MJ, Henderson GI. Control devices for electrically powered wheelchairs: prevalence, defining characteristics and user perspectives. Disabil Rehabil Assist Technol. 2017;12:618-624.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kundu AS, Mazumdar O, Lenka PK, Bhaumik S. Hand gesture recognition based omnidirectional wheelchair control using IMU and EEG sensors. J Intell Robot Syst. 2018;91:529-541.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-Rodr&#xed;guez &#xc1;, Velasco-&#xc1;lvarez F, Ron-Angevin R. Review of real brain-controlled wheelchairs. J Neural Eng. 2016;13:061001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caligari M, Godi M, Guglielmetti S, Franchignoni F, Nardone A. Eye tracking communication devices in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: impact on disability and quality of life. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2013;14:546-552.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cognolato M, Atzori M, M&#xfc;ller H. Head-mounted eye gaze tracking devices: an overview of modern devices and recent advances. J Rehabil Assist Technol Eng. 2018;5:1-13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geronimo A, Simmons Z, Schiff SJ. Performance predictors of brain-computer interfaces in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neural Eng. 2016;13:026002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leaman J, La HM. A comprehensive review of smart wheelchairs: past, present, and future. IEEE Trans Hum Mach Syst. 2017;47:486-499.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kairy D, Rushton PW, Archambault P, et al. Exploring powered wheelchair users and their caregivers' perspectives on potential intelligent power wheelchair use: a qualitative study. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2014;11:2244-2261.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rushton PW, Kairy D, Archambault P, et al. The potential impact of intelligent power wheelchair use on social participation: perspectives of users, caregivers and clinicians. Disabil Rehabil Assist Technol. 2015;10:191-197.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma C, Li W, Gravina R, Fortino G. Posture detection based on smart cushion for wheelchair users. Sensors. 2017;17:719.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>