<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">31498468</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>04</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2990</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>46</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Neuropathology and applied neurobiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Neuropathol Appl Neurobiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Neuropathological characterization of a novel TANK binding kinase (TBK1) gene loss of function mutation associated with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>279</StartPage><EndPage>291</EndPage><MedlinePgn>279-291</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/nan.12578</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="AIMS">Mutations in TANK binding kinase gene (TBK1) are causative in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS), however correlations between clinical features and TBK1 mutations have not been fully elucidated. We aimed to identify and compare TBK1 mutations to clinical features in a cohort of ALS patients from Northern England.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">TBK1 mutations were analysed in 290 ALS cases. Immunohistochemistry was performed in brain and spinal cord of one case with a novel in-frame deletion.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Seven TBK1 variants were identified, including one novel in-frame deletion (p.85delIle). In silico analysis and literature suggested four variants were pathogenic, and three were variants of uncertain significance or benign. Post-mortem immunohistochemistry established an individual with the novel in-frame deletion had classical ALS and Type B FTLD-TDP pathology, with no changes in TBK1 staining or interferon regulatory factor IRF3.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">TBK1 mutations were present in 1.38% of our cohort, and screening showed no clear genotype-phenotype associations compared to other genetic and sporadic ALS cases. TBK1 immunohistochemistry was consistent with previously published literature and we are the first to show no differential expression of interferon regulatory factor IRF3, a downstream effector of TBK1 in the immune pathway, in the TBK1-mutant tissue, compared to controls.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2019 British Neuropathological Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Weinreich</LastName><ForeName>M</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience, Sheffield Institute for Translational Neuroscience, University of Sheffield, Sheffield, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Shepheard</LastName><ForeName>S R</ForeName><Initials>SR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience, Sheffield Institute for Translational Neuroscience, University of Sheffield, Sheffield, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Verber</LastName><ForeName>N</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience, Sheffield Institute for Translational Neuroscience, University of Sheffield, Sheffield, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wyles</LastName><ForeName>M</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience, Sheffield Institute for Translational Neuroscience, University of Sheffield, Sheffield, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Heath</LastName><ForeName>P R</ForeName><Initials>PR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience, Sheffield Institute for Translational Neuroscience, University of Sheffield, Sheffield, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Highley</LastName><ForeName>J R</ForeName><Initials>JR</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4969-6526</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience, Sheffield Institute for Translational Neuroscience, University of Sheffield, Sheffield, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Kirby</LastName><ForeName>J</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7468-5917</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience, Sheffield Institute for Translational Neuroscience, University of Sheffield, Sheffield, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Shaw</LastName><ForeName>P J</ForeName><Initials>PJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience, Sheffield Institute for Translational Neuroscience, University of Sheffield, Sheffield, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Acronym>DH_</Acronym><Agency>Department of Health</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2019</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Neuropathol Appl Neurobiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7609829</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0305-1846</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 2.7.11.1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D017346">Protein Serine-Threonine Kinases</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 2.7.11.1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C403191">TBK1 protein, human</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><SupplMeshList><SupplMeshName Type="Disease" UI="C531617">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis 1</SupplMeshName></SupplMeshList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="Y">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="Y">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D056726" MajorTopicYN="N">Genetic Association Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020022" MajorTopicYN="N">Genetic Predisposition to Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000073658" MajorTopicYN="N">Loss of Function Mutation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017346" MajorTopicYN="N">Protein Serine-Threonine Kinases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="Y">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">
TBK1
</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ALS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">MND</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">loss of function</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neuropathology</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2019</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31498468</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/nan.12578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Alsultan AA, Waller R, Heath PR, Kirby J. The genetics of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: current insights. Degener Neurol Neuromuscul Dis 2016; 6: 49-64</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardiman O, Al-Chalabi A, Chio A, Corr EM, Logroscino G, Robberecht W, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat Rev Dis Primers 2017; 3: 17071</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooper-Knock J, Hewitt C, Highley JR, Brockington A, Milano A, Man S, et al. Clinico-pathological features in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with expansions in C9ORF72. Brain 2012; 135(Pt 3): 751-64</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cirulli ET, Lasseigne BN, Petrovski S, Sapp PC, Dion PA, Leblond CS, et al. Exome sequencing in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis identifies risk genes and pathways. Science 2015; 347: 1436-41</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freischmidt A, Wieland T, Richter B, Ruf W, Schaeffer V, Muller K, et al. Haploinsufficiency of TBK1 causes familial ALS and fronto-temporal dementia. Nat Neurosci 2015; 18: 631-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Zee J, Gijselinck I, Van Mossevelde S, Perrone F, Dillen L, Heeman B, et al. TBK1 mutation spectrum in an extended European patient cohort with frontotemporal dementia and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Hum Mutat 2017; 38: 297-309</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Mossevelde S, van der Zee J, Gijselinck I, Engelborghs S, Sieben A, Van Langenhove T, et al. Clinical features of TBK1 carriers compared with C9orf72, GRN and non-mutation carriers in a Belgian cohort. Brain 2016; 139(Pt 2): 452-67</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borghero G, Pugliatti M, Marrosu F, Marrosu MG, Murru MR, Floris G, et al. TBK1 is associated with ALS and ALS-FTD in Sardinian patients. Neurobiol Aging 2016; 43: e1-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pottier C, Bieniek KF, Finch N, van de Vorst M, Baker M, Perkersen R, et al. Whole-genome sequencing reveals important role for TBK1 and OPTN mutations in frontotemporal lobar degeneration without motor neuron disease. Acta Neuropathol 2015; 130: 77-92</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiao B, Sun Q, Yuan Z, Wang J, Zhou L, Yan X, et al. Rare TBK1 variants in patients with frontotemporal dementia and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in a Chinese cohort. Transl Neurodegener 2018; 7: 31</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pozzi L, Valenza F, Mosca L, Dal Mas A, Domi T, Romano A, et al. TBK1 mutations in Italian patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: genetic and functional characterisation. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2017; 88: 869-75</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tohnai G, Nakamura R, Sone J, Nakatochi M, Yokoi D, Katsuno M, et al. Frequency and characteristics of the TBK1 gene variants in Japanese patients with sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurobiol Aging 2018; 64: e15-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gijselinck I, Van Mossevelde S, van der Zee J, Sieben A, Philtjens S, Heeman B, et al. Loss of TBK1 is a frequent cause of frontotemporal dementia in a Belgian cohort. Neurology 2015; 85: 2116-25</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verheijen J, van der Zee J, Gijselinck I, Van den Bossche T, Dillen L, Heeman B, et al. Common and rare TBK1 variants in early-onset Alzheimer disease in a European cohort. Neurobiol Aging 2018; 62: e1-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilke C, Baets J, De Bleecker JL, Deconinck T, Biskup S, Hayer SN, et al. Beyond ALS and FTD: the phenotypic spectrum of TBK1 mutations includes PSP-like and cerebellar phenotypes. Neurobiol Aging 2018; 62: e9-13</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui R, Tuo M, Li P, Zhou C. Association between TBK1 mutations and risk of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis/frontotemporal dementia spectrum: a meta-analysis. Neurol Sci 2018; 39: 811-20</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Majo M, Topp SD, Smith BN, Nishimura AL, Chen HJ, Gkazi AS, et al. ALS-associated missense and nonsense TBK1 mutations can both cause loss of kinase function. Neurobiol Aging 2018; 71: e1-10</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oakes JA, Davies MC, Collins MO. TBK1: a new player in ALS linking autophagy and neuroinflammation. Mol Brain 2017; 10: 5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fecto F, Yan J, Vemula SP, Liu E, Yang Y, Chen W, et al. SQSTM1 mutations in familial and sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Arch Neurol 2011; 68: 1440-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maruyama H, Morino H, Ito H, Izumi Y, Kato H, Watanabe Y, et al. Mutations of optineurin in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nature 2010; 465: 223-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le Ber I, De Septenville A, Millecamps S, Camuzat A, Caroppo P, Couratier P, et al. TBK1 mutation frequencies in French frontotemporal dementia and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis cohorts. Neurobiol Aging 2015; 36: 3116.e5-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kearse M, Moir R, Wilson A, Stones-Havas S, Cheung M, Sturrock S, et al. Geneious basic: an integrated and extendable desktop software platform for the organization and analysis of sequence data. Bioinformatics 2012; 28: 1647-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwarz JM, Cooper DN, Schuelke M, Seelow D. MutationTaster2: mutation prediction for the deep-sequencing age. Nat Methods 2014; 11: 361-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adzhubei IA, Schmidt S, Peshkin L, Ramensky VE, Gerasimova A, Bork P, et al. A method and server for predicting damaging missense mutations. Nat Methods 2010; 7: 248-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sim NL, Kumar P, Hu J, Henikoff S, Schneider G, Ng PC. SIFT web server: predicting effects of amino acid substitutions on proteins. Nucleic Acids Res 2012; 40: W452-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desmet FO, Hamroun D, Lalande M, Collod-Beroud G, Claustres M, Beroud C. Human splicing finder: an online bioinformatics tool to predict splicing signals. Nucleic Acids Res. 2009; 37: e67</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirby J, Highley JR, Cox L, Goodall EF, Hewitt C, Hartley JA, et al. Lack of unique neuropathology in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis associated with p. K54E angiogenin (ANG) mutation. Neuropathol Appl Neurobiol 2013; 39: 562-71</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wharton SB, Minett T, Drew D, Forster G, Matthews F, Brayne C, et al. Epidemiological pathology of Tau in the ageing brain: application of staging for neuropil threads (BrainNet Europe protocol) to the MRC cognitive function and ageing brain study. Acta Neuropathol Commun 2016; 4: 11</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Project MinE ASC. Project MinE: study design and pilot analyses of a large-scale whole-genome sequencing study in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Eur J Hum Genet 2018; 26: 1537-46</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackenzie IR, Neumann M, Baborie A, Sampathu DM, Du Plessis D, Jaros E, et al. A harmonized classification system for FTLD-TDP pathology. Acta Neuropathol 2011; 122: 111-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alafuzoff I, Arzberger T, Al-Sarraj S, Bodi I, Bogdanovic N, Braak H, et al. Staging of neurofibrillary pathology in Alzheimer's disease: a study of the BrainNet Europe Consortium. Brain Pathol. 2008; 18: 484-96</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>