<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">31509351</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1932-8494</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>303</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>May</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Anatomical record (Hoboken, N.J. : 2007)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Anat Rec (Hoboken)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Size-Dependent Vulnerability of Lumbar Motor Neuron Dendritic Degeneration in SOD1<sup>G93A</sup> Mice.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1455</StartPage><EndPage>1471</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1455-1471</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/ar.24255</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The motor neuron (MN) soma surface area is correlated with motor unit type. Larger MNs innervate fast fatigue-intermediate (FInt) or fast-fatiguable (FF) muscle fibers in type FInt and FF motor units, respectively. Smaller MNs innervate slow-twitch fatigue-resistant (S) or fast fatigue-resistant (FR) muscle fibers in type S and FR motor units, respectively. In amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS), FInt and FF motor units are more vulnerable, with denervation and MN death occurring for these units before the more resilient S and FR units. Abnormal MN dendritic arbors have been observed in ALS in humans and rodent models. We used a Golgi-Cox impregnation protocol to examine soma size-dependent changes in the dendritic morphology of lumbar MNs in SOD1<sup>G93A</sup> mice, a model of ALS, at pre-symptomatic, onset and mid-disease stages. In wildtype control mice, the relationship between MN soma surface area and dendritic length or dendritic spine number was highly linear (i.e., increased MN soma size correlated with increased dendritic length and spines). By contrast, in SOD1<sup>G93A</sup> mice, this linear relationship was lost and dendritic length reduction and spine loss were observed in larger MNs, from pre-symptomatic stages onward. These changes correlated with the neuromotor symptoms of ALS in rodent models. At presymptomatic ages, changes were restricted to the larger MNs, likely to comprise vulnerable FInt and FF motor units. Our results suggest morphological changes of MN dendrites and dendritic spines are likely to contribute ALS pathogenesis, not compensate for it. Anat Rec, 303:1455-1471, 2020. &#xa9; 2019 American Association for Anatomy.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2019 American Association for Anatomy.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fogarty</LastName><ForeName>Matthew J</ForeName><Initials>MJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5140-6612</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Biomedical Sciences, The University of Queensland, St Lucia, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology and Biomedical Engineering, Mayo Clinic, Rochester, Minnesota.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mu</LastName><ForeName>Erica W H</ForeName><Initials>EWH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Biomedical Sciences, The University of Queensland, St Lucia, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lavidis</LastName><ForeName>Nickolas A</ForeName><Initials>NA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Biomedical Sciences, The University of Queensland, St Lucia, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Noakes</LastName><ForeName>Peter G</ForeName><Initials>PG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Biomedical Sciences, The University of Queensland, St Lucia, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Queensland Brain Institute, The University of Queensland, St Lucia, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bellingham</LastName><ForeName>Mark C</ForeName><Initials>MC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Biomedical Sciences, The University of Queensland, St Lucia, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2019</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Anat Rec (Hoboken)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101292775</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1932-8486</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 1.15.1.1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000072105">Superoxide Dismutase-1</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="Y">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003712" MajorTopicYN="N">Dendrites</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="Y">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D049229" MajorTopicYN="N">Dendritic Spines</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004195" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Models, Animal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051379" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008822" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice, Transgenic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009046" MajorTopicYN="N">Motor Neurons</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="Y">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000072105" MajorTopicYN="N">Superoxide Dismutase-1</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="Y">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SOD1G93A mouse</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dendrite</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dendritic spine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">motor neuron disease</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2019</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2019</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31509351</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ar.24255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>LITERATURE CITED</Title><Reference><Citation>Amendola J, Durand J. 2008. Morphological differences between wild-type and transgenic superoxide dismutase 1 lumbar motoneurons in postnatal mice. J Comp Neurol 511:329-341.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arellano JI, Benavides-Piccione R, Defelipe J, Yuste R. 2007. Ultrastructure of dendritic spines: correlation between synaptic and spine morphologies. Front Neurosci 1:131-143.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bae YC, Nakamura T, Ihn HJ, Choi MH, Yoshida A, Moritani M, Honma S, Shigenaga Y. 1999. Distribution pattern of inhibitory and excitatory synapses in the dendritic tree of single masseter alpha-motoneurons in the cat. J Comp Neurol 414:454-468.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bae JS, Simon NG, Menon P, Vucic S, Kiernan MC. 2013. The puzzling case of hyperexcitability in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Clin Neurol 9:65-74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bandaru SP, Liu S, Waxman SG, Tan AM. 2015. Dendritic spine dysgenesis contributes to hyperreflexia after spinal cord injury. J Neurophysiol 113:1598-1615.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellinger DL, Anderson WJ. 1987. Postnatal development of cell columns and their associated dendritic bundles in the lumbosacral spinal cord of the rat. II. The ventromedial cell column. Brain Res 432:69-82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellingham MC. 2011. A review of the neural mechanisms of action and clinical efficiency of riluzole in treating amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: what have we learned in the last decade? CNS Neurosci Ther 17:4-31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brandenburg JE, Gransee HM, Fogarty MJ, Sieck GC. 2018. Differences in lumbar motor neuron pruning in an animal model of early onset spasticity. J Neurophysiol 120:601-609.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brannstrom T. 1993. Quantitative synaptology of functionally different types of cat medial gastrocnemius alpha-motoneurons. J Comp Neurol 330:439-454.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke RE, Levine DN, Zajac FE 3rd. 1971. Mammalian motor units: physiological-histochemical correlation in three types in cat gastrocnemius. Science 174:709-712.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke RE, Levine DN, Tsairis P, Zajac FE 3rd. 1973. Physiological types and histochemical profiles in motor units of the cat gastrocnemius. J Physiol 234:723-748.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charcot J-M, Joffroy A. 1869. Deux cas d'atrophie musculaire progressive avec lesions de la substance grise et des faisceaux antero-lateraux de la moelle epiniere. Arch Physiol Neurol Pathol 2:744-754.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conradi S, Kellerth JO, Berthold CH, Hammarberg C. 1979. Electron microscopic studies of serially sectioned cat spinal alpha-motoneurons. IV. Motoneurons innervating slow-twitch (type S) units of the soleus muscle. J Comp Neurol 184:769-782.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cullheim S, Ulfhake B. 1979. Relations between cell body size, axon diameter and axon conduction velocity of triceps surae alpha montoneurons during the postnatal development in the cat. J Comp Neurol 188:679-686.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cullheim S, Fleshman JW, Glenn LL, Burke RE. 1987. Membrane area and dendritic structure in type-identified triceps surae alpha motoneurons. J Comp Neurol 255:68-81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dukkipati SS, Garrett TL, Elbasiouny SM. 2018. The vulnerability of spinal motoneurons and soma size plasticity in a mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Physiol 596:1723-1745.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eisen A, Nakajima M, Weber M. 1998. Corticomotorneuronal hyper-excitability in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Sci 160(Suppl 1):S64-S68.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filipchuk AA, Durand J. 2012. Postnatal dendritic development in lumbar motoneurons in mutant superoxide dismutase 1 mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuroscience 209:144-154.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foerster BR, Pomper MG, Callaghan BC, Petrou M, Edden RA, Mohamed MA, Welsh RC, Carlos RC, Barker PB, Feldman EL. 2013. An imbalance between excitatory and inhibitory neurotransmitters in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis revealed by use of 3-T proton magnetic resonance spectroscopy. JAMA Neurol 70:1009-1016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fogarty MJ. 2018a. The bigger they are the harder they fall: size-dependent vulnerability of motor neurons in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Physiol 596:2471-2472.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fogarty MJ. 2018b. Driven to decay: excitability and synaptic abnormalities in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain Res Bull 140:318-333.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fogarty MJ. 2019. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis as a synaptopathy. Neural Regen Res 14:189-192.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fogarty MJ, Sieck GC. 2019. Evolution and functional differentiation of the diaphragm muscle of mammals. Compr Physiol 9:715-766.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fogarty MJ, Hammond LA, Kanjhan R, Bellingham MC, Noakes PG. 2013. A method for the three-dimensional reconstruction of neurobiotin-filled neurons and the location of their synaptic inputs. Front Neural Circuit 7:153.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fogarty MJ, Noakes PG, Bellingham MC. 2015. Motor cortex layer V pyramidal neurons exhibit dendritic regression, spine loss, and increased synaptic excitation in the presymptomatic hSOD1(G93A) mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurosci 35:643-647.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fogarty MJ, Kanjhan R, Bellingham MC, Noakes PG. 2016a. Glycinergic neurotransmission: a potent regulator of embryonic motor neuron dendritic morphology and synaptic plasticity. J Neurosci 36:80-87.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fogarty MJ, Klenowski PM, Lee JD, Drieberg-Thompson JR, Bartlett SE, Ngo ST, Hilliard MA, Bellingham MC, Noakes PG. 2016b. Cortical synaptic and dendritic spine abnormalities in a presymptomatic TDP-43 model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Sci Rep 6:37968.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fogarty MJ, Mu EW, Noakes PG, Lavidis NA, Bellingham MC. 2016c. Marked changes in dendritic structure and spine density precede significant neuronal death in vulnerable cortical pyramidal neuron populations in the SOD1(G93A) mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathol Commun 4:77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fogarty MJ, Kanjhan R, Yanagawa Y, Noakes PG, Bellingham MC. 2017a. Alterations in hypoglossal motor neurons due to GAD67 and VGAT deficiency in mice. Exp Neurol 289:117-127.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fogarty MJ, Mu EWH, Lavidis NA, Noakes PG, Bellingham MC. 2017b. Motor areas show altered dendritic structure in an amyotrophic lateral sclerosis mouse model. Front Neurosci 11:609.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fogarty MJ, Mantilla CB, Sieck GC. 2018a. Breathing: motor control of diaphragm muscle. Physiology (Bethesda) 33:113-126.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fogarty MJ, Omar TS, Zhan WZ, Mantilla CB, Sieck GC. 2018b. Phrenic motor neuron loss in aged rats. J Neurophysiol 119:1852-1862.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freria CM, Hall JC, Wei P, Guan Z, McTigue DM, Popovich PG. 2017. Deletion of the fractalkine receptor, CX3CR1, improves endogenous repair, axon sprouting, and synaptogenesis after spinal cord injury in mice. J Neurosci 37:3568-3587.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frey D, Schneider C, Xu L, Borg J, Spooren W, Caroni P. 2000. Early and selective loss of neuromuscular synapse subtypes with low sprouting competence in motoneuron diseases. J Neurosci 20:2534-2542.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geevasinga N, Menon P, Ozdinler PH, Kiernan MC, Vucic S. 2016. Pathophysiological and diagnostic implications of cortical dysfunction in ALS. Nat Rev Neurol 12:651-661.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Genc B, Jara JH, Lagrimas AK, Pytel P, Roos RP, Mesulam MM, Geula C, Bigio EH, Ozdinler PH. 2017. Apical dendrite degeneration, a novel cellular pathology for Betz cells in ALS. Sci Rep 7:41765.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gurney ME, Pu H, Chiu AY, Dal Canto MC, Polchow CY, Alexander DD, Caliendo J, Hentati A, Kwon YW, Deng HX, et al. 1994. Motor neuron degeneration in mice that express a human Cu, Zn superoxide dismutase mutation. Science 264:1772-1775.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hammer RP Jr, Tomiyasu U, Scheibel AB. 1979. Degeneration of the human Betz cell due to amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Exp Neurol 63:336-346.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Handley EE, Pitman KA, Dawkins E, Young KM, Clark RM, Jiang TC, Turner BJ, Dickson TC, Blizzard CA. 2017. Synapse dysfunction of layer V pyramidal neurons precedes neurodegeneration in a mouse model of TDP-43 proteinopathies. Cereb Cortex 27:3630-3647.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardiman O, van den Berg LH, Kiernan MC. 2011. Clinical diagnosis and management of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat Rev Neurol 7:639-649.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris KM. 1999. Structure, development, and plasticity of dendritic spines. Curr Opin Neurobiol 9:343-348.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris KM, Jensen FE, Tsao B. 1992. Three-dimensional structure of dendritic spines and synapses in rat hippocampus (CA1) at postnatal day 15 and adult ages: implications for the maturation of synaptic physiology and long-term potentiation. J Neurosci 12:2685-2705.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heckman CJ, Enoka RM. 2012. Motor unit. Compr Physiol 2:2629-2682.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hegedus J, Putman CT, Gordon T. 2007. Time course of preferential motor unit loss in the SOD1 G93A mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurobiol Dis 28:154-164.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hegedus J, Putman CT, Tyreman N, Gordon T. 2008. Preferential motor unit loss in the SOD1 G93A transgenic mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Physiol 586:3337-3351.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henneman E. 1957. Relation between size of neurons and their susceptibility to discharge. Science 126:1345-1347.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henneman E, Somjen G, Carpenter DO. 1965. Functional Significance of Cell Size in Spinal Motoneurons. J Neurophysiol 28:560-580.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Tong J, Bi F, Wu Q, Huang B, Zhou H, Xia XG. 2012. Entorhinal cortical neurons are the primary targets of FUS mislocalization and ubiquitin aggregation in FUS transgenic rats. Hum Mol Genet 21:4602-4614.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inglis FM, Crockett R, Korada S, Abraham WC, Hollmann M, Kalb RG. 2002. The AMPA receptor subunit GluR1 regulates dendritic architecture of motor neurons. J Neurosci 22:8042-8051.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jara JH, Villa SR, Khan NA, Bohn MC, Ozdinler PH. 2012. AAV2 mediated retrograde transduction of corticospinal motor neurons reveals initial and selective apical dendrite degeneration in ALS. Neurobiol Dis 47:174-183.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jara JH, Genc B, Cox GA, Bohn MC, Roos RP, Macklis JD, Ulupinar E, Ozdinler PH. 2015. Corticospinal motor neurons are susceptible to increased ER stress and display profound degeneration in the absence of UCHL1 function. Cereb Cortex 11:4259-4272.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones EG, Powell TP. 1969. Morphological variations in the dendritic spines of the neocortex. J Cell Sci 5:509-529.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalb RG. 1994. Regulation of motor neuron dendrite growth by NMDA receptor activation. Development 120:3063-3071.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanjhan R, Fogarty MJ, Noakes PG, Bellingham MC. 2015. Developmental changes in the morphology of mouse hypoglossal motor neurons. Brain Struct Funct 7:3755-3786.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaplan A, Spiller KJ, Towne C, Kanning KC, Choe GT, Geber A, Akay T, Aebischer P, Henderson CE. 2014. Neuronal matrix metalloproteinase-9 is a determinant of selective neurodegeneration. Neuron 81:333-348.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kato T, Hirano A, Donnenfeld H. 1987. A Golgi study of the large anterior horn cells of the lumbar cords in normal spinal cords and in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathol 75:34-40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kellerth, J. O., C. H. Berthold and S. conradi (1979). "Electron microscopic studies of serially sectioned cat spinal alpha-motoneurons. III. Motoneurons innervating fast-twitch (type FR) units of the gastrocnemius muscle." J Comp Neurol 184: 755-767.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiernan JA, Hudson AJ. 1991. Changes in sizes of cortical and lower motor neurons in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain 114(Pt 2):843-853.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiernan MC, Petri S. 2012. Hyperexcitability and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology 78:1544-1545.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiernan MC, Vucic S, Cheah BC, Turner MR, Eisen A, Hardiman O, Burrell JR, Zoing MC. 2011. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet 377:942-955.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klenowski PM, Fogarty MJ, Belmer A, Noakes PG, Bellingham MC, Bartlett SE. 2015. Structural and functional characterization of dendritic arbors and GABAergic synaptic inputs on interneurons and principal cells in the rat basolateral amygdala. J Neurophysiol 114:942-957.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klenowski PM, Fogarty MJ, Shariff M, Belmer A, Bellingham MC, Bartlett SE. 2016a. Increased synaptic excitation and abnormal dendritic structure of prefrontal cortex layer V pyramidal neurons following prolonged binge-like consumption of ethanol. eNeuro 6:1-15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klenowski PM, Shariff MR, Belmer A, Fogarty MJ, Mu EW, Bellingham MC, Bartlett SE. 2016b. Prolonged consumption of sucrose in a binge-like manner, alters the morphology of medium spiny neurons in the nucleus accumbens shell. Front Behav Neurosci 10:54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klenowski PM, Wright SE, Mu EWH, Noakes PG, Lavidis NA, Bartlett SE, Bellingham MC, Fogarty MJ. 2017. Investigating methodological differences in the assessment of dendritic morphology of basolateral amygdala principal neurons: a comparison of Golgi-Cox and neurobiotin electroporation techniques. Brain Sci 7: 1-12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuhnlein P, Gdynia HJ, Sperfeld AD, Lindner-Pfleghar B, Ludolph AC, Prosiegel M, Riecker A. 2008. Diagnosis and treatment of bulbar symptoms in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat Clin Pract Neurol 4:366-374.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee JD, Kamaruzaman NA, Fung JN, Taylor SM, Turner BJ, Atkin JD, Woodruff TM, Noakes PG. 2013. Dysregulation of the complement cascade in the hSOD1G93A transgenic mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neuroinflammation 10:119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leroy F, Zytnicki D. 2015. Is hyperexcitability really guilty in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis? Neural Regen Res 10:1413-1415.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leroy F, Lamotte d'Incamps B, Imhoff-Manuel RD, Zytnicki D. 2014. Early intrinsic hyperexcitability does not contribute to motoneuron degeneration in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Elife 3:1-25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Brewer D, Burke RE, Ascoli GA. 2005. Developmental changes in spinal motoneuron dendrites in neonatal mice. J Comp Neurol 483:304-317.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liddell EGT, Sherrington CS. 1925. Recruitment and some other features of reflex inhibition. Proc R Soc Lond B 97:488-518.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma WY, Vacca-Galloway LL. 1991. Reduced branching and length of dendrites detected in cervical spinal cord motoneurons of Wobbler mouse, a model for inherited motoneuron disease. J Comp Neurol 311:210-222.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manuel M, Chardon M, Tysseling V, Heckman CJ. 2019. Scaling of motor output, from mouse to humans. Physiology (Bethesda) 34:5-13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ngo ST, Baumann F, Ridall PG, Pettitt AN, Henderson RD, Bellingham MC, McCombe PA. 2012. The relationship between Bayesian motor unit number estimation and histological measurements of motor neurons in wild-type and SOD1(G93A) mice. Clin Neurophysiol 123:2080-2091.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nieto-Gonzalez JL, Moser J, Lauritzen M, Schmitt-John T, Jensen K. 2011. Reduced GABAergic inhibition explains cortical hyperexcitability in the wobbler mouse model of ALS. Cereb Cortex 21:625-635.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nijssen J, Comley LH, Hedlund E. 2017. Motor neuron vulnerability and resistance in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathol 133:863-885.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ornung G, Ottersen OP, Cullheim S, Ulfhake B. 1998. Distribution of glutamate-, glycine- and GABA-immunoreactive nerve terminals on dendrites in the cat spinal motor nucleus. Exp Brain Res 118:517-532.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peters A, Kaiserman-Abramof IR. 1970. The small pyramidal neuron of the rat cerebral cortex. The perikaryon, dendrites and spines. Am J Anat 127:321-355.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plaitakis A, Caroscio JT. 1987. Abnormal glutamate metabolism in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol 22:575-579.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rafuse VF, Pattullo MC, Gordon T. 1997. Innervation ratio and motor unit force in large muscles: a study of chronically stimulated cat medial gastrocnemius. J Physiol 499(Pt 3):809-823.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosen DR, Siddique T, Patterson D, Figlewicz DA, Sapp P, Hentati A, Donaldson D, Goto J, P J, O'Regan HX, et al. 1993. Mutations in Cu/Zn superoxide dismutase gene are associated with familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nature 362:59-62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rothstein JD, Tsai G, Kuncl RW, Clawson L, Cornblath DR, Drachman DB, Pestronk A, Stauch BL, Coyle JT. 1990. Abnormal excitatory amino acid metabolism in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol 28:18-25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rutledge LT, Duncan J, Beatty N. 1969. A study of pyramidal cell axon collaterals in intact and partially isolated adult cerebral cortex. Brain Res 16:15-22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saba L, Viscomi MT, Caioli S, Pignataro A, Bisicchia E, Pieri M, Molinari M, Ammassari-Teule M, Zona C. 2015. Altered functionality, morphology, and vesicular glutamate transporter expression of cortical motor neurons from a presymptomatic mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Cereb Cortex 4:1512-1528.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schiaffino S, Reggiani C. 2011. Fiber types in mammalian skeletal muscles. Physiol Rev 91:1447-1531.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sgobio C, Trabalza A, Spalloni A, Zona C, Carunchio I, Longone P, Ammassari-Teule M. 2008. Abnormal medial prefrontal cortex connectivity and defective fear extinction in the presymptomatic G93A SOD1 mouse model of ALS. Genes Brain Behav 7:427-434.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaw PJ, Chinnery RM, Thagesen H, Borthwick GM, Ince PG. 1997. Immunocytochemical study of the distribution of the free radical scavenging enzymes Cu/Zn superoxide dismutase (SOD1); MN superoxide dismutase (MN SOD) and catalase in the normal human spinal cord and in motor neuron disease. J Neurol Sci 147:115-125.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shigenaga Y, Bae YC, Moritani M, Yoshida A. 2007. Spatial distribution patterns of excitatory and inhibitory synapses in the dendritic tree differ between jaw-closing and -opening motoneurons. Arch Oral Biol 52:321-324.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shoenfeld L, Westenbroek RE, Fisher E, Quinlan KA, Tysseling VM, Powers RK, Heckman CJ, Binder MD. 2014. Soma size and Cav1.3 channel expression in vulnerable and resistant motoneuron populations of the SOD1G93A mouse model of ALS. Physiol Rep 2:1-13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sieck GC, Fournier M. 1989. Diaphragm motor unit recruitment during ventilatory and nonventilatory behaviors. J Appl Physiol (1985) 66:2539-2545.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Somjen G, Carpenter DO, Henneman E. 1965. Responses of motoneurons of different sizes to graded stimulation of supraspinal centers of the brain. J Neurophysiol 28:958-965.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spalloni A, Geracitano R, Berretta N, Sgobio C, Bernardi G, Mercuri NB, Longone P, Ammassari-Teule M. 2006. Molecular and synaptic changes in the hippocampus underlying superior spatial abilities in pre-symptomatic G93A+/+ mice overexpressing the human Cu/Zn superoxide dismutase (Gly93 &gt; ALA) mutation. Exp Neurol 197:505-514.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steyn FJ, Lee K, Fogarty MJ, Veldhuis JD, McCombe PA, Bellingham MC, Ngo ST, Chen C. 2013. Growth hormone secretion is correlated with neuromuscular innervation rather than motor neuron number in early-symptomatic male amyotrophic lateral sclerosis mice. Endocrinology 154:4695-4706.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Udaka F, Kameyama M, Tomonaga M. 1986. Degeneration of Betz cells in motor neuron disease. A Golgi study. Acta Neuropathol 70:289-295.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ulfhake B, Cullheim S. 1988. Postnatal development of cat hind limb motoneurons. III: Changes in size of motoneurons supplying the triceps surae muscle. J Comp Neurol 278:103-120.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S, Rothstein JD, Kiernan MC. 2014. Advances in treating amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: insights from pathophysiological studies. Trends Neurosci 37:433-442.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams PA, Bellinger DL, Wilson CG. 2018. Changes in the Morphology of Hypoglossal Motor Neurons in the Brainstem of Developing Rats. Anat Rec (Hoboken) 302:869-892.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Q, Liu M, Huang C, Liu X, Huang B, Li N, Zhou H, Xia XG. 2015. Pathogenic Ubqln2 gains toxic properties to induce neuron death. Acta Neuropathol 129:417-428.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuste R, Bonhoeffer T. 2001. Morphological changes in dendritic spines associated with long-term synaptic plasticity. Annu Rev Neurosci 24:1071-1089.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Zundert B, Peuscher MH, Hynynen M, Chen A, Neve RL, Brown RH Jr, Constantine-Paton M, Bellingham MC. 2008. Neonatal neuronal circuitry shows hyperexcitable disturbance in a mouse model of the adult-onset neurodegenerative disease amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurosci 28:10864-10874.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>