<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">31523813</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>08</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1469-7793</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>597</Volume><Issue>22</Issue><PubDate><Year>2019</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Journal of physiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Physiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Absence of hyperexcitability of spinal motoneurons in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>5445</StartPage><EndPage>5467</EndPage><MedlinePgn>5445-5467</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1113/JP278117</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="KEY POINTS">&#x2022;Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) motoneurons become hypoexcitable with disease progression in experimental models, raising questions about the neural hyperexcitability supported by clinical observations. &#x2022;A variant of the &#x2206;F method, based on motor unit discharge frequency modulations during recruitment and derecruitment, has been developed to investigate the motoneuron capacity to self-sustained discharge in patients. &#x2022;The modulation of motor unit firing rate during ramp contraction and vibration-induced recruitment are modified in ALS, suggesting lower motoneuron capacity to self-sustained discharge, which is a sign of hypoexcitability. &#x2022;&#x2206;F-D decreases with functional impairment and its reduction is more pronounced in fast progressors. &#x2022;In patients with ALS, motoneurons exhibit hypoexcitability, which increases with disease progression.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="ABSTRACT">Experimental models have primarily revealed spinal motoneuron hypoexcitability in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS), which is contentious considering the role of glutamate-induced excitotoxicity in neurodegeneration and clinical features rather supporting hyperexcitability. This phenomenon was evaluated in human patients by investigating changes in motor unit firing during contraction and relaxation. Twenty-two ALS patients with subtle motor deficits and 28 controls performed tonic contractions of extensor carpi radialis, triceps brachialis, tibialis anterior and quadriceps, aiming to isolate a low-threshold unit (U1) on the electromyogram (EMG). Subsequently, they performed a stronger contraction or tendon vibration was delivered, to recruit higher threshold unit (U2) for 10&#xa0;s before they relaxed progressively. EMG and motor unit potential analyses suggest altered neuromuscular function in all muscles, including those with normal strength (Medical Research Council score at 5). During the preconditioning tonic phase, U1 discharge frequency did not differ significantly between groups. During recruitment, the increase in U1 frequency (&#x2206;F-R) was comparable between groups both during contraction and tendon vibration. During derecruitment, the decrease in U1 frequency (&#x2206;F-D) was reduced in ALS regardless of the recruitment mode, particularly for &#x2206;F-R&#xa0;&lt;8&#xa0;Hz in the upper limbs, consistent with the muscle weakness profile of the group. &#x2206;F-D was associated with functional disability and its reduction was more pronounced in patients with more rapid disease progression rate. This in vivo study has demonstrated reduced motoneuron capacity for self-sustained discharge, and further supports that motoneurons are normo- to hypoexcitable in ALS patients, similar to observations in experimental models.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2019 The Authors. The Journal of Physiology &#xa9; 2019 The Physiological Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Marchand-Pauvert</LastName><ForeName>V&#xe9;ronique</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0226-7169</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sorbonne Universit&#xe9;, Inserm, CNRS, Laboratoire d'Imagerie Biom&#xe9;dicale, LIB, Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Peyre</LastName><ForeName>Iseline</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sorbonne Universit&#xe9;, Inserm, CNRS, Laboratoire d'Imagerie Biom&#xe9;dicale, LIB, Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lackmy-Vallee</LastName><ForeName>Alexandra</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8182-7944</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sorbonne Universit&#xe9;, Inserm, CNRS, Laboratoire d'Imagerie Biom&#xe9;dicale, LIB, Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Querin</LastName><ForeName>Giorgia</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sorbonne Universit&#xe9;, Inserm, CNRS, Laboratoire d'Imagerie Biom&#xe9;dicale, LIB, Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurologie, AP-HP, H&#xf4;pital Piti&#xe9;-Salp&#xea;tri&#xe8;re, Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bede</LastName><ForeName>Peter</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sorbonne Universit&#xe9;, Inserm, CNRS, Laboratoire d'Imagerie Biom&#xe9;dicale, LIB, Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurologie, AP-HP, H&#xf4;pital Piti&#xe9;-Salp&#xea;tri&#xe8;re, Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Computational Neuroimaging Group, Trinity College Dublin, Dublin, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lacomblez</LastName><ForeName>Lucette</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurologie, AP-HP, H&#xf4;pital Piti&#xe9;-Salp&#xea;tri&#xe8;re, Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Debs</LastName><ForeName>Rabab</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurologie, AP-HP, H&#xf4;pital Piti&#xe9;-Salp&#xea;tri&#xe8;re, Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pradat</LastName><ForeName>Pierre-Fran&#xe7;ois</ForeName><Initials>PF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sorbonne Universit&#xe9;, Inserm, CNRS, Laboratoire d'Imagerie Biom&#xe9;dicale, LIB, Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurologie, AP-HP, H&#xf4;pital Piti&#xe9;-Salp&#xea;tri&#xe8;re, Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2019</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Physiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0266262</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0022-3751</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016022" MajorTopicYN="N">Case-Control Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004576" MajorTopicYN="N">Electromyography</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009046" MajorTopicYN="N">Motor Neurons</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009119" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Contraction</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013131" MajorTopicYN="N">Spine</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013710" MajorTopicYN="N">Tendons</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">EMG</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">humans</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">motor neuron disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">motor units</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2019</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31523813</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/JP278117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Abe K, Aoki M, Tsuji S, Itoyama Y, Sobue G, Togo M, Hamada C, Tanaka M, Akimoto M, Nakamura K, Takahashi F, Kondo K, Yoshino H, Abe K, Aoki M, Tsuji S, Itoyama Y, Sobue G, Togo M, Hamada C, Sasaki H, Yabe I, Doi S, Warita H, Imai T, Ito H, Fukuchi M, Osumi E, Wada M, Nakano I, Morita M, Ogata K, Maruki Y, Ito K, Kano O, Yamazaki M, Takahashi Y, Ishiura H, Ogino M, Koike R, Ishida C, Uchiyama T, Mizoguchi K, Obi T, Watanabe H, Atsuta N, Aiba I, Taniguchi A, Sawada H, Hazama T, Fujimura H, Kusaka H, Kunieda T, Kikuchi H, Matsuo H, Ueyama H, Uekawa K, Tanaka M, Akimoto M, Ueda M, Murakami A, Sumii R, Kudou T, Nakamura K, Morimoto K, Yoneoka T, Hirai M, Sasaki K, Terai H, Natori T, Matsui H, Kotani K, Yoshida K, Iwasaki T, Takahashi F, Kondo K, Yoshino H &amp; Writing Group; Edaravone (MCI-186) ALS 19 Study Group (2017). Safety and efficacy of edaravone in well defined patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Lancet Neurol 16, 505-512.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xc1;lvarez N, D&#xed;ez L, Avellaneda C, Serra M &amp; Rubio M&#xc1; (2018). Relevance of the pyramidal syndrome in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurol Barc Spain 33, 8-12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bennett DJ, Li Y, Harvey PJ &amp; Gorassini M (2001). Evidence for plateau potentials in tail motoneurons of awake chronic spinal rats with spasticity. J Neurophysiol 86, 1972-1982.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bennett DJ, Sanelli L, Cooke CL, Harvey PJ &amp; Gorassini MA (2004). Spastic long-lasting reflexes in the awake rat after sacral spinal cord injury. J Neurophysiol 91, 2247-2258.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bensimon G, Lacomblez L &amp; Meininger V (1994). A controlled trial of riluzole in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. ALS/Riluzole Study Group. N Engl J Med 330, 585-591.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhandari R, Kuhad A, Itoyama Y, et&#xa0;al. &amp; Writing Group; Edaravone (MCI-186) ALS 19 Study Group (2018). Edaravone: a new hope for deadly amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Drugs Today Barc Spain 1998 54, 349-360.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bogaert E, d'Ydewalle C &amp; Van Den Bosch L (2010). Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and excitotoxicity: from pathological mechanism to therapeutic target. CNS Neurol Disord Drug Targets 9, 297-304.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, Miller RG, Swash M, Munsat TL &amp; World Federation of Neurology Research Group on Motor Neuron Diseases (2000a). El Escorial revisited: revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord 1, 293-299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, Miller RG, Swash M, Munsat TL &amp; World Federation of Neurology Research Group on Motor Neuron Diseases (2000b). El Escorial revisited: revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord 1, 293-299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke D, Hagbarth KE &amp; Skuse NF (1978). Recruitment order of human spindle endings in isometric voluntary contractions. J Physiol 285, 101-112.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burkhardt MF, Martinez FJ, Wright S, Ramos C, Volfson D, Mason M, Garnes J, Dang V, Lievers J, Shoukat-Mumtaz U, Martinez R, Gai H, Blake R, Vaisberg E, Grskovic M, Johnson C, Irion S, Bright J, Cooper B, Nguyen L, Griswold-Prenner I &amp; Javaherian A (2013). A cellular model for sporadic ALS using patient-derived induced pluripotent stem cells. Mol Cell Neurosci 56, 355-364.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M &amp; Swash M (2016). Lower motor neuron dysfunction in ALS. Clin Neurophysiol 127, 2670-2681.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Turkman A &amp; Swash M (2012). Motor unit firing in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and other upper and lower motor neurone disorders. Clin Neurophysiol 123, 2312-2318.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Turkman A &amp; Swash M (2014). Sensitivity of MUP parameters in detecting change in early ALS. Clin Neurophysiol 125, 166-169.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum JM, Stambler N, Malta E, Fuller C, Hilt D, Thurmond B &amp; Nakanishi A (1999). The ALSFRS-R: a revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. BDNF ALS Study Group (Phase III). J Neurol Sci 169, 13-21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christensen PB, Nielsen JF &amp; Sinkjaer T (2003). Quantification of hyperreflexia in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) by the soleus stretch reflex. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord 4, 106-111.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cope TC &amp; Clark BD (1993). Motor-unit recruitment in self-reinnervated muscle. J Neurophysiol 70, 1787-1796.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cotel F, Antri M, Barthe J-Y &amp; Orsal D (2009). Identified ankle extensor and flexor motoneurons display different firing profiles in the neonatal rat. J Neurosci Off 29, 2748-2753.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D'Amico JM, Murray KC, Li Y, Chan KM, Finlay MG, Bennett DJ &amp; Gorassini MA (2013). Constitutively active 5-HT2/&#x3b1;1 receptors facilitate muscle spasms after human spinal cord injury. J Neurophysiol 109, 1473-1484.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Winter F, Vo T, Stam FJ, Wisman LAB, B&#xe4;r PR, Niclou SP, van Muiswinkel FL &amp; Verhaagen J (2006). The expression of the chemorepellent Semaphorin 3A is selectively induced in terminal Schwann cells of a subset of neuromuscular synapses that display limited anatomical plasticity and enhanced vulnerability in motor neuron disease. Mol Cell Neurosci 32, 102-117.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delestr&#xe9;e N, Manuel M, Iglesias C, Elbasiouny SM, Heckman CJ &amp; Zytnicki D (2014). Adult spinal motoneurones are not hyperexcitable in a mouse model of inherited amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Physiol 592, 1687-1703.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dentel C, Palamiuc L, Henriques A, Lannes B, Spreux-Varoquaux O, Gutknecht L, Ren&#xe9; F, Echaniz-Laguna A, Gonzalez de Aguilar J-L, Lesch KP, Meininger V, Loeffler J-P &amp; Dupuis L (2013). Degeneration of serotonergic neurons in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a link to spasticity. Brain J Neurol 136, 483-493.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devlin A-C, Burr K, Borooah S, Foster JD, Cleary EM, Geti I, Vallier L, Shaw CE, Chandran S &amp; Miles GB (2015). Human iPSC-derived motoneurons harbouring TARDBP or C9ORF72 ALS mutations are dysfunctional despite maintaining viability. Nat Commun 6, 5999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dharmadasa T &amp; Kiernan MC (2018). Riluzole, disease stage and survival in ALS. Lancet Neurol 17, 385-386.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dupuis L, Spreux-Varoquaux O, Bensimon G, Jullien P, Lacomblez L, Salachas F, Bruneteau G, Pradat P-F, Loeffler J-P &amp; Meininger V (2010). Platelet serotonin level predicts survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. PloS ONE 5, e13346.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ElBasiouny SM, Schuster JE &amp; Heckman CJ (2010). Persistent inward currents in spinal motoneurons: important for normal function but potentially harmful after spinal cord injury and in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Neurophysiol 121, 1669-1679.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fogarty MJ (2018). Driven to decay: Excitability and synaptic abnormalities in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain Res Bull 140, 318-333.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frey D, Schneider C, Xu L, Borg J, Spooren W &amp; Caroni P (2000). Early and selective loss of neuromuscular synapse subtypes with low sprouting competence in motoneuron diseases. J Neurosci Off 20, 2534-2542.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geevasinga N, Menon P, Ng K, Van Den Bos M, Byth K, Kiernan MC &amp; Vucic S (2016). Riluzole exerts transient modulating effects on cortical and axonal hyperexcitability in ALS. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Front Degener 17, 580-588.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorassini M, Yang JF, Siu M &amp; Bennett DJ (2002a). Intrinsic activation of human motoneurons: possible contribution to motor unit excitation. J Neurophysiol 87, 1850-1858.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorassini M, Yang JF, Siu M &amp; Bennett DJ (2002b). Intrinsic activation of human motoneurons: reduction of motor unit recruitment thresholds by repeated contractions. J Neurophysiol 87, 1859-1866.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorassini MA, Bennett DJ &amp; Yang JF (1998). Self-sustained firing of human motor units. Neurosci Lett 247, 13-16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorassini MA, Knash ME, Harvey PJ, Bennett DJ &amp; Yang JF (2004). Role of motoneurons in the generation of muscle spasms after spinal cord injury. Brain J Neurol 127, 2247-2258.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon T, Thomas CK, Munson JB &amp; Stein RB (2004). The resilience of the size principle in the organization of motor unit properties in normal and reinnervated adult skeletal muscles. Can J Physiol Pharmacol 82, 645-661.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heckman CJ, Johnson M, Mottram C &amp; Schuster J (2008). Persistent inward currents in spinal motoneurons and their influence on human motoneuron firing patterns. Neurosci Rev J Bringing Neurobiol Neurol Psychiatry 14, 264-275.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heckmann CJ, Gorassini MA &amp; Bennett DJ (2005). Persistent inward currents in motoneuron dendrites: implications for motor output. Muscle Nerve 31, 135-156.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hegedus J, Putman CT &amp; Gordon T (2007). Time course of preferential motor unit loss in the SOD1 G93A mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurobiol Dis 28, 154-164.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henneman E &amp; Mendell LM (1981). The Nervous System. Motor Control, Section ed. Brookhart JM &amp; Mountcastle VB. In Handbook of Physiology, ed. Brooks VB, pp. 423-507. American Physiological Society, Bethesda, MD, USA.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iglesias C, Sangari S, El Mendili M-M, Benali H, Marchand-Pauvert V &amp; Pradat P-F (2015). Electrophysiological and spinal imaging evidences for sensory dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. BMJ Open 5, e007659.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jahanmiri-Nezhad F, Hu X, Suresh NL, Rymer WZ &amp; Zhou P (2014). EMG-force relation in the first dorsal interosseous muscle of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. NeuroRehabilitation 35, 307-314.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson MD &amp; Heckman CJ (2010). Interactions between focused synaptic inputs and diffuse neuromodulation in the spinal cord. Ann NY Acad Sci 1198, 35-41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiehn O &amp; Eken T (1997). Prolonged firing in motor units: evidence of plateau potentials in human motoneurons? J Neurophysiol 78, 3061-3068.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuo JJ, Siddique T, Fu R &amp; Heckman CJ (2005). Increased persistent Na(+) current and its effect on excitability in motoneurones cultured from mutant SOD1 mice. J Physiol 563, 843-854.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee RH &amp; Heckman CJ (1998). Bistability in spinal motoneurons in vivo: systematic variations in persistent inward currents. J Neurophysiol 80, 583-593.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leroy F, Lamotte d'Incamps B, Imhoff-Manuel RD &amp; Zytnicki D (2014). Early intrinsic hyperexcitability does not contribute to motoneuron degeneration in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. eLife 3, e04046.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macefield VG (2005). Physiological characteristics of low-threshold mechanoreceptors in joints, muscle and skin in human subjects. Clin Exp Pharmacol Physiol 32, 135-144.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marchand-Pauvert V, Mazevet D, Nielsen J, Petersen N &amp; Pierrot-Deseilligny E (2000). Distribution of non-monosynaptic excitation to early and late recruited units in human forearm muscles. Exp Brain Res 134, 274-278.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin E, Cazenave W, Cattaert D &amp; Branchereau P (2013). Embryonic alteration of motoneuronal morphology induces hyperexcitability in the mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurobiol Dis 54, 116-126.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;nez-Silva M de L, Imhoff-Manuel RD, Sharma A, Heckman CJ, Shneider NA, Roselli F, Zytnicki D &amp; Manuel M (2018). Hypoexcitability precedes denervation in the large fast-contracting motor units in two unrelated mouse models of ALS. eLife 7, e30955.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matthews PB (1996). Relationship of firing intervals of human motor units to the trajectory of post-spike after-hyperpolarization and synaptic noise. J Physiol 492, 597-628.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McPherson JG, Ellis MD, Heckman CJ &amp; Dewald JPA (2008). Evidence for increased activation of persistent inward currents in individuals with chronic hemiparetic stroke. J Neurophysiol 100, 3236-3243.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meehan CF, Moldovan M, Marklund SL, Graffmo KS, Nielsen JB &amp; Hultborn H (2010). Intrinsic properties of lumbar motor neurones in the adult G127insTGGG superoxide dismutase-1 mutant mouse in vivo: evidence for increased persistent inward currents. Acta Physiol Oxf Engl 200, 361-376.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Millecamps S, Boill&#xe9;e S, Le Ber I, Seilhean D, Teyssou E, Giraudeau M, Moigneu C, Vandenberghe N, Danel-Brunaud V, Corcia P, Pradat PF, Le Forestier N, Lacomblez L, Bruneteau G, Camu W, Brice A, Cazeneuve C, Leguern E, Meininger V, &amp; Salachas F (2012). Phenotype difference between ALS patients with expanded repeats in C9ORF72 and patients with mutations in other ALS-related genes. J Med Genet 49, 258-263.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milner-Brown HS &amp; Stein RB (1975). The relation between the surface electromyogram and muscular force. J Physiol 246, 549-569.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morgan S &amp; Orrell RW (2016). Pathogenesis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Br Med Bull 119, 87-98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mottram CJ, Suresh NL, Heckman CJ, Gorassini MA &amp; Rymer WZ (2009). Origins of abnormal excitability in biceps brachii motoneurons of spastic-paretic stroke survivors. J Neurophysiol 102, 2026-2038.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nardone A, Galante M, Lucas B &amp; Schieppati M (2001). Stance control is not affected by paresis and reflex hyperexcitability: the case of spastic patients. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 70, 635-643.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naujock M, Stanslowsky N, Bufler S, Naumann M, Reinhardt P, Sterneckert J, Kefalakes E, Kassebaum C, Bursch F, Lojewski X, Storch A, Frickenhaus M, Boeckers TM, Putz S, Demestre M, Liebau S, Klingenstein M, Ludolph AC, Dengler R, Kim KS, Hermann A, Wegner F &amp; Petri S (2016). 4-Aminopyridine induced activity rescues hypoexcitable motor neurons from amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patient-derived induced pluripotent stem cells. Stem Cells Dayt Ohio 34, 1563-1575.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nielsen J, Morita H, Baumgarten J, Petersen N &amp; Christensen LO (1999). On the comparability of H-reflexes and MEPs. Electroencephalogr Clin Neurophysiol Suppl 51, 93-101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nijssen J, Comley LH &amp; Hedlund E (2017). Motor neuron vulnerability and resistance in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathol (Berl) 133, 863-885.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oldfield RC (1971). The assessment and analysis of handedness: the Edinburgh inventory. Neuropsychologia 9, 97-113.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pieri M, Albo F, Gaetti C, Spalloni A, Bengtson CP, Longone P, Cavalcanti S &amp; Zona C (2003). Altered excitability of motor neurons in a transgenic mouse model of familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurosci Lett 351, 153-156.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pierrot-Deseilligny E &amp; Burke D (2012). The Circuitry of the Human Spinal Cord, 2nd edn. Cambridge University Press, New York, NY.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piotrkiewicz M &amp; Hausmanowa-Petrusewicz I (2011). Motoneuron afterhyperpolarisation duration in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Physiol 589, 2745-2754.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Powers RK, Elbasiouny SM, Rymer WZ &amp; Heckman CJ (2012). Contribution of intrinsic properties and synaptic inputs to motoneuron discharge patterns: a simulation study. J Neurophysiol 107, 808-823.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Powers RK &amp; Heckman CJ (2015). Contribution of intrinsic motoneuron properties to discharge hysteresis and its estimation based on paired motor unit recordings: a simulation study. J Neurophysiol 114, 184-198.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Powers RK &amp; Heckman CJ (2017). Synaptic control of the shape of the motoneuron pool input-output function. J Neurophysiol 117, 1171-1184.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Powers RK, Nardelli P &amp; Cope TC (2008). Estimation of the contribution of intrinsic currents to motoneuron firing based on paired motoneuron discharge records in the decerebrate cat. J Neurophysiol 100, 292-303.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pun S, Santos AF, Saxena S, Xu L &amp; Caroni P (2006). Selective vulnerability and pruning of phasic motoneuron axons in motoneuron disease alleviated by CNTF. Nat Neurosci 9, 408-419.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qian K, Huang H, Peterson A, Hu B, Maragakis NJ, Ming G-L, Chen H &amp; Zhang S-C (2017). Sporadic ALS astrocytes induce neuronal degeneration in vivo. Stem Cell Rep 8, 843-855.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quinlan KA, Schuster JE, Fu R, Siddique T &amp; Heckman CJ (2011). Altered postnatal maturation of electrical properties in spinal motoneurons in a mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Physiol 589, 2245-2260.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raynor EM &amp; Shefner JM (1994). Recurrent inhibition is decreased in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology 44, 2148-2153.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Revill AL &amp; Fuglevand AJ (2011). Effects of persistent inward currents, accommodation, and adaptation on motor unit behavior: a simulation study. J Neurophysiol 106, 1467-1479.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Revill AL &amp; Fuglevand AJ (2017). Inhibition linearizes firing rate responses in human motor units: implications for the role of persistent inward currents. J Physiol 595, 179-191.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rothstein JD (2009). Current hypotheses for the underlying biology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol 65 (Suppl 1), S3-S9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sangari S, Iglesias C, El Mendili M-M, Benali H, Pradat P-F &amp; Marchand-Pauvert V (2016). Impairment of sensory-motor integration at spinal level in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Neurophysiol 127, 1968-1977.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schaefer AM, Sanes JR &amp; Lichtman JW (2005). A compensatory subpopulation of motor neurons in a mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Comp Neurol 490, 209-219.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmied A, Pouget J &amp; Vedel JP (1999). Electromechanical coupling and synchronous firing of single wrist extensor motor units in sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Neurophysiol 110, 960-974.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Segundo JP, Moore GP, Stensaas LJ &amp; Bullock TH (1963). Sensitivity of neurones in aplysia to temporal pattern of arriving impulses. J Exp Biol 40, 643-667.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simon NG, Lin CS-Y, Lee M, Howells J, Vucic S, Burke D &amp; Kiernan MC (2015). Segmental motoneuronal dysfunction is a feature of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Neurophysiol 126, 828-836.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Udina E, D'Amico J, Bergquist AJ &amp; Gorassini MA (2010). Amphetamine increases persistent inward currents in human motoneurons estimated from paired motor-unit activity. J Neurophysiol 103, 1295-1303.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vallbo AB (1970). Discharge patterns in human muscle spindle afferents during isometric voluntary contractions. Acta Physiol Scand 80, 552-566.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van den Bos MAJ, Higashihara M, Geevasinga N, Menon P, Kiernan MC &amp; Vucic S (2018). Imbalance of cortical facilitatory and inhibitory circuits underlies hyperexcitability in ALS. Neurology 91, e1669-e1676.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vandenberk MS &amp; Kalmar JM (2014). An evaluation of paired motor unit estimates of persistent inward current in human motoneurons. J Neurophysiol 111, 1877-1884.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaughan SK, Kemp Z, Hatzipetros T, Vieira F &amp; Valdez G (2015). Degeneration of proprioceptive sensory nerve endings in mice harboring amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-causing mutations. J Comp Neurol 523, 2477-2494.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S (2012). Assessing motor unit firing rates in ALS: A diagnostic and pathophysiological prospect? Clin Neurophysiol 123, 2114-2115.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S, Ziemann U, Eisen A, Hallett M &amp; Kiernan MC (2013). Transcranial magnetic stimulation and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: pathophysiological insights. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 84, 1161-1170.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wainger BJ, Kiskinis E, Mellin C, Wiskow O, Han SSW, Sandoe J, Perez NP, Williams LA, Lee S, Boulting G, Berry JD, Brown RH, Cudkowicz ME, Bean BP, Eggan K &amp; Woolf CJ (2014). Intrinsic membrane hyperexcitability of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patient-derived motor neurons. Cell Rep 7, 1-11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wienecke J, Zhang M &amp; Hultborn H (2009). A prolongation of the postspike afterhyperpolarization following spike trains can partly explain the lower firing rates at derecruitment than those at recruitment. J Neurophysiol 102, 3698-3710.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson JM, Thompson CK, Miller LC &amp; Heckman CJ (2015). Intrinsic excitability of human motoneurons in biceps brachii versus triceps brachii. J Neurophysiol 113, 3692-3699.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>