<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">31530755</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>11</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1741-2552</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2019</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>06</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of neural engineering</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Neural Eng</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Multimodal exploration of non-motor neural functions in ALS patients using simultaneous EEG-fNIRS recording.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>066036</StartPage><MedlinePgn>066036</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1088/1741-2552/ab456c</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">Despite the high prevalence of non-motor impairments reported in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS), little is known about the functional neural markers underlying such dysfunctions. In this study, a new dual-task multimodal framework relying on simultaneous electroencephalogram (EEG) and functional near-infrared spectroscopy (fNIRS) recordings was developed to characterize integrative non-motor neural functions in people with ALS.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="APPROACH">Simultaneous EEG-fNIRS data were recorded from six subjects with ALS and twelve healthy controls. Through a proposed visuo-mental paradigm, subjects performed a set of visuo-mental arithmetic operations. The data recorded were analyzed with respect to event-related changes both in the time and frequency domains for EEG and de/oxygen-hemoglobin level (HbR/HbO) changes for fNIRS. The correlation of EEG spectral features with fNIRS HbO/HbR features were then evaluated to assess the mechanisms of ALS on the electrical (EEG)-vascular (fNIRS) interrelationships.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MAIN RESULTS">We observed overall smaller increases in EEG delta and theta power, decreases in beta power, reductions in HbO responses, and distortions both in early and later EEG event-related potentials in ALS subjects compared to healthy controls. While significant correlations between EEG features and HbO responses were observed in healthy controls, these patterns were absent in ALS patients. Distortions in both electrical and hemodynamic responses are speculated to be associated with cognitive deficits in ALS that center primarily on attentional and working memory processing.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SIGNIFICANCE">Our results highlight the important role of ALS non-motor dysfunctions in electrical and hemodynamic neural dynamics as well as their interrelationships. The insights obtained through this study can enhance our understanding of the underlying non-motor neural processes in ALS and enrich future diagnostic and prognostic techniques.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Borgheai</LastName><ForeName>S B</ForeName><Initials>SB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical, Computer, and Biomedical Engineering, University of Rhode Island, Kingston, RI, United States of America.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Deligani</LastName><ForeName>R J</ForeName><Initials>RJ</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McLinden</LastName><ForeName>J</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zisk</LastName><ForeName>A</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hosni</LastName><ForeName>S I</ForeName><Initials>SI</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abtahi</LastName><ForeName>M</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mankodiya</LastName><ForeName>K</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shahriari</LastName><ForeName>Y</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>P20 GM103430</GrantID><Acronym>GM</Acronym><Agency>NIGMS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>P41 EB018783</GrantID><Acronym>EB</Acronym><Agency>NIBIB NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2019</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Neural Eng</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101217933</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1741-2552</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004569" MajorTopicYN="N">Electroencephalography</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006439" MajorTopicYN="N">Hemodynamics</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011597" MajorTopicYN="N">Psychomotor Performance</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019265" MajorTopicYN="N">Spectroscopy, Near-Infrared</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31530755</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS1567182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7093150</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1741-2552/ab456c</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Beeldman E, Raaphorst J, Klein Twennaar M, de Visser M, Schmand B A and de Haan R J 2016. The cognitive profile of ALS: a systematic review and meta-analysis update J. Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatry 87 611&#x2013;9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26283685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lomen-Hoerth C, Murphy J, Langmore S, Kramer JH, Olney RK and Miller B 2003. Are amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients cognitively normal? Neurology 60 1094&#x2013;7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12682312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy JM, Henry RG, Langmore S, Kramer JH, Miller BL and Lomen-Hoerth C 2007. Continuum of frontal lobe impairment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis Arch. Neurol 64 530&#x2013;4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17420314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner MR and Swash M 2015. The expanding syndrome of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a clinical and molecular odyssey J. Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatry 86 667&#x2013;73</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4453495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25644224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montuschi A, Iazzolino B, Calvo A, Moglia C, Lopiano L, Restagno G, Brunetti M, Ossola I, Presti AL and Cammarosano S 2015. Cognitive correlates in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a population-based study in Italy J. Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatry 86 168&#x2013;73</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24769471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kellmeyer P, Grosse-Wentrup M, Schulze-Bonhage A, Ziemann U and Ball T 2018. Electrophysiological correlates of neurodegeneration in motor and non-motor brain regions in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-implications for brain-computer interfacing J. Neural Eng 15 041003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29676287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raggi A, Iannaccone S and Cappa SF 2010. Event-related brain potentials in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a review of the international literature Amyotroph. Lateral Scler 11 16&#x2013;26</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19412819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ringholz GM, Appel SH, Bradshaw M, Cooke NA, Mosnik DM and Schulz P E 2005. Prevalence and patterns of cognitive impairment in sporadic ALS Neurology 65 586&#x2013;90</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16116120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silvoni S, Volpato C, Cavinato M, Marchetti M, Priftis K, Merico A, Tonin P, Koutsikos K, Beverina F and Piccione F 2009. P300-based brain-computer interface communication: evaluation and follow-up in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis Frontiers Neurosci. 3 60</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2858557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20582284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaehle T, Becke A, Naue N, Machts J, Abdulla S, Petri S, Kollewe K, Dengler R, Heinze H and Vielhaber S 2013. Working memory in ALS patients: preserved performance but marked changes in underlying neuronal networks PloS One 8 e71973.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3738526</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23951274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Consonni M, Catrical&#xe0; E, Dalla Bella E, Gessa VC, Lauria G and Cappa S F 2016. Beyond the consensus criteria: multiple cognitive profiles in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis? Cortex 81 162&#x2013;7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27236371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Consonni M, Contarino VE, Catrical&#xe0; E, Dalla Bella E, Pensato V, Gellera C, Lauria G and Cappa SF 2018. Cortical markers of cognitive syndromes in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis NeuroImage 19 675&#x2013;82</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6046611</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30023173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCane LM, Heckman SM, McFarland DJ, Townsend G, Mak JN, Sellers EW, Zeitlin D, Tenteromano LM, Wolpaw JR and Vaughan TM 2015. P300-based brain-computer interface (BCI) event-related potentials (ERPs): people with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) versus age-matched controls Clin. Neurophysiol 126 2124&#x2013;31</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4529383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25703940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geronimo A, Simmons Z and Schiff S J 2016. Performance predictors of brain&#x2013;computer interfaces in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis J. Neural Eng 13 026002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26824590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke T, Pinto-Grau M, Lonergan K, Bede P, O&#x2019;Sullivan M, Heverin M, Vajda A, McLaughlin R L, Pender N and Hardiman O 2017. A cross-sectional population-based investigation into behavioral change in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: subphenotypes, staging, cognitive predictors, and survival Ann. Clin. Transl. Neurol 4 305&#x2013;17</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5420811</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28491898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasper E, Schuster C, Machts J, Kaufmann J, Bittner D, Vielhaber S, Benecke R, Teipel S and Prudlo J 2014. Microstructural white matter changes underlying cognitive and behavioural impairment in ALS&#x2013;an in vivo study using DTI PloS One 9 e114543.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4263750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25501028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woolley S C, York M K, Moore D H, Strutt A M, Murphy J, Schulz P E and Katz J S 2010. Detecting frontotemporal dysfunction in ALS: utility of the ALS cognitive behavioral screen (ALS-CBS) Amyotroph. Lateral Scler 11 303&#x2013;11</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20433413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abiri R, Borhani S, Sellers E W, Jiang Y and Zhao X 2018. A comprehensive review of EEG-based brain-computer interface paradigms J. Neural Eng 16 011001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30523919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santhosh J, Bhatia M, Sahu S and Anand S 2005. Decreased electroencephalogram alpha band [8&#x2013;13 Hz] power in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients: a study of alpha activity in an awake relaxed state Neurol. India 53 99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15805665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iyer P M, Egan C, Pinto-Grau M, Burke T, Elamin M, Nasseroleslami B, Pender N, Lalor E C and Hardiman O 2015. Functional connectivity changes in resting-state EEG as potential biomarker for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis PloS One 10 e0128682.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4474889</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26091258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Putze F, Hesslinger S, Tse C, Huang Y, Herff C, Guan C and Schultz T 2014. Hybrid fNIRS-EEG based classification of auditory and visual perception processes Frontiers Neurosci. 8 373</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4235375</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25477777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koenig M A and Kaplan P W 2013. Clinical neurophysiology in acute coma and disorders of consciousness Seminars in Neurology pp 121&#x2013;32</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23888396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Massari D, Ruf CA, Furdea A, Matuz T, Van Der Heiden L, Halder S, Silvoni S and Birbaumer N 2013 Brain communication in the locked-in state Brain 136 1989&#x2013;2000</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23625062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murguialday AR, Hill J, Bensch M, Martens S, Halder S, Nijboer F, Schoelkopf B, Birbaumer N and Gharabaghi A 2011. Transition from the locked in to the completely locked-in state: a physiological analysis Clin. Neurophysiol 122 925&#x2013;33</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20888292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xfc;bler A, Neumann N, Kaiser J, Kotchoubey B, Hinterberger T and Birbaumer NP 2001. Brain-computer communication: self-regulation of slow cortical potentials for verbal communication Arch. Phys. Med. Rehabil 82 1533&#x2013;9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11689972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xfc;bler A, Kotchoubey B, Hinterberger T, Ghanayim N, Perelmouter J, Schauer M, Fritsch C, Taub E and Birbaumer N 1999. The thought translation device: a neurophysiological approach to communication in total motor paralysis Exp. Brain Res 124 223&#x2013;32</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9928845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schudlo LC and Chau T 2014. Dynamic topographical pattern classification of multichannel prefrontal NIRS signals: II. Online differentiation of mental arithmetic and rest J. Neural Eng 11 016003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24311057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naseer N and Hong K 2015. fNIRS-based brain-computer interfaces: a review Frontiers Hum. Neurosci 9 3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4309034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25674060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lloyd-Fox S, Papademetriou M, Darboe MK, Everdell NL, Wegmuller R, Prentice AM, Moore SE and Elwell C E 2014. Functional near infrared spectroscopy (fNIRS) to assess cognitive function in infants in rural Africa Sci. Rep 4 4740.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5381189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24751935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shin J, M&#xfc;ller K and Hwang H 2016. Near-infrared spectroscopy (NIRS)-based eyes-closed brain-computer interface (BCI) using prefrontal cortex activation due to mental arithmetic Sci. Rep 6 36203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5099935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27824089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shin J, M&#xfc;ller K and Hwang H 2017. Hybrid EEG-NIRS brain-computer interface under eyes-closed condition Asia-Pacific Signal and Information Processing Association Annual Summit and Conf. (APSIPA ASC) pp 721&#x2013;3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuruvilla MS, Green JR, Ayaz H and Murman DL 2013. Neural correlates of cognitive decline in ALS: an fNIRS study of the prefrontal cortex Cogn. Neurosci 4 115&#x2013;21</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4727749</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24073736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaudhary U, Xia B, Silvoni S, Cohen LG and Birbaumer N 2017. Brain&#x2013;computer interface-based communication in the completely locked-in state PLoS Biol. 15 e1002593.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5283652</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28141803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pettit LD, Bastin ME, Smith C, Bak TH, Gillingwater TH and Abrahams S 2013. Executive deficits, not processing speed relates to abnormalities in distinct prefrontal tracts in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis Brain 136 3290&#x2013;304</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24056536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan MJ, Hong K, Naseer N and Bhutta MR 2014 A hybrid EEG-fNIRS BCI: motor imagery for EEG and mental arithmetic for fNIRS 14th Int. Conf. on Control, Autom. Syst. (ICCAS 2014) pp 275&#x2013;8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amiri S, Fazel-Rezai R and Asadpour V 2013 A review of hybrid brain-computer interface systems Adv. Hum.-Comput. Interact 2013. 1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller-Putz G, Leeb R, Tangermann M, H&#xf6;hne J, K&#xfc;bler A, Cincotti F, Mattia D, Rupp R, M&#xfc;ller K and del R Mill&#xe1;n J 2015. Towards noninvasive hybrid brain&#x2013;computer interfaces: framework, practice, clinical application, and beyond Proc. IEEE 103 926&#x2013;43</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum JM, Stambler N, Malta E, Fuller C, Hilt D, Thurmond B and Nakanishi A 1999. The ALSFRS-R: a revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. BDNF ALS Study Group (Phase III) J. Neurol. Sci 169 13&#x2013;21</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10540002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krusienski DJ, Sellers EW, McFarland DJ, Vaughan TM and Wolpaw JR 2008. Toward enhanced P300 speller performance J. Neurosci. Methods 167 15&#x2013;21</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2349091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17822777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bauernfeind G, Scherer R, Pfurtscheller G and Neuper C 2011. Single-trial classification of antagonistic oxyhemoglobin responses during mental arithmetic Med. Biol. Eng. Comput 49 979.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21701852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schalk G and Mellinger J 2010. A Practical Guide to Brain&#x2013;computer Interfacing with BCI2000: General-Purpose Software for Brain-Computer Interface Research, Data Acquisition, Stimulus Presentation, and Brain Monitoring (Berlin: Springer; ) (10.1007/978-1-84996-092-2)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-1-84996-092-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simis M, Santos K, Sato J, Fregni F and Battistella L 2018. Using functional near infrared spectroscopy (fNIRS) to assess brain activity of spinal cord injury patient, during robot-assisted gait Clin. Neurophysiol 129 e4&#x2013;e44</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coyle S, Ward T, Markham C and McDarby G 2004. On the suitability of near-infrared (NIR) systems for next-generation brain-computer interfaces Physiol. Meas 25 815&#x2013;22</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15382823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scarpa F, Cutini S, Scatturin P, Dell&#x2019;Acqua R and Sparacino G 2010. Bayesian filtering of human brain hemodynamic activity elicited by visual short-term maintenance recorded through functional near-infrared spectroscopy (fNIRS) Opt. Express 18 26550&#x2013;68</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21165006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kocsis L, Herman P and Eke A 2006. The modified Beer&#x2013;Lambert law revisited Phys. Med. Biol 51 N91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16481677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oru&#xe7; I, Krigolson O, Dalrymple K, Nagamatsu LS, Handy TC and Barton JJ 2011. Bootstrap analysis of the single subject with event related potentials Cogn. Neuropsychol 28 322&#x2013;37</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22292858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vizioli L, Foreman K, Rousselet GA and Caldara R 2009. Inverting faces elicits sensitivity to race on the N170 component: a cross-cultural study J. Vis 10 15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20143908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hochberg Y and Benjamini Y 1990. More powerful procedures for multiple significance testing Stat. Med 9 811&#x2013;8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2218183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bensch M, Martens S, Halder S, Hill J, Nijboer F, Ramos A, Birbaumer N, Bogdan M, Kotchoubey B and Rosenstiel W 2014. Assessing attention and cognitive function in completely locked-in state with event-related brain potentials and epidural electrocorticography J. Neural Eng 11 026006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24556584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laureys S, Owen AM and Schiff ND 2004. Brain function in coma, vegetative state, and related disorders Lancet Neurol. 3 537&#x2013;46</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15324722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riccio A, Simione L, Schettini F, Pizzimenti A, Inghilleri M, Olivetti Belardinelli M, Mattia D and Cincotti F 2013. Attention and P300-based BCI performance in people with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis Frontiers Hum. Neurosci 7 732</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3825256</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24282396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shahriari Y, Vaughan TM, McCane L, Allison BZ, Wolpaw JR and Krusienski DJ 2019. An exploration of BCI performance variations in people with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis using longitudinal EEG data J. Neural Eng 16 056031.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31108477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinkhardt EH, J&#xfc;rgens R, Becker W, M&#xf6;lle M, Born J, Ludolph A C and Schreiber H 2008. Signs of impaired selective attention in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis J. Neurol 255 532&#x2013;8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18274808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L, Wang S and Kuang G 2013. A study of brain-computer interface paradigm based on mental arithmetic J. Biomed. Eng 30 469&#x2013;75</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23865302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polich J 2007. Updating P300: an integrative theory of P3a and P3b Clin. Neurophysiol 118 2128&#x2013;48</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2715154</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17573239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Beek L, Ghesqui&#xe8;re P, De Smedt B and Lagae L 2015. Arithmetic difficulties in children with mild traumatic brain injury at the subacute stage of recovery Dev. Med. Child Neurol 57 1042&#x2013;8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26268837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fraschini M, Demuru M, Hillebrand A, Cuccu L, Porcu S, Di Stefano F, Puligheddu M, Floris G, Borghero G and Marrosu F 2016. EEG functional network topology is associated with disability in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis Sci. Rep 6 38653.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5141491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27924954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burget F, Fiederer LDJ, Kuhner D, V&#xf6;lker M, Aldinger J, Schirrmeister RT, Do C, Boedecker J, Nebel B and Ball T 2017. Acting thoughts: towards a mobile robotic service assistant for users with limited communication skills 2017 European Conf. on Mobile Robots (ECMR) pp 1&#x2013;6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez T, Harmony T, Rodr&#xed;guez M, Bernal J, Silva J, Reyes A and Marosi E 1995. EEG activation patterns during the performance of tasks involving different components of mental calculation Electroencephalogr. Clin. Neurophysiol 94 175&#x2013;82</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7536152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deligani RJ, Hosni SI, Vaughan TM, McCane LM, Zeitlin DJ, McFarlan DJ, Krusienski DJ and Shahriari Y 2019. Neural alterations during use of a P300-based BCI by individuals with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis 9th Int. IEEE/MBS Conf. on Neural Eng. pp 899&#x2013;902</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borgheai SB, Deligani RJ, McLinden J, Abtahi M, Ostadabbas S, Mankodiya K and Shahriari Y 2019. Multimodal evaluation of mental workload using a hybrid EEG-fNIRS brain-computer interface 9th Int. IEEE/EMBS Conf. on Neural Eng. pp 973&#x2013;6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deiber M, Missonnier P, Bertrand O, Gold G, Fazio-Costa L, Iba&#xf1;ez V and Giannakopoulos P 2007. Distinction between perceptual and attentional processing in working memory tasks: a study of phase-locked and induced oscillatory brain dynamics J. Cogn. Neurosci 19 158&#x2013;72</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17214572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bastos AM, Vezoli J, Bosman CA, Schoffelen J, Oostenveld R, Dowdall JR, De Weerd P, Kennedy H and Fries P 2015. Visual areas exert feedforward and feedback influences through distinct frequency channels Neuron 85 390&#x2013;401</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25556836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siegel M, Donner TH and Engel AK 2012. Spectral fingerprints of large-scale neuronal interactions Nat. Rev. Neurosci 13 121.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22233726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Engel AK and Fries P 2010. Beta-band oscillations&#x2014;signalling the status quo? Curr. Opin. Neurobiol 20 156&#x2013;65</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20359884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spitzer B and Haegens S 2017. Beyond the status quo: a role for beta oscillations in endogenous content (re) activation Eneuro 4 e0170&#x2013;17</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5539431</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28785729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wimmer K, Ramon M, Pasternak T and Compte A 2016. Transitions between multiband oscillatory patterns characterize memory-guided perceptual decisions in prefrontal circuits J. Neurosci 36 489&#x2013;505</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4710772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26758840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zafar A and Hong K 2017. Detection and classification of three-class initial dips from prefrontal cortex Biomed. Opt. Express 8 367&#x2013;83</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5231305</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28101424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borgheai SB, Abtahi M, Mankodiya K, McLinden J and Shahriari Y 2019. Towards a single trial fNIRS-based brain-computer interface for communication 2019 9th Int. IEEE/EMBS Conf. on Neural Eng. pp 1030&#x2013;3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sammer G, Blecker C, Gebhardt H, Bischoff M, Stark R, Morgen K and Vaitl D 2007. Relationship between regional hemodynamic activity and simultaneously recorded EEG-theta associated with mental arithmetic-induced workload Hum. Brain Mapp. 28 793&#x2013;803</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6871320</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17080437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blumenfeld RS and Ranganath C 2006. Dorsolateral prefrontal cortex promotes long-term memory formation through its role in working memory organization J. Neurosci 26 916&#x2013;25</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6675388</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16421311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plichta MM, Heinzel S, Ehlis A, Pauli P and Fallgatter AJ 2007. Model-based analysis of rapid event-related functional near-infrared spectroscopy (NIRS) data: a parametric validation study NeuroImage 35 625&#x2013;34</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17258472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volpato C, Prats Sedano MA, Silvoni S, Segato N, Cavinato M, Merico A, Piccione F, Palmieri A and Birbaumer N 2016. Selective attention impairment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis Amyotroph. Lateral Scler. Frontotemp. Degeneration 17 236&#x2013;44</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26889872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campanella S, Vanhoolandt ME and Philippot P 2004. Emotional deficit in subjects with psychopathic tendencies as assessed by the Minnesota Multiphasic Personality Inventory-2: an event-related potentials study Neurosci. Lett 373 26&#x2013;31</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15555771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Unglik J, Bungener C, Delgadillo D, Salachas F, Pradat PF, Bruneteau G, Lenglet T, Le Forestier N, Couratier P and Vacher Y 2018. Emotional feeling in patients suffering from amyotrophic lateral sclerosis Geriatrie Et Psychologie Neuropsychiatrie Du Vieillissement 16 414.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30355543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kleih SC, Nijboer F, Halder S and Kubler A 2010. Motivation modulates the P300 amplitude during brain-computer interface use Clin. Neurophysiol 121 1023&#x2013;31</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20188627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>