<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">31597125</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>08</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1741-2552</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2019</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>05</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of neural engineering</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Neural Eng</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>An exploration of neural dynamics of motor imagery for people with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>016005</StartPage><MedlinePgn>016005</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1088/1741-2552/ab4c75</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">Studies of the neuropathological effects of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) on the underlying motor system have investigated abnormalities in the magnitude and timing of the event-related desynchronization (ERD) and synchronization (ERS) during motor execution (ME). However, the spatio-spectral-temporal dynamics of these sensorimotor oscillations during motor imagery (MI) have not been fully explored for these patients. This study explores the neural dynamics of sensorimotor oscillations for ALS patients during MI by quantifying ERD/ERS features in frequency, time, and space.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="APPROACH">Electroencephalogram (EEG) data were recorded from six patients with ALS and 11 age-matched healthy controls (HC) while performing a MI task. ERD/ERS features were extracted using wavelet-based time-frequency analysis and compared between the two groups to quantify the abnormal neural dynamics of ALS in terms of both time and frequency. Topographic correlation analysis was conducted to compare the localization of MI activity between groups and to identify subject-specific frequencies in the &#xb5; and &#x3b2; frequency bands.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MAIN RESULTS">Overall, reduced and delayed ERD was observed for ALS patients, particularly during right-hand MI. ERD features were also correlated with ALS clinical scores, specifically disease duration, bulbar, and cognitive functions.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SIGNIFICANCE">The analyses in this study quantify abnormalities in the magnitude and timing of sensorimotor oscillations for ALS patients during MI tasks. Our findings reveal notable differences between MI and existing results on ME in ALS. The observed alterations are speculated to reflect disruptions in the underlying cortical networks involved in MI functions. Quantifying the neural dynamics of MI plays an important role in the study of EEG-based cortical markers for ALS.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hosni</LastName><ForeName>Sarah M</ForeName><Initials>SM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical, Computer and Biomedical Engineering, University of Rhode Island, Kingston, RI, United States of America.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Deligani</LastName><ForeName>R J</ForeName><Initials>RJ</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zisk</LastName><ForeName>A</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McLinden</LastName><ForeName>J</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Borgheai</LastName><ForeName>S B</ForeName><Initials>SB</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shahriari</LastName><ForeName>Y</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>P20 GM103430</GrantID><Acronym>GM</Acronym><Agency>NIGMS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>P41 EB018783</GrantID><Acronym>EB</Acronym><Agency>NIBIB NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Neural Eng</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101217933</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1741-2552</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiopathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D062207" MajorTopicYN="Y">Brain-Computer Interfaces</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004569" MajorTopicYN="N">Electroencephalography</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007092" MajorTopicYN="N">Imagination</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009044" MajorTopicYN="N">Motor Cortex</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010775" MajorTopicYN="N">Photic Stimulation</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011597" MajorTopicYN="N">Psychomotor Performance</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31597125</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS1567178</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7158070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1741-2552/ab4c75</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abrahams S, Goldstein LH, Simmons A, Brammer M, Williams SCR, Giampietro V and Leigh PN 2004. Word retrieval in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a functional magnetic resonance imaging study Brain 127 1507&#x2013;17</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15163610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abrahams S, Leigh PN, Harvey A, Vythelingum GN, Gris&#xe9; D and Goldstein LH 2000. Verbal fluency and executive dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) Neuropsychologia 38 734&#x2013;47</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10689049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aguilera M, Bedia MG, Santos BA and Barandiaran XE 2013. The situated HKB model: how sensorimotor spatial coupling can alter oscillatory brain dynamics Frontiers Comput. Neurosci 7 117</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3750630</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23986692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benjamini Y and Hochberg Y 1995. Controlling the false discovery rate: a practical and powerful approach to multiple testing J. R. Stat. Soc. B 57 289&#x2013;300</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Binkofski F and Buccino G 2004. Motor Functions of the Broca&#x2019;s region Brain Lang. 89 362&#x2013;9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15068919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bizovi&#x10d;ar N, Dreo J, Koritnik B and Zidar J 2014. Decreased movement-related beta desynchronization and impaired post-movement beta rebound in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis Clin. Neurophysiol. 125 1689&#x2013;99</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24457137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brunner C, Delorme A and Makeig S 2013. Eeglab&#x2014;an open source matlab toolbox for electrophysiological research Biomed. Eng./Biomed. Tech (10.1515/bmt-2013-4182)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/bmt-2013-4182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24042816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carvalho D. et al. The mirror neuron system in post-stroke rehabilitation. Int. Arch. Med. 2013;6:41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4016580</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24134862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum JM, Stambler N, Malta E, Fuller C, Hilt D, Thurmond B and Nakanishi A 1999. The ALSFRS-R: a revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. BDNF ALS study group (Phase III) J. Neurol. Sci. 169 13&#x2013;21</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10540002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen MX and Donner TH 2013. Midfrontal conflict-related theta-band power reflects neural oscillations that predict behavior J. Neurophysiol. 110 2752&#x2013;63</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24068756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooper DL 2006. Broca&#x2019;s arrow: evolution, prediction, and language in the brain Anatom. Rec. B 289 9&#x2013;24</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16437554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>David O, Kilner JM and Friston KJ 2006. Mechanisms of evoked and induced responses in MEG/EEG NeuroImage 31 1580&#x2013;91</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16632378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Kleine E and Van der Lubbe RHJ 2011. Decreased load on general motor preparation and visual-working memory while preparing familiar as compared to unfamiliar movement sequences Brain Cognit. 75 126&#x2013;34</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21094573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Derambure P, Defebvre L, Dujardin K, Bourriez JL, Jacquesson JM, Destee A and Guieu JD 1993. Effect of aging on the spatio-temporal pattern of event-related desynchronization during a voluntary movement Electroencephalogr. Clin. Neurophysiol. Evoked Potentials 89 197&#x2013;203</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7686852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eisen A, Lemon R, Kiernan MC, Hornberger M and Turner MR 2015. Does dysfunction of the mirror neuron system contribute to symptoms in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis? Clin. Neurophysiol 126 1288&#x2013;94</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25727900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellis CM, Suckling J, Amaro E Jr, Bullmore ET, Simmons A, Williams SC and Leigh PN 2001. Volumetric analysis reveals corticospinal tract degeneration and extramotor involvement in ALS Neurology 57 1571&#x2013;8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11706094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farina E, Baglio F, Pomati S, D&#x2019;Amico A, Campini IC, Di Tella S, Belloni G and Pozzo T 2017. The mirror neurons network in aging, mild cognitive impairment, and alzheimer disease: a functional MRI study Frontiers Aging Neurosci. 9 371</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5715339</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29249956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fiori F et al. 2016. Erratum to: exploring motor and visual imagery in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis Exp. Brain Res. 234 1783.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26936150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garrison KA, Winstein CJ and Aziz-Zadeh L 2010. The mirror neuron system: a neural substrate for methods in stroke rehabilitation Neurorehabil. Neural Repair 24 404&#x2013;12</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20207851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerardin E, Sirigu A, Leh&#xe9;ricy S, Poline JB, Gaymard B, Marsault C, Agid Y and Le Bihan D 2000. Partially overlapping neural networks for real and imagined hand movements Cerebral Cortex 10 1093&#x2013;1104</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11053230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe9;tu S, Gr&#xe9;goire M, Saimpont A, Coll M-P, Eug&#xe8;ne F, Michon P-E and Jackson PL 2013. The neural network of motor imagery: an ALE meta-analysis Neurosci. Biobehav. Rev 37 930&#x2013;49</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23583615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hobson HM and Bishop DVM 2016. Mu suppression&#x2014;a good measure of the human mirror neuron system? Cortex 82 290&#x2013;310</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4981432</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27180217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hobson HM and Bishop DVM 2017. The interpretation of mu suppression as an index of mirror neuron activity: past, present and future R. Soc. Open Sci 4 160662.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5383811</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28405354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huster RJ, Enriquez-Geppert S, Lavallee CF, Falkenstein M and Herrmann CS 2013. Electroencephalography of response inhibition tasks: functional networks and cognitive contributions Int. J. Psychophysiol 87 217&#x2013;33</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22906815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeon Y, Nam CS, Kim Y-J and Whang MC 2011. Event-related (De) synchronization (ERD/ERS) during motor imagery tasks: implications for brain&#x2013;computer interfaces Int. J. Ind. Ergon 45 428&#x2013;36</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalcher J and Pfurtscheller G 1995. Discrimination between phase-locked and non-phase-locked event-related EEG activity Electroencephalogr. Clin. Neurophysiol 94 381&#x2013;84</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7774524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasahara T, Terasaki K, Ogawa Y, Ushiba J, Aramaki H and Masakado Y 2012. The Correlation between motor impairments and event-related desynchronization during motor imagery in ALS patients BMC Neurosci. 13 66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3437214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22703383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee T-W, Girolami M and Sejnowski TJ 1999. Independent component analysis using an extended infomax algorithm for mixed subgaussian and supergaussian sources Neural Comput. 11 417&#x2013;41</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9950738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leocani L and Comi G 2006. Movement-related event-related desynchronization in neuropsychiatric disorders Prog. Brain Res 159 351&#x2013;66</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17071242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leocani L, Rovaris M, Martinelli-Boneschi F, Annovazzi P, Filippi M, Colombo B, Martinelli V and Comi G 2005. Movement preparation is affected by tissue damage in multiple sclerosis: evidence from EEG event-related desynchronization Clin. Neurophysiol 116 1515&#x2013;9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15953556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ludolph AC, Langen KJ, Regard M, Herzog H, Kemper B, Kuwert T, B&#xf6;ttger IG and Feinendegen L 1992. Frontal lobe function in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a neuropsychologic and positron emission tomography study Acta Neurol. Scand 85 81&#x2013;9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1574993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McFarland DJ, McCane LM, David SV and Wolpaw JR 1997. Spatial filter selection for EEG-based communication Electroencephalogr. Clin. Neurophysiol 103 386&#x2013;94</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9305287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McFarland DJ, Miner LA, Vaughan TM and Wolpaw J R 2000. Mu and beta rhythm topographies during motor imagery and actual movements Brain Topogr. 12 177&#x2013;86</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10791681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehta UM, Thirthalli J, Basavaraju R, Gangadhar BN and Pascual-Leone A 2014. Reduced mirror neuron activity in schizophrenia and its association with theory of mind deficits: evidence from a transcranial magnetic stimulation study Schizophrenia Bull. 40 1083&#x2013;94</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4133670</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24214933</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munzert J, Lorey B and Zentgraf K 2009. Cognitive motor processes: the role of motor imagery in the study of motor representations Brain Res. Rev 60 306&#x2013;26</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19167426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naseer N and Hong K-S 2015. fNIRS-based brain&#x2013;computer interfaces: a review Frontiers Hum. Neurosci 9 3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4309034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25674060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pfurtscheller G 1992. Event-related synchronization (ERS): an electrophysiological correlate of cortical areas at rest Electroencephalogr. Clin. Neurophysiol 83 62&#x2013;9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1376667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pfurtscheller G and Aranibar A 1977. Event-related cortical desynchronization detected by power measurements of scalp EEG Electroencephalogr. Clin. Neurophysiol 42 817&#x2013;26</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">67933</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pfurtscheller G and Berghold A 1989. Patterns of cortical activation during planning of voluntary movement Electroencephalogr. Clin. Neurophysiol 72 250&#x2013;58</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2465128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pfurtscheller G and Klimesch W 1992. Functional topography during a visuoverbal judgment task studied with event-related desynchronization mapping J. Clin. Neurophysiol 9 120&#x2013;31</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1552000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pfurtscheller G and Lopes da Silva FH 1999. Event-related EEG/MEG synchronization and desynchronization: basic principles Clin. Neurophysiol 110 1842&#x2013;57</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10576479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pfurtscheller G and Neuper C 1994. Event-related synchronization of mu rhythm in the EEG over the cortical hand area in man Neurosci. Lett. 174 93&#x2013;96</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7970165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pfurtscheller G and Neuper C 1997. Motor imagery activates primary sensorimotor area in humans Neurosci. Lett. 239 65&#x2013;8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9469657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pfurtscheller G, Neuper C, Flotzinger D and Pregenzer M 1997. EEG-based discrimination between imagination of right and left hand movement Electroencephalogr. Clin. Neurophysiol 103 642&#x2013;51</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9546492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pfurtscheller G, Stanc&#xe1;k A Jr and Neuper C 1996. Event-related synchronization (ERS) in the alpha band&#x2014;an electrophysiological correlate of cortical idling: a review Int. J. Psychophysiol 24 39&#x2013;46</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8978434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pohl A, Anders S, Chen H, Patel HJ, Heller J, Reetz K, Mathiak K and Binkofski F 2017. Impaired emotional mirroring in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease&#x2014;a study on brain activation during processing of facial expressions Frontiers Neurol. 8 682</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5741645</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29326646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poujois A, Schneider FC, Faillenot I, Camdessanch&#xe9; J-P, Vandenberghe N, Thomas-Ant&#xe9;rion C and Antoine J-C 2013. Brain plasticity in the motor network is correlated with disease progression in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis Hum. Brain Mapp. 34 2391&#x2013;401</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6870334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22461315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proudfoot M, Rohenkohl G, Quinn A, Colclough GL, Wuu J, Talbot K, Woolrich MW, Benatar M, Nobre AC and Turner MR 2017. Altered cortical beta-band oscillations reflect motor system degeneration in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis Hum. Brain Mapp. 38 237&#x2013;54</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5215611</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27623516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riva N et al. 2012. Cortical activation to voluntary movement in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis is related to corticospinal damage: electrophysiological evidence Clin. Neurophysiol 123 1586&#x2013;92</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22326728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schalk G and Mellinger J 2010. A Practical Guide to Brain&#x2013;Computer Interfacing with BCI2000: General-Purpose Software for Brain&#x2013;Computer Interface Research, Data Acquisition, Stimulus Presentation, and Brain Monitoring (London: Springer; ) (10.1007/978-1-84996-092-2)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-1-84996-092-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schalk G, McFarland DJ, Hinterberger T, Birbaumer N and Wolpaw JR 2004. BCI2000: a general-purpose brain&#x2013;computer interface (BCI) system IEEE Trans. Biomed. Eng 51 1034&#x2013;43</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15188875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shellikeri S, Karthikeyan V, Martino R, Black SE, Zinman L, Keith J and Yunusova Y 2017. The neuropathological signature of bulbar-onset ALS: a systematic review Neurosci. Biobehav. Rev 75 378&#x2013;92</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5425954</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28163193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stanton BR, Williams VC, Nigel Leigh P, Williams SCR, Blain CRV, Giampietro VP and Simmons A 2007. Cortical activation during motor imagery is reduced in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis Brain Res. 1172 145&#x2013;51</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17765211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tallon-Baudry C, Kreiter A and Bertrand O 1999. Sustained and transient oscillatory responses in the gamma and beta bands in a visual short-term memory task in humans Vis. Neurosci. 16 449&#x2013;50</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10349966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tzagarakis C, Ince NF, Leuthold AC and Pellizze Gr 2010. Beta-band activity during motor planning reflects response uncertainty J. Neurosci. 30 11270&#x2013;7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6633326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20739547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vejux A, Namsi A, Nury T, Moreau T and Lizard G 2018. Biomarkers of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: current status and interest of oxysterols and phytosterols Frontiers Mol. Neurosci 11 12</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5797798</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29445325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vivanti G and Rogers SJ 2014. Autism and the mirror neuron system: insights from learning and teaching Phil. Trans. R. Soc. B 369 20130184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4006185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24778379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Gao X, Hong B and Gao S 2009. Practical designs of brain&#x2013;computer interfaces based on the modulation of EEG rhythms Brain Computer Interfaces (Berlin: Springer; ) pp 137&#x2013;54</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woolley SC, York MK, Moore DH, Strutt AM, Murphy J, Schulz PE and Katz JS 2010. Detecting frontotemporal dysfunction in ALS: utility of the ALS cognitive behavioral screen (ALS-CBS) Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis 11 303&#x2013;11</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20433413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan H and He B 2014. Brain&#x2013;computer interfaces using sensorimotor rhythms: current state and future perspectives IEEE Trans. Biomed. Eng 61 1425&#x2013;35</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4082720</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24759276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Chen Y, Bressler SL and Ding M 2008. Response preparation and inhibition: the role of the cortical sensorimotor beta rhythm Neuroscience 156 238&#x2013;46</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2684699</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18674598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>