<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">31750604</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1468-1331</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>27</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Respiratory function and cognitive profile in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>685</StartPage><EndPage>691</EndPage><MedlinePgn>685-691</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/ene.14130</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND PURPOSE">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) is increasingly recognized as a multisystem disorder with 30%-50% of patients exhibiting cognitive impairment. The pathophysiological mechanisms of cognitive dysfunction are probably multifactorial although hypoventilation secondary to respiratory dysfunction may contribute to cognitive decline. The current study aimed to identify the relationship between respiratory function in ALS patients and the presence and degree of cognitive impairment.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients were prospectively recruited from a multidisciplinary ALS clinic. Baseline clinical assessments including respiratory function as assessed by spirometry were recorded with forced vital capacity (FVC) &#x2264; 75% considered to be reduced respiratory function. Cognitive testing was performed utilizing the Addenbrooke's Cognitive Examination (ACE) and the Mini-Mental State Examination (MMSE).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">From a cohort of 100 ALS patients, 48% were categorized as having impaired respiratory function (FVC&#xa0;=&#xa0;58.24%&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;2.15%) whilst 52% had normal function (88.65%&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;1.27%). Compared to the group with normal respiratory function (ACE 90.68 &#xb1; 0.89, MMSE 28.22 &#xb1; 0.21), patients with respiratory dysfunction had significantly reduced cognitive function (ACE 86.83&#xa0;&#xb1; 1.5, P&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.025; MMSE 26.29&#xa0;&#xb1; 0.45, P&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.029). Furthermore, subscores demonstrated significant differences between the groups with respect to domains in memory (P&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.003) and attention (P&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.05) with a trend observed in fluency (P&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.082). There was a significant correlation between patient baseline FVC and ACE scores as well as between FVC and memory and fluency subscores (P&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;0.01).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients with respiratory compromise were more likely to develop reduced cognitive function. In addition to improving physical function, it remains plausible that non-invasive ventilation may alter the progression of cognitive impairment in ALS patients and potentially improve overall quality of life and carer burden.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2019 European Academy of Neurology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huynh</LastName><ForeName>W</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6504-8107</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Brain and Mind Centre, University of Sydney, Camperdown, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Prince of Wales Clinical School, University of New South Wales, Sydney, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sharplin</LastName><ForeName>L E</ForeName><Initials>LE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, University of Notre Dame, Sydney, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Caga</LastName><ForeName>J</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Brain and Mind Centre, University of Sydney, Camperdown, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Highton-Williamson</LastName><ForeName>E</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Brain and Mind Centre, University of Sydney, Camperdown, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kiernan</LastName><ForeName>M C</ForeName><Initials>MC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Brain and Mind Centre, University of Sydney, Camperdown, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9506311</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1351-5101</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="Y">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003071" MajorTopicYN="N">Cognition</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D060825" MajorTopicYN="N">Cognitive Dysfunction</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="Y">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015331" MajorTopicYN="N">Cohort Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018450" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Progression</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D063087" MajorTopicYN="N">Noninvasive Ventilation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012131" MajorTopicYN="N">Respiratory Insufficiency</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="Y">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014797" MajorTopicYN="N">Vital Capacity</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cognition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">forced vital capacity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">motor neuron disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">non-invasive ventilation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">respiratory function</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2019</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31750604</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ene.14130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Kiernan MC, Vucic S, Cheah BC, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet 2011; 377(9769): 942-955.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hudson AJ. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and its association with dementia, parkinsonism and other neurological disorders: a review. Brain 1981; 104(2): 217-247.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jokelainen M. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in Finland. II: Clinical characteristics. Acta Neurol Scand 1977; 56(3): 194-204.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strong MJ, Grace GM, Freedman M, et al. Consensus criteria for the diagnosis of frontotemporal cognitive and behavioural syndromes in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler 2009; 10(3): 131-146.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ringholz GM, Greene SR. The relationship between amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal dementia. Curr Neurol Neurosci Rep 2006; 6(5): 387-392.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed RM, Caga J, Devenney E, et al. Cognition and eating behavior in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: effect on survival. J Neurol 2016; 263(8): 1593-603.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Carvalho M, Ryczkowski A, Andersen P, et al. International survey of ALS experts about critical questions for assessing patients with ALS. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2017; 18(7-8): 505-510.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lomen-Hoerth C, Murphy J, Langmore S, et al. Are amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients cognitively normal? Neurology 2003; 60(7): 1094-1097.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rottig D, Leplow B, Eger K, et al. Only subtle cognitive deficits in non-bulbar amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. J Neurol 2006; 253(3): 333-339.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woolley SC, Jonathan SK. Cognitive and behavioral impairment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Phys Med Rehabil Clin N Am 2008; 19(3): 607-617.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ludolph AC, Langen KJ, Regard M, et al. Frontal lobe function in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a neuropsychologic and positron emission tomography study. Acta Neurol Scand 1992; 85(2): 81-89.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>David AS, Gillham RA. Neuropsychological study of motor neuron disease. Psychosomatics 1986; 27(6): 441-445.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallassi R, Montagna P, Ciardulli C, et al. Cognitive impairment in motor neuron disease. Acta Neurol Scand 1985; 71(6): 480-484.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abe K, Fujimura H, Toyooka K, et al. Cognitive function in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Sci 1997; 148(1): 95-100.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abrahams S, Leigh PN, Harvey A, et al. Verbal fluency and executive dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). Neuropsychologia 2000; 38(6): 734-747.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kew JJ, Goldstein LH, Leigh PN, et al. The relationship between abnormalities of cognitive function and cerebral activation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. A neuropsychological and positron emission tomography study. Brain 1993; 116(Pt 6): 1399-1423.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kew JJ, Leigh PN, Playford ED, et al. Cortical function in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. A positron emission tomography study. Brain 1993; 116(Pt 3): 655-680.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abrahams S, Goldstein LH, Kew JJM, et al. Frontal lobe dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. A PET study. Brain 1996; 119(Pt 6): 2105-2120.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abrahams S, Goldstein LH, Simmons A, et al. Word retrieval in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a functional magnetic resonance imaging study. Brain 2004; 127(Pt 7): 1507-1517.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kato S, Hayashi H, Yagishita A. Involvement of the frontotemporal lobe and limbic system in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: as assessed by serial computed tomography and magnetic resonance imaging. J Neurol Sci 1993; 116(1): 52-58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newsom-Davis IC, Lyall RA, Leigh PN, Moxham J, Goldstein LH. The effect of non-invasive positive pressure ventilation (NIPPV) on cognitive function in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS): a prospective study. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2001; 71(4): 482-487.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim SM, Lee KM, Hong YH, et al. Relation between cognitive dysfunction and reduced vital capacity in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2007; 78(12): 1387-1389.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strutt AM, Palcic J, Wager JG, et al. Cognition, behavior, and respiratory function in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. ISRN Neurol 2012; 2012: 912123.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Czaplinski A, Yen AA, Appel SH. Forced vital capacity (FVC) as an indicator of survival and disease progression in an ALS clinic population. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2006; 77(3): 390-392.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mioshi E, Dawson K, Mitchell J, et al. The Addenbrooke's Cognitive Examination Revised (ACE-R): a brief cognitive test battery for dementia screening. Int J Geriatr Psychiatry 2006; 21(11): 1078-1085.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsieh S, Schubert S, Hoon C, et al. Validation of the Addenbrooke's Cognitive Examination III in frontotemporal dementia and Alzheimer's disease. Dement Geriatr Cogn Disord 2013; 36(3-4): 242-250.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beeldman E, Jaeger B, Raaphorst J, et al. The verbal fluency index: Dutch normative data for cognitive testing in ALS. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2014; 15(5-6): 388-391.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu Z, Alruwaili ARS, Henderson RD, et al. Screening for cognitive and behavioural impairment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: frequency of abnormality and effect on survival. J Neurol Sci 2017; 376: 16-23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lillo P, Savage S, Mioshi E, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal dementia: a behavioural and cognitive continuum. Amyotroph Lateral Scler 2012; 13(1): 102-109.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raaphorst J, Beeldman E, Jaeger B, et al. Is the Frontal Assessment Battery reliable in ALS patients? Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2013; 14(1): 73-74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park SY, Kim SM, Sung JJ, et al. Nocturnal hypoxia in ALS is related to cognitive dysfunction and can occur as clusters of desaturations. PLoS ONE 2013; 8(9): e75324.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelly DA, Claypoole KH, Coppel DB. Sleep apnea syndrome: symptomatology, associated features, and neurocognitive correlates. Neuropsychol Rev 1990; 1(4): 323-342.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naegele B, Thouvard V, P&#xe9;pin JL, et al. Deficits of cognitive executive functions in patients with sleep apnea syndrome. Sleep 1995; 18(1): 43-52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feuerstein C, Naegel&#xe9; B, P&#xe9;pin JL, L&#xe9;vy P. Frontal lobe-related cognitive functions in patients with sleep apnea syndrome before and after treatment. Acta Neurol Belg 1997; 97(2): 96-107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scheltens P, Visscher F, Van Keimpema ARJ, et al. Sleep apnea syndrome presenting with cognitive impairment. Neurology 1991; 41(1): 155-156.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ortapamuk H, Naldoken S. Brain perfusion abnormalities in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease: comparison with cognitive impairment. Ann Nucl Med 2006; 20(2): 99-106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonelli Incalzi R, Marra C, Giordano A, et al. Cognitive impairment in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease - a neuropsychological and SPECT study. J Neurol 2003; 250(3): 325-332.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wightman G, Anderson V, Martin J, et al. Hippocampal and neocortical ubiquitin-immunoreactive inclusions in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with dementia. Neurosci Lett 1992; 139(2): 269-274.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okamoto K, Hirai S, Yamazaki T, et al. New ubiquitin-positive intraneuronal inclusions in the extra-motor cortices in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurosci Lett 1991; 129(2): 233-236.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitsuyama Y. Presenile dementia with motor neuron disease in Japan: clinico-pathological review of 26 cases. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 1984; 47(9): 953-959.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cervos-Navarro J, Diemer NH. Selective vulnerability in brain hypoxia. Crit Rev Neurobiol 1991; 6(3): 149-182.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Row BW. Intermittent hypoxia and cognitive function: implications from chronic animal models. Adv Exp Med Biol 2007; 618: 51-67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu W, Chi L, Row BW, et al. Increased oxidative stress is associated with chronic intermittent hypoxia-mediated brain cortical neuronal cell apoptosis in a mouse model of sleep apnea. Neuroscience 2004; 126(2): 313-323.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Portet F, Cadilhac C, Touchon J, et al. Cognitive impairment in motor neuron disease with bulbar onset. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord 2001; 2(1): 23-29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Massman PJ, Sims J, Cooke N, et al. Prevalence and correlates of neuropsychological deficits in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 1996; 61(5): 450-455.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chio A, Calvo A, Moglia C, et al. Non-invasive ventilation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a 10 year population based study. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2012; 83(4): 377-381.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berlowitz DJ, Howard ME, Fiore JF, et al. Identifying who will benefit from non-invasive ventilation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis/motor neurone disease in a clinical cohort. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2016; 87(3): 280-286.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bradley WG, Anderson F, Gowda N, et al. Changes in the management of ALS since the publication of the AAN ALS Practice Parameter 1999. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord 2004; 5(4): 240-244.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tilanus TBM, Groothuis JT, ten Broek-Pastoor JMC, et al. Respiratory assessment of ALS patients: a nationwide survey of current Dutch practice. J Neuromuscul Dis 2018; 5(4): 431-438.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>EFNS Task Force on Diagnosis and Management of Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis, Andersen PM, Abrahams S, et al. EFNS guidelines on the clinical management of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (MALS) - revised report of an EFNS task force. Eur J Neurol 2012; 19(3): 360-375.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller RG. Examining the evidence about treatment in ALS/MND. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord 2001; 2(1): 3-7.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>