<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">31773773</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>18</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1531-8249</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>87</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Annals of neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Ann Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis with Pallidonigroluysian Degeneration: A Clinicopathological Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>302</StartPage><EndPage>312</EndPage><MedlinePgn>302-312</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/ana.25652</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">The pallidonigroluysian (PNL) system, the primary component of corticosubcortical circuits, is generally spared in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). We evaluated the clinicopathological features of an unusual form of ALS with PNL degeneration (PNLD) and assessed whether ALS with PNLD represents a distinct ALS subtype.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">From a cohort of 97 autopsied cases of sporadic ALS with phosphorylated 43kDa TAR DNA-binding protein (TDP-43) inclusions, we selected those with PNLD and analyzed their clinicopathological features.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Eleven cases (11%) that showed PNLD were divided into 2 subtypes depending on the lesion distribution: (1) extensive type (n = 6), showing widespread TDP-43 pathology and multisystem degeneration, both involving the PNL system; and (2) limited type (n = 5), showing selective PNL and motor system involvement, thus being unclassifiable in terms of Brettschneider's staging or Nishihira's typing of ALS. The limited type showed a younger age at onset and predominant PNLD that accounted for the early development of extrapyramidal signs. The limited type exhibited the heaviest pathology in the subthalamus and external globus pallidus, suggesting that TDP-43 inclusions propagated via indirect or hyperdirect pathways, unlike ALS without PNLD, where the direct pathway is considered to convey TDP-43 aggregates from the cerebral cortex to the substantia nigra.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="INTERPRETATION">The PNL system can be involved in the disease process of ALS, either nonselectively as part of multisystem degeneration, or selectively. ALS with selective involvement of the PNL and motor systems exhibits unique clinicopathological features and TDP-43 propagation routes, thus representing a distinct subtype of ALS. ANN NEUROL 2020;87:302-312.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2019 American Neurological Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ito</LastName><ForeName>Junko</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7958-1052</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathology, Brain Research Institute, Niigata University, Niigata.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shimizu</LastName><ForeName>Hiroshi</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathology, Brain Research Institute, Niigata University, Niigata.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ohta</LastName><ForeName>Kentaro</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, National Hospital Organization Niigata National Hospital, Kashiwazaki.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Idezuka</LastName><ForeName>Jiro</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Ojiya Sakura Hospital, Ojiya.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tanaka</LastName><ForeName>Hajime</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Shinrakuen Hospital, Niigata.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kondo</LastName><ForeName>Hiroshi</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Brain Disease Center, Agano Hospital, Agano.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nakajima</LastName><ForeName>Takashi</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, National Hospital Organization Niigata National Hospital, Kashiwazaki.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Takahashi</LastName><ForeName>Hitoshi</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathology, Brain Research Institute, Niigata University, Niigata.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Akazawa</LastName><ForeName>Kohei</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Informatics, Niigata University Medical and Dental Hospital, Niigata.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Onodera</LastName><ForeName>Osamu</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Brain Research Institute, Niigata University, Niigata, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kakita</LastName><ForeName>Akiyoshi</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathology, Brain Research Institute, Niigata University, Niigata.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>16804840</GrantID><Agency>Japan Society for the Promotion of Science</Agency><Country>International</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>17H03554</GrantID><Agency>Japan Society for the Promotion of Science</Agency><Country>International</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>16K14571</GrantID><Agency>Japan Society for the Promotion of Science</Agency><Country>International</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>25250008</GrantID><Agency>Japan Society for the Promotion of Science</Agency><Country>International</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Ann Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7707449</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0364-5134</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><SupplMeshList><SupplMeshName Type="Disease" UI="C531617">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis 1</SupplMeshName></SupplMeshList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000369" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged, 80 and over</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000145" MajorTopicYN="N">classification</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="Y">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005917" MajorTopicYN="N">Globus Pallidus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="Y">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002479" MajorTopicYN="N">Inclusion Bodies</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009434" MajorTopicYN="N">Neural Pathways</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013378" MajorTopicYN="N">Substantia Nigra</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="Y">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020531" MajorTopicYN="N">Subthalamic Nucleus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="Y">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057177" MajorTopicYN="N">TDP-43 Proteinopathies</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000145" MajorTopicYN="N">classification</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2018</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2019</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2019</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31773773</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.25652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Neumann M, Sampathu DM, Kwong LK, et al. Ubiquitinated TDP-43 in frontotemporal lobar degeneration and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Science 2006;314:130-133.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arai T, Hasegawa M, Akiyama H, et al. TDP-43 is a component of ubiquitin-positive tau-negative inclusions in frontotemporal lobar degeneration and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Biochem Biophys Res Commun 2006;351:602-611.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishihira Y, Tan CF, Onodera O, et al. Sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: two pathological patterns shown by analysis of distribution of TDP-43-immunoreactive neuronal and glial cytoplasmic inclusions. Acta Neuropathol 2008;116:169-182.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geser F, Brandmeir NJ, Kwong LK, et al. Evidence of multisystem disorder in whole-brain map of pathological TDP-43 in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Arch Neurol 2008;65:636-641.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brettschneider J, Del Tredici K, Toledo JB, et al. Stages of pTDP-43 pathology in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol 2013;74:20-38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braak H, Brettschneider J, Ludolph AC, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-a model of corticofugal axonal spread. Nat Rev Neurol 2013;9:708-714.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeLong MR, Wichmann T. Circuits and circuit disorders of the basal ganglia. Arch Neurol 2007;64:20-24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeLong MR. Primate models of movement disorders of basal ganglia origin. Trends Neurosci 1990;13:281-285.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Contamin F, Escourolle R, Nick J, Mignot B. Atrophy of the globus pallidus, substancia nigra, and nucleus subthalamicus. Akinetic syndrome with palilalia, oppositional rigidity and catatonia [in French]. Rev Neurol (Paris) 1971;124:107-120.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong JC, Armstrong MJ, Lang AE, Hazrati LN. Clinicopathological review of pallidonigroluysian atrophy. Mov Disord 2013;28:274-281.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimoda M, Hosoda Y, Kato S, et al. Pallidonigroluysian atrophy: clinicopathological and immunohistochemical studies. Neuropathology 1996;16:21-28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasegawa K, Ryou M, Kowa H, Yagishita S. A clinicopathologic examination of pallidonigroluysian atrophy. Neuropathology 1997;17:134-139.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed Z, Josephs KA, Gonzalez J, et al. Clinical and neuropathologic features of progressive supranuclear palsy with severe pallido-nigro-luysial degeneration and axonal dystrophy. Brain 2008;131:460-472.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yokoyama Y, Toyoshima Y, Shiga A, et al. Pathological and clinical spectrum of progressive supranuclear palsy: with special reference to astrocytic tau pathology. Brain Pathol 2016;26:155-166.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayashi K, Mochizuki Y, Takeuchi R, et al. Clinicopathological characteristics of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis resulting in a totally locked-in state (communication Stage V). Acta Neuropathol Commun 2016;4:107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gray F, De Baecque C, Serdaru M, Escourolle R. Pallido-luyso-nigral atrophy and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathol Suppl 1981;7:348-351.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gray F, Eizenbaum JF, Gherardi R, et al. Luyso-pallido-nigral atrophy and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathol 1985;66:78-82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasegawa K, Kowa H, Yagishita S. Extrapyramidal system involvement in motor neuron disease. J Neurol Sci 1992;108:137-148.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergmann M, Kuchelmeister K, Migheli A, et al. Motor neuron disease with pallido-luysio-nigral atrophy. Acta Neuropathol 1993;86:105-108.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kato S, Oda M, Murahashi M, Suda N. Motor neuron disease with involvement of the pallido-luysio-nigral system and mesencephalic tegmentum. Clin Neuropathol 1995;14:241-244.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hashimoto T, Matsubara S, Mochizuki Y, et al. Forme fruste or incipient form of widespread-type amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, or motor neuron disease with pallido-nigro-luysian atrophy? An autopsy case report. Neuropathology 2008;28:309-316.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miki Y, Mori F, Nunomura J, et al. Sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with pallido-nigro-luysian degeneration: a TDP-43 immunohistochemical study. Neuropathology 2010;30:149-153.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uchino A, Ogino M, Takahashi-Fujigasaki J, et al. Pathological and immunoblot analysis of phosphorylated TDP-43 in sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with pallido-nigro-luysian degeneration. Neuropathology 2018;38:171-178.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takeuchi R, Toyoshima Y, Tada M, et al. Globular glial mixed four repeat tau and TDP-43 proteinopathy with motor neuron disease and frontotemporal dementia. Brain Pathol 2016;26:82-94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takeuchi R, Tada M, Shiga A, et al. Heterogeneity of cerebral TDP-43 pathology in sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: evidence for clinico-pathologic subtypes. Acta Neuropathol Commun 2016;4:61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piao YS, Wakabayashi K, Kakita A, et al. Neuropathology with clinical correlations of sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: 102 autopsy cases examined between 1962 and 2000. Brain Pathol 2003;13:10-22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baloh RH. TDP-43: the relationship between protein aggregation and neurodegeneration in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal lobar degeneration. FEBS J 2011;278:3539-3549.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halliday G, Bigio EH, Cairns NJ, et al. Mechanisms of disease in frontotemporal lobar degeneration: gain of function versus loss of function effects. Acta Neuropathol 2012;124:373-382.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang YJ, Xu YF, Cook C, et al. Aberrant cleavage of TDP-43 enhances aggregation and cellular toxicity. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 2009;106:7607-7612.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H, Tan CF, Mori F, et al. TDP-43-immunoreactive neuronal and glial inclusions in the neostriatum in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with and without dementia. Acta Neuropathol 2008;115:115-122.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benabid AL, Benazzouz A, Limousin P, et al. Dyskinesias and the subthalamic nucleus. Ann Neurol 2000;47:S189-S192.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudo S, Fukutani Y, Matsubara R, et al. Motor neuron disease with dementia combined with degeneration of striatonigral and pallidoluysian systems. Acta Neuropathol 2002;103:521-525.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>