<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">31788795</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>09</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-4652</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>235</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of cellular physiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Cell Physiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Regulatory T cells for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis/motor neuron disease: A clinical and preclinical systematic review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>5030</StartPage><EndPage>5040</EndPage><MedlinePgn>5030-5040</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jcp.29401</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) is a neurodegenerative disorder characterized by neuronal degeneration and inflammation in the nerves. The role of the immune system has been concentrated by researchers in the etiopathogenesis of the disease. Given the inhibitory roles of regulatory T cells (Tregs), it is expected that increasing or activating their populations in patients with ALS can have significant therapeutic effects. Here we searched databases, including CENTRAL, MEDLINE, CINAHL Plus, clinicaltrials.gov, and ICTRP for randomized clinical trials (RCTs) and non-RCTs until March 2019. For preclinical studies, we searched PubMed, Scopus, and Google Scholar up to June 2019. We also included preclinical studies, due to the lack of clinical information available, which used Tregs (or directly targeting them) for treating mice models of ALS. We identified 29 records (CENTRAL 7, MEDLINE 4, CINAHL Plus 8, and clinicaltrials.gov 10) and removed 10 duplicated publications. After screening, we identified one RCT which had been published as an abstract, three non-RCTs, and four ongoing studies. We also identified 551 records (PubMed 446, Google Scholar 68, and Scopus 37) for preclinical studies and performed a meta-analysis. Finally, we found three papers that matched our inclusion criteria for preclinical studies. Results indicated the effectiveness of the application of Tregs in the treatment of ALS. Our meta-analysis on preclinical studies revealed that Tregs significantly prolonged survival in mice models of ALS. Overall, our analysis testified that exertion of Tregs in the treatment of ALS is a promising approach, that notwithstanding, requires further evaluations.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2019 Wiley Periodicals, Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rajabinejad</LastName><ForeName>Misagh</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1217-2059</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Student Research Committee, School of Medicine, Kermanshah University of Medical Sciences, Kermanshah, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Immunology, School of Medicine, Kermanshah University of Medical Sciences, Kermanshah, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ranjbar</LastName><ForeName>Sedigheh</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1673-8961</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Student Research Committee, School of Medicine, Kermanshah University of Medical Sciences, Kermanshah, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Immunology, School of Medicine, Kermanshah University of Medical Sciences, Kermanshah, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Afshar Hezarkhani</LastName><ForeName>Leila</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0244-0379</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, School of Medicine, Farabi Hospital, Kermanshah University of Medical Sciences, Kermanshah, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Salari</LastName><ForeName>Farhad</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3211-0354</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Immunology, School of Medicine, Kermanshah University of Medical Sciences, Kermanshah, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gorgin Karaji</LastName><ForeName>Ali</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4537-5722</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Immunology, School of Medicine, Kermanshah University of Medical Sciences, Kermanshah, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rezaiemanesh</LastName><ForeName>Alireza</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2551-705X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Immunology, School of Medicine, Kermanshah University of Medical Sciences, Kermanshah, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Cell Physiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0050222</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0021-9541</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="Y">immunology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007249" MajorTopicYN="N">Inflammation</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="Y">immunology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016472" MajorTopicYN="N">Motor Neuron Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="Y">immunology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009046" MajorTopicYN="N">Motor Neurons</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D050378" MajorTopicYN="N">T-Lymphocytes, Regulatory</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="Y">immunology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">motor neuron disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">preclinical study</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">randomized controlled trial</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">regulatory T cells</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2019</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31788795</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jcp.29401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>A McCombe, P., &amp; D Henderson, R. (2011). The role of immune and inflammatory mechanisms in ALS. Current Molecular Medicine, 11(3), 246-254.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ajroud-Driss, S., &amp; Siddique, T. (2015). Sporadic and hereditary amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). Biochimica et Biophysica Acta (BBA)-Molecular Basis of Disease, 1852(4), 679-684.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alsuliman, A., Appel, S. H., Beers, D. R., Basar, R., Shaim, H., Kaur, I., &#x2026; Rezvani, K. (2016). A robust, good manufacturing practice-compliant, clinical-scale procedure to generate regulatory T cells from patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis for adoptive cell therapy. Cytotherapy, 18(10), 1312-1324.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azimi, M., Aslani, S., Mortezagholi, S., Salek, A., Javan, M. R., Rezaiemanesh, A., &#x2026; Salehi, E. (2016). Identification, isolation, and functional assay of regulatory T cells. Immunological Investigations, 45(7), 584-602. https://doi.org/10.1080/08820139.2016.1193869</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bargh, S. R. C., Tafakhori, A., Masoumi, F., Rahmani, F., Ahmadi, M., Namdar, A., &#x2026; Zamani, B. (2018). Evaluation of regulatory T lymphocytes and IL2Ra and FOXP3 gene expression in peripheral mononuclear cells from patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Irish Journal of Medical Science (1971-), 1-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beers, D. R., &amp; Appel, S. H. (2019). Immune dysregulation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Mechanisms and emerging therapies. The Lancet Neurology, 18(2), 211-220.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beers, D. R., Henkel, J. S., Zhao, W., Wang, J., Huang, A., Wen, S., &#x2026; Appel, S. H. (2011). Endogenous regulatory T lymphocytes ameliorate amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in mice and correlate with disease progression in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain, 134(5), 1293-1314.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beers, D. R., Zhao, W., Wang, J., Zhang, X., Wen, S., Neal, D., &#x2026; Rezvani, K. (2017). ALS patients' regulatory T lymphocytes are dysfunctional, and correlate with disease progression rate and severity. JCI Insight, 2(5).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bensimon, G., Camu, W., Payan, C., Tree, T., Veyrune, J.-L., Malaspina, A., &#x2026; Leigh, P. (2017). Immuno-modulation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-a phase II study of safety and activity of low dose interleukin-2 (IMODALS study). Neurology, 88(16 Suppl.), S3.006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks, B. R. (1994). El escorial World Federation of Neurology criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Journal of the Neurological Sciences, 124, 96-107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks, B. R., Miller, R. G., Swash, M., &amp; Munsat, T. L. (2000). El Escorial revisited: Revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis and Other Motor Neuron Disorders, 1(5), 293-299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum, J. M., Stambler, N., Malta, E., Fuller, C., Hilt, D., Thurmond, B., &amp; Nakanishi, A. (1999). The ALSFRS-R: A revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. Journal of the Neurological Sciences, 169(1-2), 13-21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Czaplinski, A., Yen, A., &amp; Appel, S. H. (2006). Forced vital capacity (FVC) as an indicator of survival and disease progression in an ALS clinic population. Journal of Neurology, Neurosurgery and Psychiatry, 77(3), 390-392.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henkel, J. S., Beers, D. R., Wen, S., Rivera, A. L., Toennis, K. M., Appel, J. E., &#x2026; Appel, S. H. (2013). Regulatory T-lymphocytes mediate amyotrophic lateral sclerosis progression and survival. EMBO Molecular Medicine, 5(1), 64-79.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins, J. &amp; Green, S. (Eds.), (2011). Cochrane handbook for systematic reviews of interventions. Version 5.1.0. Oxford, UK: The Cochrane Collaboration. www.cochrane-handbook.org</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lasiene, J., &amp; Yamanaka, K. (2011). Glial cells in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology Research International, 2011, 1-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mancuso, R., &amp; Navarro, X. (2015). Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Current perspectives from basic research to the clinic. Progress in Neurobiology, 133, 1-26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandrioli, J., D'Amico, R., Zucchi, E., Gessani, A., Fini, N., Fasano, A., &#x2026; Lunetta, C. (2018). Rapamycin treatment for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Protocol for a phase II randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, multicenter, clinical trial (RAP-ALS trial). Medicine, 97(24) e11119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mateen, F. J., Carone, M., &amp; Sorenson, E. J. (2010). Patients who survive 5 years or more with ALS in Olmsted County, 1925-2004. Journal of Neurology, Neurosurgery &amp; Psychiatry, 81(10), 1144-1146.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menon, P., McKay, F., Schibeci, S., Booth, D., Marmash, N., Parnell, G., &#x2026; Vucic, S. (2014). Regulatory T cells in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A role for disease modulation? Journal of Clinical Neuroscience, 21(11), 2050.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohr, A., Malhotra, R., Mayer, G., Gorochov, G., &amp; Miyara, M. (2018). Human FOXP3+ T regulatory cell heterogeneity. Clinical &amp; Translational Immunology, 7(1), 1005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moisse, K., &amp; Strong, M. J. (2006). Innate immunity in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Biochimica et Biophysica Acta (BBA)-Molecular Basis of Disease, 1762(11-12), 1083-1093.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen, M. D., D'Aigle, T., Gowing, G., Julien, J.-P., &amp; Rivest, S. (2004). Exacerbation of motor neuron disease by chronic stimulation of innate immunity in a mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Journal of Neuroscience, 24(6), 1340-1349.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paganoni, S., Alshikho, M. J., Luppino, S., Chan, J., Pothier, L., Schoenfeld, D., &#x2026; Atassi, N. (2019). A pilot trial of RNS60 in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle &amp; Nerve, 59(3), 303-308.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phani, S., Re, D. B., &amp; Przedborski, S. (2012). The role of the innate immune system in ALS. Frontiers in Pharmacology, 3, 150.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puhan, M. A., Sch&#xfc;nemann, H. J., Murad, M. H., Li, T., Brignardello-Petersen, R., Singh, J. A., &#x2026; Guyatt, G. H. (2014). A GRADE Working Group approach for rating the quality of treatment effect estimates from network meta-analysis. BMJ, 349, g5630.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheean, R. K., McKay, F. C., Cretney, E., Bye, C. R., Perera, N. D., Tomas, D., &#x2026; Turner, B. J. (2018). Association of regulatory T-cell expansion with progression of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A study of humans and a transgenic mouse model. JAMA Neurology, 75(6), 681-689.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simmons, Z., Felgoise, S. H., Rodriguez, J. L., Walsh, S. M., Bremer, B. A., &amp; Stephens, H. E. (2010). Validation of a shorter ALS-specific quality of life instrument: The ALSSQOL-R. Paper presented at the Neurology.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Talbot, K., Feneberg, E., Scaber, J., Thompson, A. G., &amp; Turner, M. R. (2018). Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: The complex path to precision medicine. Journal of Neurology, 265(10), 2454-2462.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thonhoff, J. R., Beers, D. R., Zhao, W., Pleitez, M., Simpson, E. P., Berry, J. D., &#x2026; Appel, S. H. (2018). Expanded autologous regulatory T-lymphocyte infusions in ALS: A phase I, first-in-human study. Neurology-Neuroimmunology Neuroinflammation, 5(4), e465.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vallarola, A., Sironi, F., Tortarolo, M., Gatto, N., De Gioia, R., Pasetto, L., &#x2026; Watson, R. (2018). RNS60 exerts therapeutic effects in the SOD1 ALS mouse model through protective glia and peripheral nerve rescue. Journal of Neuroinflammation, 15(1), 65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Dyke, J. M., Smit-Oistad, I. M., Macrander, C., Krakora, D., Meyer, M. G., &amp; Suzuki, M. (2016). Macrophage-mediated inflammation and glial response in the skeletal muscle of a rat model of familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). Experimental Neurology, 277, 275-282.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, W., Beers, D. R., &amp; Appel, S. H. (2013). Immune-mediated mechanisms in the pathoprogression of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Journal of Neuroimmune Pharmacology, 8(4), 888-899.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, W., Beers, D. R., Liao, B., Henkel, J. S., &amp; Appel, S. H. (2012). Regulatory T lymphocytes from ALS mice suppress microglia and effector T lymphocytes through different cytokine-mediated mechanisms. Neurobiology of Disease, 48(3), 418-428. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nbd.2012.07.008</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zou, Z.-Y., Zhou, Z.-R., Che, C.-H., Liu, C.-Y., He, R.-L., &amp; Huang, H.-P. (2017). Genetic epidemiology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Journal of Neurology, Neurosurgery and Psychiatry, 88(7), 540-549.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>