<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">31802540</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1440-1789</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>40</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Neuropathology : official journal of the Japanese Society of Neuropathology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Neuropathology</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Phenotypic variability and its pathological basis in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>40</StartPage><EndPage>56</EndPage><MedlinePgn>40-56</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/neup.12606</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) is characterized by its inherent clinicopathological variability. The concurrence of upper and lower motor neuron signs is a common feature in the majority of patients with ALS. However, some patients manifest an atypical clinical course, with only upper or lower motor neuron signs, or various extra-motor symptoms including cognitive dysfunction, parkinsonism, autonomic dysfunction, or ophthalmoparesis. This variability indicates different manifestations of ALS and is reflected by ALS pathology spreading into the central nervous system. The presence of cytoplasmic inclusions positive for transactivation response DNA-binding protein 43 kDa (TDP-43) is a key feature in ALS. Loss of TDP-43 from the nucleus and its subsequent aggregation in the cytoplasm may occur in susceptible regions and may be associated with neuronal loss. However, in some regions, there is no apparent neuronal loss while TDP-43 accumulation is evident; in contrast, in other regions, neuronal loss is apparent without any evidence of TDP-43 accumulation. Therefore, in addition to TDP-43 dysfunction, underlying region-specific cellular vulnerability may exist in the upper and lower motor neurons and frontotemporal system in patients with ALS. The microscopic discrepancy and selective vulnerability may be linked to the macroscopic propensities of the sites of onset, and may also determine the direction and rate of progression of the lesions. Thus, there may be multicentric sites of onset, region-oriented disease development, and different speeds of disease progression across patients with ALS. ALS lesions occur in motor-related areas but may spread to neighboring areas. However, since lesions may spread in a discontinuous manner, and the dynamics of disease propagation have not been able to be identified, it remains controversial whether the stepwise appearance of TDP-43-positive inclusions is based on direct cell-to-cell protein propagation. Further understanding of the phenotypic variability of ALS and its pathological basis may serve as a guide for investigating the underlying pathogenesis of ALS.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2019 Japanese Society of Neuropathology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Takeda</LastName><ForeName>Takahiro</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, National Hospital Organization Chibahigashi National Hospital, Chiba, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Tokyo Women's Medical University, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kitagawa</LastName><ForeName>Kazuo</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Tokyo Women's Medical University, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Arai</LastName><ForeName>Kimihito</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, National Hospital Organization Chibahigashi National Hospital, Chiba, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Australia</Country><MedlineTA>Neuropathology</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9606526</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0919-6544</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="Y">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000073537" MajorTopicYN="N">Biological Variation, Population</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001921" MajorTopicYN="N">Brain</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018450" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Progression</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057174" MajorTopicYN="N">Frontotemporal Lobar Degeneration</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="Y">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009046" MajorTopicYN="N">Motor Neurons</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="Y">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bunina body</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Charcot</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">TDP-43</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">frontotemporal lobar degeneration</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2019</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2019</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31802540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/neup.12606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Ince PG, Highley JR, Wharton SB. Motor neuron disorders. In: Love S, Budka H, Ironside J, Perry A, (eds). Greenfield's Neuropathology, 9th edn, vol. 1. Boca Raton: CRC Press, 2015; 817-848.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neumann M, Sampathu DM, Kwong LK et al. Ubiquitinated TDP-43 in frontotemporal lobar degeneration and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Science 2006; 314: 130-133.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arai T, Hasegawa M, Akiyama H et al. TDP-43 is a component of ubiquitin-positive tau-negative inclusions in frontotemporal lobar degeneration and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Biochem Biophys Res Commun 2006; 351: 602-611.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishihira Y, Tan CF, Onodera O et al. Sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Two pathological patterns shown by analysis of distribution of TDP-43-immunoreactive neuronal and glial cytolasmic inclusions. Acta Neuropathol 2008; 116: 169-182.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brettschneider J, Del Tredici K, Toledo JB et al. Stages of pTDP-43 pathology in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol 2013; 74: 20-38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neumann M, Mackenzie IRA. Review: Neuropathology of non-tau frontotemporal lobar degeneration. Neuropathol Appl Neurobiol 2019; 45: 19-40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ringholz GM, Appel SH, Bradshaw M, Cooke NA, Mosnik DM, Schulz PE. Prevalence and patterns of cognitive impairment in sporadic ALS. Neurology 2005; 65: 586-590.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boekestein WA, Kleine BU, Hageman G, Schelhaas HJ, Zwarts MJ. Sensitivity and specificity of the 'Awaji' electrodiagnostic criteria for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Retrospective comparison of the Awaji and revised El Escorial criteria for ALS. Amyotroph Lateral Scler 2010; 11: 497-501.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen A, Weimer L, Brannagan T 3rd et al. Experience with the Awaji Island modifications to the ALS diagnostic criteria. Muscle Nerve 2010; 42: 831-832.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gawel M, Kuzma-Kozakiewicz M, Szmidt-Salkowska E, Kami&#x144;ska A. Are we really closer to improving the diagnostic sensitivity in ALS patients with Awaji criteria? Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2014; 15: 257-261.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geevasinga N, Menon P, Yiannikas C, Kiernan MC, Vucic S. Diagnostic utility of cortical excitability studies in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Eur J Neurol 2014; 21: 1451-1457.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higashihara M, Sonoo M, Imafuku I et al. Fasciculation potentials in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and the diagnostic yield of the Awaji algorithm. Muscle Nerve 2012; 45: 175-182.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noto Y, Misawa S, Kanai K et al. Awaji ALS criteria increase the diagnostic sensitivity in patients with bulbar onset. Clin Neurophysiol 2012; 123: 382-385.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charcot JM. Scl&#xe9;rose des cordons lat&#xe9;raux de la moelle &#xe9;pini&#xe9;re chez une femme hyst&#xe9;rique atteinte de contracture permanente des quatre membres. Bull Soc Med 1865: 24-35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charcot J-M, Joffroy A. Deux cas d'atrophie musculaire progressive avec l&#xe9;sions de la substance grise et de faisceaux ant&#xe9;rolat&#xe9;raux de la moelle &#xe9;pini&#xe8;re. Arch Physiol Norm Pathol 1869; 1: 354-367; 2:628-649; 3:744-757.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charcot J-M. Amyotrophies spinales deuteropathiques scl&#xe9;rose lat&#xe9;rale amyotrophique. In: Oeuvres Compl&#xe8;tes, vol. 2. Paris: Bureaux du Progr&#xe8;s M&#xe9;dical, 1874; 234-248.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goetz CG. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Early contributions of Jean-Martin Charcot. Muscle Nerve 2000; 23: 336-343.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Talbott EO, Malek AM, Lacomis D. The epidemiology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. In: Aminoff MJ, Boller F, Swaab DF, (eds). Handbook of Clinical Neurology, vol. 138, Neuroepidemiology, 3rd Series. Amsterdam: Elsevier, 2016; 225-223.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oskarsson B, Gendron TF, Staff NP. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: An update for 2018. Mayo Clin Proc 2018; 93: 1617-1628.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takeda T, Uchihara T, Nakayama Y et al. Dendritic retraction, but not atrophy, is consistent in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-comparison between Onuf's neurons and other sacral motor neurons. Acta Neuropathol Commun 2014; 2: 11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bunina TL. On intracellular inclusions in familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Korsakov J Neuropathol Psychiatory 1962; 62: 1293-1299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okamoto K, Morimatsu M, Hirai S, Ishida Y. Intracytoplasmic inclusions (Bunina bodies) in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Pathol Jpn 1980; 30: 591-597.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okamoto K, Hirai S, Amari M, Watanabe M, Sakurai A. Bunina bodies in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis immunostained with rabbit anti-cystatin C serum. Neurosci Lett 1993; 162: 125-128.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mizuno Y, Amari M, Takatama M, Aizawa H, Mihara B, Okamoto K. Transferrin localizes in Bunina bodies in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathol 2006; 112: 597-603.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sasaki S, Maruyama S. Ultrastructural study of Bunina bodies in the anterior horn neurons of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurosci Lett 1993; 154: 117-120.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshida S, Mitani K, Wakayama I, Kihira T, Yase Y. Bunina body formation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A morphometric-statistical and trace element study featuring aluminum. J Neurol Sci 1995; 130: 88-94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mori F, Tanji K, Zhang HX et al. Maturation process of TDP-43-positive neuronal cytoplasmic inclusions in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with and without dementia. Acta Neuropathol 2008; 116: 193-203.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leigh PN, Anderton BH, Dodson A, Gallo JM, Swash M, Power DM. Ubiquitin deposits in anterior horn cells in motor neurone disease. Neurosci Lett 1988; 93: 197-203.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chou S. Motoneuron inclusions in ALS are heavily ubiquitinated. J Neuropathol Exp Neurol 1988; 47: 334.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lowe J, Lennox G, Jefferson D et al. A filamentous inclusion body within anterior horn neurones in motor neurone disease defined by immunocytochemical localisation of ubiquitin. Neurosci Lett 1988; 94: 203-210.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackenzie IR, Neumann M, Baborie A et al. A harmonized classification system for FTLD-TDP pathology. Acta Neuropathol 2011; 122: 111-113.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brettschneider J, Del Tredici K, Irwin DJ et al. Sequential distribution of pTDP-43 pathology in behavioral variant frontotemporal dementia (bvFTD). Acta Neuropathol 2014; 127: 423-439.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackenzie IR, Neumann M. Reappraisal of TDP-43 pathology in FTLD-U subtypes. Acta Neuropathol 2017; 134: 79-96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishihira Y, Gefen T, Mao Q et al. Revisiting the utility of TDP-43 immunoreactive (TDP-43-ir) pathology to classify FTLD-TDP subtypes. Acta Neuropathol 2019; 138: 167-169.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takeda T, Iijima M, Shimizu Y et al. p.N345K mutation in TARDBP in a patient with familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: An autopsy case. Neuropathology 2019; 39: 286-293.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nonneman A, Robberecht W, Van Den Bosch L. The role of oligodendroglial dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurodegener Dis Manag 2014; 4: 223-239.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kato S, Oda M, Tanabe H. Diminution of dopaminergic neurons in the substantia nigra of sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuropathol Appl Neurobiol 1993; 19: 300-304.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakano I. Frontotemporal dementia with motor neuron disease (amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with dementia). Neuropathology 2000; 20: 68-75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brettschneider J, Libon DJ, Toledo JB et al. Microglial activation and TDP-43 pathology correlate with executive dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathol 2012; 123: 395-407.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takeda T, Iijima M, Uchihara T et al. TDP-43 Pathology progression along the olfactory pathway as a possible substrate for olfactory impairment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neuropathol Exp Neurol 2015; 74: 547-556.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riku Y, Watanabe H, Yoshida M et al. Marked involvement of the striatal efferent system in TAR DNA-binding protein 43&#x2009;kDa-related frontotemporal lobar degeneration and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neuropathol Exp Neurol 2016; 75: 801-811.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCluskey L, Vandriel S, Elman L et al. ALS-Plus syndrome: Non-pyramidal features in a large ALS cohort. J Neurol Sci 2014; 345: 118-124.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garg N, Park SB, Vucic S et al. Differentiating lower motor neuron syndromes. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2017; 88: 474-483.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gombault A. Scl&#xe9;rose sym&#xe9;trique des cordon lat&#xe9;raux de la moelle et des pyramides ant&#xe9;rieurses dans le bulbe. Arch Physiol Norm Pathol 1871-1872; 4: 509-518.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2; A, Calvo A, Moglia C, Mazzini L, Mora G, PARALS study group. Phenotypic heterogeneity of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A population based study. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2011; 82: 740-746.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swinnen B, Robberecht W. The phenotypic variability of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat Rev Neurol 2014; 10: 661-670.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aran FA. Recherches sur une maladie non encore d&#xe9;crite du syst&#xe8;me musculaire: Atrophie musculaire progressive. Arch G&#xe9;n M&#xe9;d 1850; 24: 5-36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cruveilhier J. Sur la paralysie musculaire progressive amyotrophique. Bull Acad M&#xe9;d 1853; 18: 490-502.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duchenne de Boulogne GBA. &#xc9;tude compar&#xe9;e de l&#xe9;sions anatomiques dans l'atrophie musculaire progressive et dans la paralysie g&#xe9;n&#xe9;rale. Union m&#xe9;dicale 1853; 7: 202.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prudlo J, Bi&#xdf;bort C, Glass A et al. White matter pathology in ALS and lower motor neuron ALS variants: A diffusion tensor imaging study using tract-based spatial statistics. J Neurol 2012; 259: 1848-1859.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brownell B, Oppenheimer DR, Hughes JT. The central nervous system in motor neurone disease. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 1970; 33: 338-357.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ince PG, Evans J, Knopp M et al. Corticospinal tract degeneration in the progressive muscular atrophy variant of ALS. Neurology 2003; 60: 1252-1258.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wijesekera LC, Mathers S, Talman P et al. Natural history and clinical features of the flail arm and flail leg ALS variants. Neurology 2009; 72: 1087-1094.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gamez J, Cervera C, Codina A. Flail arm syndrome of Vulpian-Bernhart's form of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 1999; 67: 258.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katz JS, Wolfe GI, Andersson PB et al. Brachial amyotrophic diplegia: A slowly progressive motor neuron disorder. Neurology 1999; 53: 1071-1076.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu MT, Ellis CM, Al-Chalabi A, Leigh PN, Shaw CE. Flail arm syndrome: A distinctive variant of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 1998; 65: 950-951.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erb W. Uber einen wenig bekannten spinalen Symptomencomplex. Berliner Klinische Wochenschrift 1875; 12: 357-359.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erb W. Spastic and syphilitic spinal paralysis. Lancet 1902; 2: 969-974.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finegan E, Chipika RH, Shing SLH, Hardiman O, Bede P. Primary lateral sclerosis: A distinct entity or part of the ALS spectrum? Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2019; 20: 133-145.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tartaglia MC, Rowe A, Findlater K, Orange JB, Grace G, Strong MJ. Differentiation between primary lateral sclerosis and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Examination of symptoms and signs at disease onset and during follow-up. Arch Neurol 2007; 64: 232-236.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wais V, Rosenbohm A, Petri S et al. The concept and diagnostic criteria of primary lateral sclerosis. Acta Neurol Scand 2017; 136: 204-211.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon P, Cheng B, Katz IB et al. The natural history of primary lateral sclerosis. Neurology 2006; 66: 647-653.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kosaka T, Fu YJ, Shiga A et al. Primary lateral sclerosis: Upper-motor-predominant amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with frontotemporal lobar degeneration-immunohistochemical and biochemical analyses of TDP-43. Neuropathology 2012; 32: 373-384.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaiser SR, Mitra D, Williams TL, Baker MR. Mills' syndrome revisited. J Neurol 2019; 266: 667-679.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doran M, Enevoldson TP, Ghadiali EJ, Larner AJ. Mills syndrome with dementia: Broadening the phenotype of FTD/MND. J Neurol 2005; 252: 846-847.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuasa R. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with organic dementia (in Japanese with English abstract). Rinsho Shinkeigaku 1964; 4: 529-534.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonduelle M, Bouygues P, Escourolle R, Lormeau G. &#xc9;volution simultan&#xe9;e d'une scl&#xe9;rose lat&#xe9;rale amyotrophique, d'un syndrome Parkinsonnien et d'une d&#xe9;mence progressive. &#xc0; propos de deux observations anatomo-cliniques saessai d'interpr&#xe9;tation. J Neurol Sci 1968; 6: 315-332.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitsuyama Y. Presenile dementia with motor neuron disease in Japan: Clinico-pathological review of 26 cases. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 1984; 47: 953-959.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rippon GA, Scarmeas N, Gordon PH et al. An observational study of cognitive impairment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Arch Neurol 2006; 63: 345-352.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phukan J, Pender NP, Hardiman O. Cognitive impairment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet Neurol 2007; 6: 994-1003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waldemar G, Vorstrup S, Jensen TS, Johnsen A, Boysen G. Focal reductions of cerebral blood flow in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A [99mTc]-d,l-HMPAO SPECT study. J Neurol Sci 1992; 107: 19-28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takeda T, Uchihara T, Arai N, Mizutani T, Iwata M. Progression of hippocampal degeneration in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with or without memory impairment: Distinction from Alzheimer disease. Acta Neuropathol 2009; 117: 35-44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamada H, Takeda T, Uchihara T et al. Macroscopic localized subicular thinning as a potential indicator of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Eur Neurol 2018; 9: 200-205.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takeda T, Uchihara T, Mochizuki Y, Mizutani T, Iwata M. Memory deficits in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients with dementia and degeneration of the perforant pathway a clinicopathological study. J Neurol Sci 2007; 260: 225-230.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beeldman E, Raaphorst J, Klein Twennaar M, de Visser M, Schmand BA, de Haan RJ. The cognitive profile of ALS: A systematic review and meta-analysis update. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2016; 87: 611-619.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strong MJ, Grace GM, Freedman M et al. Consensus criteria for the diagnosis of frontotemporal cognitive and behavioural syndromes in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler 2009; 10: 131-146.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garruto RM, Yanagihara R. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in the Mariana Islands. In: De Jong JMBV, (ed). Handbook of Clinical Neurology, vol. 15. Amsterdam: Elsevier Science Publishers, 1991; 253-271.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuzuhara S, Kokubo Y, Sasaki R et al. Familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and parkinsonism-dementia complex of the Kii Peninsula of Japan: Clinical and neuropathological study and tau analysis. Ann Neurol 2001; 49: 501-511.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Itoh N, Ishiguro K, Arai H et al. Biochemical and ultrastructural study of neurofibrillary tangles in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis/parkinsonism-dementia complex in the Kii peninsula of Japan. J Neuropathol Exp Neurol 2003; 62: 791-798.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mimuro M, Yoshida M, Kuzuhara S, Kokubo Y. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and parkinsonism-dementia complex of the Hohara focus of the Kii Peninsula: A multiple proteinopathy? Neuropathology 2018; 38: 98-107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uchino A, Ogino M, Takahashi-Fujigasaki J et al. Pathological and immunoblot analysis of phosphorylated TDP-43 in sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with pallido-nigro-luysian degeneration. Neuropathology 2018; 38: 171-178.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gray F, Eizenbaum JF, Gherardi R, Degos JD, Poirier J. Luyso-pallido-nigral atrophy and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathol 1985; 66: 78-82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergmann M, Kuchelmeister K, Migheli A, Schiffer D, Gullotta F. Motor neuron disease with pallido-luysio-nigral atrophy. Acta Neuropathol 1993; 86: 105-108.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasegawa K, Kowa H, Yagishita S. Extrapyramidal system involvement in motor neuron disease. J Neurol Sci 1992; 108: 137-148.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miki Y, Mori F, Nunomura J et al. Sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with pallido-nigro-luysian degeneration: A TDP-43 immunohistochemical study. Neuropathology 2010; 30: 149-153.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossor AM, Jaunmuktane Z, Rossor MN, Hoti G, Reilly MM. TDP43 pathology in the brain, spinal cord, and dorsal root ganglia of a patient with FOSMN. Neurology 2019; 92: e951-e956.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonduelle M. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. In: Vinken PJ, Bruyn GW, (eds). Handbook of Clinical Neurology, vol. 22. New York: American Elsevier Publishing Co, Inc, 1975; 281-338.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castaigne P, Lhermitte F, Cambier J, Escourolle R, Le Bigot P. &#xc9;tude neuropathologique de 61 observations de scl&#xe9;rose lat&#xe9;rale amyotrophique. Discussion nosologique. Rev Neurol (Paris) 1972; 127: 401-414.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horoupian DS, Thal L, Katzman R et al. Dementia and motor neuron disease: Morphometric, biochemical, and Golgi studies. Ann Neurol 1984; 16: 305-313.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kato S, Oda M, Tanabe H. Iminution of dopaminergic neurons in the substantia nigra of sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuropathol Appl Neurobiol 1993; 19: 300-304.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindquist SG, Duno M, Batbayli M et al. Corticobasal and ataxia syndromes widen the spectrum of C9ORF72 hexanucleotide expansion disease. Clin Genet 2013; 83: 279-283.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elden AC, Kim HJ, Hart MP et al. Ataxin-2 intermediate-length polyglutamine expansions are associated with increased risk for ALS. Nature 2010; 466: 1069-1075.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xe4;umer D, East SZ, Tseu B et al. FTLD-ALS of TDP-43 type and SCA2 in a family with a full ataxin-2 polyglutamine expansion. Acta Neuropathol 2014; 128: 597-604.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nanetti L, Fancellu R, Tomasello C, Gellera C, Pareyson D, Mariotti C. Rare association of motor neuron disease and spinocerebellar ataxia type 2 (SCA2): A new case and review of the literature. J Neurol 2009; 256: 1926-1928.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hart MP, Brettschneider J, Lee VM, Trojanowski JQ, Gitler AD. Distinct TDP-43 pathology in ALS patients with ataxin 2 intermediate-length polyQ expansions. Acta Neuropathol 2012; 124: 221-230.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mannen T, Iwata M, Toyokura Y, Nagashima K. Preservation of a certain motoneurone group of the sacral cord in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Its clinical significance. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 1977; 40: 464-469.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pringle CE, Hudson AJ, Munoz DG, Kiernan JA, Brown WF, Ebers GC. Primary lateral sclerosis. Clinical features, neuropathology and diagnostic criteria. Brain 1992; 115: 495-520.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arlandis S, V&#xe1;zquez-Costa JF, Mart&#xed;nez-Cuenca E, Sevilla T, Boronat F, Broseta E. Urodynamic findings in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients with lower urinary tract symptoms: Results from a pilot study. NeurourolUrodyn 2017; 36: 626-631.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leveille A, Kiernan J, Goodwin JA, Antel J. Eye movements in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Arch Neurol 1982; 39: 684-686.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takeda T, Uchihara T, Mochizuki Y et al. Supranuclear ophthalmoparesis and vacuolar degeneration of the cerebral white matter in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A clinicopathological study. Amyotroph Lateral Scler 2012; 13: 74-83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atsuta N, Watanabe H, Ito M et al. Age at onset influences on wide-ranged clinical features of sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Sci 2009; 276: 163-169.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braak H, Ludolph AC, Neumann M, Ravits J, Del Tredici K. Pathological TDP-43 changes in Betz cells differ from those in bulbar and spinal &#x3b1;-motoneurons in sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathol 2017; 133: 79-90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nana AL, Sidhu M, Gaus SE et al. Neurons selectively targeted in frontotemporal dementia reveal early stage TDP-43 pathobiology. Acta Neuropathol 2019; 137: 27-46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sekiguchi T, Kanouchi T, Shibuya K et al. Spreading of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis lesions-multifocal hits and local propagation? J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2014; 85: 85-91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spiller KJ, Cheung CJ, Restrepo CR et al. Selective motor neuron resistance and recovery in a new inducible mouse model of TDP-43 proteinopathy. J Neurosci 2016; 36: 7707-7717.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du Beau A, Shakya Shrestha S, Bannatyne BA, Jalicy SM, Linnen S, Maxwell DJ. Neurotransmitter phenotypes of descending systems in the rat lumbar spinal cord. Neuroscience 2012; 227: 67-79.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paxinos G, Mai JK. The Human Nervous System, 2nd edn. San Diego: Academic Press, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nijssen J, Comley LH, Hedlund E. Motor neuron vulnerability and resistance in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathol 2017; 133: 863-885.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ragagnin AMG, Shadfar S, Vidal M, Jamali MS, Atkin JD. Motor neuron susceptibility in ALS/FTD. Front Neurosci 2019; 13: 532.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee S, Kim HJ. Prion-like mechanism in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Are protein aggregates the key? Exp Neurobiol 2015; 24: 1-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smethurst P, Newcombe J, Troakes C et al. In vitro prion-like behaviour of TDP-43 in ALS. Neurobiol Dis 2016; 96: 236-247.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furukawa Y, Kaneko K, Watanabe S, Yamanaka K, Nukina N. A seeding reaction recapitulates intracellular formation of Sarkosyl-insoluble transactivation response element (TAR) DNA-binding protein-43 inclusions. J Biol Chem 2011; 286: 18664-18672.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feiler MS, Strobel B, Freischmidt A et al. TDP-43 is intercellularly transmitted across axon terminals. J Cell Biol 2015; 211: 897-911.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nonaka T, Masuda-Suzukake M, Arai T et al. Prion-like properties of pathological TDP-43 aggregates from diseased brains. Cell Rep 2013; 4: 124-134.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gajdusek DC, Gibbs CJ. Attempts to demonstrate a transmissible agent in kuru, amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, and other sub-acute and chronic nervous system degenerations of man. Nature 1964; 204: 257-259.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uchida A, Sasaguri H, Kimura N et al. Non-human primate model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with cytoplasmic mislocalization of TDP-43. Brain 2012; 135: 833-846.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller A, Pratt H, Schiffer RB. Pseudobulbar affect: The spectrum of clinical presentations, etiologies and treatments. Expert Rev Neurother 2011; 11: 1077-1088.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eisen AA. Primary lateral sclerosis. In: Eisen AA, Shaw PJ, (eds). Handbook of Clinical Neurology, vol. 82, 3rd Series. Amsterdam: Elsevier, 2007; 315-325.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed Z, Bigio EH, Budka H et al. Globular glial tauopathies (GGT): Consensus recommendations. Acta Neuropathol 2013; 126: 537-544.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lashley T, Rohrer JD, Mead S, Revesz T. Review: An update on clinical, genetic and pathological aspects of frontotemporal lobardegenerations. Neuropathol Appl Neurobiol 2015; 41: 858-881.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kobayashi Z, Kawakami I, Arai T et al. Pathological features of FTLD-FUS in a Japanese population: Analyses of nine cases. J Neurol Sci 2013; 335: 89-95.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>