<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">31837153</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>10</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-4598</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>61</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Muscle &amp; nerve</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Muscle Nerve</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Single-pulse transcranial magnetic stimulation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>330</StartPage><EndPage>337</EndPage><MedlinePgn>330-337</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/mus.26780</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION">Transcranial magnetic stimulation (TMS) is one of the best methods to identify changes in the corticospinal tract. We used single-pulse TMS at the beginning of the disease and in the follow-up in a group of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">We evaluated the corticospinal tract in the bulbar, upper, and lower regions in 55 patients with ALS, and we monitored them for a period of 24&#x2009;months. Data were correlated with clinical scales.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">An increase of central motor conduction time (CMCT) was the most sensitive marker of upper motor neuron involvement. The resting motor threshold, CMCT, and the central silent period increased linearly with disease duration and upper/lower motor neuron involvement.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION">Transcranial magnetic stimulation could be an essential neurophysiological technique in the early phase of ALS because it has been shown to be useful in detecting subclinical upper motor neuron involvement. Multiple evaluations of several regions increase TMS sensitivity.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2019 Wiley Periodicals, Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Civardi</LastName><ForeName>Carlo</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9125-3198</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, ASLTO4, Ivrea, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Collini</LastName><ForeName>Alessandra</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, ASLTO4, Ivrea, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mazzini</LastName><ForeName>Letizia</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ALS Centre Department of Neurology Maggiore della Carit&#xe0; University Hospital, Novara, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Monaco</LastName><ForeName>Francesco</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology Maggiore della Carit&#xe0; University Hospital, Novara, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Geda</LastName><ForeName>Claudio</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, ASLTO4, Ivrea, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Muscle Nerve</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7803146</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0148-639X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="Y">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019054" MajorTopicYN="N">Evoked Potentials, Motor</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009046" MajorTopicYN="N">Motor Neurons</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009431" MajorTopicYN="N">Neural Conduction</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011712" MajorTopicYN="N">Pyramidal Tracts</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D050781" MajorTopicYN="Y">Transcranial Magnetic Stimulation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ALS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">TMS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">central silent period</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cortical excitability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">corticospinal tract</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31837153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.26780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, Miller RG, Swash M, Munsat TL. World Federation of Neurology Research Group on Motor Neuron Diseases. El Escorial revisited: revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord. 2000;1:293-299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Dengler R, Eisen A, et al. Electrodiagnostic criteria for the diagnosis of ALS. Clin Neurophysiol. 2008;119:497-503.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner MR, Benatar M. Ensuring continued progress in biomarkers for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 2015;51:14-18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Brien MD. Aid to the Examination of the Peripheral Nervous System. 4th ed. London, United Kingdom: WB Saunders; 2004:1-3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norris FH Jr, Calanchini PR, Fallat RJ, et al. The administration of guanidine in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology. 1974;24:721-728.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum JM, Stambler N, Malta E, et al. The ALSFRS-R: a revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. BDNF ALS Study Group (Phase III). J Neurol Sci. 1999;169:13-21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sonoo M, Kuwabara S, Shimizu T, et al. Utility of trapezius EMG for diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 2009;39:63-70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Swash M. Nerve conduction studies in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 2000;23:344-352.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossini PM, Burke D, Chen R, et al. Non-invasive electrical and magnetic stimulation of the brain, spinal cord, roots and peripheral nerves: basic principles and procedures for routine clinical research application. An updated report from an IFCN Committee. Clin Neurophysiol. 2015;126:1071-1107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mills KR, Nithi KA. Corticomotor threshold is reduced in early sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 1997;20:1137-1141.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Troni W, Bianco C, Coletti Moja M, Dotta M. Improved methodology for lumbosacral nerve root stimulation. Muscle Nerve. 1996;19:595-604.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Truffert A, Rosler KM, Magistris MR. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis versus cervical spondylotic myelopathy: a study using transcranial magnetic stimulation with recordings from the trapezius and limb muscles. Clin Neurophysiol. 2000;1031-1038.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cantello R, Gianelli M, Civardi C, Mutani R. Magnetic brain stimulation: the silent period after the motor evoked potential. Neurology. 1992;42:1951-1959.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ravits JM, La Spada AR. ALS motor phenotype heterogeneity, focality, and spread: deconstructing motor neuron degeneration. Neurology. 2009;73:805-811.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rothwell JC, Thompson PD, Day BL, Marsden CD. Motor cortex stimulation in intact man. 1. Brain. 1987;110:1173-1190.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mills KR. The natural history of central motor abnormalities in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain. 2003;126:2558-2566.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eisen A, Shytbel W, Murphy K, Hoirch M. Cortical magnetic stimulation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 1990;13:146-151.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Triggs WJ, Menkes D, Onorato J, et al. Transcranial magnetic stimulation identifies upper motor neuron involvement in motor neuron disease. Neurology. 1999;53:605-611.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salerno A, Georgesco M. Alterations of various parameters of evoked motor potentials in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurophysiol Clin. 1996;26:227-235.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desiato MT, Caramia MD. Towards a neurophysiological marker of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis as revealed by changes in cortical excitability. Electroencephalogr Clin Neurophysiol. 1997;105:1-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miscio G, Pisano F, Mora G, Mazzini L. Motor neuron disease: usefulness of transcranial magnetic stimulation in improving the diagnosis. Clin Neurophysiol. 1999;110:975-981.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Urban PP, Vogt T, Hopf HC. Corticobulbar tract involvement in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. A transcranial magnetic stimulation study. Brain. 1998;121:1099-1108.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Turkman A, Swash M. Motor responses evoked by transcranial magnetic stimulation and peripheral nerve stimulation in the ulnar innervation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: the effect of upper and lower motor neuron lesion. J Neurol Sci. 2003;210:83-90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Attarian S, Azulay JP, Lardillier D, et al. Transcranial magnetic stimulation in lower motor neuron diseases. Clin Neurophysiol. 2005;116:35-42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ziemann U, Winter M, Reimers CD, et al. Impaired motor cortex inhibition in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Evidence from paired transcranial magnetic stimulation. Neurology. 1997;49:1292-1298.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S, Kiernan MC. Cortical excitability testing distinguishes Kennedy's disease from amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Neurophysiol. 2008;46:1396-1404.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eisen A, Pant B, Stewart H. Cortical excitability in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a clue to pathogenesis. Can J Neurol Sci. 1993;20:11-16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mills KR, Nithi KA. Peripheral and central motor conduction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Sci. 1998;159:82-87.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S, Kiernan MC. Novel threshold tracking techniques suggest that cortical hyperexcitability is an early feature of motor neuron disease. Brain. 2006;129:2436-2446.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S, Cheah BC, Kiernan MC. Defining the mechanisms that underlie cortical hyperexcitability in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Exp Neurol. 2009;220:177-182.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dengler R, Konstanzer A, K&#xfc;ther G, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: macro-EMG and twitch forces of single motor units. Muscle Nerve. 1990;13:545-550.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davison C. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: origin and extent of the upper motor neuron lesion. Arch Neurol Psychiatry. 1941;46:1039-1056.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Floyd AG, Yu QP, Piboolnurak P, et al. Transcranial magnetic stimulation in ALS: utility of central motor conduction tests. Neurology. 2009;72:498-504.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Swash M. Sensitivity electrophysiological tests for upper and lower motor neuron dysfunction in ALS: a six-month longitudinal study. Muscle Nerve. 2010;41:208-211.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheah BC, Vucic S, Krishnan AV, et al. Neurophysiological index as a biomarker for ALS progression: validity of mixed effects models. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2011;12:33-38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weber M, Eisen A, Nakajima M. Corticomotoneuronal activity in ALS: changes in the peristimulus time histogram over time. Clin Neurophysiol. 2000;111:169-177.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ziemann U, Reis J, Schwenkreis P, et al. TMS and drugs revisited 2014. Clin Neurophysiol. 2015;126:1847-1868.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schelhaas HJ, Arts IM, Overeem S, et al. Measuring the cortical silent period can increase diagnostic confidence for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2007;8:16-19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foerster BR, Callaghan BC, Petrou M, et al. Decreased motor cortex &#x3b3;-aminobutyric acid in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology. 2012;78:1596-1600.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammadi B, Kollewe K, Samii A, et al. Functional neuroimaging at different disease stages reveals distinct phases of neuroplastic changes in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Hum Brain Mapp. 2011;32:750-758.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>