<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">31853962</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>30</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1469-493X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>12</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2019</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>19</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Cochrane database of systematic reviews</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cochrane Database Syst Rev</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Cell-based therapies for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis/motor neuron disease.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>CD011742</StartPage><MedlinePgn>CD011742</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">CD011742</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/14651858.CD011742.pub3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS), which is also known as motor neuron disease (MND), is a fatal disease associated with rapidly progressive disability, for which no definitive treatment exists. Current treatment approaches largely focus on relieving symptoms to improve the quality of life of those affected. The therapeutic potential of cell-based therapies in ALS/MND has not been fully evaluated, given the paucity of high-quality clinical trials. Based on data from preclinical studies, cell-based therapy is a promising treatment for ALS/MND. This review was first published in 2015 when the first clinical trials of cell-based therapies were still in progress. We undertook this update to incorporate evidence now available from randomised controlled trials (RCTs).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES">To assess the effects of cell-based therapy for people with ALS/MND, compared with placebo or no treatment.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SEARCH METHODS">On 31 July 2019, we searched the Cochrane Neuromuscular Specialised Register, CENTRAL, MEDLINE, and Embase. We also searched two clinical trials registries for ongoing or unpublished studies.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SELECTION CRITERIA">We included RCTs that assigned people with ALS/MND to receive cell-based therapy versus a placebo or no additional treatment. Co-interventions were allowed, provided that they were given to each group equally.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DATA COLLECTION AND ANALYSIS">We followed standard Cochrane methodology.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MAIN RESULTS">Two RCTs involving 112 participants were eligible for inclusion in this review. One study compared autologous bone marrow-mesenchymal stem cells (BM-MSC) plus riluzole versus control (riluzole only), while the other study compared combined intramuscular and intrathecal administration of autologous mesenchymal stem cells secreting neurotrophic factors (MSC-NTF) to placebo. The latter study was reported as an abstract and provided no numerical data. Both studies were funded by biotechnology companies. The only study that contributed to the outcome data in the review involved 64 participants, comparing BM-MSC plus riluzole versus control (riluzole only). It reported outcomes after four to six months. It had a low risk of selection bias, detection bias and reporting bias, but a high risk of performance bias and attrition bias. The certainty of evidence was low for all major efficacy outcomes, with imprecision as the main downgrading factor, because the range of plausible estimates, as shown by the 95% confidence intervals (CIs), encompassed a range that would likely result in different clinical decisions. Functional impairment, expressed as the mean change in the Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Functional Rating Scale-Revised (ALSFRS-R) score from baseline to six months after cell injection was slightly reduced (better) in the BM-MSC group compared to the control group (mean difference (MD) 3.38, 95% CI 1.22 to 5.54; 1 RCT, 56 participants; low-certainty evidence). ALSFRS-R has a range from 48 (normal) to 0 (maximally impaired); a change of 4 or more points is considered clinically important. The trial did not report outcomes at 12 months. There was no clear difference between the BM-MSC and the no treatment group in change in respiratory function (per cent predicted forced vital capacity; FVC%; MD -0.53, 95% CI -5.37 to 4.31; 1 RCT, 56 participants; low-certainty evidence); overall survival at six months (risk ratio (RR) 1.07, 95% CI 0.94 to 1.22; 1 RCT, 64 participants; low-certainty evidence); risk of total adverse events (RR 0.86, 95% CI 0.62 to 1.19; 1 RCT, 64 participants; low-certainty evidence) or serious adverse events (RR 0.47, 95% CI 0.13 to 1.72; 1 RCT, 64 participants; low-certainty evidence). The study did not measure muscle strength.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="AUTHORS' CONCLUSIONS">Currently, there is a lack of high-certainty evidence to guide practice on the use of cell-based therapy to treat ALS/MND. Uncertainties remain as to whether this mode of therapy is capable of restoring muscle function, slowing disease progression, and improving survival in people with ALS/MND. Although one RCT provided low-certainty evidence that BM-MSC may slightly reduce functional impairment measured on the ALSFRS-R after four to six months, this was a small phase II trial that cannot be used to establish efficacy. We need large, prospective RCTs with long-term follow-up to establish the efficacy and safety of cellular therapy and to determine patient-, disease- and cell treatment-related factors that may influence the outcome of cell-based therapy. The major goals of future research are to determine the appropriate cell source, phenotype, dose and method of delivery, as these will be key elements in designing an optimal cell-based therapy programme for people with ALS/MND. Future research should also explore novel treatment strategies, including combinations of cellular therapy and standard or novel neuroprotective agents, to find the best possible approach to prevent or reverse the neurological deficit in ALS/MND, and to prolong survival in this debilitating and fatal condition.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2019 The Cochrane Collaboration. Published by John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abdul Wahid</LastName><ForeName>S Fadilah</ForeName><Initials>SF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Universiti Kebangsaan Malaysia Medical Centre, Cell Therapy Center, Jalan Yaacob Latif, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia, 56000.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Law</LastName><ForeName>Zhe Kang</ForeName><Initials>ZK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Universiti Kebangsaan Malaysia Medical Centre, Department of Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ismail</LastName><ForeName>Nor Azimah</ForeName><Initials>NA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Universiti Kebangsaan Malaysia Medical Centre, Cell Therapy Center, Jalan Yaacob Latif, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia, 56000.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lai</LastName><ForeName>Nai Ming</ForeName><Initials>NM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Taylor's University, School of Medicine, Subang Jaya, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Cochrane Database Syst Rev</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100909747</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1361-6137</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="UpdateOf"><RefSource>Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2016 Nov 08;11:CD011742</RefSource><PMID Version="1">27822919</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D064987" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cell- and Tissue-Based Therapy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018450" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Progression</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016032" MajorTopicYN="N">Randomized Controlled Trials as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014797" MajorTopicYN="N">Vital Capacity</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>SFAW is a consultant haematologist and professor of internal medicine and performed haematopoietic stem cell transplantation for people with blood and bone marrow diseases. She has been actively involved in many clinical trials utilising cell and cell&#x2010;based products for blood cancers and various degenerative conditions. No known conflicts of interest. ZKL is a neurologist and manages patients with a range of neurological diseases including ALS/MND. No known conflicts of interest. NAI is a research officer and a clinical study co&#x2010;ordinator involved in production of clinical grade cell and cell&#x2010;based products and managing clinical trials. No known conflict of interest. NML is a Paediatrician and Neonatologist by training, and a Cochrane Trainer. He has no known conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31853962</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6920743</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD011742.pub3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References to studies included in this review</Title><ReferenceList><Title>Gothelf 2017 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Aricha R, Cudkowicz M, Berry J, Windebank A, Staff N, Owegi M, et al. In vivo modulation of neurotrophic and inflammatory factors in the CSF of ALS patients treated with NurOwn (MSC NTF cells).. Cytotherapy 2017;19(5 Suppl 1):S199. [DOI: 10.1016/j.jcyt.2017.02.297; EMBASE: 621642066]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcyt.2017.02.297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aricha R, Kaspi H, Cudkowicz M, Berry J, Windebank A, Staff N, et al. Modulation of CSF mirnas in ALS phase 2 study participants treated with MSC&#x2010;NTF cells (NurOwn). Neurology 2018;90(15 Suppl):S25.005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gothelf Y, Cudkowicz M, Berry J, Windebank A, Staff N, Owegi M, et al. Safety and efficacy of transplantation of NurOwn (autologous mesenchymal stromal cells secreting neurotrophic factors) in patients with ALS: a phase 2 randomized double blind placebo controlled trial. Cryotherapy 2017;19(5 Suppl 1):S23. [EMBASE: 621642188]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kern R, Cudkowicz M, Berry J, Windebank A, Staff N, Owegi M, et al. NurOwn phase 2 ALS trial: ALSFRS&#x2010;R improvement is reflected in subscale domains. Neurology 2018;90(15 Suppl):Abstract No:S38.002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NCT02017912. A phase 2, randomised, double blind, placebo controlled multicenter study to evaluate safety and efficacy of transplantation of autologous mesenchymal stem cells secreting neurotrophic factors (MSC&#x2010;NTF) in patients with ALS. clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/study/NCT02017912 (first received 23 December 2013).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Oh 2018 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Kim SH. Phase I/II trials of autologous BM derived stem cell therapy in ALS. Clinical Neurology 2016;56:S228. [EMBASE: 615586834]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim SH, Oh K&#x2010;W, Kwon M&#x2010;S, Moon CM, Noh M&#x2010;Y, Kim HY, et al. A phase 2 study for safety and efficacy evaluation of treatment of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis using autologous bone&#x2010;marrow&#x2010;derived stromal cell. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis and Frontotemporal Degeneration 2015;16(Suppl 1):53. [EMBASE: 72104358]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NCT01363401. Safety and efficacy study of autologous bone marrow derived stem cell treatment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis [An open&#x2010;label, phase I/II trial for safety and efficacy study of autologous bone marrow derived stem cell treatment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis]. clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT01363401 (first received 1 June 2011). [CTG: NCT01363401]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh KW, Noh MY, Kwon MS, Kim HY, Oh SI, Park J, et al. Repeated intrathecal mesenchymal stem cells for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Annals of Neurology 2018;84(3):361&#x2010;73. [PUBMED: 30048006]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6175096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30048006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>References to studies excluded from this review</Title><ReferenceList><Title>Gabr 2017 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Gabr H, Kishk N, Belal E, Aboelfotooh A, M E. Intrathecal autologous bone marrow derived mesenchymal stem cell therapy for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Cytotherapy 2017;19(5 Suppl 1):S199&#x2010;200.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Karussis 2013 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Karussis D, Petrou P, Offen D, Gothelf Y, Levy Y, Argov Z, et al. Treatment of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) with autologous differentiated mesenchymal stem cells: preliminary results of a phase I/II clinical trial in 12 patients. Journal of Neurology 2013;260(Suppl 1):S22&#x2010;3. [DOI: 10.1007/s00415-013-6924-0]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00415-013-6924-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karussis D, Petrou P, Offen D, Gotkine M, Argov Z, Vaknin&#x2010;Dembinsky A, et al. Interim analysis of 12 patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) treated with autologous differentiated mesenchymal stem cells: preliminary data of a Phase I/II clinical trial. Neurology 2013;80(19):e202&#x2010;3. [DOI: 10.1212/WNL.0b013e3182924c84]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0b013e3182924c84</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrou P, Gothelf Y, Argov Z, Gotkine M, Levy YS, Kassis I, et al. Safety and clinical effects of mesenchymal stem cells secreting neurotrophic factor transplantation in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: results of phase 1/2 and 2a clinical trials. JAMA Neurology 2016;73(3):337&#x2010;44. [DOI: 10.1001/jamaneurol.2015.4321; PUBMED: 26751635]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamaneurol.2015.4321</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26751635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Mazzini 2015 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Mazzini L, Gelati M, Profico DC, Sgaravizzi G, Projetti Pensi M, Muzi G, et al. Human neural stem cell transplantation in ALS: initial results from a phase I trial. Journal of Translational Medicine 2015;13:17. [DOI: 10.1186/s12967-014-0371-2; PUBMED: 25889343]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12967-014-0371-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4359401</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25889343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazzini L, Gelati M, Soraru G, Profico D, Muzi G, Ricciolini C, et al. Data from a completed phase I clinical trial with intraspinal injection of neural stem cells in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis and Frontotemporal Degeneration 2016;17(Suppl 1):243.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Nabavi 2019 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Nabavi SM, Arab L, Jarooghi N, Bolurieh T, Abbasi F, Mardpour S, et al. Safety, feasibility of intravenous and intrathecal injection of autologous bone marrow derived mesenchymal stromal cells in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: an open label phase I clinical trial. Cell Journal 2019;20(4):592&#x2010;8. [PUBMED: 30124008]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6099146</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30124008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Petrou 2015 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Gothelf Y, Petrou P, Gotkine M, Vaknin&#x2010;Dembinsky A, Levy Y, Offen D, et al. Update on clinical trials with autologous bone marrow&#x2010;derived mesenchymal stem cells secreting neurotrophic factors (MSC&#x2010;NTF) in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). Cytotherapy 2015;17(6 Suppl):S38&#x2010;9. [DOI: 10.1016/j.jcyt.2015.03.434]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcyt.2015.03.434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karussis D, Petrou P, Offen D, Argov Z, Gotkine M, Levi Y, et al. Analysis of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) treated with autologous differentiated mesenchymal stem cells: a phase I/II and IIA clinical trial. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis and Frontotemporal Degeneration 2013;14(Suppl 2):48. [DOI: 10.3109/21678421.2013.838413/078]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/21678421.2013.838413/078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karussis D, Petrou P, Offen D, Argov Z, Goudkin M, Levi Y, et al. Analysis of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) treated with autologous differentiated mesenchymal stem cells: A phase I/II and IIa clinical trial. Journal of Neurology 2014;261(Suppl 1):S47&#x2010;8. [DOI: 10.1007/s00415-013-6924-0]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00415-013-6924-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrou P, Gothelf Y, Argov Z, Gotkine M, Levy YS, Kassis I, et al. Safety and clinical effects of mesenchymal stem cells secreting neurotrophic factor transplantation in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: results of phase 1/2 and 2a clinical trials. JAMA Neurology 2016;73(3):337&#x2010;44. [DOI: 10.1001/jamaneurol.2015.4321; PUBMED: 26751635]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamaneurol.2015.4321</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26751635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrou P, Gotkine M, Gothelf Y, Levy Y, Offen D, Vaknin&#x2010;Dembinsky A, et al. Autologous transplantation of mesenchymal stem cells secreting neurotrophic factors (NurownTM) in ALS: results of a phase 2 clinical trial. Neurology 2015;84(14 Suppl):P2.059.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>References to ongoing studies</Title><ReferenceList><Title>NCT01254539 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Henriquez K, Mingo Casado P, Saez V, Izura V. Cellular therapy in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Preliminary results of a phase I/II clinical trial. Clinical Neurophysiology 2014;125(Suppl 1):S194&#x2010;5. [EMBASE: 71541589]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iniesta F, Gomez&#x2010;Espuch J, Blanquer M, Perez&#x2010;Espejo MA, Garcia&#x2010;Santos JM, Ruiz&#x2010;Lopez FJ, et al. Bone marrow mononuclear cell therapy for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Preliminary results of a randomised, double&#x2010;blind, stratified controlled, parallel group phase I&#x2010;II clinical trial. Human Gene Therapy 2013;24(12):A49. [DOI: 10.1089/hum.2013.2513]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/hum.2013.2513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>NCT01254539. Phase I/II clinical trial on the use of autologous bone marrow stem cells in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (Extension CMN/ELA). clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT01254539 (accessed September 2015).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>NCT02286011 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Cano R, Martin C, Pastore C, Blanquer M, Iniesta P, Gomez&#x2010;Espuch J, et al. Phase I/II clinical trial of intramuscular implantation of autologous bone marrow stem cells in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. Basic &amp; Clinical Pharmacology &amp; Toxicology 2012;111(Supp s1):40: Abstract no: P102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>EUCTR2011&#x2010;004801&#x2010;25&#x2010;ES. A phase I/II clinical trial of the bone marrow's autologous stem cells in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. www.clinicaltrialsregister.eu/ctr&#x2010;search/trial/2011&#x2010;004801&#x2010;25/ES (accessed September 2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NCT02286011. Intramuscular infusion of autologous bone marrow stem cells in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (TCIM/ELA) [Phase I clinical trial on intramuscular infusion of autologous bone marrow stem cells in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.]. clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT02286011 (first received 7 November 2014).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>NCT02290886 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>NCT02290886. A multicenter phase I/II clinical trial to evaluate safety of mesenchymal stem cell in patients with amyotrophic sclerosis lateral [Clinical trial phase I/II, randomised, controlled with placebo, triple blind to evaluate safety, and indications of efficiency of the intravenous administration of the therapy with 3 doses of MSC in patients with ALS moderated to severe]. clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/study/NCT02290886 (first received 14 November 2014).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>NCT03280056 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>NCT03280056. Safety and efficacy of repeated administrations of NurOwn&#xae; in ALS patients [A phase 3, randomized double&#x2010;blind, placebo&#x2010;controlled multicenter study to evaluate efficacy and safety of repeated administration of NurOwn&#xae; (autologous mesenchymal stem cells secreting neurotrophic factors) in participants with ALS]. clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/study/NCT03280056 (first received 12 September 2017). [BCT&#x2010;002&#x2010;US]</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Additional references</Title><ReferenceList><Title>Abdul 2018</Title><Reference><Citation>Abdul Wahid SF, Ismail NA, Wan Jamaludin WF, Muhamad NA, Abdul Hamid MKA, Harunarashid H, et al. Autologous cells derived from different sources and administered using different regimens for 'no&#x2010;option' critical lower limb ischaemia patients. Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews 2018, Issue 8. [DOI: 10.1002/14651858.CD010747.pub2; PUBMED: 30155883]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD010747.pub2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6513643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30155883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Abe 2014</Title><Reference><Citation>Abe K, Itoyama Y, Sobue G, Tsuji S, Aoki M, Doyu M, et al. Edaravone ALS Study Group. Confirmatory double&#x2010;blind, parallel&#x2010;group, placebo&#x2010;controlled study of efficacy and safety of edaravone (MCI&#x2010;186) in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis and Frontotemporal Degeneration 2014;15(7&#x2010;8):610&#x2010;7. [DOI: 10.3109/21678421.2014.959024]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/21678421.2014.959024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4266079</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25286015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Baek 2012</Title><Reference><Citation>Baek W, Kim YS, Koh SH, Lim SW, Kim HY, Yi HJ, et al. Stem cell transplantation into the intraventricular space via an Ommaya reservoir in a patient with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Journal of Neurosurgical Sciences 2012;56(3):261&#x2010;3. [; PUBMED: 22854595]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22854595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Bensimon 1994</Title><Reference><Citation>Bensimon G, Lacomblez L, Meininger V. A controlled trial of riluzole in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. ALS/Riluzole Study Group. New England Journal of Medicine 1994;330(9):585&#x2010;91. [PUBMED: 8302340]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8302340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Bernardo 2007</Title><Reference><Citation>Bernardo ME, Zaffaroni N, Novara F, Cometa AM, Avanzini MA, Moretta A, et al. Human bone marrow derived mesenchymal stem cells do not undergo transformation after long&#x2010;term in vitro culture and do not exhibit telomere maintenance mechanisms. Cancer Research 2007;67(19):9142&#x2010;9. [PUBMED: 17909019]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17909019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Black 2001</Title><Reference><Citation>Black IB, Woodbury D. Adult rat and human bone marrow stromal stem cells differentiate into neurons. Blood Cells, Molecules &amp; Diseases 2001;27(3):632&#x2010;6. [PUBMED: 11482877]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11482877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Blanquer 2012</Title><Reference><Citation>Blanquer M, Moraleda JM, Iniesta F, Gomez&#x2010;Espuch J, Meca&#x2010;Lallana J, Villaverde R, et al. Neurotrophic bone marrow cellular nests prevent spinal motoneuron degeneration in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients: a pilot safety study. Stem Cells 2012;30(6):1277&#x2010;85. [DOI: 10.1002/stem.1080; PUBMED: 22415951]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/stem.1080</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22415951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Bourke 2006</Title><Reference><Citation>Bourke SC, Tomlinson M, Williams TL, Bullock RE, Shaw PJ, Gibson GJ. Effects of non&#x2010;invasive ventilation on survival and quality of life in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a randomised controlled trial. Lancet Neurology 2006;5(2):140&#x2010;7. [DOI: 10.1016/S1474-4422(05)70326-4; PUBMED: 16426990 ]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1474-4422(05)70326-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16426990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Brooks 2000</Title><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, Miller RG, Swash M, Munsat TL, World Federation of Neurology Research Group on Motor Neuron Diseases. El Escorial revisited: revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis and Other Motor Neuron Disorders 2000;1(5):293&#x2010;9. [PUBMED: 11464847]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11464847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Campbell 2001</Title><Reference><Citation>Campbell MK, Mollison J, Grimshaw JM. Cluster trials in implementation research: estimation of intracluster correlation coefficients and sample size. Statistics in Medicine 2001;20(3):391&#x2010;9. [PUBMED: 11180309]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11180309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Caroscio 1987</Title><Reference><Citation>Caroscio JT, Mulvihill MN, Sterling R, Abrams B. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Its natural history. Neurologic Clinics 1987;5(1):1&#x2010;8. [PUBMED: 3561382]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3561382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Cashman 2008</Title><Reference><Citation>Cashman N, Tan LY, Krieger C, Madler B, Mackay A, Mackenzie I, et al. Pilot study of granulocyte colony stimulating factor (G&#x2010;CSF)&#x2010;mobilized peripheral blood stem cells in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). Muscle &amp; Nerve 2008;37(5):620&#x2010;5. [; DOI: 10.1002/mus.20951; PUBMED: 18335482]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.20951</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18335482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Castrillo&#x2010;Viguera 2010</Title><Reference><Citation>Castrillo&#x2010;Viguera C, Grasso DL, Simpson E, Shefner J, Cudkowicz ME. Clinical significance in the change of decline in ALSFRS&#x2010;R. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis 2010;11(1&#x2010;2):178&#x2010;80. [PUBMED: 19634063]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19634063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Cedarbaum 1999</Title><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum JM, Stambler N, Malta E, Fuller C, Hilt D, Thurmond B, et al. The ALSFRS&#x2010;R: a revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. BDNF ALS Study Group (Phase III). Journal of the Neurological Sciences 1999;169(1&#x2010;2):13&#x2010;21. [PUBMED: 10540002]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10540002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Chen 1996</Title><Reference><Citation>Chen R, Grand'Maison F, Strong MJ, Ramsay DA, Bolton CF. Motor neuron disease presenting as acute respiratory failure: a clinical and pathological study. Journal of Neurology, Neurosurgery, and Psychiatry 1996;60(4):455&#x2010;8. [PUBMED: 8774419]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1073907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8774419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Chen 2007</Title><Reference><Citation>Chen L, Huang H, Zhang J, Zhang F, Liu Y, Xi H, et al. Short&#x2010;term outcome of olfactory ensheathing cells transplantation for treatment of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Zhongguo Xiu Fu Chong Jian Wai Ke za Zhi [Chinese Journal of Reparative and Reconstructive Surgery] 2007;21(9):961&#x2010;6. [PUBMED: 17933231]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17933231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Chen 2008</Title><Reference><Citation>Chen Y, Shao JZ, Xiang LX, Dong XJ, Zhang GR. Mesenchymal stem cells: a promising candidate in regenerative medicine. International Journal of Biochemistry and Molecular Biology 2008;40(5):815&#x2010;20. [DOI: 10.1016/j.biocel.2008.01.007; PUBMED: 18295530]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biocel.2008.01.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18295530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Chew 2007</Title><Reference><Citation>Chew S, Khandji AG, Montes J, Mitsumoto H, Gordon PH. Olfactory ensheathing glia injections in Beijing: misleading patients with ALS. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis 2007;8(5):314&#x2010;6. [PUBMED: 17917850]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17917850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Chio 2011</Title><Reference><Citation>Chio A, Mora G, Bella V, Caponnetto C, Mancardi G, Sabatelli M, et al. Repeated courses of granulocyte colony&#x2010;stimulating factor in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: clinical and biological results from a prospective multicenter study. Muscle &amp; Nerve 2011;43(2):189&#x2010;95. [; DOI: 10.3109/14653240903300682; PUBMED: 21254083]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/14653240903300682</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21254083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Cruz 2018</Title><Reference><Citation>Cruz MP. Edaravone (Radicava): a novel neuroprotective agent for the treatment of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. P &amp; T : a Peer&#x2010;reviewed Journal for Formulary Management 2018;43(1):25&#x2010;8. [PUBMED: 29290672]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5737249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29290672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Deda 2009</Title><Reference><Citation>Deda H, Inci MC, Kurekci AE, Sav A, Kayihan K, Ozgun E, et al. Treatment of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients by autologous bone marrow&#x2010;derived hematopoietic stem cell transplantation: a 1&#x2010;year follow&#x2010;up. Cytotherapy 2009;11(1):18&#x2010;25. [; PUBMED: 19012065]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19012065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Deeks 2011</Title><Reference><Citation>Deeks JJ, Higgins JP, Altman DG, on behalf of the Cochrane Statistical Methods Group. Chapter 10: Analysing data and undertaking meta&#x2010;analyses. In: Higgins JP, Green S, editor(s). Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions Version 5.1.0 (updated March 2011). The Cochrane Collaboration, 2011. Available from handbook.cochrane.org.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>del Aguila 2003</Title><Reference><Citation>Aguila MA, Longstreth WT Jr, McGuire V, Koepsell TD, Belle G. Prognosis in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a population&#x2010;based study. Neurology 2003;60(5):813&#x2010;9. [PUBMED: 12629239]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12629239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Deng 2011</Title><Reference><Citation>Deng HX, Chen W, Hong ST, Boycott KM, Gorrie GH, Siddique N, et al. Mutations in UBQLN2 cause dominant X&#x2010;linked juvenile and adult&#x2010;onset ALS and ALS/dementia. Nature 2011;477(7363):211&#x2010;5. [DOI: 10.1038/nature10353]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nature10353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3169705</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21857683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Escorcio&#x2010;Bezerra 2016</Title><Reference><Citation>Escorcio&#x2010;Bezerra ML, Abrahao A, Castro I, Chieia MA, Azevedo LA, Pinheiro DS, et al. MUNIX: reproducibility and clinical correlations in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clinical Neurophysiology 2016;127(9):2979&#x2010;84. [DOI: 10.1016/j.clinph.2016.06.011; PUBMED: 27458836]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clinph.2016.06.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27458836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Feldman 2014</Title><Reference><Citation>Feldman EL, Boulis NM, Hur J, Johe K, Rutkove SB, Federici T, et al. Intraspinal neural stem cell transplantation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: phase 1 trial outcomes. Annals of Neurology 2014;75(3):363&#x2010;73. [PUBMED: 24510776]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4005820</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24510776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Gawel 2016</Title><Reference><Citation>Gawel M, Zalewska E, Lipowska M, Kostera&#x2010;Pruszczyk A, Szmidt&#x2010;Salkowska E, Kaminska A. Motor unit number estimation as a complementary test to routine electromyography in the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Journal of Electromyography and Kinesiology 2016;26:60&#x2010;5. [DOI: 10.1016/j.jelekin.2015.11.001]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jelekin.2015.11.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26614440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Giordana 2010</Title><Reference><Citation>Giordana MT, Grifoni S, Votta B, Magistrello M, Vercellino M, Pellerino A, et al. Neuropathology of olfactory ensheathing cell transplantation into the brain of two amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) patients. Brain Pathology (Zurich, Switzerland) 2010;20(4):730&#x2010;7. [DOI: 10.1111/j.1750-3639.2009.00353.x; PUBMED: 19919605]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1750-3639.2009.00353.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8094845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19919605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Goodall 2006</Title><Reference><Citation>Goodall EF, Morrison KE. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (motor neuron disease): proposed mechanisms and pathways to treatment. Expert Reviews in Molecular Medicine 2006;8(11):1&#x2010;22. [PUBMED: 16723044]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16723044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Goutman 2015</Title><Reference><Citation>Goutman SA, Chen KS, Feldman EL. Recent advances and the future of stem cell therapies in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurotherapeutics 2015;12(2):428&#x2010;48. [DOI: 10.1007/s13311-015-0339-9; PUBMED: 25776222]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13311-015-0339-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4404436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25776222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Gowing 2011</Title><Reference><Citation>Gowing G, Svendsen CN. Stem cell transplantation for motor neuron disease: current approaches and future perspectives. Neurotherapeutics 2011;8(4):591&#x2010;606. [DOI: 10.1007/s13311-011-0068-7; PUBMED: 21904789]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13311-011-0068-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3210365</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21904789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>GRADEpro 2018 [Computer program]</Title><Reference><Citation>GRADE Working Group, McMaster University. GRADEpro GDT. Version 3.6. Hamilton (ON): GRADE Working Group, McMaster University, 2018.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Hardingham 2010</Title><Reference><Citation>Hardingham GE, Patani R, Baxter P, Wyllie DJ, Chandran S. Human embryonic stem cell&#x2010;derived neurons as a tool for studying neuroprotection and neurodegeneration. Molecular Neurobiology 2010;42(1):97&#x2010;102. [DOI: 10.1007/s12035-010-8136-2; PUBMED: 20431962]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12035-010-8136-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2948543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20431962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Higgins 2011a</Title><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Altman DG, Sterne JA. Chapter 8: Assessing risk of bias in included studies. In: Higgins JP, Green S, editor(s). Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions Version 5.1.0 (updated March 2011). The Cochrane Collaboration, 2011. Available from handbook.cochrane.org.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Higgins 2011b</Title><Reference><Citation>McKenzie JE, Brennan SE. Chapter 12: Synthesizing and presenting findings using other methods. In: Higgins JP, Green S, editor(s). Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions Version 5.1.0 (updated March 2011). The Cochrane Collaboration, 2011. Available from handbook.cochrane.org.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Huang 2008</Title><Reference><Citation>Huang H, Chen L, Xi H, Wang H, Zhang J, Zhang F, et al. Fetal olfactory ensheathing cells transplantation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients: a controlled pilot study. Clinical Transplantation 2008;22(6):710&#x2010;8. [PUBMED: 18673377]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18673377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Jenkinson 2000</Title><Reference><Citation>Jenkinson C, Levvy G, Fitzpatrick R, Garratt A. The amyotrophic lateral sclerosis assessment questionnaire (ALSAQ&#x2010;40): tests of data quality, score reliability and response rate in a survey of patients. Journal of the Neurological Sciences 2000;180(1&#x2010;2):94&#x2010;100. [PUBMED: 11090872]]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11090872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Jenkinson 2007</Title><Reference><Citation>Jenkinson C, Fitzpatrick R, Swash M, Jones G. Comparison of the 40&#x2010;item Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Assessment Questionnaire (ALSAQ&#x2010;40) with a short&#x2010;form five&#x2010;item version (ALSAQ&#x2010;5) in a longitudinal survey. Clinical Rehabilitation 2007;21(3):266&#x2010;72. [DOI: 10.1177/0269215506071123; PUBMED: 17329284]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0269215506071123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17329284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Jeong 2015</Title><Reference><Citation>Jeong H, Yim HW, Cho Y, Kim HB, Oh IH, Jeong S. Systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis of efficacy and safety of stem cell therapy in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Cytotherapy 2015;17(6 Suppl):S66. [DOI: 10.1016/j.jcyt.2015.03.530]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcyt.2015.03.530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Jiang 2002</Title><Reference><Citation>Jiang Y, Jahagirdar BN, Reinhardt RL, Schwartz RE, Keene CD, Ortiz&#x2010;Gonzalez XR, et al. Pluripotency of mesenchymal stem cells derived from adult marrow. Nature 2002;418(6893):41&#x2010;9. [PUBMED: 12077603]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12077603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Karussis 2010</Title><Reference><Citation>Karussis D, Karageorgiou C, Vaknin&#x2010;Dembinsky A, Gowda&#x2010;Kurkalli B, Gomori JM, Kassis I, et al. Safety and immunological effects of mesenchymal stem cell transplantation in patients with multiple sclerosis and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Archives of Neurology 2010;67(10):1187&#x2010;94. [DOI: 10.1001/archneurol.2010.248; PUBMED: 20937945]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archneurol.2010.248</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3036569</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20937945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Kim 2002</Title><Reference><Citation>Kim BJ, Seo JH, Bubien JK, Oh YS. Differentiation of adult bone marrow stem cells into neuroprogenitor cells in vitro. Neuroreport 2002;13(9):1185&#x2010;8. [PUBMED: 12151766]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12151766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Liu 2000</Title><Reference><Citation>Liu S, Qu Y, Stewart TJ, Howard MJ, Chakrabortty S, Holekamp TF, et al. Embryonic stem cells differentiate into oligodendrocytes and myelinate in culture and after spinal cord transplantation. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America 2000;97(11):6126&#x2010;31. [PUBMED: 10823956]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC18569</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10823956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Logroscino 2005</Title><Reference><Citation>Logroscino G, Beghi E, Zoccolella S, Palagano R, Fraddosio A, Simone I, et al. Incidence of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in southern Italy: a population based study. Journal of Neurology, Neurosurgery, and Psychiatry 2005;76(8):1094&#x2010;8. [PUBMED: 16024886]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1739746</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16024886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Logroscino 2008</Title><Reference><Citation>Logroscino G, Traynor BJ, Hardiman O, Chio A, Couratier P, Mitchell JD, et al. Descriptive epidemiology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: new evidence and unsolved issues. Journal of Neurology, Neurosurgery, and Psychiatry 2008;79(1):6&#x2010;11. [PUBMED: 18079297]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18079297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Lunn 2014</Title><Reference><Citation>Lunn JS, Sakowski SA, Feldman EL. Concise review: stem cell therapies for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: recent advances and prospects for the future. Stem Cells (Dayton, Ohio) 2014;32(5):1099&#x2010;109. [DOI: 10.1002/stem.1628; PUBMED: 24448926]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/stem.1628</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4225704</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24448926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Martinez 2009</Title><Reference><Citation>Martinez HR, Gonzalez&#x2010;Garza MT, Moreno&#x2010;Cuevas JE, Caro E, Gutierrez&#x2010;Jimenez E, Segura JJ. Stem&#x2010;cell transplantation into the frontal motor cortex in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. Cytotherapy 2009;11(1):26&#x2010;34. [; DOI: 10.1080/14653240802644651; PUBMED: 19191058]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14653240802644651</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19191058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Martinez 2012</Title><Reference><Citation>Martinez HR, Molina&#x2010;Lopez JF, Gonzalez&#x2010;Garza MT, Moreno&#x2010;Cuevas JE, Caro&#x2010;Osorio E, Gil&#x2010;Valadez A, et al. Stem cell transplantation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients: methodological approach, safety, and feasibility. Cell Transplantation 2012;21(9):1899&#x2010;907. [; PUBMED: 23356668]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23356668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Mazzini 2003</Title><Reference><Citation>Mazzini L, Fagioli F, Boccaletti R, Mareschi K, Oliveri G, Olivieri C, et al. Stem cell therapy in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a methodological approach in humans. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis and Other Motor Neuron Disorders 2003;4(3):158&#x2010;61. [; PUBMED: 13129802]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13129802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Mazzini 2006</Title><Reference><Citation>Mazzini L, Mareschi K, Ferrero I, Vassallo E, Oliveri G, Boccaletti R, et al. Autologous mesenchymal stem cells: clinical applications in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurological Research 2006;28(5):523&#x2010;6. [PUBMED: 16808883]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16808883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Mazzini 2012</Title><Reference><Citation>Mazzini L, Mareschi K, Ferrero I, Miglioretti M, Stecco A, Servo S, et al. Mesenchymal stromal cell transplantation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a long&#x2010;term safety study. Cytotherapy 2012;14(1):56&#x2010;60. [DOI: 10.3109/14653249.2011.613929; PUBMED: 21954839]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/14653249.2011.613929</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21954839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>McDonald 1999</Title><Reference><Citation>McDonald JW, Liu XZ, Qu Y, Liu S, Mickey SK, Turetsky D, et al. Transplanted embryonic stem cells survive, differentiate and promote recovery in injured rat spinal cord. Nature Medicine 1999;5(12):1410&#x2010;2. [PUBMED: 10581084]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10581084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Miller 2012</Title><Reference><Citation>Miller RG, Mitchell JD, Moore DH. Riluzole for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS)/motor neuron disease (MND). Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews 2012, Issue 3. [DOI: 10.1002/14651858.CD001447.pub3]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD001447.pub3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Moher 2009</Title><Reference><Citation>Moher D, Liberati A, Tetzlaff J, Altman DG, The PRISMA Group. Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic Reviews and Meta&#x2010;Analyses: the PRISMA statement. PLoS Medicine 2009;6(7):e1000097. [DOI: 10.1371/journal.pmed1000097]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pmed1000097</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2707599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19621072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Moura 2016</Title><Reference><Citation>Moura MC, Novaes MR, Zago YS, Eduardo EJ, Casulari LA. Efficacy of stem cell therapy in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Journal of Clinical Medicine Research 2016;8(4):317&#x2010;24. [PUBMED: 26985252]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4780495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26985252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Murray 2004</Title><Reference><Citation>Murray B, Mitsumoto H. Disorders of upper and lower motor neurons. In: Bradley WG, Daroff RB, Fenichel GM, Jankovic J editor(s). Neurology in Clinical Practice. 4th Edition. Vol. 1, Philadelphia (PA): Butterworth&#x2010;Heinemann, 2004:2223&#x2010;65.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Nefussy 2010</Title><Reference><Citation>Nefussy B, Artamonov I, Deutsch V, Naparstek E, Nagler A, Drory VE. Recombinant human granulocyte&#x2010;colony stimulating factor administration for treating amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a pilot study. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis 2010;11(1&#x2010;2):187&#x2010;93. [; DOI: 10.3109/17482960902933809; PUBMED: 19449238]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/17482960902933809</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19449238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Oakes 2017</Title><Reference><Citation>Oakes JA, Davies MC, Collins MO. TBK1: a new player in ALS linking autophagy and neuroinflammation. Molecular Brain 2017;10(1):5. [DOI: 10.1186/s13041-017-0287-x]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13041-017-0287-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5288885</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28148298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Oh 2015</Title><Reference><Citation>Oh KW, Moon C, Kim HY, Oh SI, Park J, Lee JH, et al. Phase I trial of repeated intrathecal autologous bone marrow&#x2010;derived mesenchymal stromal cells in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Stem Cells Translational Medicine 2015;4(6):590&#x2010;7. [; DOI: 10.5966/sctm.2014-0212; PUBMED: 25934946]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5966/sctm.2014-0212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4449093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25934946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Piepers 2010</Title><Reference><Citation>Piepers S, Berg LH. No benefits from experimental treatment with olfactory ensheathing cells in patients with ALS. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis 2010;11(3):328&#x2010;30. [DOI: 10.3109/17482961003663555; PUBMED: 20433414]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/17482961003663555</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20433414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Prabhakar 2012</Title><Reference><Citation>Prabhakar S, Marwaha N, Lal V, Sharma RR, Rajan R, Khandelwal N. Autologous bone marrow&#x2010;derived stem cells in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a pilot study. Neurology India 2012;60(5):465&#x2010;9. [; PUBMED: 23135021]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23135021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Rabin 1999</Title><Reference><Citation>Rabin BA, Borchelt DR. Motor neuron disease. In: Koliatsos VE, Ratan RR editor(s). Cell Death and Diseases of the Nervous System. New York (NY): Springer Science + Business Media, 1999:429&#x2010;43.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Rabin 2001</Title><Reference><Citation>Rabin R, Charro F. EQ&#x2010;5D: a measure of health status from the EuroQol Group. Annals of Medicine 2001;33(5):337&#x2010;43. [PUBMED: 11491192]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11491192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Radunovic 2013</Title><Reference><Citation>Radunovic A, Annane D, Rafiq MK, Mustfa N. Mechanical ventilation for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis/motor neuron disease. Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews 2013, Issue 3. [DOI: 10.1002/14651858.CD004427.pub3; PUBMED: 23543531]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD004427.pub3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23543531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Renton 2014</Title><Reference><Citation>Renton AE, Chi&#xf2; A, Traynor BJ. State of play in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis genetics. Nature Neuroscience 2014;17(1):17&#x2010;23. [DOI: 10.1038/nn.3584; PUBMED: 24369373]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nn.3584</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4544832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24369373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Review Manager 2014 [Computer program]</Title><Reference><Citation>Nordic Cochrane Centre, The Cochrane Collaboration. Review Manager 5 (RevMan 5). Version 5.3. Copenhagen: Nordic Cochrane Centre, The Cochrane Collaboration, 2014.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Sanchez&#x2010;Ramos 2000</Title><Reference><Citation>Sanchez&#x2010;Ramos J, Song S, Cardozo&#x2010;Pelaez F, Hazzi C, Stedeford T, Willing A, et al. Adult bone marrow stromal cells differentiate into neural cells in vitro. Experimental Neurology 2000;164(2):247&#x2010;56. [PUBMED: 10915564]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10915564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Sharma 2015</Title><Reference><Citation>Sharma AK, Sane HM, Paranjape AA, Gokulchandran N, Nagrajan A, D'sa M, et al. The effect of autologous bone marrow mononuclear cell transplantation on the survival duration in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis &#x2013; a retrospective controlled study. American Journal of Stem Cells 2015;4(1):50&#x2010;65. [PUBMED: 25973331]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4396155</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25973331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Shaw 2005</Title><Reference><Citation>Shaw PJ. Molecular and cellular pathways of neurodegeneration in motor neurone disease. Journal of Neurology, Neurosurgery, and Psychiatry 2005;76(8):1046&#x2010;57. [PUBMED: 16024877]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1739758</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16024877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Stein 2016</Title><Reference><Citation>Stein F, Kobor I, Bogdahn U, Schulte&#x2010;Mattler WJ. Toward the validation of a new method (MUNIX) for motor unit number assessment. Journal of Electromyography and Kinesiology 2016;27:73&#x2010;7. [DOI: 10.1016/j.jelekin.2016.02.001; PUBMED: 26930263 ]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jelekin.2016.02.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26930263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Terada 2002</Title><Reference><Citation>Terada N, Hamazaki T, Oka M, Hoki M, Mastalerz DM, Nakano Y, et al. Bone marrow cells adopt the phenotype of other cells by spontaneous cell fusion. Nature 2002;416(6880):542&#x2010;5. [PUBMED: 11932747]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11932747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Thonhoff 2009</Title><Reference><Citation>Thonhoff JR, Ojeda L, Wu P. Stem cell&#x2010;derived motor neurons: applications and challenges in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Current Stem Cell Research &amp; Therapy 2009;4(3):178&#x2010;99. [PUBMED: 19492980]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2887342</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19492980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Turner 2003</Title><Reference><Citation>Turner MR, Parton MJ, Shaw CE, Leigh PN, Al&#x2010;Chalabi A. Prolonged survival in motor neuron disease: a descriptive study of the King's database 1990&#x2010;2002. Journal of Neurology, Neurosurgery, and Psychiatry 2003;74(7):995&#x2010;7. [PUBMED: 12810805]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1738535</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12810805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Uccelli 2008</Title><Reference><Citation>Uccelli A, Moretta L, Pistoia V. Mesenchymal stem cells in health and disease. Nature Reviews Immunology 2008;8(9):726&#x2010;36. [DOI: 10.1038/nri2395; PUBMED: 19172693]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nri2395</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19172693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Ware 1992</Title><Reference><Citation>Ware JE Jr, Sherbourne CD. The MOS 36&#x2010;item short&#x2010;form health survey (SF&#x2010;36). I. Conceptual framework and item selection. Medical Care 1992;30(6):473&#x2010;83. [PUBMED: 1593914]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1593914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Woodbury 2000</Title><Reference><Citation>Woodbury D, Schwarz EJ, Prockop DJ, Black IB. Adult rat and human bone marrow stromal cells differentiate into neurons. Journal of Neuroscience Research 2000;61(4):364&#x2010;70. [PUBMED: 10931522]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10931522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Writing Group 2017</Title><Reference><Citation>Writing Group, Edaravone (MCI&#x2010;186) ALS 19 Study Group. Safety and efficacy of edaravone in well defined patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a randomised, double&#x2010;blind, placebo&#x2010;controlled trial. Lancet Neurology 2017;16(7):505&#x2010;12. [DOI: 10.1016/S1474-4422(17)30115-1]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1474-4422(17)30115-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28522181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>References to other published versions of this review</Title><ReferenceList><Title>Abdul Wahid 2015</Title><Reference><Citation>Abdul Wahid SF, Law ZK, Lai NM, Ismail NA, Azman Ali R. Cell&#x2010;based therapies for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis/motor neuron disease. Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews 2015, Issue 6. [DOI: 10.1002/14651858.CD011742]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD011742</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6464737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27822919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Abdul&#x2010;Wahid 2016</Title><Reference><Citation>Abdul Wahid SF, Law ZK, Lai NM, Ismail NA, Azman Ali R. Cell&#x2010;based therapies for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis/motor neuron disease. Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews 2016, Issue 11. [DOI: 10.1002/14651858.CD011742.pub2]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD011742.pub2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6464737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27822919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>