<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">31863499</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>21</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-0258</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>39</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>30</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Statistics in medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Stat Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Exploratory identification of predictive biomarkers in randomized trials with normal endpoints.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>923</StartPage><EndPage>939</EndPage><MedlinePgn>923-939</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/sim.8452</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>One of the main endeavours in present-day medicine, especially in oncological research, is to provide evidence for individual treatment decisions ("stratified medicine"). In the pursuit of optimal treatment decision rules, the identification of predictive biomarkers that modify the treatment effect is essential. Proposed methods have often been based on recursive partitioning since a wide variety of interaction patterns can be captured automatically and the results are easily interpretable. Furthermore, these methods are readily extendable to high-dimensional settings by means of ensemble learning. In this article, we present predMOB, an adaptation of the model-based recursive partitioning (MOB) for subgroup analysis approach specifically tailored to the identification of predictive factors. In a simulation study, predMOB outperforms the original MOB with respect to the number of false detections and shows to be more robust in moderately complex settings. Furthermore, we compare the results of predMOB for the application to a public data base of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients to those obtained from the original MOB and are able to elucidate the nature of the biomarkers' effects.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2019 The Authors. Statistics in Medicine published by John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Krzykalla</LastName><ForeName>Julia</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5242-9824</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Biostatistics, German Cancer Research Center (DKFZ), Heidelberg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medizinische Fakult&#xe4;t, Universit&#xe4;t Heidelberg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Benner</LastName><ForeName>Axel</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Biostatistics, German Cancer Research Center (DKFZ), Heidelberg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kopp-Schneider</LastName><ForeName>Annette</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Biostatistics, German Cancer Research Center (DKFZ), Heidelberg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Stat Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8215016</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0277-6715</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D015415">Biomarkers</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015415" MajorTopicYN="N">Biomarkers</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003198" MajorTopicYN="N">Computer Simulation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016208" MajorTopicYN="N">Databases, Factual</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016032" MajorTopicYN="N">Randomized Controlled Trials as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">individual treatment effect</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">model-based recursive partitioning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">modified covariates</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">predictive factors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">random forests</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31863499</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/sim.8452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>European Medicines Agency, Committee for Medicinal Products for Human Use (CHMP). Vectibix Assessment report. https://www.ema.europa.eu/en/documents/variation-report/vectibix-h-c-741-ii-0017-epar-assessment-report-variation_ en.pdf. Published March 2017. Accessed August 15, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>European Medicines Agency, Committee for Medicinal Products for Human Use (CHMP). Erbitux Assessment report. https://www.ema.europa.eu/en/documents/variation-report/erbitux-h-c-558-ii-0062-epar-assessment-report-variation_en.pdf. Published November 2013. Accessed August 15, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sparano JA, Gray RJ, Makower DF, et al. Prospective validation of a 21-gene expression assay in breast cancer. N Engl J Med. 2015;373(21):2005-2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>European Medicines Agency. Guideline on the investigation of subgroups in confirmatory clinical trials. https://www.ema.europa.eu/en/documents/scientific-guideline/guideline-investigation-subgroups-confirmatory-clinical-trials_en.pdf. Published January 2019. Accessed August 15, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marshall SW. Power for tests of interaction: effect of raising the type I error rate. Epidemiol Perspect Innov. 2007;4(1):4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su X, Tsai CL, Wang H, Nickerson DM, Li B. Subgroup analysis via recursive partitioning. J Mach Learn Res. 2009;10:141-158.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breiman L, Friedman JH, Olshen RA, Stone CJ. Classification and Regression Trees. Wadsworth and Brooks: Monterey, CA; 1984.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Negassa A, Ciampi A, Abrahamowicz M, Shapiro S, Boivin JF. Tree-structured subgroup analysis for censored survival data: validation of computationally inexpensive model selection criteria. Stat Comput. 2005;15(3):231-239.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su X, Zhou T, Yan X, Fan J, Yang S. Interaction trees with censored survival data. Int J Biostat. 2008;4(1):2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su X, Pe&#xf1;a AT, Liu L, Levine RA. Random forests of interaction trees for estimating individualized treatment effects in randomized trials. Stat Med. 2018;37(17):2547-2560.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dusseldorp E, Conversano C, van Os BJ. Combining an additive and tree-based regression model simultaneously: STIMA. J Comput Graph Stat. 2010;19(3):514-530.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lipkovich I, Dmitrienko A, Denne J, Enas G. Subgroup identification based on differential effect search-A recursive partitioning method for establishing response to treatment in patient subpopulations. Stat Med. 2011;30(21):2601-2621.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loh WY. Regression tress with unbiased variable selection and interaction detection. Stat Sin. 2002;12:361-386.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loh WY, He X, Man M. A regression tree approach to identifying subgroups with differential treatment effects. Stat Med. 2015;34(11):1818-1833.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hothorn T, Hornik K, Zeileis A. Unbiased recursive partitioning: a conditional inference framework. J Comput Graph Stat. 2006;15(3):651-674.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeileis A, Hothorn T, Hornik K. Model-based recursive partitioning. J Comput Graph Stat. 2008;17(2):492-514.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seibold H, Zeileis A, Hothorn T. Model-based recursive partitioning for subgroup analyses. Int J Biostat. 2016;12(1):45-63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dusseldorp E, Van Mechelen I. Qualitative interaction trees: a tool to identify qualitative treatment-subgroup interactions. Stat Med. 2014;33(2):219-237.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rubin DB. Estimating causal effects of treatments in randomized and nonrandomized studies. J Educ Psychol. 1974;66(5):688.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foster JC, Taylor JM, Ruberg SJ. Subgroup identification from randomized clinical trial data. Stat Med. 2011;30(24):2867-2880.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian L, Alizadeh AA, Gentles AJ, Tibshirani R. A simple method for estimating interactions between a treatment and a large number of covariates. J Am Stat Assoc. 2014;109(508):1517-1532.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Powers S, Qian J, Jung K, et al. Some methods for heterogeneous treatment effect estimation in high dimensions. Stat Med. 2018;37(11):1767-1787.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guelman L, Guill&#xe9;n M, P&#xe9;rez-Mar&#xed;n AM. Uplift random forests. Cybern Syst. 2015;46(3-4):230-248.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Athey S, Imbens G. Recursive partitioning for heterogeneous causal effects. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2016;113(27):7353-7360.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ondra T, Dmitrienko A, Friede T, et al. Methods for identification and confirmation of targeted subgroups in clinical trials: a systematic review. J Biopharm Stat. 2016;26(1):99-119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lipkovich I, Dmitrienko A, D'Agostino RB Sr. Tutorial in biostatistics: data-driven subgroup identification and analysis in clinical trials. Stat Med. 2017;36(1):136-196.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alemayehu D, Chen Y, Markatou M. A comparative study of subgroup identification methods for differential treatment effect: performance metrics and recommendations. Stat Methods Med Res. 2018;27(12):3658-3678.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Signorovitch JE. Identifying Informative Biological Markers in High-Dimensional Genomic Data and Clinical Trials [Ph.D. thesis]. Boston, MA: Harvard University; 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeileis A, Hornik K. Generalized M-fluctuation tests for parameter instability. Stat Neerl. 2007;61(4):488-508.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seibold H, Zeileis A, Hothorn T. Individual treatment effect prediction for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. Stat Methods Med Res. 2018;27(10):3104-3125.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kononenko I, Hong SJ. Attribute selection for modelling. Future Gener Comput Syst. 1997;13(2):181-195.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breiman L. Random forests. Mach Learn. 2001;45(1):5-32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishwaran H, Kogalur UB, Gorodeski EZ, Minn AJ, Lauer MS. High-dimensional variable selection for survival data. J Am Stat Assoc. 2010;105(489):205-217.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strobl C, Boulesteix AL, Kneib T, Augustin T, Zeileis A. Conditional variable importance for random forests. BMC Bioinformatics. 2008;9(1):307.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seifert S, Gundlach S, Szymczak S. Surrogate minimal depth as an importance measure for variables in random forests. Bioinformatics. 2019;35(19):3663-3671.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>European Medicines Agency. Rilutek: EPAR summary for the public. https://www.ema.europa.eu/en/documents/overview/rilutek-epar-summary-public_en.pdf. Published April 2016. Accessed August 15, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atassi N, Berry J, Shui A, et al. The PRO-ACT database. Neurology. 2014;83(19):1719-1725.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The ACTS Study Group. The amyotrophic lateral sclerosis functional rating scale: assessment of activities of daily living in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Arch Neurol. 1996;53(2):141-147.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedman JH. Greedy function approximation: a gradient boosting machine. Ann Stat. 2001;29(5):1189-1232.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hinchcliffe M, Smith A. Riluzole: real-world evidence supports significant extension of median survival times in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Degener Neurol Neuromuscul Dis. 2017;7:61-70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beltran-Parrazal L, Charles A. Riluzole inhibits spontaneous Ca2+ signaling in neuroendocrine cells by activation of K+ channels and inhibition of Na+ channels. Br J Pharmacol. 2003;140(5):881-888.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellingham MC. A review of the neural mechanisms of action and clinical efficiency of riluzole in treating amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: what have we learned in the last decade? CNS Neurosci Ther. 2011;17(1):4-31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kursa MB, Rudnicki WR. Feature selection with the Boruta package. J Stat Softw. 2010;36(11):1-13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janitza S, Celik E, Boulesteix AL. A computationally fast variable importance test for random forests for high-dimensional data. Adv Data Anal Classif. 2018;12(4):885-915.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Degenhardt F, Seifert S, Szymczak S. Evaluation of variable selection methods for random forests and omics data sets. Brief Bioinform. 2017;20(2):492-503.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hothorn T, Jung HH. RandomForest4Life: a random forest for predicting ALS disease progression. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2014;15(5-6):444-452.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korepanova N, Seibold H, Steffen V, Hothorn T. Survival forests under test: Impact of the proportional hazards assumption on prognostic and predictive forests for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis survival. Stat Methods Med Res. 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hothorn T, M&#xf6;st L, B&#xfc;hlmann P. Most likely transformations. Scand Stat Theory Appl. 2018;45(1):110-134.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R Core Team. R: A Language and Environment for Statistical Computing. Vienna, Austria: R Foundation for Statistical Computing; 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hothorn T, Zeileis A. partykit: a modular toolkit for recursive partytioning in R. J Mach Learn Res. 2015;16:3905-3909.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seibold H, Zeileis A, Hothorn T. model4you: Stratified and Personalised Models Based on Model-Based Trees and Forests. R package version 0.9-2. 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldfeld K. simstudy: Simulation of Study Data. R package version 0.1.9. 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hothorn T. TH.data: TH's Data Archive. R package version 1.0-8. 2017.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>