<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">31875983</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>10</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-4598</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>61</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Muscle &amp; nerve</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Muscle Nerve</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A new parameter to discriminate amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients from healthy participants by motor cortical excitability changes.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>354</StartPage><EndPage>362</EndPage><MedlinePgn>354-362</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/mus.26786</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION">We sought a combination of abnormalities to define a more sensitive measure of cortical excitability in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">The automatic threshold tracking method was employed to assess the resting motor threshold, intracortical facilitation (ICF), short-interval intracortical inhibition (SICI), and short-interval intracortical faciilitation (SICF) in patients and controls.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">SICF at interstimulus intervals (ISI) between 1 and 1.8&#x2009;ms and 2 and 3&#x2009;ms as well as average SICI and SICI at ISIs of 1 and 2.5&#x2009;ms were significantly reduced in ALS. The SICI curve was altered, displaying a solitary peak. Discriminant analysis revealed that the combination of SICI 2.5&#x2009;ms and the mean SICF between 1 and 1.8&#x2009;ms ISIs was the most sensitive parameter to distinguish patients with ALS from healthy participants.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION">Along with the reduced SICI and its altered shape, connectivity between motor cortical circuits is changed in ALS. Combination with SICF increases the diagnostic utility of SICI in ALS.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2019 Wiley Periodicals, Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cengiz</LastName><ForeName>B&#xfc;lent</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Clinical Neurophysiology Division, Gazi University Faculty of Medicine, Ankara, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kuruo&#x11f;lu</LastName><ForeName>Reha</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Clinical Neurophysiology Division, Gazi University Faculty of Medicine, Ankara, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Muscle Nerve</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7803146</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0148-639X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="Y">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000071080" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cortical Excitability</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003430" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Sectional Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004568" MajorTopicYN="N">Electrodiagnosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004576" MajorTopicYN="N">Electromyography</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019054" MajorTopicYN="N">Evoked Potentials, Motor</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009044" MajorTopicYN="N">Motor Cortex</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D050781" MajorTopicYN="N">Transcranial Magnetic Stimulation</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ALS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SICF</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SICI</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">motor cortical excitability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">threshold tracking</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31875983</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.26786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Shibuya K, Simon NG, Geevasinga N, et al. The evolution of motor cortical dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Neurophysiol. 2017;128:1075-1082.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eisen A, Pant B, Stewart H. Cortical excitability in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a clue to pathogenesis. Can J Neurol Sci. 1993;20:11-16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Floyd AG, Yu QP, Piboolnurak P, et al. Transcranial magnetic stimulation in ALS: utility of central motor conduction tests. Neurology. 2009;72:498-504.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mills KR, Nithi KA. Corticomotor threshold is reduced in early sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 1997;20:1137-1141.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prout AJ, Eisen AA. The cortical silent period and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 1994;17:217-223.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ziemann U. Transcranial magnetic stimulation. In: Hallett M, ed. Movement Disorders, Handbook of Clinical Neurophysiology. Elsevier; 2003:95-123.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bae JS, Simon NG, Menon P, Vucic S, Kiernan MC. The puzzling case of hyperexcitability in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Clin Neurol. 2013;9:65-74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grieve SM, Menon P, Korgaonkar MS, et al. Potential structural and functional biomarkers of upper motor neuron dysfunction in ALS. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2015;17:85-92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menon P, Geevasinga N, van den Bos M, Yiannikas C, Kiernan MC, Vucic S. Cortical hyperexcitability and disease spread in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Eur J Neurol. 2017;24:816-824.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shibuya K, Park SB, Geevasinga N, et al. Motor cortical function determines prognosis in sporadic ALS. Neurology. 2016;87:513-520.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner MR, Osei-Lah AD, Hammers A, et al. Abnormal cortical excitability in sporadic but not homozygous D90A SOD1 ALS. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2005;76:1279-1285.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S, Cheah BC, Yiannikas C, Kiernan MC. Cortical excitability distinguishes ALS from mimic disorders. Clin Neurophysiol. 2011;122:1860-1866.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S, Kiernan MC. Cortical excitability testing distinguishes Kennedy's disease from amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Neurophysiol. 2008;119:1088-1096.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S, Nicholson GA, Kiernan MC. Cortical hyperexcitability may precede the onset of familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain. 2008;131:1540-1550.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zanette G, Tamburin S, Manganotti P, Refatti N, Forgione A, Rizzuto N. Different mechanisms contribute to motor cortex hyperexcitability in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Neurophysiol. 2002;113:1688-1697.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geevasinga N, Menon P, Nicholson GA, et al. Cortical function in asymptomatic carriers and patients with C9orf72 amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. JAMA Neurol. 2015;72:1268-1274.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geevasinga N, Menon P, Yiannikas C, Kiernan MC, Vucic S. Diagnostic utility of cortical excitability studies in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Eur J Neurol. 2014;21:1451-1457.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Dengler R, Eisen A, et al. Electrodiagnostic criteria for diagnosis of ALS. Clin Neurophysiol. 2008;119:497-503.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinical Electromyography OSJ. Nerve Conduction Studies. Philadelphia, PA: Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins; 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher RJ, Nakamura Y, Bestmann S, Rothwell JC, Bostock H. Two phases of intracortical inhibition revealed by transcranial magnetic threshold tracking. Exp Brain Res. 2002;143:240-248.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chervyakov AV, Bakulin IS, Savitskaya NG, et al. Navigated transcranial magnetic stimulation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 2015;51:125-131.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karandreas N, Papadopoulou M, Kokotis P, Papapostolou A, Tsivgoulis G, Zambelis T. Impaired interhemispheric inhibition in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2007;8:112-118.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caramia MD, Cicinelli P, Paradiso C, et al. Excitability changes of muscular responses to magnetic brain stimulation in patients with central motor disorders. Electroencephalogr Clin Neurophysiol. 1991;81:243-250.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Turkman A, Swash M. Motor responses evoked by transcranial magnetic stimulation and peripheral nerve stimulation in the ulnar innervation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: the effect of upper and lower motor neuron lesion. J Neurol Sci. 2003;210:83-90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eisen A, Swash M. Clinical neurophysiology of ALS. Clin Neurophysiol. 2001;112:2190-2201.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sommer M, Tergau F, Wischer S, Reimers CD, Beuche W, Paulus W. Riluzole does not have an acute effect on motor thresholds and the intracortical excitability in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol. 1999;246(Suppl 3):III22-III26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ziemann U, Winter M, Reimers CD, Reimers K, Tergau F, Paulus W. Impaired motor cortex inhibition in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Evidence from paired transcranial magnetic stimulation. Neurology. 1997;49:1292-1298.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S, Kiernan MC. Novel threshold tracking techniques suggest that cortical hyperexcitability is an early feature of motor neuron disease. Brain. 2006;129:2436-2446.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ziemann U, Tergau F, Wassermann EM, Wischer S, Hildebrandt J, Paulus W. Demonstration of facilitatory I wave interaction in the human motor cortex by paired transcranial magnetic stimulation. J Physiol. 1998;511:181-190.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van den Bos MAJ, Higashihara M, Geevasinga N, Menon P, Kiernan MC, Vucic S. Imbalance of cortical facilitatory and inhibitory circuits underlies hyperexcitability in ALS. Neurology. 2018;91:e1669-e1676.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bae JS, Menon P, Mioshi E, Kiernan MC, Vucic S. Cortical excitability differences between flexor pollicis longus and APB. Neurosci Lett. 2013;541:150-154.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roshan L, Paradiso GO, Chen R. Two phases of short-interval intracortical inhibition. Exp Brain Res. 2003;151:330-337.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comley L, Allodi I, Nichterwitz S, et al. Motor neurons with differential vulnerability to degeneration show distinct protein signatures in health and ALS. Neuroscience. 2015;291:216-229.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petri S, Krampfl K, Hashemi F, et al. Distribution of GABAA receptor mRNA in the motor cortex of ALS patients. J Neuropathol Exp Neurol. 2003;62:1041-1051.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li W, Zhang J, Zhou C, et al. Abnormal functional connectivity density in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Front Aging Neurosci. 2018;10:215.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verstraete E, Veldink JH, Mandl RC, van den Berg LH, van den Heuvel MP. Impaired structural motor connectome in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. PLoS One. 2011;6:e24239.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verstraete E, Veldink JH, van den Berg LH, van den Heuvel MP. Structural brain network imaging shows expanding disconnection of the motor system in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Hum Brain Mapp. 2014;35:1351-1361.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menon P, Kiernan MC, Vucic S. Cortical hyperexcitability precedes lower motor neuron dysfunction in ALS. Clin Neurophysiol. 2015;126:803-809.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>