<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">31883180</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>19</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1440-1789</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>40</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Neuropathology : official journal of the Japanese Society of Neuropathology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Neuropathology</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Soluble iron accumulation induces microglial glutamate release in the spinal cord of sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>152</StartPage><EndPage>166</EndPage><MedlinePgn>152-166</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/neup.12632</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Previous studies on sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (SALS) demonstrated iron accumulation in the spinal cord and increased glutamate concentration in the cerebrospinal fluid. To clarify the relationship between the two phenomena, we first performed quantitative and morphological analyses of substances related to iron and glutamate metabolism using spinal cords obtained at autopsy from 12 SALS patients and 12 age-matched control subjects. Soluble iron content determined by the Ferrozine method as well as ferritin (Ft) and glutaminase C (GLS-C) expression levels on Western blots were significantly higher in the SALS group than in the control group, while ferroportin (FPN) levels on Western blots were significantly reduced in the SALS group as compared to the control group. There was no significant difference in aconitase 1 (ACO1) and tumor necrosis factor-alpha (TNF&#x3b1;)-converting enzyme (TACE) levels on Western blots between the two groups. Immunohistochemically, Ft, ACO1, TACE, TNF&#x3b1;, and GLS-C were proven to be selectively expressed in microglia. Immunoreactivities for FPN and hepcidin were localized in neuronal and glial cells. Based on these observations, it is predicted that soluble iron may stimulate microglial glutamate release. To address this issue, cell culture experiments were carried out on a microglial cell line (BV-2). Treatment of BV-2 cells with ferric ammonium citrate (FAC) brought about significant increases in intracellular soluble iron and Ft expression levels and conditioned medium glutamate and TNF&#x3b1; concentrations. Glutamate concentration was also significantly increased in conditioned media of TNF&#x3b1;-treated BV-2 cells. While the FAC-driven increases in glutamate and TNF&#x3b1; release were completely canceled by pretreatment with ACO1 and TACE inhibitors, respectively, the TNF&#x3b1;-driven increase in glutamate release was completely canceled by GLS-C inhibitor pretreatment. Moreover, treatment of BV-2 cells with hepcidin resulted in a significant reduction in FPN expression levels on Western blots of the intracellular total protein extracts. The present results provide in vivo and in vitro evidence that microglial glutamate release in SALS spinal cords is enhanced by intracellular soluble iron accumulation-induced activation of ACO1 and TACE and by increased extracellular TNF&#x3b1;-stimulated GLS-C upregulation, and suggest a positive feedback mechanism to maintain increased intracellular soluble iron levels, involving TNF&#x3b1;, hepcidin, and FPN.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2019 Japanese Society of Neuropathology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Niida-Kawaguchi</LastName><ForeName>Motoko</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Pathological Neuroscience, Department of Pathology, Tokyo Women's Medical University, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kakita</LastName><ForeName>Akiyoshi</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathology, Brain Research Institute, Niigata University, Niigata, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Noguchi</LastName><ForeName>Noriko</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Life Systems, Faculty of Life and Medical Sciences, Doshisha University, Kyoto, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kazama</LastName><ForeName>Miku</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, Tokyo Women's Medical University, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Masui</LastName><ForeName>Kenta</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Pathological Neuroscience, Department of Pathology, Tokyo Women's Medical University, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kato</LastName><ForeName>Yoichiro</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Pathological Neuroscience, Department of Pathology, Tokyo Women's Medical University, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yamamoto</LastName><ForeName>Tomoko</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Pathological Neuroscience, Department of Pathology, Tokyo Women's Medical University, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sawada</LastName><ForeName>Tatsuo</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Pathological Neuroscience, Department of Pathology, Tokyo Women's Medical University, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kitagawa</LastName><ForeName>Kazuo</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Tokyo Women's Medical University, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Watabe</LastName><ForeName>Kazuhiko</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Technology, Faculty of Health Sciences, Kyorin University, Mitaka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shibata</LastName><ForeName>Noriyuki</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Pathological Neuroscience, Department of Pathology, Tokyo Women's Medical University, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2018-12</GrantID><Agency>Brain Research Institute, Niigata University</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2017-15</GrantID><Agency>Brain Research Institute, Niigata University</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2016-02</GrantID><Agency>Brain Research Institute, Niigata University</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><Agency>TWMU Career Development Center</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Australia</Country><MedlineTA>Neuropathology</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9606526</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0919-6544</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>3KX376GY7L</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D018698">Glutamic Acid</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>E1UOL152H7</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D007501">Iron</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><SupplMeshList><SupplMeshName Type="Disease" UI="C531617">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis 1</SupplMeshName></SupplMeshList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000369" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged, 80 and over</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002102" MajorTopicYN="N">Cadaver</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018698" MajorTopicYN="N">Glutamic Acid</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007501" MajorTopicYN="N">Iron</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017628" MajorTopicYN="N">Microglia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013116" MajorTopicYN="N">Spinal Cord</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">aconitase, amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">glutamate</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">glutaminase</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">soluble iron</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tumor necrosis factor-alpha</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2019</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2019</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31883180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/neup.12632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Moos T, Nielsen TR, Skj&#xf8;rringe T, Morgan EH. Iron trafficking inside the brain. J Neurochem 2007; 103: 1730-1740.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crichton RR, Dexter DT, Ward RJ. Brain iron metabolism and perturbation in neurological diseases. J Neural Transm 2011; 118: 301-314.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li L, Holscher C, Chen B-B, Zhang Z-F, Liu Y-Z. Hepcidin treatment modulates the expression of divalent metal transporter-1, ceruloplasmin, and ferroportin-1 in the rat cerebral cortex and hippocampus. Biol Trace Elem Res 2011; 143: 1581-1593.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Urrutia P, Aguirre P, Esparza A et al. Inflammation alters the expression of DMT1, FPN1 and hepcidin, and it causes iron accumulation in central nervous system cells. J Neurochem 2013; 126: 541-549.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCarthy RC, Kosman DJ. Iron transport across the blood-brain barrier: Development, neurovascular regulation and cerebral amyloid angiopathy. Cell Mol Life Sci 2015; 72: 709-727.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoepken HH, Korten T, Robinson SR, Dringen R. Iron accumulation, iron-mediated toxicity and altered levels of ferritin and transferrin receptor in cultured astrocytes during incubation with ferric ammonium citrate. J Neurochem 2004; 88: 1194-1202.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomsen MS, Andersen MV, Christoffersen PR, Jensen MD, Lichota J, Moos T. Neurodegeneration with inflammation is accompanied by accumulation of iron and ferritin in microglia and neurons. Neurobiol Dis 2015; 81: 108-118.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Musci G, Polticelli F, Bonaccorsi di Patti MC. Ceruloplasmin-ferroportin system of iron traffic in vertebrates. World J Biol Chem 2014; 5: 204-215.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel BN, David S. A novel glycosylphosphatidylinositol-anchored form of ceruloplasmin is expressed by mammalian astrocytes. J Biol Chem 1997; 272: 20185-20190.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dringen R, Bishop GM, Koeppe M, Dang TN, Robinson SR. The pivotal role of astrocytes in the metabolism of iron in the brain. Neurochem Res 2007; 32: 1884-1890.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown RH, Al-Chalabi A. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. N Engl J Med 2017; 377: 162-172.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasarskis EJ, andon L, Lovell MA, Ehemann WD. Aluminium, calcium, and iron in the spinal cord patients with sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis using laser microprobe mass spectroscopy: A preliminary study. J Neurol Sci 1995; 130: 203-208.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rothstein JD, Tsai G, Kuncl RW et al. Abnormal excitatory amino acid metabolism in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol 1990; 28: 18-25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lovejoy DB, Guillemin GJ. The potential for transition metal-mediated neurodegeneration in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Front Aging Neurosci 2014; 6: 173. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnagi.2014.00173</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garbuzova-Davis S, Hernandez-Ontiveros DG, Rodrigues MCO et al. Impaired blood-brain/spinal cord barrier in ALS patients. Brain Res 2012; 1469: 114-128.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winkler EA, Sengillo JD, Sullivan JS, Henkel JS, Appel SH, Zlokovic BV. Blood-spinal cord barrier breakdown and pericyte reductions in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathol 2013; 125: 111-120.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamadera M, Fujimura H, Inoue K et al. Microvascular disturbance with decreased pericyte coverage is prominent in the ventral horn of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2015; 16: 393-401.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sasaki S. Aletrations of the blood-spinal cord barrier in sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuropathology 2015; 35: 518-528.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puentes F, Malaspina A, Noort JMV, Amor S. Non-neuronal cells in ALS: Role of glial, immune cells and blood-CNS barriers. Brain Pathol 2016; 26: 248-257.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeong SY, Rathore KI, Schulz K, Ponka P, Arosio P, David S. Dysregulation of iron homeostasis in the CNS contributes to disease progression in a mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurosci 2009; 29: 610-619.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Q, Zhang X, Chen S et al. Prevention of motor neuron degeneration by novel iron chelators in SOD1G93A transgenic mice of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurodegener Dis 2011; 8: 310-321.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petillon C, Hergesheimer R, Puy H et al. The relevancy of data regarding the metabolism of iron to our understanding of deregulated mechanisms in ALS; hypotheses and pitfalls. Front Neurosci 2019; 12: 1031. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnins.2018.01031</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rothstein JD, Kammen MV, Levey AI, Martin LJ, Kuncl RW. Selective loss of glial glutamate transporter GLT-1 in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol 1995; 38: 73-84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedersen WA, Fu W, Keller JN et al. Protein modification by the lipid peroxidation product 4-hydroxynonenal in the spinal cords of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. Ann Neurol 1998; 44: 819-824.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawaguchi M, Shibata N, Horiuchi S, Kobayashi M. Glyoxal inactivates glutamate transporter-1 in cultured rat astrocytes. Neuropathology 2005; 25: 27-36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Qin ZH. Molecular and cellular mechanisms of excitotoxic neuronal death. Apoptosis 2010; 15: 1382-1402.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lau A, Tymianski M. Glutamate receptors, neurotoxicity and neurodegeneration. Pflugers Arch 2010; 460: 525-542.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N&#xfa;&#xf1;ez MT, N&#xfa;&#xf1;ez-Millacura C, Tapia V et al. Iron-activated iron uptake: A positive feedback loop mediated by iron regulatory protein 1. Biometals 2003; 16: 83-90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGahan MC, Harned J, Mukunnemkeril M, Goralska M, Fleisher L, Ferrell JB. Iron alters glutamate secretion by regulating cytosolic aconitase activity. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol 2005; 288: C1117-C1124.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lall MM, Ferrell J, Nagar S, Fleisher LN, McGaban MC. Iron regulates L-cystine uptake and glutathione levels in lens epithelial and retinal pigment epithelial cells by its effect on cytosolic aconitase. Invest Ophthalmol Vis Sci 2008; 49: 310-319.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohan MJ, Seaton T, Mitchell J et al. The tumor necrosis factor-&#x3b1; converting enzyme (TACE): A unique metalloproteinase with highly defined substrate selectivity. Biochemistry 2002; 41: 9462-9469.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee JK, Shin JH, Gwag BJ, Choi E-J. Iron accumulation promotes TACE-mediated TNF-&#x3b1; secretion and neurodegeneration in a mouse model of ALS. Neurobiol Dis 2015; 80: 63-69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maras JS, Das S, Sharma S et al. Iron-overload triggers ADAM-17 mediated inflammation in severe alcoholic hepatitis. Sci Rep 2018; 8: 10264. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-018-28483-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tortarolo M, Coco DL, Veglianese P et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, a multisystem pathology: Insights into the role of TNF&#x3b1;. Mediators Inflamm 2017; 2017: 1-16. https://doi.org/10.1155/2017/2985051</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olmos G, Llad&#xf3; J. Tumor necrosis factor alpha: A link between neuroinflammation and excitotoxicity. Mediators Inflamm 2014; 2014: 1-12. https://doi.org/10.1155/2014/961231</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takeuchi H, Jin S, Wang J et al. Tumor necrosis factor-&#x3b1; induces neurotoxicity via glutamate release from hemichannels of activated microglia in an autocrine manner. J Biol Chem 2006; 281: 21362-21368.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de la Rosa V, Campos-Sandoval JA, Mart&#xed;n-Rufi&#xe1;n M et al. A novel glutaminase isoform in mammalian tissues. Neurochem Int 2009; 55: 76-84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xe1;rquez J, Campos-Sandoval JA, Pe&#xf1;alver A et al. Glutamate and brain glutaminases in drug addiction. Neurochem Res 2017; 42: 846-857.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee E-J, Moon P-G, Baek M-C, Kim H-S. Comparison of the effects of matrix metalloproteinase inhibitors on TNF-&#x3b1; release from activated microglia and TNF-&#x3b1; converting enzyme activity. Biomol Ther 2014; 22: 414-419.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Majestic BJ, Schauer JJ, Shafer MM et al. Development of a wet-chemical method for speciation of iron in atmospheric aerosols. Environ Sci Technol 2006; 40: 2346-2351.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma SK, Babitch JA. Application of Bradford's protein assay to chick brain subcellular fractions. J Biochem Biophys Methods 1980; 2: 247-250.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi S-Y, Esaki N, Yoshimura T, Soda K. Reaction mechanism of glutamate racemase, a pyridoxal phosphate-independent amino acid racemase. J Biochem 1992; 112: 139-142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nadjar Y, Gordon P, Corcia P et al. Elevated serum ferritin is associated with reduced survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. PLoS One 2012; 7: e45034. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0045034</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu X, Yang Y, Su J, Yao C. Meta-analysis of the relationship between amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and susceptibility to serum ferritin level elevation. Neurosciences (Riyadh) 2016; 21: 120-125.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu J, Wang N, Qi F et al. Serum ferritin is a candidate biomarker of disease aggravation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Biomed Rep 2018; 9: 333-338.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell RM, Simmons Z, Beard JL, Stephens HE, Connor JR. Plasma biomarkers associated with ALS and their relationship to iron homeostasis. Muscle Nerve 2010; 42: 95-103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawahara Y, Ito K, Sun H, Aizawa H, Kanazawa I, Kwak S. RNA editing and death of motor neurons. Nature 2004; 427: 801.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwak S, Kawahara Y. Deficient RNA editing of GluR2 and neuronal death in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Mol Med 2005; 83: 110-120.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aizawa H, Sawada J, Hideyama T et al. TDP-43 pathology in sporadic ALS occurs in motor neurons lacking the RNA editing enzyme ADAR2. Acta Neuropathol 2010; 120: 75-84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamashita T, Hideyama T, Hachiga K et al. A role for ccalpine-dependent cleavage of TDP-43 in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis pathology. Nat Commun 2012; 3: 1307. https://doi.org/10.1038/ncomms2303</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamashita T, Kwak S. The molecular link between inefficient GluA2 Q/R site-RNA editing and TDP-43 pathology in motor neurons of sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. Brain Res 2014; 1584: 28-38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayala V, Granado-Serrano AB, Cacabelos D et al. Cell stress induces TDP-43 pathological changes associated with ERK1/2 dysfunction: Implications in ALS. Acta Neuropathol 2011; 122: 259-270.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahajan SS, Thai KH, Chen K, Ziff E. Exposure of neurons to excitotoxic levels of glutamate induces cleavage of the RNA editing enzyme adenosine deaminase acting on RNA 2, and loss of GluR2 editing. Neuroscience 2011; 189: 305-315.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alexianu ME, Ho BK, Mohamed AH, La Bella V, Smith RG, Appel SH. The role of calcium-binding proteins in selective motomeirpm vulnerability in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol 1994; 36: 846-858.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takeuchi H, Suzumura A. Gap junctions and hemichannels composed of connexins: Potential therapeutic targets for neurodegenerative diseases. Front Cell Neurosci 2014; 8: 189. https://doi.org/10.3389/fncel.2014.00189</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellingham MC. A review of the neural mechanisms of action and clinical efficiency of riluzole in treating amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: What have we learned in the last decade? CNS Neurosci Ther 2011; 17: 4-31.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>