<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">31918429</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1421-9972</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>73</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Folia phoniatrica et logopaedica : official organ of the International Association of Logopedics and Phoniatrics (IALP)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Folia Phoniatr Logop</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Communicative Participation in People with Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>101</StartPage><EndPage>108</EndPage><MedlinePgn>101-108</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1159/000505022</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Communication is affected in most people with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS); up to 80-95% will reach a point where they are no longer able to meet their communicative needs with natural speech. The deterioration of speech and communicative abilities presumably has an impact on communicative participation. However, little is known about how these factors relate to each other in this population of patients.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">This study aimed to investigate the association between communicative participation, functional deficits, and severity of dysarthria in individuals with ALS.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHOD">Thirty people with ALS were rated for (1) communicative participation, using the Communicative Participation Item Bank (CPIB, Swedish); and (2) disability related to the disease, using the Revised ALS Functional Rating Scale (Swedish). An expert listening panel assessed intelligibility and severity of dysarthria based on recorded text readings and sentences from the Swedish Test of Intelligibility.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">CPIB scores were significantly lower for participants with moderate/severe dysarthria than for those with no/mild dysarthria and correlated with bulbar function and intelligibility.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">The study found that the CPIB provides a means to rate and discuss communicative participation with persons with ALS, which could assist in the planning of further efforts/services.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>The Author(s). Published by S. Karger AG, Basel.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sixt B&#xf6;rjesson</LastName><ForeName>Malin</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurologopedics, Sahlgrenska University Hospital, Gothenburg, Sweden, malin.sixt.borjesson@vgregion.se.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Speech and Language Pathology Unit, Institute of Neuroscience and Physiology, University of Gothenburg, Gothenburg, Sweden, malin.sixt.borjesson@vgregion.se.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hartelius</LastName><ForeName>Lena</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Speech and Language Pathology Unit, Institute of Neuroscience and Physiology, University of Gothenburg, Gothenburg, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Laakso</LastName><ForeName>Katja</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Speech and Language Pathology Unit, Institute of Neuroscience and Physiology, University of Gothenburg, Gothenburg, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Folia Phoniatr Logop</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9422792</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1021-7762</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003142" MajorTopicYN="N">Communication</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004401" MajorTopicYN="N">Dysarthria</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013060" MajorTopicYN="N">Speech</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013064" MajorTopicYN="N">Speech Disorders</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013065" MajorTopicYN="N">Speech Intelligibility</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Communicative Participation Item Bank</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Communicative participation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dysarthria</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Intelligibility</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors have no conflicts of interest to declare.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2019</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31918429</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7949226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000505022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">000505022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Andersen PM, Abrahams S, Borasio GD, de Carvalho M, Chio A, Van Damme P, et al. EFNS Task Force on Diagnosis and Management of Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis EFNS guidelines on the clinical management of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (MALS)&#x2014;revised report of an EFNS task force. Eur J Neurol. 2012 Mar;19((3)):360&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21914052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wijesekera LC, Leigh PN. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Orphanet J Rare Dis. 2009 Feb;4((3)):3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2656493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19192301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomik B, Guiloff RJ. Dysarthria in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A review. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2010;11((1-2)):4&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20184513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beukelman D, Fager S, Nordness A. Communication support for People with ALS. Neurol Res Int. 2011;2011:714693.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3096454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21603029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization . ICF: International Classification of Functioning, Disability and Health. Geneva, Switzerland: WHO; 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ust&#xfc;n TB, Chatterji S, Bickenbach J, Kostanjsek N, Schneider M. The International Classification of Functioning, Disability and Health: a new tool for understanding disability and health. Disabil Rehabil. 2003 Jun;25((11-12)):565&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12959329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dykstra A. Communicative participation and speech intelligibility: complexities and challenges. Dev Med Child Neurol. 2013 May;55((5)):403&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23441870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eadie TL, Yorkston KM, Klasner ER, Dudgeon BJ, Deitz JC, Baylor CR, et al. Measuring communicative participation: a review of self-report instruments in speech-language pathology. Am J Speech Lang Pathol. 2006 Nov;15((4)):307&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2649949</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17102143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yorkston KM, Beukelman DR, Strand EA, Bell KR. Management of Motor Speech Disorders in Children and Adults. Austin: Pro-Ed; 1999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller N. Measuring up to speech intelligibility. Int J Lang Commun Disord. 2013 Nov-Dec;48((6)):601&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24119170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sussman JE, Tjaden K. Perceptual measures of speech from individuals with Parkinson's disease and multiple sclerosis: intelligibility and beyond. J Speech Lang Hear Res. 2012 Aug;55((4)):1208&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5564315</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22232396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dykstra A.  What is communicative participation? Canada: Western University; 2013. July 8.  Available from:  http://www.uwo.ca/fhs/cpl/whatis.html.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baylor C, Burns M, Eadie T, Britton D, Yorkston K. A qualitative study of interference with communicative participation across communication disorders in adults. Am J Speech Lang Pathol. 2011 Nov;20((4)):269&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3296484</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21813820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartelius L, Elmberg M, Holm R, L&#xf6;vberg AS, Nikolaidis S. Living with dysarthria: evaluation of a self-report questionnaire. Folia Phoniatr Logop. 2008;60((1)):11&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18057906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McAuliffe MJ, Baylor CR, Yorkston KM. Variables associated with communicative participation in Parkinson's disease and its relationship to measures of health-related quality-of-life. Int J Speech Lang Pathol. 2017 Aug;19((4)):407&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6190828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27347713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yorkston KM, Baylor C, Amtmann D. Communicative participation restrictions in multiple sclerosis: associated variables and correlation with social functioning. J Commun Disord. 2014 Nov-Dec;52:196&#x2013;206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4718073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24947986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yorkston K, Baylor C, Mach H. Factors Associated With Communicative Participation in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. J Speech Lang Hear Res. 2017 Jun;60((6S Suppl)):1791&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5544405</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28655040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baylor C, Hula W, Donovan NJ, Doyle PJ, Kendall D, Yorkston K. An introduction to item response theory and Rasch models for speech-language pathologists. Am J Speech Lang Pathol. 2011 Aug;20((3)):243&#x2013;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21622595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baylor CR, Yorkston KM, Eadie TL, Miller RM, Amtmann D. Developing the communicative participation item bank: rasch analysis results from a spasmodic dysphonia sample. J Speech Lang Hear Res. 2009 Oct;52((5)):1302&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3074579</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19717652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baylor C, Yorkston K, Eadie T, Kim J, Chung H, Amtmann D. The Communicative Participation Item Bank (CPIB): item bank calibration and development of a disorder-generic short form. J Speech Lang Hear Res. 2013 Aug;56((4)):1190&#x2013;208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4377222</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23816661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baylor C. &#x201c;I'll Have What He's Having&#x2026;&#x201d; and Other Restrictions in Communicative Participation. JAMA Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg. 2018 Aug;144((8)):693&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29955788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nordberg M, Syrj&gt;kyly ML.  Unpublished graduate paper. Stockholm: Karolinska Institutet, Department of Clinical Science, Intervention and Technology (CLINTEC) Division of Speech and Language Pathology; Validation of translation into Swedish of Communicative Participation Item Bank by cognitive interviews with persons with MS or ataxia. Available from:  https://clintec.ki.se/Exam_logopedi/pdf/355.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mellenthin L, Roos E.  Validation of the Swedish translation of Communicative Participation Item Bank on individuals with Parkinson's disease or atypical Parkinsonism. Unpublished graduate paper. Gothenburg: University of Gothenburg, Speech and Language Pathology Unit; 2013.  available from  https://core.ac.uk/display/18175394.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baylor C, McAuliffe MJ, Hughes LE, Yorkston K, Anderson T, Kim J, et al. A differential item functioning (DIF) analysis of the Communicative Participation Item Bank (CPIB): comparing individuals with Parkinson's disease from the United States and New Zealand. J Speech Lang Hear Res. 2014 Feb;57((1)):90&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4704866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24687470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum JM, Stambler N, Malta E, Fuller C, Hilt D, Thurmond B, et al. BDNF ALS Study Group (Phase III) The ALSFRS-R: a revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. J Neurol Sci. 1999 Oct;169((1-2)):13&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10540002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Functional Rating Scale. Assessment of activities of daily living in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. The ALS CNTF treatment study (ACTS) phase I-II Study Group. Arch Neurol. 1996 Feb;53((2)):141&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8639063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bacci ED, Staniewska D, Coyne KS, Boyer S, White LA, Zach N, et al. Pooled Resource Open-Access ALS Clinical Trials Consortium Item response theory analysis of the Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Functional Rating Scale-Revised in the Pooled Resource Open-Access ALS Clinical Trials Database. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2016;17((3-4)):157&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26473473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozanne AG, Persson LI. Correlations in health status between estimates of families of people with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and estimates of staff. Palliat Support Care. 2013 Jun;11((3)):183&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23013718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartelius L, Svensson P. Dysartritest. Stockholm: Psykologif&#xf6;rlaget AB; 1990.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eadie T, Kapsner-Smith M, Bolt S, Sauder C, Yorkston K, Baylor C. Relationship between perceived social support and patient-reported communication outcomes across communication disorders: a systematic review. Int J Lang Commun Disord. 2018 Nov;53((6)):1059&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7335018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30039920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>