<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">31916305</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>03</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1531-8249</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>87</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Annals of neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Ann Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Life Course Adiposity and Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis: A Mendelian Randomization Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>434</StartPage><EndPage>441</EndPage><MedlinePgn>434-441</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/ana.25671</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">Observational studies have indicated that life course adiposity is associated with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). However, whether such an association reflects causality remains unclear. We aimed to determine whether life course adiposity such as birth weight (BW), childhood body mass index (BMI), adult BMI, body fat percentage (BF%), and waist-to-hip ratio (WHR) have causal effects on ALS.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Single nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs) significantly associated with life course adiposity were used as instrumental variables to estimate the causal effects on ALS. We used summary-level data from a cohort of 20,806 cases and 59,804 controls in a Mendelian randomization (MR) framework.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Genetically predicted one standard deviation (1-SD) increase in BF% was associated with lower risk of ALS (odds ratio [OR] = 0.67, 95% confidence interval [CI] = 0.54-0.83, p =&#x2009;3.25E-04) after Bonferroni correction (p &lt;&#x2009;0.05/5). Genetically predicted 1-SD higher childhood BMI was suggestively associated with lower risk of ALS (OR = 0.88, 95% CI = 0.78-0.99, p =&#x2009;0.031). The weighted median method indicated a suggestive association between BMI and ALS (OR = 0.86, 95% CI = 0.69-0.96, p =&#x2009;0.016). Neither a genetically predicted 1-SD increase in BW (inverse variance weighted [IVW]: OR = 1.01, 95% CI = 0.87-1.17, p =&#x2009;0.939) nor WHR adjusted for BMI (IVW: OR = 0.90, 95% CI = 0.76-1.05, p =&#x2009;0.178) was associated with ALS.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="INTERPRETATION">Our findings provide novel evidence supporting a causal role of higher adiposity, taken as a whole, on lower risk of ALS. A deeper understanding of the energy metabolism of ALS is more likely to identify feasible nutritional interventions and even novel therapeutic targets that might improve the survival of ALS patients. Ann Neurol 2020;87:434-441.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020 American Neurological Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Linjing</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Peking University Third Hospital, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tang</LastName><ForeName>Lu</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Peking University Third Hospital, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Tao</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics, School of Public Health, Peking University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Molecular Cardiovascular Sciences (Peking University), Ministry of Education, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fan</LastName><ForeName>Dongsheng</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3129-9821</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Peking University Third Hospital, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory for Neuroscience, National Health Commission/Ministry of Education, Peking University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Ann Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7707449</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0364-5134</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="CommentIn"><RefSource>Ann Neurol. 2020 Jul;88(1):203</RefSource><PMID Version="1">32372439</PMID></CommentsCorrections><CommentsCorrections RefType="CommentIn"><RefSource>Ann Neurol. 2020 Jul;88(1):203-204</RefSource><PMID Version="1">32374448</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000273" MajorTopicYN="N">Adipose Tissue</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D050154" MajorTopicYN="N">Adiposity</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000367" MajorTopicYN="N">Age Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="Y">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001724" MajorTopicYN="N">Birth Weight</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015992" MajorTopicYN="N">Body Mass Index</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016022" MajorTopicYN="N">Case-Control Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057182" MajorTopicYN="N">Mendelian Randomization Analysis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020641" MajorTopicYN="N">Polymorphism, Single Nucleotide</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D049629" MajorTopicYN="N">Waist-Hip Ratio</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="N">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31916305</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.25671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Turner MR, Hardiman O, Benatar M, et al. Controversies and priorities in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet Neurol 2013;12:310-322.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Reilly EJ, Wang H, Weisskopf MG, et al. Premorbid body mass index and risk of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degen 2013;14:205-211.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peter RS, Rosenbohm A, Dupuis L, et al. Life course body mass index and risk and prognosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: results from the ALS registry Swabia. Eur J Epidemiol 2017;32:901-908.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakken O, Meyer HE, Stigum H, Holmoy T. High BMI is associated with low ALS risk: a population-based study. Neurology 2019;93:e424-e432.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kioumourtzoglou MA, Rotem RS, Seals RM, et al. Diabetes mellitus, obesity, and diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a population-based study. JAMA Neurol 2015;72:905-911.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallo V, Wark PA, Jenab M, et al. Prediagnostic body fat and risk of death from amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: the EPIC cohort. Neurology 2013;80:829-838.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ioannides ZA, Steyn FJ, Henderson RD, et al. Anthropometric measures are not accurate predictors of fat mass in ALS. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degen 2017;18:486-491.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D'Ovidio F, d'Errico A, Carna P, et al. The role of pre-morbid diabetes on developing amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Eur J Neurol 2018;25:164-170.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bandres-Ciga S, Noyce AJ, Hemani G, et al. Shared polygenic risk and causal inferences in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol 2019;85:470-481.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huisman MH, Seelen M, van Doormaal PT, et al. Effect of presymptomatic body mass index and consumption of fat and alcohol on amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. JAMA Neurol 2015;72:1155-1162.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dupuis L, Pradat PF, Ludolph AC, Loeffler JP. Energy metabolism in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet Neurol 2011;10:75-82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Afshin A, Forouzanfar MH, Reitsma MB, et al. Health effects of overweight and obesity in 195 countries over 25&#x2009;years. New Engl J Med 2017;377:13-27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawlor DA, Harbord RM, Sterne JA, et al. Mendelian randomization: using genes as instruments for making causal inferences in epidemiology. Stat Med 2008;27:1133-1163.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding M, Huang T, Bergholdt HK, et al. Dairy consumption, systolic blood pressure, and risk of hypertension: Mendelian randomization study. BMJ 2017;356:j1000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geng T, Smith CE, Li C, Huang T. Childhood BMI and adult type 2 diabetes, coronary artery diseases, chronic kidney disease, and cardiometabolic traits: a Mendelian randomization analysis. Diabetes Care 2018;41:1089-1096.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horikoshi M, Beaumont RN, Day FR, et al. Genome-wide associations for birth weight and correlations with adult disease. Nature 2016;538:248-252.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Felix JF, Bradfield JP, Monnereau C, et al. Genome-wide association analysis identifies three new susceptibility loci for childhood body mass index. Hum Mol Genet 2016;25:389-403.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu Y, Day FR, Gustafsson S, et al. New loci for body fat percentage reveal link between adiposity and cardiometabolic disease risk. Nat Commun 2016;7:10495.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Locke AE, Kahali B, Berndt SI, et al. Genetic studies of body mass index yield new insights for obesity biology. Nature 2015;518:197-206.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shungin D, Winkler TW, Croteau-Chonka DC, et al. New genetic loci link adipose and insulin biology to body fat distribution. Nature 2015;518:187-196.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicolas A, Kenna KP, Renton AE, et al. Genome-wide analyses identify KIF5A as a novel ALS gene. Neuron 2018;97:1268-1283.e1266.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowden J, Davey Smith G, Burgess S. Mendelian randomization with invalid instruments: effect estimation and bias detection through Egger regression. Int J Epidemiol 2015;44:512-525.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burgess S, Bowden J, Fall T, et al. Sensitivity analyses for robust causal inference from Mendelian randomization analyses with multiple genetic variants. Epidemiology 2017;28:30-42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowden J, Davey Smith G, Haycock PC, Burgess S. Consistent estimation in Mendelian randomization with some invalid instruments using a weighted median estimator. Genet Epidemiol 2016;40:304-314.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burgess S, Thompson SG. Interpreting findings from Mendelian randomization using the MR-Egger method. Eur J Epidemiol 2017;32:377-389.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paganoni S, Deng J, Jaffa M, et al. Body mass index, not dyslipidemia, is an independent predictor of survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve 2011;44:20-24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dupuis L, Oudart H, Rene F, et al. Evidence for defective energy homeostasis in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: benefit of a high-energy diet in a transgenic mouse model. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 2004;101:11159-11164.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ioannides ZA, Ngo ST, Henderson RD, et al. Altered metabolic homeostasis in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: mechanisms of energy imbalance and contribution to disease progression. Neurodegener Dis 2016;16:382-397.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dodge JC, Treleaven CM, Fidler JA, et al. Metabolic signatures of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis reveal insights into disease pathogenesis. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 2013;110:10812-10817.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pradat PF, Bruneteau G, Gordon PH, et al. Impaired glucose tolerance in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler 2010;11:166-171.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steyn FJ, Ioannides ZA, van Eijk RPA, et al. Hypermetabolism in ALS is associated with greater functional decline and shorter survival. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2018;89:1016-1023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorges M, Vercruysse P, Muller HP, et al. Hypothalamic atrophy is related to body mass index and age at onset in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2017;88:1033-1041.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vercruysse P, Sinniger J, El Oussini H, et al. Alterations in the hypothalamic melanocortin pathway in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain 2016;139(Pt 4):1106-1122.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng P, Zhou X. Causal effects of blood lipids on amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a Mendelian randomization study. Hum Mol Genet 2019;28:688-697.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verghese PB, Castellano JM, Holtzman DM. Apolipoprotein E in Alzheimer's disease and other neurological disorders. Lancet Neurol 2011;10:241-252.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrari R, Wang Y, Vandrovcova J, et al. Genetic architecture of sporadic frontotemporal dementia and overlap with Alzheimer's and Parkinson's diseases. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2017;88:152-164.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chio A, Brunetti M, Barberis M, et al. The role of APOE in the occurrence of frontotemporal dementia in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. JAMA Neurol 2016;73:425-430.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith GD, Ebrahim S. Mendelian randomization: prospects, potentials, and limitations. Intl J Epidemiol 2004;33:30-42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pierce BL, Burgess S. Efficient design for Mendelian randomization studies: subsample and 2-sample instrumental variable estimators. Am J Epidemiol 2013;178:1177-1184.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hemani G, Bowden J, Davey Smith G. Evaluating the potential role of pleiotropy in Mendelian randomization studies. Hum Mol Genet 2018;27:R195-R208.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>VanderWeele TJ, Tchetgen Tchetgen EJ, Cornelis M, Kraft P. Methodological challenges in mendelian randomization. Epidemiology. 2014;25:427-435.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>