<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">31914665</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>08</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1530-6860</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>34</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>FASEB journal : official publication of the Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>FASEB J</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Species-specific consequences of an E40K missense mutation in superoxide dismutase 1 (SOD1).</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>458</StartPage><EndPage>473</EndPage><MedlinePgn>458-473</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1096/fj.201901455R</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>A glutamic acid to lysine (E40K) residue substitution in superoxide dismutase 1 (SOD1) is associated with canine degenerative myelopathy: the only naturally occurring large animal model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). The E40 residue is highly conserved across mammals, except the horse, which naturally carries the (dog mutant) K40 residue. Here we hypothesized that in vitro expression of mutant dog SOD1 would recapitulate features of human ALS (ie, SOD1 protein aggregation, reduced cell viability, perturbations in mitochondrial morphology and membrane potential, reduced ATP production, and increased superoxide ion levels); further, we hypothesized that an equivalent equine SOD1 variant would share similar perturbations in vitro, thereby explain horses' susceptibility to certain neurodegenerative diseases. As in human ALS, expression of mutant dog SOD1 was associated with statistically significant increased aggregate formation, raised superoxide levels (ROS), and altered mitochondrial morphology (increased branching (form factor)), when compared to wild-type dog SOD1-expressing cells. Similar deficits were not detected in cells expressing the equivalent horse SOD1 variant. Our data helps explain the ALS-associated cellular phenotype of dogs expressing the mutant SOD1 protein and reveals that species-specific sequence conservation does not necessarily predict pathogenicity. The work improves understanding of the etiopathogenesis of canine degenerative myelopathy.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2019 Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Draper</LastName><ForeName>Alexandra C E</ForeName><Initials>ACE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Comparative Neuromuscular Disease Laboratory, Royal Veterinary College, University of London, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wilson</LastName><ForeName>Zoe</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Comparative Neuromuscular Disease Laboratory, Royal Veterinary College, University of London, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maile</LastName><ForeName>Charlotte</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Comparative Neuromuscular Disease Laboratory, Royal Veterinary College, University of London, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Faccenda</LastName><ForeName>Danilo</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mitochondrial Cell Biology and Pharmaceutical Research Unit, Department of Comparative Biomedical Sciences, Royal Veterinary College, University of London, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Campanella</LastName><ForeName>Michelangelo</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mitochondrial Cell Biology and Pharmaceutical Research Unit, Department of Comparative Biomedical Sciences, Royal Veterinary College, University of London, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University College London Consortium for Mitochondrial Research, University College London, University of London, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Piercy</LastName><ForeName>Richard J</ForeName><Initials>RJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Comparative Neuromuscular Disease Laboratory, Royal Veterinary College, University of London, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2019</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>FASEB J</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8804484</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0892-6638</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>8L70Q75FXE</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000255">Adenosine Triphosphate</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 1.15.1.1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000072105">Superoxide Dismutase-1</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000255" MajorTopicYN="N">Adenosine Triphosphate</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="Y">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004285" MajorTopicYN="N">Dogs</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006736" MajorTopicYN="N">Horses</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008928" MajorTopicYN="N">Mitochondria</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020125" MajorTopicYN="Y">Mutation, Missense</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010802" MajorTopicYN="N">Phylogeny</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013045" MajorTopicYN="N">Species Specificity</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000072105" MajorTopicYN="N">Superoxide Dismutase-1</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="Y">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019076" MajorTopicYN="N">Transgenes</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">degenerative myelopathy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dog</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">horse</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">superoxide dismutase 1</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2019</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2019</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31914665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1096/fj.201901455R</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Bento&#x2010;Abreu A, Van Damme P, Van Den Bosch L, Robberecht W. The neurobiology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Eur J Neurosci. 2010;31(12):2247&#x2010;2265.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosen DR. Mutations in Cu/Zn superoxide dismutase gene are associated with familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nature. 1993;364(6435):362.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Awano T, Johnson GS, Wade CM et al. Genome&#x2010;wide association analysis reveals a SOD1 mutation in canine degenerative myelopathy that resembles amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2009;106(8):2794&#x2010;2799.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katz ML, Jensen CA, Student JT, Johnson GC, Coates JR. Cervical spinal cord and motor unit pathology in a canine model of SOD1&#x2010;associated amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Sci. 2017;378:193&#x2010;203.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boill&#xe9;e S, Vande Velde C, Cleveland DW, ALS: a disease of motor neurons and their nonneuronal neighbors. Neuron. 2006;52(1):39&#x2010;59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miosge LA, Field MA, Sontani Y, et al. Comparison of predicted and actual consequences of missense mutations. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2015;112(37):E5189&#x2010;E5198.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ivansson EL, Megquier K, Kozyrev SV, et al. Variants within the SP110 nuclear body protein modify risk of canine degenerative myelopathy. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2016;113(22):E3091&#x2010;E3100.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Windley Z, Comparative Functional and Morphological Effects of SOD&#x2010;1 Mutations, in Comparative Biomedical Sciences. London: Royal Veterinary College, University of London; 2012:p. 94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orlando L, Ginolhac A, Zhang G, et al. Recalibrating Equus evolution using the genome sequence of an early Middle Pleistocene horse. Nature. 2013;499(7456):74&#x2010;78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammed HO, Cummings JF, Divers TJ, de la Rua-Domenech R, de Lahunter A. Epidemiology of equine motor neuron disease. Vet Res. 1994;25(2&#x2013;3):275&#x2010;278.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Draper ACE, Piercy RJ. Pathological classification of equine recurrent laryngeal neuropathy. J Vet Intern Med. 2018;32(4):1397&#x2010;1409.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Librado P, Gamba C, Gaunitz C, et al. Ancient genomic changes associated with domestication of the horse. Science. 2017;356(6336):442&#x2010;445.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finno CJ, Valberg SJ. A comparative review of vitamin E and associated equine disorders. J Vet Intern Med. 2012;26(6):1251&#x2010;1266.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maile CA, Hingst JR, Mahalingan KK, et al. A highly prevalent equine glycogen storage disease is explained by constitutive activation of a mutant glycogen synthase. Biochim Biophys Acta Gen Subj. 2017;1861(1 Pt A):3388&#x2010;3398.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCue ME, Valberg SJ, Miller MB, et al. Glycogen synthase (GYS1) mutation causes a novel skeletal muscle glycogenosis. Genomics. 2008;91(5):458&#x2010;466.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naylor RJ, Livesey L, Schumacher J, et al. Allele copy number and underlying pathology are associated with subclinical severity in equine type 1 polysaccharide storage myopathy (PSSM1). PLoS ONE. 2012;7(7):e42317.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parge HE, Hallewell RA, Tainer JA. Atomic structures of wild&#x2010;type and thermostable mutant recombinant human Cu, Zn superoxide dismutase. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 1992;89(13):6109&#x2010;6113.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miao L, St Clair DK. Regulation of superoxide dismutase genes: implications in disease. Free Radic Biol Med. 2009;47(4):344&#x2010;356.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crisp MJ, Beckett J, Coates JR, Miller TM. Canine degenerative myelopathy: biochemical characterization of superoxide dismutase 1 in the first naturally occurring non&#x2010;human amyotrophic lateral sclerosis model. Exp Neurol. 2013;248:1&#x2010;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saccon RA, Bunton&#x2010;Stasyshyn RKA, Fisher EMC, Fratta P. Is SOD1 loss of function involved in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis? Brain. 2013;136(Pt 8):2342&#x2010;2358.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crown AM, Roberts BL, Crosby K, et al. Experimental Mutations in Superoxide Dismutase 1 Provide Insight into Potential Mechanisms Involved in Aberrant Aggregation in Familial Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. G3 (Bethesda). 2019;9(3):719&#x2010;728.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green SL, Tolwani RJ, Varma S, Quignon P, Galibert F, Cork LC. Structure, chromosomal location, and analysis of the canine Cu/Zn superoxide dismutase (SOD1) gene. J Hered. 2002;93(2):119&#x2010;124.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zimmerman MC, Oberley LW, Flanagan SW. Mutant SOD1&#x2010;induced neuronal toxicity is mediated by increased mitochondrial superoxide levels. J Neurochem. 2007;102(3):609&#x2010;618.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richardson K, Allen SP, Mortiboys H, et al. The effect of SOD1 mutation on cellular bioenergetic profile and viability in response to oxidative stress and influence of mutation&#x2010;type. PLoS ONE. 2013;8(6):e68256.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H, Yi J, Li X, Xiao Y, Dhakal K, Zhou J. ALS&#x2010;associated mutation SOD1(G93A) leads to abnormal mitochondrial dynamics in osteocytes. Bone. 2018;106:126&#x2010;138.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khetan S, Guvendiren M, Legant WR, Cohen DM, Chen CS, Burdick JA. Degradation&#x2010;mediated cellular traction directs stem cell fate in covalently crosslinked three&#x2010;dimensional hydrogels. Nat Mater. 2013;12(5):458&#x2010;465.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoerndli FJ, Toigo M, Schild A, G&#xf6;tz J, Day PJ. Reference genes identified in SH&#x2010;SY5Y cells using custom&#x2010;made gene arrays with validation by quantitative polymerase chain reaction. Anal Biochem. 2004;335(1):30&#x2010;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hildyard JC, Wells DJ. Identification and validation of quantitative PCR reference genes suitable for normalizing expression in normal and dystrophic cell culture models of myogenesis. PLoS Curr. 2014. https://doi.org/10.1371/currents.md.faafdde4bea8df4aa7d06cd5553119a6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hildyard JCW, Taylor&#x2010;Brown F, Massey C, Wells DJ, Piercy RJ. Determination of qPCR reference genes suitable for normalizing gene expression in a canine model of duchenne muscular dystrophy. J Neuromuscul Dis. 2018;5(2):177&#x2010;191.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schindelin J, Arganda&#x2010;Carreras I, Frise E, et al. Fiji: an open&#x2010;source platform for biological&#x2010;image analysis. Nat Methods. 2012;9(7):676&#x2010;682.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Innovagen. Innovagen Protein Calculator; 2015 [cited 2018; Available from: https://pepcalc.com/protein-calculator.php.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kobatake Y, Sakai H, Tsukui T, et al. Localization of a mutant SOD1 protein in E40K&#x2010;heterozygous dogs: implications for non&#x2010;cell&#x2010;autonomous pathogenesis of degenerative myelopathy. J Neurol Sci. 2017;372:369&#x2010;378.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perry SW, Norman JP, Barbieri J, Brown EB, Gelbard HA. Mitochondrial membrane potential probes and the proton gradient: a practical usage guide. Biotechniques. 2011;50(2):98&#x2010;115.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayyan M, Hashim MA, AlNashef IM. Superoxide ion: generation and chemical implications. Chem Rev. 2016;116(5):3029&#x2010;3085.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakamae S, Kobatake Y, Suzuki R, et al. Accumulation and aggregate formation of mutant superoxide dismutase 1 in canine degenerative myelopathy. Neuroscience. 2015;303:229&#x2010;240.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stevens JC, Chia R, Hendriks WT, et al. Modification of superoxide dismutase 1 (SOD1) properties by a GFP tag&#x2013;implications for research into amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). PLoS ONE. 2010;5(3):e9541.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keskin I, Birve A, Berdynski M, et al. Comprehensive analysis to explain reduced or increased SOD1 enzymatic activity in ALS patients and their relatives. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2017;18(5&#x2013;6):457&#x2010;463.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henriques SF, Patissier C, Bourg N, et al. Different outcome of sarcoglycan missense mutation between human and mouse. PLoS ONE. 2018;13(1):e0191274.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kobuke K, Piccolo F, Garringer KW, et al. A common disease&#x2010;associated missense mutation in alpha&#x2010;sarcoglycan fails to cause muscular dystrophy in mice. Hum Mol Genet. 2008;17(9):1201&#x2010;1213.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polymeropoulos MH, et al. Mutation in the alpha&#x2010;synuclein gene identified in families with Parkinson's disease. Science. 1997;276(5321):2045&#x2010;2047.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaufmann W, Bolon B, Bradley A, et al. Proliferative and nonproliferative lesions of the rat and mouse central and peripheral nervous systems. Toxicol Pathol. 2012;40(4 Suppl):87S&#x2010;157S.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munch C, Bertolotti A. Exposure of hydrophobic surfaces initiates aggregation of diverse ALS&#x2010;causing superoxide dismutase&#x2010;1 mutants. J Mol Biol. 2010;399(3):512&#x2010;525.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munch C, O'Brien J, Bertolotti A. Prion&#x2010;like propagation of mutant superoxide dismutase&#x2010;1 misfolding in neuronal cells. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2011;108(9):3548&#x2010;3553.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prudencio M, Hart PJ, Borchelt DR, Andersen PM. Variation in aggregation propensities among ALS&#x2010;associated variants of SOD1: correlation to human disease. Hum Mol Genet. 2009;18(17):3217&#x2010;3226.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keskin I, Forsgren E, Lange DJ, et al. Effects of cellular pathway disturbances on misfolded superoxide dismutase&#x2010;1 in fibroblasts derived from ALS patients. PLoS ONE. 2016;11(2):e0150133.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grad LI, Yerbury JJ, Turner BJ, et al. Intercellular propagated misfolding of wild&#x2010;type Cu/Zn superoxide dismutase occurs via exosome&#x2010;dependent and &#x2010;independent mechanisms. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2014;111(9):3620&#x2010;3625.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiti F, Stefani M, Taddei N, Ramponi G, Dobson CM. Rationalization of the effects of mutations on peptide and protein aggregation rates. Nature. 2003;424(6950):805&#x2010;808.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tiwari A, Xu Z, Hayward LJ. Aberrantly increased hydrophobicity shared by mutants of Cu, Zn&#x2010;superoxide dismutase in familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Biol Chem. 2005;280(33):29771&#x2010;29779.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdolvahabi A, Shi Y, Rhodes N, Cook N, Mart&#xed; A, Shaw B. Arresting amyloid with coulomb's law: acetylation of ALS&#x2010;linked SOD1 by aspirin impedes aggregation. Biophys J. 2015;108(5):1199&#x2010;1212.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi Y, Abdolvahabi A, Shaw BF. Protein charge ladders reveal that the net charge of ALS&#x2010;linked superoxide dismutase can be different in sign and magnitude from predicted values. Protein Sci. 2014;23(10):1417&#x2010;1433.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldsteins G, Keksa&#x2010;Goldsteine V, Ahtoniemi T, et al. Deleterious role of superoxide dismutase in the mitochondrial intermembrane space. J Biol Chem. 2008;283(13):8446&#x2010;8452.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mortiboys H, Thomas KJ, Koopman WJ, et al. Mitochondrial function and morphology are impaired in parkin&#x2010;mutant fibroblasts. Ann Neurol. 2008;64(5):555&#x2010;565.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koopman WJ, Verkaart S, Visch HJ, et al. Inhibition of complex I of the electron transport chain causes O2&#x2010;. &#x2010;mediated mitochondrial outgrowth. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol. 2005;288(6):C1440&#x2010;C1450.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deheshi S, Dabiri B, Fan S, Tsang M, Rintoul GL. Changes in mitochondrial morphology induced by calcium or rotenone in primary astrocytes occur predominantly through ros&#x2010;mediated remodeling. J Neurochem. 2015;133(5):684&#x2010;699.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koopman WJH, Nijtmans LGJ, Dieteren CEJ, et al. Mammalian mitochondrial complex I: biogenesis, regulation, and reactive oxygen species generation. Antioxid Redox Signal. 2010;12(12):1431&#x2010;1470.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coussee E, De Smet P, Bogaert E, et al. G37R SOD1 mutant alters mitochondrial complex I activity, Ca(2+) uptake and ATP production. Cell Calcium. 2011;49(4):217&#x2010;225.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Q, Vande Velde C, Israelson A, et al. ALS&#x2010;linked mutant superoxide dismutase 1 (SOD1) alters mitochondrial protein composition and decreases protein import. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2010;107(49):21146&#x2010;21151.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li N, Ragheb K, Lawler G, et al. Mitochondrial complex I inhibitor rotenone induces apoptosis through enhancing mitochondrial reactive oxygen species production. J Biol Chem. 2003;278(10):8516&#x2010;8525.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dlaskov&#xe1; A, Hlavat&#xe1; L, Je&#x17e;ek J, Je&#x17e;ek P. Mitochondrial complex I superoxide production is attenuated by uncoupling. Int J Biochem Cell Biol. 2008;40(10):2098&#x2010;2109.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Detmer SA, Chan DC. Functions and dysfunctions of mitochondrial dynamics. Nat Rev Mol Cell Biol. 2007;8(11):870&#x2010;879.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coates JR, Wininger FA. Canine degenerative myelopathy. Vet Clin North Am Small Anim Pract. 2010;40(5):929&#x2010;950.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abu&#x2010;Hamad S, Kahn J, Leyton&#x2010;Jaimes MF, Rosenblatt J, Israelson A. Misfolded SOD1 accumulation and mitochondrial association contribute to the selective vulnerability of motor neurons in familial ALS: correlation to human disease. ACS Chem Neurosci. 2017;8(10):2225&#x2010;2234.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raimondi A, Mangolini A, Rizzardini M, et al. Cell culture models to investigate the selective vulnerability of motoneuronal mitochondria to familial ALS&#x2010;linked G93ASOD1. Eur J Neurosci. 2006;24(2):387&#x2010;399.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Votion D&#x2010;M, Gnaiger E, Lemieux H, Mouithys&#x2010;Mickalad A, Serteyn D. Physical fitness and mitochondrial respiratory capacity in horse skeletal muscle. PLoS ONE. 2012;7(4):e34890.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee D&#x2010;Y, Jeon GS, Shim Y&#x2010;M, Seong S&#x2010;Y, Lee K&#x2010;W, Sung J&#x2010;J. Modulation of SOD1 subcellular localization by transfection with wild&#x2010; or mutant&#x2010;type SOD1 in primary neuron and astrocyte cultures from ALS mice. Exp Neurobiol. 2015;24(3):226&#x2010;234.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milani P, Gagliardi S, Cova E, Cereda C. SOD1 transcriptional and posttranscriptional regulation and its potential implications in ALS. Neurol Res Int. 2011;2011:458427.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ge W&#x2010;W, Leystra&#x2010;Lantz C, Sanelli TR, et al. Neuronal tissue&#x2010;specific ribonucleoprotein complex formation on SOD1 mRNA: alterations by ALS SOD1 mutations. Neurobiol Dis. 2006;23(2):342&#x2010;350.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berglund AC, et al. RBPDB: The Database of RNA&#x2010;binding Specificities; 2018. Available from: http://rbpdb.ccbr.utoronto.ca/index.php.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung C&#x2010;Y, Berson A, Kennerdell JR, et al. Aberrant activation of non&#x2010;coding RNA targets of transcriptional elongation complexes contributes to TDP&#x2010;43 toxicity. Nat Commun. 2018;9(1):4406&#x2010;4418.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodwin M, Mohan A, Batra R, et al. MBNL sequestration by toxic RNAs and RNA misprocessing in the myotonic dystrophy brain. Cell Rep. 2015;12(7):1159&#x2010;1168.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>