<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">31943276</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>25</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-4598</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>62</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Muscle &amp; nerve</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Muscle Nerve</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Small fiber neuropathy in unexpected clinical settings: a review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>167</StartPage><EndPage>175</EndPage><MedlinePgn>167-175</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/mus.26808</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Small fiber neuropathy (SFN) is being recognized with increasing frequency in neuromuscular practice due to improved diagnostic techniques. Although there are some common etiologies, up to one-third of cases are considered idiopathic. In recent years, several disorders have unexpectedly been reported in association with SFN, on clinical grounds and complementary investigations, including quantitative sensory testing, intraepidermal nerve fiber density and confocal corneal microscopy. Knowledge of these disorders is important in clinical practice as increased awareness enables prompt diagnosis of SFN in these settings and early optimal therapeutic management of affected patients. Furthermore, these new developments may lead to a better understanding of the pathophysiologic mechanisms underlying SFN in these different disorders as well as, in some cases, an expanded spectrum of affected organs and systems. This article reviews these reported associations, their possible pathophysiologic bases, and the potential resulting management implications.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020 Wiley Periodicals, Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ghasemi</LastName><ForeName>Majid</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Regional Neuromuscular Service, University Hospitals Birmingham, Birmingham, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, School of Medicine, Isfahan University of Medical Sciences, Isfahan, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rajabally</LastName><ForeName>Yusuf A</ForeName><Initials>YA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Regional Neuromuscular Service, University Hospitals Birmingham, Birmingham, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Aston Medical School, Aston University, Birmingham, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Muscle Nerve</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7803146</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0148-639X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D053918">Papillomavirus Vaccines</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="Y">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001706" MajorTopicYN="N">Biopsy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003315" MajorTopicYN="N">Cornea</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000294" MajorTopicYN="N">innervation</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004535" MajorTopicYN="N">Ehlers-Danlos Syndrome</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004817" MajorTopicYN="N">Epidermis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000294" MajorTopicYN="N">innervation</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005071" MajorTopicYN="N">Evoked Potentials</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005356" MajorTopicYN="N">Fibromyalgia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="Y">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020275" MajorTopicYN="N">Guillain-Barre Syndrome</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="Y">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020961" MajorTopicYN="N">Lewy Body Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018613" MajorTopicYN="N">Microscopy, Confocal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D036421" MajorTopicYN="N">Nerve Fibers, Unmyelinated</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053918" MajorTopicYN="N">Papillomavirus Vaccines</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010300" MajorTopicYN="N">Parkinson Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="Y">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020277" MajorTopicYN="N">Polyradiculoneuropathy, Chronic Inflammatory Demyelinating</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="Y">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011601" MajorTopicYN="N">Psychophysics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020187" MajorTopicYN="N">REM Sleep Behavior Disorder</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000071075" MajorTopicYN="N">Small Fiber Neuropathy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000139" MajorTopicYN="N">chemically induced</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="Y">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ehlers Danlos syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Parkinson disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">REM sleep behavior disorder</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">inflammatory neuropathy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">small fiber neuropathy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">vaccination</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31943276</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.26808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Hoeijmakers JG, Faber CG, Lauria G, Merkies IS, Waxman SG. Small-fibre neuropathies--advances in diagnosis, pathophysiology and management. Nat Rev Neurol. 2012;8(7):369-379.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wooten M, Weng HJ, Hartke TV, et al. Three functionally distinct classes of C-fibre nociceptors in primates. Nat Commun. 2014;5:4122.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gasser HS. The classification of nerve fibers. Ohio J Sci. 1941;41:145-159.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peters MJ, Bakkers M, Merkies IS, Hoeijmakers JG, van Raak EP, Faber CG. Incidence and prevalence of small-fiber neuropathy: a survey in the Netherlands. Neurology. 2013;81(15):1356-1360.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke JF, Skolarus LE, Callaghan BC, Kerber KA. Choosing Wisely: highest-cost tests in outpatient neurology. Ann Neurol. 2013;73(5):679-683.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouhassira D, Lant&#xe9;ri-Minet M, Attal N, Laurent B, Touboul C. Prevalence of chronic pain with neuropathic characteristics in the general population. Pain. 2008;136(3):380-387.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uceyler N, Kafke W, Riediger N, et al. Elevated proinflammatory cytokine expression in affected skin in small fiber neuropathy. Neurology. 2010;74(22):1806-1813.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cunha FQ, Poole S, Lorenzetti BB, Ferreira SH. The pivotal role of tumour necrosis factor alpha in the development of inflammatory hyperalgesia. Br J Pharmacol. 1992;107(3):660-664.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russell FA, Fernandes ES, Courade JP, Keeble JE, Brain SD. Tumour necrosis factor alpha mediates transient receptor potential vanilloid 1-dependent bilateral thermal hyperalgesia with distinct peripheral roles of interleukin-1beta, protein kinase C and cyclooxygenase-2 signalling. Pain. 2009;142(3):264-274.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bednarik J, Vlckova-Moravcova E, Bursova S, Belobradkova J, Dusek L, Sommer C. Etiology of small-fiber neuropathy. J Peripher Nerv Syst. 2009;14(3):177-183.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devigili G, Tugnoli V, Penza P, et al. The diagnostic criteria for small fibre neuropathy: from symptoms to neuropathology. Brain. 2008;131(Pt 7):1912-1925.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emery EC, Luiz AP, Wood JN. Nav1.7 and other voltage-gated sodium channels as drug targets for pain relief. Expert Opin Ther Targets. 2016;20(8):975-983.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Greef BTA, Hoeijmakers JGJ, Gorissen-Brouwers CML, Geerts M, Faber CG, Merkies ISJ. Associated conditions in small fiber neuropathy - a large cohort study and review of the literature. Eur J Neurol. 2018;25(2):348-355.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P T. Quantitative Sensory Testing. In: Bashar K, Kaminski HJ, Ruff R, eds. Neuromuscular Disorders in Clinical Practice. New York: Springer Science + Business Media; 2014:223-233.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lauria G, Hsieh ST, Johansson O, et al. European Federation of Neurological Societies/Peripheral Nerve Society Guideline on the use of skin biopsy in the diagnosis of small fiber neuropathy. Report of a joint task force of the European Federation of Neurological Societies and the Peripheral Nerve Society. Eur J Neurol. 2010;17(7):903-912, e44-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lauria G, Bakkers M, Schmitz C, et al. Intraepidermal nerve fiber density at the distal leg: a worldwide normative reference study. J Peripher Nerv Syst. 2010;15(3):202-207.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petropoulos IN, Ponirakis G, Khan A, et al. Corneal confocal microscopy: ready for prime time. Clin Exp Optom. 2019. https://doi.org/10.1111/cxo.12887.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gemignani F. Small fiber neuropathy or small fiber pathology? Pain. 2017;158(5):988-989.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uceyler N. Small fiber pathology--a culprit for many painful disorders? Pain. 2016;157(Suppl 1):S60-S66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibbons CH, Schmidt P, Biaggioni I, et al. The recommendations of a consensus panel for the screening, diagnosis, and treatment of neurogenic orthostatic hypotension and associated supine hypertension. J Neurol. 2017;264:1567-1582.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolfe F, Clauw DJ, Fitzcharles MA, et al. The American College of Rheumatology preliminary diagnostic criteria for fibromyalgia and measurement of symptom severity. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken). 2010;62(5):600-610.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarzi-Puttini P, Atzeni FJA. Fibromyalgia: a never-ending story of central and peripheral pain mechanisms. Arthritis Rheumatol. 2014;66(7):1687-1688.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jensen KB, Loitoile R, Kosek E, et al. Patients with fibromyalgia display less functional connectivity in the brain's pain inhibitory network. Mol Pain. 2012;8:32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim SH. Skin biopsy findings: implications for the pathophysiology of fibromyalgia. Med Hypotheses. 2007;69(1):141-144.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giannoccaro MP, Donadio V, Incensi A, Avoni P, Liguori R. Small nerve fiber involvement in patients referred for fibromyalgia. Muscle Nerve. 2014;49(5):757-759.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caro XJ, Winter EF. Dumas AJ. A subset of fibromyalgia patients have findings suggestive of chronic inflammatory demyelinating polyneuropathy and appear to respond to IVIg. Rheumatology (Oxford). 2008;47(2):208-211.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uceyler N, Zeller D, Kahn AK, et al. Small fibre pathology in patients with fibromyalgia syndrome. Brain. 2013;136(Pt 6):1857-1867.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kosmidis ML, Koutsogeorgopoulou L, Alexopoulos H, et al. Reduction of Intraepidermal Nerve Fiber Density (IENFD) in the skin biopsies of patients with fibromyalgia: a controlled study. J Neurol Sci. 2014;347(1-2):143-147.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caro XJ, Winter EF. Evidence of abnormal epidermal nerve fiber density in fibromyalgia: clinical and immunologic implications. Arthritis Rheum (Hoboken). 2014;66(7):1945-1954.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doppler K, Rittner HL, Deckart M, Sommer C. Reduced dermal nerve fiber diameter in skin biopsies of patients with fibromyalgia. Pain. 2015;156(11):2319-2325.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawson VH, Grewal J, Hackshaw KV, Mongiovi PC, Stino AM. Fibromyalgia syndrome and small fiber, early or mild sensory polyneuropathy. Muscle Nerve. 2018;58(5):625-630.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lodahl M, Treister R, Oaklander AL. Specific symptoms may discriminate between fibromyalgia patients with vs without objective test evidence of small-fiber polyneuropathy. Pain Rep. 2018;3(1):e633.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oudejans L, He X, Niesters M, Dahan A, Brines M, van Velzen M. Cornea nerve fiber quantification and construction of phenotypes in patients with fibromyalgia. Sci Rep. 2016;6:23573.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramirez M, Martinez-Martinez LA, Hernandez-Quintela E, Velazco-Casapia J, Vargas A, Martinez-Lavin M. Small fiber neuropathy in women with fibromyalgia. An in vivo assessment using corneal confocal bio-microscopy. Semin Arthritis Rheum. 2015;45(2):214-219.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erkan Turan K, Kocabeyoglu S, Unal-Cevik I, Bezci F, Akinci A, Irkec M. Ocular surface alterations in the context of corneal in vivo confocal microscopic characteristics in patients with fibromyalgia. Cornea. 2018;37(2):205-210.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leinders M, Doppler K, Klein T, et al. Increased cutaneous miR-let-7d expression correlates with small nerve fiber pathology in patients with fibromyalgia syndrome. Pain. 2016;157(11):2493-2503.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evdokimov D, Frank J, Klitsch A, et al. Reduction of skin innervation is associated with a severe fibromyalgia phenotype. Ann Neurol. 2019;86(4):504-516.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grayston R, Czanner G, Elhadd K, et al. A systematic review and meta-analysis of the prevalence of small fiber pathology in fibromyalgia: implications for a new paradigm in fibromyalgia etiopathogenesis. Semin Arthritis Rheum. 2019;48(5):933-940.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sluka KA, Clauw DJ. Neurobiology of fibromyalgia and chronic widespread pain. Neuroscience. 2016;338:114-129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oaklander AL, Herzog ZD, Downs HM, Klein MM. Objective evidence that small-fiber polyneuropathy underlies some illnesses currently labeled as fibromyalgia. Pain. 2013;154(11):2310-2316.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>UKPDS. Intensive blood-glucose control with sulphonylureas or insulin compared with conventional treatment and risk of complications in patients with type 2 diabetes (UKPDS 33). UK Prospective Diabetes Study (UKPDS) Group. Lancet. 1998;352(9131):837-853.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaudhuri KR, Healy DG, Schapira AHJTLN. Non-motor symptoms of Parkinson's disease: diagnosis and management. Lancet Neurol. 2006;5(3):235-245.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajabally YA, Martey JJN. Neuropathy in Parkinson disease: prevalence and determinants. Neurology. 2011;77(22):1947-1950.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf6;kk JJL. Treatment with levodopa can affect latent vitamin B 12 and folic acid deficiency. Patients with Parkinson disease runt the risk of elevated homocysteine levels. 2003;100(35):2674-2677.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calzetti S, Bellanova MF, Negrotti A, Saccani E, Capozzi A, Pietrini V. Non-length-dependent somatosensory small fiber pathology presenting with restless legs syndrome in pre-motor Parkinson's disease. Evidence from skin biopsy in four patients. J Clin Neurosci. 2019;69:139-142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adewusi JK, Hadjivassiliou M, Vinagre-Arag&#xf3;n A, et al. Peripheral neuropathic pain in idiopathic Parkinson's disease: prevalence and impact on quality of life; a case controlled study. J Neurol Sci. 2018;392:3-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nolano M, Provitera V, Estraneo A, et al. Sensory deficit in Parkinson's disease: evidence of a cutaneous denervation. Brain. 2008;131(Pt 7):1903-1911.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin CH, Chao CC, Wu SW, et al. Pathophysiology of small-fiber sensory system in Parkinson's disease: skin innervation and contact heat evoked potential. Medicine. 2016;95(10):e3058.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Podgorny PJ, Suchowersky O, Romanchuk KG, Feasby TE. Evidence for small fiber neuropathy in early Parkinson's disease. Parkinsonism Relat Disord. 2016;28:94-99.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kass-Iliyya L, Javed S, Gosal D, et al. Small fiber neuropathy in Parkinson's disease: a clinical, pathological and corneal confocal microscopy study. Parkinsonism Relat Disord. 2015;21(12):1454-1460.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nolano M, Provitera V, Manganelli F, et al. Loss of cutaneous large and small fibers in naive and l-dopa-treated PD patients. Neurology. 2017;89(8):776-784.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang N, Gibbons CH, Lafo J. Freeman R. alpha-Synuclein in cutaneous autonomic nerves. Neurology. 2013;81(18):1604-1610.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dauvilliers Y, Schenck CH, Postuma RB, et al. REM sleep behaviour disorder. Nat Rev Dis Primers. 2018;4(1):19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donadio V, Doppler K, Incensi A, et al. Abnormal alpha-synuclein deposits in skin nerves: intra- and inter-laboratory reproducibility. Eur J Neurol. 2019;26:1245-1251.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strobel AV, Tankisi H, Finnerup NB, et al. Somatosensory function is impaired in patients with idiopathic REM sleep behaviour disorder. Sleep Med. 2018;42:83-89.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schrempf W, Katona I, Dogan I, et al. Reduced intraepidermal nerve fiber density in patients with REM sleep behavior disorder. Parkinsonism Relat Disord. 2016;29:10-16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hammad M, Silva A, Glass J, Sladky J, Benatar MJN. Clinical, electrophysiologic, and pathologic evidence for sensory abnormalities in ALS. Neurology. 2007;69(24):2236-2242.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishida N, Hongo S, Kumano A, et al. Relationship between pain and functional status in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a multicenter cross-sectional study. J Palliat Med. 2018;21(5):588-591.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chio A, Canosa A, Gallo S, et al. Pain in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a population-based controlled study. Eur J Neurol. 2012;19(4):551-555.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chio A, Mora G, Lauria G. Pain in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet Neurol. 2017;16(2):144-157.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerkhoff H, Jennekens FG, Troost D, Veldman H. Nerve growth factor receptor immunostaining in the spinal cord and peripheral nerves in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathol. 1991;81(6):649-656.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luigetti M, Conte A, Del Grande A, Bisogni G, Romano A, Sabatelli M. Sural nerve pathology in ALS patients: a single-centre experience. Neurol Sci. 2012;33(5):1095-1099.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hammad M, Silva A, Glass J, Sladky JT, Benatar M. Clinical, electrophysiologic, and pathologic evidence for sensory abnormalities in ALS. Neurology. 2007;69(24):2236-2242.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weis J, Katona I, Muller-Newen G, et al. Small-fiber neuropathy in patients with ALS. Neurology. 2011;76(23):2024-2029.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Truini A, Biasiotta A, Onesti E, et al. Small-fibre neuropathy related to bulbar and spinal-onset in patients with ALS. J Neurol. 2015;262(4):1014-1018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dalla Bella E, Lombardi R, Porretta-Serapiglia C, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis causes small fiber pathology. Eur J Neurol. 2016;23(2):416-420.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren Y, Liu W, Li Y, et al. Cutaneous somatic and autonomic nerve TDP-43 deposition in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol. 2018;265(8):1753-1763.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrari G, Grisan E, Scarpa F, et al. Corneal confocal microscopy reveals trigeminal small sensory fiber neuropathy in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Front Aging Neurosci. 2014;6:278.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beighton P, De Paepe A, Steinmann B, Tsipouras P, Wenstrup RJ. Ehlers-Danlos syndromes: revised nosology, Villefranche, 1997. Ehlers-Danlos National Foundation (USA) and Ehlers-Danlos Support Group (UK). Am J Med Genet. 1998;77(1):31-37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Camerota F, Celletti C, Castori M, Grammatico P, Padua L. Neuropathic pain is a common feature in Ehlers-Danlos syndrome. J Pain Symptom Manag. 2011;41(1):e2-e4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rombaut L, Scheper M, De Wandele I, et al. Chronic pain in patients with the hypermobility type of Ehlers-Danlos syndrome: evidence for generalized hyperalgesia. Clin Rheumatol. 2015;34(6):1121-1129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cazzato D, Castori M, Lombardi R, et al. Small fiber neuropathy is a common feature of Ehlers-Danlos syndromes. Neurology. 2016;87(2):155-159.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez-Galan MA, Perez-Vilar S, Diez-Domingo J, et al. Adverse reactions to human papillomavirus vaccine in the Valencian Community (2007-2011). An Pediatr (Barc). 2014;81(5):303-309.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blitshteyn S. Postural tachycardia syndrome following human papillomavirus vaccination. Eur J Neurol. 2014;21(1):135-139.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souayah N, Ajroud-Driss S, Sander HW, Brannagan TH, Hays AP, Chin RL. Small fiber neuropathy following vaccination for rabies, varicella or Lyme disease. Vaccine. 2009;27(52):7322-7325.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibbels E, Kentenich M. Unmyelinated fibers in sural nerve biopsies of chronic inflammatory demyelinating polyneuropathy. Acta Neuropathol. 1990;80(4):439-447.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schneider C, Bucher F, Cursiefen C, Fink GR, Heindl LM, Lehmann HC. Corneal confocal microscopy detects small fiber damage in chronic inflammatory demyelinating polyneuropathy (CIDP). J Peripher Nerv Syst. 2014;19(4):322-327.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martinez V, Fletcher D, Martin F, et al. Small fibre impairment predicts neuropathic pain in Guillain-Barre syndrome. Pain. 2010;151(1):53-60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomaides TN, Kerezoudi EP, Zoukos Y, Chaudhuri KR. Thermal thresholds and motor sensory conduction measurements in Guillain Barre syndrome: 12-month follow-up study. Eur Neurol. 1992;32(5):274-280.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan CL, Tseng TJ, Lin YH, Chiang MC, Lin WM, Hsieh ST. Cutaneous innervation in Guillain-Barre syndrome: pathology and clinical correlations. Brain. 2003;126(Pt 2):386-397.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seneviratne U, Gunasekera S. Acute small fibre sensory neuropathy: another variant of Guillain-Barre syndrome? J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2002;72(4):540-542.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiang MC, Lin YH, Pan CL, Tseng TJ, Lin WM, Hsieh ST. Cutaneous innervation in chronic inflammatory demyelinating polyneuropathy. Neurology. 2002;59(7):1094-1098.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Figueroa JJ, Dyck PJ, Laughlin RS, et al. Autonomic dysfunction in chronic inflammatory demyelinating polyradiculoneuropathy. Neurology. 2012;78(10):702-708.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luigetti M, Madia F, Conte A, Tonali P, Sabatelli M. Neuropathy with predominant small fiber involvement associated with abnormal anti-MAG titer. Internal Med. 2010;49(23):2627-2629.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajabally YA, Delmont E, Hiew FL, et al. Prevalence, correlates and impact of pain and cramps in anti-MAG neuropathy: a multicentre European study. Eur J Neurol. 2018;25(1):135-141.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emery EC, Young GT, Berrocoso EM, Chen L, McNaughton PA. HCN2 ion channels play a central role in inflammatory and neuropathic pain. Science. 2011;333(6048):1462-1466.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han C, Hoeijmakers JG, Ahn HS, et al. Nav1.7-related small fiber neuropathy: impaired slow-inactivation and DRG neuron hyperexcitability. Neurology. 2012;78(21):1635-1643.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klein CJ, Lennon VA, Aston PA, McKeon A, Pittock SJ. Chronic pain as a manifestation of potassium channel-complex autoimmunity. Neurology. 2012;79(11):1136-1144.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Favoni V, Liguori R, Incensi A, Fileccia E, Donadio V. The incidental finding of elevated anti GQ1B antibodies in a patient with selective small fiber neuropathy. J Neurol Sci. 2018;388:192-194.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giannoccaro MP, Donadio V, Incensi A, et al. Skin biopsy and I-123 MIBG scintigraphy findings in idiopathic Parkinson's disease and parkinsonism: a comparative study. Mov Disord. 2015;30(7):986-989.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dabby R, Djaldetti R, Shahmurov M, et al. Skin biopsy for assessment of autonomic denervation in Parkinson's disease. J Neural Transm. 2006;113(9):1169-1176.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nolano M, Provitera V, Stancanelli A, et al. Small fiber pathology parallels disease progression in Parkinson disease: a longitudinal study. Acta Neuropathol. 2018;136(3):501-503.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sassone J, Taiana M, Lombardi R, et al. ALS mouse model SOD1G93A displays early pathology of sensory small fibers associated to accumulation of a neurotoxic splice variant of peripherin. Hum Mol Genet. 2016;25(8):1588-1599.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>