<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">31954073</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>21</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1460-9568</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>52</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The European journal of neuroscience</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Neurosci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The influence of metallothionein treatment and treadmill running exercise on disease onset and survival in SOD1<sup>G93A</sup> amyotrophic lateral sclerosis mice.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>3223</StartPage><EndPage>3241</EndPage><MedlinePgn>3223-3241</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/ejn.14682</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) is a fatal neurodegenerative disease, characterised by the degeneration of motor neurons innervating skeletal muscle. The mechanisms underlying neurodegeneration in ALS are not yet fully elucidated, and with current therapeutics only able to extend lifespan by a matter of months there is a clear need for novel therapies to increase lifespan and patient quality of life. Here, we evaluated whether moderate-intensity treadmill exercise and/or treatment with metallothionein-2 (MT2), a neuroprotective protein, could improve survival, behavioural or neuropathological outcomes in SOD1<sup>G93A</sup> familial ALS mice. Six-week-old female SOD1<sup>G93A</sup> mice were allocated to one of four treatment groups: MT2 injection, i.m.; moderate treadmill exercise; neither MT2 nor exercise; or both MT2 and exercise. MT2-treated mice survived around 3% longer than vehicle-treated mice, with this mild effect reaching statistical significance in Cox proportional hazards analysis once adjusted for potential confounders. Mixed model body weight trajectories over time indicated that MT2-treated mice, with or without exercise, reached maximum body weight at a later age, suggesting a delay in disease onset of around 4% compared to saline-treated mice. Exercise alone did not significantly increase survival or delay disease onset, and neither exercise nor MT2 substantially ameliorated gait abnormalities or muscle strength loss. We conclude that neither exercise nor MT2 treatment was detrimental in female SOD1<sup>G93A</sup> mice, and further study could determine whether the mild effect of peripheral MT2 administration on disease onset and survival could be improved via direct administration of MT2 to the central nervous system.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020 Federation of European Neuroscience Societies and John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lewis</LastName><ForeName>Katherine E A</ForeName><Initials>KEA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1264-464X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, University of Tasmania, Hobart, TAS, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wicking Dementia Research and Education Centre, University of Tasmania, Hobart, TAS, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bennett</LastName><ForeName>William</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, University of Tasmania, Hobart, TAS, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wicking Dementia Research and Education Centre, University of Tasmania, Hobart, TAS, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Blizzard</LastName><ForeName>Christopher L</ForeName><Initials>CL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Menzies Institute for Medical Research, University of Tasmania, Hobart, TAS, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>West</LastName><ForeName>Adrian K</ForeName><Initials>AK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, University of Tasmania, Hobart, TAS, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wicking Dementia Research and Education Centre, University of Tasmania, Hobart, TAS, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chung</LastName><ForeName>Roger S</ForeName><Initials>RS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Australian School of Advanced Medicine, Macquarie University, Sydney, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chuah</LastName><ForeName>Meng Inn</ForeName><Initials>MI</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, University of Tasmania, Hobart, TAS, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wicking Dementia Research and Education Centre, University of Tasmania, Hobart, TAS, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>Motor Neurone Disease Research Institute of Australia</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>France</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Neurosci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8918110</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0953-816X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>9038-94-2</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D008668">Metallothionein</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 1.15.1.1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000072105">Superoxide Dismutase-1</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004195" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Models, Animal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008668" MajorTopicYN="N">Metallothionein</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051379" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008822" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice, Transgenic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010805" MajorTopicYN="Y">Physical Conditioning, Animal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000072105" MajorTopicYN="Y">Superoxide Dismutase-1</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">antioxidant</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">metallothionein-2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mixed modelling</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neurodegeneration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">treadmill exercise</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31954073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ejn.14682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Ambjorn, M., Asmussen, J. W., Lindstam, M., Gotfryd, K., Jacobsen, C., Kiselyov, V. V., &#x2026; Berezin, V. (2008). Metallothionein and a peptide modeled after metallothionein, EmtinB, induce neuronal differentiation and survival through binding to receptors of the low-density lipoprotein receptor family. Journal of Neurochemistry, 104, 21-37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aschner, M. (1996). The functional significance of brain metallothioneins. The FASEB Journal, 10, 1129-1136. https://doi.org/10.1096/fasebj.10.10.8751715</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asmussen, J. W., Ambjorn, M., Bock, E., &amp; Berezin, V. (2009). Peptides modeled after the alpha-domain of metallothionein induce neurite outgrowth and promote survival of cerebellar granule neurons. European Journal of Cell Biology, 88, 433-443.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asmussen, J. W., Von Sperling, M. L., &amp; Penkowa, M. (2009). Intraneuronal signaling pathways of metallothionein. Journal of Neuroscience Research, 87, 2926-2936. https://doi.org/10.1002/jnr.22118</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barber, S. C., Mead, R. J., &amp; Shaw, P. J. (2006). Oxidative stress in ALS: A mechanism of neurodegeneration and a therapeutic target. Biochimica et Biophysica Acta, 1762, 1051-1067. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bbadis.2006.03.008</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beers, D. R., Henkel, J. S., Zhao, W., Wang, J., Huang, A., Wen, S., &#x2026; Appel, S. H. (2011). Endogenous regulatory T lymphocytes ameliorate amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in mice and correlate with disease progression in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain, 134, 1293-1314. https://doi.org/10.1093/brain/awr074</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beghi, E., Logroscino, G., Chio, A., Hardiman, O., Millul, A., Mitchell, D., &#x2026; Traynor, B. J. (2010). Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, physical exercise, trauma and sports: Results of a population-based pilot case-control study. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis, 11, 289-292. https://doi.org/10.3109/17482960903384283</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bensimon, G., Lacomblez, L., &amp; Meininger, V. (1994). A controlled trial of riluzole in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. ALS/Riluzole study group. New England Journal of Medicine, 330, 585-591. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJM199403033300901</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown, R. H., &amp; Al-Chalabi, A. (2017). Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. New England Journal of Medicine, 377, 162-172. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJMra1603471</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carreras, I., Yuruker, S., Aytan, N., Hossain, L., Choi, J.-K., Jenkins, B. G., &#x2026; Dedeoglu, A. (2010). Moderate exercise delays the motor performance decline in a transgenic model of ALS. Brain Research, 1313, 192-201. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.brainres.2009.11.051</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2;, A., Logroscino, G., Hardiman, O., Swingler, R., Mitchell, D., Beghi, E., &#x2026; On Behalf of the Eurals Consortium. (2009). Prognostic factors in ALS: A critical review. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis, 10, 310-323. https://doi.org/10.3109/17482960802566824</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chio, A., &amp; Mora, G. (2012). Physical fitness and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Dangerous liaisons or common genetic pathways? Journal of Neurology, Neurosurgery and Psychiatry, 83, 389. https://doi.org/10.1136/jnnp-2012-302351</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung, R. S., Adlard, P. A., Dittmann, J., Vickers, J. C., Chuah, M. I., &amp; West, A. K. (2004). Neuron-glia communication: Metallothionein expression is specifically up-regulated by astrocytes in response to neuronal injury. Journal of Neurochemistry, 88, 454-461. https://doi.org/10.1046/j.1471-4159.2003.02193.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung, R. S., Dittmann, J., Chuah, M. I., Vickers, J. C., &amp; West, A. K. (2004). Neuron-astrocyte signalling regulates astrocytic expression of neuroprotective metallothionein protein following neuronal injury. Journal of Neurochemistry, 88, 18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung, R. S., Penkowa, M., Dittmann, J., King, C. E., Bartlett, C., Asmussen, J. W., &#x2026; West, A. K. (2008). Redefining the role of metallothionein within the injured brain: Extracellular metallothioneins play an important role in the astrocyte-neuron response to injury. Journal of Biological Chemistry, 283, 15349-15358. https://doi.org/10.1074/jbc.M708446200</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung, R. S., Vickers, J. C., Chuah, M. I., &amp; West, A. K. (2003). Metallothionein-IIa promotes initial neurite elongation and postinjury reactive neurite growth and facilitates healing after focal cortical brain injury. Journal of Neuroscience, 23, 3336-3342. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.23-08-03336.2003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cousins, R. J., &amp; Leinart, A. S. (1988). Tissue-specific regulation of zinc metabolism and metallothionein genes by interleukin 1. The FASEB Journal, 2, 2884-2890. https://doi.org/10.1096/fasebj.2.13.2458983</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cox, P. A., Richer, R., Metcalf, J. S., Banack, S. A., Codd, G. A., &amp; Bradley, W. G. (2009). Cyanobacteria and BMAA exposure from desert dust: A possible link to sporadic ALS among Gulf War veterans. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis, 10(Suppl 2), 109-117. https://doi.org/10.3109/17482960903286066</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cruz, M. P. (2018). Edaravone (Radicava): A novel neuroprotective agent for the treatment of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. P &amp; T, 43, 25-28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dal Bello-Haas, V., Florence, J. M., Kloos, A. D., Scheirbecker, J., Lopate, G., Hayes, S. M., &#x2026; Mitsumoto, H. (2007). A randomized controlled trial of resistance exercise in individuals with ALS. Neurology, 68, 2003-2007. https://doi.org/10.1212/01.wnl.0000264418.92308.a4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dal Bello-Haas, V., Florence, J. M., &amp; Krivickas, L. S. (2008). Therapeutic exercise for people with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis or motor neuron disease. Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews, CD005229.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D'Amico, E., Factor-Litvak, P., Santella, R. M., &amp; Mitsumoto, H. (2013). Clinical perspective on oxidative stress in sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Free Radical Biology &amp; Medicine, 65, 509-527. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.freeradbiomed.2013.06.029</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Almeida, J. P., Silvestre, R., Pinto, A. C., &amp; de Carvalho, M. (2012). Exercise and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurological Sciences, 33, 9-15. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10072-011-0921-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deforges, S., Branchu, J., Biondi, O., Grondard, C., Pariset, C., Lecolle, S., &#x2026; Charbonnier, F. (2009). Motoneuron survival is promoted by specific exercise in a mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Journal of Physiology, 587, 3561-3572. https://doi.org/10.1113/jphysiol.2009.169748</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desseille, C., Deforges, S., Biondi, O., Houdebine, L., D'Amico, D., Lamaziere, A., &#x2026; Charbonnier, F. (2017). Specific physical exercise improves energetic metabolism in the skeletal muscle of amyotrophic-lateral-sclerosis mice. Frontiers in Molecular Neuroscience, 10, 332. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnmol.2017.00332</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drory, V. E., Goltsman, E., Reznik, J. G., Mosek, A., &amp; Korczyn, A. D. (2001). The value of muscle exercise in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Journal of the Neurological Sciences, 191, 133-137. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0022-510X(01)00610-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebadi, M., Brown-Borg, H., El Refaey, H., Singh, B. B., Garrett, S., Shavali, S., &amp; Sharma, S. K. (2005). Metallothionein-mediated neuroprotection in genetically engineered mouse models of Parkinson's disease. Molecular Brain Research, 134, 67-75. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.molbrainres.2004.09.011</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edaravone ALS Study Group (2017). Safety and efficacy of edaravone in well defined patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. The Lancet Neurology, 16, 505-512.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fitzgerald, M., Nairn, P., Bartlett, C. A., Chung, R. S., West, A. K., &amp; Beazley, L. D. (2007). Metallothionein-IIA promotes neurite growth via the megalin receptor. Experimental Brain Research, 183, 171-180. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00221-007-1032-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garbuzova-Davis, S., Haller, E., Saporta, S., Kolomey, I., Nicosia, S. V., &amp; Sanberg, P. R. (2007). Ultrastructure of blood-brain barrier and blood-spinal cord barrier in SOD1 mice modeling ALS. Brain Research, 1157, 126-137. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.brainres.2007.04.044</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerber, Y. N., Sabourin, J. C., Hugnot, J. P., &amp; Perrin, F. E. (2012). Unlike physical exercise, modified environment increases the lifespan of SOD1G93A mice however both conditions induce cellular changes. PLoS ONE, 7, e45503. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0045503</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gong, Y. H., &amp; Elliott, J. L. (2000). Metallothionein expression is altered in a transgenic murine model of familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Experimental Neurology, 162, 27-36. https://doi.org/10.1006/exnr.2000.7323</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gurney, M. E., Pu, H., Chiu, A. Y., Dal Canto, M. C., Polchow, C. Y., Alexander, D. D., &#x2026; Siddique, T. (1994). Motor neuron degeneration in mice that express a human Cu, Zn superoxide dismutase mutation. Science, 264, 1772-1775. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.8209258</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hall, E. D., Oostveen, J. A., &amp; Gurney, M. E. (1998). Relationship of microglial and astrocytic activation to disease onset and progression in a transgenic model of familial ALS. Glia, 23, 249-256. https://doi.org/10.1002/(SICI)1098-1136(199807)23:3&lt;249:AID-GLIA7&gt;3.0.CO;2-#</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hashimoto, K., Hayashi, Y., Inuzuka, T., &amp; Hozumi, I. (2009). Exercise induces metallothioneins in mouse spinal cord. Neuroscience, 163, 244-251. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuroscience.2009.05.067</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heiman-Patterson, T. D., Deitch, J. S., Blankenhorn, E. P., Erwin, K. L., Perreault, M. J., Alexander, B. K., &#x2026; Alexander, G. M. (2005). Background and gender effects on survival in the TgN(SOD1-G93A)1Gur mouse model of ALS. Journal of the Neurological Sciences, 236, 1-7. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jns.2005.02.006</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herbert, R. P., Harris, J., Chong, K. P., Chapman, J., West, A. K., &amp; Chuah, M. I. (2012). Cytokines and olfactory bulb microglia in response to bacterial challenge in the compromised primary olfactory pathway. Journal of Neuroinflammation, 9, 109. https://doi.org/10.1186/1742-2094-9-109</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hozumi, I., Yamada, M., Uchida, Y., Ozawa, K., Takahashi, H., &amp; Inuzuka, T. (2008). The expression of metallothioneins is diminished in the spinal cords of patients with sporadic ALS. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis, 9, 294-298. https://doi.org/10.1080/17482960801934312</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huisman, M. H., Seelen, M., de Jong, S. W., Dorresteijn, K. R., van Doormaal, P. T., van der Kooi, A. J., &#x2026; Veldink, J. H. (2013). Lifetime physical activity and the risk of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Journal of Neurology, Neurosurgery and Psychiatry, 84, 976-981. https://doi.org/10.1136/jnnp-2012-304724</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Igaz, L. M., Kwong, L. K., Lee, E. B., Chen-Plotkin, A., Swanson, E., Unger, T., &#x2026; Lee, V. M. (2011). Dysregulation of the ALS-associated gene TDP-43 leads to neuronal death and degeneration in mice. Journal of Clinical Investigation, 121, 726-738. https://doi.org/10.1172/JCI44867</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaspar, B. K., Frost, L. M., Christian, L., Umapathi, P., &amp; Gage, F. H. (2005). Synergy of insulin-like growth factor-1 and exercise in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Annals of Neurology, 57, 649-655. https://doi.org/10.1002/ana.20451</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kassa, R. M., Bonafede, R., Boschi, F., Bentivoglio, M., &amp; Mariotti, R. (2017). Effect of physical exercise and anabolic steroid treatment on spinal motoneurons and surrounding glia of wild-type and ALS mice. Brain Research, 1657, 269-278. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.brainres.2016.12.029</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirkinezos, I. G., Hernandez, D., Bradley, W. G., &amp; Moraes, C. T. (2003). Regular exercise is beneficial to a mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Annals of Neurology, 53, 804-807. https://doi.org/10.1002/ana.10597</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lehman, E. J., Hein, M. J., Baron, S. L., &amp; Gersic, C. M. (2012). Neurodegenerative causes of death among retired National Football League players. Neurology, 79, 1970-1974. https://doi.org/10.1212/WNL.0b013e31826daf50</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leung, J. Y. K., Bennett, W. R., King, A. E., &amp; Chung, R. S. (2018). The impact of metallothionein-II on microglial response to tumor necrosis factor-alpha (TNFalpha) and downstream effects on neuronal regeneration. Journal of Neuroinflammation, 15, 56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leung, Y. K., Pankhurst, M., Dunlop, S. A., Ray, S., Dittmann, J., Eaton, E. D., &#x2026; Chung, R. S. (2010). Metallothionein induces a regenerative reactive astrocyte phenotype via JAK/STAT and RhoA signalling pathways. Experimental Neurology, 221, 98-106. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.expneurol.2009.10.006</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewis, K. E., Chung, R. S., West, A. K., &amp; Chuah, M. I. (2012). Distribution of exogenous metallothionein following intraperitoneal and intramuscular injection of metallothionein-deficient mice. Histology and Histopathology, 27, 1459-1470.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewis, K., Rasmussen, A., Bennett, W., King, A., West, A., Chung, R., &amp; Chuah, M. (2014). Microglia and motor neurons during disease progression in the SOD1G93A mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Changes in arginase1 and inducible nitric oxide synthase. Journal of Neuroinflammation, 11, 55. https://doi.org/10.1186/1742-2094-11-55</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liebetanz, D., Hagemann, K., von Lewinski, F., Kahler, E., &amp; Paulus, W. (2004). Extensive exercise is not harmful in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. European Journal of Neuroscience, 20, 3115-3120. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1460-9568.2004.03769.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahoney, D. J., Rodriguez, C., Devries, M., Yasuda, N., &amp; Tarnopolsky, M. A. (2004). Effects of high-intensity endurance exercise training in the G93A mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle and Nerve, 29, 656-662. https://doi.org/10.1002/mus.20004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manso, Y., Adlard, P. A., Carrasco, J., Vasak, M., &amp; Hidalgo, J. (2011). Metallothionein and brain inflammation. JBIC Journal of Biological Inorganic Chemistry, 16, 1103-1113. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00775-011-0802-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagano, S., Satoh, M., Sumi, H., Fujimura, H., Tohyama, C., Yanagihara, T., &amp; Sakoda, S. (2001). Reduction of metallothioneins promotes the disease expression of familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis mice in a dose-dependent manner. European Journal of Neuroscience, 13, 1363-1370. https://doi.org/10.1046/j.0953-816x.2001.01512.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ostrakhovitch, E. A., Olsson, P. E., Jiang, S., &amp; Cherian, M. G. (2006). Interaction of metallothionein with tumor suppressor p53 protein. FEBS Letters, 580, 1235-1238. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.febslet.2006.01.036</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puttaparthi, K., Gitomer, W. L., Krishnan, U., Son, M., Rajendran, B., &amp; Elliott, J. L. (2002). Disease progression in a transgenic model of familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis is dependent on both neuronal and non-neuronal zinc binding proteins. Journal of Neuroscience, 22, 8790-8796. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.22-20-08790.2002</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ravits, J., Appel, S., Baloh, R. H., Barohn, R., Brooks, B. R., Elman, L., &#x2026; Ringel, S. (2013). Deciphering amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: What phenotype, neuropathology and genetics are telling us about pathogenesis. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis and Frontotemporal Degeneration, 14(Suppl 1), 5-18. https://doi.org/10.3109/21678421.2013.778548</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richards, R. I., Heguy, A., &amp; Karin, M. (1984). Structural and functional analysis of the human metallothionein-IA gene: Differential induction by metal ions and glucocorticoids. Cell, 37, 263-272. https://doi.org/10.1016/0092-8674(84)90322-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roos, P. M., Vesterberg, O., &amp; Nordberg, M. (2006). Metals in motor neuron diseases. Experimental Biology and Medicine, 231, 1481-1487. https://doi.org/10.1177/153537020623100906</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanjak, M., Bravver, E., Bockenek, W. L., Norton, H. J., &amp; Brooks, B. R. (2010). Supported treadmill ambulation for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A pilot study. Archives of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, 91, 1920-1929. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apmr.2010.08.009</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schneider, C. A., Rasband, W. S., &amp; Eliceiri, K. W. (2012). NIH Image to ImageJ: 25 years of image analysis. Nature Methods, 9, 671-675. https://doi.org/10.1038/nmeth.2089</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott, S., Kranz, J. E., Cole, J., Lincecum, J. M., Thompson, K., Kelly, N., &#x2026; Heywood, J. A. (2008). Design, power, and interpretation of studies in the standard murine model of ALS. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis, 9, 4-15. https://doi.org/10.1080/17482960701856300</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sillevis Smitt, P. A., Blaauwgeers, H. G., Troost, D., &amp; de Jong, J. M. (1992). Metallothionein immunoreactivity is increased in the spinal cord of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuroscience Letters, 144, 107-110. https://doi.org/10.1016/0304-3940(92)90727-O</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sonn, K., Pankratova, S., Korshunova, I., Zharkovsky, A., Bock, E., Berezin, V., &amp; Kiryushko, D. (2010). A metallothionein mimetic peptide protects neurons against kainic acid-induced excitotoxicity. Journal of Neuroscience Research, 88, 1074-1082.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sorrells, A. D., Corcoran-Gomez, K., Eckert, K. A., Fahey, A. G., Hoots, B. L., Charleston, L. B., &#x2026; Markowitz, H. (2009). Effects of environmental enrichment on the amyotrophic lateral sclerosis mouse model. Laboratory Animals, 43, 182-190. https://doi.org/10.1258/la.2008.005090</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stam, N. C., Nithianantharajah, J., Howard, M. L., Atkin, J. D., Cheema, S. S., &amp; Hannan, A. J. (2008). Sex-specific behavioural effects of environmental enrichment in a transgenic mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. European Journal of Neuroscience, 28, 717-723. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1460-9568.2008.06374.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suzuki, K., &amp; Koizumi, S. (2000). Individual metal responsive elements of the human metallothionein-IIA gene independently mediate responses to various heavy metal signals. Industrial Health, 38, 87-90. https://doi.org/10.2486/indhealth.38.87</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tokuda, E., Okawa, E., Watanabe, S., &amp; Ono, S. I. (2014). Overexpression of metallothionein-I, a copper-regulating protein, attenuates intracellular copper dyshomeostasis and extends lifespan in a mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis caused by mutant superoxide dismutase-1. Human Molecular Genetics, 23, 1271-1285. https://doi.org/10.1093/hmg/ddt517</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tokuda, E., Ono, S., Ishige, K., Naganuma, A., Ito, Y., &amp; Suzuki, T. (2007). Metallothionein proteins expression, copper and zinc concentrations, and lipid peroxidation level in a rodent model for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Toxicology, 229, 33-41. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tox.2006.09.011</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tokuda, E., Watanabe, S., Okawa, E., &amp; Ono, S. (2015). Regulation of intracellular copper by induction of endogenous metallothioneins improves the disease course in a mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurotherapeutics, 12, 461-476. https://doi.org/10.1007/s13311-015-0346-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trendelenburg, G., Prass, K., Priller, J., Kapinya, K., Polley, A., Muselmann, C., &#x2026; Dirnagl, U. (2002). Serial analysis of gene expression identifies metallothionein-II as major neuroprotective gene in mouse focal cerebral ischemia. Journal of Neuroscience, 22, 5879-5888. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.22-14-05879.2002</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Lookeren Campagne, M., Thibodeaux, H., van Bruggen, N., Cairns, B., Gerlai, R., Palmer, J. T., &#x2026; Lowe, D. G. (1999). Evidence for a protective role of metallothionein-1 in focal cerebral ischemia. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 96, 12870-12875. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.96.22.12870</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Lookeren Campagne, M., Thibodeaux, H., van Bruggen, N., Cairns, B., &amp; Lowe, D. G. (2000). Increased binding activity at an antioxidant-responsive element in the metallothionein-1 promoter and rapid induction of metallothionein-1 and -2 in response to cerebral ischemia and reperfusion. Journal of Neuroscience, 20, 5200-5207. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.20-14-05200.2000</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veldink, J. H., Bar, P. R., Joosten, E. A., Otten, M., Wokke, J. H., &amp; van den Berg, L. H. (2003). Sexual differences in onset of disease and response to exercise in a transgenic model of ALS. Neuromuscular Disorders, 13, 737-743. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0960-8966(03)00104-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wegorzewska, I., Bell, S., Cairns, N. J., Miller, T. M., &amp; Baloh, R. H. (2009). TDP-43 mutant transgenic mice develop features of ALS and frontotemporal lobar degeneration. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 106, 18809-18814. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.0908767106</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weisskopf, M. G., O'Reilly, E. J., McCullough, M. L., Calle, E. E., Thun, M. J., Cudkowicz, M., &amp; Ascherio, A. (2005). Prospective study of military service and mortality from ALS. Neurology, 64, 32-37. https://doi.org/10.1212/01.WNL.0000148649.17706.D9</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>