<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">32000403</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>11</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-5964</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>99</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Medicine (Baltimore)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Differential role of triggering receptors expressed on myeloid cells 2 R47H in 3 neurodegenerative diseases based on a systematic review and meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e18921</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e18921</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e18921</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MD.0000000000018921</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Recent studies have suggested that the potential functional polymorphism R47H in triggering receptors expressed on myeloid cells 2 (TREM2) is associated with several neurodegenerative diseases, however, the results remain inconclusive. This meta-analysis aimed to investigate the association between TREM2 R47H and the risk for 3 typical neurodegenerative diseases: Alzheimer disease (AD), Parkinson disease (PD), and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A literature review was carried out using PubMed, Medline, and Embase. Data analysis was conducted using Stata 15.0 software. The pooled odds ratio (ORs) and 95% confidence interval (CIs) were calculated.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 35 articles were identified as eligible: 22 on AD, 3 on ALS, 7 on PD, 2 on AD and ALS, and 1 on ALS and PD. The AD set included 23,092 cases and 30,920 controls, the ALS set included 7391 cases and 12,442 controls, and the PD set included 8498 patients and 9161 controls. We found that R47H was associated with an increased risk of AD in the total pooled population (P&#x200a;&lt;&#x200a;.001, OR&#x200a;=&#x200a;4.02, 95% CI&#x200a;=&#x200a;3.15-5.13). However, this significant difference existed for Caucasian people (OR&#x200a;=&#x200a;4.16, 95% CI&#x200a;=&#x200a;3.24-5.33) but not for Asian or African people. Moreover, we did not find any significant differences in minor allele frequency distribution between the PD and control groups or between the ALS and control groups, not only for the total pooled population but also for the subgroups of different ethnicities.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Our study suggested that R47H in the TREM2 gene leads to an increased risk for developing AD, but not for ALS and PD, which adds evidence to the notion that diverse pathogenesis may be involved in different neurogenerative diseases.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Bin</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, the First Hospital of Yulin, Yulin, Shaanxi.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Rui</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, the First Hospital of Yulin, Yulin, Shaanxi.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Yufan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, the First Hospital of Yulin, Yulin, Shaanxi.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gao</LastName><ForeName>Xia</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Geriatrics, Dazhou Central Hospital, Dazhou, Sichuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Medicine (Baltimore)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>2985248R</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0025-7974</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D008562">Membrane Glycoproteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D011971">Receptors, Immunologic</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C498715">TREM2 protein, human</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000544" MajorTopicYN="N">Alzheimer Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="Y">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="Y">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020022" MajorTopicYN="N">Genetic Predisposition to Disease</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008562" MajorTopicYN="N">Membrane Glycoproteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="Y">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010300" MajorTopicYN="N">Parkinson Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="Y">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011110" MajorTopicYN="N">Polymorphism, Genetic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011971" MajorTopicYN="N">Receptors, Immunologic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="Y">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors have no conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32000403</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7004756</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000018921</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005792-202001310-00050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Scrivo A, Bourdenx M, Pampliega O, et al. Selective autophagy as a potential therapeutic target for neurodegenerative disorders. Lancet Neurol 2018;17:802&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6359907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30129476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lill CM, Bertram L. Towards unveiling the genetics of neurodegenerative diseases. Semin Neurol 2011;31:531&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22266890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakashima-Yasuda H, Uryu K, Robinson J, et al. Co-morbidity of TDP-43 proteinopathy in Lewy body related diseases. Acta Neuropathol 2007;114:221&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17653732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schafferer S, Khurana R, Refolo V, et al. Changes in the miRNA-mRNA regulatory network precede motor symptoms in a Mouse Model of Multiple System Atrophy: clinical implications. PLoS One 2016;11:e0150705.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4786272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26962858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mosca L, Lunetta C, Tarlarini C, et al. Wide phenotypic spectrum of the TARDBP gene: homozygosity of A382T mutation in a patient presenting with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, Parkinson's disease, and frontotemporal lobar degeneration, and in neurologically healthy subject. Neurobiol Aging 2012;33:1846.e1&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22398199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruiz A, Dols-Icardo O, Bullido MJ, et al. Assessing the role of the TREM2 p.R47H variant as a risk factor for Alzheimer's disease and frontotemporal dementia. Neurobiol Aging 2014;35:444.e1&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24041969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pottier C, Wallon D, Rousseau S, et al. TREM2 R47H variant as a risk factor for early-onset Alzheimer's disease. J Alzheimers Dis 2013;35:45&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23380991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guerreiro R, Wojtas A, Bras J, et al. TREM2 variants in Alzheimer's disease. N Engl J Med 2013;368:117&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3631573</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23150934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenthal SL, Bamne MN, Wang X, et al. More evidence for association of a rare TREM2 mutation (R47H) with Alzheimer's disease risk. Neurobiol Aging 2015;36:2443.e21&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4465085</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26058841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finelli D, Rollinson S, Harris J, et al. TREM2 analysis and increased risk of Alzheimer's disease. Neurobiol Aging 2015;36:546.e9&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25260849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuyvers E, Bettens K, Philtjens S, et al. Investigating the role of rare heterozygous TREM2 variants in Alzheimer's disease and frontotemporal dementia. Neurobiol Aging 2014;35:726.e11&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24119542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehrjoo Z, Najmabadi A, Abedini SS, et al. Association study of the TREM2 gene and identification of a novel variant in Exon 2 in Iranian patients with late-onset Alzheimer's disease. Med Princ Pract 2015;24:351&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5588241</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26021840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu JT, Jiang T, Wang YL, et al. Triggering receptor expressed on myeloid cells 2 variant is rare in late-onset Alzheimer's disease in Han Chinese individuals. Neurobiol Aging 2014;35:937.e1&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24184202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma J, Zhou Y, Xu J, et al. Association study of TREM2 polymorphism rs75932628 with late-onset Alzheimer's disease in Chinese Han population. Neurol Res 2014;36:894&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24725293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang P, Guo Q, Zhou Y, et al. Lack of association between triggering receptor expressed on myeloid cells 2 polymorphism rs75932628 and late-onset Alzheimer's disease in a Chinese Han population. Psychiatr Genet 2018;28:16&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5757673</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29256968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiao B, Liu X, Tang B, et al. Investigation of TREM2, PLD3, and UNC5C variants in patients with Alzheimer's disease from mainland China. Neurobiol Aging 2014;35:2422.e9&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24866402</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung SJ, Kim MJ, Kim J, et al. Exome array study did not identify novel variants in Alzheimer's disease. Neurobiol Aging 2014;35:1958.e13&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24685331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyashita A, Wen Y, Kitamura N, et al. Lack of genetic association between TREM2 and late-onset Alzheimer's disease in a Japanese population. J Alzheimers Dis 2014;41:1031&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24762945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jay TR, von Saucken VE, Landreth GE. TREM2 in neurodegenerative diseases. Mol Neurodegener 2017;12:56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5541421</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28768545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su WH, Shi ZH, Liu SL, et al. The rs75932628 and rs2234253 polymorphisms of the TREM2 gene were associated with susceptibility to frontotemporal lobar degeneration in Caucasian populations. Ann Hum Genet 2018;82:177&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29322490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogaki K, Heckman MG, Koga S, et al. Association study between multiple system atrophy and TREM2 p.R47H. Neurol Genet 2018;4:e257.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6089688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30109269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walton RL, Soto-Ortolaza AI, Murray ME, et al. TREM2 p.R47H substitution is not associated with dementia with Lewy bodies. Neurol Genet 2016;2:e85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4946771</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27458607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ortega-Cubero S, Lorenzo-Betancor O, Lorenzo E, et al. TREM2 R47H variant and risk of essential tremor: a cross-sectional international multicenter study. Parkinsonism Relat Disord 2015;21:306&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4408541</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25585992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peplonska B, Berdynski M, Mandecka M, et al. TREM2 variants in neurodegenerative disorders in the Polish population. Homozygosity and compound heterozygosity in FTD patients. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2018;19:407&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29557178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayer AH, Wojta K, Ramos EM, et al. Frequency of the TREM2 R47H Variant in Various Neurodegenerative Disorders. Alzheimer Dis Assoc Disord 2019;33:327&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7050643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31513029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rayaprolu S, Mullen B, Baker M, et al. TREM2 in neurodegeneration: evidence for association of the p.R47H variant with frontotemporal dementia and Parkinson's disease. Mol Neurodegener 2013;8:19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3691612</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23800361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giraldo M, Lopera F, Siniard AL, et al. Variants in triggering receptor expressed on myeloid cells 2 are associated with both behavioral variant frontotemporal lobar degeneration and Alzheimer's disease. Neurobiol Aging 2013;34:2077.e11&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3830921</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23582655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benitez BA, Cooper B, Pastor P, et al. TREM2 is associated with the risk of Alzheimer's disease in Spanish population. Neurobiol Aging 2013;34:1711.e15&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3596468</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23391427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slattery CF, Beck JA, Harper L, et al. R47H TREM2 variant increases risk of typical early-onset Alzheimer's disease but not of prion or frontotemporal dementia. Alzheimers Dement 2014;10:602.e4&#x2013;8.e4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4627504</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25160042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez Murcia JD, Schmutz C, Munger C, et al. Assessment of TREM2 rs75932628 association with Alzheimer's disease in a population-based sample: the Cache County Study. Neurobiol Aging 2013;34:2889.e11&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3779500</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23855982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin SC, Benitez BA, Karch CM, et al. Coding variants in TREM2 increase risk for Alzheimer's disease. Hum Mol Genet 2014;23:5838&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4189899</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24899047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roussos P, Katsel P, Fam P, et al. The triggering receptor expressed on myeloid cells 2 (TREM2) is associated with enhanced inflammation, neuropathological lesions and increased risk for Alzheimer's dementia. Alzheimers Dement 2015;11:1163&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4461564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25499537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin SC, Carrasquillo MM, Benitez BA, et al. TREM2 is associated with increased risk for Alzheimer's disease in African Americans. Mol Neurodegener 2015;10:19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4426167</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25886450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Landoulsi Z, Ben Djebara M, Kacem I, et al. Genetic analysis of TREM2 variants in Tunisian patients with Alzheimer's disease. Med Princ Pract 2018;27:317&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6167692</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29723869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arboleda-Bustos CE, Ortega-Rojas J, Mahecha MF, et al. The p.R47H variant of TREM2 gene is associated with late-onset alzheimer disease in colombian population. Alzheimer Dis Assoc Disord 2018;32:305&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30222607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cady J, Koval ED, Benitez BA, et al. TREM2 variant p.R47H as a risk factor for sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. JAMA Neurol 2014;71:449&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4087113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24535663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lill CM, Rengmark A, Pihlstrom L, et al. The role of TREM2 R47H as a risk factor for Alzheimer's disease, frontotemporal lobar degeneration, amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, and Parkinson's disease. Alzheimers Dement 2015;11:1407&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4627856</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25936935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen X, Chen Y, Wei Q, et al. Assessment of TREM2 rs75932628 association with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in a Chinese population. J Neurol Sci 2015;355:193&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26026943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mengel D, Thelen M, Balzer-Geldsetzer M, et al. TREM2 rare variant p.R47H is not associated with Parkinson's disease. Parkinsonism Relat Disord 2016;23:109&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26651418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benitez BA, Cruchaga C. United States-Spain Parkinson's Disease Research G. TREM2 and neurodegenerative disease. N Engl J Med 2013;369:1567&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4380008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24131187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng SJ, Nie K, Gan R, et al. Triggering receptor expressed on myeloid cells 2 variants are rare in Parkinson's disease in a Han Chinese cohort. Neurobiol Aging 2014;35:1780.e11&#x2013;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24602511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z, Zhong L, Gu L, et al. Association study of TREM2 polymorphism rs75932628 with leucoaraiosis or Parkinson's disease in the Han Chinese population. BMJ Open 2016;6:e009499.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4716257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26758262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan T, Song Z, Yuan L, et al. Genetic analysis of TREM2 variants in Chinese Han patients with sporadic Parkinson's disease. Neurosci Lett 2016;612:189&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26704436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y, Chen X, Guo X, et al. Assessment of TREM2 rs75932628 association with Parkinson's disease and multiple system atrophy in a Chinese population. Neurol Sci 2015;36:1903&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26058955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung WS, Welsh CA, Barres BA, et al. Do glia drive synaptic and cognitive impairment in disease? Nat Neurosci 2015;18:1539&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4739631</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26505565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng Q, Danao J, Talreja S, et al. TREM2-activating antibodies abrogate the negative pleiotropic effects of the Alzheimer's disease variant Trem2(R47H) on murine myeloid cell function. J Biol Chem 2018;293:12620&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6093249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29599291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lessard CB, Malnik SL, Zhou Y, et al. High-affinity interactions and signal transduction between Abeta oligomers and TREM2. EMBO Mol Med 2018;10:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6220267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30341064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng-Hathaway PJ, Reed-Geaghan EG, Jay TR, et al. The Trem2 R47H variant confers loss-of-function-like phenotypes in Alzheimer's disease. Mol Neurodegener 2018;13:29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5984804</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29859094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang M, Wang D, Xu Z, et al. Lack of genetic association between TREM2 and Alzheimer's disease in East Asian population: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Am J Alzheimers Dis Other Demen 2015;30:541&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25852195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou SL, Tan CC, Hou XH, et al. TREM2 variants and neurodegenerative diseases: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Alzheimers Dis 2019;68:1171&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30883352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu G, Liu Y, Jiang Q, et al. Convergent genetic and expression datasets highlight TREM2 in Parkinson's disease susceptibility. Mol Neurobiol 2016;53:4931&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26365049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>