<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">32028398</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>18</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-5964</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>99</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Medicine (Baltimore)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Phase 2 randomized placebo controlled double blind study to assess the efficacy and safety of tecfidera in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (TEALS Study): Study protocol clinical trial (SPIRIT Compliant).</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e18904</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e18904</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e18904</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MD.0000000000018904</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) is a progressive and fatal neurodegenerative disorder of the human motor system. Neuroinflammation appears to be an important modulator of disease progression in ALS. Specifically, reduction of regulatory T cell (Treg) levels, along with an increase in pro-inflammatory effector T cells, macrophage activation and upregulation of co-stimulatory pathways have all been associated with a rapid disease course in ALS. Autologous infusion of expanded Tregs into sporadic ALS patients, resulted in greater suppressive function, slowing of disease progression and stabilization of respiratory function. Tecfidera (dimethyl fumarate) increases the ratio of anti-inflammatory (Treg) to proinflammatory T-cells in patients with relapsing remitting multiple sclerosis and rebalances the regulatory: inflammatory axis towards a neuroprotective phenotype. Consequently, the aim of this study was to assess the efficacy, safety, and tolerability of Tecfidera in sporadic ALS.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">The study is an investigator led Phase 2 multi-center, randomized, placebo controlled, double blind clinical trial assessing the efficacy and safety of Tecfidera in patients with sporadic ALS. The study duration is 40 weeks, with a 36-week study period and end of study visit occurring at 40 weeks or at early termination/withdrawal from study. The TEALS study has been registered with the Australian and New Zealand Clinical Trials registry (ANZCTR) under the trials registration number ACTRN12618000534280 and has been approved by the Human Research Ethics Committee and Research Governance Office at the lead site (Westmead Hospital) with the ethics number HREC/17/WMEAD/353. The participating sites have obtained site specific ethics and governance approvals from the local institution.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The primary endpoint is slowing of disease progression as reflected by the differences in the ALS Functional Rating Score-Revised (ALSFRS-R) score at Week 36. The secondary endpoints will include effects in survival, lower motor neuron function, respiratory function, quality of life and safety.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This Phase 2 multi-center, randomized, placebo controlled, double blind clinical trial will provide evidence of efficacy and safety of Tecfidera in sporadic ALS.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vucic</LastName><ForeName>Steve</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of neurology, Westmead Hospital.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Westmead Clinical School University of Sydney, Sydney.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ryder</LastName><ForeName>Julie</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of neurology, Westmead Hospital.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mekhael</LastName><ForeName>Linda</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of neurology, Westmead Hospital.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rd</LastName><ForeName>Henderson</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Royal Brisbane and Women's Hospital, Brisbane.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mathers</LastName><ForeName>Susan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Calvary Health Care Bethlehem, Melbourne.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Needham</LastName><ForeName>Merilee</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Fiona Stanley Hospital, IIID Murdoch University, Notre Dame University and Perron Institute for Neurological and Neurosciences Translational Research.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dw</LastName><ForeName>Schultz</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Flinders Medical Centre, Adelaide.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mc</LastName><ForeName>Kiernan</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Brain and Mind Center, University of Sydney, Sydney, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><CollectiveName>TEALS study group</CollectiveName></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D000078325">Clinical Trial Protocol</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017427">Clinical Trial, Phase II</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016448">Multicenter Study</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Medicine (Baltimore)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>2985248R</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0025-7974</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D018696">Neuroprotective Agents</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>FO2303MNI2</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000069462">Dimethyl Fumarate</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="Y">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001315" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Australia</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000069462" MajorTopicYN="N">Dimethyl Fumarate</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018450" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Progression</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004311" MajorTopicYN="N">Double-Blind Method</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018696" MajorTopicYN="N">Neuroprotective Agents</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009520" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">New Zealand</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012107" MajorTopicYN="N">Research Design</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors have no conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32028398</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7015658</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000018904</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005792-202002070-00015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Kiernan MC, Vucic S, Cheah BC, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet 2011;377:942&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21296405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geevasinga N, Menon P, Ozdinler PH, et al. Pathophysiological and diagnostic implications of cortical dysfunction in ALS. Nat Rev Neurol 2016;12:651&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27658852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lacomblez L, Bensimon G, Leigh PN, et al. Dose-ranging study of riluzole in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis/Riluzole Study Group II. Lancet 1996;347:1425&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8676624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bensimon G, Lacomblez L, Meininger V. A controlled trial of riluzole in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. ALS/Riluzole Study Group. N Engl J Med 1994;330:585&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8302340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang T, Al Khleifat A, Meurgey JH, et al. Stage at which riluzole treatment prolongs survival in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a retrospective analysis of data from a dose-ranging study. Lancet Neurol 2018;17:416&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5899963</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29525492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Writing Group EM-EM10 Safety and efficacy of edaravone in well defined patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Lancet Neurol 2017;16:505&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28522181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Chalabi A, Calvo A, Chio A, et al. Analysis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis as a multistep process: a population-based modelling study. Lancet Neurol 2014;13:1108&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4197338</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25300936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S, Westeneng HJ, Al-Chalabi A, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis as a multi-step process: an Australia population study. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2019;20:532&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31284763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cudkowicz ME, Katz J, Moore DH, et al. Toward more efficient clinical trials for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler 2010;11:259&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19961263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dharmadasa T, Henderson RD, Talman PS, et al. Motor neurone disease: progress and challenges. Med J Aust 2017;206:357&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28446118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beers DR, Henkel JS, Xiao Q, et al. Wild-type microglia extend survival in PU.1 knockout mice with familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 2006;103:16021&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1613228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17043238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beers DR, Henkel JS, Zhao W, et al. CD4+ T cells support glial neuroprotection, slow disease progression, and modify glial morphology in an animal model of inherited ALS. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 2008;105:15558&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2547419</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18809917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beers DR, Henkel JS, Zhao W, et al. Endogenous regulatory T lymphocytes ameliorate amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in mice and correlate with disease progression in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain 2011;134:1293&#x2013;314.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3097891</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21596768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beers DR, Zhao W, Liao B, et al. Neuroinflammation modulates distinct regional and temporal clinical responses in ALS mice. Brain Behav Immun 2011;25:1025&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3096756</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21176785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beers DR, Zhao W, Wang J, et al. ALS patients&#x2019; regulatory T lymphocytes are dysfunctional, and correlate with disease progression rate and severity. JCI Insight 2017;2:e89530.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5333967</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28289705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Appel SH, Beers DR, Henkel JS. T cell-microglial dialogue in Parkinson's disease and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: are we listening? Trends Immunol 2010;31:7&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4126423</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19879804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boillee S, Yamanaka K, Lobsiger CS, et al. Onset and progression in inherited ALS determined by motor neurons and microglia. Science 2006;312:1389&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16741123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamanaka K, Chun SJ, Boillee S, et al. Astrocytes as determinants of disease progression in inherited amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat Neurosci 2008;11:251&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3137510</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18246065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiu IM, Chen A, Zheng Y, et al. T lymphocytes potentiate endogenous neuroprotective inflammation in a mouse model of ALS. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 2008;105:17913&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2581614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18997009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakaguchi S, Miyara M, Costantino CM, et al. FOXP3+ regulatory T cells in the human immune system. Nat Rev Immunol 2010;10:490&#x2013;500.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20559327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banerjee R, Mosley RL, Reynolds AD, et al. Adaptive immune neuroprotection in G93A-SOD1 amyotrophic lateral sclerosis mice. PLoS One 2008;3:0002740.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2481277</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18648532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheean RK, McKay FC, Cretney E, et al. Association of Regulatory T-Cell Expansion With Progression of Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis: A Study of Humans and a Transgenic Mouse Model. JAMA Neurol 2018;75:681&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5885208</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29507931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen X, Feng W, Huang R, et al. Evidence for peripheral immune activation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Sci 2014;347:90&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25312013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saresella M, Piancone F, Tortorella P, et al. T helper-17 activation dominates the immunologic milieu of both amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and progressive multiple sclerosis. Clin Immunol 2013;148:79&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23665549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi N, Kawano Y, Tateishi T, et al. Increased IL-13-producing T cells in ALS: positive correlations with disease severity and progression rate. J Neuroimmunol 2007;182:232&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17097743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang R, Gascon R, Miller R, et al. Evidence for systemic immune system alterations in sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (sALS). J Neuroimmunol 2005;159:215&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15652422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lincecum JM, Vieira FG, Wang MZ, et al. From transcriptome analysis to therapeutic anti-CD40L treatment in the SOD1 model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat Genet 2010;42:392&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20348957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henkel JS, Beers DR, Wen S, et al. Regulatory T-lymphocytes mediate amyotrophic lateral sclerosis progression and survival. EMBO Mol Med 2013;5:64&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3569654</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23143995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao W, Beers DR, Hooten KG, et al. Characterization of gene expression phenotype in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis monocytes. JAMA Neurol 2017;74:677&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5822209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28437540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thonhoff JR, Beers DR, Zhao W, et al. Expanded autologous regulatory T-lymphocyte infusions in ALS: A phase I, first-in-human study. Neurol Neuroimmunol Neuroinflamm 2018;5:e465.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5961523</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29845093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gold R, Kappos L, Arnold DL, et al. Placebo-controlled phase 3 study of oral BG-12 for relapsing multiple sclerosis. N Engl J Med 2012;367:1098&#x2013;107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22992073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fox RJ, Miller DH, Phillips JT, et al. Placebo-controlled phase 3 study of oral BG-12 or glatiramer in multiple sclerosis. N Engl J Med 2012;367:1087&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22992072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghadiri M, Rezk A, Li R, et al. Dimethyl fumarate-induced lymphopenia in MS due to differential T-cell subset apoptosis. Neurol Neuroimmunol Neuroinflamm 2017;4:e340.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5365096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28377940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gross CC, Schulte-Mecklenbeck A, Klinsing S, et al. Dimethyl fumarate treatment alters circulating T helper cell subsets in multiple sclerosis. Neurol Neuroimmunol Neuroinflamm 2016;3:e183.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4701136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26767188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum JM, Stambler N, Malta E, et al. The ALSFRS-R: a revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. BDNF ALS Study Group (Phase III). J Neurol Sci 1999;169:13&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10540002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Swash M. Nerve conduction studies in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve 2000;23:344&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10679710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menon P, Kiernan MC, Vucic S. ALS pathophysiology: insights form the split-hand phenomenon. Clin Neurophysiol 2014;49:836&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menon P, Kiernan MC, Vucic S. Cortical excitability differences in hand muscles follow a split-hand pattern in healthy controls. Muscle Nerve 2014;49:836&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24037729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menon P, Kiernan MC, Vucic S. Cortical dysfunction underlies the development of the split-hand in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. PLoS One 2014;9:e87124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3901749</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24475241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shepheard SR, Chataway T, Schultz DW, et al. The extracellular domain of neurotrophin receptor p75 as a candidate biomarker for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. PLoS One 2014;9:e87398.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3903651</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24475283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shepheard SR, Wuu J, Cardoso M, et al. Urinary p75(ECD): a prognostic, disease progression, and pharmacodynamic biomarker in ALS. Neurology 2017;88:1137&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5373786</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28228570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia R, Shepheard S, Jin J, et al. Urinary extracellular domain of neurotrophin receptor p75 as a biomarker for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in a Chinese cohort. Sci Rep 2017;7:5127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5506052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28698670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simmons Z, Felgoise SH, Bremer BA, et al. The ALSSQOL: balancing physical and nonphysical factors in assessing quality of life in ALS. Neurology 2006;67:1659&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17101900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Labra J, Menon P, Byth K, et al. Rate of disease progression: a prognostic biomarker in ALS. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2016;87:628&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26152368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kimura F, Fujimura C, Ishida S, et al. Progression rate of ALSFRS-R at time of diagnosis predicts survival time in ALS. Neurology 2006;66:265&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16434671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hooten KG, Beers DR, Zhao W, et al. Protective and toxic neuroinflammation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurotherapeutics 2015;12:364&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4404435</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25567201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>