<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">32040174</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1096-0929</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>175</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Jun</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Toxicological sciences : an official journal of the Society of Toxicology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Toxicol Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Assessing Effects of BHV-0223 40 mg Zydis Sublingual Formulation and Riluzole 50 mg Oral Tablet on Liver Function Test Parameters Utilizing DILIsym.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>292</StartPage><EndPage>300</EndPage><MedlinePgn>292-300</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1093/toxsci/kfaa019</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>For patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis who take oral riluzole tablets, approximately 50% experience alanine transaminase (ALT) levels above upper limit of normal (ULN), 8% above 3&#xd7; ULN, and 2% above 5&#xd7; ULN. BHV-0223 is a novel 40&#x2009;mg rapidly sublingually disintegrating (Zydis) formulation of riluzole, bioequivalent to conventional riluzole 50&#x2009;mg oral tablets, that averts the need for swallowing tablets and mitigates first-pass hepatic metabolism, thereby potentially reducing risk of liver toxicity. DILIsym is a validated multiscale computational model that supports evaluation of liver toxicity risks. DILIsym was used to compare the hepatotoxicity potential of oral riluzole tablets (50&#x2009;mg BID) versus BHV-0223 (40&#x2009;mg BID) by integrating clinical data and in vitro toxicity data. In a simulated population (SimPops), ALT levels &gt; 3&#xd7; ULN were predicted in 3.9% (11/285) versus 1.4% (4/285) of individuals with oral riluzole tablets and sublingual BHV-0223, respectively. This represents a relative risk reduction of 64% associated with BHV-0223 versus conventional riluzole tablets. Mechanistic investigations revealed that oxidative stress was responsible for the predicted ALT elevations. The validity of the DILIsym representation of riluzole and assumptions is supported by its ability to predict rates of ALT elevations for riluzole oral tablets comparable with that observed in clinical data. Combining a mechanistic, quantitative representation of hepatotoxicity with interindividual variability in both susceptibility and liver exposure suggests that sublingual BHV-0223 confers diminished rates of liver toxicity compared with oral tablets of riluzole, consistent with having a lower overall dose of riluzole and bypassing first-pass liver metabolism.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2020. Published by Oxford University Press on behalf of the Society of Toxicology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Longo</LastName><ForeName>Diane M</ForeName><Initials>DM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>DILIsym Services, Inc., Research Triangle Park, North Carolina 27709.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shoda</LastName><ForeName>Lisl K M</ForeName><Initials>LKM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>DILIsym Services, Inc., Research Triangle Park, North Carolina 27709.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Howell</LastName><ForeName>Brett A</ForeName><Initials>BA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>DILIsym Services, Inc., Research Triangle Park, North Carolina 27709.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Coric</LastName><ForeName>Vladimir</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biohaven Pharmaceuticals, Inc., New Haven, Connecticut 06510.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Berman</LastName><ForeName>Robert M</ForeName><Initials>RM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biohaven Pharmaceuticals, Inc., New Haven, Connecticut 06510.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Qureshi</LastName><ForeName>Irfan A</ForeName><Initials>IA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biohaven Pharmaceuticals, Inc., New Haven, Connecticut 06510.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D003160">Comparative Study</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Toxicol Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9805461</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1096-0929</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>7LJ087RS6F</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D019782">Riluzole</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000284" MajorTopicYN="Y">Administration, Oral</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000286" MajorTopicYN="Y">Administration, Sublingual</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000369" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged, 80 and over</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="Y">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D056487" MajorTopicYN="N">Chemical and Drug Induced Liver Injury, Chronic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="Y">etiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="Y">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008111" MajorTopicYN="N">Liver Function Tests</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019782" MajorTopicYN="N">Riluzole</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="Y">adverse effects</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">BHV-0223</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">DILI</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">DILIsym</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">quantitative systems pharmacology modeling</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32040174</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7253195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/toxsci/kfaa019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">5732695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bartlett J. A., van der Voort Maarschalk K. (2012). Understanding the oral mucosal absorption and resulting clinical pharmacokinetics of asenapine. AAPS PharmSciTech 13, 1110&#x2013;1115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3513449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22936407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Battista C., Yang K., Stahl S. H., Mettetal J. T., Watkins P. B., Siler S. Q., Howell B. A. (2018). Using quantitative systems toxicology to investigate observed species differences in CKA-mediated hepatotoxicity. Toxicol. Sci. 166, 123&#x2013;130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6204762</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30060248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bensimon G., Doble A. (2004). The tolerability of riluzole in the treatment of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Expert Opin. Drug Saf. 3, 525&#x2013;534.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15500412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bensimon G., Lacomblez L., Meininger V. (1994). A controlled trial of riluzole in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. ALS/Riluzole Study Group. N. Engl. J. Med. 330, 585&#x2013;591.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8302340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhattacharya S., Shoda L. K. M., Zhang Q., Woods C. G., Howell B. A., Siler S. Q., Woodhead J. L., Yang Y., McMullen P., Watkins P. B., et al. (2012). Modeling drug- and chemical-induced hepatotoxicity with systems biology approaches. Front. Physiol. 3, 462.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3522076</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23248599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bloomingdale P., Housand C., Apgar J. F., Millard B. L., Mager D. E., Burke J. M., Shah D. K. (2017). Quantitative systems toxicology. Curr. Opin. Toxicol. 4, 79&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5754001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29308440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks B. R., Sanjak M. (2004). Disease-modifying drug therapies. Amyotroph. Lateral Scler. Other Mot. Neuron Disord. 5(Suppl. 1), 68&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15512878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chandu B. R., Nama S., Kanala K., Challa B. R., Shaik R. P., Khagga M. (2010). Quantitative estimation of riluzole in human plasma by LC-ESI-MS/MS and its application to a bioequivalence study. Anal. Bioanal. Chem. 398, 1367&#x2013;1374.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20683584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doble A. (1996). The pharmacology and mechanism of action of riluzole. Neurology 47, S233&#x2013;241.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8959995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Georgoulopoulou E., Fini N., Vinceti M., Monelli M., Vacondio P., Bianconi G., Sola P., Nichelli P., Mandrioli J. (2013). The impact of clinical factors, riluzole and therapeutic interventions on ALS survival: A population based study in Modena, Italy. Amyotroph. Lateral Scler. Front. Degener. 14, 338&#x2013;345.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23373475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howell B. A., Siler S. Q., Barton H. A., Joshi E. M., Cabal A., Eichenbaum G., Watkins P. B. (2016). Development of quantitative systems pharmacology and toxicology models within consortia: Experiences and lessons learned through DILIsym development. Drug Discov. Today Dis. Models 22, 5&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howell B. A., Yang Y., Kumar R., Woodhead J. L., Harrill A. H., Clewell H. J. 3rd, Andersen M. E., Siler S. Q., Watkins P. B. (2012). In vitro to in vivo extrapolation and species response comparisons for drug-induced liver injury (DILI) using DILIsymTM: A mechanistic, mathematical model of DILI. J. Pharmacokinet. Pharmacodyn. 39, 527&#x2013;541.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22875368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lacomblez L., Bensimon G., Leigh P. N., Guillet P., Powe L., Durrleman S., Delumeau J. C., Meininger V. (1996). A confirmatory dose-ranging study of riluzole in ALS. ALS/Riluzole Study Group-II. Neurology 47, S242&#x2013;S250.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8959996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le Liboux A., Lefebvre P., Le Roux Y., Truffinet P., Aubeneau M., Kirkesseli S., Montay G. (1997). Single- and multiple-dose pharmacokinetics of riluzole in white subjects. J. Clin. Pharmacol. 37, 820&#x2013;827.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9549636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longo D. M., Generaux G. T., Howell B. A., Siler S. Q., Antoine D. J., Button D., Caggiano A., Eisen A., Iaci J., Stanulis R., et al. (2017). Refining liver safety risk assessment: Application of mechanistic modeling and serum biomarkers to cimaglermin alfa (GGF2) clinical trials. Clin. Pharmacol. Ther. 102, 961&#x2013;969.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5697568</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28419467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longo D. M., Woodhead J. L., Walker P., Her&#xe9;di-Szab&#xf3; K., Mogyor&#xf3;si K., Wolenski F. S., Dragan Y. P., Mosedale M., Siler S. Q., Watkins P. B., et al. (2019). Quantitative systems toxicology analysis of in vitro mechanistic assays reveals importance of bile acid accumulation and mitochondrial dysfunction in TAK-875-induced liver injury. Toxicol. Sci. 167, 458&#x2013;467.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6358270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30289550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandrioli J., Malerba S. A., Beghi E., Fini N., Fasano A., Zucchi E., De Pasqua S., Guidi C., Terlizzi E., Sette E., et al. (2018). Riluzole and other prognostic factors in ALS: A population-based registry study in Italy. J. Neurol. 265, 817&#x2013;827.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29404735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell J. D., O&#x2019;brien M. R., Joshi M. (2006). Audit of outcomes in motor neuron disease (MND) patients treated with riluzole. Amyotroph. Lateral Scler. 7, 67&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16753969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakano Y., Hirayama K., Terao K. (1987). Hepatic ultrastructural changes and liver dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Arch. Neurol. 44, 103&#x2013;106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3800708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shoda L. K., Battista C., Siler S. Q., Pisetsky D. S., Watkins P. B., Howell B. A. (2017). Mechanistic modelling of drug-induced liver injury: Investigating the role of innate immune responses. Gene Regul. Syst. Biol. 11, 1177625017696074.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5459514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28615926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shoda L. K., Woodhead J. L., Siler S. Q., Watkins P. B., Howell B. A. (2014). Linking physiology to toxicity using DILIsym(&#xae;), a mechanistic mathematical model of drug-induced liver injury. Biopharm. Drug Dispos. 35, 33&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24214486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watkins P. B. (2019). The DILI-sim Initiative: Insights into hepatotoxicity mechanisms and biomarker interpretation. Clin. Transl. Sci. 12, 122&#x2013;129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6440570</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30762301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woodhead J. L., Brock W. J., Roth S. E., Shoaf S. E., Brouwer K. L. R., Church R., Grammatopoulos T. N., Stiles L., Siler S. Q., Howell B. A., et al. (2017). Application of a mechanistic model to evaluate putative mechanisms of tolvaptan drug-induced liver injury and identify patient susceptibility factors. Toxicol. Sci. 155, 61&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5216653</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27655350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woodhead J. L., Howell B. A., Yang Y., Harrill A. H., Clewell H. J., Andersen M. E., Siler S. Q., Watkins P. B. (2012). An analysis of N-acetylcysteine treatment for acetaminophen overdose using a systems model of drug-induced liver injury. J. Pharmacol. Exp. Ther. 342, 529&#x2013;540.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22593093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woodhead J. L., Yang K., Oldach D., MacLauchlin C., Fernandes P., Watkins P. B., Siler S. Q., Howell B. A. (2019). Analyzing the mechanisms behind macrolide antibiotic-induced liver injury using quantitative systems toxicology modeling. Pharm. Res. 36, 48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6373306</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30734107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woodhead J. L., Yang K., Siler S. Q., Watkins P. B., Brouwer K. L. R., Barton H. A., Howell B. A. (2014). Exploring BSEP inhibition-mediated toxicity with a mechanistic model of drug-induced liver injury. Front. Pharmacol. 5, 240.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4224072</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25426072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia B., Yang Z., Zhou H., Lukacova V., Zhu W., Milewski M., Kesisoglou F. (2015). Development of a novel oral cavity compartmental absorption and transit model for sublingual administration: Illustration with Zolpidem. AAPS J. 17, 631&#x2013;642.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4406949</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25716146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang K., Battista C., Woodhead J. L., Stahl S. H., Mettetal J. T., Watkins P. B., Siler S. Q., Howell B. A. (2017). Systems pharmacology modeling of drug-induced hyperbilirubinemia: Differentiating hepatotoxicity and inhibition of enzymes/transporters. Clin. Pharmacol. Ther. 101, 501&#x2013;509.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5367379</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28074467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y., Nadanaciva S., Will Y., Woodhead J. L., Howell B. A., Watkins P. B., Siler S. Q. (2015). MITOsym&#xae;: A mechanistic, mathematical model of hepatocellular respiration and bioenergetics. Pharm. Res. 32, 1975&#x2013;1992.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4422870</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25504454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>