<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">32045022</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>19</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1469-7793</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>599</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>May</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Journal of physiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Physiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Neuropsychological and neurophysiological aspects of brain-computer-interface (BCI) control in paralysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2351</StartPage><EndPage>2359</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2351-2359</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1113/JP278775</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Brain-computer interfaces (BCIs) aim to help paralysed patients to interact with their environment by controlling external devices using brain activity, thereby bypassing the dysfunctional motor system. Some neuronal disorders, such as amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS), severely impair the communication capacity of patients. Several invasive and non-invasive brain-computer interfaces (BCIs), most notably using electroencephalography (EEG), have been developed to provide a means of communication to paralysed patients. However, except for a few reports, all available BCI literature for the paralysed (mostly ALS patients) describes patients with intact eye movement control, i.e. patients in a locked-in state (LIS) but not a completely locked-in state (CLIS). In this article we will discuss: (1) the fundamental neuropsychological learning factors and neurophysiological factors determining BCI performance in clinical applications; (2) the difference between LIS and CLIS; (3) recent development in BCIs for communication with patients in the completely locked-in state; (4) the effect of BCI-based communication on emotional well-being and quality of life; and (5) the outlook and the methodology needed to provide a means of communication for patients who have none. Thus, we present an overview of available studies and recent results and try to anticipate future developments which may open new doors for BCI communication with the completely paralysed.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020 The Authors. The Journal of Physiology published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of The Physiological Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chaudhary</LastName><ForeName>Ujwal</ForeName><Initials>U</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7887-1012</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Medical Psychology and Behavioral Neurobiology, University of T&#xfc;bingen, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wyss-Center for Bio- and Neuro-Engineering, Geneva, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mrachacz-Kersting</LastName><ForeName>Natalie</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2814-5351</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Applied Sciences and Arts, Dortmund, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Birbaumer</LastName><ForeName>Niels</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Medical Psychology and Behavioral Neurobiology, University of T&#xfc;bingen, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Physiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0266262</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0022-3751</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001921" MajorTopicYN="N">Brain</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D062207" MajorTopicYN="Y">Brain-Computer Interfaces</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003201" MajorTopicYN="N">Computers</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004569" MajorTopicYN="N">Electroencephalography</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010243" MajorTopicYN="N">Paralysis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">brain-computer interface (BCI)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">communication</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">completely locked-in state (CLIS)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">electroencephalogram</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">functional near-infrared spectroscopy (NIRS)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">invasive BCI</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">locked-in state (LIS)</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32045022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/JP278775</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Ardali MK, Rana A, Pourmohammad M, Birbaumer N &amp; Chaudhary U (2019). Semantic and BCI-performance in completely paralyzed patients: Possibility of language attrition in completely locked in syndrome. Brain Lang 194, 93-97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bacher D, Jarosiewicz B, Masse NY, Stavisky SD, Simeral JD, Newell K, Oakley EM, Cash SS, Friehs G &amp; Hochberg LR (2015). Neural Point-and-Click communication by a person with incomplete locked-in syndrome. Neurorehabil Neural Repair 29, 462-471.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bauer G, Gerstenbrand F, &amp; Rumpl E (1979). Varieties of the locked-in syndrome. J Neurol 221, 77-91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bansal AK, Truccolo W, Vargas-Irwin CE &amp; Donoghue JP (2012). Decoding 3D reach and grasp from hybrid signals in motor and premotor cortices: spikes, multiunit activity, and local field potentials. J Neurophysiol 107, 1337-1355.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Birbaumer N (2006). Breaking the silence: brain-computer interfaces (BCI) for communication and motor control. Psychophysiology 43, 517-532.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Birbaumer N, &amp; Chaudhary U (2015). Learning from brain control: clinical application of brain-computer interfaces. e-Neuroforum 21, 87-96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Birbaumer N, Elbert T, Canavan AG &amp; Rockstroh B (1990). Slow potentials of the cerebral cortex and behavior. Physiol Rev 70, 1-41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Birbaumer N, Ghanayim N, Hinterberger T, Iversen I, Kotchoubey B, K&#xfc;bler A, Perelmouter J, Taub E &amp; Flor H (1999). A spelling device for the paralysed. Nature 398, 297-298.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Birbaumer N, Ruiz S &amp; Sitaram R (2013). Learned regulation of brain metabolism. Trends Cogn Sci 17, 295-302.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brunner P, Ritaccio AL, Emrich JF, Bischof H &amp; Schalk G (2011). Rapid communication with a &#x201c;P300&#x201d; matrix speller using electrocorticographic signals (ECoG). Front Neurosci 5, 5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cipresso P, Carelli L, Solca F, Meazzi D, Meriggi P, Poletti B, Dorothee L, Ludolph AC, Silani V &amp; Riva G (2012). The use of P300-based BCIs in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: From augmentative and alternative communication to cognitive assessment. Brain Behav 2, 479-498.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chadwick EK, Blana D, Simeral JD, Lambrecht J, Kim SP, Cornwell AS, Taylor DM, Hochberg LR, Donoghue JP &amp; Kirsch RF (2011). Continuous neuronal ensemble control of simulated arm reaching by a human with tetraplegia. J Neural Eng 8, 034003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaudhary U, Birbaumer N &amp; Curado MR (2015). Brain-Machine Interface (BMI) in paralysis. Ann Phys Rehabil Med 58, 9-13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaudhary U, Birbaumer N &amp; Ramos-Murguialday A (2016a). Brain-computer interfaces for communication and rehabilitation. Nat Rev Neurol 12, 513.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaudhary U, Birbaumer N &amp; Ramos-Murguialday A (2016b). Brain computer interfaces in the completely locked-in state and chronic stroke. Prog Brain Res 228, 131-161.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaudhary U, Xia B, Silvoni S, Cohen LG &amp; Birbaumer N (2017). Brain-computer interface-based communication in the completely locked-in state. PLoS bio 15, e1002593.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collinger JL, Wodlinger B, Downey JE, Wang W, Tyler-Kabara EC, Weber DJ, McMorland AJC, Velliste M, Boninger ML &amp; Schwartz AB (2013). High-performance neuroprosthetic control by an individual with tetraplegia. Lancet 381, 557-564.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coscia M, Wessel MJ, Chaudary U, Mill&#xe1;n JD, Micera S, Guggisberg A, Vuadens P, Donoghue J, Birbaumer N &amp; Hummel FC (2019). Neurotechnology-aided interventions for upper limb motor rehabilitation in severe chronic stroke. Brain 142, 2182-2197.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dworkin BR &amp; Miller NE (1986). Failure to replicate visceral learning in the acute curarized rat preparation. Behav Neurosci 100, 299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dykstra AR, Chan AM, Quinn BT, Zepeda R, Keller CJ, Cormier J, Madsen JR, Eskandar EN &amp; Cash SS (2012). Individualized localization and cortical surface-based registration of intracranial electrodes. Neuroimage 59, 3563-3570.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farwell LA &amp; Donchin E (1988). Talking off the top of your head: toward a mental prosthesis utilizing event-related brain potentials. Electroencephalogr Clin Neurophysiol 70, 510-523.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilja V, Nuyujukian P, Chestek CA, Cunningham JP, Yu BM, Fan JM, Churchland MM, Kaufman MT, Kao JC, Ryu SI &amp; Shenoy KV (2012). A high-performance neural prosthesis enabled by control algorithm design. Nat Neurosci 15, 1752-1757.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilja V, Pandarinath C, Blabe CH, Nuyujukian P, Simeral JD, Sarma AA, Sorice BL, Perge JA, Jarosiewicz B, Hochberg LR, Shenoy KV &amp; Henderson JM (2015). Clinical translation of a high-performance neural prosthesis. Nat Med 21, 6-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallegos-Ayala G, Furdea A, Takano K, Ruf CA, Flor H &amp; Birbaumer N (2014). Brain communication in a completely locked-in patient using bedside near-infrared spectroscopy. Neurology 82, 1930-1932.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halder S, Rea M, Andreoni R, Nijboer F, Hammer EM, Kleih SC, Birbaumer N &amp; K&#xfc;bler A (2010). An auditory oddball brain-computer interface for binary choices. Clin Neurophysiol 121, 516-523.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hinterberger T, Veit R, Wilhelm B, Weiskopf N, Vatine JJ &amp; Birbaumer N (2005). Neuronal mechanisms underlying control of a brain-computer interface. Eur J Neurosci 21, 3169-3181.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hochberg LR, Serruya MD, Friehs GM, Mukand JA, Saleh M, Caplan AH, Branner A, Chen D, Penn RD &amp; Donoghue JP (2006). Neuronal ensemble control of prosthetic devices by a human with tetraplegia. Nature 442, 164-171.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hochberg LR, Bacher D, Jarosiewicz B, Masse NY, Simeral JD, Vogel J, Haddadin S, Liu J, Cash SS, van der Smagt P &amp; Donoghue JP (2012). Reach and grasp by people with tetraplegia using a neurally controlled robotic arm. Nature 485, 372-375.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jarosiewicz B, Sarma AA, Bacher D, Masse NY, Simeral JD, Sorice B, Oakley EM, Blabe C, Pandarinath C, Gilja V, Cash SS, Eskandar EN, Friehs G, Henderson JM, Shenoy KV, Donoghue JP &amp; Hochberg LR (2015). Virtual typing by people with tetraplegia using a self-calibrating intracortical brain-computer interface. Sci Transl Med 7, 313ra179-313ra179.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiernan MC, Vucic S, Cheah BC, Turner MR, Eisen A, Hardiman O, Burrell JR &amp; Zoing MC (2011). Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet North Am Ed 377, 942-955.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koralek AC, Costa RM &amp; Carmena JM (2013). Temporally precise cell-specific coherence develops in corticostriatal networks during learning. Neuron 79, 865-872.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kramer MA, Eden UT, Lepage KQ, Kolaczyk ED, Bianchi MT &amp; Cash SS (2011). Emergence of persistent networks in long-term intracranial EEG recordings. J Neurosci 31, 15757-15767.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xfc;bler A &amp; Birbaumer N (2008). Brain-computer interfaces and communication in paralysis: Extinction of goal directed thinking in completely paralysed patients? Clin Neurophysiol 119, 2658-2666.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xfc;bler A, Neumann N, Kaiser J, Kotchoubey B, Hinterberger T &amp; Birbaumer NP (2001). Brain-computer communication: Self-regulation of slow cortical potentials for verbal communication. Arch Phys Med Rehabil 82, 1533-1539.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xfc;bler A, Nijboer F, Mellinger J, Vaughan TM, Pawelzik H, Schalk G, McFarland DJ, Birbaumer N &amp; Wolpaw JR (2005). Patients with ALS can use sensorimotor rhythms to operate a brain-computer interface. Neurology 64, 1775-1777.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leuthardt EC, Schalk G, Wolpaw JR, Ojemann JG &amp; Moran DW (2004). A brain-computer interface using electrocorticographic signals in humans. J Neural Eng 1, 63-71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linse K, R&#xfc;ger W, Joos M, Schmitz-Peiffer H, Storch A &amp; Hermann A (2017). Eye-tracking-based assessment suggests preserved well-being in locked-in patients. Ann Neurol 81, 310-315.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lul&#xe9; D, Ehlich B, Lang D, Sorg S, Heimrath J, K&#xfc;bler A, Birbaumer N &amp; Ludolph AC (2013). Quality of life in fatal disease: the flawed judgement of the social environment. J Neurol 260, 2836-2843.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lul&#xe9; D, Zickler C, H&#xe4;cker S, Bruno MA, Demertzi A, Pellas F, Laureys S &amp; K&#xfc;bler A (2009). Life can be worth living in locked-in syndrome. Prog Brain Res 177, 339-351.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malekshahi A, Chaudhary U, Jaramillo-Gonzalez A, Luna AL, Rana A, Tonin A, Birbaumer N &amp; Gais S (2019). Sleep in the completely locked-in state (CLIS) in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Sleep, https://doi.org/10.1093/sleep/zsz185.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milekovic T, Sarma AA, Bacher D, Simeral JD, Saab J, Pandarinath C, Sorice BL, Oakley EM, Tringale KR, Eskandar E, Cash SS, Henderson JM, Shenoy KV, Donoghue JP &amp; Hochberg LR (2018). Stable long-term BCI-enabled communication in ALS and locked-in syndrome using LFP signals. J Neurophysiol 120, 343-360.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCane LM, Heckman SM, Mcfarland DJ, Townsend G, Mak JN, Sellers EW, Zeitlin D, Tenteromano LM, Wolpaw JR &amp; Aughan TM (2015). Clinical Neurophysiology P300-based brain-computer interface (BCI) event-related potentials (ERPs): People with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) vs. age-matched controls. Clin Neurophysiol 26, 1-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moran D (2010). Evolution of brain-computer interface: action potentials, local field potentials and electrocorticograms. Curr Opin Neurobiol 20, 741-745</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naito M, Michioka Y, Ozawa K, Ito Y, Kiguchi M &amp; Kanazawa T (2007). A communication means for totally locked-in ALS patients based on changes in cerebral blood volume measured with near-infrared light. IEICE Trans Inf Syst E90-D, 1028-1037.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nowicka N, Juranek J, Juranek JK &amp; Wojtkiewicz J (2019). Risk Factors and Emerging Therapies in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. Int J Mol Sci, 20, 2616.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nijboer F, Sellers EW, Mellinger J, Jordan MA, Matuz T, Furdea A, Halder S, Mochty U, Krusienski DJ, Vaughan TM, Wolpaw JR, Birbaumer N &amp; K&#xfc;bler A (2008). A P300-based brain-computer interface for people with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Neurophysiol 119, 1909-16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okahara Y, Takano K, Nagao M, Kondo K, Iwadate Y, Birbaumer N &amp; Kansaku K (2018). Long-term use of a neural prosthesis in progressive paralysis. Sci Rep 8, 16787.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pandarinath C, Nuyujukian P, Blabe CH, Sorice BL, Saab J, Willett FR, Hochberg LR, Shenoy KV &amp; Henderson JM (2017). High performance communication by people with paralysis using an intracortical brain-computer interface. Elife 6, e18554.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schalk G, Miller KJ, Anderson NR, Wilson JA, Smyth MD, Ojemann JG, Moran DW, Wolpaw JR &amp; Leuthardt EC (2008). Two-dimensional movement control using electrocorticographic signals in humans. J Neural Eng 5, 75-84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schevon CA, Ng SK, Cappell J, Goodman RR, McKhann G Jr, Waziri A, Branner A, Sosunov A, Schroeder CE &amp; Emerson RG (2008). Microphysiology of epileptiform activity in human neocortex. J Clin Neurophysiol 25, 321-330.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schevon CA, Trevelyan AJ, Schroeder CE, Goodman RR, McKhann G &amp; Emerson RG (2009). Spatial characterization of interictal high frequency oscillations in epileptic neocortex. Brain 132, 3047-3059.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schevon CA, Weiss SA, McKhann G, Goodman RR, Yuste R, Emerson RG &amp; Trevelyan AJ (2012). Evidence of an inhibitory restraint of seizure activity in humans. Nat Commun 3, 1060.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sellers, EW, Ryan, DB &amp; Hauser, CK (2015). Non-invasive brain-computer interface enables communication after brainstem stroke. Sci Transl Med 6, 257re7-257re7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sellers EW, Vaughan TM &amp; Wolpaw JR (2010). A brain-computer interface for long-term independent home use. Amyotroph Lateral Scler 11, 449-455.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simeral JD, Kim S-P, Black MJ, Donoghue JP &amp; Hochberg LR (2011). Neural control of cursor trajectory and click by a human with tetraplegia 1000 days after implant of an intracortical microelectrode array. J Neural Eng 8, 025027.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sitaram R, Ros T, Stoeckel L, Haller S, Scharnowski F, Lewis-Peacock J, Weiskopf N, Blefari ML, Rana M, Oblak E, Birbaumer N &amp; Sulzer J (2017). Closed-loop brain training: the science of neurofeedback. Nat Rev Neurosci 18, 86-100.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vansteensel MJ, Pels EG, Bleichner MG, Branco MP, Denison T, Freudenburg ZV, Gosselaar P, Leinders S, Ottens TH, Van Den Boom MA, Van Rijen PC, Aarnoutse EJ &amp; Ramsey NF (2016). Fully implanted brain-computer interface in a locked-in patient with ALS. N Engl J Med 375, 2060-2066.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weiss SA, Banks GP, McKhann GM, Goodman RR, Emerson RG, Trevelyan AJ &amp; Schevon CA (2013). Ictal high frequency oscillations distinguish two types of seizure territories in humans. Brain 136, 3796-3808.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weiss SA, Lemesiou A, Connors R, Banks GP, McKhann GM, Goodman RR, Zhao B, Filippi CG, Nowell M, Rodionov R, Diehl B, McEvoy AW, Walker MC, Trevelyan AJ, Bateman LM, Emerson RG &amp; Schevon CA (2015). Seizure localization using ictal phase-locked high gamma: A retrospective surgical outcome study. Neurology 84, 2320-2328.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang W, Collinger JL, Degenhart AD, Tyler-Kabara EC, Schwartz AB, Moran DW, Weber DJ, Wodlinger B, Vinjamuri RK, Ashmore RC, Kelly JW &amp; Boninger ML (2013). An electrocorticographic brain interface in an individual with tetraplegia. PLoS One 8, e55344.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolpaw JR, Bedlack RS, Reda DJ, Ringer RJ, Banks PG, Vaughan TM, Heckman SM, McCane LM, Carmack CS, Winden S, McFarland DJ, Sellers EW, Shi H, Paine T, Higgins DS, Lo AC, Patwa HS, Hill KJ, Huang GD &amp; Ruff RL (2018). Independent home use of a brain-computer interface by people with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology 91, e258-e267.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolpaw JR, Birbaumer N, McFarland D, Pfurtscheller G &amp; Vaughan TM (2002). Brain-computer interfaces for communication and control. Clin Neurophysiol 113, 767-791.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolpaw JR &amp; McFarland DJ (2004). Control of a two-dimensional movement signal by a non-invasive brain-computer interface in humans. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 101, 17849-17854.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>