<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">32068892</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-4598</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>61</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Muscle &amp; nerve</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Muscle Nerve</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Upper motor neuron burden measurement in motor neuron diseases: Does one scale fit all?</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>431</StartPage><EndPage>432</EndPage><MedlinePgn>431-432</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/mus.26836</ELocationID><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Babu</LastName><ForeName>Suma</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Sean M. Healey &amp; AMG Center for ALS, Massachusetts General Hospital, Harvard Medical School, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016421">Editorial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016420">Comment</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Muscle Nerve</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7803146</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0148-639X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="CommentOn"><RefSource>Muscle Nerve. 2020 Apr;61(4):508-511</RefSource><PMID Version="1">31743477</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016472" MajorTopicYN="Y">Motor Neuron Disease</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009046" MajorTopicYN="N">Motor Neurons</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32068892</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.26836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Feys P, Lamers I, Francis G, et al. The Nine-Hole Peg Test as a manual dexterity performance measure for multiple sclerosis. Mult Scler. 2017;23(5):711-720.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanjak M, Langford V, Holsten S, et al. Six-minute walk test as a measure of walking capacity in ambulatory individuals with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2017;98:2301-2307.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishaque A, Mah D, Seres P, et al. Evaluating the cerebral correlates of survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Clin Transl Neurol. 2018;5(11):1350-1361.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green JR, Allison KM, Cordella C, et al. Additional evidence for a therapeutic effect of dextromethorphan/quinidine on bulbar motor function in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a quantitative speech analysis. Br J Clin Pharmacol. 2018;84:2849-2856.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huynh W, Simon NG, Grosskreutz J, Turner MR, Vucic S, Kiernan MC. Assessment of the upper motor neuron in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Neurophysiol. 2016;127:2643-2660.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rusz J, Bonnet C, Klempir J, et al. Speech disorders reflect differing pathophysiology in Parkinson's disease, progressive supranuclear palsy and multiple system atrophy. J Neurol. 2015;262:992-1001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meseguer-Henarejos AB, Sanchez-Meca J, Lopez-Pina JA, Carles-Hernandez R. Inter- and intra-rater reliability of the Modified Ashworth Scale: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Eur J Phys Rehabil Med. 2018;54(4):576-590.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farrar JT, Troxel AB, Stott C, Duncombe P, Jensen MP. Validity, reliability, and clinical importance of change in a 0-10 numeric rating scale measure of spasticity: a post hoc analysis of a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Clin Ther. 2008;30:974-985.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hobart JC, Riazi A, Thompson AJ, et al. Getting the measure of spasticity in multiple sclerosis: the Multiple Sclerosis Spasticity Scale (MSSS-88). Brain. 2006;129(Pt 1):224-234.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rekand T. Clinical assessment and management of spasticity: a review. Acta Neurol Scand Suppl. 2010;190:62-66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meca-Lallana JE, Hernandez-Clares R, Carreon-Guarnizo E. Spasticity in multiple sclerosis and role of glatiramer acetate treatment. Brain Behav. 2015;5:e00367.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bohannon RW, Smith MB. Interrater reliability of a modified Ashworth scale of muscle spasticity. Phys Ther. 1987;67(2):206-207.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellis CM, Simmons A, Jones DK, et al. Diffusion tensor MRI assesses corticospinal tract damage in ALS. Neurology. 1999;53(5):1051-1058.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zurcher NR, Loggia ML, Lawson R, et al. Increased in vivo glial activation in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: assessed with [(11)C]-PBR28. Neuroimage Clin. 2015;7:409-414.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woo JH, Wang S, Melhem ER, et al. Linear associations between clinically assessed upper motor neuron disease and diffusion tensor imaging metrics in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. PLoS One. 2014;9:e105753.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quinn C, Edmundson C, Dahodwala N, Elman L. Reliable and efficient scale to assess upper motor neuron disease burden in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. Published online Nov. 2019;19. https://doi.org/10.1002/mus.26764.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore SR, Gresham LS, Bromberg MB, Kasarkis EJ, Smith RA. A self-report measure of affective lability. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 1997;63(1):89-93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chew S, Atassi N. Positron emission tomography molecular imaging biomarkers for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Front Neurol. 2019;10:135.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratai EM, Alshikho MJ, Zurcher NR, et al. Integrated imaging of [(11)C]-PBR28 PET, MR diffusion and magnetic resonance spectroscopy (1)H-MRS in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuroimage Clin. 2018;20:357-364.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S, Ziemann U, Eisen A, Hallett M, Kiernan MC. Transcranial magnetic stimulation and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: pathophysiological insights. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2013;84:1161-1170.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>