<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">32073458</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>07</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1537-1611</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>21</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of clinical neuromuscular disease</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Clin Neuromuscul Dis</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>An Open-Label, Prospective Study Evaluating the Clinical and Immunological Effects of Higher Dose Granulocyte Colony-Stimulating Factor in ALS.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>127</StartPage><EndPage>134</EndPage><MedlinePgn>127-134</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/CND.0000000000000275</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">We evaluated the safety and tolerability of higher-dose granulocyte colony-stimulating factor (G-CSF) in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. In addition, rates of disease progression and serum G-CSF levels and other immunological and hematological markers were measured.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Three patients with advanced amyotrophic lateral sclerosis were treated with G-CSF subcutaneously at 5 &#x3bc;g/kg twice daily for 5 consecutive days monthly for 4-12 months. Patients were monitored for adverse effects, and disease progression was assessed with ALSFRS-R and other measures.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Patients tolerated higher-dose G-CSF well with no serious adverse events. Adverse effects were mild to moderate with musculoskeletal pain and malaise being most often reported. No significant change in the rate of disease progression was noted for ALSFRS-R or other measures. Bone marrow progenitor cells were rapidly mobilized for a duration of approximately 9 days with transient and variable effect on cytokines.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Higher-dose G-CSF was well tolerated in this cohort with no apparent effect on disease progression up to 1 year.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pocock</LastName><ForeName>Kristyn</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of South Florida, Tampa, FL; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Suresh</LastName><ForeName>Niraja</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of South Florida, Tampa, FL; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Suradi</LastName><ForeName>Yazan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of South Florida, Tampa, FL; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dang</LastName><ForeName>Samuel</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of South Florida, Tampa, FL; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Harvey</LastName><ForeName>Brittany</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of South Florida, Tampa, FL; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cao</LastName><ForeName>Chuanhai</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutical Sciences, College of Pharmacy, University of South Florida, Tampa, FL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sutherland</LastName><ForeName>Kyle</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutical Sciences, College of Pharmacy, University of South Florida, Tampa, FL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lin</LastName><ForeName>Xiaoyang</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutical Sciences, College of Pharmacy, University of South Florida, Tampa, FL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vu</LastName><ForeName>Tuan H</ForeName><Initials>TH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of South Florida, Tampa, FL; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gooch</LastName><ForeName>Clifton</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of South Florida, Tampa, FL; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016430">Clinical Trial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Clin Neuromuscul Dis</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100887391</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1522-0443</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>143011-72-7</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D016179">Granulocyte Colony-Stimulating Factor</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="Y">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018450" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Progression</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016179" MajorTopicYN="N">Granulocyte Colony-Stimulating Factor</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="Y">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D059630" MajorTopicYN="N">Mesenchymal Stem Cells</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="N">drug effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010865" MajorTopicYN="N">Pilot Projects</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011446" MajorTopicYN="N">Prospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32073458</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/CND.0000000000000275</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00131402-202003000-00001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Welte K, Platzer E, Lu L, et al. Purification and biochemical characterization of human pluripotent hematopoietic colony-stimulating factor. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 1985;82:1526&#x2013;1530.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang Y, Jahagirdar BN, Reinhardt RL, et al. Pluripotency of mesenchymal stem cells derived from adult marrow. Nature. 2002;418:41&#x2013;49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mezey E, Key S, Vogelsang G, et al. Transplanted bone marrow generates new neurons in human brains. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2003;100:1364&#x2013;1369.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cogle CR, Yachnis AT, Laywell ED, et al. Bone marrow transdifferentiation in brain after transplantation: a retrospective study. Lancet. 2004;363:1432&#x2013;1437.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanaka M, Kikuchi H, Ishizu T, et al. Intrathecal upregulation of granulocyte colony stimulating factor and its neuroprotective actions on motor neurons in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neuropathol Exp Neurol. 2006;65:816&#x2013;825.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pitzer C, Kruger C, Plaas C, et al. Granulocyte-colony stimulating factor improves outcome in a mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain. 2008;131(pt 12):3335&#x2013;3347.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henriques A, Pitzer C, Dupuis L, et al. G-CSF protects motoneurons against axotomy-induced apoptotic death in neonatal mice. BMC Neurosci. 2010;11:25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henriques A, Kastner S, Chatzikonstantinou E, et al. Gene expression changes in spinal motoneurons of the SOD1(G93A) transgenic model for ALS after treatment with G-CSF. Front Cell Neurosci. 2014;8:464.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henriques A, Pitzer C, Dittgen T, et al. CNS-targeted viral delivery of G-CSF in an animal model for ALS: improved efficacy and preservation of the neuromuscular unit. Mol Ther. 2011;19:284&#x2013;292.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamasaki R, Tanaka M, Fukunaga M, et al. Restoration of microglial function by granulocyte-colony stimulating factor in ALS model mice. J Neuroimmunol. 2010;229:51&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rando A, Gasco S, de la Torre M, et al. Granulocyte colony-stimulating factor Ameliorates skeletal muscle dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis mice and improves proliferation of SOD1-G93A myoblasts in vitro. Neurodegener Dis. 2017;17:1&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao BG, Lu CZ, Link H. Cell biology and clinical promise of G-CSF: immunomodulation and neuroprotection. J Cell Mol Med. 2007;11:1272&#x2013;1290.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komine-Kobayashi M, Zhang N, Liu M, et al. Neuroprotective effect of recombinant human granulocyte colony-stimulating factor in transient focal ischemia of mice. J Cereb Blood Flow Metab. 2006;26:402&#x2013;413.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chio A, Mora G, La Bella V, et al. Repeated courses of granulocyte colony-stimulating factor in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: clinical and biological results from a prospective multicenter study. Muscle Nerve. 2011;43:189&#x2013;195.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grassinger J, Khomenko A, Hart C, et al. Safety and feasibility of long term administration of recombinant human granulocyte-colony stimulating factor in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Cytokine. 2014;67:21&#x2013;28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarella C, Rutella S, Gualandi F, et al. Consistent bone marrow-derived cell mobilization following repeated short courses of granulocyte-colony-stimulating factor in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: results from a multicenter prospective trial. Cytotherapy. 2010;12:50&#x2013;59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nefussy B, Artamonov I, Deutsch V, et al. Recombinant human granulocyte-colony stimulating factor administration for treating amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a pilot study. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2010;11:187&#x2013;193.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith TJ, Bohlke K, Armitage JO. Recommendations for the use of white blood cell growth factors: American Society of Clinical Oncology Clinical Practice Guideline update. J Oncol Pract. 2015;11:511&#x2013;513.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith TJ, Khatcheressian J, Lyman GH, et al. 2006 update of recommendations for the use of white blood cell growth factors: an evidence-based clinical practice guideline. J Clin Oncol. 2006;24:3187&#x2013;3205.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hubl W, Iturraspe J, Martinez GA, et al. Measurement of absolute concentration and viability of CD34+ cells in cord blood and cord blood products using fluorescent beads and cyanine nucleic acid dyes. Cytometry. 1998;34:121&#x2013;127.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao C, Wang L, Lin X, et al. Caffeine synergizes with another coffee component to increase plasma GCSF: linkage to cognitive benefits in Alzheimer's mice. J Alzheimers Dis. 2011;25:323&#x2013;335.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bensimon G, Lacomblez L, Delumeau JC, et al. A study of riluzole in the treatment of advanced stage or elderly patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol. 2002;249:609&#x2013;615.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Labra J, Menon P, Byth K, et al. Rate of disease progression: a prognostic biomarker in ALS. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2016;87:628&#x2013;632.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon PH, Cheung YK. Progression rate of ALSFRS-R at time of diagnosis predicts survival time in ALS. Neurology. 2006;67:1314&#x2013;1315; author reply-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gooch CL, Shefner JM. ALS surrogate markers: MUNE. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord. 2004;5(suppl 1):104&#x2013;107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schneider A, Kruger C, Steigleder T, et al. The hematopoietic factor G-CSF is a neuronal ligand that counteracts programmed cell death and drives neurogenesis. J Clin Invest. 2005;115:2083&#x2013;2098.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babu GN, Kumar A, Chandra R, et al. Elevated inflammatory markers in a group of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients from northern India. Neurochem Res. 2008;33:1145&#x2013;1149.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tortarolo M, Lo Coco D, Veglianese P, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, a multisystem pathology: insights into the role of TNFalpha. Mediators Inflamm. 2017;2017:2985051.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tremolizzo L, Pellegrini A, Conti E, et al. BDNF serum levels with respect to multidimensional assessment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurodegener Dis. 2016;16:192&#x2013;198.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>