<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">32097525</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>21</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1468-1331</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>27</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Antidiabetics, statins and the risk of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1010</StartPage><EndPage>1016</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1010-1016</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/ene.14190</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Medications that are used for treatment of metabolic disorders have been suggested to be associated with the development of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">To examine the associations of antidiabetics and statins with the subsequent risk of ALS we conducted a population-based nested case-control study of 2475 Swedish residents diagnosed with ALS during July 2006 to December 2013 and 12&#xa0;375 population controls (five for each ALS case). We extracted information on filled prescriptions of antidiabetics and statins for both cases and controls from the Swedish Prescribed Drug Register during the years before ALS diagnosis. Conditional logistic regression was used to calculate odds ratios (ORs) for the associations of these medications with ALS risk.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Patients with ALS were less likely to have been prescribed with antidiabetics compared with controls [OR, 0.76; 95% confidence intervals (CI), 0.65-0.90]. Conversely, statins were not associated with ALS risk overall (OR, 1.08; 95% CI, 0.98-1.19), although a positive association was noted among women (OR, 1.28; 95% CI, 1.10-1.48). The latter association was mostly explained by ALS cases being more likely to have a first prescription of statins during the year before diagnosis compared with controls (OR, 2.54; 95% CI, 1.84-3.49).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">The inverse association of antidiabetics with ALS is consistent with the previously reported inverse association between type 2 diabetes and ALS risk. The increase in prescription of statins during the year before ALS diagnosis deserves attention because it might reflect an acceleration of the course of ALS due to statin use.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020 The Authors. European Journal of Neurology published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of European Academy of Neurology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mariosa</LastName><ForeName>D</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8181-1419</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Epidemiology and Biostatistics, Karolinska Institutet, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kamel</LastName><ForeName>F</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Epidemiology Branch, National Institute of Environmental Health Sciences, NIH, DHHS, Research Triangle Park, NC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bellocco</LastName><ForeName>R</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Epidemiology and Biostatistics, Karolinska Institutet, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Statistics and Quantitative Methods, University of Milano-Bicocca, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ronnevi</LastName><ForeName>L-O</ForeName><Initials>LO</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Neuroscience, Karolinska Institutet, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Almqvist</LastName><ForeName>C</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Epidemiology and Biostatistics, Karolinska Institutet, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Lung and Allergy Unit, Astrid Lindgren Children's Hospital, Karolinska University Hospital, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Larsson</LastName><ForeName>H</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Epidemiology and Biostatistics, Karolinska Institutet, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Sciences, &#xd6;rebro University, &#xd6;rebro, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ye</LastName><ForeName>W</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6859-4648</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Epidemiology and Biostatistics, Karolinska Institutet, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fang</LastName><ForeName>F</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3310-6456</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Environmental Medicine, Karolinska Institutet, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>the Swedish Society for Medical Research</Agency><Country>International</Country></Grant><Grant><Agency>EU Joint Programme - Neurodegenerative Disease Research (JPND)</Agency><Country>International</Country></Grant><Grant><Agency>Ulla-Carin Lindquist Foundation</Agency><Country>International</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2013-00782</GrantID><Agency>Forskningsr&#xe5;det om H&#xe4;lsa, Arbetsliv och V&#xe4;lf&#xe4;rd</Agency><Country>International</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>340-2013-5867</GrantID><Agency>Swedish Initiative for Research on Microdata in the Social and Medical Sciences (SIMSAM)</Agency><Country>International</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2019-01088</GrantID><Agency>Vetenskapsr&#xe5;det</Agency><Country>International</Country></Grant><Grant><Agency>Karolinska Institutet</Agency><Country>International</Country></Grant><Grant><Agency>the Intramural Research Program of the National Institutes of Health, National Institute of Environmental Health Sciences</Agency><Country>International</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052060">Research Support, N.I.H., Intramural</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9506311</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1351-5101</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D019161">Hydroxymethylglutaryl-CoA Reductase Inhibitors</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D007004">Hypoglycemic Agents</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016022" MajorTopicYN="N">Case-Control Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003924" MajorTopicYN="N">Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019161" MajorTopicYN="N">Hydroxymethylglutaryl-CoA Reductase Inhibitors</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007004" MajorTopicYN="N">Hypoglycemic Agents</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012307" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013548" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Sweden</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">antidiabetics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">diabetes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">risk factors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">statins</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32097525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ene.14190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Dupuis L, Corcia P, Fergani A, et al. Dyslipidemia is a protective factor in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology 2008; 70: 1004-1009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sutedja NA, van der Schouw YT, Fischer K, et al. Beneficial vascular risk profile is associated with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2011; 82: 638-642.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mariosa D, Kamel F, Bellocco R, Ye W, Fang F. Association between diabetes and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in Sweden. Eur J Neurol 2015; 22: 1436-1442.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kioumourtzoglou MA, Rotem RS, Seals RM, Gredal O, Hansen J, Weisskopf MG. Diabetes mellitus, obesity, and diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a population-based study. JAMA Neurol 2015; 72: 905-911.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mariosa D, Hammar N, Malmstrom H, et al. Blood biomarkers of carbohydrate, lipid, and apolipoprotein metabolisms and risk of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A more than 20-year follow-up of the Swedish AMORIS cohort. Ann Neurol 2017; 81: 718-728.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pradat PF, Bruneteau G, Gordon PH, et al. Impaired glucose tolerance in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler 2010; 11: 166-171.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ingre C, Chen L, Zhan Y, et al. Lipids, apolipoproteins, and prognosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology 2020. https://doi.org/10.1212/WNL.0000000000009322</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardoso S, Correia S, Santos RX, et al. Insulin is a two-edged knife on the brain. J Alzheimers Dis 2009; 18: 483-507.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun H, Knippenberg S, Thau N, et al. Therapeutic potential of N-acetyl-glucagon-like peptide-1 in primary motor neuron cultures derived from non-transgenic and SOD1-G93A ALS mice. Cell Mol Neurobiol 2013; 33: 347-357.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dupuis L, Dengler R, Heneka MT, et al. A randomized, double blind, placebo-controlled trial of pioglitazone in combination with riluzole in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. PLoS One 2012; 7: e37885.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jawaid A, Paganoni S, Hauser C, Schulz PE. Trials of antidiabetic drugs in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: proceed with caution? Neurodegener Dis 2014; 13: 205-208.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaneb HM, Sharp PS, Rahmani-Kondori N, Wells DJ. Metformin treatment has no beneficial effect in a dose-response survival study in the SOD1(G93A) mouse model of ALS and is harmful in female mice. PLoS One 2011; 6: e24189.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beltowski J. Statins and ALS: the possible role of impaired LXR signaling. Med Sci Monit 2010; 16: Ra73-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee SH, Choi NY, Yu HJ, et al. Atorvastatin protects NSC-34 motor neurons against oxidative stress by activating PI3K, ERK and free radical scavenging. Mol Neurobiol 2016; 53: 695-705.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Golomb BA, Verden A, Messner AK, Koslik HJ, Hoffman KB. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis associated with statin use: a disproportionality analysis of the FDA's adverse event reporting system. Drug Safety 2018; 41: 403-413.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sorensen HT, Riis AH, Lash TL, Pedersen L. Statin use and risk of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and other motor neuron disorders. Circ Cardiovasc Qual Outcomes 2010; 3: 413-417.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freedman DM, Kuncl RW, Cahoon EK, Rivera DR, Pfeiffer RM. Relationship of statins and other cholesterol-lowering medications and risk of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in the US elderly. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2018; 19: 538-546.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jawaid A, Salamone AR, Strutt AM, et al. ALS disease onset may occur later in patients with pre-morbid diabetes mellitus. Eur J Neurol 2010; 17: 733-739.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ingre C, Roos PM, Piehl F, Kamel F, Fang F. Risk factors for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Epidemiol 2015; 7: 181-193.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longinetti E, Regod&#xf3;n Wallin A, Samuelsson K, et al. The Swedish motor neuron disease quality registry. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2018; 19: 528-537.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nefussy B, Hirsch J, Cudkowicz ME, Drory VE. Gender-based effect of statins on functional decline in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Sci 2011; 300: 23-27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su XW, Nandar W, Neely EB, Simmons Z, Connor JR. Statins accelerate disease progression and shorten survival in SOD1(G93A) mice. Muscle Nerve 2016; 54: 284-291.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voora D, Shah SH, Spasojevic I, et al. The SLCO1B1*5 genetic variant is associated with statin-induced side effects. J Am Coll Cardiol 2009; 54: 1609-1619.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joy TR, Hegele RA. Narrative review: statin-related myopathy. Ann Intern Med 2009; 150: 858-868.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>SEARCH Collaborative Group, Link E, Parish S, et al. SLCO1B1 variants and statin-induced myopathy - a genome wide study. N Engl J Med 2008; 359: 789-799.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chipika RH, Finegan E, Li Hi Shing S, Hardiman O, Bede P. Tracking a fast-moving disease: longitudinal markers, monitoring, and clinical trial endpoints in ALS. Front Neurol 2019; 10: 229.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>