<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">32134532</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>25</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-4598</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>62</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Muscle &amp; nerve</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Muscle Nerve</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Hypothesis: amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and environmental pollutants.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>187</StartPage><EndPage>191</EndPage><MedlinePgn>187-191</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/mus.26855</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Genetic, epigenetic, and environmental factors are relevant in the causation of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) in a multistep cascade. We suggest that exposure to environmental pollutants in early life is one such factor. ALS was first described in the 19th century in the context of the Industrial Revolution that began more than 50&#x2009;years earlier. The rising incidence of ALS thereafter correlates with increasing longevity, but this is an incomplete association. We suggest that increasing exposure to environmental pollutants due to industrial activity, acting over a lifetime, is also important. The combination of genetic mutations and pollutant exposure, with increased life expectancy, may account for the apparent variations in incidence of the disease in different countries and continents and even regionally within a given country. This hypothesis is testable by focused epidemiological studies, evaluating early and lifelong industrial pollutant exposure of differing types, within the Bradford Hill framework.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020 Wiley Periodicals, Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Swash</LastName><ForeName>Michael</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8717-8914</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Barts and The London School of Medicine, Queen Mary University of London and Royal London Hospital, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Neuroscience, University of Lisbon, Lisbon, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Eisen</LastName><ForeName>Andrew</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Neurology, University of British Columbia, Vancouver, British Columbia, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016456">Historical Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Muscle Nerve</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7803146</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0148-639X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000073885">C9orf72 Protein</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D004268">DNA-Binding Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D004785">Environmental Pollutants</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C000598624">TARDBP protein, human</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 1.15.1.1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000072105">Superoxide Dismutase-1</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="Y">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000266" MajorTopicYN="N">history</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000073885" MajorTopicYN="N">C9orf72 Protein</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015984" MajorTopicYN="N">Causality</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004268" MajorTopicYN="N">DNA-Binding Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004781" MajorTopicYN="N">Environmental Exposure</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000266" MajorTopicYN="N">history</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="Y">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004785" MajorTopicYN="Y">Environmental Pollutants</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D059647" MajorTopicYN="Y">Gene-Environment Interaction</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D049672" MajorTopicYN="N">History, 19th Century</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D049673" MajorTopicYN="N">History, 20th Century</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D049674" MajorTopicYN="N">History, 21st Century</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015994" MajorTopicYN="N">Incidence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000067896" MajorTopicYN="N">Industrial Development</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000266" MajorTopicYN="N">history</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="Y">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008017" MajorTopicYN="Y">Life Expectancy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009154" MajorTopicYN="N">Mutation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000072105" MajorTopicYN="N">Superoxide Dismutase-1</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ALS genetics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ALS pathogenesis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">environmental pollution</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">multistep process</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32134532</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.26855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Bernard C. Introduction to the Study of Experimental Medicine (trans from Paris 1865 edition). Mineola, NY: Dover Books; 1957:38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corcia P, Meininger V. 150th Anniversary of Charcot&#x2019;s description of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain. 2019;142:3306-3313.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charcot JM. De la scl&#xe9;rose lat&#xe9;rale amyotrophique. Prog M&#xe9;d. 1874;23:325-326, 341-344, 421-423, 453-455.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Chalabi A, Hardiman O. The epidemiology of ALS: a conspiracy of genes, environment and time. Nat Rev Neurol. 2013;9:617-628.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill AB. The environment and disease: association or causation? Proc R Soc Med. 1965;58:295-300.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eisen A, Kiernan N, Mitsumoto H, Swash M. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a long preclinical period? J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2014;85:1232-1238.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Es M, Hardiman O, Chio A, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet. 2017;390:2084-2098.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armon C. An evidence-based medicine approach to the evaluation of the role of exogenous risk factors in sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuroepidemiology. 2003;22:217-228.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swash M. Diet and risk of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: is lifestyle important? JAMA Neurol. 2014;71:1085-1086.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McHenry LC, Garrison FH. Garrison's History of Neurology. Philadelphia: WB Saunders; 1969.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cruveilhier J. Sur le paralysie musculaire, progressive, atrophique. Bull Acad Med. 1853;18:490-501. 546-583.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radcliffe CB, Lockhart CJ. An important case of paralysis and muscular atrophy with disease of the nervous centres. Br Foreign Medico-Chirurg Rev. 1862;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dewhurst K. Willis&#x2019; Oxford Casebooks (1650-1652). Oxford, UK: Sanford; 1981:1-199.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roser M. Life expectancy. Our world in data. https://ourworldindata.org/life-expectancy. Accessed on, February 10, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li T-M, Alberman E, Swash M. Comparison of sporadic and familial disease among 580 cases of motor neurone disease. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 1988;51:778-784.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner MR, Barnwell J, Al-Chalabi A, Eisen A. Young-onset amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: historical and other observations. Brain. 2012;135:2883-2891.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Landrigan PJ, Fuller R, Acosta NJR, et al. The Lancet Commission on pollution and health. Lancet. 2018;391:462-512.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dinda S. Environmental Kuznets curve hypothesis: a survey. Ecol Economics. 2004;49:431-455.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamel F, Umbach DM, Munsat TL, Shefner JM, Sandler DP. Association of cigarette smoking with anyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuroepidemiology. 1999;18:194-202.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dube MF, Green CR. Methods of collection of smoke for analytical purposes. Recent Adv Tobacco Sci. 1998;8:42-102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goutman SA, Boss J, Patterson A, Mukherjee B, Batterman S, Feldman E. High plasma concentrations of organic pollutants negatively impact survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2019;90:907-912.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armon C. From Snow Hill to ALS: an epidemiological odyssey in search of ALS causation. J Neurol Sci. 2018;391:134-140.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kondo K, Tsubaki T. Case-control studies of motor neuron disease: association with mechanical injuries. Arch Neurol. 1981;38:220-226.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fitzgerald KC, O'Reilly EJ, Falcone GJ, et al. Dietary &#x3c9;-3 polyunsaturated fatty acid intake and risk for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. JAMA Neurol. 2014;71:1102-1110.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barker DJ. The fetal and infant origins of adult disease. BMJ. 1990;301:1111.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Block ML, Garciduenas L. Air pollution: mechanisms of neuro-inflammation and CNS disease. Trends Neurosci. 2009;32:506-516.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Younan D, Petkus AJ, Widaman KF, et al. Particulate matter and episodic memory decline mediated by early neuroanatomic biomarkers of Alzheimer's disease. Brain. 2019;143:289-302.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bell ML, Davis DL, Fletcher T. A retrospective assessment of mortality from the London smog episode of 1952: the role of influenza and pollution. Environ Health Perspect. 2004;112:6-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grova N, Schroeder H, Olivier J-L, Turner JD. Epigenetic and neurological ijmpairments associated with early life exposure to persistent organic pollutants. Int J Genomics. 2019:2085496. https://doi.org/10.1155/2019/2085496.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cavalli G, Heard E. Advances in epigenetics link genetics to the environment and disease. Nature. 2019;571:489-499.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feigin VL, Vos T, Nichols E, Owolabi MO, Carroll WM, Dichgans M. The global burden of neurological disorders: translating evidence into policy. Lancet Neurol. 2020;19:255-265.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plato CC, Garruto RM, Galasto D, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and Parkinsonism-dementia complex of Guam: changing incidence rates during the past 60&#x2009;years. Am J Epidemiol. 2003;157:149-157.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pablo J, Banack SA, Cox PA, et al. Cyanobacterial neurotoxins in brain in ALS and Alzheimer disease. Acta Neurol Scand. 2009;120:216-225.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kondo K. Epidemiology of motor neuron disease. In: Leigh PN, Swash M, eds. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. London: Springer; 1995:19-34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chancellor AM, Warlow CP. Adult onset motor neuron disease: world-wide mortality, incidence and distribution since 1950. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 1992;55:1106-1115.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durrleman S, Alperovitch A. Increasing trend of ALS in France and elsewhere: are the changes real? Neurology. 1989;39:768-773.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kahana E, Zilber N. Changes in the incidence of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in Israel. Arch Neurol. 1984;41:157-160.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Annegers JF, Appel S, Lee JR, Perkins P. Incidence and prevalence of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in Harris County, Texas, 1985-1988. Arch Neurol. 1991;48:589-593.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGuire V, Lonstreth WT Jr, Nelson LM, et al. Occupational exposures and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a population-based case-control study. Am J Epidemiol. 1997;145:1076-1088.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy M, Quinn S, Young J, Parkin P, Taylor B. Increasing incidence of ALS in Canterbury, New Zealand: a 22-year study. Neurology. 2008;71:1889-1895.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaldivar T, Gutierrez J, Lara G, Carbonara M, Logroscino G, Hardiman O. Reduced frequency of ALS in an ethnically mixed population: a population-based mortality study. Neurology. 2009;72:1640-1645.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu L, Liu T, Liu L, et al. Global variation in prevalence and incidence of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Neurol. 2019. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00415-019-09652-y. PMID: 31797084.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chio A, Logroscino G, Traynor BJ, et al. Global epidemiology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a systematic review of the published literature. Neuroepidemiology. 2013;41:118-130.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marin B, Boumedienne F, Logroscino G, et al. Variation in worldwide incidence of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a meta-analysis. Int J Epidemiol. 2017;46:57-74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chio A, Swash M. Alcohol and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a possible neuroprotective effect. Eur J Neurol. 2016;23:221-222.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pupillo E, Bianchi E, Vanacore N, Montalto C, Robustelli della Cuna FS, Beghi E. EPI-02. Soccer and ALS: the last season of an Italian soap opera. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2019;20(suppl S1):101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner MR, Wicks P, Brownstein CA, et al. Concordance between the site of onset and limb dominance in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2011;82:853-854.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polymenidou M, Cleveland D. The seeds of neurodegeneration: prion-like spreading in ALS. Cell. 2011;147:498-508.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackenzie IR, Rademakers R, Neumann M. TDP-43 and FUS in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal dementia. Lancet Neurol. 2010;10:995-1007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wells C, Brennan SE, Keon M, Saksena NK. Prionoid proteins in the pathogenesis of neurodegenerative diseases. Front Mol Neurosci. 2019;12:271.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arthur KC, Calvo A, Price TR, Geiger JT, Chio A, Traynor BJ. Projected increase in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis from 2015 to 2040. Nat Commun. 2016;7:12408.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Chalabi A, Calvo A, Chio A, et al. Analysis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis as a multistep process: a population-based modelling study. Lancet Neurol. 2014;13:1108-1113.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S, Westeneng HJ, Al-Chalabi A, Van Den Berg LH, Talman P, Kiernan MC. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis as a multi-step process: an Australia population study. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2019;20:532-537.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chio A, Mazzini L, D'Alfonso S, et al. The multistep hypothesis of ALS revisited: the role of genetic mutations. Neurology. 2018;91:e635-e642.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Talbot K. Familial versus sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a false dichotomy. Brain. 2011;134:3429-3431.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>