<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">32141984</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1537-1603</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>38</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Jul</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of clinical neurophysiology : official publication of the American Electroencephalographic Society</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Clin Neurophysiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Intrarater and Interrater Reliability of Heckmatt Scoring System in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>293</StartPage><EndPage>298</EndPage><MedlinePgn>293-298</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/WNP.0000000000000690</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This study aims to determine the intrarater and interrater reliability of the Heckmatt score in the upper extremity muscles in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and to investigate its relationship with the clinical features and quantitative echo intensity measurements.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">The Heckmatt scores of multiple upper extremity muscles were calculated in 28 patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and examined the relationships of these values with quantitative ultrasound (QUS) measurements and the Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Functional Rating Scale-Revised.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The Heckmatt scores showed strong intrarater and interrater correlations with Cohen's Kappa scores ranging from 0.7 to 0.91. In all investigated muscles, the Heckmatt scores showed moderate correlations with quantitative echo intensity measurements and Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Functional Rating Scale-Revised dressing subscale.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The Heckmatt score is a reliable method in evaluating muscles of the upper extremities in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. It moderately correlates with quantitative values and functional status.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2020 by the American Clinical Neurophysiology Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kenis-Coskun</LastName><ForeName>Ozge</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departments of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gunes</LastName><ForeName>Taskin</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurology, Marmara University Medical Faculty, Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Isak</LastName><ForeName>Baris</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurology, Marmara University Medical Faculty, Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yagci</LastName><ForeName>Ilker</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departments of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016430">Clinical Trial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Clin Neurophysiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8506708</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0736-0258</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000369" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged, 80 and over</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003430" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Sectional Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015203" MajorTopicYN="N">Reproducibility of Results</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012720" MajorTopicYN="Y">Severity of Illness Index</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014463" MajorTopicYN="N">Ultrasonography</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D034941" MajorTopicYN="N">Upper Extremity</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors have no funding or conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32141984</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/WNP.0000000000000690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00004691-202107000-00007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Tindall B, Council MR. Aids to the investigation of the peripheral nervous system. London: Medical Research Council, 1986.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arts IM, van Rooij FG, Overeem S, et al. Quantitative muscle ultrasonography in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ultrasound Med Biol 2008;34:354&#x2013;361.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pathak S, Caress JB, Wosiski-Kuhn M, Milligan C, Williams D, Cartwright MS. A pilot study of neuromuscular ultrasound as a biomarker for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve 2019;59:181&#x2013;186.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martinez-Paya JJ, Rios-Diaz J, Medina-Mirapeix F, Vazquez-Costa JF, Del Bano-Aledo ME. Monitoring progression of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis using ultrasound morpho-textural muscle biomarkers: a pilot study. Ultrasound Med Biol 2018;44:102&#x2013;109.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cartwright MS, Walker FO, Griffin LP, Caress JB. Peripheral nerve and muscle ultrasound in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve 2011;44:346&#x2013;351.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Florence JM, Pandya S, King WM, et al. Intrarater reliability of manual muscle test (Medical Research Council scale) grades in Duchenne's muscular dystrophy. Phys Ther 1992;72:115&#x2013;122. discussion 122&#x2013;116.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Dengler R, Eisen A, et al. Electrodiagnostic criteria for diagnosis of ALS. Clin Neurophysiol 2008;119:497&#x2013;503.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Traynor BJ, Codd MB, Corr B, Forde C, Frost E, Hardiman OM. Clinical features of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis according to the El Escorial and Airlie House diagnostic criteria: a population-based study. Arch Neurol 2000;57:1171&#x2013;1176.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verma A, Bradley WG. Atypical motor neuron disease and related motor syndromes. Semin Neurol 2001;21:177&#x2013;187.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filiz K, Balal M, Demir T, Alparslan ZN, Sarica Y. Adaptation to Turkish and reliability study of the revised Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Functional Rating Scale (ALSFRS-R). Arch Neuropsychiatry 2016;53:229.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum JM, Stambler N, Malta E, et al. The ALSFRS-R: a revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. BDNF ALS Study Group (Phase III). J Neurol Sci 1999;169:13&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seok HY, Park J, Kim YH, Oh KW, Kim SH, Kim BJ. Split hand muscle echo intensity index as a reliable imaging marker for differential diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2018;89:943&#x2013;948.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arts IM, Pillen S, Schelhaas HJ, Overeem S, Zwarts MJ. Normal values for quantitative muscle ultrasonography in adults. Muscle Nerve 2010;41:32&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heckmatt JZ, Leeman S, Dubowitz V. Ultrasound imaging in the diagnosis of muscle disease. J Pediatr 1982;101:656&#x2013;660.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nielsen PK, Jensen BR, Darvann T, Jorgensen K, Bakke M. Quantitative ultrasound tissue characterization in shoulder and thigh muscles&#x2014;a new approach. BMC Musculoskelet Disord 2006;7:2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Weighted kappa: nominal scale agreement with provision for scaled disagreement or partial credit. Psychol Bull 1968;70:213&#x2013;220.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arts IM, Overeem S, Pillen S, Schelhaas HJ, Zwarts MJ. Muscle ultrasonography to predict survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2011;82:552&#x2013;554.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arts IMP, Overeem S, Pillen S, Jurgen Schelhaas H, Zwarts MJ. Muscle changes in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a longitudinal ultrasonography study. Clin Neurophysiol 2011;122:623&#x2013;628.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martinez-Paya JJ, Del Bano-Aledo ME, Rios-Diaz J, Tembl-Ferrairo JI, Vazquez-Costa JF, Medina-Mirapeix F. Muscular echovariation: a new biomarker in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ultrasound Med Biol 2017;43:1153&#x2013;1162.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>