<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">32159905</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>06</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2702</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>29</Volume><Issue>13-14</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of clinical nursing</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Clin Nurs</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Everyday life experiences of close relatives of people with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis receiving home mechanical ventilation-A qualitative study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2306</StartPage><EndPage>2316</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2306-2316</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/jocn.15239</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="AIMS AND OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To explore everyday life experience of relatives of people with amytrophic&#xa0;lateral sclerosis (ALS) living at home with mechanical ventilation and formal caregivers.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">ALS is a rapidly progressive disease affecting not only the patient but also close relatives. A burden is placed on relatives affecting their mental and physical health in settings where they provide care. Few studies have examined the everyday life challenges of close relatives with formal caregivers at home and home mechanical ventilation, which often prolongs survival.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DESIGN" NlmCategory="METHODS">We undertook a qualitative study with a phenomenological-hermeneutic approach inspired by Ricoeur. Eleven close relatives were interviewed, and the three-level analysis method developed by Dreyer and Pedersen was conducted. The Consolidated Criteria for Reporting Qualitative Research checklist was used.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Four themes were derived from the data during analysis: Vulnerable relatives fighting to keep track of everything, Formal caregivers-a distressing relief, A prison without personal space and We are in this together until the end.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Close relatives of persons with ALS are burdened with everyday life challenges despite having formal caregivers at home, and they feel imprisoned. Despite these challenges and concerns about the end of life of their relative, they stay until the end.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RELEVANCE TO CLINICAL PRACTICE" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">There is clearly a need to investigate interventions in clinical practice supporting close relatives to prepare them for what to expect during a prolonged disease course.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020 John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Winther</LastName><ForeName>Dorte</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5320-0431</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Intensive Care, Aarhus University Hospital, Aarhus N, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kirkegaard Lorenzen</LastName><ForeName>Charlotte</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Intensive Care, Aarhus University Hospital, Aarhus N, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dreyer</LastName><ForeName>Pia</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3581-7438</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Intensive Care, Aarhus University Hospital, Aarhus N, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Public Health, Section of Nursing, Aarhus University, Aarhus C, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Clin Nurs</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9207302</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0962-1067</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000451" MajorTopicYN="Y">nursing</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017028" MajorTopicYN="N">Caregivers</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="Y">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018450" MajorTopicYN="Y">Disease Progression</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005190" MajorTopicYN="N">Family</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="Y">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011368" MajorTopicYN="N">Professional-Family Relations</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D036301" MajorTopicYN="N">Qualitative Research</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012121" MajorTopicYN="N">Respiration, Artificial</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000451" MajorTopicYN="N">nursing</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">caregiver burden</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">carers</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mechanical ventilation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neurology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">qualitative study</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">relative</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32159905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jocn.15239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Andersen, P. M., Abrahams, S., Borasio, G. D., de Carvalho, M., Chio, A., Van Damme, P., &#x2026; Weber, M. (2012). EFNS guidelines on the clinical management of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (MALS)? Revised report of an EFNS task force. European Journal of Neurology, 19(3), 360-375. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1468-1331.2011.03501.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anonymous (2003). Ethical guidelines for nursing research in the nordic countries [etiske retningslinier for sygeplejeforskning i norden]. Edn.: Sykepleiernes samarbeid i norden. Oslo.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aoun, S. M., Deas, K., Kristjanson, L. J., &amp; Kissane, D. W. (2017). Identifying and addressing the support needs of family caregivers of people with motor neurone disease using the carer support needs assessment tool. Palliative &amp; Supportive Care, 15(1), 32-43. https://doi.org/10.1017/S1478951516000341</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baxter, S. K., Baird, W. O., Thompson, S., Bianchi, S. M., Walters, S. J., Lee, E., &#x2026; McDermott, C. J. (2013). The impact on the family carer of motor neurone disease and intervention with noninvasive ventilation. Journal of Palliative Medicine, 16(12), 162-1609. https://doi.org/10.1089/jpm.2013.0211</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bock, M., Duong, Y. N., Kim, A., Allen, I., Murphy, J., &amp; Lomen-Hoerth, C. (2016). Cognitive-behavioral changes in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Screening prevalence and impact on patients and caregivers. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis &amp; Frontotemporal Degeneration, 17(5-6), 366-373. https://doi.org/10.3109/21678421.2016.1165257</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bradbury-Jones, C., Sambrook, S., &amp; Irvine, F. (2009). The phenomenological focus group: An oxymoron? Journal of Advanced Nursing, 65(3), 663-671. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2648.2008.04922.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruletti, G., Comini, L., Scalvini, S., Morini, R., Luisa, A., Paneroni, M., &amp; Vitacca, M. (2015). A two-year longitudinal study on strain and needs in caregivers of advanced ALS patients. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis &amp; Frontotemporal Degeneration, 16(3-4), 187-195. https://doi.org/10.3109/21678421.2014.974616</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke, T., Elamin, M., Galvin, M., Hardiman, O., &amp; Pender, N. (2015). Caregiver burden in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A cross-sectional investigation of predictors. Journal of Neurology, 262(6), 1526-1532. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00415-015-7746-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Creemers, H., de Moree, S., Veldink, J. H., Nollet, F., van den Berg, L. H., &amp; Beelen, A. (2016). Factors related to caregiver strain in ALS: A longitudinal study. Journal of Neurology, Neurosurgery, and Psychiatry, 87(7), 775-781. https://doi.org/10.1136/jnnp-2015-311651</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dreyer, P., Lorenzen, C. K., Schou, L., &amp; Felding, M. (2014). Survival in ALS with home mechanical ventilation non-invasively and invasively: A 15-year cohort study in west Denmark. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis &amp; Frontotemporal Degeneration, 15(1-2), 62-67. https://doi.org/10.3109/21678421.2013.837929</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dreyer, P. S., &amp; Pedersen, B. D. (2009). Distanciation in Ricoeur's theory of interpretation: Narrations in a study of life experiences of living with chronic illness and home mechanical ventilation. Nursing Inquiry, 16(1), 64-73. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1440-1800.2009.00433.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dybwik, K., Toll&#xe5;li, T., Nielsen, E. W., &amp; Brinchmann, B. S. (2010). Why does the provision of home mechanical ventilation vary so widely? Chron Respir Dis, 7(2), 67-73. https://doi.org/10.1177/1479972309357497</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dybwik, K., Tollali, T., Nielsen, E. W., &amp; Brinchmann, B. S. (2011). "Fighting the system": Families caring for ventilator-dependent children and adults with complex health care needs at home. BMC Health Services Research, 11, 156-6963-11-156. https://doi.org/10.1186/1472-6963-11-156</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galvin, M., Corr, B., Madden, C., Mays, I., McQuillan, R., Timonen, V., &#x2026; Hardiman, O. (2016). Caregiving in ALS - a mixed methods approach to the study of burden. BMC Palliative Care, 15(1), 81-016-0153-0. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12904-016-0153-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gauthier, A., Vignola, A., Calvo, A., Cavallo, E., Moglia, C., Sellitti, L., &#x2026; Chio, A. (2007). A longitudinal study on quality of life and depression in ALS patient-caregiver couples. Neurology, 68(12), 923-926.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gelinas, D. F., O'Connor, P., &amp; Miller, R. G. (1998). Quality of life for ventilator-dependent ALS patients and their caregivers. Journal of the Neurological Sciences, 160(Suppl 1), S134-S136.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaub-Wittemer, D., Steinbuchel, N., Wasner, M., Laier-Groeneveld, G., &amp; Borasio, G. D. (2003). Quality of life and psychosocial issues in ventilated patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and their caregivers. Journal of Pain and Symptom Management, 26(4), 890-896.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kvale, S., &amp; Brinkmann, S. (2009). Interviews: Learning the craft of qualitative research interviewing, 2nd ed. Los Angeles, CA: Sage Publications.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marconi, A., Meloni, G., Fossati, F., Lunetta, C., Bastianello, S., Melazzini, M., &#x2026; Corbo, M. (2012). Aggressiveness, sexuality, and obsessiveness in late stages of ALS patients and their effects on caregivers. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis: Official Publication of the World Federation of Neurology Research Group on Motor Neuron Diseases, 13(5), 452-458. https://doi.org/10.3109/17482968.2012.696658</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell, L. A., Hirdes, J., Poss, J. W., Slegers-Boyd, C., Caldarelli, H., &amp; Martin, L. (2015). Informal caregivers of clients with neurological conditions: Profiles, patterns and risk factors for distress from a home care prevalence study. BMC Health Services Research, 15, 350-015-1010-1. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12913-015-1010-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mockford, C., Jenkinson, C., &amp; Fitzpatrick, R. (2006). A review: Carers, MND and service provision. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis: Official Publication of the World Federation of Neurology Research Group on Motor Neuron Diseases, 7(3), 132-141.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mustfa, N., Walsh, E., Bryant, V., Lyall, R. A., Addington-Hall, J., Goldstein, L. H., &#x2026; Leigh, P. N. (2006). The effect of noninvasive ventilation on ALS patients and their caregivers. Neurology, 66(8), 1211-1217.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh, J., An, J. W., Oh, K. W., Oh, S. I., Kim, J. A., Kim, S. H., &amp; Lee, J. S. (2015). Depression and caregiving burden in families of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Journal of Korean Academy of Nursing, 45(2), 202-210. https://doi.org/10.4040/jkan.2015.45.2.202</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olsson Ozanne, A., Graneheim, U., Persson, L., &amp; Strang, S. (2012). Factors that facilitate and hinder the manageability of living with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in both patients and next of kin. Journal of Clinical Nursing, 21(9), 1364-1373. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2702.2011.03809.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozanne, A. O., Graneheim, U. H., &amp; Strang, S. (2015). Struggling to find meaning in life among spouses of people with ALS. Palliative &amp; Supportive Care, 13(4), 909-916. https://doi.org/10.1017/S1478951514000625</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pagnini, F., Rossi, G., Lunetta, C., Banfi, P., Castelnuovo, G., Corbo, M., &amp; Molinari, E. (2010). Burden, depression, and anxiety in caregivers of people with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Psychology, Health &amp; Medicine, 15(6), 685-693. https://doi.org/10.1080/13548506.2010.507773</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peters, M., Fitzpatrick, R., Doll, H., Playford, E. D., &amp; Jenkinson, C. (2012). The impact of perceived lack of support provided by health and social care services to caregivers of people with motor neuron disease. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis: Official Publication of the World Federation of Neurology Research Group on Motor Neuron Diseases, 13(2), 223-228. https://doi.org/10.3109/17482968.2011.649759</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinho, A. C., &amp; Goncalves, E. (2016). Are amyotrophic lateral sclerosis caregivers at higher risk for health problems? Acta Medica Portuguesa, 29(1), 56-62. https://doi.org/10.20344/amp.6590</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ricoeur, P. (1973a). Creativity in language. Philosophy Today, 17(2), 97-111.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ricoeur, P. (1973b). From existentialism to the philosophy of language. Philosophy Today, 17(2), 88-96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ricoeur, P. (1976). Interpretation theory: Discourse and the surplus of meaning, 1st ed. Fort Worth, TX: Texas Christian University Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simon&#xff;, C. P., Pedersen, B. D., Dreyer, P., &amp; Birkelund, R. (2015). Dealing with existential anxiety in exercise-based cardiac rehabilitation: A phenomenological-hermeneutic study of patients' lived experiences. Journal of Clinical Nursing, 24(17-18), 2581-2590. https://doi.org/10.1111/jocn.12867</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strong, M. J., Abrahams, S., Goldstein, L. H., Woolley, S., Mclaughlin, P., Snowden, J., &#x2026; Turner, M. R. (2017). Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis - frontotemporal spectrum disorder (ALS-FTSD): Revised diagnostic criteria. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis &amp; Frontotemporal Degeneration, 18(3-4), 153-174. https://doi.org/10.1080/21678421.2016.1267768</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sundhed.dk (2019). Amyotrofisk lateral sclerose. Retrieved from https://www.sundhed.dk/sundhedsfaglig/laegehaandbogen/neurologi/tilstande-og-sygdomme/oevrige-sygdomme/amyotrofisk-lateral-sklerose/ Assessed 26 October 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sundling, I., Ekman, S., Weinberg, J., &amp; Klefbeck, B. (2009). Patients' with ALS and caregivers' experiences of non-invasive home ventilation. Advances in Physiotherapy, 11(3), 114-120. https://doi.org/10.1080/14038190701803351</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tong, A., Sainsbury, P., &amp; Craig, J. (2007). Consolidated criteria for reporting qualitative research (COREQ): A 32-item checklist for interviews and focus groups. International Journal for Quality in Health Care, 19, 349-357. https://doi.org/10.1093/intqhc/mzm042</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tramonti, F., Barsanti, I., Bongioanni, P., Bogliolo, C., &amp; Rossi, B. (2014). A permanent emergency: A longitudinal study on families coping with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Families, Systems &amp; Health: The Journal of Collaborative Family Healthcare, 32(3), 271-279. https://doi.org/10.1037/fsh0000032</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsara, V., Serasli, E., Voutsas, V., Lazarides, V., &amp; Christaki, P. (2006). Burden and coping strategies in families of patients under noninvasive home mechanical ventilation. Respiration, 73(1), 61-67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weisser, F. B., Bristowe, K., &amp; Jackson, D. (2015). Experiences of burden, needs, rewards and resilience in family caregivers of people living with motor neurone Disease/Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A secondary thematic analysis of qualitative interviews. Palliative Medicine, 29(8), 737-745. https://doi.org/10.1177/0269216315575851</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams, M. T., Donnelly, J. P., Holmlund, T., &amp; Battaglia, M. (2008). ALS: Family caregiver needs and quality of life. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis: Official Publication of the World Federation of Neurology Research Group on Motor Neuron Diseases, 9(5), 279-286. https://doi.org/10.1080/17482960801934148</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>