<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">32198562</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>06</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1432-1254</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>65</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of biometeorology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Biometeorol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The role of magnetic fields in neurodegenerative diseases.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>107</StartPage><EndPage>117</EndPage><MedlinePgn>107-117</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s00484-020-01896-y</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The term neurodegenerative diseases include a long list of diseases affecting the nervous system that are characterized by the degeneration of different neurological structures. Among them, Alzheimer disease (AD), Parkinson disease (PD), and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) are the most representative ones. The vast majority of cases&#xa0;are sporadic and results from the interaction of genes and environmental factors in genetically predisposed individuals. Among environmental conditions, electromagnetic field exposure has begun to be assessed as a potential risk factor for neurodegeneration. In this review, we discuss the existing literature regarding electromagnetic fields and neurodegenerative diseases. Epidemiological studies in AD, PD, and ALS have shown discordant results; thus, a clear correlation between electromagnetic exposure and neurodegeneration has not been demonstrated. In addition, we discuss the role of electromagnetic radiation as a potential non-invasive therapeutic strategy for some neurodegenerative diseases, particularly for PD and AD.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Riancho</LastName><ForeName>Javier</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Service of Neurology, Hospital Sierrallana-IDIVAL, Barrio Ganzo s/n, 39300, Torrelavega, Spain. javier.riancho86@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>CIBERNED, Barcelona, Spain. javier.riancho86@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medicine and Psychiatry Department, University of Cantabria, Santander, Spain. javier.riancho86@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sanchez de la Torre</LastName><ForeName>Jose Ram&#xf3;n</ForeName><Initials>JR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Service of Neurology, Hospital Sierrallana-IDIVAL, Barrio Ganzo s/n, 39300, Torrelavega, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Paz-Fajardo</LastName><ForeName>Luc&#xed;a</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Service of Internal Medicine, Hospital Sierrallana, Torrelavega, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Limia</LastName><ForeName>Cristina</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Service of Internal Medicine, Hospital Sierrallana, Torrelavega, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Santurtun</LastName><ForeName>Ana</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Legal Medicine and Toxicology Unit, Department of Physiology and Pharmacology, University of Cantabria, Santander, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cifra</LastName><ForeName>Michal</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Photonics and Electronics of the Czech Academy of Sciences, Chabersk&#xe1; 1014/57, 182 51, Prague, Czech Republic.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kourtidis</LastName><ForeName>Kostas</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Environmental Engineering, Democritus University of Thrace, 67100, Xanthi, Greece.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Environmental and Networking Technologies and Applications Unit (ENTA), Athena Research and Innovation Center, 67100, Xanthi, Greece.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fdez-Arroyabe</LastName><ForeName>Pablo</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Geography and Planning Department, Geobiomet Research Group, University of Cantabria, Santander, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Biometeorol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0374716</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0020-7128</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000544" MajorTopicYN="Y">Alzheimer Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004574" MajorTopicYN="N">Electromagnetic Fields</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019636" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neurodegenerative Diseases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010300" MajorTopicYN="Y">Parkinson Disease</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Electromagnetic fields</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neurodegenerative diseases</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Parkinson&#x2019;s disease</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32198562</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00484-020-01896-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s00484-020-01896-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Adair RK (1991) Constraints on biological effects of weak extremely-low-frequency electromagnetic fields. Phys Rev A 43(2):1039</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adair RK (2003) Biophysical limits on athermal effects of RF and microwave radiation. Bioelectromagnetics 24:39&#x2013;48</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aftanas LI, Gevorgyan MM, Zhanaeva SY, Dzemidovich SS, Kulikova KI, al&#x2019;perina E, Danilenko KV, Idova GV (2018) Therapeutic effects of repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation (rTMS) on neuroinflammation and neuroplasticity in patients with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: a placebo-controlled study. Bull Exp Biol Med 165:195&#x2013;199</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akbarnejad Z, Esmaeilpour K, Shabani M, Asadi-Shekaari M, Saeedi GM, Ahmadi-Zeidabadi M (2018) Spatial memory recovery in Alzheimer&#x2019;s rat model by electromagnetic field exposure. Int J Neurosci 128:691&#x2013;696</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al Chalabi A, Hardiman O (2013) The epidemiology of ALS: a conspiracy of genes, environment and time. Nat Rev Neurol 9:617&#x2013;628</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andr&#xe9;-Obadia N, Lamblin MD, Sauleau P (2015) French recommendations on electroencephalography. Neurophysiol Clin 45:1&#x2013;17</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anninos PA, Tsagas N, Sandyk R, Derpapas K (1991) Magnetic stimulation in the treatment of partial seizures. Int J Neurosci 60:141&#x2013;171</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anninos PA, Adamopoulos AV, Kotini A, Tsagas N (2000) Nonlinear analysis of brain activity in magnetic influenced Parkinson patients. Brain Topogr 13:35&#x2013;144</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arendash GW, Sanchez-Ramos J, Mori T, Mamcarz M, Lin X, Runfeldt M, Wang L, Zhang G, Sava V, Tan J, Cao C (2010) Electromagnetic field treatment protects against and reverses cognitive impairment in Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease mice. J Alzheimers Dis 19:191&#x2013;210</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barker AT, Jalinous R, Freeston IL (1985) Non-invasive magnetic stimulation of human motor cortex. Lancet 1:1106&#x2013;1107</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barnes FS, Greenebaum B (2015) The effects of weak magnetic fields on radical pairs: weak magnetic field effects on radicals. Bioelectromagnetics 36:45&#x2013;54</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bateman R (2015) Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease and other dementias: advances in 2014. Lancet Neurol 14:4&#x2013;6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benassi B, Filomeni G, Montagna C et al (2016) Extremely low frequency magnetic field (ELF-MF) exposure sensitizes SH-SY5Y cells to the pro-Parkinson&#x2019;s disease toxin MPP(.). Mol Neurobiol 53:4247&#x2013;4260</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bharath S, Hsu M, Kaur D, Rajagopalan S, Andersen JK (2002) Glutathione, iron and Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Biochem Pharmacol 64:1037&#x2013;1048</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brouwer M, Koeman T, van den Brandt PA, Kromhout H, Schouten LJ, Peters S, Huss A, Vermeulen R (2015) Occupational exposures and Parkinson&#x2019;s disease mortality in a prospective Dutch cohort. Occup Environ Med 72:448&#x2013;455</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Capone F, Dileone M, Profice P et al (2009) Does exposure to extremely low frequency magnetic fields produce functional changes in human brain? J Neural Transm (Vienna) 116:257&#x2013;265</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Capozzella A, Sacco C, Chighine A, Loreti B, Scala B, Casale T, Sinibaldi F, Tomei G, Giubilati R, Tomei F, Rosati MV (2014) Work related etiology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS): a meta-analysis. Ann Ig 26:456&#x2013;472</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castanedo-Vazquez D, Bosque-Varela P, Sainz-Pelayo A, Riancho J (2019) Infectious agents and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: another piece of the puzzle of motor neuron degeneration. J Neurol 266:27&#x2013;36</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chafai DE, Sulimenko V, Havelka D, Kub&#xed;nov&#xe1; L, Dr&#xe1;ber P, Cifra M (2019) Reversible and irreversible modulation of tubulin self-assembly by intense nanosecond pulsed electric fields. Adv Mater 31:1903636</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cherry NJ (2002) Schumann resonances, a plausible biophysical mechanism for the human health effects of solar/geomagnetic activity. Nat Hazards 26:279&#x2013;331</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chou YH, Hickey PT, Sundman M, Song AW, Chen NK (2015) Effects of repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation on motor symptoms in Parkinson disease: a systematic review and meta-analysis. JAMA Neurol 72:432&#x2013;440</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cifra M, Fields JZ, Farhadi A (2011) Electromagnetic cellular interactions. Prog Biophys Mol Biol 105:223&#x2013;246</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Concei&#xe7;&#xe3;o R, Melg&#xe3;o M, Silva HG, Nicoll K, Harrison RG, Reis AH (2016) Transport of the smoke plume from Chiado&#x2019;s fire in Lisbon (Portugal) sensed by atmospheric electric field measurements. Air Qual Atmos Health 9:275&#x2013;283</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Consales C, Merla C, Marino C, Benassi B (2012) Electromagnetic fields, oxidative stress, and neurodegeneration. Int J Cell Biol 2012:683897</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davanipour Z, Tseng CC, Lee PJ, Sobel E (2007) A case-control study of occupational magnetic field exposure and Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease: results from the California Alzheimer&#x2019;s Disease Diagnosis and Treatment Centers. BMC Neurol 7:13</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demitrack MA, Thase ME (2009) Clinical significance of transcranial magnetic stimulation (TMS) in the treatment of pharmacoresistant depression: synthesis of recent data. Psychopharmacol Bull 42:5&#x2013;38</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fdez-Arroyabe P, Lecha Estela L, Schimt F (2018) Digital divide, biometeorological data infrastructures and human vulnerability definition. Int J Biometeorol 62:733&#x2013;740</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feychting M, Jonsson F, Pedersen NL, Ahlbom A (2003) Occupational magnetic field exposure and neurodegenerative disease. Epidemiology. 14:413&#x2013;419</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frei P, Poulsen AH, Mezei G et al (2013) Residential distance to high-voltage power lines and risk of neurodegenerative diseases: a Danish population-based case-control study. Am J Epidemiol 177:970&#x2013;978</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibson SB, Abbott D, Farnham JM, Thai KK, McLean H, Figueroa KP, Bromberg MB, Pulst SM, Cannon-Albright L (2016) Population-based risks for cancer in patients with ALS. Neurology 87:289&#x2013;294</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graves AB, Rosner D, Echeverria D, Yost M, Larson EB (1999) Occupational exposure to electromagnetic fields and Alzheimer disease. Alzheimer Dis Assoc Disord 13:165&#x2013;170</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gunnarsson LG, Bodin L (2017) Parkinson&#x2019;s disease and occupational exposures: a systematic literature review and meta-analyses. Scand J Work Environ Health 43:197&#x2013;209</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gunnarsson LG, Bodin L (2019) Occupational exposures and neurodegenerative diseases-a systematic literature review and meta-analyses. Int J Environ Res Public Health:16</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe5;kansson N, Gustavsson P, Johansen C, Floderus B (2003) Neurodegenerative diseases in welders and other workers exposed to high levels of magnetic fields. Epidemiology. 14:420&#x2013;426</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halberg F (1963) Circadian (about twenty-four-hour) rhythms in experimental medicine. Proc R Soc Med 56:253&#x2013;257</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harrison RG, Nicoll KA, Aplin KL (2017) Evaluating stratiform cloud base charge remotely. Geophys Res Lett 44:6407&#x2013;6412</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hebert LE, Scherr PA, Bienias JL, Bennett DA, Evans DA (2003) Alzheimer disease in the US population: prevalence estimates using the 2000 census. Arch Neurol 60:1119&#x2013;1122</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hei WH, Byun SH, Kim JS et al (2016) Effects of electromagnetic field (PEMF) exposure at different frequency and duration on the peripheral nerve regeneration: in vitro and in vivo study. Int J Neurosci 126:739&#x2013;748</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hekstra DR, Ian White K, Socolich MA, Henning RW, &#x160;rajer V, Ranganathan R (2016) Electric-field-stimulated protein mechanics. Nature 540:400&#x2013;405</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoogendam JM, Ramakers GM, Di Lazzaro V (2010) Physiology of repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation of the human brain. Brain Stimul 3:95&#x2013;118</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hug K, R&#xf6;&#xf6;sli M, Rapp R (2006) Magnetic field exposure and neurodegenerative diseases--recent epidemiological studies. Soz Praventivmed 51:210&#x2013;220</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huss A, Spoerri A, Egger M, Kromhout H, Vermeulen R (2015a) Occupational exposure to magnetic fields and electric shocks and risk of ALS: the Swiss National Cohort. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 16:80&#x2013;85</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huss A, Koeman T, Kromhout H, Vermeulen R (2015b) Extremely low frequency magnetic field exposure and Parkinson&#x2019;s disease--a systematic review and meta-analysis of the data. Int J Environ Res Public Health 12:7348&#x2013;7356</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huss A, Peters S, Vermeulen R (2018) Occupational exposure to extremely low-frequency magnetic fields and the risk of ALS: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Bioelectromagnetics 39:156&#x2013;163</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ilieva S, Cheshmedzhieva D, Dudev T (2019) Electric field influence on the helical structure of peptides: insights from DFT/PCM computations. Phys Chem Chem Phys 21:16198&#x2013;16206</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jadidi M, Biat SM, Sameni HR, Safari M, Vafaei AA, Ghahari L (2016) Mesenchymal stem cells that located in the electromagnetic fields improves rat model of Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Iran J Basic Med Sci 19:741&#x2013;748</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jagust W (2018) Imaging the evolution and pathophysiology of Alzheimer disease. Nat Rev Neurosci 19:687&#x2013;700</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang DP, Li J, Zhang J, Xu SL, Kuang F, Lang HY, Wang YF, An GZ, Li JH, Guo GZ (2013) Electromagnetic pulse exposure induces overexpression of beta amyloid protein in rats. Arch Med Res 44:178&#x2013;184</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang DP, Li J, Zhang J, Xu SL, Kuang F, Lang HY, Wang YF, An GZ, Li J, Guo GZ (2016) Long-term electromagnetic pulse exposure induces Abeta deposition and cognitive dysfunction through oxidative stress and overexpression of APP and BACE1. Brain Res 1642:10&#x2013;19</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johansen C (2000) Exposure to electromagnetic fields and risk of central nervous system disease in utility workers. Epidemiology. 11:539&#x2013;543</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johansen C, Olsen JH (1998) Mortality from amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, other chronic disorders, and electric shocks among utility workers. Am J Epidemiol 148:362&#x2013;368</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasper S, H&#xf6;flich G (1993) Application of transcranial magnetic stimulation in treatment of drug-resistant major depression&#x2014;a report of two cases. Hum Psychopharmacol</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koeman T, Slottje P, Schouten LJ, Peters S, Huss A, Veldink JH, Kromhout H, van den Brandt PA, Vermeulen R (2017) Occupational exposure and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in a prospective cohort. Occup Environ Med 74:578&#x2013;585</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ku&#x10d;era O, Cifra M (2013) Cell-to-cell signaling through light: just a ghost of chance? Cell Commun Signal 11:1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lefaucheur JP, Andr&#xe9;-Obadia N, Antal A et al (2014) Evidence-based guidelines on the therapeutic use of repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation (rTMS). Clin Neurophysiol 125:2150&#x2013;2206</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lekhraj R, Cynamon DE, DeLuca SE, Taub ES, Pilla AA, Casper D (2014) Pulsed electromagnetic fields potentiate neurite outgrowth in the dopaminergic MN9D cell line. J Neurosci Res 92:761&#x2013;771</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lerchl A, Nonaka KO, Reiter RJ (1991) Pineal gland &#x201c;magnetosensitivity&#x201d; to static magnetic fields is a consequence of induced electric currents (eddy currents). J Pineal Res 10:109&#x2013;116</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewczuk B, Redlarski G, &#x17b;ak A et al (2014) Influence of electric, magnetic, and electromagnetic fields on the circadian system: current stage of knowledge. Biomed Res Int 2014:169459</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li CY, Sung FC (2003) Association between occupational exposure to power frequency electromagnetic fields and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a review. Am J Ind Med 43:212&#x2013;220</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Yan X, Liu J, Li L, Hu X, Sun H, Tian J (2014) Pulsed electromagnetic field enhances brain-derived neurotrophic factor expression through L-type voltage-gated calcium channel- and Erk-dependent signaling pathways in neonatal rat dorsal root ganglion neurons. Neurochem Int 75:96&#x2013;104</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longo FM, Yang T, Hamilton S, Hyde JF, Walker J, Jennes L, Stach R, Sisken BF (1999) Electromagnetic fields influence NGF activity and levels following sciatic nerve transection. J Neurosci Res 55:230&#x2013;237</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macias MY, Battocletti JH, Sutton CH, Pintar FA, Maiman DJ (2000) Directed and enhanced neurite growth with pulsed magnetic field stimulation. Bioelectromagnetics. 21:272&#x2013;286</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malling ASB, Morberg BM, Wermuth L, Gredal O, Bech P, Jensen BR (2018) Effect of transcranial pulsed electromagnetic fields (T-PEMF) on functional rate of force development and movement speed in persons with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: a randomized clinical trial. PLoS One 13:e0204478</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malling ASB, Morberg BM, Wermuth L, Gredal O, Bech P, Jensen BR (2019) The effect of 8&#x2009;weeks of treatment with transcranial pulsed electromagnetic fields on hand tremor and inter-hand coherence in persons with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. J Neuroeng Rehabil 16:19</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marracino P, Havelka D, Pr&#x16f;&#x161;a J, Liberti M, Tuszynski J, Ayoub AT, Apollonio F, Cifra M (2019) Tubulin response to intense nanosecond-scale electric field in molecular dynamics simulation. Sci Rep 9:10477</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCartney DL, Stevenson AJ, Walker RM, Gibson J, Morris SW, Campbell A, Murray AD, Whalley HC, Porteous DJ, McIntosh AM, Evans KL, Deary IJ, Marioni RE (2018) Investigating the relationship between DNA methylation age acceleration and risk factors for Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. Alzheimers Dement (Amst) 10:429&#x2013;437</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller BL, Boeve BF (2013) The behavioral neurology of dementia. Cambridge University Press, Cambridge</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morberg BM, Malling AS, Jensen BR, Gredal O, Bech P, Wermuth L (2018) Effects of transcranial pulsed electromagnetic field stimulation on quality of life in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Eur J Neurol 25:963&#x2013;e974</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noonan CW, Reif JS, Yost M, Touchstone J (2002) Occupational exposure to magnetic fields in case-referent studies of neurodegenerative diseases. Scand J Work Environ Health 28:42&#x2013;48</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panagopoulos DJ, Chrousos GP (2019) Shielding methods and products against man-made electromagnetic fields: protection versus risk. Sci Total Environ 667:255&#x2013;262</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park RM, Schulte PA, Bowman JD, Walker JT, Bondy SC, Yost MG, Touchstone JA, Dosemeci M (2005) Potential occupational risks for neurodegenerative diseases. Am J Ind Med 48:63&#x2013;77</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedersen C, Poulsen AH, Rod NH et al (2017) Occupational exposure to extremely low-frequency magnetic fields and risk for central nervous system disease: an update of a Danish cohort study among utility workers. Int Arch Occup Environ Health 90:619&#x2013;628</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petri AK, Schmiedchen K, Stunder D, Dechent D, Kraus T, Bailey WH, Driessen S (2017) Biological effects of exposure to static electric fields in humans and vertebrates: a systematic review. Environ Health 16:41</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poulletier de Gannes F, Ruffi&#xe9; G, Taxile M, Ladev&#xe8;ze E, Hurtier A, Haro E, Duleu S, Charlet de Sauvage R, Billaudel B, Geffard M, Veyret B, Lagroye I (2009) Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) and extremely-low frequency (ELF) magnetic fields: a study in the SOD-1 transgenic mouse model. Amyotroph Lateral Scler 10:370&#x2013;373</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiu C, Fratiglioni L, Karp A, Winblad B, Bellander T (2004) Occupational exposure to electromagnetic fields and risk of Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. Epidemiology 15:687&#x2013;694</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahbek UL, Tritsaris K, Dissing S (2005) Interactions of low-frequency, pulsed electromagnetic fields with living tissueb biochemical responses and clinical results. Oral Biosci Med 2:1&#x2013;12</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riancho J, Lozano-Cuesta P, Santurtun A, Sanchez-Juan P, Lopez-Vega JM, Berciano J, Polo JM (2016) Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in Northern Spain 40 years later: what has changed? Neurodegener Dis 16:337&#x2013;341</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riancho J, Vazquez-Higuera JL, Pozueta A, Lage C, Kazimierczak M, Bravo M, Calero M, Gonzalez A, Rodriguez E, Lleo A, Sanchez-Juan P (2017) MicroRNA profile in patients with Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease: analysis of miR-9-5p and miR-598 in raw and exosome enriched cerebrospinal fluid samples. J Alzheimers Dis 57:483&#x2013;491</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riancho J, Bosque-Varela P, Perez-Pereda S, Povedano M, de Munain AL, Santurtun A (2018) The increasing importance of environmental conditions in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Int J Biometeorol 62:1361&#x2013;1374</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riancho J, Gonzalo I, Ruiz-Soto M, Berciano J (2019) Why do motor neurons degenerate? Actualization in the pathogenesis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurologia 34:27&#x2013;37</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xf6;&#xf6;sli M, L&#xf6;rtscher M, Egger M, Pfluger D, Schreier N, L&#xf6;rtscher E, Locher P, Spoerri A, Minder C (2007) Mortality from neurodegenerative disease and exposure to extremely low-frequency magnetic fields: 31 years of observations on Swiss railway employees. Neuroepidemiology. 28:197&#x2013;206</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandyk R (1995a) Improvement in short-term visual memory by weak electromagnetic fields in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Int J Neurosci 81:67&#x2013;82</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandyk R (1995b) Improvement of body image perception in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease by treatment with weak electromagnetic fields. Int J Neurosci 82:269&#x2013;283</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandyk R, Iacono RP (1993) Rapid improvement of visuoperceptive functions by picotesla range magnetic fields in patients with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Int J Neurosci 70:233&#x2013;254</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandyk R, Iacono RP (1994) Reversal of micrographia in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease by application of picotesla range magnetic fields. Int J Neurosci 77:77&#x2013;84</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandyk R, Anninos PA, Tsagas N, Derpapas K (1992) Magnetic fields in the treatment of Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Int J Neurosci 63:141&#x2013;150</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santurtun A, Villar A, Delgado-Alvarado M, Riancho J (2016) Trends in motor neuron disease: association with latitude and air lead levels in Spain. Neurol Sci 37:1271&#x2013;1275</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Savitz DA, Checkoway H, Loomis DP (1998a) Magnetic field exposure and neurodegenerative disease mortality among electric utility workers. Epidemiology 9:398&#x2013;404</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Savitz DA, Loomis DP, Tse CK (1998b) Electrical occupations and neurodegenerative disease: analysis of U.S. mortality data. Arch Environ Health 53:71&#x2013;74</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seidler A, Geller P, Nienhaus A, Bernhardt T, Ruppe I, Eggert S, Hietanen M, Kauppinen T, Frolich L (2007) Occupational exposure to low frequency magnetic fields and dementia: a case-control study. Occup Environ Med 64:108&#x2013;114</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selmaoui B, Lambrozo J, Touitou Y (1996) Magnetic fields and pineal function in humans: evaluation of nocturnal acute exposure to extremely low frequency magnetic fields on serum melatonin and urinary 6-sulfatoxymelatonin circadian rhythms. Life Sci 58:1539&#x2013;1549</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Semm P (1992) Pineal function in mammals and birds is altered by earth-strength magnetic fields. In: Electromagnetic fields and circadian rhythmicity. Birkh&#xe4;user Boston, Boston, pp 53&#x2013;62</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva HG, Lopes FM, Pereira S, Nicoll K, Barbosa SM, Concei&#xe7;&#xe3;o R, Neves S, Harrison RG, Collares Pereira M (2016) Saharan dust electrification perceived by a triangle of atmospheric electricity stations in Southern Portugal. J Electrost 84:106&#x2013;120</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh D (2007) The atmospheric global electric circuit: an overview. Atmos Res 84:91&#x2013;110</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sobel E, Dunn M, Davanipour Z, Qian Z, Chui HC (1996) Elevated risk of Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease among workers with likely electromagnetic field exposure. Neurology 47:1477&#x2013;1481</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soderqvist F, Hardell L, Carlberg M, Mild KH (2010) Radiofrequency fields, transthyretin, and Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. J Alzheimers Dis 20:599&#x2013;606</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Son Y, Jeong YJ, Kwon JH, Choi HD, Pack JK, Kim N, Lee YS, Lee HJ (2016) 1950 MHz radiofrequency electromagnetic fields do not aggravate memory deficits in 5xFAD mice. Bioelectromagnetics 37:391&#x2013;399</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sorahan T, Kheifets L (2007) Mortality from Alzheimer&#x2019;s, motor neuron and Parkinson&#x2019;s disease in relation to magnetic field exposure: findings from the study of UK electricity generation and transmission workers, 1973-2004. Occup Environ Med 64:820&#x2013;826</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sorahan T, Mohammed N (2014) Neurodegenerative disease and magnetic field exposure in UK electricity supply workers. Occup Med (Lond) 64:454&#x2013;460</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsong TY, Astumian RD (1986) 863&#x2014;absorption and conversion of electric field energy by membrane bound ATPases. Bioelectrochem Bioenerg 15:457&#x2013;476</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner MR, Goldacre R, Ramagopalan S, Talbot K, Goldacre MJ (2013) Autoimmune disease preceding amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: an epidemiologic study. Neurology 81:1222&#x2013;1225</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Umarao P, Bose S, Bhattacharyya S, Kumar A, Jain S (2016) Neuroprotective potential of superparamagnetic iron oxide nanoparticles along with exposure to electromagnetic field in 6-OHDA rat model of Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. J Nanosci Nanotechnol 16:261&#x2013;269</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Usselman RJ, Chavarriaga C, Castello PR, Procopio M, Ritz T, Dratz EA, Singel DJ, Martino CF (2016) The quantum biology of reactive oxygen species partitioning impacts cellular bioenergetics. Sci Rep 6:38543</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van der Mark M, Vermeulen R, Nijssen PC et al (2015) Extremely low-frequency magnetic field exposure, electrical shocks and risk of Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Int Arch Occup Environ Health 88:227&#x2013;234</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vergara X, Kheifets L, Greenland S, Oksuzyan S, Cho YS, Mezei G (2013) Occupational exposure to extremely low-frequency magnetic fields and neurodegenerative disease: a meta-analysis. J Occup Environ Med 55:135&#x2013;146</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang MD, Gomes J, Cashman NR, Little J, Krewski D (2014) A meta-analysis of observational studies of the association between chronic occupational exposure to lead and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Occup Environ Med 56:1235&#x2013;1242</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang CX, Hilburn IA, Wu D-A, Mizuhara Y, Couste CP, Abrahams JNH, Bernstein SE, Matani A, Shimojo S, Kirschvink JL (2019) Transduction of the geomagnetic field as evidenced from alpha-band activity in the human brain. eneuro, 2019. ENEURO:0483&#x2013;0418</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wechsler LS, Checkoway H, Franklin GM, Costa LG (1991) A pilot study of occupational and environmental risk factors for Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Neurotoxicology. 12:387&#x2013;392</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wever R (1973) Human circadian rhythms under the influence of weak electric fields and the different aspects of these studies. Int J Biometeorol 17:227&#x2013;223</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wever R (1974) ELF-effects on human circadian rhythms. In: ELF and VLF electromagnetic field effects. Springer US, Boston, pp 101&#x2013;144</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winblad B, Amouyel P, Andrieu S, Ballard C, Brayne C, Brodaty H, Cedazo-Minguez A, Dubois B, Edvardsson D, Feldman H, Fratiglioni L, Frisoni GB, Gauthier S, Georges J, Graff C, Iqbal K, Jessen F, Johansson G, Jonsson L, Kivipelto M, Knapp M, Mangialasche F, Melis R, Nordberg A, Rikkert MO, Qiu C, Sakmar TP, Scheltens P, Schneider LS, Sperling R, Tjernberg LO, Waldemar G, Wimo A, Zetterberg H (2016) Defeating Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease and other dementias: a priority for European science and society. Lancet Neurol 15:455&#x2013;532</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang C, Guo Z, Peng H et al (2018) Repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation therapy for motor recovery in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: a meta-analysis. Brain Behav 8:e01132</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zanjani A, Zakzanis KK, Daskalakis ZJ, Chen R (2015) Repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation of the primary motor cortex in the treatment of motor signs in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: a quantitative review of the literature. Mov Disord 30:750&#x2013;758</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zarranz JJ (2008) Neurolog&#xed;a, 4&#xaa; edn. Elsevier, Madrid</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Liu X, Zhang J, Li N (2015) Short-term effects of extremely low frequency electromagnetic fields exposure on Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease in rats. Int J Radiat Biol 91:28&#x2013;34</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J, Sumich A, Wang GY (2017) Acute effects of radiofrequency electromagnetic field emitted by mobile phone on brain function. Bioelectromagnetics 38:329&#x2013;338</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou H, Chen G, Chen C, Yu Y, Xu Z (2012) Association between extremely low-frequency electromagnetic fields occupations and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a meta-analysis. PLoS One 7:e48354</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ziemann U, Paulus W, Nitsche MA, Pascual-Leone A, Byblow WD, Berardelli A, Siebner HR, Classen J, Cohen LG, Rothwell JC (2008) Consensus: motor cortex plasticity protocols. Brain Stimul 1:164&#x2013;182</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zufiria M, Gil-Bea FJ, Fernandez-Torron R, Poza JJ, Munoz-Blanco JL, Rojas-Garcia R, Riancho J, de Munain AL (2016) ALS: a bucket of genes, environment, metabolism and unknown ingredients. Prog Neurobiol 142:104&#x2013;129</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>