<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">32197935</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>22</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1573-2509</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>249</Volume><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Schizophrenia research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Schizophr Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A bioinformatic inquiry of the EAAT2 interactome in postmortem and neuropsychiatric datasets.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>38</StartPage><EndPage>46</EndPage><MedlinePgn>38-46</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.schres.2020.03.018</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0920-9964(20)30121-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Altered expression and localization of the glutamate transporter EAAT2 is found in schizophrenia and other neuropsychiatric (major depression, MDD) and neurological disorders (amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, ALS). However, the EAAT2 interactome, the network of proteins that physically or functionally interact with EAAT2 to support its activity, has yet to be characterized in severe mental illness. We compiled a list of "core" EAAT2 interacting proteins. Using Kaleidoscope, an R-shiny application, we data mined publically available postmortem transcriptome datasets to determine whether components of the EAAT2 interactome are differentially expressed in schizophrenia and, using Reactome, identify which interactome-associated biological pathways are altered. Overall, these "look up" studies highlight region-specific, primarily frontal cortex (dorsolateral prefrontal cortex and anterior cingulate cortex), changes in the EAAT2 interactome and implicate altered metabolism pathways in schizophrenia. Pathway analyses also suggest that perturbation of components of the EAAT2 interactome in animal models of antipsychotic administration impact metabolism. Similar changes in metabolism pathways are seen in ALS, in addition to altered expression of many components of the EAAT2 interactome. However, although EAAT2 expression is altered in a postmortem MDD dataset, few other components of the EAAT2 interactome are changed. Thus, "look up" studies suggest region- and disease-relevant biological pathways related to the EAAT2 interactome that implicate glutamate reuptake perturbations in schizophrenia, while providing a useful tool to exploit "omics" datasets.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2020 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Asah</LastName><ForeName>Sophie</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosciences, University of Toledo, Toledo, OH, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alganem</LastName><ForeName>Khaled</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosciences, University of Toledo, Toledo, OH, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McCullumsmith</LastName><ForeName>Robert E</ForeName><Initials>RE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosciences, University of Toledo, Toledo, OH, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>O'Donovan</LastName><ForeName>Sinead M</ForeName><Initials>SM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosciences, University of Toledo, Toledo, OH, USA. Electronic address: sinead.odonovan@utoledo.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>K08 MH074016</GrantID><Acronym>MH</Acronym><Agency>NIMH NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01 MH107487</GrantID><Acronym>MH</Acronym><Agency>NIMH NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R21 MH107916</GrantID><Acronym>MH</Acronym><Agency>NIMH NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Schizophr Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8804207</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0920-9964</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D027342">Excitatory Amino Acid Transporter 2</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D027342" MajorTopicYN="N">Excitatory Amino Acid Transporter 2</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019295" MajorTopicYN="N">Computational Biology</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012559" MajorTopicYN="Y">Schizophrenia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006179" MajorTopicYN="N">Gyrus Cinguli</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bioinformatics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">EAAT2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Postmortem</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of competing interest The authors have no conflicts to declare.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32197935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS1577691</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7494586</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.schres.2020.03.018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0920-9964(20)30121-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Alevizopoulos K, Calogeropoulou T, Lang F, Stournaras C, 2014. Na+/K+ ATPase inhibitors in cancer. Curr Drug Targets 15(10), 988&#x2013;1000.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25198786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aperia A, 2007. New roles for an old enzyme: Na,K-ATPase emerges as an interesting drug target. J Intern Med 261(1), 44&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17222167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arion D, Corradi JP, Tang S, Datta D, Boothe F, He A, Cacace AM, Zaczek R, Albright CF, Tseng G, Lewis DA, 2015. Distinctive transcriptome alterations of prefrontal pyramidal neurons in schizophrenia and schizoaffective disorder. Molecular psychiatry.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4492919</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25560755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arion D, Huo Z, Enwright JF, Corradi JP, Tseng G, Lewis DA, 2017. Transcriptome Alterations in Prefrontal Pyramidal Cells Distinguish Schizophrenia From Bipolar and Major Depressive Disorders. Biological psychiatry 82(8), 594&#x2013;600.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5610065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28476208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bauer D, Gupta D, Harotunian V, Meador-Woodruff JH, McCullumsmith RE, 2008. Abnormal expression of glutamate transporter and transporter interacting molecules in prefrontal cortex in elderly patients with schizophrenia. Schizophrenia research 104(1&#x2013;3), 108&#x2013;120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2656372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18678470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bauer D, Haroutunian V, Meador-Woodruff JH, McCullumsmith RE, 2010. Abnormal glycosylation of EAAT1 and EAAT2 in prefrontal cortex of elderly patients with schizophrenia. Schizophrenia research 117(1), 92&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2822023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19716271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beasley CL, Pennington K, Behan A, Wait R, Dunn MJ, Cotter D, 2006. Proteomic analysis of the anterior cingulate cortex in the major psychiatric disorders: Evidence for disease-associated changes. Proteomics 6(11), 3414&#x2013;3425.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16637010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blacker CJ, Millischer V, Webb LM, Ho AMC, Schalling M, Frye MA, Veldic M, 2019. EAAT2 as a Research Target in Bipolar Disorder and Unipolar Depression: A Systematic Review. Molecular Neuropsychiatry.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7206595</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32399469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bristol LA, Rothstein JD, 1996. Glutamate transporter gene expression in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis motor cortex. Annals of neurology 39(5), 676&#x2013;679.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8619555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choudary PV, Molnar M, Evans SJ, Tomita H, Li JZ, Vawter MP, Myers RM, Bunney WE Jr., Akil H, Watson SJ, Jones EG, 2005. Altered cortical glutamatergic and GABAergic signal transmission with glial involvement in depression. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America 102(43), 15653&#x2013;15658.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1257393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16230605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark D, Dedova I, Cordwell S, Matsumoto I, 2006. A proteome analysis of the anterior cingulate cortex gray matter in schizophrenia. Molecular psychiatry 11(5), 459&#x2013;470, 423.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16491132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark D, Dedova I, Cordwell S, Matsumoto I, 2007. Altered proteins of the anterior cingulate cortex white matter proteome in schizophrenia. Proteomics. Clinical applications 1(2), 157&#x2013;166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21136665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cudkowicz ME, Titus S, Kearney M, Yu H, Sherman A, Schoenfeld D, Hayden D, Shui A, Brooks B, Conwit R, Felsenstein D, Greenblatt DJ, Keroack M, Kissel JT, Miller R, Rosenfeld J, Rothstein JD, Simpson E, Tolkoff-Rubin N, Zinman L, Shefner JM, Ceftriaxone Study I, 2014. Safety and efficacy of ceftriaxone for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a multi-stage, randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Lancet Neurol 13(11), 1083&#x2013;1091.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4216315</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25297012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dean B, Thomas N, Scarr E, Udawela M, 2016. Evidence for impaired glucose metabolism in the striatum, obtained postmortem, from some subjects with schizophrenia. Translational psychiatry 6(11), e949.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5314134</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27845781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enwright Iii JF, Huo Z, Arion D, Corradi JP, Tseng G, Lewis DA, 2017. Transcriptome alterations of prefrontal cortical parvalbumin neurons in schizophrenia. Molecular psychiatry.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5938166</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29112193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Focking M, Lopez LM, English JA, Dicker P, Wolff A, Brindley E, Wynne K, Cagney G, Cotter DR, 2015. Proteomic and genomic evidence implicates the postsynaptic density in schizophrenia. Molecular psychiatry 20(4), 424&#x2013;432.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25048004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foster JB, Zhao F, Wang X, Xu Z, Lin K, Askwith CC, Hodgetts KJ, Lin CG, 2018. Pyridazine-derivatives Enhance Structural and Functional Plasticity of Tripartite Synapse Via Activation of Local Translation in Astrocytic Processes. Neuroscience 388, 224&#x2013;238.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6667176</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30056115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fray AE, Ince PG, Banner SJ, Milton ID, Usher PA, Cookson MR, Shaw PJ, 1998. The expression of the glial glutamate transporter protein EAAT2 in motor neuron disease: an immunohistochemical study. The European journal of neuroscience 10(8), 2481&#x2013;2489.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9767379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fromer M, Roussos P, Sieberts SK, Johnson JS, Kavanagh DH, Perumal TM, Ruderfer DM, Oh EC, Topol A, Shah HR, Klei LL, Kramer R, Pinto D, Gumus ZH, Cicek AE, Dang KK, Browne A, Lu C, Xie L, Readhead B, Stahl EA, Xiao J, Parvizi M, Hamamsy T, Fullard JF, Wang YC, Mahajan MC, Derry JM, Dudley JT, Hemby SE, Logsdon BA, Talbot K, Raj T, Bennett DA, De Jager PL, Zhu J, Zhang B, Sullivan PF, Chess A, Purcell SM, Shinobu LA, Mangravite LM, Toyoshiba H, Gur RE, Hahn CG, Lewis DA, Haroutunian V, Peters MA, Lipska BK, Buxbaum JD, Schadt EE, Hirai K, Roeder K, Brennand KJ, Katsanis N, Domenici E, Devlin B, Sklar P, 2016. Gene expression elucidates functional impact of polygenic risk for schizophrenia. Nature neuroscience 19(11), 1442&#x2013;1453.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5083142</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27668389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gandal MJ, Haney JR, Parikshak NN, Leppa V, Ramaswami G, Hartl C, Schork AJ, Appadurai V, Buil A, Werge TM, Liu C, White KP, CommonMind C, Psych EC, i P-BWG, Horvath S, Geschwind DH, 2018. Shared molecular neuropathology across major psychiatric disorders parallels polygenic overlap. Science 359(6376), 693&#x2013;697.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5898828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29439242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gegelashvili G, Bjerrum OJ, 2019. Glutamate transport system as a key constituent of glutamosome: Molecular pathology and pharmacological modulation in chronic pain. Neuropharmacology.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31047920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Genda EN, Jackson JG, Sheldon AL, Locke SF, Greco TM, O&#x2019;Donnell JC, Spruce LA, Xiao R, Guo W, Putt M, Seeholzer S, Ischiropoulos H, Robinson MB, 2011. Co-compartmentalization of the astroglial glutamate transporter, GLT-1, with glycolytic enzymes and mitochondria. The Journal of neuroscience : the official journal of the Society for Neuroscience 31(50), 18275&#x2013;18288.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3259858</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22171032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldberg J, Currais A, Prior M, Fischer W, Chiruta C, Ratliff E, Daugherty D, Dargusch R, Finley K, Esparza-Molto PB, Cuezva JM, Maher P, Petrascheck M, Schubert D, 2018. The mitochondrial ATP synthase is a shared drug target for aging and dementia. Aging Cell 17(2).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5847861</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29316249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez-Gonzalez IM, Garcia-Tardon N, Gimenez C, Zafra F, 2009. Splice variants of the glutamate transporter GLT1 form hetero-oligomers that interact with PSD-95 and NMDA receptors. Journal of neurochemistry 110(1), 264&#x2013;274.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19457061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson JG, O&#x2019;Donnell JC, Krizman E, Robinson MB, 2015. Displacing hexokinase from mitochondrial voltage-dependent anion channel impairs GLT-1-mediated glutamate uptake but does not disrupt interactions between GLT-1 and mitochondrial proteins. Journal of neuroscience research 93(7), 999&#x2013;1008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4441544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25546576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaffe AE, Straub RE, Shin JH, Tao R, Gao Y, Collado-Torres L, Kam-Thong T, Xi HS, Quan J, Chen Q, Colantuoni C, Ulrich WS, Maher BJ, Deep-Soboslay A, BrainSeq C, Cross AJ, Brandon NJ, Leek JT, Hyde TM, Kleinman JE, Weinberger DR, 2018. Developmental and genetic regulation of the human cortex transcriptome illuminate schizophrenia pathogenesis. Nature neuroscience 21(8), 1117&#x2013;1125.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6438700</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30050107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katsel P, Byne W, Roussos P, Tan W, Siever L, Haroutunian V, 2011. Astrocyte and glutamate markers in the superficial, deep, and white matter layers of the anterior cingulate gyrus in schizophrenia. Neuropsychopharmacology : official publication of the American College of Neuropsychopharmacology 36(6), 1171&#x2013;1177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3077461</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21270770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klempan TA, Sequeira A, Canetti L, Lalovic A, Ernst C, ffrench-Mullen J, Turecki G, 2009. Altered expression of genes involved in ATP biosynthesis and GABAergic neurotransmission in the ventral prefrontal cortex of suicides with and without major depression. Molecular psychiatry 14(2), 175&#x2013;189.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17938633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krystal JH, Anticevic A, Yang GJ, Dragoi G, Driesen NR, Wang XJ, Murray JD, 2017. Impaired Tuning of Neural Ensembles and the Pathophysiology of Schizophrenia: A Translational and Computational Neuroscience Perspective. Biological psychiatry 81(10), 874&#x2013;885.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5407407</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28434616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Labonte B, Engmann O, Purushothaman I, Menard C, Wang J, Tan C, Scarpa JR, Moy G, Loh YE, Cahill M, Lorsch ZS, Hamilton PJ, Calipari ES, Hodes GE, Issler O, Kronman H, Pfau M, Obradovic ALJ, Dong Y, Neve RL, Russo S, Kazarskis A, Tamminga C, Mechawar N, Turecki G, Zhang B, Shen L, Nestler EJ, 2017. Sex-specific transcriptional signatures in human depression. Nature medicine 23(9), 1102&#x2013;1111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5734943</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28825715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lauriat TL, McInnes LA, 2007. EAAT2 regulation and splicing: relevance to psychiatric and neurological disorders. Molecular psychiatry 12(12), 1065&#x2013;1078.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17684493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lehre KP, Danbolt NC, 1998. The number of glutamate transporter subtype molecules at glutamatergic synapses: chemical and stereological quantification in young adult rat brain. The Journal of neuroscience : the official journal of the Society for Neuroscience 18(21), 8751&#x2013;8757.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6793562</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9786982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li D, Herault K, Zylbersztejn K, Lauterbach MA, Guillon M, Oheim M, Ropert N, 2015. Astrocyte VAMP3 vesicles undergo Ca2+ -independent cycling and modulate glutamate transporter trafficking. The Journal of physiology 593(13), 2807&#x2013;2832.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4506183</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25864578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin CL, Kong Q, Cuny GD, Glicksman MA, 2012. Glutamate transporter EAAT2: a new target for the treatment of neurodegenerative diseases. Future Med Chem 4(13), 1689&#x2013;1700.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3580837</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22924507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martins-de-Souza D, Maccarrone G, Wobrock T, Zerr I, Gormanns P, Reckow S, Falkai P, Schmitt A, Turck CW, 2010a. Proteome analysis of the thalamus and cerebrospinal fluid reveals glycolysis dysfunction and potential biomarkers candidates for schizophrenia. Journal of psychiatric research 44(16), 1176&#x2013;1189.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20471030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martins-de-Souza D, Schmitt A, Roder R, Lebar M, Schneider-Axmann T, Falkai P, Turck CW, 2010b. Sex-specific proteome differences in the anterior cingulate cortex of schizophrenia. Journal of psychiatric research 44(14), 989&#x2013;991.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20381070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCullumsmith R, Shan D, Yates S, Roberts R, 2014. Astroglia and Severe Mental Illness: A Role for Glutamate Microdomains., in: Parpura V, Verkhratsky A (Eds.), Pathological Potential of Neuroglia. Springer, New York, NY.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCullumsmith RE, Meador-Woodruff JH, 2011. Novel approaches to the study of postmortem brain in psychiatric illness: old limitations and new challenges. Biological psychiatry 69(2), 127&#x2013;133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21094488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Medina A, Burke S, Thompson RC, Bunney W Jr., Myers RM, Schatzberg A, Akil H, Watson SJ, 2013. Glutamate transporters: a key piece in the glutamate puzzle of major depressive disorder. Journal of psychiatric research 47(9), 1150&#x2013;1156.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23706640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meltzer HY, 2013. Update on typical and atypical antipsychotic drugs. Annu Rev Med 64, 393&#x2013;406.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23020880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miguel-Hidalgo JJ, Waltzer R, Whittom AA, Austin MC, Rajkowska G, Stockmeier CA, 2010. Glial and glutamatergic markers in depression, alcoholism, and their comorbidity. Journal of affective disorders 127(1&#x2013;3), 230&#x2013;240.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2975814</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20580095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moody CL, Funk AJ, Devine E, Devore Homan CR, Boison D, McCullumsmith RE, O&#x2019;Donovan SM, 2019. Adenosine Kinase Expression in the Frontal Cortex in Schizophrenia. Schizophrenia bulletin.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7147579</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32275755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy-Royal C, Dupuis JP, Varela JA, Panatier A, Pinson B, Baufreton J, Groc L, Oliet SH, 2015. Surface diffusion of astrocytic glutamate transporters shapes synaptic transmission. Nature neuroscience 18(2), 219&#x2013;226.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25581361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Donovan SM, Hasselfeld K, Bauer D, Simmons M, Roussos P, Haroutunian V, Meador-Woodruff JH, McCullumsmith RE, 2015. Glutamate transporter splice variant expression in an enriched pyramidal cell population in schizophrenia. Translational psychiatry 5, e579.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4490284</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26057049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Donovan SM, Sullivan CR, McCullumsmith RE, 2017. The role of glutamate transporters in the pathophysiology of neuropsychiatric disorders. NPJ schizophrenia 3(1), 32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5608761</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28935880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parkin GM, Udawela M, Gibbons A, Dean B, 2018. Glutamate transporters, EAAT1 and EAAT2, are potentially important in the pathophysiology and treatment of schizophrenia and affective disorders. World J Psychiatry 8(2), 51&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6033743</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29988908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pennington K, Beasley CL, Dicker P, Fagan A, English J, Pariante CM, Wait R, Dunn MJ, Cotter DR, 2008. Prominent synaptic and metabolic abnormalities revealed by proteomic analysis of the dorsolateral prefrontal cortex in schizophrenia and bipolar disorder. Molecular psychiatry 13(12), 1102&#x2013;1117.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17938637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piniella D, Martinez-Blanco E, Ibanez I, Bartolome-Martin D, Porlan E, Diez-Guerra J, Gimenez C, Zafra F, 2018. Identification of novel regulatory partners of the glutamate transporter GLT-1. Glia 66(12), 2737&#x2013;2755.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30394597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prabakaran S, Swatton JE, Ryan MM, Huffaker SJ, Huang JT, Griffin JL, Wayland M, Freeman T, Dudbridge F, Lilley KS, Karp NA, Hester S, Tkachev D, Mimmack ML, Yolken RH, Webster MJ, Torrey EF, Bahn S, 2004. Mitochondrial dysfunction in schizophrenia: evidence for compromised brain metabolism and oxidative stress. Molecular psychiatry 9(7), 684&#x2013;697, 643.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15098003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Regenold WT, Pratt M, Nekkalapu S, Shapiro PS, Kristian T, Fiskum G, 2012. Mitochondrial detachment of hexokinase 1 in mood and psychotic disorders: implications for brain energy metabolism and neurotrophic signaling. Journal of psychiatric research 46(1), 95&#x2013;104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22018957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rizig MA, McQuillin A, Ng A, Robinson M, Harrison A, Zvelebil M, Hunt SP, Gurling HM, 2012. A gene expression and systems pathway analysis of the effects of clozapine compared to haloperidol in the mouse brain implicates susceptibility genes for schizophrenia. Journal of psychopharmacology 26(9), 1218&#x2013;1230.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22767372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson MB, Jackson JG, 2016. Astroglial glutamate transporters coordinate excitatory signaling and brain energetics. Neurochemistry international 98, 56&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4969184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27013346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rose EM, Koo JC, Antflick JE, Ahmed SM, Angers S, Hampson DR, 2009. Glutamate transporter coupling to Na,K-ATPase. The Journal of neuroscience : the official journal of the Society for Neuroscience 29(25), 8143&#x2013;8155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6666056</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19553454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rothstein JD, Martin LJ, Kuncl RW, 1992. Decreased glutamate transport by the brain and spinal cord in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. The New England journal of medicine 326(22), 1464&#x2013;1468.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1349424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rothstein JD, Van Kammen M, Levey AI, Martin LJ, Kuncl RW, 1995. Selective loss of glial glutamate transporter GLT-1 in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Annals of neurology 38(1), 73&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7611729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roussos P, Katsel P, Davis KL, Siever LJ, Haroutunian V, 2012. A system-level transcriptomic analysis of schizophrenia using postmortem brain tissue samples. Archives of general psychiatry 69(12), 1205&#x2013;1213.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22868662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saia-Cereda VM, Santana AG, Schmitt A, Falkai P, Martins-de-Souza D, 2017. The Nuclear Proteome of White and Gray Matter from Schizophrenia Postmortem Brains. Mol Neuropsychiatry 3(1), 37&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5582429</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28879200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schubert KO, Focking M, Cotter DR, 2015. Proteomic pathway analysis of the hippocampus in schizophrenia and bipolar affective disorder implicates 14-3-3 signaling, aryl hydrocarbon receptor signaling, and glucose metabolism: potential roles in GABAergic interneuron pathology. Schizophrenia research 167(1&#x2013;3), 64&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25728835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sequeira A, Mamdani F, Ernst C, Vawter MP, Bunney WE, Lebel V, Rehal S, Klempan T, Gratton A, Benkelfat C, Rouleau GA, Mechawar N, Turecki G, 2009. Global brain gene expression analysis links glutamatergic and GABAergic alterations to suicide and major depression. PloS one 4(8), e6585.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2719799</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19668376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shan D, Lucas EK, Drummond JB, Haroutunian V, Meador-Woodruff JH, McCullumsmith RE, 2013. Abnormal expression of glutamate transporters in temporal lobe areas in elderly patients with schizophrenia. Schizophrenia research 144(1&#x2013;3), 1&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3572263</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23356950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shan D, Mount D, Moore S, Haroutunian V, Meador-Woodruff JH, McCullumsmith RE, 2014. Abnormal partitioning of hexokinase 1 suggests disruption of a glutamate transport protein complex in schizophrenia. Schizophrenia research 154(1&#x2013;3), 1&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4151500</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24560881</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shan D, Yates S, Roberts RC, McCullumsmith RE, 2012. Update on the neurobiology of schizophrenia: a role for extracellular microdomains. Minerva psichiatrica 53(3), 233&#x2013;249.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3783347</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24077131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soliman MA, Aboharb F, Zeltner N, Studer L, 2017. Pluripotent stem cells in neuropsychiatric disorders. Molecular psychiatry 22(9), 1241&#x2013;1249.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5582162</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28322279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sullivan CR, Koene RH, Hasselfeld K, O&#x2019;Donovan SM, Ramsey A, McCullumsmith RE, 2019a. Neuron-specific deficits of bioenergetic processes in the dorsolateral prefrontal cortex in schizophrenia. Molecular psychiatry 24(9), 1319&#x2013;1328.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6119539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29497148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sullivan CR, Mielnik CA, Funk A, O&#x2019;Donovan SM, Bentea E, Pletnikov M, Ramsey AJ, Wen Z, Rowland LM, McCullumsmith RE, 2019b. Measurement of lactate levels in postmortem brain, iPSCs, and animal models of schizophrenia. Sci Rep 9(1), 5087.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6433855</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30911039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sullivan CR, Mielnik CA, O&#x2019;Donovan SM, Funk AJ, Bentea E, DePasquale EA, Alganem K, Wen Z, Haroutunian V, Katsel P, Ramsey AJ, Meller J, McCullumsmith RE, 2019c. Connectivity Analyses of Bioenergetic Changes in Schizophrenia: Identification of Novel Treatments. Mol Neurobiol 56(6), 4492&#x2013;4517.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7584383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30338483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takahashi K, Foster JB, Lin CL, 2015a. Glutamate transporter EAAT2: regulation, function, and potential as a therapeutic target for neurological and psychiatric disease. Cellular and molecular life sciences : CMLS 72(18), 3489&#x2013;3506.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26033496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takahashi K, Kong Q, Lin Y, Stouffer N, Schulte DA, Lai L, Liu Q, Chang LC, Dominguez S, Xing X, Cuny GD, Hodgetts KJ, Glicksman MA, Lin CL, 2015b. Restored glial glutamate transporter EAAT2 function as a potential therapeutic approach for Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. The Journal of experimental medicine 212(3), 319&#x2013;332.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4354363</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25711212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanaka K, Watase K, Manabe T, Yamada K, Watanabe M, Takahashi K, Iwama H, Nishikawa T, Ichihara N, Kikuchi T, Okuyama S, Kawashima N, Hori S, Takimoto M, Wada K, 1997. Epilepsy and exacerbation of brain injury in mice lacking the glutamate transporter GLT-1. Science 276(5319), 1699&#x2013;1702.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9180080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson &#x2212;L, 2017. - iMN (Exp 2) - ALS, SMA and Control (unaffected) iMN cell lines differentiated from iPS cell lines using a long differentiation protocol - RNA-seq.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tzingounis AV, Wadiche JI, 2007. Glutamate transporters: confining runaway excitation by shaping synaptic transmission. Nature reviews. Neuroscience 8(12), 935&#x2013;947.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17987031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vandoorne T, De Bock K, Van Den Bosch L, 2018. Energy metabolism in ALS: an underappreciated opportunity? Acta Neuropathol 135(4), 489&#x2013;509.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5978930</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29549424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Velasquez E, Martins-de-Souza D, Velasquez I, Carneiro GRA, Schmitt A, Falkai P, Domont GB, Nogueira FCS, 2019. Quantitative Subcellular Proteomics of the Orbitofrontal Cortex of Schizophrenia Patients. Journal of proteome research 18(12), 4240&#x2013;4253.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31581776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wan C, Borgeson B, Phanse S, Tu F, Drew K, Clark G, Xiong X, Kagan O, Kwan J, Bezginov A, Chessman K, Pal S, Cromar G, Papoulas O, Ni Z, Boutz DR, Stoilova S, Havugimana PC, Guo X, Malty RH, Sarov M, Greenblatt J, Babu M, Derry WB, Tillier ER, Wallingford JB, Parkinson J, Marcotte EM, Emili A, 2015. Panorama of ancient metazoan macromolecular complexes. Nature 525(7569), 339&#x2013;344.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5036527</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26344197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wen Z, Nguyen HN, Guo Z, Lalli MA, Wang X, Su Y, Kim NS, Yoon KJ, Shin J, Zhang C, Makri G, Nauen D, Yu H, Guzman E, Chiang CH, Yoritomo N, Kaibuchi K, Zou J, Christian KM, Cheng L, Ross CA, Margolis RL, Chen G, Kosik KS, Song H, Ming GL, 2014. Synaptic dysregulation in a human iPS cell model of mental disorders. Nature 515(7527), 414&#x2013;418.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4501856</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25132547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wesseling H, Chan MK, Tsang TM, Ernst A, Peters F, Guest PC, Holmes E, Bahn S, 2013. A combined metabonomic and proteomic approach identifies frontal cortex changes in a chronic phencyclidine rat model in relation to human schizophrenia brain pathology. Neuropsychopharmacology : official publication of the American College of Neuropsychopharmacology 38(12), 2532&#x2013;2544.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3799075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23942359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yimer EM, Hishe HZ, Tuem KB, 2019. Repurposing of the beta-Lactam Antibiotic, Ceftriaxone for Neurological Disorders: A Review. Front Neurosci 13, 236.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6444273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30971875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zimmer ER, Parent MJ, Souza DG, Leuzy A, Lecrux C, Kim HI, Gauthier S, Pellerin L, Hamel E, Rosa-Neto P, 2017. [(18)F]FDG PET signal is driven by astroglial glutamate transport. Nature neuroscience 20(3), 393&#x2013;395.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5378483</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28135241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zoltowska KM, Maesako M, Meier J, Berezovska O, 2018. Novel interaction between Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease-related protein presenilin 1 and glutamate transporter 1. Sci Rep 8(1), 8718.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5992168</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29880815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuccoli GS, Saia-Cereda VM, Nascimento JM, Martins-de-Souza D, 2017. The Energy Metabolism Dysfunction in Psychiatric Disorders Postmortem Brains: Focus on Proteomic Evidence. Front Neurosci 11, 493.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5594406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28936160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>