<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">32215816</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>18</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1476-3524</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>38</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Neurotoxicity research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Neurotox Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Energy Balance as a Moderator of Neurologic Disease Risk and Progression.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>242</StartPage><EndPage>248</EndPage><MedlinePgn>242-248</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s12640-020-00190-4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) is a devastating disease that like multiple other neurologic diseases has no curative treatment currently available. Environmental exposures to known neurotoxic compounds (e.g., pesticides, heavy metals, cyanobacterial toxins, etc.) are identified as risk factors associated with ALS. Assuming these environmental factors have causative roles in disease risk and given the ubiquity of these types of exposures for the modern human, why are not more people afflicted with ALS? Herein is proposed an energy balance moderation framework (EBMF)-a framework that postulates energy balance as a key moderator of neurologic disease risk. The EBMF proposes that the ability of the body to handle toxic compound exposures through excretion, metabolism, and/or storage impacts the acute and chronic tissue-specific toxicity which is moderated by energy balance. In this model, positive energy balance (weight gain or excess body weight/mass) would be protective against acute neurotoxic exposure permitting the assimilation and sequestration of toxic compounds within body stores separate from the nervous system. However, this protective buffering could be lost during sustained negative energy balance (weight loss) with the release of sequestered compounds redistributing to the nervous system. The EBMF may have relevance beyond ALS for other neurologic diseases with demonstrated environmental risks (such as Alzheimer's and Parkinson's disease) and offers new insights into potential strategies to reduce disease risk and develop novel treatments.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Smith</LastName><ForeName>Daniel L</ForeName><Initials>DL</Initials><Suffix>Jr</Suffix><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1602-2023</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nutrition Sciences, University of Alabama at Birmingham, Birmingham, AL, USA. dsmithjr@uab.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nutrition Obesity Research Center, University of Alabama at Birmingham, Birmingham, AL, USA. dsmithjr@uab.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nathan Shock Center for Excellence in the Basic Biology of Aging, Birmingham, AL, USA. dsmithjr@uab.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>, 1720 2nd Ave S, Webb 423, Birmingham, AL, 35294-3360, USA. dsmithjr@uab.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pavela</LastName><ForeName>Gregory</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nutrition Obesity Research Center, University of Alabama at Birmingham, Birmingham, AL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Behavior, University of Alabama at Birmingham, Birmingham, AL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>P30 AG050886</GrantID><Acronym>AG</Acronym><Agency>NIA NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>P30 DK056336</GrantID><Acronym>DK</Acronym><Agency>NIDDK NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>P30AG050886</GrantID><Acronym>AG</Acronym><Agency>NIA NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Neurotox Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100929017</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1029-8428</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="Y">etiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018450" MajorTopicYN="Y">Disease Progression</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004734" MajorTopicYN="Y">Energy Metabolism</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004781" MajorTopicYN="Y">Environmental Exposure</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012307" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Alzheimer&#x2019;s</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Energy balance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neurodegenerative</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Parkinson&#x2019;s</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pesticide</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Toxin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Weight loss</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Disclosures: The authors declare no conflict of interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32215816</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS1745664</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8593878</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12640-020-00190-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s12640-020-00190-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Aziz NA, van der Marck MA, Pijl H, Olde Rikkert MG, Bloem BR, Roos RA (Weight loss in neurodegenerative disorders. J Neurol 255:1872&#x2013;1880.2008).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19165531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker RH. Some Effects of the War on the Wildlife of Micronesia. Transactions of the Eleventh North American Wildlife Conference , 205&#x2013;213. 1946. Washington, D.C., American Wildlife Institute. Quee, E. M. Ref Type: Conference Proceeding</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banack SA, Cox PA (Biomagnification of cycad neurotoxins in flying foxes: implications for ALS-PDC in Guam. Neurology 61:387&#x2013;389.2003).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12913204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bayat S, Geiser F, Kristiansen P, Wilson SC (Organic contaminants in bats: trends and new issues. Environ Int 63:40&#x2013;52.2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24263138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biskind MS (Public health aspects of the new insecticides. Am J Dig Dis 20:331&#x2013;341.1953).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13104369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bradley WG, Borenstein AR, Nelson LM, Codd GA, Rosen BH, Stommel EW, Cox PA (Is exposure to cyanobacteria an environmental risk factor for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and other neurodegenerative diseases? Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 14:325&#x2013;333.2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23286757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bradley WG, Cox PA (Beyond Guam: cyanobacteria, BMAA and sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler 10 Suppl 2:5&#x2013;6.2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19929725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bradley WG, Mash DC (Beyond Guam: the cyanobacteria/BMAA hypothesis of the cause of ALS and other neurodegenerative diseases. Amyotroph Lateral Scler 10 Suppl 2:7&#x2013;20.2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19929726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bradley WG, Miller RX, Levine TD, Stommel EW, Cox PA (Studies of Environmental Risk Factors in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis (ALS) and a Phase I Clinical Trial of L-Serine. Neurotox Res 33:192&#x2013;198.2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28527102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bray GA, Champagne CM (Beyond energy balance: there is more to obesity than kilocalories. J Am Diet Assoc 105:S17&#x2013;S23.2005).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15867891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caller T, Henegan P, Stommel E (The Potential Role of BMAA in Neurodegeneration. Neurotox Res 33:222&#x2013;226.2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28612294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Catenacci VA, Hill JO, Wyatt HR (The obesity epidemic. Clin Chest Med 30:415&#x2013;44, vii.2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19700042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen KM, Craig UK, Lee CT, Haddock R (Cycad neurotoxin, consumption of flying foxes, and ALS/PDC disease in Guam. Neurology 59:1664&#x2013;1665.2002).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12451227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chernoff N, Hill DJ, Diggs DL, Faison BD, Francis BM, Lang JR, Larue MM, Le TT, Loftin KA, Lugo JN, Schmid JE, Winnik WM (A critical review of the postulated role of the non-essential amino acid, beta-N-methylamino-L-alanine, in neurodegenerative disease in humans. J Toxicol Environ Health B Crit Rev 20:1&#x2013;47.2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6503681</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28598725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chevrier J, Dewailly E, Ayotte P, Mauriege P, Despres JP, Tremblay A (Body weight loss increases plasma and adipose tissue concentrations of potentially toxic pollutants in obese individuals. Int J Obes Relat Metab Disord 24:1272&#x2013;1278.2000).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11093288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cho MR, Shin JY, Hwang JH, Jacobs DR Jr., Kim SY, Lee DH (Associations of fat mass and lean mass with bone mineral density differ by levels of persistent organic pollutants: National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey 1999&#x2013;2004. Chemosphere 82:1268&#x2013;1276.2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21196025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark DR Jr. (Death in bats from DDE, DDT or dieldrin: diagnosis via residues in carcass fat. Bull Environ Contam Toxicol 26:367&#x2013;374.1981).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7284633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark DR Jr., Kroll JC (Effects of DDE on experimentally poisoned free-tailed bats (Tadarida brasiliensis): lethal brain concentrations. J Toxicol Environ Health 3:893&#x2013;901.1977).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">599587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark DR Jr., Prouty RM (Experimental feeding of DDE and PCB to female big brown bats (Eptesicus fuscus). J Toxicol Environ Health 2:917&#x2013;928.1977).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">404435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corbella J, To-Figueras J, Rodamilans M, Gomez J (Mobilization, redistribution and excretion of hexachlorobenzene following food restriction in rats. IARC Sci Publ:289&#x2013;295.1986).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3596716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cox PA, Davis DA, Mash DC, Metcalf JS, Banack SA (Dietary exposure to an environmental toxin triggers neurofibrillary tangles and amyloid deposits in the brain. Proc Biol Sci 283.2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4795023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26791617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cox PA, Kostrzewa RM, Guillemin GJ (BMAA and Neurodegenerative Illness. Neurotox Res 33:178&#x2013;183.2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28540663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cox PA, Sacks OW (Cycad neurotoxins, consumption of flying foxes, and ALS-PDC disease in Guam. Neurology 58:956&#x2013;959.2002).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11914415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cudkowicz ME, Shefner JM, Schoenfeld DA, Brown RH Jr., Johnson H, Qureshi M, Jacobs M, Rothstein JD, Appel SH, Pascuzzi RM, Heiman-Patterson TD, Donofrio PD, David WS, Russell JA, Tandan R, Pioro EP, Felice KJ, Rosenfeld J, Mandler RN, Sachs GM, Bradley WG, Raynor EM, Baquis GD, Belsh JM, Novella S, Goldstein J, Hulihan J (A randomized, placebo-controlled trial of topiramate in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology 61:456&#x2013;464.2003).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12939417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deichmann WB (Toxicology of DDT and related chlorinated hydrocarbon pesticides. J Occup Med 14:285&#x2013;292.1972).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5020448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deichmann WB, MacDonald WE, Cubit DA (DDT tissue retention: sudden rise induced by the addition of aldrin to a fixed DDT intake. Science 172:275&#x2013;276.1971).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5548708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeMichele SJ (Nutrition of lead. Comp Biochem Physiol A Comp Physiol 78:401&#x2013;408.1984).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6147225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dunlop RA, Powell JT, Metcalf JS, Guillemin GJ, Cox PA (L-Serine-Mediated Neuroprotection Includes the Upregulation of the ER Stress Chaperone Protein Disulfide Isomerase (PDI). Neurotox Res 33:113&#x2013;122.2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28975502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Factor-Litvak P, Al-Chalabi A, Ascherio A, Bradley W, Chio A, Garruto R, Hardiman O, Kamel F, Kasarskis E, McKee A, Nakano I, Nelson LM, Eisen A (Current pathways for epidemiological research in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 14 Suppl 1:33&#x2013;43.2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5434707</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23678878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fischer J, Johnson MA (Low body weight and weight loss in the aged. J Am Diet Assoc 90:1697&#x2013;1706.1990).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2131340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>French SA, Jeffery RW, Folsom AR, Williamson DF, Byers T (History of intentional and unintentional weight loss in a population-based sample of women aged 55 to 69 years. Obes Res 3:163&#x2013;170.1995).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7719962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaddey HL, Holder K (Unintentional weight loss in older adults. Am Fam Physician 89:718&#x2013;722.2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24784334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallagher D, Allen A, Wang Z, Heymsfield SB, Krasnow N (Smaller organ tissue mass in the elderly fails to explain lower resting metabolic rate. Ann N Y Acad Sci 904:449&#x2013;455.2000).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10865788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garand GW, Strobridge TR (1971) History of the U.S. Marine Corps Operations in World War II: Western Pacific Operations, vol. IV. Washington, D.C.: U.S. Marine Corps.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geluso KN, Altenbach JS, Wilson DE (Bat mortality: pesticide poisoning and migratory stress. Science 194:184&#x2013;186.1976).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">959845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geyer HJ, Scheunert I, Rapp K, Gebefugi I, Steinberg C, Kettrup A (The relevance of fat content in toxicity of lipophilic chemicals to terrestrial animals with special reference to dieldrin and 2,3,7,8-tetrachlorodibenzo-p-dioxin (TCDD). Ecotoxicol Environ Saf 26:45&#x2013;60.1993a).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7691535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geyer HJ, Scheuntert I, Rapp K, Kettrup A, Korte F, Greim H, Rozman K (Correlation between acute toxicity of 2,3,7,8-tetrachlorodibenzo-p-dioxin (TCDD) and total body fat content in mammals. Toxicology 65:97&#x2013;107.1990).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2274972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geyer HJ, Steinberg CE, Scheunert I, Bruggemann R, Schutz W, Kettrup A, Rozman K (A review of the relationship between acute toxicity (LC50) of gamma-hexachlorocyclohexane (gamma-HCH, Lindane) and total lipid content of different fish species. Toxicology 83:169&#x2013;179.1993b).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7504334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goutman SA, Boss J, Patterson A, Mukherjee B, Batterman S, Feldman EL (High plasma concentrations of organic pollutants negatively impact survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 90:907&#x2013;912.2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6625908</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30760645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gunnarsson LG, Bodin L (Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis and Occupational Exposures: A Systematic Literature Review and Meta-Analyses. Int J Environ Res Public Health 15.2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6265680</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30373166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hall DG, Bohart GE (The Sarcophagidae of Guam. Proceedings of the Entomological Society of Washington 50:127&#x2013;135.1948).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hall RH (A new threat to public health: organochlorines and food. Nutr Health 8:33&#x2013;43.1992).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1603449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hammerschlag N, Davis DA, Mondo K, Seely MS, Murch SJ, Glover WB, Divoll T, Evers DC, Mash DC (Cyanobacterial Neurotoxin BMAA and Mercury in Sharks. Toxins (Basel) 8.2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4999854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27537913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hobson EV, McDermott CJ (Supportive and symptomatic management of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat Rev Neurol 12:526&#x2013;538.2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27514291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jandacek RJ, Anderson N, Liu M, Zheng S, Yang Q, Tso P (Effects of yo-yo diet, caloric restriction, and olestra on tissue distribution of hexachlorobenzene. Am J Physiol Gastrointest Liver Physiol 288:G292&#x2013;G299.2005).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15513954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jandacek RJ, Heubi JE, Buckley DD, Khoury JC, Turner WE, Sjodin A, Olson JR, Shelton C, Helms K, Bailey TD, Carter S, Tso P, Pavuk M (Reduction of the body burden of PCBs and DDE by dietary intervention in a randomized trial. J Nutr Biochem 25:483&#x2013;488.2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3960503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24629911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jandacek RJ, Rider T, Keller ER, Tso P (The effect of olestra on the absorption, excretion and storage of 2,2&#x2019;,5,5&#x2019; tetrachlorobiphenyl; 3,3&#x2019;,4,4&#x2019; tetrachlorobiphenyl; and perfluorooctanoic acid. Environ Int 36:880&#x2013;883.2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2891251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19616301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jandacek RJ, Tso P (Enterohepatic circulation of organochlorine compounds: a site for nutritional intervention. J Nutr Biochem 18:163&#x2013;167.2007).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17296488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jenkins JM (Natural history of the Guam Rail. Condor 81:404&#x2013;408.1979).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jenkins JM. The Native Forest Birds of Guam. Ornithological Monographs[31]. 1983. Washington, D.C., The American Ornithologists&#x2019; Union. Ref Type: Serial (Book,Monograph)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones G, Jacobs DS, Kunz TH, Willig MR, Racey PA (Carpe noctem: the importance of bats as bioindicators. Endangered Species Research 8:93&#x2013;115.2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamel F, Umbach DM, Bedlack RS, Richards M, Watson M, Alavanja MC, Blair A, Hoppin JA, Schmidt S, Sandler DP (Pesticide exposure and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurotoxicology 33:457&#x2013;462.2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3358481</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22521219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kannan K, Yun SH, Rudd RJ, Behr M (High concentrations of persistent organic pollutants including PCBs, DDT, PBDEs and PFOS in little brown bats with white-nose syndrome in New York, USA. Chemosphere 80:613&#x2013;618.2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20493513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee DH, Porta M, Lind L, Lind PM, Jacobs DR Jr. (Neurotoxic chemicals in adipose tissue: A role in puzzling findings on obesity and dementia. Neurology 90:176&#x2013;182.2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5798659</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29358509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levine TD, Miller RG, Bradley WG, Moore DH, Saperstein DS, Flynn LE, Katz JS, Forshew DA, Metcalf JS, Banack SA, Cox PA (Phase I clinical trial of safety of L-serine for ALS patients. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 18:107&#x2013;111.2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27589995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meltzer AA, Everhart JE (Unintentional weight loss in the United States. Am J Epidemiol 142:1039&#x2013;1046.1995).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7485049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morassutti I, Giometto M, Baruffi C, Marcon ML, Michieletto S, Giometto B, Spinella N, Paccagnella A (Nutritional intervention for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Minerva Gastroenterol Dietol 58:253&#x2013;260.2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22971635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mostafalou S, Abdollahi M (Pesticides: an update of human exposure and toxicity. Arch Toxicol 91:549&#x2013;599.2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27722929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mozaffarian D, Rosenberg I, Uauy R (History of modern nutrition science-implications for current research, dietary guidelines, and food policy. BMJ 361:k2392.2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5998735</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29899124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murch SJ, Cox PA, Banack SA (A mechanism for slow release of biomagnified cyanobacterial neurotoxins and neurodegenerative disease in Guam. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 101:12228&#x2013;12231.2004).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC514403</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15295100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mutter LC, Blanke RV, Jandacek RJ, Guzelian PS (Reduction in the body content of DDE in the Mongolian gerbil treated with sucrose polyester and caloric restriction. Toxicol Appl Pharmacol 92:428&#x2013;435.1988).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2451319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohmiya Y, Nakai K (Effect of starvation on excretion, distribution and metabolism of DDT in mice. Tohoku J Exp Med 122:143&#x2013;153.1977).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">888138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pablo J, Banack SA, Cox PA, Johnson TE, Papapetropoulos S, Bradley WG, Buck A, Mash DC (Cyanobacterial neurotoxin BMAA in ALS and Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. Acta Neurol Scand 120:216&#x2013;225.2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19254284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pelletier C, Imbeault P, Tremblay A (Energy balance and pollution by organochlorines and polychlorinated biphenyls. Obes Rev 4:17&#x2013;24.2003).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12608524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Redgrave TG, Wallace P, Jandacek RJ, Tso P (Treatment with a dietary fat substitute decreased Arochlor 1254 contamination in an obese diabetic male. J Nutr Biochem 16:383&#x2013;384.2005).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15936651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reed DM, Brody JA (Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and parkinsonism-dementia on Guam, 1945&#x2013;1972. I. Descriptive epidemiology. Am J Epidemiol 101:287&#x2013;301.1975).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1124759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimizu T, Nagaoka U, Nakayama Y, Kawata A, Kugimoto C, Kuroiwa Y, Kawai M, Shimohata T, Nishizawa M, Mihara B, Arahata H, Fujii N, Namba R, Ito H, Imai T, Nobukuni K, Kondo K, Ogino M, Nakajima T, Komori T (Reduction rate of body mass index predicts prognosis for survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a multicenter study in Japan. Amyotroph Lateral Scler 13:363&#x2013;366.2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22632442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spencer PS (Guam ALS/parkinsonism-dementia: a long-latency neurotoxic disorder caused by &#x201c;slow toxin(s)&#x201d; in food? Can J Neurol Sci 14:347&#x2013;357.1987).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3315142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stommel EW, Field NC, Caller TA (Aerosolization of cyanobacteria as a risk factor for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Med Hypotheses 80:142&#x2013;145.2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23246360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stone R (Toxicology. Fruit bats linked to mystery disease. Science 296:241.2002).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11951013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas DM, Ivanescu AE, Martin CK, Heymsfield SB, Marshall K, Bodrato VE, Williamson DA, Anton SD, Sacks FM, Ryan D, Bray GA (Predicting successful long-term weight loss from short-term weight-loss outcomes: new insights from a dynamic energy balance model (the POUNDS Lost study). Am J Clin Nutr 101:449&#x2013;454.2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4340057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25733628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>To-Figueras J, Gomez-Catalan J, Rodamilans M, Corbella J (Mobilization of stored hexachlorobenzene and p,p-dichlorodiphenyldichloroethylene during partial starvation in rats. Toxicol Lett 42:79&#x2013;86.1988).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3388450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uversky VN, Li J, Bower K, Fink AL (Synergistic effects of pesticides and metals on the fibrillation of alpha-synuclein: implications for Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Neurotoxicology 23:527&#x2013;536.2002).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12428725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walker R, Davidson M, Gray W (Gender differences in 1-year survival rates after weight loss in people with idiopathic Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Int J Palliat Nurs 18:35&#x2013;39.2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22306718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallace JI, Schwartz RS, LaCroix AZ, Uhlmann RF, Pearlman RA (Involuntary weight loss in older outpatients: incidence and clinical significance. J Am Geriatr Soc 43:329&#x2013;337.1995).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7706619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang MD, Little J, Gomes J, Cashman NR, Krewski D (Identification of risk factors associated with onset and progression of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis using systematic review and meta-analysis. Neurotoxicology 61:101&#x2013;130.2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27377857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z, Bosy-Westphal A, Schautz B, Muller M (Mechanistic model of mass-specific basal metabolic rate: evaluation in healthy young adults. Int J Body Compos Res 9:147.2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4192648</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25309131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wannamethee SG, Shaper AG, Lennon L (Reasons for intentional weight loss, unintentional weight loss, and mortality in older men. Arch Intern Med 165:1035&#x2013;1040.2005).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15883243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>White H, Pieper C, Schmader K (The association of weight change in Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease with severity of disease and mortality: a longitudinal analysis. J Am Geriatr Soc 46:1223&#x2013;1227.1998).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9777903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong S, Ciliska D (Intentional weight loss was associated with lower mortality, whereas unintentional weight loss was associated with increased mortality. Evid Based Nurs 6:121.2003).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14577404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wood SA, Armitage JM, Binnington MJ, Wania F (Deterministic modeling of the exposure of individual participants in the National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey (NHANES) to polychlorinated biphenyls. Environ Sci Process Impacts 18:1157&#x2013;1168.2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27711883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zukal J, Pikula J, Bandouchova H (Bats as bioindicators of heavy metal pollution: history and prospect. Mammalian Biology 80:220&#x2013;227.2015).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>