<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">32251109</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>19</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1537-7385</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>99</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>American journal of physical medicine &amp; rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Am J Phys Med Rehabil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Differentiating Flail Limb Syndrome From Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>895</StartPage><EndPage>901</EndPage><MedlinePgn>895-901</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/PHM.0000000000001438</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">The aim of the study was to investigate differences between flail limb syndrome and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DESIGN">A retrospective chart review identified 16 cases of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and 16 of flail limb syndrome. Revised Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Functional Rating Scale, compound muscle action potential amsplitudes, and rate of loss of vital capacity were compared.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Comparing amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and flail limb syndrome patients, rate of loss of vital capacity was 5.26% &#xb1; 0.33% versus 0.54% &#xb1; 0.06%, respectively (P &lt; 0.05). No patient in the flail limb syndrome group had a rate of loss of vital capacity more than 0.65% per month. No patient in the amyotrophic lateral sclerosis group had a rate of loss of vital capacity less than 4.6% per month. The average ulnar nerve compound muscle action potential amplitudes were significantly lower in flail limb syndrome (P &lt; 0.05). No significant difference was observed in the rate of Revised Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Functional Rating Scale decline or average peroneal, tibial, and median nerve compound muscle action potential amplitudes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">In flail limb syndrome, an average monthly decrease in vital capacity exceeding 0.65% may suggest a spread of motor neuron loss to higher cervical anterior horn areas and raise the possibility of progression to amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Larger prospective studies are needed to investigate the rate of VC decline in flail limb syndrome and limb-onset amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and to establish whether a cutoff score combining rate of loss of vital capacity and compound muscle action potential amplitude mainly of the ulnar nerve might predict progression of flail limb syndrome to amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, the knowledge of which can facilitate appropriate patient counseling.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kornitzer</LastName><ForeName>Jeffrey</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Department of Neurology, Rutgers University - New Jersey Medical School, Newark, New Jersey (JK, HFA, MZ, JRB, AK, EF, NS); St. Joseph's Children's Hospital, Paterson, New Jersey (JK); and Department of Neurology - New York University School of Medicine, New York, New York (HWS).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abdulrazeq</LastName><ForeName>Hael F</ForeName><Initials>HF</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zaidi</LastName><ForeName>Mohammad</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bach</LastName><ForeName>John R</ForeName><Initials>JR</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kazi</LastName><ForeName>Abdul</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Feinstein</LastName><ForeName>Erin</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sander</LastName><ForeName>Howard W</ForeName><Initials>HW</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Souayah</LastName><ForeName>Nizar</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Am J Phys Med Rehabil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8803677</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0894-9115</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="Y">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001132" MajorTopicYN="N">Arm</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003937" MajorTopicYN="N">Diagnosis, Differential</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018450" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Progression</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004576" MajorTopicYN="N">Electromyography</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007866" MajorTopicYN="N">Leg</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013577" MajorTopicYN="N">Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014797" MajorTopicYN="N">Vital Capacity</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32251109</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/PHM.0000000000001438</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00002060-202010000-00009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Shahrizaila N, Sobue G, Kuwabara S, et al.: Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and motor neuron syndromes in Asia. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2016;87:821&#x2013;30</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shoesmith CL, Findlater K, Rowe A, et al.: Prognosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with respiratory onset. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2007;78:629&#x2013;31</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tortelli R, Copetti M, Panza F, et al.: Time to generalisation as a predictor of prognosis in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2016;87:678&#x2013;9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, Miller RG, Swash M, et al.: El Escorial revisited: revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord 2000;1:293&#x2013;9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van den Berg-Vos RM, Visser J, Kalmijn S, et al.: A long-term prospective study of the natural course of sporadic adult-onset lower motor neuron syndromes. Arch Neurol 2009;66:751&#x2013;7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoon BN, Choi SH, Rha JH, et al.: Comparison between flail arm syndrome and upper limb onset amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: clinical features and Electromyographic findings. Exp Neurobiol 2014;23:253&#x2013;7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hubers A, Hildebrandt V, Petri S, et al.: Clinical features and differential diagnosis of flail arm syndrome. J Neurol 2016;263:390&#x2013;5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wijesekera LC, Mathers S, Talman P, et al.: Natural history and clinical features of the flail arm and flail leg ALS variants. Neurology 2009;72:1087&#x2013;94</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kimura J: Electrodiagnosis in Diseases of Nerve and Muscle: Principles and Practice. Philadelphia, FA Davis, 1989</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hankinson JL, Odencrantz JR, Fedan KB: Spirometric reference values from a sample of the general US population. Am J Respir Crit Care Med 1999;159:179&#x2013;87</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tortelli R, Copetti M, Panza F, et al.: Time to generalization and prediction of survival in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a retrospective observational study. Eur J Neurol 2016;23:1117&#x2013;25</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum JM, Stambler N, Malta E, et al.: The ALSFRS-R: a revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. BDNF ALS Study Group (Phase III). J Neurol Sci 1999;169:13&#x2013;21</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H, Tang L, Zhang N, et al.: Ventilation function disorder of flail arm syndrome [in Chinese]. Zhonghua Nei Ke Za Zhi 2015;54:749&#x2013;52</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goncalves MR, Ishikawa Y, Saporito L, et al.: Continuous noninvasive ventilatory support outcomes for neuromuscular disease: a multicentre collaboration and literature review. Pulmonol 2019. doi:10.1016/j.pulmoe.2019.05.006. [Epub ahead of print]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pulmoe.2019.05.006.</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;-F&#xe0;bregas J: Forced vital capacity deterioration in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis has an inflexion point. Eur J Neurol 1996;3:40&#x2013;3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahajan KR, Bach JR, Saporito L, et al.: Diaphragm pacing and noninvasive respiratory management of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis/motor neuron disease. Muscle Nerve 2012;46:851&#x2013;5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bourke SC, Bullock RE, Williams TL, et al.: Noninvasive ventilation in ALS: indications and effect on quality of life. Neurology 2003;61:171&#x2013;7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lo Coco D, Marchese S, Pesco MC, et al.: Noninvasive positive-pressure ventilation in ALS: predictors of tolerance and survival. Neurology 2006;67:761&#x2013;5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kleopa KA, Sherman M, Neal B, et al.: Bipap improves survival and rate of pulmonary function decline in patients with ALS. J Neurol Sci 1999;164:82&#x2013;8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schiffman PL, Belsh JM: Pulmonary function at diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: rate of deterioration. Chest 1993;103:508&#x2013;13</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bach JR, Upadhyaya N: Association of need for tracheotomy with decreasing mechanical in-exsufflation flows in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Am J Phys Med Rehabil 2018;97:e20&#x2013;2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chio A, Calvo A, Moglia C, et al.: Phenotypic heterogeneity of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a population based study. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2011;82:740&#x2013;6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang H, Liu M, Li X, et al.: Neurophysiological differences between flail arm syndrome and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. PLoS One 2015;10:e0127601</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S, Kiernan MC: Abnormalities in cortical and peripheral excitability in flail arm variant amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2007;78:849&#x2013;52</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berry JD, Cudkowicz ME: New considerations in the design of clinical trials for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Investig (Lond) 2011;1:1375&#x2013;89</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franchignoni F, Mora G, Giordano A, et al.: Evidence of multidimensionality in the ALSFRS-R Scale: a critical appraisal on its measurement properties using Rasch analysis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2013;84:1340&#x2013;5</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>