<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">32297335</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>26</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-4598</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>62</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Muscle &amp; nerve</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Muscle Nerve</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Paravertebral block for radiologically inserted gastrostomy tube placement in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>70</StartPage><EndPage>75</EndPage><MedlinePgn>70-75</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/mus.26894</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION">Radiologically inserted gastrostomy (RIG) placement in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) carries risks related to periprocedural sedation and analgesia. To minimize these risks, we used a paravertebral block (PVB) technique for RIG placement.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">We retrospectively reviewed patients with ALS undergoing RIG placement under PVB between 2013 and 2017.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Ninety-nine patients with ALS underwent RIG placement under PVB. Median (range) age was 66 (28 to 86) years, ALS Functional Rating Scale-Revised score was 27 (6 to 45), and forced vital capacity was 47% (8%-79%) at time of RIG placement. Eighty-five (85.9%) patients underwent RIG placement as outpatients, with a mean postanesthesia care unit stay of 2.3&#x2009;hours. The readmission rate was 4% at both 1 and 30&#x2009;days postprocedure.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION">PVB for RIG placement has a low rate of adverse events and provides effective periprocedural analgesia in patients with ALS, the majority of whom can be treated as outpatients.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020 Wiley Periodicals, Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Porter</LastName><ForeName>Steven B</ForeName><Initials>SB</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8657-2004</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology and Perioperative Medicine, Mayo Clinic, Jacksonville, Florida, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McClain</LastName><ForeName>Robert L</ForeName><Initials>RL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology and Perioperative Medicine, Mayo Clinic, Jacksonville, Florida, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Robards</LastName><ForeName>Christopher B</ForeName><Initials>CB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology and Perioperative Medicine, Mayo Clinic, Jacksonville, Florida, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Paz-Fumagalli</LastName><ForeName>Ricardo</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Vascular/Interventional Radiology, Mayo Clinic, Jacksonville, Florida, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Clendenen</LastName><ForeName>Steven R</ForeName><Initials>SR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology and Perioperative Medicine, Mayo Clinic, Jacksonville, Florida, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Logvinov</LastName><ForeName>Ilana I</ForeName><Initials>II</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology and Perioperative Medicine, Mayo Clinic, Jacksonville, Florida, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hex</LastName><ForeName>Karina O</ForeName><Initials>KO</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology and Perioperative Medicine, Mayo Clinic, Jacksonville, Florida, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Palmucci</LastName><ForeName>Carla</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Mayo Clinic, Jacksonville, Florida, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oskarsson</LastName><ForeName>Bj&#xf6;rn E</ForeName><Initials>BE</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1725-9866</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Mayo Clinic, Jacksonville, Florida, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Muscle Nerve</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7803146</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0148-639X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="CommentIn"><RefSource>Muscle Nerve. 2020 Jul;62(1):5-6</RefSource><PMID Version="1">32329080</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000369" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged, 80 and over</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="Y">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000601" MajorTopicYN="Y">surgery</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005471" MajorTopicYN="N">Fluoroscopy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005774" MajorTopicYN="N">Gastrostomy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009407" MajorTopicYN="N">Nerve Block</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014797" MajorTopicYN="N">Vital Capacity</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">analgesia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anesthesia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">gastrostomy tube</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">paravertebral block</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">radiologically inserted gastrostomy</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32297335</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.26894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Ringel SP, Murphy JR, Alderson MK, et al. The natural history of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology. 1993;43:1316-1322.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasarskis EJ, Mendiondo MS, Matthews DE, et al. Estimating daily energy expenditure in individuals with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Am J Clin Nutr. 2014;99:792-803.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller RG, Jackson CE, Kasarskis EJ, et al. Practice parameter update: the care of the patient with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: drug, nutritional, and respiratory therapies (an evidence-based review): report of the Quality Standards Subcommittee of the American Academy of Neurology. Neurology. 2009;73:1218-1226.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>EFNS Task Force on Diagnosis Management of Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. EFNS guidelines on the clinical management of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (MALS)-revised report of an EFNS task force. Eur J Neurol. 2012;19:360-375.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Clinical Guideline Centre (UK). Motor Neurone Disease: Assessment and Management. London: National Institute for Health and Care Excellence; 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDonnell E, Schoenfeld D, Paganoni S, Atassi N. Causal inference methods to study gastric tube use in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology. 2017;89:1483-1489.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katzberg HD, Benatar M. Enteral tube feeding for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis/motor neuron disease. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2011;CD004030. https://doi.org/10.1002/14651858.CD004030.pub3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorrie GH, Chandran S, Colville S, et al. Improved survival and 30-day mortality after gastrostomy in Scottish motor neurone disease patients: evidence from a national retrospective cohort study using STROBE criteria. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2019;20:165-171.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allen JA, Chen R, Ajroud-Driss S, et al. Gastrostomy tube placement by endoscopy versus radiologic methods in patients with ALS: a retrospective study of complications and outcome. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2013;14:308-314.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desport JC, Mabrouk T, Bouillet P, Perna A, Preux PM, Couratier P. Complications and survival following radiologically and endoscopically-guided gastrostomy in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord. 2005;6:88-93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karmakar MK. Thoracic paravertebral block. Anesthesiology. 2001;95:771-780.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lonnqvist PA, MacKenzie J, Soni AK, Conacher ID. Paravertebral blockade. Failure rate and complications. Anaesthesia. 1995;50:813-815.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, Miller RG, Swash M, et al. El Escorial revisited: revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord. 2000;1:293-299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum JM, Stambler N, Malta E, et al. The ALSFRS-R: a revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. BDNF ALS Study Group (Phase III). J Neurol Sci. 1999;169:13-21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knudson RJ, Slatin RC, Lebowitz MD, Burrows B. The maximal expiratory flow-volume curve. Normal standards, variability, and effects of age. Am Rev Respir Dis. 1976;113:587-600.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greengrass RA, Duclas R Jr. Paravertebral blocks. Int Anesthesiol Clin. 2012;50:56-73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rio A, Ampong MA, Turner MR, et al. Comparison of two percutaneous radiological gastrostomy tubes in the nutritional management of ALS patients. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord. 2005;6:177-181.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chavada G, El-Nayal A, Lee F, et al. Evaluation of two different methods for per-oral gastrostomy tube placement in patients with motor neuron disease (MND): PIG versus PEG procedures. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2010;11:531-536.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chio A, Galletti R, Finocchiaro C, et al. Percutaneous radiological gastrostomy: a safe and effective method of nutritional tube placement in advanced ALS. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2004;75:645-647.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blondet A, Lebigot J, Nicolas G, et al. Radiologic versus endoscopic placement of percutaneous gastrostomy in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: multivariate analysis of tolerance, efficacy, and survival. J Vasc Interv Radiol. 2010;21:527-533.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ProGas Study Group. Gastrostomy in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ProGas): a prospective cohort study. Lancet Neurol. 2015;14:702-709.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strijbos D, Hofstede J, Keszthelyi D, Masclee AAM, Gilissen LPL. Percutaneous endoscopic gastrostomy under conscious sedation in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis is safe: an observational study. Eur J Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2017;29:1303-1308.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoeper AM, Barbara DW, Watson JC, Sprung J, Weingarten TN. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and anesthesia: a case series and review of the literature. J Anesth. 2019;33:257-265.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirstein MM, Korner S, Schneider A, Manns MP, Petri S, Voigtlander T. Percutaneous endoscopic gastrostomy with and without jejunal extension in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Eur J Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2018;30:257-262.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma A, Bach JR, Swan KG. Open gastrostomy under local anesthesia for patients with neuromuscular disorders. Am Surg. 2010;76:369-371.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewis D, Ampong MA, Rio A, et al. Mushroom-cage gastrostomy tube placement in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a 5-year experience in 104 patients in a single institution. Eur Radiol. 2009;19:1763-1771.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balendra R, Al Khleifat A, Fang T, Al-Chalabi A. A standard operating procedure for King's ALS clinical staging. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2019;20:159-164.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ardon AE, Greengrass RA, Bhuria U, Porter SB, Robards CB, Blasser K. The use of paravertebral blockade for analgesia after anterior-approach total hip arthroplasty. Middle East J Anaesthesiol. 2015;23:81-89.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koonce SL, McLaughlin SA, Eck DL, et al. Breast cancer recurrence in patients receiving epidural and paravertebral anesthesia: a retrospective, case-control study. Middle East J Anaesthesiol. 2014;22:567-571.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilbert J, Hultman J. Thoracic paravertebral block: a method of pain control. Acta Anaesthesiol Scand. 1989;33:142-145.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sahu A, Kumar R, Hussain M, Gupta A, Raghwendra KH. Comparisons of single-injection thoracic paravertebral block with ropivacaine and bupivacaine in breast cancer surgery: a prospective, randomized, double-blinded study. Anesth Essays Res. 2016;10:655-660.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>