<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">32297678</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>29</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-4598</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>61</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Muscle &amp; nerve</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Muscle Nerve</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Use of Telehealth to Enhance Care in ALS and other Neuromuscular Disorders.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>682</StartPage><EndPage>691</EndPage><MedlinePgn>682-691</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/mus.26838</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Telehealth has the potential to improve the efficiency of healthcare while reducing the burden on patients and caregivers. Encounters can be synchronous or asynchronous. When used for care of those with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) by individual health care providers or by a multidisciplinary team, synchronous telehealth is feasible, acceptable, may produce outcomes comparable to those of in-person care, and is cost effective. Individuals with ALS who use telehealth tend to have lower physical and respiratory function and to live farther from an ALS clinic than those who exclusively attend in-person clinic visits. Asynchronous telehealth can be used as a substitute full multidisciplinary visits, or for remote monitoring of pulmonary function, gait/falls, and speech. Barriers to implementing telehealth on a wider scale include disparities in access to technology and challenges surrounding medical licensure and billing, but these are being addressed.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020 Wiley Periodicals, Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Haulman</LastName><ForeName>Anne</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Penn State Health Milton S. Hershey Medical Center, Hershey, Pennsylvania.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Geronimo</LastName><ForeName>Andrew</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7754-3754</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, Penn State Health Milton S. Hershey Medical Center, Hershey, Pennsylvania.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chahwala</LastName><ForeName>Amit</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Virtual Health, Penn State Health Milton S. Hershey Medical Center, Hershey, Pennsylvania.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Simmons</LastName><ForeName>Zachary</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8574-5332</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Penn State Health Milton S. Hershey Medical Center, Hershey, Pennsylvania.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>UL1 TR002014</GrantID><Acronym>TR</Acronym><Agency>NCATS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Muscle Nerve</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7803146</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0148-639X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000553" MajorTopicYN="N">Ambulatory Care</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000639" MajorTopicYN="Y">trends</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009468" MajorTopicYN="N">Neuromuscular Diseases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010342" MajorTopicYN="Y">Patient Acceptance of Health Care</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017060" MajorTopicYN="N">Patient Satisfaction</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017216" MajorTopicYN="N">Telemedicine</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000639" MajorTopicYN="Y">trends</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ALS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mHealth</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mobile health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">telehealth</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">telemedicine</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32297678</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.26838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Howard IM, Kaufman MS. Telehealth applications for outpatients with neuromuscular or musculoskeletal disorders. Muscle Nerve. 2018;58:475-485.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ray KN, Chari AV, Engberg J, Bertolet M, Mehrotra A. Disparities in time spent seeking medical care in the United States. JAMA Intern Med. 2015;175:1983-1986.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Handschu R, Scibor M, Willaczek B, et al. Telemedicine in acute stroke: remote video-examination compared to simple telephone consultation. J Neurol. 2008;255:1792-1797. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00415-008-0066-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amorim E, Shih MM, Koehler SA, et al. Impact of telemedicine implementation in thrombolytic use for acute ischemic stroke: the University of Pittsburgh Medical Center telestroke network experience. J Stroke Cerebrovasc Dis. 2013;22:527-531. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jstrokecerebrovasdis.2013.02.004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller-Barna P, Hubert GJ, Boy S, et al. Telestroke units serving as a model of care in rural areas: 10-year experience of the telemedical project for integrative stroke care. Stroke. 2014;45:2739-2744. https://doi.org/10.1161/STROKEAHA.114.006141.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaidi SF, Jumma MA, Urra XN, et al. Telestroke-guided intravenous tissue-type plasminogen activator treatment achieves a similar clinical outcome as thrombolysis at a comprehensive stroke center. Stroke. 2011;42:3291-3293. https://doi.org/10.1161/STROKEAHA.111.625046.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robb JF, Hyland MH, Goodman AD. Comparison of telemedicine versus in-person visits for persons with multiple sclerosis: a randomized crossover study of feasibility, cost, and satisfaction. Mult Scler Relat Disord. 2019;36:101258. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.msard.2019.05.001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedman DI, Rajan B, Seidmann A. A randomized trial of telemedicine for migraine management. Cephalalgia. 2019;39:1577-1585. https://doi.org/10.1177/0333102419868250.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bekkelund SI, M&#xfc;ller KI. Video consultations in medication overuse headache. A randomized controlled trial. Brain Behav. 2019;9:1-8. https://doi.org/10.1002/brb3.1344.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spear K, Auinger P, Simone R, Dorsey E, Francis J. Patient views on telemedicine for Parkinson disease. J Parkinsons Dis. 2019;9:401. https://doi.org/10.3233/JPD-181557.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Vries NM, Smilowska K, Hummelink J, et al. Exploring the Parkinson patients' perspective on home-based video recording for movement analysis: a qualitative study. BMC Neurol. 2019;19:1-6. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12883-019-1301-y.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Powers J, Buckner J. Reaching out to rural caregivers and veterans with dementia utilizing clinical video-telehealth. Geriatrics. 2018;3:29. https://doi.org/10.3390/geriatrics3020029.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Traynor BJ, Alexander M, Corr B, Frost E, Hardiman O. Effect of a multidisciplinary amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) clinic on ALS survival: a population based study, 1996-2000. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2003;74:1258-1261. https://doi.org/10.1136/jnnp.74.9.1258.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2; A, Bottacchi E, Buffa C, Mutani R, Mora G. Positive effects of tertiary centres for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis on outcome and use of hospital facilities. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2006;77:948-950. https://doi.org/10.1136/jnnp.2005.083402.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rooney J, Byrne S, Heverin M, et al. A multidisciplinary clinic approach improves survival in ALS:A comparative study of ALS in Ireland and Northern Ireland. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2015;86:496-501. https://doi.org/10.1136/jnnp-2014-309601.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aridegbe T, Kandler R, Walters SJ, Walsh T, Shaw PJ, McDermott CJ. The natural history of motor neuron disease: assessing the impact of specialist care. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2013;14:13-19. https://doi.org/10.3109/17482968.2012.690419.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Den Berg JP, Kalmijn S, Lindeman E, et al. Multidisciplinary ALS care improves quality of life in patients with ALS. Neurology. 2005;65:1264-1267. https://doi.org/10.1212/01.wnl.0000180717.29273.12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stephens HE, Felgoise S, Young J, Simmons Z. Multidisciplinary ALS clinics in the USA: a comparison of those who attend and those who do not. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2015;16:196-201. https://doi.org/10.3109/21678421.2014.994530.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stephens HE, Young J, Felgoise SH, Simmons Z. A qualitative study of multidisciplinary ALS clinic use in the United States. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2016;17:55-61. https://doi.org/10.3109/21678421.2015.1069851.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horton DK, Graham S, Punjani R, et al. A spatial analysis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) cases in the United States and their proximity to multidisciplinary ALS clinics, 2013. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2018;19:126-133. https://doi.org/10.1080/21678421.2017.1406953.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy V, Felgoise SH, Walsh SM, Simmons Z. Problem solving skills predict quality of life and psychological morbidity in ALS caregivers. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2009;10:147-153. https://doi.org/10.1080/17482960802245007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hecht MJ, Graesel E, Tigges S, et al. Burden of care in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Palliat Med. 2003;17:327-333. https://doi.org/10.1191/0269216303pm754oa.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henderson RD, Hutchinson N, Douglas JA, Douglas C. Telehealth for motor neurone disease. Med J Aust. 2014;201:31. https://doi.org/10.5694/mja14.00170.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van De Rijn M, Paganoni S, Levine-Weinberg M, et al. Experience with telemedicine in a multi-disciplinary ALS clinic. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2018;19:143-148. https://doi.org/10.1080/21678421.2017.1392577.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geronimo A, Wright C, Morris A, Walsh S, Snyder B, Simmons Z. Incorporation of telehealth into a multidisciplinary ALS Clinic: feasibility and acceptability. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2017;18:555-561. https://doi.org/10.1080/21678421.2017.1338298.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller RG, Brooks BR, Swain-Eng RJ, et al. Quality improvement in neurology: amyotrophic lateral sclerosis quality measures: report of the quality measurement and reporting subcommittee of the American academy of neurology. Neurology. 2013;81:2136-2140. https://doi.org/10.1212/01.wnl.0000437305.37850.f9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selkirk SM, Washington MO, McClellan F, Flynn B, Seton JM, Strozewski R. Delivering tertiary centre specialty care to ALS patients via telemedicine: a retrospective cohort analysis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2017;18:324-332. https://doi.org/10.1080/21678421.2017.1313867.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paganoni S, van de Rijn M, Drake K, et al. Adjusted cost analysis of video televisits for the care of people with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 2019;60:147-154. https://doi.org/10.1002/mus.26606.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pulley MT, Brittain R, Hodges W, et al. Multidisciplinary amyotrophic lateral sclerosis telemedicine care: The store and forward method. Muscle Nerve. 2019;59:34-39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller RG, Jackson CE, Kasarskis EJ, et al. Practice parameter update: the care ofthe patient with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: drug, nutritional, and respiratory therapies (an evidence-based review): report ofthe Quality Standards Subcommittee ofthe American Academy of Neurology. Neurology. 2009;73:1218-1226. https://doi.org/10.1212/WNL.0b013e3181bc0141.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bourke SC, Tomlinson M, Williams TL, Bullock RE, Shaw PJ, Gibson GJ. Effects of non-invasive ventilation on survival and quality of life in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a randomised controlled trial. Lancet Neurol. 2006;5:140-147. https://doi.org/10.1016/S1474-4422(05)70326-4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butz M, Wollinsky KH, Wiedemuth-Catrinescu U, et al. Longitudinal effects of noninvasive positive-pressure ventilation in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2003;82:597-604. https://doi.org/10.1097/01.phm.0000078239.83545.d0.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller RG, Brooks BR, Swain-Eng RJ, et al. Quality improvement in neurology: amyotrophic lateral sclerosis quality measures. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2014;15:165-168. https://doi.org/10.3109/21678421.2013.875706.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geronimo A, Simmons Z. Evaluation of remote pulmonary function testing in motor neuron disease. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2019;20:348-355. https://doi.org/10.1080/21678421.2019.1587633.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>PRIZE4LIFE, Neurological Clinical Research Institute. PRO-ACT. Published 2020. https://nctu.partners.org/ProACT/Document/DisplayLatest/5. Accessed February 7, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, Li J, Huang W, Anderson FA, Miller RG, Mitsumoto H. Epidemiology of falls in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients: analysis of cross-sectional and prospective cohorts in the ALS CARE registry. Ann Neurol. 2007;62(suppl 11):S23-S24. Published online: 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pieterse AJ, Luttikhold TB, de Laat K, Bloem BR, van Engelen BG, Munneke M. Falls in patients with neuromuscular disorders. J Neurol Sci. 2006;251:87-90. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jns.2006.09.008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schell WE, Mar VS, Da Silva CP. Correlation of falls in patients with Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis with objective measures of balance, strength, and spasticity. NeuroRehabilitation. 2019;44:85-93. https://doi.org/10.3233/NRE-182531.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hobson EV, Baird WO, Partridge R, et al. The TiM system: developing a novel telehealth service to improve access to specialist care in motor neurone disease using user-centered design. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2018;19:351-361. https://doi.org/10.1080/21678421.2018.1440408.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rutkove SB, Qi K, Shelton K, Liss J, Berisha V, Shefner JM. ALS longitudinal studies with frequent data collection at home: study design and baseline data. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2019;20:61-67. https://doi.org/10.1080/21678421.2018.1541095.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rural Health Information Hub. Barriers to telehealth in rural areas. https://www.ruralhealthinfo.org/toolkits/telehealth/1/barriers.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Office of the National Coordinator for Health Information Technology (ONC). Are there state licensing issues related to telehealth? Published 2020. https://www.healthit.gov/faq/are-there-state-licensing-issues-related-telehealth.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Interstate Medical Licensure Compact. The IMLC. Published 2020. https://imlcc.org/. Accessed February 7, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.S. Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services. Telehealth. https://www.medicare.gov/coverage/telehealth. Published 2020. Accessed February 7, 2020.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>