<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">32307753</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>19</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1530-6860</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>34</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>FASEB journal : official publication of the Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>FASEB J</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The potential interplay between energy metabolism and innate complement activation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>7225</StartPage><EndPage>7233</EndPage><MedlinePgn>7225-7233</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1096/fj.201901781</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) is a fatal and rapidly progressing motor neuron disease without effective treatment. Although the precise mechanisms leading to ALS are yet to be determined, there is now increasing evidence implicating the defective energy metabolism and components of the innate immune complement system in the onset and progression of its motor phenotypes. This review will survey the mechanisms by which the energy metabolism and the complement system are altered during the disease progression of ALS and how it can contribute to disease. Furthermore, it will also examine how complement activation can modify the energy metabolism in metabolic disorders, in order to highlight how the complement system and energy metabolism may be linked in ALS.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020 Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McDonald</LastName><ForeName>Tanya S</ForeName><Initials>TS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Biomedical Sciences, The University of Queensland, St. Lucia, QLD, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McCombe</LastName><ForeName>Pamela A</ForeName><Initials>PA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2704-8517</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Queensland Centre for Clinical Research, The University of Queensland, Herston, QLD, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Royal Brisbane &amp; Women's Hospital, Herston, QLD, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Woodruff</LastName><ForeName>Trent M</ForeName><Initials>TM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1382-911X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Biomedical Sciences, The University of Queensland, St. Lucia, QLD, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>John D</ForeName><Initials>JD</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9976-7396</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Biomedical Sciences, The University of Queensland, St. Lucia, QLD, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Queensland Centre for Clinical Research, The University of Queensland, Herston, QLD, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>FASEB J</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8804484</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0892-6638</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>9007-36-7</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D003165">Complement System Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="Y">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003167" MajorTopicYN="N">Complement Activation</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="Y">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003165" MajorTopicYN="N">Complement System Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="Y">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018450" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Progression</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004734" MajorTopicYN="N">Energy Metabolism</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="Y">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007113" MajorTopicYN="N">Immunity, Innate</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="Y">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009046" MajorTopicYN="N">Motor Neurons</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">TCA cycle</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">glucose metabolism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neurodegeneration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neuroinflammation</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32307753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1096/fj.201901781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Brown RH, Al-Chalabi A. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. N Engl J Med. 2017;377:162-172.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosler KM, Truffert A, Hess CW, Magistris MR. Quantification of upper motor neuron loss in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Neurophysiol. 2000;111:2208-2218.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parker SE, Hanton AM, Stefanou SN, Noakes PG, Woodruff TM, Lee JD. Revisiting the role of the innate immune complement system in ALS. Neurobiol Dis. 2019;127:223-232.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vandoorne T, De Bock K, Van Den Bosch L. Energy metabolism in ALS: an underappreciated opportunity? Acta Neuropathol. 2018;135:489-509.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lumeng CN, Saltiel AR. Inflammatory links between obesity and metabolic disease. J Clin Investig. 2011;121:2111-2117.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manthey HD, Woodruff TM, Taylor SM, Monk PN. Complement component 5a (C5a). Int J Biochem Cell Biol. 2009;41:2114-2117.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarma JV, Ward PA. The complement system. Cell Tissue Res. 2011;343:227-235.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>West EE, Kolev M, Kemper C. Complement and the regulation of T cell responses. Annu Rev Immunol. 2018;36:309-338.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brennan FH, Lee JD, Ruitenberg MJ, Woodruff TM. Therapeutic targeting of complement to modify disease course and improve outcomes in neurological conditions. Semin Immunol. 2016;28:292-308.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heurich B, El Idrissi NB, Donev RM, et al. Complement upregulation and activation on motor neurons and neuromuscular junction in the SOD1 G93A mouse model of familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neuroimmunol. 2011;235:104-109.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee JD, Kamaruzaman NA, Fung JNT, et al. Dysregulation of the complement cascade in the hSOD1G93A transgenic mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neuroinflammation. 2013;10:119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang HA, Lee JD, Lee KM, Woodruff TM, Noakes PG. Complement C5a-C5aR1 signalling drives skeletal muscle macrophage recruitment in the hSOD1(G93A) mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Skelet Muscle. 2017;7:10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Humayun S, Gohar M, Volkening K, et al. The complement factor C5a receptor is upregulated in NFL&#x2212;/&#x2212; mouse motor neurons. J Neuroimmunol. 2009;210:52-62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee JD, Kumar V, Fung JN, Ruitenberg MJ, Noakes PG, Woodruff TM. Pharmacological inhibition of complement C5a-C5a1 receptor signalling ameliorates disease pathology in the hSOD1(G93A) mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Br J Pharmacol. 2017;174:689-699.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woodruff TM, Costantini KJ, Crane JW, et al. The complement factor C5a contributes to pathology in a rat model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Immunol. 2008;181:8727-8734.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woodruff TM, Lee JD, Noakes PG. Role for terminal complement activation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis disease progression. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2014;111:E3-E4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bahia El Idrissi N, Fluiter K, Vieira FG, Baas F. Complement component C6 inhibition decreases neurological disability in female transgenic SOD1G93A mouse model of Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. Ann Neurodegener Dis. 2016;1:1015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Llanos P, Contreras-Ferrat A, Barrientos G, Valencia M, Mears D, Hidalgo C. Glucose-dependent insulin secretion in pancreatic &#x3b2;-cell islets from male rats requires Ca2+ release via ROS-stimulated ryanodine receptors. PLoS ONE. 2015;10:e0129238.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quesada I, Tudur&#xed; E, Ripoll C, Nadal &#xc1;. Physiology of the pancreatic &#x3b1;-cell and glucagon secretion: role in glucose homeostasis and diabetes. J Endocrinol. 2008;199:5-19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Habegger KM, Heppner KM, Geary N, Bartness TJ, DiMarchi R, Tschop MH. The metabolic actions of glucagon revisited. Nat Rev Endocrinol. 2010;6:689-697.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilcox G. Insulin and insulin resistance. Clinical Biochemist Reviews. 2005;26:19-39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boucher J, Kleinridders A, Kahn CR. Insulin receptor signaling in normal and insulin-resistant states. Cold Spring Harbor Perspectives in Biology. 2014;6:a009191.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saltiel AR, Kahn CR. Insulin signalling and the regulation of glucose and lipid metabolism. Nature. 2001;414:799-806.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J, Liu F. Tissue-specific insulin signaling in the regulation of metabolism and aging. IUBMB Life. 2014;66:485-495.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bryant NJ, Govers R, James DE. Regulated transport of the glucose transporter GLUT4. Nat Rev Mol Cell Biol. 2002;3:267-277.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Apelt J, Mehlhorn G, Schliebs R. Insulin-sensitive GLUT4 glucose transporters are colocalized with GLUT3-expressing cells and demonstrate a chemically distinct neuron-specific localization in rat brain. J Neurosci Res. 1999;57:693-705.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brant AM, Jess TJ, Milligan G, Brown CM, Gould GW. Immunological analysis of glucose transporters expressed in different regions of the rat brain and central nervous system. Biochem Biophys Res Comm. 1993;192:1297-1302.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>El Messari S, Leloup C, Quignon M, Brisorgueil M-J, Penicaud L, Arluison M. Immunocytochemical localization of the insulin-responsive glucose transporter 4 (Glut4) in the rat central nervous system. J Comp Neurol. 1998;399:492-512.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Unger JW, Livingston JN, Moss AM. Insulin receptors in the central nervous system: localization, signalling mechanisms and functional aspects. Prog Neurogibol. 1991;36:343-362.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vannucci SJ, Koehler-Stec EM, Li K, Reynolds TH, Clark R, Simpson IA. GLUT4 glucose transporter expression in rodent brain: effect of diabetes. Brain Res. 1998;797:1-11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun Y, Lu C-J, Chen R-C, Hou W-H, Li C-Y. Risk of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in patients with diabetes: a nationwide population-based cohort study. Journal of epidemiology/Japan Epidemiological Association. 2014;25:445-451.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kioumourtzoglou M-A, Rotem RS, Seals RM, Gredal O, Hansen J, Weisskopf MG. Diabetes mellitus, obesity, and diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a population-based study. JAMA Neurology. 2015;72:905-911.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mariosa D, Kamel F, Bellocco R, Ye W, Fang F. Association between diabetes and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in Sweden. Eur J Neurol. 2015;22:1436-1442.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Staels B. Metformin and pioglitazone: effectively treating insulin resistance. Curr Med Res Opin. 2006;22:S27-S37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiaei M, Kipiani K, Chen J, Calingasan NY, Beal MF. Peroxisome proliferator-activated receptor-gamma agonist extends survival in transgenic mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Exp Neurol. 2005;191:331-336.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sch&#xfc;tz B, Reimann J, Dumitrescu-Ozimek L, et al. The oral antidiabetic pioglitazone protects from neurodegeneration and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-like symptoms in superoxide dismutase-G93A transgenic mice. J Neurosci. 2005;25:7805-7812.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaneb HM, Sharp PS, Rahmani-Kondori N, Wells DJ. Metformin treatment has no beneficial effect in a dose-response survival study in the SOD1 G93A mouse model of ALS and is harmful in female mice. PLoS ONE. 2011;6:e24189.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sinacore DR, Gulve EA. The role of skeletal muscle in glucose transport, glucose homeostasis, and insulin resistance: implications for physical therapy. Phys Ther. 1993;73:878-891.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ionasescu V, Luca N. Studies on carbohydrate metabolism in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and hereditary proximal spinal muscular atrophy. Acta Neurol Scand. 1964;40:47-57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reyes ET, Perurena OH, Festoff BW, Jorgensen R, Moore WV. Insulin resistance in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Sci. 1984;63:317-324.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saffer D, Morley J, Bill PL. Carbohydrate metabolism in motor neurone disease. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 1977;40:533-537.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palamiuc L, Schlagowski A, Ngo ST, et al. A metabolic switch toward lipid use in glycolytic muscle is an early pathologic event in a mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. EMBO Mol Med. 2015;7:526-546.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henriksen EJ, Rodnick KJ, Mondon CE, James DE, Holloszy JO. (1991) Effect of denervation or unweighting on GLUT-4 protein in rat soleus muscle. J Appl Physiol. 1985;70:2322-2327.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mueller PS, Quick DT. Studies of glucose, insulin, and lipid metabolism in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and other neuromuscular disorders. J Lab Clin Med. 1970;76:190-201.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desseille C, Deforges S, Biondi O, et al. Specific physical exercise improves energetic metabolism in the skeletal muscle of amyotrophic-lateral- sclerosis mice. Front Mol Neurosci. 2017;10:332.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stallings NR, Puttaparthi K, Dowling KJ, et al. TDP-43, an ALS linked protein, regulates fat deposition and glucose homeostasis. PLoS ONE. 2013;8:e71793.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gitcho MA, Baloh RH, Chakraverty S, et al. TDP-43 A315T mutation in familial motor neuron disease. Ann Neurol. 2008;63:535-538.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sreedharan J, Blair IP, Tripathi VB, et al. TDP-43 mutations in familial and sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Science. 2008;319:1668-1672.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao X, Bak S, Pedersen AJ, Jensen ON, Hojlund K. Insulin increases phosphorylation of mitochondrial proteins in human skeletal muscle in vivo. J Proteome Res. 2014;13:2359-2369.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sleigh A, Raymond-Barker P, Thackray K, et al. Mitochondrial dysfunction in patients with primary congenital insulin resistance. J Clin Invest. 2011;121:2457-2461.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouteloup C, Desport JC, Clavelou P, et al. Hypermetabolism in ALS patients: an early and persistent phenomenon. J Neurol. 2009;256:1236-1242.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carri MT, Cozzolino M. SOD1 and mitochondria in ALS: a dangerous liaison. J Bioenerg Biomembr. 2011;43:593-599.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Funalot B, Desport JC, Sturtz F, Camu W, Couratier P. High metabolic level in patients with familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2009;10:113-117.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steyn FJ, Ioannides ZA, van Eijk RPA, et al. Hypermetabolism in ALS is associated with greater functional decline and shorter survival. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2018;89:1016-1023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Browne SE, Yang L, DiMauro JP, Fuller SW, Licata SC, Beal MF. Bioenergetic abnormalities in discrete cerebral motor pathways presage spinal cord pathology in the G93A SOD1 mouse model of ALS. Neurobiol Dis. 2006;22:599-610.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cistaro A, Valentini MC, Chio A, et al. Brain hypermetabolism in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a FDG PET study in ALS of spinal and bulbar onset. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging. 2012;39:251-259.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pagani M, Chio A, Valentini MC, et al. Functional pattern of brain FDG-PET in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology. 2014;83:1067-1074.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Laere K, Vanhee A, Verschueren J, et al. Value of 18fluorodeoxyglucose-positron-emission tomography in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a prospective study. JAMA Neurol. 2014;71:553-561.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szelechowski M, Amoedo N, Obre E, et al. Metabolic reprogramming in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Sci Rep. 2018;8:3953.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dupuis L, Oudart H, Rene F, Gonzalez de Aguilar JL, Loeffler JP. Evidence for defective energy homeostasis in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: benefit of a high-energy diet in a transgenic mouse model. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2004;101:11159-11164.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Genton L, Viatte V, Janssens JP, Heritier AC, Pichard C. Nutritional state, energy intakes and energy expenditure of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) patients. Clin Nutr. 2011;30:553-559.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasarskis EJ, Berryman S, Vanderleest JG, Schneider AR, McClain CJ. Nutritional status of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: relation to the proximity of death. Am J Clin Nutr. 1996;63:130-137.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lou JS. Fatigue in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Phys Med Rehabil Clin N Am. 2008;19:533-543 ix.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McElhiney MC, Rabkin JG, Gordon PH, Goetz R, Mitsumoto H. Prevalence of fatigue and depression in ALS patients and change over time. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2009;80:1146-1149.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimizu T, Nagaoka U, Nakayama Y, et al. Reduction rate of body mass index predicts prognosis for survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a multicenter study in Japan. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2012;13:363-366.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed RM, Mioshi E, Caga J, et al. Body mass index delineates ALS from FTD: implications for metabolic health. J Neurol. 2014;261:1774-1780.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paganoni S, Deng J, Jaffa M, Cudkowicz ME, Wills AM. Body mass index, not dyslipidemia, is an independent predictor of survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 2011;44:20-24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindauer E, Dupuis L, Muller HP, Neumann H, Ludolph AC, Kassubek J. Adipose tissue distribution predicts survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. PLoS ONE. 2013;8:e67783.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamadeh MJ, Rodriguez MC, Kaczor JJ, Tarnopolsky MA. Caloric restriction transiently improves motor performance but hastens clinical onset of disease in the Cu/Zn-superoxide dismutase mutant G93A mouse. Muscle Nerve. 2005;31:214-220.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mattson MP, Cutler RG, Camandola S. Energy intake and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuromolecular Med. 2007;9:17-20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel BP, Safdar A, Raha S, Tarnopolsky MA, Hamadeh MJ. Caloric restriction shortens lifespan through an increase in lipid peroxidation, inflammation and apoptosis in the G93A mouse, an animal model of ALS. PLoS ONE. 2010;5:e9386.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fergani A, Oudart H, Gonzalez De Aguilar JL, et al. Increased peripheral lipid clearance in an animal model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Lipid Res. 2007;48:1571-1580.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mamane Y, Chung Chan C, Lavallee G, et al. The C3a anaphylatoxin receptor is a key mediator of insulin resistance and functions by modulating adipose tissue macrophage infiltration and activation. Diabetes. 2009;58:2006-2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phieler J, Chung KJ, Chatzigeorgiou A, et al. The complement anaphylatoxin C5a receptor contributes to obese adipose tissue inflammation and insulin resistance. J Immunol. 2013;191:4367-4374.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roy C, Gupta A, Fisette A, et al. C5a receptor deficiency alters energy utilization and fat storage. PLoS ONE. 2013;8:e62531.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roy C, Paglialunga S, Fisette A, et al. Shift in metabolic fuel in acylation-stimulating protein-deficient mice following a high-fat diet. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2008;294:E1051-E1059.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia Z, Stanhope KL, Digitale E, et al. Acylation-stimulating protein (ASP)/complement C3adesArg deficiency results in increased energy expenditure in mice. J Biol Chem. 2004;279:4051-4057.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roy C, Paglialunga S, Schaart G, et al. Relationship of C5L2 receptor to skeletal muscle substrate utilization. PLoS ONE. 2013;8:e57494.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johswich K, Klos A. C5L2-an anti-inflammatory molecule or a receptor for acylation stimulating protein (C3a-desArg)? Adv Exp Med Biol. 2007;598:159-180.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johswich K, Martin M, Thalmann J, Rheinheimer C, Monk PN, Klos A. Ligand specificity of the anaphylatoxin C5L2 receptor and its regulation on myeloid and epithelial cell lines. J Biol Chem. 2006;281:39088-39095.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li R, Coulthard LG, Wu MC, Taylor SM, Woodruff TM. C5L2: a controversial receptor of complement anaphylatoxin, C5a. FASEB J. 2013;27:855-864.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paglialunga S, Schrauwen P, Roy C, et al. Reduced adipose tissue triglyceride synthesis and increased muscle fatty acid oxidation in C5L2 knockout mice. J Endocrinol. 2007;194:293-304.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>