<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">32337820</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>26</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2982</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>32</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Neurogastroenterology and motility</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Neurogastroenterol Motil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Association between maximum tongue pressure and swallowing safety and efficacy in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e13859</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e13859</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/nmo.13859</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Oropharyngeal dysphagia (OD) is common in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS), leading to a reduction of swallowing safety and efficacy. The tongue has an important role in swallowing function for oral processing and bolus propulsion through the pharynx. The study aims to analyze the association between instrumental findings of OD and tongue pressure.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Patients with ALS referred for fiberoptic endoscopic evaluation of swallowing (FEES) were recruited. FEES was conducted to test swallowing function with liquid (5, 10, and 20&#xa0;ml), semisolid (5, 10, and 20&#xa0;ml), and solid. FEES recordings were assessed for swallowing safety, using the penetration-aspiration scale (PAS), and for swallowing efficacy, using the Yale Pharyngeal Residue Severity Rating Scale (YPRSRS). PAS scores &gt;2 were suggestive of penetration, PAS scores &gt;5 of aspiration, and YPRSRS scores &gt;2 of residue. Maximum tongue pressure (MTP) and tongue endurance were measured using the Iowa Oral Performance Instrument. Tongue pressure measurements were compared between patients with and without penetration, aspiration, or residue.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="KEY RESULTS">Fifty-five patients with ALS were included. Mean MTP was 29.7&#xa0;kPa, and median tongue endurance was 10&#xa0;seconds. Patients with residue in the pyriform sinus had a significantly lower MTP than patients without residue in the pyriform sinus with semisolids 10&#xa0;ml (P&#xa0;=&#xa0;.011) and 20&#xa0;ml (P&#xa0;=&#xa0;.032). Patients with a tongue endurance &lt;10&#xa0;seconds exhibited higher frequency of penetration with liquids 5&#xa0;ml (P&#xa0;=&#xa0;.046), liquids 10&#xa0;ml (P&#xa0;=&#xa0;.015), and solids (P&#xa0;=&#xa0;.22).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION AND INFERENCES">In patients with ALS, MTP is significantly associated with an impairment of swallowing efficacy and tongue endurance was significantly associated with an impairment of swallowing safety.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020 John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pizzorni</LastName><ForeName>Nicole</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3939-0742</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical and Clinical Sciences "Luigi Sacco", University of Milan, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ginocchio</LastName><ForeName>Daniela</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ALS Center, Istituti Clinici Scientifici Maugeri IRCCS, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bianchi</LastName><ForeName>Federica</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ALS Center, Istituti Clinici Scientifici Maugeri IRCCS, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Feroldi</LastName><ForeName>Sarah</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ALS Center, Istituti Clinici Scientifici Maugeri IRCCS, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vedrodyova</LastName><ForeName>Miriam</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ALS Center, Istituti Clinici Scientifici Maugeri IRCCS, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mora</LastName><ForeName>Gabriele</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ALS Center, Istituti Clinici Scientifici Maugeri IRCCS, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schindler</LastName><ForeName>Antonio</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical and Clinical Sciences "Luigi Sacco", University of Milan, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Neurogastroenterol Motil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9432572</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1350-1925</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003679" MajorTopicYN="N">Deglutition</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003680" MajorTopicYN="N">Deglutition Disorders</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004724" MajorTopicYN="N">Endoscopy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010614" MajorTopicYN="N">Pharynx</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011312" MajorTopicYN="N">Pressure</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">deglutition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">deglutition disorders</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pharyngeal diseases</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tongue</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32337820</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/nmo.13859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Rowlan LP, Shneider NA. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. N Engl J Med. 2011;344:1688-1700.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen A, Garrett CG. Original articles: otolaryngologic presentation of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg. 2005;132:500-504.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xfc;hnlein P, Gdynia H-J, Sperfeld A-D, et al. Diagnosis and treatment of bulbar symptoms in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat Clin Pract Neurol. 2008;4:366-374.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lever TE, Gorsek A, Cox KT, et al. An animal model of oral dysphagia in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Dysphagia. 2009;24:180-195.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lever TE, Simon E, Cox KT, et al. A mouse model of pharyngeal dysphagia in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Dysphagia. 2010;25:112-126.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawai S, Tsukuda M, Mochimatsu I, et al. A study of the early stage of Dysphagia in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Dysphagia. 2003;18:1-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rofes L, Arreola V, Almirall J, et al. Diagnosis and management of oropharyngeal dysphagia and its nutritional and respiratory complications in the elderly. Gastroenterol Res Pract. 2011;2011:818979.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paris G, Martinaud O, Petit A, et al. Oropharyngeal dysphagia in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis alters quality of life. J Oral Rehabil. 2013;40:199-204.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fattori B, Siciliano G, Mancini V, et al. Dysphagia in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: relationships between disease progression and fiberoptic endoscopic evaluation of swallowing. Auris Nasus Larynx. 2017;44:306-312.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waito AA, Valenzano TJ, Peladeau-Pigeon M, Steele CM. Trends in research literature describing dysphagia in motor neuron diseases (MND): a scoping review. Dysphagia. 2017;32:734-747.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hind J, Divyak E, Zielinski J, et al. Comparison of standardized bariums with varying rheological parameters on swallowing kinematics in males. J Rehabil Res Dev. 2012;49:1399-1404.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steele CM, Alsanei WA, Ayanikalath S, et al. The influence of food texture and liquid consistency modification on swallowing physiology and function: a systematic review. Dysphagia. 2015;30:2-26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butler SG, Stuart A, Markley L, Feng X, Kritchevsky SB. Aspiration as a function of age, sex, liquid type, bolus volume, and bolus delivery across the healthy adult life span. Ann Otol Rhinol Laryngol. 2018;127:21-32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Youmans SR, Stierwalt JAG. Measure of tongue function related to normal swallowing. Dysphagia. 2006;21:102-111.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butler SG, Stuart A, Leng X, et al. The relationship of aspiration status with tongue and handgrip strength in healthy older adults. J Gerontol Series A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2011;66:452-458.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Namasivayam-MacDonald AM, Morrison JM, Steele CM, Keller H. How swallow pressure and dysphagia affect malnutrition and mealtime outcomes in long-term care. Dysphagia. 2017;32:785-796.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minagi Y, Ono T, Hori K, et al. Relationships between dysphagia and tongue pressure during swallowing in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease patients. J Oral Rehabil. 2018;46:459-466.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weikamp JG, Schelhaas HJ, Hendriks JCM, de Swart BJM, Geurts ACH. Prognostic value of decreased tongue strength on survival time in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol. 2012;259:2360-2365.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Easterling C, Antinoja J, Cashin S, Barkhaus PE. Changes in tongue pressure, pulmonary function, and salivary flow in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Dysphagia. 2013;28:217-225.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hiraoka A, Yoshikawa M, Nakamori M, et al. Maximum tongue pressure is associated with swallowing dysfunction in ALS patients. Dysphagia. 2017;32:542-547.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garber CE, Blissmer B, Deschenes MR, et al. Quantity and quality of exercise for developing and maintaining cardiorespiratory, musculoskeletal, and neuromotor fitness in apparently healthy adults: guidance for prescribing exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2011;43:1334-1359.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kays SA, Hind JA, Gangnon RE, Robbins J. Effects of dining on tongue endurance and swallowing-related outcomes. J Speech Lang Hear Res. 2010;53:898-907.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lou JS. Fatigue in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Phys Med Rehabil Clin N Am. 2008;19:533-543.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, Miller RG, Swash M, Munsat TL. El Escorial revisited: revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord. 2000;1:293-299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum JM, Stambler N, Malta E, et al. The ALSFRS-R: a revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. BDNF ALS Study Group (Phase III). J Neurol Sci. 1999;169:13-21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vanderwegen J, Guns C, Van Nuffelen G, Elen R, De Bodt M. The influence of age, sex, bulb position, visual feedback, and the order of testing on maximum anterior and posterior tongue strength and endurance in healthy Belgian adults. Dysphagia. 2013;28:159-166.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark HM, Henson PA, Barber WD, Stierwalt JA, Sherrill M. Relationships among subjective and objective measures of tongue strength and oral phase swallowing impairments. Am J Speech Lang Pathol. 2003;12:40-50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huckabee ML, McIntosh T, Fuller L, et al. The Test of Masticating and Swallowing Solids (TOMASS): reliability, validity and international normative data. Int J Lang Commun Disord. 2018;53:144-156.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenbek JC, Robbins JA, Roecker EB, Cotle JL, Wood JL. A penetration-aspiration scale. Dysphagia. 1996;11:93-98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neubauer PD, Rademaker AW, Leder SB. The Yale pharyngeal residue severity rating scale: an anatomically defined and image-based tool. Dysphagia. 2015;30:521-528.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Battel I, Calvo I, Walshe M. Cross-cultural validation of the Italian version of the Functional Oral Intake Scale. Folia Phoniatr Logop. 2018;70:117-123.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robbins J, Levine R, Wood J, Roecker EB, Luschei E. Age effects on lingual pressure generation as a risk factor for dysphagia. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 1995;50:M257-M262.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirota N, Konaka K, Ono T, et al. Reduced tongue pressure against the hard palate on the paralyzed side during swallowing predicts dysphagia in patients with acute stroke. Stroke. 2010;41:2982-2984.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konaka K, Kondo J, Hirota N, et al. Relationship between tongue pressure and dysphagia in stroke patients. Eur Neurol. 2010;64:101-107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maeda K, Akagi J. Decreased tongue pressure is associated with sarcopenia and sarcopenic dysphagia in the elderly. Dysphagia. 2015;30:80-87.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pitts LL, Morales S, Stierwalt JAG. Lingual pressure as a clinical indicator of swallowing function in Parkinson's disease. J Speech Lang Hear Res. 2018;61:257-265.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palmer PM, Jaffe DM, McCulloch TM, Finnegan EM, Van Daele DJ, Luschei ES. Quantitative contributions of the muscles of the tongue, floor-of-mouth, jaw, and velum to tongue-to-palate pressure generation. J Speech Lang Hear Res. 2008;51:828-835.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waito AA, Tabor-Gray LC, Steele CM, Plowman EK. Reduced pharyngeal constriction is associated with impaired swallowing efficiency in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis (ALS). Neurogastroenterol Motil. 2018;30:e13450.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Youmans SR, Youmans GL, Stierwalt JAG. Differences in tongue strength across age and gender: is there a diminished strength reserve? Dysphagia. 2009;24:57-65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Namiki C, Hara K, Tohara H, et al. Tongue-pressure resistance training improves tongue and suprahyoid muscle functions simultaneously. Clin Interv Aging. 2019;14:601-608.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plowman EK. Is there a role for exercise in the management of bulbar dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis? J Speech Lang Hear Res. 2015;58:1151-1166.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plowman EK, Tabor-Gray L, Rosado KM, et al. Impact of expiratory strength training in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: results of a randomized, sham-controlled trial. Muscle Nerve. 2019;59:40-46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robison RD. The impact of lingual resistance training in two individuals with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. A case series. Graduate theses and dissertations. 2015. http://scholarcommons.usf.edu/etd/5768. Accessed September 10, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smaoui S, Langridge A, Steele CM. The effect of lingual resistance training interventions on adult swallow function: a systematic review. Dysphagia. 2019. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00455-019-10066-1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giraldo-Cadavid LF, Leal-Lea&#xf1;o LR, Leon-Basantes GA, et al. Accuracy of endoscopic and videofluoroscopic evaluations of swallowing for oropharyngeal dysphagia. Laryngoscope. 2017;127:2002-2010.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>