<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">32337711</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>07</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1873-3468</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>594</Volume><Issue>14</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>FEBS letters</Title><ISOAbbreviation>FEBS Lett</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Molecular dissection of ALS-linked TDP-43 - involvement of the Gly-rich domain in interaction with G-quadruplex mRNA.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2254</StartPage><EndPage>2265</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2254-2265</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/1873-3468.13800</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>TDP-43 is the major pathogenic protein of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). Previously, we identified that TDP-43 interacts with G-quadruplex (G4)-containing RNA and is involved in their long-distance transport in neurons. For the molecular dissection of the TDP-43 and G4-RNA interaction, we analyzed it here in&#xa0;vitro and in cultured cells using a set of 10 mutant TDP-43 proteins from familial and sporadic ALS patients as well as using the TDP-43 C-terminal Gly-rich domain alone. Our results altogether indicate the involvement of the Gly-rich region of TDP-43 in the initial recognition and binding of G4-RNA, which then induces tight binding of TDP-43 with target RNAs, supposedly in conjunction with its RNA recognition motifs.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020 Federation of European Biochemical Societies.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ishiguro</LastName><ForeName>Akira</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1867-3134</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Center for Micro-Nano Technology, Hosei University, Koganei, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kimura</LastName><ForeName>Nobuyuki</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5813-7227</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Section of Cell Biology and Pathology, Department of Alzheimer's Disease Research, Center for Development of Advanced Medicine for Dementia, National Center for Geriatrics and Gerontology, Obu, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Noma</LastName><ForeName>Takashi</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biological Science, Graduate School of Science, and Faculty of Science Osaka University, Toyonaka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shimo-Kon</LastName><ForeName>Rieko</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biological Science, Graduate School of Science, and Faculty of Science Osaka University, Toyonaka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ishihama</LastName><ForeName>Akira</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Center for Micro-Nano Technology, Hosei University, Koganei, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kon</LastName><ForeName>Takahide</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biological Science, Graduate School of Science, and Faculty of Science Osaka University, Toyonaka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>FEBS Lett</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0155157</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0014-5793</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D004268">DNA-Binding Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D012333">RNA, Messenger</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C000598624">TARDBP protein, human</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>TE7660XO1C</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D005998">Glycine</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="Y">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004268" MajorTopicYN="N">DNA-Binding Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="Y">chemistry</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="N">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054856" MajorTopicYN="Y">G-Quadruplexes</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005998" MajorTopicYN="N">Glycine</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057809" MajorTopicYN="N">HEK293 Cells</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009154" MajorTopicYN="N">Mutation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000072417" MajorTopicYN="N">Protein Domains</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D034443" MajorTopicYN="N">RNA Transport</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012333" MajorTopicYN="N">RNA, Messenger</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="Y">chemistry</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">G-quadruplex</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">RNA</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">TDP-43</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mRNA transport</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32337711</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/1873-3468.13800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Rhodes D and Lipps HJ (2015) G-quadruplexes and their regulatory roles in biology. Nucleic Acids Res 43, 8627-8637.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fay MM, Lyons SM and Ivanov P (2017) RNA G-quadruplexes in biology: principles and molecular mechanisms. J Mol Biol 429, 2127-2147.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saranathan N and Vivekanandan P (2019) G-quadruplexes: more than just a kink in microbial genomes. Trends Microbiol 27, 148-163.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Subramanian M, Rage F, Tabet R, Flatter E, Mandel JL and Moine H (2011) G-quadruplex RNA structure as a signal for neurite mRNA targeting. EMBO Rep 12, 697-704.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishiguro A, Kimura N, Watanabe Y, Watanabe S and Ishihama A (2016) TDP-43 binds and transports G-quadruplex-containing mRNAs into neurites for local translation. Genes Cells 21, 466-481.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ivanov P, O'Day E, Emara MM, Wagner G, Lieberman J and Anderson P (2014) G-quadruplex structures contribute to the neuroprotective effects of angiogenin-induced tRNA fragments. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA 111, 18201-18206.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maizels N (2015) G4-associated human diseases. EMBO Rep 16, 910-922.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor JP, Brown RH Jr and Cleveland DW (2016) Decoding ALS: from genes to mechanism. Nature 539, 197-206.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ito D, Hatano M and Suzuki N (2017) RNA binding proteins and the pathological cascade in ALS/FTD neurodegeneration. Sci Transl Med 9, pii: eaah5436.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeJesus-Hernandez M, Mackenzie IR, Boeve BF, Boxer AL, Baker M, Rutherford NJ, Nicholson AM, Finch NA, Flynn H, Adamson J et al. (2011) Expanded GGGGCC hexanucleotide repeat in noncoding region of C9ORF72 causes chromosome 9p-linked FTD and ALS. Neuron 72, 245-256.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng KW, He YD, Liu HH, Li XM, Hao YH and Tan Z (2017) Superhelicity constrains a localized and R-loop-dependent formation of G-quadruplexes at the upstream region of transcription. ACS Chem Biol 12, 2609-2618.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salvi JS and Mekhail K (2015) R-loops highlight the nucleus in ALS. Nucleus 6, 23-29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kapeli K, Martinez FJ and Yeo GW (2017) Genetic mutations in RNA-binding proteins and their roles in ALS. Hum Genet 136, 1193-1214.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao M, Kim JR, van Bruggen R and Park J (2018) RNA-binding proteins in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Mol Cells 41, 818-829.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oyoshi T and Kurokawa R (2012) Structure of noncoding RNA is a determinant of function of RNA binding proteins in transcriptional regulation. Cell Biosci 2, 1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stefanovic S, Bassell GJ and Mihailescu MR (2015) G quadruplex RNA structures in PSD-95 mRNA: potential regulators of miR-125a seed binding site accessibility. RNA 21, 48-60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zamiri B, Reddy K, Macgregor RB Jr and Pearson CE (2013) TMPyP4 porphyrin distorts RNA G-quadruplex structures of the disease-associated r(GGGGCC)n repeat of the C9orf72 gene and blocks interaction of RNA-binding proteins. J Biol Chem 289, 4653-4659.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X and Xu Y (2018) HnRNPA1 specifically recognizes the base of nucleotide at the loop of RNA G-quadruplex. Molecules 23, pii: E237.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scalabrin M, Frasson I, Ruggiero E, Perrone R, Tosoni E, Lago S, Tassinari M, Pal&#xf9; G and Richter SN (2017) The cellular protein hnRNP A2/B1 enhances HIV-1 transcription by unfolding LTR promoter G-quadruplexes. Sci Rep 7, 45244.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mori K, Lammich S, Mackenzie IR, Forn&#xe9; I, Zilow S, Kretzschmar H, Edbauer D, Janssens J, Kleinberger G, Cruts M et al. (2013) hnRNP A3 binds to GGGGCC repeats and is a constituent of p62-positive/TDP43-negative inclusions in the hippocampus of patients with C9orf72 mutations. Acta Neuropathol 125, 413-423.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takahama K, Kino K, Arai S, Kurokawa R and Oyoshi T (2011) Identification of Ewing's sarcoma protein as a G-quadruplex DNA- and RNA-binding protein. FEBS J 278, 988-998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byrd AK, Zybailov BL, Maddukuri L, Gao J, Marecki JC, Jaiswal M, Bell MR, Griffin WC, Reed MR, Chib S et al. (2016) Evidence that G-quadruplex DNA accumulates in the cytoplasm and participates in stress granule assembly in response to oxidative stress. J Biol Chem 291, 18041-18057.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackenzie IR, Bigio EH, Ince PG, Geser F, Neumann M, Cairns NJ, Kwong LK, Forman MS, Ravits J, Stewart H et al. (2007) Pathological TDP-43 distinguishes sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis from amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with SOD1 mutations. Ann Neurol 61, 427-434.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sreedharan J, Blair IP, Tripathi VB, Hu X, Vance C, Rogelj B, Ackerley S, Durnall JC, Williams KL, Buratti E et al. (2008) TDP-43 mutations in familial and sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Science 319, 1668-1672.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pesiridis GS, Lee VM and Trojanowski JQ (2009) Mutations in TDP-43 link glycine-rich domain functions to amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Hum Mol Genet 18, R156-R162.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuo PH, Doudeva LG, Wang YT, Shen CK and Yuan HS (2009) Structural insights into TDP-43 in nucleic-acid binding and domain interactions. Nucleic Acids Res 37, 1799-1808.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shiina Y, Arima K, Tabunoki H and Satoh J (2010) TDP-43 dimerizes in human cells in culture. Cell Mol Neurobiol 30, 641-652.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang IF, Wu LS, Chang HY and Shen CK (2008) TDP-43, the signature protein of FTLD-U, is a neuronal activity-responsive factor. J Neurochem 105, 797-806.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moisse K, Volkening K, Leystra-Lantz C, Welch I, Hill T and Strong MJ (2009) Divergent patterns of cytosolic TDP-43 and neuronal progranulin expression following axotomy: implications for TDP-43 in the physiological response to neuronal injury. Brain Res 1249, 202-211.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tollervey JR, Curk T, Rogelj B, Briese M, Cereda M, Kayikci M, K&#xf6;nig J, Hortob&#xe1;gyi T, Nishimura AL, Zupunski V et al. (2011) Characterizing the RNA targets and position-dependent splicing regulation by TDP-43. Nat Neurosci 14, 452-458.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coyne AN, Zaepfel BL and Zarnescu DC (2017) Failure to deliver and translate-new insights into RNA dysregulation in ALS. Front Cell Neurosci 11, 243.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ravanidis S, Kattan FG and Doxakis E (2018) Unraveling the pathways to neuronal homeostasis and disease: mechanistic insights into the role of RNA-binding proteins and associated factors. Int J Mol Sci 19, E2280.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buratti E, D&#xf6;rk T, Zuccato E, Pagani F, Romano M and Baralle FE (2001) Nuclear factor TDP-43 and SR proteins promote in vitro and in vivo CFTR exon 9 skipping. EMBO J 20, 1774-1784.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polymenidou M, Lagier-Tourenne C, Hutt KR, Huelga SC, Moran J, Liang TY, Ling SC, Sun E, Wancewicz E, Mazur C et al. (2011) Long pre-mRNA depletion and RNA missplicing contribute to neuronal vulnerability from loss of TDP-43. Nat Neurosci 4, 459-468.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sephton CF, Cenik C, Kucukural A, Dammer EB, Cenik B, Han Y, Dewey CM, Roth FP, Herz J, Peng J et al. (2011) Identification of neuronal RNA targets of TDP-43-containing ribonucleoprotein complexes. J Biol Chem 286, 1204-1215.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lukavsky PJ, Daujotyte D, Tollervey JR, Ule J, Stuani C, Buratti E, Baralle FE, Damberger FF and Allain FH (2013) Molecular basis of UG-rich RNA recognition by the human splicing factor TDP-43. Nat Struct Mol Biol 20, 1443-1449.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buratti E (2015) Functional significance of TDP-43 mutations in disease. Adv Genet 91, 1-53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Imperatore JA, McAninch DS, Valdez-Sinon AN, Bassell GJ and Mihailescu MR (2020) FUS recognizes G quadruplex structures within neuronal mRNAs. Front Mol Biosci 7, 6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Q, Yokoshi M, Okada H and Kawahara Y (2015) The cleavage pattern of TDP-43 determines its rate of clearance and cytotoxicity. Nat Commun 6, 6183.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ling SC, Albuquerque CP, Han JS, Lagier-Tourenne C, Tokunaga S, Zhou H and Cleveland DW (2010) ALS-associated mutations in TDP-43 increase its stability and promote TDP-43 complexes with FUS/TLS. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA 107, 13318-13323.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barmada SJ, Skibinski G, Korb E, Rao EJ, Wu JY and Finkbeiner S (2010) Cytoplasmic mislocalization of TDP-43 is toxic to neurons and enhanced by a mutation associated with familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurosci 30, 639-649.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watanabe S, Kaneko K and Yamanaka K (2013) Accelerated disease onset with stabilized familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS)-linked mutant TDP-43 proteins. J Biol Chem 288, 3641-3654.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voigt A, Herholz D, Fiesel FC, Kaur K, M&#xfc;ller D, Karsten P, Weber SS, Kahle PJ, Marquardt T and Schulz JB (2010) TDP-43-mediated neuron loss in vivo requires RNA-binding activity. PLoS ONE 5, e12247.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finelli MJ, Liu KX, Wu Y, Oliver PL and Davies KE (2015) Oxr1 improves pathogenic cellular features of ALS-associated FUS and TDP-43 mutations. Hum Mol Genet 24, 3529-3544.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jung H, Yoon BC and Holt CE (2012) Axonal mRNA localization and local protein synthesis in nervous system assembly, maintenance and repair. Nat Rev Neurosci 13, 308-324.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holt CE and Schuman EM (2013) The central dogma decentralized: new perspectives on RNA function and local translation in neurons. Neuron 80, 648-657.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jovi&#x10d;i&#x107; A, Paul JW III and Gitler AD (2016) Nuclear transport dysfunction: a common theme in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal dementia. J Neurochem 138, 134-144.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loureiro JR, Oliveira CL and Silveira I (2016) Unstable repeat expansions in neurodegenerative diseases: nucleocytoplasmic transport emerges on the scene. Neurobiol Aging 39, 174-183.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim HJ and Taylor JP (2017) Lost in transportation: nucleocytoplasmic transport defects in ALS and other neurodegenerative diseases. Neuron 96, 285-297.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x160;talekar M, Yin X, Rebolj K, Darovic S, Troakes C, Mayr M, Shaw CE and Rogelj B (2015) Proteomic analyses reveal that loss of TDP-43 affects RNA processing and intracellular transport. Neuroscience 293, 157-170.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fallini C, Bassell GJ and Rossoll W (2012) The ALS disease protein TDP-43 is actively transported in motor neuron axons and regulates axon outgrowth. Hum Mol Genet 21, 3703-3718.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mageon A, Junqueira RM and Sachetto-Martins S (2010) Functional diversity of the plant glycine-rich proteins superfamily. Plant Signal Behav 5, 99-104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim JS, Park SJ, Kwak KJ, Kim YO, Kim JY and Song J (2007) Cold shock domain proteins and glycine-rich RNA-binding proteins from Arabidopsis thaliana can promote the cold adaptation process in Escherichia coli. Nucleic Acids Res 35, 506-516.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakaminami K, Karlson DT and Imai R (2006) Functional conservation of cold shock domains in bacteria and higher plants. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA 103, 10122-110127.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>