<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">32343854</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>21</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1460-9568</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>52</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The European journal of neuroscience</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Neurosci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Cytoplasmic localization of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-related TDP-43 proteins modulates stress granule formation.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>3995</StartPage><EndPage>4008</EndPage><MedlinePgn>3995-4008</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/ejn.14762</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>TDP-43 is an RNA/DNA-binding protein associated with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). Under pathological conditions, TDP-43 exported from the nucleus accumulates in the cytoplasm, forming inclusion bodies. However, the molecular mechanisms that contribute to such aggregation are unclear. The pathogenic processes that lead to aggregation in ALS were investigated by analysing the effects of wildtype human TDP-43 or with mutations in the nuclear localization sequence (NLS) or those associated with ALS in stress granule formation. TDP-43 (WT, &#x2206;NLS or G348C), with or without a GFP-tag, was expressed in SH-SY5Y neuroblastoma or HeLa cells and stress granules induced by oxidative stress or heat shock. Stress granule formation was altered in cells strongly expressing GFP-TDP-&#x2206;NLS, or untagged TDP-43-&#x2206;NLS in the cytoplasm but not the negative controls, GFP or GFP-UtrCH. In contrast, there was no reduction in stress granule formation by cells that expressed untagged TDP-43 (WT or G348C) in the nucleus upon stress induction. GFP labelling of TDP-43 (WT or G348C) promotes high cytoplasmic expression and nuclear aggregation. Stress granule formation was impaired in cells expressing GFP-TDP-43 (WT or G348C) in the cytoplasm. Overall, these results suggest that stress granule formation may be inhibited by high levels of TDP-43 protein in the cytoplasm. As stress granules serve a protective function, their deregulation may promote neurodegeneration due to an aberrant stress response.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020 Federation of European Neuroscience Societies and John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Besnard-Gu&#xe9;rin</LastName><ForeName>Corinne</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5468-1337</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sorbonne Universit&#xe9;, Universit&#xe9; Pierre et Marie Curie (UPMC), Universit&#xe9; de Paris 06, Unit&#xe9; Mixte 75, Institut National de la Sant&#xe9; et de la Recherche M&#xe9;dicale (INSERM) Unit&#xe9; 1127, Centre National de la Recherche Scientifique (CNRS), Unit&#xe9; Mixte de Recherche 7225, Institut du Cerveau et de la Moelle &#xc9;pini&#xe8;re (ICM), Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>France</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Neurosci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8918110</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0953-816X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D004268">DNA-Binding Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C000598624">TARDBP protein, human</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002467" MajorTopicYN="N">Cell Nucleus</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003593" MajorTopicYN="N">Cytoplasm</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004268" MajorTopicYN="N">DNA-Binding Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006367" MajorTopicYN="N">HeLa Cells</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">TAR DNA-binding protein (TARDBP) neurodegenerative diseases</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">heat shock</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sodium arsenite</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32343854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ejn.14762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Afroz, T., Hock, E. M., Ernst, P., Foglieni, C., Jambeau, M., Gilhespy, L. A. B., &#x2026; Polymenidou, M. (2017). Functional and dynamic polymerization of the ALS-linked protein TDP-43 antagonizes its pathologic aggregation. Nature Communications, 8, 1-14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson, E. N., Gochenaur, L., Singh, A., Grant, R., Patel, K., Watkins, S., &#x2026; Pandey, U. B. (2018). Traumatic injury induces stress granule formation and enhances motor dysfunctions in ALS/FTD models. Human Molecular Genetics, 27, 1366-1381.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arai, T., Hasegawa, M., Akiyama, H., Ikeda, K., Nonaka, T., Mori, H., &#x2026; Oda, T. (2006). TDP-43 is a component of ubiquitin-positive tau-negative inclusions in frontotemporal lobar degeneration and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Biochemical and Biophysical Research Communications, 351, 602-611.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aulas, A., &amp; Vande Velde, C. (2015). Alterations in stress granule dynamics driven by TDP-43 and FUS: A link to pathological inclusions in ALS?Frontiers in Cellular Neuroscience, 9, 423.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayala, Y. M., Zago, P., D&#x2019;Ambrogio, A., Xu, Y.-F., Petrucelli, L., Buratti, E., &amp; Baralle, F. E. (2008). Structural determinants of the cellular localization and shuttling of TDP-43. Journal of Cell Science, 121, 3778-3785.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barmada, S. J., Skibinski, G., Korb, E., Rao, E. J., Wu, J. Y., &amp; Finkbeiner, S. (2010). Cytoplasmic mislocalization of TDP-43 is toxic to neurons and enhanced by a mutation associated with familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Journal of Neuroscience, 30, 639-649. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.4988-09.2010</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bentmann, E., Haass, C., &amp; Dormann, D. (2013). Stress granules in neurodegeneration - Lessons learnt from TAR DNA binding protein of 43 kDa and fused in sarcoma. FEBS Journal, 280, 4348-4370.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bentmann, E., Neumann, M., Tahirovic, S., Rodde, R., Dormann, D., &amp; Haass, C. (2012). Requirements for stress granule recruitment of fused in sarcoma (FUS) and TAR DNA-binding protein of 43 kDa (TDP-43). Journal of Biological Chemistry, 287, 23079-23094. https://doi.org/10.1074/jbc.M111.328757</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blokhuis, A. M., Groen, E. J. N., Koppers, M., van denBerg, L. H., &amp; Pasterkamp, R. J. (2013). Protein aggregation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathologica, 125, 777-794.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burkel, B. M., vonDassow, G., &amp; Bement, W. M. (2007). Versatile fluorescent probes for actin filaments based on the actin-binding domain of utrophin brian. Cell Motility and the Cytoskeleton, 64, 822-832.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cascella, R., Capitini, C., Fani, G., Dobson, C. M., Cecchi, C., &amp; Chiti, F. (2016). Quantification of the relative contributions of loss-offunction and gain-of-function mechanisms in TAR DNA-binding protein 43 (TDP-43) proteinopathies. Journal of Biological Chemistry, 291, 19437-19448.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen-plotkin, A. S., Lee, V. M., &amp; Trojanowski, J. Q. (2010). TAR DNA-binding protein 43 in neurodegenerative disease. Nature Reviews Neurology, 6, 211-220.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colombrita, C., Zennaro, E., Fallini, C., Weber, M., Sommacal, A., Buratti, E., &#x2026; Ratti, A. (2009). TDP-43 is recruited to stress granules in conditions of oxidative insult. Journal of Neurochemistry, 111, 1051-1061.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dayton, R. D., Gitcho, M. A., Orchard, E. A., Wilson, J. D., Wang, D. B., Cain, C. D., &#x2026; Klein, R. L. (2013). Selective forelimb impairment in rats expressing a pathological TDP-43 25 kDa C-terminal fragment to mimic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Molecular Therapy, 21, 1324-1334. https://doi.org/10.1038/mt.2013.88</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dewey, C. M., Cenik, B., Sephton, C. F., Dries, D. R., Mayer, P., Good, S. K., &#x2026; Yu, G. (2011). TDP-43 is directed to stress granules by sorbitol, a novel physiological osmotic and oxidative stressor. Molecular and Cellular Biology, 31, 1098-1108.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dormann, D., &amp; Haass, C. (2011). TDP-43 and FUS: A nuclear affair. Trends in Neurosciences, 34, 339-348.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gasset-Rosa, F., Lu, S., Yu, H., Chen, C., Melamed, Z., Guo, L., &#x2026; Cleveland, D. W. (2019). Cytoplasmic TDP-43 de-mixing independent of stress granules drives inhibition of nuclear import, loss of nuclear TDP-43, and cell death. Neuron, 102, 339-357.e7. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2019.02.038</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gitcho, M. A., Baloh, R. H., Chakraverty, S., Norton, J. B., Levitch, D., Hatanpaa, K. J., &#x2026; Cairns, N. J. (2008). TDP-43 A315T mutation in familial motor neuron disease. Annals of Neurology, 63, 535-538.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon, D., Dafinca, R., Scaber, J., Alegre-Abarrategui, J., Farrimond, L., Scott, C., &#x2026; Talbot, K. (2019). Single-copy expression of an amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-linked TDP-43 mutation (M337V) in BAC transgenic mice leads to altered stress granule dynamics and progressive motor dysfunction. Neurobiology of Diseases, 121, 148-162. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nbd.2018.09.024</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grant, C., &amp; Mitchell, C. S. (2015). An assessment of possible neuropathology and clinical relationships in 46 sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patient autopsies. Neuro-Degenerative Diseases, 15, 301-312.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hua, Y., &amp; Zhou, J. (2004). Survival motor neuron protein facilitates assembly of stress granules. FEBS Letters, 572, 69-74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Igaz, L. M., Kwong, L. K., Lee, E. B., Chen-plotkin, A., Swanson, E., Unger, T., &#x2026; Lee, V. M. (2011). Dysregulation of the ALS-associated gene TDP-43 leads to neuronal death and degeneration in mice. Journal of Clinical Investigation, 121, 726-738.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kabashi, E., Bercier, V., Lissouba, A., Liao, M., Brustein, E., Rouleau, G. A., &amp; Drapeau, P. (2011). Fus and tardbp but not sod1 interact in genetic models of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. PLoS Genetics, 7, 17-28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kabashi, E., Lin, L., Tradewell, M. L., Dion, P. A., Bercier, V., Bourgouin, P., &#x2026; Drapeau, P. (2010). Gain and loss of function of ALS-related mutations of TARDBP (TDP-43) cause motor deficits in vivo. Human Molecular Genetics, 19, 671-683.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kabashi, E., Valdmanis, P. N., Dion, P., Spiegelman, D., Mcconkey, B. J., Velde, C. V., &#x2026; Rouleau, G. A. (2008). TARDBP mutations in individuals with sporadic and familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nature Genetics, 40, 572-575.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kedersha, N., Ivanov, P., &amp; Anderson, P. (2013). Stress granules and cell signaling: More than just a passing phase?. Trends in Biochemical Sciences, 38(10), 496-506.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer, B. C., &amp; Wheeler, J. M. (2010). Loss of murine TDP-43 disrupts motor function and plays an essential role in embryogenesis Brian. Acta Neuropathologica, 119, 409-419.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lagier-Tourenne, C., Polymenidou, M., &amp; Cleveland, D. W. (2010). TDP-43 and FUS/TLS: Emerging roles in RNA processing and neurodegeneration. Human Molecular Genetics, 19, 46-64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Y. R., King, O. D., Shorter, J., &amp; Gitler, A. D. (2013). Stress granules as crucibles of ALS pathogenesis. Journal of Cell Biology, 201, 361-372.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu-Yesucevitz, L., Bilgutay, A., Zhang, Y. J., Vanderwyde, T., Citro, A., Mehta, T., &#x2026; Wolozin, B. (2010). Tar DNA binding protein-43 (TDP-43) associates with stress granules: Analysis of cultured cells and pathological brain tissue. PLoS ONE, 5, 1-15. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0013250</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDonald, K. K., Aulas, A., Destroismaisons, L., Pickles, S., Beleac, E., Camu, W., &#x2026; Velde, C. V. (2011). TAR DNA-binding protein 43 (TDP-43) regulates stress granule dynamics via differential regulation of G3BP and TIA-1. Human Molecular Genetics, 20, 1400-1410.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitsuzawa, S., Akiyama, T., Nishiyama, A., Suzuki, N., Kato, M., Warita, H., &#x2026; Aoki, M. (2018). TARDBP p. G376D mutation, found in rapid progressive familial ALS, induces mislocalization of TDP-43. eNeurologicalSci, 11, 20-22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Navone, F., Genevini, P., &amp; Borgese, N. (2015). Autophagy and neurodegeneration: Insights from a cultured cell model of ALS. Cells, 4, 354-386. https://doi.org/10.3390/cells4030354</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neumann, M., Sampathu, D. M., Kwong, L. K., Truax, A. C., Micsenyi, M. C., Chou, T. T., &#x2026; Lee, V.- M.-Y. (2006). Ubiquitinated TDP-43 in frontotemporal lobar degeneration and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Science, 314, 130-133.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nonaka, T., Kametani, F., Arai, T., Akiyama, H., &amp; Hasegawa, M. (2009). Truncation and pathogenic mutations facilitate the formation of intracellular aggregates of TDP-43. Human Molecular Genetics, 18, 3353-3364.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orr&#xf9;, S., Coni, P., Floris, A., Littera, R., Carcassi, C., Sogos, V., &amp; Brancia, C. (2016). Reduced stress granule formation and cell death in fibroblasts with the A382T mutation of TARDBP gene: Evidence for loss of TDP-43 nuclear function. Human Molecular Genetics, 25, ddw276. https://doi.org/10.1093/hmg/ddw276</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin, H., Lim, L., Wei, Y., &amp; Song, J. (2014). TDP-43 N terminus encodes a novel ubiquitin-like fold and its unfolded form in equilibrium that can be shifted by binding to ssDNA. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 111, 18619-18624.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rutherford, N. J., Zhang, Y., Baker, M., Gass, J. M., Finch, N. A., Xu, Y., &#x2026; Rademakers, R. (2008). Novel mutations in TARDBP (TDP-43) in patients with familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. PLoS Genetics, 4, 1-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sasaguri, H., Chew, J., Xu, Y.-F., Gendron, T. F., Garrett, A., Lee, C. W., &#x2026; Zhang, Y.-J. (2016). The extreme N-terminus of TDP-43 mediates the cytoplasmic aggregation of TDP-43 and associated toxicity in vivo. Brain Research, 1647, 57-64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sephton, C. F., Good, S. K., Atkin, S., Dewey, C. M., Mayer, P., Herz, J., &amp; Yu, G. (2010). TDP-43 is a developmentally regulated protein essential for early embryonic development. Journal of Biological Chemistry, 285, 6826-6834.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seyfried, N. T., Gozal, Y. M., Dammer, E. B., Xia, Q., Duong, D. M., Cheng, D., &#x2026; Peng, J. (2010). Multiplex SILAC analysis of a cellular TDP-43 proteinopathy model reveals protein inclusions associated with SUMOylation and diverse polyubiquitin chains. Molecular &amp; Cellular Proteomics: MCP, 9, 705-718.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spector, D. L. (2001). Nuclear domains. Journal of Cell Science, 114, 2891-2893.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sreedharan, J., Blair, I. P., Tripathi, V. B., Hu, X., Vance, C., Rogelj, B., &#x2026; Shaw, C. (2008). TDP-43 mutations in familial and sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Science, 319, 1668-1672.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun, Z., Diaz, Z., Fang, X., Hart, M. P., Chesi, A., Shorter, J., &amp; Gitler, A. D. (2011). Molecular determinants and genetic modifiers of aggregation and toxicity for the als disease protein fus/tls. PLoS Biology, 9, 1-25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Udan-Johns, M., Bengoechea, R., Bell, S., Shao, J., Diamond, M. I., True, H. L., &#x2026; Baloh, R. H. (2014). Prion-like nuclear aggregation of TDP-43 during heat shock is regulated by HSP40/70 chaperones. Human Molecular Genetics, 23, 157-170.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Deerlin, V. M., Leverenz, J. B., Bekris, L. M., Bird, T. D., Yuan, W., Elman, L. B., &#x2026; Yu, C.-E. (2008). TARDBP mutations in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with TDP-43 neuropathology: A genetic and histopathological analysis. The Lancet Neurology, 7, 409-416. https://doi.org/10.1016/S1474-4422(08)70071-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wegorzewska, I., Bell, S., Cairns, N. J., Miller, T. M., &amp; Baloh, R. H. (2009). TDP-43 mutant transgenic mice develop features of ALS and frontotemporal lobar degeneration. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 106, 18809-18814.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wils, H., Kleinberger, G., Janssens, J., Pereson, S., Joris, G., Cuijt, I., &#x2026; Kumar-Singh, S. (2010). TDP-43 transgenic mice develop spastic paralysis and neuronal inclusions characteristic of ALS and frontotemporal lobar degeneration. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 107, 3858-3863.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winton, M. J., Igaz, L. M., Wong, M. M., Kwong, L. K., Trojanowski, J. Q., &amp; Lee, V. M. Y. (2008). Disturbance of nuclear and cytoplasmic TAR DNA-binding protein (TDP-43) induces disease-like redistribution, sequestration, and aggregate formation. Journal of Biological Chemistry, 283, 13302-13309. https://doi.org/10.1074/jbc.M800342200</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wobst, H. J., Wesolowski, S. S., Chadchankar, J., Delsing, L., Jacobsen, S., Mukherjee, J., &#x2026; Moss, S. J. (2017). Cytoplasmic relocalization of TAR DNA-binding protein 43 is not sufficient to reproduce cellular pathologies associated with ALS in vitro. Frontiers in Molecular Neuroscience, 10, 1-13. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnmol.2017.00046</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolozin, B. (2012). Regulated protein aggregation: Stress granules and neurodegeneration. Molecular Neurodegeneration, 7, 1-12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, L.-S.-S., Cheng, W.-C.-C., Hou, S.-C.-C., Yan, Y.-T.-T., Jiang, S.-T.-T., &amp; Shen, C. K. J. (2010). TDP-43, a neuro-pathosignature factor, is essential for early mouse embryogenesis. Genesis, 48, 56-62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, Y.-F., Gendron, T. F., Zhang, Y.-J., Lin, W.-L., D'Alton, S., Sheng, H., &#x2026; Petrucelli, L. (2010). Wild-type human TDP-43 expression causes TDP-43 phosphorylation, mitochondrial aggregation, motor deficits and early mortality in transgenic mice. Journal of Neuroscience, 30, 10851-10859. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.1630-10.2010</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, C., Tan, W., Whittle, C., Qiu, L., Cao, L., Akbarian, S., &amp; Xu, Z. (2010). The C-terminal TDP-43 fragments have a high aggregation propensity and harm neurons by a dominant-negative mechanism. PLoS ONE, 5, 1-15. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0015878</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Y. J., Caulfield, T., Xu, Y. F., Gendron, T. F., Hubbard, J., Stetler, C., &#x2026; Petrucelli, L. (2013). The dual functions of the extreme N-terminus of TDP-43 in regulating its biological activity and inclusion formation. Human Molecular Genetics, 22, 3112-3122.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Y.-J., Xu, Y.-F., Cook, C., Gendron, T. F., Roettges, P., Link, C. D., &#x2026; Petrucelli, L. (2009). Aberrant cleavage of TDP-43 enhances aggregation and cellular toxicity. PNAS, 106, 7607-7612. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.0900688106</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>