<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">32347416</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1432-0460</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>36</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Dysphagia</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Dysphagia</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Biomechanical Biomarkers of Tongue Impairment During Swallowing in Persons Diagnosed with Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>147</StartPage><EndPage>156</EndPage><MedlinePgn>147-156</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s00455-020-10116-z</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">The impact of tongue dysfunction on deglutition in persons diagnosed with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) is not well understood. This information is needed to improve our understanding of the mechanisms of swallowing impairment, for identifying risk factors of dysphagia, and for establishing impairment-specific treatments aimed at slowing the loss of swallow function.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES">The goals of this study were to determine the relation between biomechanical measures of oral tongue movements using electromagnetic articulography (EMA) and measures of swallow physiology, swallow safety and efficiency, and self-reported swallowing function.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Participants were diagnosed with ALS by a neurologist following the El Escorial Criteria from the World Federation of Neurology. Twelve participants underwent (1) EMA to derive biomechanical measures of the tongue, (2) videofluoroscopic evaluation to measure swallow physiology, safety, and efficiency, and (3) maximal tongue strength testing using the Iowa Oral Pressure Instrument (IOPI). Participants completed self-reported functional assessments. Spearman's rank correlations assessed for associations between lingual biomechanics and swallowing physiology, swallow safety and efficiency, and self-reported bulbar function.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Results demonstrated strong associations between biomechanical and swallowing physiology, swallow safety, and self-reported measures. Notably, swallowing safety during thin liquid intake was associated with tongue speed (r&#x2009;=&#x2009;-&#x2009;0.7, p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05) and range of motion (r&#x2009;=&#x2009;-&#x2009;0.71, p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05), and swallowing safety during puree intake was associated with tongue strength (r&#x2009;=&#x2009;-&#x2009;0.69, p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Our findings underscore the importance of tongue movements on swallowing physiology and safety, help improve our understanding of mechanisms of swallowing impairment, and highlight a potential clinical tool to index bulbar impairment.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Perry</LastName><ForeName>Bridget J</ForeName><Initials>BJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4219-2552</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Tufts University Medical Center, 35 Kneeland Street, Boston, MA, 02111, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stipancic</LastName><ForeName>Kaila L</ForeName><Initials>KL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MGH Institute of Health Professions, 79/96 13th Street, Charlestown, MA, 02129, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Martino</LastName><ForeName>Rosemary</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Speech-Language Pathology, University of Toronto, Toronto, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Otolaryngology-Head and Neck Surgery, Rehabilitation Sciences Institute, University of Toronto, Toronto, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Krembil Research Institute, University Health Network, 160-500 University Ave., Toronto, ON, M5G 1V7, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Plowman</LastName><ForeName>Emily K</ForeName><Initials>EK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Aerodigestive Research Core, University of Florida, Gainesville, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Speech-Language Hearing Sciences and Neurology, University of Florida, Gainesville, FL, 32610, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Green</LastName><ForeName>Jordan R</ForeName><Initials>JR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Communication Sciences &amp; Disorders, MGH Institute of Health Professions, 79/96 13th Street, Charlestown, MA, 02129, USA. jgreen2@mghihp.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Speech &amp; Hearing Bioscience and Technology Program, Harvard Medical School, 79/96 13th Street, Charlestown, MA, 02129, USA. jgreen2@mghihp.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>TL1 TR002546</GrantID><Acronym>TR</Acronym><Agency>NCATS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R21 DC016664</GrantID><Acronym>DC</Acronym><Agency>NIDCD NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>K24 DC016312</GrantID><Acronym>DC</Acronym><Agency>NIDCD NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>F31 DC015941</GrantID><Acronym>DC</Acronym><Agency>NIDCD NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Dysphagia</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8610856</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0179-051X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D015415">Biomarkers</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015415" MajorTopicYN="N">Biomarkers</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002933" MajorTopicYN="N">Cineradiography</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003679" MajorTopicYN="N">Deglutition</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003680" MajorTopicYN="Y">Deglutition Disorders</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014059" MajorTopicYN="N">Tongue</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Deglutition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Deglutition disorders</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dysphagia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Electromagnetic articulography</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Kinematics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Lingual impairment</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict of Interest: The authors declare that they have no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32347416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS1588778</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8220556</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00455-020-10116-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s00455-020-10116-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ruoppolo G, Schettino I, Frasca V, Giacomelli E, Prosperini L, Cambieri C, et al. Dysphagia in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Prevalence and clinical findings. Acta Neurol Scand. Wiley/Blackwell (10.1111); 2013;128:397&#x2013;401.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23668293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desport JC, Preux PM, Truong TC, Vallat JM, Sautereau D, Couratier P. Nutritional status is a prognostic factor for survival in ALS patients. Neurology. American Academy of Neurology; 1999;53:1059&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10496266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langmore SE, Lehman ME. Physiologic Deficits in the Orofacial System Underlying Dysarthria in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. J Speech Lang Hear Res. American Speech-Language-Hearing Association; 1994;37:28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8170127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Logemann JA. Critical Factors in the Oral Control Needed for Chewing and Swallowing. J Texture Stud. 2014;45:173&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4224116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25386030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark HM, Henson PA, Barber WD, Stierwalt JAG, Sherrill M. Relationships Among Subjective and Objective Measures of Tongue Strength and Oral Phase Swallowing Impairments. Am J Speech-Language Pathol. American Speech-Language-Hearing Association; 2003; 12:40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12680812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinovitch SN, Hershler C, Romilly DP. A tongue force measurement system for the assessment of oral-phase swallowing disorders. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 1991;72:38&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1985622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stierwalt JAG, Youmans SR. Tongue Measures in Individuals With Normal and Impaired Swallowing. Am J Speech-Language Pathol. American Speech-Language-Hearing Association; 2007; 16:148.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17456893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshida M, Kikutani T, Tsuga K, Utanohara Y, Hayashi R, Akagawa Y. Decreased Tongue Pressure Reflects Symptom of Dysphagia. Dysphagia. Springer-Verlag; 2006;21:61&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16544085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butler SG, Stuart A, Leng X, Wilhelm E, Rees C, Williamson J, et al. The Relationship of Aspiration Status With Tongue and Handgrip Strength in Healthy Older Adults. Journals Gerontol Ser A Biol Sci Med Sci. Oxford University Press; 2011;66A:452&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3107020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21300744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim HD, Choi JB, Yoo SJ, Chang MY, Lee SW, Park JS. Tongue-to-palate resistance training improves tongue strength and oropharyngeal swallowing function in subacute stroke survivors with dysphagia. J Oral Rehabil. Wiley/Blackwell (10.1111); 2017;44:59&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27883209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lazarus CL, Husaini H, Falciglia D, DeLacure M, Branski RC, Kraus D, et al. Effects of exercise on swallowing and tongue strength in patients with oral and oropharyngeal cancer treated with primary radiotherapy with or without chemotherapy. Int J Oral Maxillofac Surg. Elsevier; 2014;43:523&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24332586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robbins J, Kays SA, Gangnon RE, Hind JA, Hewitt AL, Gentry LR, et al. The effects of lingual exercise in stroke patients with dysphagia. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2007;88:150&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17270511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeates EM, Molfenter SM, Steele CM. Improvements in tongue strength and pressure-generation precision following a tongue-pressure training protocol in older individuals with dysphagia: three case reports. Clin Interv Aging. Dove Press; 2008:3:735&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2682406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19281066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Athukorala RP, Jones RD, Sella O, Huckabee M-L. Skill Training for Swallowing Rehabilitation in Patients With Parkinson&#x2019;s Disease. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. W.B. Saunders; 2014;95:1374&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24816250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawai S, Tsukuda M, Mochimatsu I, Enomoto H, Kagesato Y, Hirose H, et al.. A Study of the Early Stage of Dysphagia in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. Dysphagia.Springer-Verlag; 2003;18:1&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12497190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Connell DA, Rieger J, Harris JR, Dziegielewski P, Zalmanowitz J, Sytsanko A, et al. Swallowing Function in Patients With Base of Tongue Cancers Treated With Primary Surgery and Reconstructed With a Modified Radial Forearm Free Flap. Arch Otolaryngol Neck Surg. American Medical Association; 2008;134:857.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18711061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pauloski BR, Logemann JA, Fox JC, Colangelo LA. Biomechanical Analysis of the Pharyngeal Swallow in Postsurgical Patients With Anterior Tongue and Floor of Mouth Resection and Distal Flap Reconstruction. J Speech Lang Hear Res. American Speech-Language-Hearing Association; 1995;38:110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7731203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steele CM, Lieshout PHHM Van. Use of Electromagnetic Midsagittal Articulography in the Study of Swallowing. J Speech, Lang Hear Res @BULLET. 2004;47:342&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15157134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green JR, Wang Y-T. Tongue-surface movement patterns during speech and swallowing. J Acoust Soc Am. Acoustical Society of America; 2003;113:2820.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2754124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12765399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steele CM, Van Lieshout P. Tongue movements during water swallowing in healthy young and older adults. J Speech Lang Hear Res. American Speech-Language-Hearing Association; 2009;52:1255&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19797138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson EM, Green JR. Coordinative organization of lingual propulsion during the normal adult swallow. Dysphagia. 2006;21:226&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2866114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17221289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perry BJ, Martino R, Yunusova Y, Plowman EK, Green JR. Lingual and Jaw Kinematic Abnormalities Precede Speech and Swallowing Impairments in ALS. Dysphagia. 2018;</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6244810</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29774424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, Miller RG, Swash M, Munsat TL. El Escorial revisited: Revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Mot Neuron Disord. Taylor &amp; Francis; 2009;1:293&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11464847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green JR, Wang J, Wilson DL. SMASH: A tool for articulatory data processing and analysis. Interspeech. 2013. p. 1331&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shellikeri S, Green JR, Kulkarni M, Rong P, Martino R, Zinman L, et al. Speech Movement Measures as Markers of Bulbar Disease in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. J Speech Lang Hear Res. John Benjamins, Amsterdam, the Netherlands; 2016;59:887.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5345561</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27679842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>IOPI Medical Inc. Iowa Oral Performance Instrument. Redmond, Wa;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin-Harris B, Brodsky MB, Michel Y, Castell DO, Schleicher M, Sandidge J, et al. MBS Measurement Tool for Swallow Impairment&#x2014;MBSImp: Establishing a Standard. Dysphagia. Springer-Verlag; 2008;23:392&#x2013;405.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4217120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18855050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenbek JC, Robbins JA, Roecker EB, Coyle JL, Wood JL. A penetration-aspiration scale. Dysphagia. 1996;11:93&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8721066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum JM, Stambler N, Malta E, Fuller C, Hilt D, Thurmond B, et al. The ALSFRS-R: a revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. BDNF ALS Study Group (Phase III). J Neurol Sci. 1999;169:13&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10540002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belafsky PC, Mouadeb DA, Rees CJ, Pryor JC, Postma GN, Allen J, et al. Validity and reliability of the Eating Assessment Tool (EAT-10). Ann Otol Rhinol Laryngol. 2008;117:919&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19140539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crary MA, Mann GDC, Groher ME. Initial Psychometric Assessment of a Functional Oral Intake Scale for Dysphagia in Stroke Patients. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. Elsevier; 2005;86:1516&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16084801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>RStudio. RStudio: Integrated development environment for R (Version 1.2.1335). 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yorkston K, Beukelman D, Hakel M. Speech Intelligibility Test (SIT) for Windows. Lincoln, Nebraska, USA: Madonna Rehabilitation Hospital; 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuhnlein P, Kubler A, Raubold S, Worrell M, Kurt A, Gdynia H-J, et al. Palliative care and circumstances of dying in German ALS patients using non-invasive ventilation. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2008;9:91&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18428001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murono S, Hamaguchi T, Yoshida H, Nakanishi Y, Tsuji A, Endo K, et al. Evaluation of dysphagia at the initial diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Auris Nasus Larynx. 2015;42:213&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25466359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solazzo A, Monaco L, Vecchio L Del, Reginelli A, Iacobellis F, Capasso R, et al. Earliest Videofluoromanometric Pharyngeal Signs of Dysphagia in ALS Patients. Dysphagia. Springer US; 2014;29:539&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25142240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuruvilla MS, Green JR, Yunusova Y, Hanford K. Spatiotemporal coupling of the tongue in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Speech Lang Hear Res. American Speech-Language-Hearing Association; 2012;55:1897&#x2013;909.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4607050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22615476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yunusova Y, Weismer G, Westbury JR, Lindstrom MJ. Articulatory Movements During Vowels in Speakers With Dysarthria and Healthy Controls. J Speech Lang Hear Res. 2008;51:596.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18506038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Logemann JA. Evaluation and treatment of swallowing disorders. PRO-ED; 1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han H, Shin G, Jun A, Park T, Ko D, Choi E, et al. The Relation Between the Presence of Aspiration or Penetration and the Clinical Indicators of Dysphagia in Poststroke Survivors. Ann Rehabil Med. 2016;40:88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4775763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26949674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin-Harris B, Brodsky MB, Michel Y, Lee F-S, Walters B. Delayed Initiation of the Pharyngeal Swallow: Normal Variability in Adult Swallows. J Speech Lang Hear Res. American Speech-Language-Hearing Association; 2007;50:585.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17538102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steele CM, Cichero JAY. Physiological factors related to aspiration risk: a systematic review. Dysphagia. Springer; 2014;29:295&#x2013;304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4062811</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24562507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goeleven A, Robberecht W, Sonies B, Carbonez A, Dejaeger E. Manofluorographic evaluation of swallowing in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and its relationship with clinical evaluation of swallowing. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2006;7:241&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17127562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kidney D, Alexander M, Corr B, O&#x2019;Toole O, Hardiman O. Oropharyngeal dysphagia in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: neurological and dysphagia specific rating scales. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Mot Neuron Disord. 2004;5:150&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15512903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plowman EK, Tabor LC, Robison R, Gaziano J, Dion C, Watts SA, et al. Discriminant ability of the Eating Assessment Tool-10 to detect aspiration in individuals with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurogastroenterol Motil. 2016;28:85&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4688134</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26510823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jordan Hazelwood R, Armeson KE, Hill EG, Bonilha HS, Martin-Harris B. Identification of Swallowing Tasks From a Modified Barium Swallow Study That Optimize the Detection of Physiological Impairment. J Speech Lang Hear Res. 2017;60:1855.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5831085</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28614846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plowman EK, Tabor LC, Wymer J, Pattee G. The evaluation of bulbar dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: survey of clinical practice patterns in the United States. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Front Degener. Taylor &amp; Francis; 2017;18:351&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7001984</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28425762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>