<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">32346913</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>25</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1468-1331</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>27</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Plateaus in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis progression: results from a population-based cohort.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1397</StartPage><EndPage>1404</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1397-1404</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/ene.14287</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND PURPOSE">The aim was to assess the frequency of plateaus in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) progression using a large population-based cohort.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Data from the Piemonte and Valle d'Aosta ALS register were used. Patients who were diagnosed between 2007 and 2014 were considered. The follow-up period was extended until 31 December 2018. Visits after tracheostomy were excluded. A plateau was defined as a stable Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Functional Rating Scale revised (ALSFRSr) score lasting at least 6, 12 or 18&#xa0;months.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Out of 1214 patients, 200 (16.5%), 93 (7.7%) and 52 (4.3%) showed at least one plateau lasting a minimum of 6, 12 and 18&#xa0;months, respectively. Plateaus occurred mostly at high ALSFRSr scores and were more frequent during the initial phases of the disease course. Spinal onset [odds ratio (OR) 1.83, 95% confidence interval (CI) 1.16-2.95, P value 0.01) and predominant upper motor neuron phenotype (OR 2.18, 95% CI 1.36-3.48, P value 0.001) conferred a higher risk for the subsequent appearance of plateaus; conversely, older age at diagnosis (OR 0.25, 95% CI 0.11-0.54, P value 0.002 for &gt;75 year age class) reduced this risk.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Plateaus in ALS progression lasting at least 6&#xa0;months appear in about one out of six patients and could last even 12, 18&#xa0;months or more in a smaller subgroup of patients. Plateau occurrence should not lead the neurologist to automatically reconsider ALS diagnosis and should be considered for future clinical trial design.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020 European Academy of Neurology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vasta</LastName><ForeName>R</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0393-4736</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>'Rita Levi Montalcini' Department of Neuroscience, ALS Center, University of Turin, Turin, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>D'Ovidio</LastName><ForeName>F</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6304-5415</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>'Rita Levi Montalcini' Department of Neuroscience, ALS Center, University of Turin, Turin, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Canosa</LastName><ForeName>A</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5876-4079</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>'Rita Levi Montalcini' Department of Neuroscience, ALS Center, University of Turin, Turin, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Manera</LastName><ForeName>U</ForeName><Initials>U</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>'Rita Levi Montalcini' Department of Neuroscience, ALS Center, University of Turin, Turin, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Torrieri</LastName><ForeName>M C</ForeName><Initials>MC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>'Rita Levi Montalcini' Department of Neuroscience, ALS Center, University of Turin, Turin, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Grassano</LastName><ForeName>M</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>'Rita Levi Montalcini' Department of Neuroscience, ALS Center, University of Turin, Turin, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>De Marchi</LastName><ForeName>F</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, ALS Center, Azienda Ospedaliero Universitaria Maggiore della Carit&#xe0;, Novara, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mazzini</LastName><ForeName>L</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, ALS Center, Azienda Ospedaliero Universitaria Maggiore della Carit&#xe0;, Novara, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moglia</LastName><ForeName>C</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>'Rita Levi Montalcini' Department of Neuroscience, ALS Center, University of Turin, Turin, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurology 1, Azienda Ospedaliero Universitaria Citt&#xe0; della Salute e della Scienza, Turin, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Calvo</LastName><ForeName>A</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>'Rita Levi Montalcini' Department of Neuroscience, ALS Center, University of Turin, Turin, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurology 1, Azienda Ospedaliero Universitaria Citt&#xe0; della Salute e della Scienza, Turin, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chi&#xf2;</LastName><ForeName>A</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>'Rita Levi Montalcini' Department of Neuroscience, ALS Center, University of Turin, Turin, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurology 1, Azienda Ospedaliero Universitaria Citt&#xe0; della Salute e della Scienza, Turin, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9506311</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1351-5101</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000601" MajorTopicYN="N">surgery</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015331" MajorTopicYN="N">Cohort Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018450" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Progression</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014139" MajorTopicYN="N">Tracheostomy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cohort studies</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">motor neuron diseases</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">progression analysis</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32346913</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ene.14287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Kiernan MC, Vucic S, Cheah BC, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet 2011; 377: 942-955.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, Miller RG, Swash M, Munsat TL. World Federation of Neurology Research Group on motor neuron diseases. El Escorial revisited: revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord 2000; 1: 293-299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Chalabi A, Hardiman O, Kiernan MC, Chi&#xf2; A, Rix-Brooks B, van den Berg LH. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: moving towards a new classification system. Lancet Neurol 2016; 15: 1182-1194.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atassi N, Berry J, Shui A, et al. The PRO-ACT database: design, initial analyses, and predictive features. Neurology 2014; 83: 1719-1725.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bedlack RS, Vaughan T, Wicks P, et al. How common are ALS plateaus and reversals? Neurology 2016; 86: 808-812.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2; A, Canosa A, Gallo S, et al. ALS clinical trials: do enrolled patients accurately represent the ALS population? Neurology 2011; 77: 1432-1437.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2; A, Mora G, Moglia C, et al. Secular trends of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: the Piemonte and Valle d&#x2019;Aosta register. JAMA Neurol 2017; 74: 1097.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2; A, Calvo A, Moglia C, Mazzini L, Mora G, PARALS study group. Phenotypic heterogeneity of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a population based study. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2011; 82: 740-746.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum JM, Stambler N, Malta E, et al. The ALSFRS-R: a revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. BDNF ALS Study Group (Phase III). J Neurol Sci 1999; 169: 13-21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strong MJ, Abrahams S, Goldstein LH, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis - frontotemporal spectrum disorder (ALS-FTSD): revised diagnostic criteria. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Front Degener 2017; 18: 153-174.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandrioli J, Biguzzi S, Guidi C, et al. Heterogeneity in ALSFRS-R decline and survival: a population-based study in Italy. Neurol Sci 2015; 36: 2243-2252.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore DH, Miller RG. Improving efficiency of ALS clinical trials using lead-in designs. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Mot Neuron Disord 2004; 5(Suppl. 1): 57-60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pradas J, Finison L, Andres PL, Thornell B, Hollander D, Munsat TL. The natural history of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and the use of natural history controls in therapeutic trials. Neurology 1993; 43: 751-755.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon PH, Cheng B, Salachas F, et al. Progression in ALS is not linear but is curvilinear. J Neurol 2010; 257: 1713-1717.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poesen K, De Schaepdryver M, Stubendorff B, et al. Neurofilament markers for ALS correlate with extent of upper and lower motor neuron disease. Neurology 2017; 88: 2302-2309.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2; A. Cognitive impairment progression across ALS clinical stages: an evidence of lesions spreading. Neurology 2019; 93: e984-e994.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dandaba M, Couratier P, Labrunie A, et al. Characteristics and prognosis of oldest old subjects with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuroepidemiology 2017; 49: 64-73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2; A, Logroscino G, Hardiman O, et al. Prognostic factors in ALS: a critical review. Amyotroph Lateral Scler 2009; 10: 310-323.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iazzolino B, Pain D, Peotta L, et al. Validation of the revised classification of cognitive and behavioural impairment in ALS. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2019; 90: 734-739.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2; A, Moglia C, Canosa A, et al. ALS phenotype is influenced by age, sex, and genetics: a population-based study. Neurology 2020; 94: e802-e810.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackenzie IRA, Ansorge O, Strong M, et al. Pathological heterogeneity in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with FUS mutations: two distinct patterns correlating with disease severity and mutation. Acta Neuropathol (Berl) 2011; 122: 87-98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hooten KG, Beers DR, Zhao W, Appel SH. Protective and toxic neuroinflammation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurotherapeutics 2015; 12: 364-375.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beers DR, Zhao W, Appel SH. The role of regulatory T lymphocytes in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. JAMA Neurol 2018; 75: 656-658.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rashid Chehreh Bargh S, Tafakhori A, Masoumi F, et al. Evaluation of regulatory T lymphocytes and IL2Ra and FOXP3 gene expression in peripheral mononuclear cells from patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ir J Med Sci 2018; 187: 1065-1071.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schaefer AM, Sanes JR, Lichtman JW. A compensatory subpopulation of motor neurons in a mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Comp Neurol 2005; 490: 209-219.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frey D, Schneider C, Xu L, Borg J, Spooren W, Caroni P. Early and selective loss of neuromuscular synapse subtypes with low sprouting competence in motoneuron diseases. J Neurosci 2000; 20: 2534-2542.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nijssen J, Comley LH, Hedlund E. Motor neuron vulnerability and resistance in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathol (Berl). 2017; 133: 863-885.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dantes M, McComas A. The extent and time course of motoneuron involvement in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve 1991; 14: 416-421.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kent-Braun JA, Walker CH, Weiner MW, Miller RG. Functional significance of upper and lower motor neuron impairment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve 1998; 21: 762-768.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Albuquerque M, Branco LMT, Rezende TJR, de Andrade HMT, Nucci A, Fran&#xe7;a MC. Longitudinal evaluation of cerebral and spinal cord damage in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. NeuroImage Clin 2017; 14: 269-276.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verstraete E, Turner MR, Grosskreutz J, Filippi M, Benatar M, Attendees of the 4th NiSALS Meeting. Mind the gap: the mismatch between clinical and imaging metrics in ALS. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Front Degener 2015; 16: 524-529.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bede P, Hardiman O. Lessons of ALS imaging: pitfalls and future directions - a critical review. NeuroImage Clin 2014; 4: 436-443.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin J, Hu F, Zhang Q, et al. Dominant heterogeneity of upper and lower motor neuron degeneration to motor manifestation of involved region in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Sci Rep 2019; 9: 20059.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franchignoni F, Mora G, Giordano A, Volanti P, Chi&#xf2; A. Evidence of multidimensionality in the ALSFRS-R scale: a critical appraisal on its measurement properties using Rasch analysis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2013; 84: 1340-1345.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>