<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">32365404</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>08</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2990</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>47</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Neuropathology and applied neurobiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Neuropathol Appl Neurobiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>TDP43 proteinopathy is associated with aberrant DNA methylation in human amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>61</StartPage><EndPage>72</EndPage><MedlinePgn>61-72</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/nan.12625</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) is a fatal neurodegenerative disease characterized by motor neurone (MN) degeneration and death. ALS can be sporadic (sALS) or familial, with a number of associated gene mutations, including C9orf72 (C9ALS). DNA methylation is an epigenetic mechanism whereby a methyl group is attached to a cytosine (5mC), resulting in gene expression repression. 5mC can be further oxidized to 5-hydroxymethylcytosine (5hmC). DNA methylation has been studied in other neurodegenerative diseases, but little work has been conducted in ALS.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="AIMS">To assess differences in DNA methylation in individuals with ALS and the relationship between DNA methylation and TDP43 pathology.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Post mortem tissue from controls, sALS cases and C9ALS cases were assessed by immunohistochemistry for 5mC and 5hmC in spinal cord, motor cortex and prefrontal cortex. LMNs were extracted from a subset of cases using laser capture microdissection. DNA from these underwent analysis using the MethylationEPIC array to determine which molecular processes were most affected.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">There were higher levels of 5mC and 5hmC in sALS and C9ALS in the residual lower motor neurones (LMNs) of the spinal cord. Importantly, in LMNs with TDP43 pathology there was less nuclear 5mC and 5hmC compared to the majority of residual LMNs that lacked TDP43 pathology. Enrichment analysis of the array data suggested RNA metabolism was particularly affected.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">DNA methylation is a contributory factor in ALS LMN pathology. This is not so for glia or neocortical neurones.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020 The Authors. Neuropathology and Applied Neurobiology published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of British Neuropathological Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Appleby-Mallinder</LastName><ForeName>C</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sheffield Institute for Translational Neuroscience (SITraN), University of Sheffield, Sheffield, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schaber</LastName><ForeName>E</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sheffield Institute for Translational Neuroscience (SITraN), University of Sheffield, Sheffield, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kirby</LastName><ForeName>J</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7468-5917</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sheffield Institute for Translational Neuroscience (SITraN), University of Sheffield, Sheffield, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shaw</LastName><ForeName>P J</ForeName><Initials>PJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sheffield Institute for Translational Neuroscience (SITraN), University of Sheffield, Sheffield, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cooper-Knock</LastName><ForeName>J</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sheffield Institute for Translational Neuroscience (SITraN), University of Sheffield, Sheffield, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Heath</LastName><ForeName>P R</ForeName><Initials>PR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sheffield Institute for Translational Neuroscience (SITraN), University of Sheffield, Sheffield, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Highley</LastName><ForeName>J R</ForeName><Initials>JR</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4969-6526</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sheffield Institute for Translational Neuroscience (SITraN), University of Sheffield, Sheffield, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cellular Pathology, Hull Royal Infirmary, Hull, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Acronym>DH_</Acronym><Agency>Department of Health</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Neuropathol Appl Neurobiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7609829</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0305-1846</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D004268">DNA-Binding Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>8J337D1HZY</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D003596">Cytosine</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="Y">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003596" MajorTopicYN="N">Cytosine</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019175" MajorTopicYN="N">DNA Methylation</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004268" MajorTopicYN="N">DNA-Binding Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D044127" MajorTopicYN="N">Epigenesis, Genetic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015870" MajorTopicYN="N">Gene Expression</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009154" MajorTopicYN="N">Mutation</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019636" MajorTopicYN="N">Neurodegenerative Diseases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="Y">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057177" MajorTopicYN="N">TDP-43 Proteinopathies</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">DNA hydroxymethylation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">DNA methylation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">epigenetics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">motor neurone disease</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32365404</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/nan.12625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Charcot JM, Joffory A. Deux cas d&#x2019;atrophie musculaire progressive avec lesions de la substance grise et des faisceaux antero-lateraux de la moelle epiniere. Arch Physiol Neurol Pathol 1869; 2: 744-54</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ludolph A, Drory V, Hardiman O, Nakano I, Ravits J, Robberecht W, et al. A revision of the El Escorial criteria - 2015. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2015; 16: 291-2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harwood CA, McDermott CJ, Shaw PJ. Physical activity as an exogenous risk factor in motor neuron disease (MND): a review of the evidence. Amyotroph Lateral Scler 2009; 10: 191-204</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niccoli T, Partridge L, Isaacs AM. Ageing as a risk factor for ALS/FTD. Hum Mol Genet 2017; 26: R105-13</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ince PG, Highley JR, Kirby J, Wharton SB, Takahashi H, Strong MJ, et al. Molecular pathology and genetic advances in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: an emerging molecular pathway and the significance of glial pathology. Acta Neuropathol 2011; 122: 657-71</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neumann M, Sampathu DM, Kwong LK, Truax AC, Micsenyi MC, Chou TT, et al. Ubiquitinated TDP-43 in frontotemporal lobar degeneration and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Science 2006; 314: 130-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zarei S, Carr K, Reiley L, Diaz K, Guerra O, Altamirano PF, et al. A comprehensive review of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Surg Neurol Int 2015; 6: 171</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rademakers R. C9orf72 repeat expansions in patients with ALS and FTD. Lancet Neurol 2012; 11: 297-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ou SH, Wu F, Harrich D, Garcia-Martinez LF, Gaynor RB. Cloning and characterization of a novel cellular protein, TDP-43, that binds to human immunodeficiency virus type 1 TAR DNA sequence motifs. J Virol 1995; 69: 3584-96</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scotter EL, Chen HJ, Shaw CE. TDP-43 proteinopathy and ALS: insights into disease mechanisms and therapeutic targets. Neurotherapeutics 2015; 12: 352-63</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peters OM, Ghasemi M, Brown RH Jr. Emerging mechanisms of molecular pathology in ALS. J Clin Invest 2015; 125: 1767-79</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tollervey JR, Curk T, Rogelj B, Briese M, Cereda M, Kayikci M, et al. Characterizing the RNA targets and position-dependent splicing regulation by TDP-43. Nat Neurosci 2011; 14: 452-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izumikawa K, Nobe Y, Yoshikawa H, Ishikawa H, Miura Y, Nakayama H, et al. TDP-43 stabilises the processing intermediates of mitochondrial transcripts. Sci Rep 2017; 7: 7709</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higashi S, Kabuta T, Nagai Y, Tsuchiya Y, Akiyama H, Wada K. TDP-43 associates with stalled ribosomes and contributes to cell survival during cellular stress. J Neurochem 2013; 126: 288-300</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vazquez-Villase&#xf1;or I, Garwood CJ, Heath PR, Simpson JE, Ince PG, Wharton SB. Expression of p16 and p21 in the frontal association cortex of ALS/MND brains suggests neuronal cell cycle dysregulation and astrocyte senescence in early stages of the disease. Neuropathol Appl Neurobiol 2020; 46: 171-85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tammen SA, Friso S, Choi SW. Epigenetics: the link between nature and nurture. Mol Aspects Med 2013; 34: 753-64</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robertson KD, Wolffe AP. DNA methylation in health and disease. Nat Rev Genet 2000; 1: 11-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ito S, Shen L, Dai Q, Wu SC, Collins LB, Swenberg JA, et al. Tet proteins can convert 5-methylcytosine to 5-formylcytosine and 5-carboxylcytosine. Science 2011; 333: 1300-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L, Lu X, Lu J, Liang H, Dai Q, Xu GL, et al. Thymine DNA glycosylase specifically recognizes 5-carboxylcytosine-modified DNA. Nat Chem Biol 2012; 8: 328-30</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin SG, Wu X, Li AX, Pfeifer GP. Genomic mapping of 5-hydroxymethylcytosine in the human brain. Nucleic Acids Res 2011; 39: 5015-24</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Branco MR, Ficz G, Reik W. Uncovering the role of 5-hydroxymethylcytosine in the epigenome. Nat Rev Genet 2011; 13: 7-13</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Globisch D, Munzel M, Muller M, Michalakis S, Wagner M, Koch S, et al. Tissue distribution of 5-hydroxymethylcytosine and search for active demethylation intermediates. PLoS One 2010; 5: e15367</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones MJ, Goodman SJ, Kobor MS. DNA methylation and healthy human aging. Aging Cell 2015; 14: 924-32</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horvath S. DNA methylation age of human tissues and cell types. Genome Biol 2013; 14: R115</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horvath S, Raj K. DNA methylation-based biomarkers and the epigenetic clock theory of ageing. Nat Rev Genet 2018; 19: 371-84</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roubroeks JAY, Smith RG, van den Hove DLA, Lunnon K. Epigenetics and DNA methylomic profiling in Alzheimer's disease and other neurodegenerative diseases. J Neurochem 2017; 143: 158-70</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romesser PB, Romanyshyn JC, Schupak KD, Setton J, Riaz N, Wolden SL, et al. Percutaneous endoscopic gastrostomy in oropharyngeal cancer patients treated with intensity-modulated radiotherapy with concurrent chemotherapy. Cancer 2012; 118: 6072-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lunnon K, Smith R, Hannon E, De Jager PL, Srivastava G, Volta M, et al. Methylomic profiling implicates cortical deregulation of ANK1 in Alzheimer's disease. Nat Neurosci 2014; 17: 1164-70</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watson CT, Roussos P, Garg P, Ho DJ, Azam N, Katsel PL, et al. Genome-wide DNA methylation profiling in the superior temporal gyrus reveals epigenetic signatures associated with Alzheimer's disease. Genome Med 2016; 8: 5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Villar-Menendez I, Blanch M, Tyebji S, Pereira-Veiga T, Albasanz JL, Martin M, et al. Increased 5-methylcytosine and decreased 5-hydroxymethylcytosine levels are associated with reduced striatal A2AR levels in Huntington's disease. Neuromolecular Med 2013; 15: 295-309</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morahan JM, Yu B, Trent RJ, Pamphlett R. A genome-wide analysis of brain DNA methylation identifies new candidate genes for sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler 2009; 10: 418-29</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Figueroa-Romero C, Hur J, Bender DE, Delaney CE, Cataldo MD, Smith AL, et al. Identification of epigenetically altered genes in sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. PLoS One 2012; 7: e52672</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ince PG, Highley JR, Wharton SB. Motor neuron disorders. In Greenfield's Neuropathology9th edn. Eds S Love, A Perry, J Ironside, H Budka. Boca Raton, FL: CRC Press, 2015; 817-48</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. A coefficient of agreement for nominal scales. Educ Psychol Meas 1960; 20: 37-46</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assenov Y, Muller F, Lutsik P, Walter J, Lengauer T, Bock C. Comprehensive analysis of DNA methylation data with RnBeads. Nat Methods 2014; 11: 1138-40</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muller F, Scherer M, Assenov Y, Lutsik P, Walter J, Lengauer T, Bock C. RnBeads 2.0: comprehensive analysis of DNA methylation data. Genome Biol 2019; 20: 55</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Science WIo. GeneCards. 2019. Available at: https://www.genecards.org/ (last accessed September 17, 2019)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Day JJ, Kennedy AJ, Sweatt JD. DNA methylation and its implications and accessibility for neuropsychiatric therapeutics. Annu Rev Pharmacol Toxicol 2015; 55: 591-611</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu H, Liu X, Deng Y, Qing H. DNA methylation, a hand behind neurodegenerative diseases. Front Aging Neurosci 2013; 5: 85</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hemendinger RA, Armstrong EJ 3rd, Brooks BR. Methyl vitamin B12 but not methylfolate rescues a motor neuron-like cell line from homocysteine-mediated cell death. Toxicol Appl Pharmacol 2011; 251: 217-25</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Highley JR, Kirby J, Jansweijer JA, Webb PS, Hewamadduma CA, Heath PR, et al. Loss of nuclear TDP-43 in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) causes altered expression of splicing machinery and widespread dysregulation of RNA splicing in motor neurones. Neuropathol Appl Neurobiol 2014; 40: 670-85</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>