<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">32396653</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>25</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1468-1331</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>27</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Statins, diabetes mellitus and prognosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: data from 501 patients of a population-based registry in southwest Germany.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1405</StartPage><EndPage>1414</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1405-1414</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/ene.14300</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND PURPOSE">A wide variety of metabolic changes, including an increased incidence of diabetes mellitus (DM) and dyslipidaemia, has been described in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). The aim of this study was to investigate the associations of statin use and history of DM with onset of disease and survival in patients with ALS.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">In all, 501 patients (mean age 65.2&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;10.9&#xa0;years; 58.5% male) from the ALS Registry Swabia recruited between October 2010 and April 2016 were included in this prospective cohort study. Data were collected using a standardized questionnaire.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Statin use (n&#xa0;=&#xa0;65) was not associated with overall survival (P&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.62). Age of ALS onset in patients with DM was 4.2&#xa0;years later (95% confidence interval 1.3-7.2&#xa0;years) than in patients without DM (P&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;0.01). The overall survival of patients with high body mass index at study entry (&gt;27.0&#xa0;kg/m<sup>2</sup> , upper quartile, n&#xa0;=&#xa0;127) was prolonged by more than 5 months compared to patients with low body mass index (&lt;22.0&#xa0;kg/m<sup>2</sup> , lower quartile, n&#xa0;=&#xa0;123; P&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.04).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">This study supports the view that statin use is not associated with overall survival of ALS patients, suggesting that statins are not harmful and should not be discontinued in ALS. Furthermore, the delayed onset of ALS in patients with DM may mirror the potentially protective metabolic profile associated with type 2 DM. Consistently, this study provides further evidence that high body mass index is a positive prognostic factor in ALS.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020 The Authors. European Journal of Neurology published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of European Academy of Neurology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schumacher</LastName><ForeName>J</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of Ulm, Ulm, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Peter</LastName><ForeName>R S</ForeName><Initials>RS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Epidemiology and Medical Biometry, University of Ulm, Ulm, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nagel</LastName><ForeName>G</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6185-8535</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Epidemiology and Medical Biometry, University of Ulm, Ulm, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rothenbacher</LastName><ForeName>D</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Epidemiology and Medical Biometry, University of Ulm, Ulm, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rosenbohm</LastName><ForeName>A</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of Ulm, Ulm, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ludolph</LastName><ForeName>A C</ForeName><Initials>AC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of Ulm, Ulm, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dorst</LastName><ForeName>J</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6352-0909</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of Ulm, Ulm, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><CollectiveName>ALS Registry Swabia Study Group</CollectiveName></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>577631</GrantID><Agency>Deutsche Forschungsgemeinschaft</Agency><Country>International</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9506311</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1351-5101</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D019161">Hydroxymethylglutaryl-CoA Reductase Inhibitors</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003920" MajorTopicYN="N">Diabetes Mellitus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005858" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Germany</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019161" MajorTopicYN="N">Hydroxymethylglutaryl-CoA Reductase Inhibitors</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011379" MajorTopicYN="N">Prognosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011446" MajorTopicYN="N">Prospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012042" MajorTopicYN="N">Registries</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">diabetes mellitus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">prognostic factors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">statins</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">survival</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32396653</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ene.14300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Forsgren L, Almay B, Holmgren G, Wall S. Epidemiology of motor neuron disease in northern Sweden. Acta Neurol Scand 1983; 68: 20-29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bensimon G, Lacomblez L, Meininger V. A controlled trial of riluzole in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. The ALS/Riluzole Study Group. N Engl J Med 1994; 330: 585-591.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller R, Mitchell J, Moore D. Riluzole for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS)/motor neuron disease (MND). Cochrane Database Syst Rev 2012; CD001447.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenbohm A, Peter R, Erhardt S, et al. Epidemiology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in southern Germany. The ALS Registry Study Group. J Neurol 2017; 264: 749-757.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasarskis E, Berryman S, Vanderleest J, Schneider A, McClain C. Nutritional status of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: relation to the proximity of death. Am J Clin Nutr 1996; 63: 130-137.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desport J, Preux P, Truong T, Vallat J, Sautereau D, Couratier P. Nutritional status is a prognostic factor for survival in ALS patients. Neurology 1999; 53: 1059-1063.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desport J, Preux P, Magy L, et al. Factors correlated with hypermetabolism in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Am J Clin Nutr 2001; 74: 328-334.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Funalot B, Desport J, Sturtz F, Camu W, Couratier P. High metabolic level in patients with familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2009; 10: 113-117.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mariosa D, Beard J, Umbach D, et al. Body mass index and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a study of US military veterans. Am J Epidemiol 2017; 185: 362-371.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dupuis L, Dengler R, Heneka M, et al. A randomized, double blind, placebo-controlled trial of pioglitazone in combination with riluzole in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. The GERP ALS Study Group. PLoS One 2012; 7: e37885.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vercruysse P, Sinniger J, El Oussini H, et al. Alterations in the hypothalamic melanocortin pathway in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. The GERP ALS Study Group. Brain 2016; 139: 1106-1122.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cykowski M, Takei H, Schulz P, Appel S, Powell S. TDP-43 pathology in the basal forebrain and hypothalamus of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathol Commun 2014; 2: 171-182.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorges M, Vercruysse P, M&#xfc;ller H, et al. Hypothalamic atrophy is related to body mass index and age at onset in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2017; 88: 1033-1041.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dupuis L, Corcia P, Fergani A, De Aguilar J, Bonnefont-Rousselot D, Bittar R. Dyslipidemia is a protective factor in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology 2008; 70: 1004-1009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pradat P, Bruneteau G, Gordon P, et al. Impaired glucose tolerance in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2010; 11: 166-171.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2; A, Calvo A, Ilardi A, et al. Lower serum lipid levels are related to respiratory impairment in patients with ALS. Neurology 2009; 73: 1681-1685.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zinman L, Sadeghi R, Gawel M, Patton D, Kiss A. Are statin medications safe in patients with ALS? Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2008; 9: 223-228.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng Z, Sheng L, Shang H. Statins and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2013; 14: 241-245.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drory V, Bronipolsky T, Artamonov I, Nefussy B. Influence of statins treatment on survival in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Sci 2008; 273: 81-83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimizu T, Honda M, Ohashi T, et al. Hyperosmolar hyperglycemic state in advanced amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2011; 12: 379-381.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergman R, Ader M. Free fatty acids and pathogenesis of type 2 diabetes mellitus. Trends Endocrinol Metab 2000; 11: 351-356.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jawaid A, Salamone A, Strutt A, et al. ALS disease onset may occur later in patients with pre-morbid diabetes mellitus. Eur J Neurol 2010; 17: 733-739.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kioumourtzoglou M, Rotem R, Seals R, Gredal O, Hansen J, Weisskopf M. Diabetes mellitus, obesity, and diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a population-based study. JAMA Neurol 2015; 72: 905-911.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uenal H, Rosenbohm A, Kufeldt J, et al. Incidence and geographical variation of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) in southern Germany - completeness of the ALS Registry Swabia. PLoS One 2014; 9: e93932.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagel G, Uenal H, Rosenbohm A, Ludolph A, Rothenbacher D. Implementation of a population-based epidemiological rare disease registry: study protocol of the amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) -registry Swabia. The ALS Registry Study Group. BMC Neurol 2013; 13: 1-10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peter R, Rosenbohm A, Dupuis L, et al. Life course body mass index and risk and prognosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: results from the ALS registry Swabia. Eur J Epidemiol 2017; 32: 901-908.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum J, Stambler N, Malta E, et al. The ALSFRS-R: a revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. BDNF ALS Study Group (Phase III). J Neurol Sci 1999; 169: 13-21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks B, Miller R, Swash M, Munsat T. El Escorial revisited: revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. World Federation of Neurology Research Group on Motor Neuron Diseases. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord 2000; 1: 293-299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knopf HC, Busch MA, Du Y, Truthmann J, Schienkiewitz A, Scheidt-Nave C. Changes in the prevalence of statin use in Germany - findings from national health interview and examination surveys 1997-1999 and 2008-2011. Z Evid Fortbild Qual Gesundhwes 2017; 122: 22-31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seelen M, van Doormaal P, Visser A, et al. Prior medical conditions and the risk of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol 2014; 261: 1949-1956.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mariosa D, Hammar N, Malmstr&#xf6;m H, et al. Blood biomarkers of carbohydrate, lipid and apolipoprotein metabolisms and risk of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a more than 20 year follow-up of the Swedish AMORIS cohort. Ann Neurol 2017; 81: 718-728.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dorst J, K&#xfc;hnlein P, Hendrich C, Kassubek J, Sperfeld A, Ludolph A. Patients with elevated triglyceride and cholesterol serum levels have a prolonged survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol 2011; 258: 613-617.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paganoni S, Ma J, Jaffa M, Cudkowicz M, Wills A. Body mass index, not dyslipidemia, is an independent predictor of survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve 2011; 44: 20-24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nefussy B, Hirsch J, Cudkowicz M, Drory V. Gender-based effect of statins on functional decline in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Sci 2011; 300: 23-27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edwards I, Star K, Kiuru A. Statins, neuromuscular degenerative disease and an amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-like syndrome: an analysis of individual case safety reports from Vigibase. Drug Saf 2007; 30: 515-525.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Golomb B, Kwon E, Koperski S, Evans M. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-like conditions in possible association with cholesterol-lowering drugs: an analysis of patient reports to the University of California, San Diego (UCSD) statin effects study. Drug Saf 2009; 32: 649-661.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xf8;rensen H, Riis A, Lash T, Pedersen L. Statin use and risk of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and other motor neuron disorders. Circ Cardiovasc Qual Outcomes 2010; 3: 413-417.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moglia C, Calvo A, Canosa A, et al. Influence of arterial hypertension, type 2 diabetes and cardiovascular risk factors on ALS outcome: a population-based study. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2017; 18: 590-597.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paganoni S, Hyman T, Shui A, et al. Pre-morbid type 2 diabetes mellitus is not a prognostic factor in ALS. Muscle Nerve 2015; 52: 339-343.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mariosa D, Kamel F, Bellocco R, Ye W, Fang F. Association between diabetes and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in Sweden. Eur J Neurol 2015; 22: 1436-1442.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Reilly &#xc9;, Wang H, Weisskopf M, et al. Premorbid body mass index and risk of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2013; 14: 205-211.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks B. Natural history of ALS: symptoms, strength, pulmonary function, and disability. Neurology 1996; 47: 71-82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hollinger S, Okosun I, Mitchell C. Antecedent disease and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: what is protecting whom? Front Neurol 2016; 7.47</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#x2019;Ovidio F, D&#x2019;Errico A, Carn&#xe0; P, Calvo A, Costa G, Chi&#xf2; A. The role of pre-morbid diabetes on developing amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Eur J Neurol 2018; 25: 164-170.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagel G, Peter R, Rosenbohm A, et al. Adipokines, C-reactive protein and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis - results from a population- based ALS registry in Germany. Sci Rep 2017; 7: 4374</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenbohm A, Nagel G, Peter R, et al. Association of serum retinol-binding protein 4 concentration with risk for and prognosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. JAMA Neurol 2018; 75: 600-607.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2; A, Logroscino G, Hardiman O, et al. Prognostic factors in ALS: a critical review. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2009; 10: 310-323.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ludolph A, Schuster J, Dorst J, et al. Safety and efficacy of rasagiline as an add-on therapy to riluzole in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a randomised, double-blind, parallel-group, placebo-controlled, phase 2 trial. Lancet Neurol 2018; 17: 681-688.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edaravone Study Group. Safety and efficacy of edaravone in well defined patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Lancet Neurol 2017; 16: 505-512.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>