<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">32415876</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>25</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-4598</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>62</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Muscle &amp; nerve</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Muscle Nerve</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Optimizing telemedicine to facilitate amyotrophic lateral sclerosis clinical trials.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>321</StartPage><EndPage>326</EndPage><MedlinePgn>321-326</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/mus.26921</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) has the largest drug pipeline among neuromuscular diseases, with over 160 companies actively involved in ALS research. There is a growing need to recruit trial participants, but ALS patients often have limited mobility and most ALS trials are conducted in a small number of major centers. These factors effectively limit patient participation, particularly for those in rural areas. The current coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) pandemic has necessitated the more widespread use of telemedicine technology for clinical care, and has prompted consideration of its increased use for clinical trials. In this opinion piece, we describe the current state of telemedicine for recruitment, consenting, and screening of participants for clinical trials. We also summarize the available data on remote administration of outcome measures. Current challenges include validation of outcome measures for remote assessment, as well as technological, regulatory, and licensure barriers.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020 Wiley Periodicals, Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Govindarajan</LastName><ForeName>Raghav</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of Missouri, Columbia, Missouri.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Berry</LastName><ForeName>James D</ForeName><Initials>JD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology and Neurology Clinical Trials Unit, Massachusetts General Hospital, Boston, Massachusetts.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Paganoni</LastName><ForeName>Sabrina</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Healey Center for ALS at Mass General Hospital, Massachusetts General Hospital, Boston, Massachusetts and Spaulding Rehabilitation Hospital, Department of PM&amp;R, Harvard Medical School, Boston, Massachusetts.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pulley</LastName><ForeName>Michael T</ForeName><Initials>MT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of Florida, Jacksonville, Florida.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Simmons</LastName><ForeName>Zachary</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8574-5332</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Penn State Health M.S. Hershey Medical Center, Hershey, Pennsylvania.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Muscle Nerve</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7803146</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0148-639X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="Y">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000073640" MajorTopicYN="Y">Betacoronavirus</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002986" MajorTopicYN="N">Clinical Trials as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018352" MajorTopicYN="N">Coronavirus Infections</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="Y">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058873" MajorTopicYN="Y">Pandemics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011024" MajorTopicYN="N">Pneumonia, Viral</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="Y">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="Y">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017216" MajorTopicYN="N">Telemedicine</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ALS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">clinical trials</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">eConsent</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">telemedicine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">telepresenter</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">telescreening</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32415876</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.26921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Bensimon G, Lacomblez L, Meininger V. A controlled trial of riluzole in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. ALS/Riluzole Study Group. N Engl J Med. 1994;330(9):585-591.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lacomblez L, Bensimon G, Leigh PN, Guillet P, Meininger V. Dose-ranging study of riluzole in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis/Riluzole Study Group II. Lancet. May 25, 1996;347(9013):1425-1431.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Writing Group; Edaravone (MCI-186) ALS 19 Study Group. Safety and efficacy of edaravone in well defined patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Lancet Neurol. 2017;16(7):505-512.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, Thisted RA, Appel SH, et al. Treatment of pseudobulbar affect in ALS with dextromethorphan/quinidine: a randomized trial. Neurology. 2004;63(8):1364-1370.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dunn A. First-of-its-kind trial in ALS spurs hope for brutal disease. Biopharmadive. September 25, 2019. biopharmadive.com/news/als-platform-trial-mass-general-healey-center/563595/. .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saltzman J. To speed drug development, Mass. General to begin ALS trials that test several compounds at once. September 23, 2019. https://sp-foundation.org/news-resources/news-article-archive.html/article/2019/09/23/to-speed-drug-development-mass-general-to-begin-als-trials-that-test-several-compounds-at-once</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horton DK, Graham S, Punjani R, et al. A spatial analysis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) cases in the United States and their proximity to multidisciplinary ALS clinics, 2013. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2018;19(1-2):126-133.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stephens HE, Young J, Felgoise SH, Simmons Z. A qualitative study of multidisciplinary ALS clinic use in the United States. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2015;17(1-2):55-61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bedlack RS, Pastula DM, Welsh E, Pulley D, Cudkowicz ME. Scrutinizing enrollment in ALS clinical trials: room for improvement? Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2008;9(5):257-265.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pulley MT, Brittain R, Hodges W, Frazier C, Miller L, Matyjasik-Liggett M. Multidisciplinary amyotrophic lateral sclerosis telemedicine care: the store and forward method. Muscle Nerve. 2019;59(1):34-39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geronimo A, Wright C, Morris A, Walsh S, Snyder B, Simmons Z. Incorporation of telehealth into a multidisciplinary ALS Clinic: feasibility and acceptability. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2017;18(7-8):555-561.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van De Rijn M, Paganoni S, Levine-Weinberg M, et al. Experience with telemedicine in a multi-disciplinary ALS clinic. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2018;19(1-2):143-148.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson NM. Coronavirus offers opportunity for physicians to try telemedicine March 18, 2020. https://www.medicaleconomics.com/news/coronavirus-offers-opportunity-physicians-try-telemedicine</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bunnell BE, Sprague G, Qanungo S, et al. An exploration of useful telemedicine-based resources for clinical research. Telemed J E Health. 2020;26(1):51-65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rutkove SB, Qi K, Shelton K, Liss J, Berisha V, Shefner JM. ALS longitudinal studies with frequent data collection at home: study design and baseline data. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2019;20(1-2):61-67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melao A. CENTAUR phase 2 trial of AMX0035, potential ALS treatment, finishes collecting data. https://alsnewstoday.com/2019/10/09/centaur-trial-amx0035-in-als-finishes-collecting-data/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bedlack RS, Wicks P, Heywood J, Kasarskis E. Modifiable barriers to enrollment in American ALS research studies. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2010;11(6):502-507.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharpe TJ. Adopting eConsent to better patient experience in clinical Trials. June. 2019;18. https://www.clinicalleader.com/doc/adopting-econsent-to-better-patient-experience-in-clinical-trials-0001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nims P. The role of telepresenter. September 26, 2013. https://www.nrtrc.org/education-article-19</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weinstein RS, Krupinski EA, Doarn CR. Clinical examination component of telemedicine, telehealth, mhealth, and connected health medical practices. Med Clin North Am. 2018;102(3):533-544.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum JM, Stambler N, Malta E, et al. The ALSFRS-R: a revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. BDNF ALS Study Group (Phase III). J Neurol Sci. 1999;169(1-2):13-21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montes J, Levy G, Albert S, et al. Development and evaluation of a self-administered version of the ALSFRS-R. Neurology. 2006;67(7):1294-1296.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaufmann P, Levy G, Montes J, et al. Excellent inter-rater, intra-rater, and telephone-administered reliability of the ALSFRS-R in a multicenter clinical trial. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2007;8(1):42-46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakker LA, Schr&#xf6;der CD, Tan HHG, et al. Development and assessment of the inter-rater and intra-rater reproducibility of a self-administration version of the ALSFRS-R. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2020;91:75-81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berry JD, Paganoni S, Carlson K, et al. Design and results of a smartphone-based digital phenotyping study to quantify ALS progression. Ann Clin Transl Neurol. 2019;6(5):873-881.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plowman EK, Tabor LC, Robison R, et al. Discriminant ability of the Eating Assessment Tool-10 to detect aspiration in individuals with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurogastroenterol Motil. 2016;28(1):85-90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Felgoise SH, Feinberg R, Stephens HE, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-specific quality of life-short form (ALSSQOL-SF): a brief, reliable, and valid version of the ALSSQOL-R. Muscle Nerve. 2018;58(5):646-654.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jenkinson C, Fitzpatrick R, Brennan C, Swash M. Evidence for the validity and reliability of the ALS assessment questionnaire: the ALSAQ-40. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord. 1999;1(1):33-40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith RA, Berg JE, Pope LE, Callahan JD, Wynn D, Thisted RA. Validation of the CNS emotional lability scale for pseudobulbar affect (pathological laughing and crying) in multiple sclerosis patients. Mult Scler. 2004;10(6):679-685.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibbons CJ, Mills RJ, Thornton EW, et al. Development of a patient reported outcome measure for fatigue in motor neurone disease: the Neurological Fatigue Index (NFI-MND). Health Qual Life Outcomes. 2011;9:101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCormack MC, Kaminsky DA, 2020 members of the ATS Proficiency Standards for Pulmonary Function Testing Committee. Pulmonary function laboratories: advice regarding COVID-19. https://www.thoracic.org/professionals/clinical-resources/disease-related-resources/pulmonary-function-laboratories.php</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geronimo A, Simmons Z. Evaluation of remote pulmonary function testing in motor neuron disease. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2019;20(5-6):348-355.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Eijk RPA, Bakers JNE, Bunte TM, de Fockert AJ, Eijkemans MJC, van den Berg LH. Accelerometry for remote monitoring of physical activity in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a longitudinal cohort study. J Neurol. 2019;266(10):2387-2395.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott Kruse C, Karem P, Shifflett K, Vegi L, Ravi K, Brooks M. Evaluating barriers to adopting telemedicine worldwide: a systematic review. J Telemed Telecare. 2018;24(1):4-12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>EveryCRSReport.com. Broadband Internet Access and the Digital Divide: Federal Assistance Programs (October 24, 2001 - October 25, 2019). https://www.everycrsreport.com/reports/RL30719.html. Accessed April 4, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whisman MA, Perez JE, Ramel W. Factor structure of the Beck Depression Inventory-Second Edition (BDI-II) in a student sample. J Clin Psychol. 2000;56:545-551.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holland JC, Kash KM, Passik S, et al. A brief spiritual beliefs inventory for use in quality of life research in life-threatening illness. Psychooncology. 1998;7(6):460-469.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breitbart W, Rosenfeld B, Roth A, Smith MJ, Cohen K, Passik S. The Memorial Delirium Assessment Scale. J Pain Symptom Manage. 1997;13(3):128-137.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perkinson MA, Albert SM, Luborsky M, Moss M, Glicksman A. Exploring the validity of the Affect Balance Scale with a sample of family caregivers. J Gerontol. 1994;49(5):S264-S275.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirsch IB, Martinez J, Dorsey ER, et al. Incorporating Site-less clinical trials into drug development: a framework for action. Clin Ther. 2017;39(5):1064-1076.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Center for Drug Evaluation and Research (CDER) Office of Scientific Investigations (OSI). https://www.fda.gov/about-fda/center-drug-evaluation-and-research-cder/office-scientific-investigations. Accessed April 4, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>FDA Good Clinical Practices. http://www.fda.gov/oc/gcp/default.htm. Accessed April 4, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Code of Federal Regulations (CFR). http://www.accessdata.fda.gov/scripts/cdrh/cfdocs/cfcfr/cfrsearch.cfm. Accessed April 4, 2020.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>