<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">32432818</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>06</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1468-1331</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>27</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>2-Deoxy-2-[<sup>18</sup> F]fluoro-d-glucose positron emission tomography, cortical thickness and white matter graph network abnormalities in brains of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal dementia suggest early neuronopathy rather than axonopathy.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1904</StartPage><EndPage>1912</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1904-1912</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/ene.14332</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND PURPOSE">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) is a motor neuron disorder, although extra-motor degeneration is well recognized, especially in frontotemporal regions manifested as ALS with frontotemporal dementia (ALS-FTD). Previous neuroimaging studies of the brains of ALS-FTD patients have measured abnormalities of either grey matter (GM) or white matter (WM) structures but not of both together. Therefore, the aim was to evaluate both GM and WM in the same ALS-FTD patient using functional and structural neuroimaging. By doing so, insights could be gained into whether neurodegeneration in ALS-FTD is primarily a neuronopathy or axonopathy.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">After high-resolution brain 2-deoxy-2-[<sup>18</sup> F]fluoro-D-glucose (<sup>18</sup> F-FDG) positron emission tomography (PET) and magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) scans were obtained in ALS-FTD patients and in age- and sex-matched neurological controls, changes in metabolic rate, cortical thickness (CT) and WM network analysis using graph theory were analyzed.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Significant reductions in <sup>18</sup> F-FDG PET metabolism, CT and WM connections were observed in motor and extra-motor brain regions of ALS-FTD patients compared to controls. Both CT and underlying WM networks were abnormal in frontal, temporal, parietal and occipital lobes of ALS-FTD patients with 86 of 90 brain regions showing reductions of CT.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">Abnormalities in significantly fewer WM networks underlying the affected cortical regions suggest that neurodegeneration in brains of ALS-FTD patients is primarily a 'neuronopathy' rather than an 'axonopathy.'</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020 European Academy of Neurology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rajagopalan</LastName><ForeName>V</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9040-0785</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical and Electronics Engineering, Birla Institute of Technology and Science Pilani, Hyderabad Campus, Hyderabad, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Engineering, Lerner Research Institute, Cleveland Clinic, Cleveland, OH, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pioro</LastName><ForeName>E P</ForeName><Initials>EP</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0737-6065</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neuromuscular Center, Department of Neurology, Neurological Institute, Cleveland Clinic, Cleveland, OH, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosciences, Lerner Research Institute, Cleveland Clinic, Cleveland, OH, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9506311</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1351-5101</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>IY9XDZ35W2</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D005947">Glucose</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001921" MajorTopicYN="N">Brain</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Frontotemporal Dementia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005947" MajorTopicYN="N">Glucose</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008279" MajorTopicYN="N">Magnetic Resonance Imaging</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D049268" MajorTopicYN="N">Positron-Emission Tomography</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D066127" MajorTopicYN="Y">White Matter</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ALS-FTD</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">FDG-PET</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">WM brain network</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cortical thickness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neuronopathy</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32432818</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ene.14332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Abrahams S, Goldstein LH, Kew JJ, et al. Frontal lobe dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. A PET study. Brain 1996; 119: 2105-2120.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang JL, Lomen-Hoerth C, Murphy J, et al. A voxel-based morphometry study of patterns of brain atrophy in ALS and ALS/FTLD. Neurology 2005; 65: 75-80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajagopalan V, Pioro EP. Differential involvement of corticospinal tract fibers in ALS phenotypes: a diffusion tensor tractography and imaging study. Neuroimage Clin 2017; 14: 574-549.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajagopalan V, Yue GH, Pioro EP. Brain white matter diffusion tensor metrics from clinical 1.5T MRI distinguish between ALS phenotypes. J Neurol. 2013; 260: 2532-2540.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pasko R. The radial edifice of cortical architecture: from neuronal silhouettes to genetic engineering. Brain Res Rev 2007; 55: 204-219.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuster C, Kasper E, Dyrba M, et al. Cortical thinning and its relation to cognition in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurobiol Aging 2014; 35: 240-246.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajagopalan V, Pioro EP. Comparing brain structural MRI and metabolic FDG-PET changes in patients with ALS-FTD: 'the chicken or the egg?' question. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2015; 86: 952-958.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kushner PDSD, Wright S. Reactive astrogliosis is widespread in the subcortical white matter of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis brain. J Neuropathol Exp Neurol 1991; 50: 263-277.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weydt P, Moller T. Neuroinflammation in the pathogenesis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuroreport 2005; 16: 527-531.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen J, Kostenko V, Pioro EP, Trapp BD. MR imaging-based estimation of upper motor neuron density in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a feasibility study. Radiology 2018; 287: 955-964.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canosa A, Pagani M, Cistaro A, et al. 18F-FDG-PET correlates of cognitive impairment in ALS. Neurology 2016; 86: 44-49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renard D, Collombier L, Castelnovo G, Fourcade G, Kotzki PO, LaBauge P. Brain FDG-PET changes in ALS and ALS-FTD. Acta Neurol Belg 2011; 111: 306-309.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajagopalan V, Pioro EP. Longitudinal 18F-FDG PET and MRI reveal evolving imaging pathology that corresponds to disease progression in a patient with ALS-FTD. Front Neurol 2019; 10: 234.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Omer T, Finegan E, Hutchinson S, et al. Neuroimaging patterns along the ALS-FTD spectrum: a multiparametric imaging study. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2017; 18: 611-623.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Schuff N, Woolley SC, et al. Progression of white matter degeneration in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a diffusion tensor imaging study. Amyotroph Lateral Scler 2011; 12: 421-429.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajagopalan V, Liu Z, Allexandre D, et al. Brain white matter shape changes in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS): a fractal dimension study. PLoS One 2013; 8: e73614.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lillo P, Mioshi E, Burrell JR, Kiernan MC, Hodges JR, Hornberger M. Grey and white matter changes across the amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-frontotemporal dementia continuum. PLoS One 2012; 7: e43993.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dimond D, Ishaque A, Chenji S, et al. White matter structural network abnormalities underlie executive dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Hum Brain Mapp 2017; 38: 1249-1268.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minoshima S, Frey KA, Koeppe RA, Foster NL, Kuhl DE. A diagnostic approach in Alzheimer's disease using three-dimensional stereotactic surface projections of fluorine-18-FDG PET. J Nucl Med 1995; 36: 1238-1248.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minoshima S, Koeppe RA, Frey KA, Kuhl DE. Anatomical standardization: linear scaling and nonlinear warping of functional brain images. J Nucl Med 1994; 35: 1528-1537.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fischl B, Dale AM. Measuring the thickness of the human cerebral cortex from magnetic resonance images. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA 2000; 97: 11050-11055.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leemans AJ, Jeurissen B, Sijbers J, Jones DK. ExploreDTI: a graphical toolbox for processing, analyzing, and visualizing diffusion MR data. In Proc Intl Soc Mag Reson Med 2009 Apr 18; 2009: Vol. 17, p. 3537.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tzourio-Mazoyer N, Landeau B, Papathanassiou D, et al. Automated anatomical labeling of activations in SPM using a macroscopic anatomical parcellation of the MNI MRI single-subject brain. NeuroImage 2002; 15: 273-289.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hosseini SMH, Hoeft F, Kesler SR. GAT: a graph-theoretical analysis toolbox for analyzing between-group differences in large-scale structural and functional brain networks. PLoS One 2012; 7: e40709.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, Miller RG, Swash M, Munsat TL. El Escorial revisited: revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord 2000; 1: 293-299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Floeter MK, Gendron TF. Biomarkers for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal dementia associated with hexanucleotide expansion mutations in C9orf72. Front Neurol 2018; 9: 1063.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byrne S, Elamin M, Bede P, et al. Cognitive and clinical characteristics of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis carrying a C9orf72 repeat expansion: a population-based cohort study. Lancet Neurol 2012; 11: 232-240.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parvizi J, Anderson SW, Martin CO, Damasio H, Damasio AR. Pathological laughter and crying: a link to the cerebellum. Brain 2001; 124: 1708-1719.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verstraete E, Veldink JH, Mandl RCW, van den Berg LH, van den Heuvel MP. Impaired structural motor connectome in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. PLoS One 2011; 6: e24239.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sporns O. Networks of the Brain. London: MIT Press, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gong G, He Y, Concha L, et al. Mapping anatomical connectivity patterns of human cerebral cortex using in vivo diffusion tensor imaging tractography. Cerebral Cortex 2009; 19: 524-536.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coffman KA, Dum RP, Strick PL. Cerebellar vermis is a target of projections from the motor areas in the cerebral cortex. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA 2011; 108: 16068-16073.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan RH, Devenney E, Dobson-Stone C, et al. Cerebellar integrity in the amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-frontotemporal dementia continuum. PloS One 2014; 9: e105632.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abrahams S, Goldstein LH, Suckling J, et al. Frontotemporal white matter changes in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol 2005; 252: 321-331.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agosta F, Sala S, Valsasina P, et al. Brain network connectivity assessed using graph theory in frontotemporal dementia. Neurology 2013; 81: 134-143.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt R, Verstraete E, de Reus MA, Veldink JH, van den Berg LH, van den Heuvel MP. Correlation between structural and functional connectivity impairment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Hum Brain Mapp 2014; 35: 4386-4395.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kassubek J, Unrath A, Huppertz HJ, et al. Global brain atrophy and corticospinal tract alterations in ALS, as investigated by voxel-based morphometry of 3-D MRI. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord 2005; 6: 213-20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neumann M, Sampathu DM, Kwong LK, et al. Ubiquitinated TDP-43 in frontotemporal lobar degeneration and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Science 2006; 314: 130-133.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitwell JL, Avula R, Senjem ML, et al. Gray and white matter water diffusion in the syndromic variants of frontotemporal dementia. Neurology 2010; 74: 1279-1287.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bede P, Hardiman O. Longitudinal structural changes in ALS: a three time-point imaging study of white and gray matter degeneration. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2018; 19: 232-241.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>