<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">32452880</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1537-7385</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>99</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>American journal of physical medicine &amp; rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Am J Phys Med Rehabil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of Exercise in Patients With Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>801</StartPage><EndPage>810</EndPage><MedlinePgn>801-810</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/PHM.0000000000001419</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">The aim of this study was to systematically review the efficacy and safety of exercise in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DESIGN">Randomized controlled trials of exercises for ALS were searched in PubMed, EMBASE, Web of Science, Cochrane Library, China Biology Medicine database, China National Knowledge Internet, VIP database, and Wanfang database. The primary outcomes were functional ability, pulmonary function, and quality of life. The secondary outcomes were muscle strength, fatigue and adverse events. Meta-analysis was performed using the RevMan Version 5.3 software.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Seven randomized controlled trials including 322 patients with ALS met the inclusion criteria. Meta-analysis showed that the functional scores at long-term (standardized means difference, 0.47; 95% confidence interval, 0.08-0.86; P = 0.02) and forced vital capacity percentage predicted (mean difference, 1.71; 95% confidence interval, 0.10-3.31; P = 0.04) of patients with ALS in the exercise group were significantly higher than those in the group of no exercise or usual care. No significant difference was observed in muscle strength and quality of life. Endurance or aerobic exercise improved the functional scores of patients with ALS (standardized means difference, 0.36; 95% confidence interval, 0.04-0.68; P = 0.03). Exercise did not aggravate fatigue or result in adverse event.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">Exercise can significantly improve the functional ability and pulmonary function of patients with ALS safely.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Meng</LastName><ForeName>Lijiao</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Rehabilitation Medicine Center, West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu Sichuan, China (LM, XL, CL, YC, YG, QG); Key Laboratory of Rehabilitation Medicine in Sichuan Province, West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu Sichuan, China (LM, CL, YG, QG); and MacLehose Medical Rehabilitation Center, HKSAR, China (RCCT).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Xiaoxiao</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Cheng</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tsang</LastName><ForeName>Raymond C C</ForeName><Initials>RCC</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Yi</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ge</LastName><ForeName>Yanlei</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gao</LastName><ForeName>Qiang</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Am J Phys Med Rehabil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8803677</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0894-9115</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="CommentIn"><RefSource>Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2021 Apr 1;100(4):e55-e56</RefSource><PMID Version="1">33252466</PMID></CommentsCorrections><CommentsCorrections RefType="CommentIn"><RefSource>Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2021 Apr 1;100(4):e56-e57</RefSource><PMID Version="1">33252474</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000203" MajorTopicYN="N">Activities of Daily Living</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001945" MajorTopicYN="N">Breathing Exercises</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005081" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise Therapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016032" MajorTopicYN="N">Randomized Controlled Trials as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32452880</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/PHM.0000000000001419</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00002060-202009000-00008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, Miller RG, Swash M, et al.; World Federation of Neurology Research Group on Motor Neuron Diseases: El Escorial revisited: revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord 2000;1:293&#x2013;9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiernan MC, Vucic S, Cheah BC, et al.: Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet 2011;377:942&#x2013;55</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardiman O, Al-Chalabi A, Chio A, et al.: Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat Rev Dis Primers 2017;3:17071</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marin B, Boumediene F, Logroscino G, et al.: Variation in worldwide incidence of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a meta-analysis. Int J Epidemiol 2017;46:57&#x2013;74</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Talbott EO, Malek AM, Lacomis D: The epidemiology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Handb Clin Neurol 2016;138:225&#x2013;38</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Es MA, Hardiman O, Chio A, et al.: Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet 2017;390:2084&#x2013;98</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maloney FP, Burks JS, Ringel SP: Effects of Exercise in Neuromuscular Disease. New York, JB Lippincott, 1985:228&#x2013;38</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clawson LL, Cudkowicz M, Krivickas L, et al.: A randomized controlled trial of resistance and endurance exercise in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2018;19(3&#x2013;4):250&#x2013;8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lunetta C, Lizio A, Sansone VA, et al.: Strictly monitored exercise programs reduce motor deterioration in ALS: preliminary results of a randomized controlled trial. J Neurol 2016;263:52&#x2013;60</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Groenestijn AC, Schroder CD, van Eijk RPA, et al.: Aerobic exercise therapy in ambulatory patients with ALS: a randomized controlled trial. Neurorehabil Neural Repair 2019;33:153&#x2013;64</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merico A, Cavinato M, Gregorio C, et al.: Effects of combined endurance and resistance training in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a pilot, randomized, controlled study. Eur J Transl Myol 2018;28:7278</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lui AJ, Byl NN: A systematic review of the effect of moderate intensity exercise on function and disease progression in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Phys Ther 2009;33:68&#x2013;87</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dal Bello-Haas V, Florence JM: Therapeutic exercise for people with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis or motor neuron disease. Cochrane Database Syst Rev 2013:Cd005229</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The ALS CNTF (ciliary neurotrophic factor) Treatment Study (ACTS) Phase I&#x2013;II Study Group: The Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Functional Rating Scale. Assessment of activities of daily living in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Arch Neurol 1996;53:141&#x2013;7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum JM, Stambler N, Malta E, et al.: The ALSFRS-R: a revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. BDNF ALS Study Group (phase III). J Neurol Sci 1999;169(1&#x2013;2):13&#x2013;21</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bourke SC, McColl E, Shaw PJ, et al.: Validation of quality of life instruments in ALS. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord 2004;5:55&#x2013;60</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jenkinson C, Fitzpatrick R, Brennan C, et al.: Evidence for the validity and reliability of the ALS assessment questionnaire: the ALSAQ-40. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord 1999;1:33&#x2013;40</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andres PL, Hedlund W, Finison L, et al.: Quantitative motor assessment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology 1986;36:937&#x2013;41</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krupp LB, LaRocca NG, Muir-Nash J, et al.: The Fatigue Severity Scale. Application to patients with multiple sclerosis and systemic lupus erythematosus. Arch Neurol 1989;46:1121&#x2013;3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dittner AJ, Wessely SC, Brown RG: The assessment of fatigue: a practical guide for clinicians and researchers. J Psychosom Res 2004;56:157&#x2013;70</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Morton NA: The PEDro scale is a valid measure of the methodological quality of clinical trials: a demographic study. Aust J Physiother 2009;55:129&#x2013;33</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>PEDro: PEDro statistics. Available at: https://www.pedro.org.au/english/downloads/pedro-statistics/. Accessed April 10, 2019</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JPT, Green S: Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions. Version 5.1.0. Cochrane Collaboration. England: John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd, 2011</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bello-Haas VD, Florence JM, Kloos AD, et al.: A randomized controlled trial of resistance exercise in individuals with ALS. Neurology 2007;68:2003&#x2013;7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plowman EK, Tabor-Gray L, Rosado KM, et al.: Impact of expiratory strength training in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: results of a randomized, sham-controlled trial. Muscle Nerve 2019;59:40&#x2013;6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drory VE, Goltsman E, Goldman Reznik J, et al.: The value of muscle exercise in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Sci 2001;191(1&#x2013;2):133&#x2013;7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCrate ME, Kaspar BK: Physical activity and neuroprotection in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuromolecular Med 2008;10:108&#x2013;17</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gardiner P, Dai Y, Heckman CJ: Effects of exercise training on alpha-motoneurons. J Appl Physiol 2006;101:1228&#x2013;36</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garbuzova-Davis S, Haller E, Saporta S, et al.: Ultrastructure of blood-brain barrier and blood-spinal cord barrier in SOD1 mice modeling ALS. Brain Res 2007;1157:126&#x2013;37</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Julien JP: ALS: astrocytes move in as deadly neighbors. Nat Neurosci 2007;10:535&#x2013;7</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>