<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">32453096</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>26</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1537-1611</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>21</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of clinical neuromuscular disease</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Clin Neuromuscul Dis</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Role of Radiation Therapy and Botulinum Toxin Injections in the Management of Sialorrhea in Patients With Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis: A Systematic Review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>205</StartPage><EndPage>221</EndPage><MedlinePgn>205-221</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/CND.0000000000000273</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Half of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis experience sialorrhea due to facial weakness. Although anticholinergic medications are first-line therapy, they often lead to unacceptable side effects. Radiation therapy and botulinum toxin may be considered when medical management fails. In this systematic review, we investigated the effectiveness of these interventions.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Eligible studies were retrieved from PubMed and Scopus databases up to March 2017 along with hand-searching of references from primary articles.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Fourteen studies (N = 138) examined the benefits of botulinum toxin. Studies varied in salivary glands treated, dosages used, and the use of botulinum toxin subtype A or B. A majority of studies showed benefit after treatment. Although most studies reported only mild adverse effects, 2 case studies revealed severe complications including recurrent TMJ dislocations and rapid deterioration in bulbar function. Ten studies (N = 171) examined the benefits of radiation. Most studies reported improvement with only mild adverse events reported.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Both radiation and botulinum toxin are effective treatments for sialorrhea in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and should be considered when medical management fails. Radiation may offer longer duration of symptom improvement with fewer complications.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shehee</LastName><ForeName>Lindsey</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Otolaryngology, Medical University of South Carolina, Charleston, SC; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>O'Rourke</LastName><ForeName>Ashli</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Otolaryngology, Medical University of South Carolina, Charleston, SC; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Garand</LastName><ForeName>Kendrea L</ForeName><Initials>KL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Speech Pathology and Audiology, University of South Alabama, Mobile, AL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Clin Neuromuscul Dis</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100887391</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1522-0443</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D009465">Neuromuscular Agents</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 3.4.24.69</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D001905">Botulinum Toxins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001905" MajorTopicYN="N">Botulinum Toxins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009465" MajorTopicYN="N">Neuromuscular Agents</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012798" MajorTopicYN="N">Sialorrhea</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="Y">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000532" MajorTopicYN="Y">radiotherapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32453096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/CND.0000000000000273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00131402-202006000-00003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Wijesekera LC, Leigh PN. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Orphanet J Rare Dis. 2009;4:3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abhinav K, Stanton B, Johnston C, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in south-east england: a population-based study. Neuroepidemiology. 2007;29:44&#x2013;48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bourry N, Guy N, Achard JL, et al. Salivary glands radiotherapy to reduce sialorrhea in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: dose and energy. Cancer Radiother. 2013;17:191&#x2013;195.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi A, Mora G, Leone M, et al. Early symptom progression rate is related to ALS outcome. Neurology. 2002;59:99&#x2013;103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newall AR, Orser R, Hunt M. The control of oral secretions in bulbar ALS/MND. J Neurol Sci. 1996;139(suppl l):43&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young CA, Ellis C, Johnson J, et al. Treatment for sialorrhea (excessive saliva) in people with motor neuron disease/amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2011;CD006981.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blackhall LJ. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and palliative care: where we are, and the road ahead. Muscle Nerve. 2012;45:311&#x2013;318.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinto A, Evangelista T, Carvalho L, et al. Respiratory assistance with a non-invasive ventilator (Bipap) in MND/ALS patients: survival rates in a controlled trial. J Neurol Sci. 1995;129:19&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bourke SC, Tomlinson M, Williams TL, et al. Effects of non-invasive ventilation on survival and quality of life in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a randomised controlled trial. Lancet Neurol. 2006;5:140&#x2013;147.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lechtzin N, Scott Y, Busse AM, et al. Early use of non-invasive ventilation prolongs survival in subjects with ALS. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2006;8:185&#x2013;188.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Squires N, Adrian W, John R. The management of drooling in adults with neurological conditions. Curr Opin Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg. 2012;20:171&#x2013;176.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oxford Centre for Evidence-based Medicine&#x2014;Levels of Evidence (2009). Centre of Evidence-based Medicine.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giess R, Naumann M, Werner E, et al. Injections of botulinum toxin A into the salivary glands improve sialorrhoea in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2000;69:121&#x2013;123.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manrique D. Application of botulinum toxin to reduce the saliva in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Braz J Otorhinolaryngol. 2005;71:566&#x2013;569.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilio F, Iacovelli E, Frasca V, et al. Botulinum toxin type A for the treatment of sialorrhoea in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a clinical and neurophysiological study. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2010;11:359&#x2013;363.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez-Murphy E, Marti-Bonmati E, Camps-Segui E, et al. Manually guided botulinum toxin type A submandibular injections for the treatment of sialorrhea in tube-fed patients with advanced amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Am J Health Syst Pharm. 2011;68:1680&#x2013;1681.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verma A, Steele J. Botulinum toxin improves sialorrhea and quality of living in bulbar amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 2006;34:235&#x2013;237.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott KR, Kothari MJ, Venkatesh YS, et al. Parotid gland injections of botulinum toxin a are effective in treating sialorrhea in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Clin Neuromuscul Dis. 2005;7:62&#x2013;65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neppelberg E, Haugen DF, Thorsen L, et al. Radiotherapy reduces sialorrhea in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Eur J Neurol. 2007;14:1373&#x2013;1377.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Contarino MF, Pompili M, Tittoto P, et al. Botulinum toxin B ultrasound-guided injections for sialorrhea in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and Parkinson's disease. Parkinsonism Relat Disord. 2007;13:299&#x2013;303.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa J, Rocha ML, Ferreira J, et al. Botulinum toxin type-B improves sialorrhea and quality of life in bulbaronset amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol. 2008;255:545&#x2013;550.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson CE, Gronseth G, Rosenfeld J, et al. Randomized double-blind study of botulinum toxin type B for sialorrhea in ALS patients. Muscle Nerve. 2009;39:137&#x2013;143.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan EK, Lo YL, Seah A, et al. Recurrent jaw dislocation after botulinum toxin treatment for sialorrhoea in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Sci. 2001;190:95&#x2013;97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meijer JW, van Kuijk AA, Geurts AC, et al. Acute deterioration of bulbar function after botulinum toxin treatment for sialorrhoea in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2008;87:321&#x2013;324.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winterholler MG, Erbguth FJ, Wolf S, et al. Botulinum toxin for the treatment of sialorrhoea in ALS: serious side effects of a transductal approach. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2001;70:417&#x2013;418.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen PM, Gr&#xf6;nberg H, Franzen L, et al. External radiation of the parotid glands significantly reduces drooling in patients with motor neurone disease with bulbar paresis. J Neurol Sci. 2001;191:111&#x2013;114.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assouline A, Levy A, Abdelnour-Mallet M, et al. Radiation therapy for hypersalivation: a prospective study in 50 amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. Int J Radiat Oncol Biol Phys. 2014;88:589&#x2013;595.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amador Mdel M, Assouline A, Gonzalez-Bermejo J, et al. Radiotherapy treatment of sialorrhea in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis requiring non-invasive ventilation. J Neurol. 2015;262:1981&#x2013;1983.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasarskis EJ, Hodskins J, St Clair WH. Unilateral parotid electron beam radiotherapy as palliative treatment for sialorrhea in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Sci. 2011;308:155&#x2013;157.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guy N, Bourry N, Dallel R, et al. Comparison of radiotherapy types in the treatment of sialorrhea in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Palliat Med. 2011;14:391&#x2013;395.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stalpers LJ, Moser EC. Results of radiotherapy for drooling in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology. 2002;58:1308.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weikamp JG, Schinagl DA, Verstappen CC, et al. Botulinum toxin-A injections vs radiotherapy for drooling in ALS. Acta Neurol Scand. 2016;134:224&#x2013;231.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The clinical measurement of swallowing in health and in neurogenic dysphagia. Dysphagia. 1996;11:270&#x2013;271.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harriman M, Morrison M, Hay J, et al. Use of radiotherapy for control of sialorrhea in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Otolaryngol. 2001;30:242&#x2013;245.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anagnostou E, Rentzos M, Alexakis T, et al. Volume matters: the influence of different botulinum toxin-A dilutions for sialorrhea in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 2013;47:276&#x2013;278.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levitsky G, Alekhin A, Serdyuk A, et al. Open-label comparative study of amitriptyline and disport efficacy in control of sialorrhea in ALS. Eur J Neurol. 2005;12:165.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ludolph A, Drory V, Hardiman O, et al. A revision of the El Escorial Criteria. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2015;16:291&#x2013;292.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum JM, Stambler N, Malta E, et al. The ALSFRS-R: a revised functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. J Neurol Sci. 1999;169:13&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>