<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">32468479</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>11</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0065-2598</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>1195</Volume><PubDate><Year>2020</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Advances in experimental medicine and biology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Adv Exp Med Biol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Transcriptomics and Metabolomics in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>205</StartPage><EndPage>212</EndPage><MedlinePgn>205-212</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/978-3-030-32633-3_29</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) is a fatal neurodegenerative disease involving progressive and selective loss of motor neurons, muscle weakness, paralysis and death. The pathogenesis of ALS is not clearly understood, while reliable prognostic markers have not been identified to detect symptoms at earlier time points. The rapid development of microarray technology offers great potential for simultaneous analysis of the transcriptional expression of thousands of genes, aiming to determine novel candidate targets for efficient treatment. Additionally, metabolomics, as a high-throughput approach, is gaining significant attention in ALS research providing an opportunity to develop predictive biomarkers that may be utilized as indicators of clinical symptoms of ALS. In this review, recent evidences from gene expression profiling studies in ALS are illustrated in order to examine molecular signatures related to the disease's pathogenesis and potential discovery of therapeutic targets. Moreover, potent challenges are presented regarding the utilization of the metabolomics approach as a diagnostic tool in context with distinctive biomarkers' identification.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Krokidis</LastName><ForeName>Marios G</ForeName><Initials>MG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Center for Scientific Research "Demokritos", Institute of Nanoscience and Nanotechnology, Patriarchou Grigoriou &amp; Neapoleos, Athens, Greece. m.krokidis@inn.demokritos.gr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Adv Exp Med Biol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0121103</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0065-2598</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="Y">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020869" MajorTopicYN="N">Gene Expression Profiling</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055432" MajorTopicYN="Y">Metabolomics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D059467" MajorTopicYN="Y">Transcriptome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Biomarkers</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Metabolomics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Microarrays</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neurodegenerative diseases</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32468479</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-3-030-32633-3_29</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Aronica E, Baas F, Iyer A, ten Asbroek A, Morello G, Cavallaro S (2015) Molecular classification of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis by unsupervised clustering of gene expression in motor cortex. Neurobiol Dis 74:359&#x2013;376</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25500340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nbd.2014.12.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babu GN, Kumar A, Chandra R, Puri SK, Singh RL, Kalita J, Misra UK (2008) Oxidant-antioxidant imbalance in the erythrocytes of sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients correlates with the progression of disease. Neurochem Int 52:1284&#x2013;1289</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18308427</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuint.2008.01.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bingol K (2018) Recent Advances in Targeted and Untargeted Metabolomics by NMR and MS/NMR Methods. High Throughput 7:E9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29670016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ht7020009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blasco H, Corcia P, Moreau C, Veau S, Fournier C, Vourc&#x2019;h P, Emond P, Gordon P, Pradat PF, Praline J, Devos D, Nadal-Desbarats L, Andres CR (2010) 1H-NMR-based metabolomic profiling of CSF in early amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. PLoS One 5:e13223</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20949041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2951909</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0013223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boutahar N, Wierinckx A, Camdessanche J, Antoine J, Reynaud E, Lassabliere F, Lachuer J, Borg J (2011) Differential effect of oxidative or exitotoxic stress on the transcriptional profile of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-linked mutant SOD1 cultured neurons. J Neurosci Res 89:1439&#x2013;1450</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21647936</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jnr.22672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, Jorgenson JA, Newhouse BJ, Shefner JM, Agnese W (2018) Edaravone in the treatment of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: efficacy and access to therapy&#xa0;&#x2013; a roundtable discussion. Am J Manag Care 24(9 Suppl):S175&#x2013;S186</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29693363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bucchia M, Ramirez A, Parente V, Simone C, Nizzardo M, Magri F, Dametti S, Corti S (2015) Therapeutic development in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Ther 37:668&#x2013;680</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25666449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clinthera.2014.12.020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buratti E, Baralle F (2001) Characterization and functional implications of the RNA binding properties of nuclear factor TDP-43, a novel splicing regulator of CFTR exon 9. J Biol Chem 276:36337&#x2013;36343</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11470789</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1074/jbc.M104236200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buratti E, Baralle F (2008) Multiple roles of TDP-43 in gene expression, splicing regulation, and human disease. Front Biosci 13:867&#x2013;878</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17981595</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2741/2727</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheah B, Vucic S, Krishnan A, Kiernan M (2010) Riluzole, neuroprotection and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Curr Med Chem 17:1942&#x2013;1199</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20377511</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/092986710791163939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi JK, K&#xfc;stermann E, Dedeoglu A, Jenkins BG (2009) Magnetic resonance spectroscopy of regional brain metabolite markers in FALS mice and the effects of dietary creatine supplementation. Eur J Neurosci 30:2143&#x2013;2150</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19930399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2846694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1460-9568.2009.07015.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooper-Knock J, Kirby J, Ferraiuolo L, Heath P, Rattray M, Shaw P (2012) Gene expression profiling in human neurodegenerative disease. Nat Rev Neurol 8:518&#x2013;530</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22890216</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrneurol.2012.156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Oliveira GP, Maximino J, Maschietto M, Zanoteli E, Puga R, Lima L, Carraro D, Chadi G (2014) Early gene expression changes in skeletal muscle from SOD1(G93A) amyotrophic lateral sclerosis animal model. Cell Mol Neurobiol 34:451&#x2013;462</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24442855</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10571-014-0029-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeJesus-Hernandez M, Mackenzie I, Boeve B, Boxer A, Baker M, Rutherford N, Nicholson A, Finch N, Flynn H, Adamson J et al (2010) Expanded GGGGCC hexanucleotide repeat in noncoding region of C9ORF72 causes chromosome 9p-linked FTD and ALS. Neuron 72:245&#x2013;256</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuron.2011.09.011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng H, Chen W, Hong S, Boycott K, Gorrie G, Siddique N, Yang Y (2011) Mutations in UBQLN2 cause dominant X-linked juvenile and adult-onset alS and ALS/dementia. Nature 477:211&#x2013;215</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21857683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3169705</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nature10353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng H, Gao K, Jankovic J (2014) The role of FUS gene variants in neurodegenerative diseases. Nat Rev Neurol 10(6):337&#x2013;348</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24840975</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrneurol.2014.78</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Droppelmann C, Campos-Melo D, Ishtiaq M, Volkening K, Strong M (2014) RNA metabolism in ALS: when normal processes become pathological. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 15:321&#x2013;336</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24555412</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/21678421.2014.881377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foran E, Bogush A, Goffredo M, Roncaglia P, Gustincich S, Pasinelli P, Trotti D (2011) Motor neuron impairment mediated by a sumoylated fragment of the glial glutamate transporter EAAT2. Glia 59:1719&#x2013;1731</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21769946</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3896305</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/glia.21218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foran E, Rosenblum L, Bogush A, Pasinelli P, Trotti D (2014) Sumoylation of the astroglial glutamate transporter EAAT2 governs its intracellular compartmentalization. Glia 62:1241&#x2013;1253</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24753081</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4061158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/glia.22677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenway M, Andersen P, Russ C, Ennis S, Cashman S, Donaghy C, Patterson V, Swingler R, Kieran D, Prehn J, Morrison K, Green A, Acharya K, Brown R, Hardiman O (2006) ANG mutations segregate with familial and &#x2018;sporadic&#x2019; amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat Genet 38:411&#x2013;413</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16501576</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ng1742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta S, Kim S, Wang Y, Dinasarapu A, Subramaniam S (2014) Statistical insights into major human muscular diseases. Hum Mol Genet 23:3772&#x2013;3778</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24569163</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4415066</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/hmg/ddu090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heath P, Kirby J, Shaw P (2013) Investigating cell death mechanisms in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis using transcriptomics. Front Cell Neurosci 7:259</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24381542</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3865770</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fncel.2013.00259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman NJ (2017) Omics and exercise: global approaches for mapping exercise biological networks. Cold Spring Harb Perspect Med 7:a029884</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28348175</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5629985</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/cshperspect.a029884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Honda D, Ishigaki S, Iguchi Y, Fujioka Y, Udagawa T, Masuda A, Ohno K, Katsuno M, Sobue G (2013) The TDP-43 neurotoxicity in Drosophila. PLoS One 8:e57214</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/annotation/beae09ab-07c8-43de-b2de-a7e8368b77f6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krokidis MG, Vlamos P (2018) Transcriptomics in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Front Biosci (Elite Ed) 10:103&#x2013;121</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2741/e811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kudo L, Parfenova L, Vi N, Lau K, Pomakian J, Valdmanis P, Rouleau G, Vinters H, Wiedau-Pazos M, Karsten S (2010) Integrative gene-tissue microarray-based approach for identification of human disease biomarkers: application to amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Hum Mol Genet 19(16):3233&#x2013;3253</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20530642</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/hmg/ddq232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumimoto E, Fore T, Zhang B (2013) Transcriptome profiling following neuronal and glial expression of ALS-linked SOD1 in Drosophila. G3 (Bethesda) 3:695&#x2013;708</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1534/g3.113.005850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maruyama H, Morino H, Ito H, Izumi Y, Kato H, Watanabe Y, Kinoshita Y, Kamada M, Nodera H, Suzuki H, Komure O, Matsuura S, Kobatake K, Morimoto N, Abe K, Suzuki N, Aoki M, Kawata A, Hirai T, Kato T, Ogasawara K, Hirano A, Takumi T, Kusaka H, Hagiwara K, Kaji R, Kawakami H (2010) Mutations of optineurin in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nature 465:223&#x2013;226</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20428114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nature08971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maximino J, de Oliveira G, Alves C, Chadi G (2014) Deregulated expression of cytoskeleton related genes in the spinal cord and sciatic nerve of presymptomatic SOD1(G93A) Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis mouse model. Front Cell Neurosci 8:148</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24904291</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4033281</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fncel.2014.00148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Narayanan R, Mangelsdorf M, Panwar A, Butler T, Noakes P, Wallace R (2012) Identification of RNA bound to the TDP-43 ribonucleoprotein complex in the adult mouse brain. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 14:252&#x2013;260</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23134510</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/21678421.2012.734520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nardo G, Iennaco R, Fusi N, Heath P, Marino M, Trolese M, Ferraiuolo L, Lawrence N, Shaw P, Bendotti C (2013) Transcriptomic indices of fast and slow disease progression in two mouse models of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain 136:3305&#x2013;3332</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24065725</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awt250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niessen HG, Debska-Vielhaber G, Sander K, Angenstein F, Ludolph AC, Hilfert L, Willker W, Leibfritz D, Heinze HJ, Kunz WS, Vielhaber S (2007) Metabolic progression markers of neurodegeneration in the transgenic G93A-SOD1 mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Eur J Neurosci 25:1669&#x2013;1677</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17432958</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1460-9568.2007.05415.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patin F, Baranek T, Vourc&#x2019;h P, Nadal-Desbarats L, Goossens JF, Marouillat S, Dessein AF, Descat A, Hounoum BM, Bruno C, Watier H, Si-Tahar M, Leman S, Lecron JC, Andres CR, Corcia P, Blasco H (2016) Combined Metabolomics and Transcriptomics Approaches to Assess the IL-6 Blockade as a Therapeutic of ALS: Deleterious Alteration of Lipid Metabolism. Neurotherapeutics 13:905&#x2013;917</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27444617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5081117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13311-016-0461-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renton AE, Chio A, Traynor B (2014) State of play in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis genetics. Nat Neurosci 1:17&#x2013;23</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nn.3584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosen D, Siddique T, Patterson D, Figlewicz D, Sapp P, Hentati A, Donaldson D, Goto J, O&#x2019;Regan J, Deng H, Brown R Jr (1993) Mutations in Cu/Zn superoxide dismutase gene are associated with familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nature 362:59&#x2013;62</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8446170</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/362059a0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rozen S, Cudkowicz ME, Bogdanov M, Matson WR, Kristal BS, Beecher C, Harrison S, Vouros P, Flarakos J, Vigneau-Callahan K, Matson TD, Newhall KM, Beal MF, Brown RH Jr, Kaddurah-Daouk R (2005) Metabolomic analysis and signatures in motor neuron disease. Metabolomics 1:101&#x2013;108</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18820733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2553219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11306-005-4810-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saris C, Groen E, van Vught P, van Es M, Blauw H, Veldink J, van den Berg L (2013) Gene expression profile of SOD1-G93A mouse spinal cord, blood and muscle. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 14:190&#x2013;198</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23298163</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/21678421.2012.749914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith EF, Shaw PJ, De Vos KJ (2019) The role of mitochondria in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurosci Lett 710:132933</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neulet.2017.06.052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sreedharan J, Blair I, Tripathi V, Hu X, Vance C, Rogelj B, Ackerley S, Durnall J, Williams K, Buratti E, Baralle F, de Belleroche J, Mitchell J, Leigh R, Al-Chalabi A, Miller C, Nicholson G, Shaw C (2008) TDP43 mutations in familial and sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Science 319:1668&#x2013;1672</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18309045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.1154584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takei K, Watanabe K, Yuki S, Akimoto M, Sakata T, Palumbo J (2017) Edaravone and its clinical development for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 18(sup1):5&#x2013;10</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28872907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/21678421.2017.1353101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang JH, Byun J, Pennathur S (2010) Analytical approaches to metabolomics and applications to systems biology. Semin Nephrol 30:500&#x2013;511</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21044761</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2989741</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.semnephrol.2010.07.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y, Hentati A, Deng H, Dabbagh O, Sasaki T, Hirano M, Hung W, Ouahchi K, Yan J, Azim A, Cole N, Gascon G, Yagmour A, Ben-Hamida M, Pericak-Vance M, Hentati F, Siddique T (2001) The gene encoding alsin, a protein with three guanine-nucleotide exchange factor domains, is mutated in a form of recessive amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat Genet 29:160&#x2013;165</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ng1001-160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu L, Guan Y, Wu X, Chen Y, Liu Z, Du H, Wang X (2013) Wnt Signaling is altered by spinal cord neuronal dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis transgenic mice. Neurochem Res 38:1904&#x2013;1913</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23784673</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4170800</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11064-013-1096-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhan L, Hanson K, Kim S, Tare A, Tibbetts R (2013) Identification of genetic modifiers of ALS/FTLD-related RNA-binding proteins TDP-43 and FUS have common downstream RNA targets in cortical neurons. FEBS Open Bio 4:1&#x2013;10</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zoccolella S, Simone IL, Capozzo R, Tortelli R, Leo A, D&#x2019;Errico E, Logroscino G (2011) An exploratory study of serum urate levels in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol 258:238&#x2013;243</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20842370</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00415-010-5735-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>