<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">32481440</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>24</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-5964</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>99</Volume><Issue>22</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>May</Month><Day>29</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Medicine (Baltimore)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Tamoxifen for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A randomized double-blind clinical trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e20423</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e20423</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MD.0000000000020423</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) is the most common cause of motor neuron disease, and effective treatment for ALS is still lacking. Transactive response (TAR) -DNA-binding protein-43 (TDP-43) is aggregated in the neurons of ALS patients. Animal studies shown TDP-43 aggregation can be attenuated by enhancing autophagy by tamoxifen. However, its beneficial effects for ALS patients remain unknown.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Eighteen patients with ALS without mutations in superoxide dismutase-1 (SOD-1) or fused in sarcoma (FUS) genes were randomly assigned into the tamoxifen 40&#x200a;mg/day or placebo group in a double-blinded manner and all were given riluzole twice daily. Participants were followed up at 1, 3, 6, and 12 months. The primary end point was time to death or dependence on mechanical ventilation. Secondary end points were decline of the revised ALS Functional Rating Scale (ALSFRS-R) score and pulmonary function measured by forced vital capacity (FVC).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Ten participants were randomly assigned in the treatment group with tamoxifen, 7 finished trial, 1 reach primary endpoint; while 8 participants in the placebo group, 2 finished trial and 2 reach primary end point. The proportion of participants reaching the primary end point was lower in the tamoxifen group but did not reach statistical significance. At the 1-, 3-, and 6-month follow-up, the average decline rates of the ALSFRS-R score were slower in the tamoxifen group. No significant difference was observed in FVC and ALSFRS-R score at 12 months between groups.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Tamoxifen exerted only a modest effect on attenuate progression for 6 months in this small trial. Additional larger scale studies should be necessary to confirm whether enhancing autophagy can attenuate ALS progression.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Po-Chih</ForeName><Initials>PC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3911-0891</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurology Department, Shuang-Ho Hospital.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Taipei Neuroscience Institute, Taipei Medical University, New Taipei City.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>PhD Program for Neural Regenerative Medicine, College of Medical Science and Technology, Taipei Medical University and National Health Research Institutes.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, School of Medicine, College of Medicine.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hsieh</LastName><ForeName>Yi-Chen</ForeName><Initials>YC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>PhD Program for Neural Regenerative Medicine, College of Medical Science and Technology, Taipei Medical University and National Health Research Institutes.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>PhD Program in Biotechnology Research and Development, College of Pharmacy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Master Program in Applied Molecular Epidemiology, College of Public Health, Taipei Medical University, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Chi-Chen</ForeName><Initials>CC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>PhD Program for Neural Regenerative Medicine, College of Medical Science and Technology, Taipei Medical University and National Health Research Institutes.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Neurotrauma and Neuroregeneration.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hu</LastName><ForeName>Chaur-Jong</ForeName><Initials>CJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurology Department, Shuang-Ho Hospital.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Taipei Neuroscience Institute, Taipei Medical University, New Taipei City.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>PhD Program for Neural Regenerative Medicine, College of Medical Science and Technology, Taipei Medical University and National Health Research Institutes.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, School of Medicine, College of Medicine.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D017427">Clinical Trial, Phase II</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Medicine (Baltimore)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>2985248R</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0025-7974</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D018696">Neuroprotective Agents</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>094ZI81Y45</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D013629">Tamoxifen</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="Y">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001343" MajorTopicYN="N">Autophagy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="N">drug effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018450" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Progression</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004311" MajorTopicYN="N">Double-Blind Method</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018696" MajorTopicYN="N">Neuroprotective Agents</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012720" MajorTopicYN="N">Severity of Illness Index</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013629" MajorTopicYN="N">Tamoxifen</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32481440</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000020423</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005792-202005290-00085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Kiernan MC, Vucic S, Cheah BC, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet 2011;377:942&#x2013;55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsai CP, Chang BH, Lee CT. Underlying cause and place of death among patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in Taiwan: a population-based study, 2003-2008. J Epidemiol 2013;23:424&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bensimon G, Lacomblez L, Meininger V. A controlled trial of riluzole in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. ALS/Riluzole Study Group. N Engl J Med 1994;330:585&#x2013;91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abe K, Aoki M, Tsuji S, et al. Safety and efficacy of edaravone in well defined patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Lancet Neurol 2017;16:505&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gros-Louis F, Gaspar C, Rouleau GA. Genetics of familial and sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Biochim Biophys Acta 2006;1762:956&#x2013;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neumann M, Sampathu DM, Kwong LK, et al. Ubiquitinated TDP-43 in frontotemporal lobar degeneration and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Science 2006;314:130&#x2013;3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen TJ, Lee VM, Trojanowski JQ. TDP-43 functions and pathogenic mechanisms implicated in TDP-43 proteinopathies. Trends Mol Med 2011;17:659&#x2013;67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratti A, Buratti E. Physiological functions and pathobiology of TDP-43 and FUS/TLS proteins. J Neurochem 2016;138: (Suppl 1): 95&#x2013;111.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farrawell NE, Lambert-Smith IA, Warraich ST, et al. Distinct partitioning of ALS associated TDP-43, FUS and SOD1 mutants into cellular inclusions. Sci Rep 2015;5:13416.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan CF, Eguchi H, Tagawa A, et al. TDP-43 immunoreactivity in neuronal inclusions in familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with or without SOD1 gene mutation. Acta Neuropathol 2007;113:535&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blair IP, Williams KL, Warraich ST, et al. FUS mutations in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: clinical, pathological, neurophysiological and genetic analysis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2010;81:639&#x2013;45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsai CP, Soong BW, Lin KP, et al. FUS, TARDBP, and SOD1 mutations in a Taiwanese cohort with familial ALS. Neurobiol Aging 2011;32:13&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang IF, Tsai KJ, Shen CK. Autophagy activation ameliorates neuronal pathogenesis of FTLD-U mice: a new light for treatment of TARDBP/TDP-43 proteinopathies. Autophagy 2013;9:239&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang IF, Guo BS, Liu YC, et al. Autophagy activators rescue and alleviate pathogenesis of a mouse model with proteinopathies of the TAR DNA-binding protein 43. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 2012;109:15024&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riggs BL, Hartmann LC. Selective estrogen-receptor modulators -- mechanisms of action and application to clinical practice. N Engl J Med 2003;348:618&#x2013;29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boulos AS, Deshaies EM, Dalfino JC, et al. Tamoxifen as an effective neuroprotectant in an endovascular canine model of stroke. J Neurosurg 2011;114:1117&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian DS, Liu JL, Xie MJ, et al. Tamoxifen attenuates inflammatory-mediated damage and improves functional outcome after spinal cord injury in rats. J Neurochem 2009;109:1658&#x2013;67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez-Burgos, Rivera-Cervantes MC, Vel&#xe1;zquez-Zamora DA, et al. Selective estrogen receptor modulators regulate dendritic spine plasticity in the hippocampus of male rats. Neural Plast 2012;2012:309494.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rubinsztein DC, Gestwicki JE, Murphy LO, et al. Potential therapeutic applications of autophagy. Nat Rev Drug Discov 2007;6:304&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, Miller RG, Swash M, et al. El Escorial revisited: revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord 2000;1:293&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Engelender S, Isacson O. The threshold theory for Parkinson's disease. Trends Neurosci 2017;40:4&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitehouse PJ, Price DL, Struble RG, et al. Alzheimer's disease and senile dementia: loss of neurons in the basal forebrain. Science 1982;215:1237&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clavelou P, Blanquet M, Peyrol F, et al. Rates of progression of weight and forced vital capacity as relevant measurement to adapt amyotrophic lateral sclerosis management for patient Result of a French multicentre cohort survey. J Neurol Sci 2013;331:126&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mangialasche F, Solomon A, Winblad B, et al. Alzheimer's disease: clinical trials and drug development. Lancet Neurol 2010;9:702&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandrioli J, Biguzzi S, Guidi C, et al. Real-world evidence - what is it and what can it tell us? N Engl J Med 2016;375:2293&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2; A, Logroscino G, Hardiman O, et al. Prognostic factors in ALS: a critical review. Amyotroph Lateral Scler 2009;10:310&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>