<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">32497246</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1476-5381</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>178</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>British journal of pharmacology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Br J Pharmacol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS), cancer, autoimmunity and metabolic disorders: An unsolved tantalizing challenge.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1269</StartPage><EndPage>1278</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1269-1278</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/bph.15151</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) commonly referred to as motor neurone disease, is a neurodegenerative disease of unknown pathogenesis that progresses rapidly and has attracted an increased amount of scholarly interest in recent years. The current conception of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis has transitioned into a more complex theory in which individual genetic risk, ageing and environmental factors interact, leading to disease onset in subjects in whom the sum of these factors reach a determined threshold. Based on this conceptualization, the environmental conditions, particularly those that are potentially modifiable, are becoming increasingly relevant. In this review, the current integrative model of the disease is discussed. In addition, we explore the role of cancer, autoimmunity and metabolic diseases as examples of novel, non-genetic and environmental factors. Together with the potential triggers or perpetuating pathogenic mechanisms along with new insights into potential lines of future research are provided. LINKED ARTICLES: This article is part of a themed issue on Neurochemistry in Japan. To view the other articles in this section visit http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/bph.v178.6/issuetoc.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020 The British Pharmacological Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Riancho</LastName><ForeName>Javier</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Service of Neurology, Hospital Sierrallana-IDIVAL, Torrelavega, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine and Psychiatry, University of Cantabria, Santander, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centro de Investigaci&#xf3;n en Red de Enfermedades Neurodegenerativas, CIBERNED, Instituto Carlos III, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Delgado-Alvarado</LastName><ForeName>Manuel</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Service of Neurology, Hospital Sierrallana-IDIVAL, Torrelavega, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biomedical Research Networking Center for Mental Health (CIBERSAM), ISC III, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Andreu</LastName><ForeName>Mar&#xed;a Dolores</ForeName><Initials>MD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Service of Endrocrinology, Hospital Sierrallana-IDIVAL, Torrelavega, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Paz-Fajardo</LastName><ForeName>Luc&#xed;a</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Service of Internal Medicina, Hospital Sierrallana-IDIVAL, Torrelavega, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Arozamena</LastName><ForeName>Sara</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Service of Neurology, Hospital Sierrallana-IDIVAL, Torrelavega, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gil-Bea</LastName><ForeName>Francisco Javier</ForeName><Initials>FJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centro de Investigaci&#xf3;n en Red de Enfermedades Neurodegenerativas, CIBERNED, Instituto Carlos III, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurosciences Area, Biodonostia Research Institute, San Sebasti&#xe1;n, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>L&#xf3;pez de Muna&#xed;n</LastName><ForeName>Adolfo</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centro de Investigaci&#xf3;n en Red de Enfermedades Neurodegenerativas, CIBERNED, Instituto Carlos III, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurosciences Area, Biodonostia Research Institute, San Sebasti&#xe1;n, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurology Department, Donostia University Hospital, OSAKIDETZA, San Sebasti&#xe1;n, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurosciences Department, Basque Country University, San Sebasti&#xe1;n, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Br J Pharmacol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7502536</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0007-1188</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015551" MajorTopicYN="N">Autoimmunity</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009369" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neoplasms</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019636" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neurodegenerative Diseases</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012307" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32497246</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bph.15151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Ahmed, R. M., Caga, J., Devenney, E., Hsieh, S., Bartley, L., Highton-Williamson, E., &#x2026; Kiernan, M. C. (2016). Cognition and eating behavior in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: effect on survival. Journal of Neurology, 263, 1593-1603. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00415-016-8168-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed, R. M., Highton-Williamson, E., Caga, J., Thornton, N., Ramsey, E., Zoing, M., &#x2026; Kiernan, M. C. (2018). Lipid metabolism and survival across the frontotemporal dementia-amyotrophic lateral sclerosis spectrum: Relationships to eating behavior and cognition. Journal of Alzheimer's Disease, 61, 773-783.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al Chalabi, A., Fang, F., Hanby, M. F., Leigh, P. N., Shaw, C. E., Ye, W., &amp; Rijsdijk, F. (2010). An estimate of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis heritability using twin data. Journal of Neurology, Neurosurgery, and Psychiatry, 81, 1324-1326. https://doi.org/10.1136/jnnp.2010.207464</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al Chalabi, A., &amp; Hardiman, O. (2013). The epidemiology of ALS: A conspiracy of genes, environment and time. Nature Reviews. Neurology, 9, 617-628. https://doi.org/10.1038/nrneurol.2013.203</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al Chalabi, A., Calvo, A., Chio, A., Colville, S., Ellis, C. M., Hardiman, O., &#x2026; Pearce, N. (2014). Analysis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis as a multistep process: A population-based modelling study. Lancet Neurology, 13, 1108-1113. https://doi.org/10.1016/S1474-4422(14)70219-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alberti, K. G., &amp; Zimmet, P. Z. (1998). Definition, diagnosis and classification of diabetes mellitus and its complications. Part 1: Diagnosis and classification of diabetes mellitus provisional report of a WHO consultation. Diabetic Medicine, 15, 539-553. https://doi.org/10.1002/(SICI)1096-9136(199807)15:7&lt;539::AID-DIA668&gt;3.0.CO;2-S</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alexander, S. P. H., Cidlowski, J. A., Kelly, E., Mathie, A., Peters, J. A., Veale, E. L., &#x2026; Davies, J. A. (2019). THE CONCISE GUIDE TO PHARMACOLOGY 2019/20: Nuclear hormone receptors. British Journal of Pharmacology, 176(Suppl 1), S229-S246.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arthur, K. C., Calvo, A., Price, T. R., Geiger, J. T., Chio, A., &amp; Traynor, B. J. (2016). Projected increase in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis from 2015 to 2040. Nature Communications, 7, 1-6. https://doi.org/10.1038/ncomms12408</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atanasio, A., Decman, V., White, D., Ramos, M., Ikiz, B., Lee, H. C., &#x2026; Lai, K. M. (2016). C9orf72 ablation causes immune dysregulation characterized by leukocyte expansion, autoantibody production, and glomerulonephropathy in mice. Scientific Reports, 6, 1-14. https://doi.org/10.1038/srep23204</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bjornstad, P., Snell-Bergeon, J. K., McFann, K., Wadwa, R. P., Rewers, M., Rivard, C. J., &#x2026; Maahs, D. M. (2014). Serum uric acid and insulin sensitivity in adolescents and adults with and without type 1 diabetes. J Diabetes Complications, 28, 298-304. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jdiacomp.2013.12.007</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouteloup, C., Desport, J. C., Clavelou, P., Guy, N., Derumeaux-Burel, H., Ferrier, A., &amp; Couratier, P. (2009). Hypermetabolism in ALS patients: An early and persistent phenomenon. Journal of Neurology, 256, 1236-1242. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00415-009-5100-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burberry, A., Suzuki, N., Wang, J. Y., Moccia, R., Mordes, D. A., Stewart, M. H., &#x2026; Eggan, K. (2016). Loss-of-function mutations in the C9ORF72 mouse ortholog cause fatal autoimmune disease. Science Translational Medicine, 8, 1-26, 347ra93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chhetri, S. K., Majeed, T., Lekwuwa, G., &amp; Boothman, B. (2015). Very high titers of voltage-gated potassium channel antibodies in a patient with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle &amp; Nerve, 51, 147-147. https://doi.org/10.1002/mus.24460</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiang, P. M., Ling, J., Jeong, Y. H., Price, D. L., Aja, S. M., &amp; Wong, P. C. (2010). Deletion of TDP-43 down-regulates Tbc1d1, a gene linked to obesity, and alters body fat metabolism. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 107, 16320-16324. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1002176107</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeJesus-Hernandez, M., Mackenzie, I. R., Boeve, B. F., Boxer, A. L., Baker, M., Rutherford, N. J., &#x2026; Rademakers, R. (2011). Expanded GGGGCC hexanucleotide repeat in noncoding region of C9ORF72 causes chromosome 9p-linked FTD and ALS. Neuron, 72, 245-256. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2011.09.011</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delaye, J. B., Patin, F., Piver, E., Bruno, C., Vasse, M., Vourc'h, P., &#x2026; Blasco, H. (2017). Low IDL-B and high LDL-1 subfraction levels in serum of ALS patients. Journal of the Neurological Sciences, 380, 124-127. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jns.2017.07.019</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demestre, M., Pullen, A., Orrell, R. W., &amp; Orth, M. (2005). ALS-IgG-induced selective motor neurone apoptosis in rat mixed primary spinal cord cultures. Journal of Neurochemistry, 94, 268-275. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1471-4159.2005.03184.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desport, J. C., Preux, P. M., Magy, L., Boirie, Y., Vallat, J. M., Beaufrere, B., &amp; Couratier, P. (2001). Factors correlated with hypermetabolism in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. The American Journal of Clinical Nutrition, 74, 328-334. https://doi.org/10.1093/ajcn/74.3.328</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desport, J. C., Preux, P. M., Truong, T. C., Vallat, J. M., Sautereau, D., &amp; Couratier, P. (1999). Nutritional status is a prognostic factor for survival in ALS patients. Neurology, 53, 1059-1063. https://doi.org/10.1212/WNL.53.5.1059</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dormann, D., &amp; Haass, C. (2013). Fused in sarcoma (FUS): An oncogene goes awry in neurodegeneration. Molecular and Cellular Neurosciences, 56, 475-486. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcn.2013.03.006</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Driver, J. A., Beiser, A., Au, R., Kreger, B. E., Splansky, G. L., Kurth, T., &#x2026; Wolf, P. A. (2012). Inverse association between cancer and Alzheimer's disease: Results from the Framingham Heart Study. BMJ, 344, 1-11, e1442. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.e1442</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dupuis, L., Corcia, P., Fergani, A., Gonzalez De Aguilar, J. L., Bonnefont-Rousselot, D., Bittar, R., &#x2026; Meininger, V. (2008). Dyslipidemia is a protective factor in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology, 70, 1004-1009. https://doi.org/10.1212/01.wnl.0000285080.70324.27</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dupuis, L., Dengler, R., Heneka, M. T., Meyer, T., Zierz, S., Kassubek, J., &#x2026; Ludolph, A. C. (2012). A randomized, double blind, placebo-controlled trial of pioglitazone in combination with riluzole in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. PLoS ONE, 7, e37885. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0037885</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dupuis, L., Pradat, P. F., Ludolph, A. C., &amp; Loeffler, J. P. (2011). Energy metabolism in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet Neurology, 10, 75-82. https://doi.org/10.1016/S1474-4422(10)70224-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang, F., Al Chalabi, A., Ronnevi, L. O., Turner, M. R., Wirdefeldt, K., Kamel, F., &amp; Ye, W. (2013). Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and cancer: A register-based study in Sweden. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis and Frontotemporal Degeneration, 14, 362-368. https://doi.org/10.3109/21678421.2013.775309</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-Eulate, G., Ruiz-Sanz, J. I., Riancho, J., Zufiria, M., GereNu, G., Fernandez-Torron, R., &#x2026; Gil-Bea, F. J. (2020). A comprehensive serum lipidome profiling of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral. Scler. Frontotemporal. Degener., 21(3-4), 252-262.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fitzgerald, K. C., O'Reilly, E. J., Fondell, E., Falcone, G. J., McCullough, M. L., Park, Y., &#x2026; Ascherio, A. (2013). Intakes of vitamin C and carotenoids and risk of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Pooled results from 5 cohort studies. Annals of Neurology, 73, 236-245. https://doi.org/10.1002/ana.23820</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freedman, D. M., Curtis, R. E., Daugherty, S. E., Goedert, J. J., Kuncl, R. W., &amp; Tucker, M. A. (2013). The association between cancer and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Cancer Causes &amp; Control, 24, 55-60. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10552-012-0089-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freedman, D. M., Travis, L. B., Gridley, G., &amp; Kuncl, R. W. (2005). Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis mortality in 1.9 million US cancer survivors. Neuroepidemiology, 25, 176-180. https://doi.org/10.1159/000087447</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freedman, D. M., Wu, J., Daugherty, S. E., Kuncl, R. W., Enewold, L. R., &amp; Pfeiffer, R. M. (2014). The risk of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis after cancer in U.S. elderly adults: A population-based prospective study. International Journal of Cancer, 135, 1745-1750.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gadoth, A., Nefussy, B., Bleiberg, M., Klein, T., Artman, I., &amp; Drory, V. E. (2015). Transglutaminase 6 antibodies in the serum of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. jama Neurology, 72, 676-681. https://doi.org/10.1001/jamaneurol.2015.48</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallo, V., Wark, P. A., Jenab, M., Pearce, N., Brayne, C., Vermeulen, R., &#x2026; Vineis, P. (2013). Prediagnostic body fat and risk of death from amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: The EPIC cohort. Neurology, 80, 829-838. https://doi.org/10.1212/WNL.0b013e3182840689</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geloso, M. C., Corvino, V., Marchese, E., Serrano, A., Michetti, F., &amp; D'Ambrosi, N. (2017). The dual role of microglia in ALS: Mechanisms and therapeutic approaches. Frontiers in Aging Neuroscience, 9, 1-10. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnagi.2017.00242</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibson, S. B., Abbott, D., Farnham, J. M., Thai, K. K., McLean, H., Figueroa, K. P., &#x2026; Cannon-Albright, L. (2016). Population-based risks for cancer in patients with ALS. Neurology, 87, 289-294. https://doi.org/10.1212/WNL.0000000000002757</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harding, S. D., Sharman, J. L., Faccenda, E., Southan, C., Pawson, A. J., Ireland, S., &#x2026; NC-IUPHAR. (2018). The IUPHAR/BPS Guide to PHARMACOLOGY in 2018: Updates and expansion to encompass the new guide to IMMUNOPHARMACOLOGY. Nucleic Acids Research, 46, D1091-D1106. https://doi.org/10.1093/nar/gkx1121</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holmoy, T. (2008). T cells in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. European Journal of Neurology, 15, 360-366. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1468-1331.2008.02065.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, R., Guo, X., Chen, X., Zheng, Z., Wei, Q., Cao, B., &#x2026; Shang, H. (2015). The serum lipid profiles of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients: A study from south-west China and a meta-analysis. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis and Frontotemporal Degeneration, 16, 359-365. https://doi.org/10.3109/21678421.2015.1047454</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hyder, F., Patel, A. B., Gjedde, A., Rothman, D. L., Behar, K. L., &amp; Shulman, R. G. (2006). Neuronal-glial glucose oxidation and glutamatergic-GABAergic function. Journal of Cerebral Blood Flow and Metabolism, 26, 865-877. https://doi.org/10.1038/sj.jcbfm.9600263</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ismail, A., Cooper-Knock, J., Highley, J. R., Milano, A., Kirby, J., Goodall, E., &#x2026; Shaw, P. J. (2013). Concurrence of multiple sclerosis and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in patients with hexanucleotide repeat expansions of C9ORF72. Journal of Neurology, Neurosurgery, and Psychiatry, 84, 79-87. https://doi.org/10.1136/jnnp-2012-303326</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jesus, P., Fayemendy, P., Nicol, M., Lautrette, G., Sourisseau, H., Preux, P. M., &#x2026; Couratier, P. (2018). Hypermetabolism is a deleterious prognostic factor in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. European Journal of Neurology, 25, 97-104. https://doi.org/10.1111/ene.13468</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasarskis, E. J., Berryman, S., Vanderleest, J. G., Schneider, A. R., &amp; McClain, C. J. (1996). Nutritional status of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Relation to the proximity of death. The American Journal of Clinical Nutrition, 63, 130-137. https://doi.org/10.1093/ajcn/63.1.130</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kioumourtzoglou, M. A., Rotem, R. S., Seals, R. M., Gredal, O., Hansen, J., &amp; Weisskopf, M. G. (2015). Diabetes mellitus, obesity, and diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A population-based study. JAMA Neurology, 72, 905-911. https://doi.org/10.1001/jamaneurol.2015.0910</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuczmarski, T., Stommel, E. W., Riley, K., Tandan, R., Chaudhry, V., Clawson, L., &#x2026; Andrew, A. S. (2017). Medical history of chemotherapy or immunosuppressive drug treatment and risk of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). Journal of Neurology, 264, 1763-1767. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00415-017-8564-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le Masson, G., Przedborski, S., &amp; Abbott, L. F. (2014). A computational model of motor neuron degeneration. Neuron, 83, 975-988. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2014.07.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leese, G. P., Wang, J., Broomhall, J., Kelly, P., Marsden, A., Morrison, W., &#x2026; Morris, A. D. (2003). Frequency of severe hypoglycemia requiring emergency treatment in type 1 and type 2 diabetes: A population-based study of health service resource use. Diabetes Care, 26, 1176-1180. https://doi.org/10.2337/diacare.26.4.1176</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lo, R. Y., Tanner, C. M., Van Den Eeden, S. K., Albers, K. B., Leimpeter, A. D., &amp; Nelson, L. M. (2010). Comorbid cancer in Parkinson's disease. Movement Disorders, 25, 1809-1817. https://doi.org/10.1002/mds.23246</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Logroscino, G., Traynor, B. J., Hardiman, O., Chio, A., Mitchell, D., Swingler, R. J., &#x2026; Beghi, E. (2010). Incidence of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in Europe. Journal of Neurology, Neurosurgery, and Psychiatry, 81, 385-390. https://doi.org/10.1136/jnnp.2009.183525</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mariosa, D., Beard, J. D., Umbach, D. M., Bellocco, R., Keller, J., Peters, T. L., &#x2026; Kamel, F. (2017). Body mass index and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A study of US Military Veterans. American Journal of Epidemiology, 185, 362-371. https://doi.org/10.1093/aje/kww140</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mariosa, D., Kamel, F., Bellocco, R., Ye, W., &amp; Fang, F. (2015). Association between diabetes and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in Sweden. European Journal of Neurology, 22, 1436-1442. https://doi.org/10.1111/ene.12632</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>May, C., Nordhoff, E., Casjens, S., Turewicz, M., Eisenacher, M., Gold, R., &#x2026; Meyer, H. E. (2014). Highly immunoreactive IgG antibodies directed against a set of twenty human proteins in the sera of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis identified by protein array. PLoS ONE, 9, 1-10, e89596. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0089596</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller, R. G., Block, G., Katz, J. S., Barohn, R. J., Gopalakrishnan, V., Cudkowicz, M., &#x2026; Azhir, A. (2015). Randomized phase 2 trial of NP001-a novel immune regulator: Safety and early efficacy in ALS. Neurology-Neuroimmunology Neuroinflammation, 2, 1-9, e100. https://doi.org/10.1212/NXI.0000000000000100</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller, Z. A., Sturm, V. E., Camsari, G. B., Karydas, A., Yokoyama, J. S., Grinberg, L. T., &#x2026; Miller, B. L. (2016). Increased prevalence of autoimmune disease within C9 and FTD/MND cohorts: Completing the picture. Neurology-Neuroimmunology Neuroinflammation, 3, 1-8, e301. https://doi.org/10.1212/NXI.0000000000000301</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moglia, C., Calvo, A., Grassano, M., Canosa, A., Manera, U., D'Ovidio, F., &#x2026; Chio, A. (2019). Early weight loss in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Outcome relevance and clinical correlates in a population-based cohort. Journal of Neurology, Neurosurgery, and Psychiatry, 90, 666-673. https://doi.org/10.1136/jnnp-2018-319611</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakayama, Y., Shimizu, T., Matsuda, C., Haraguchi, M., Hayashi, K., Bokuda, K., &#x2026; Isozaki, E. (2019). Body weight variation predicts disease progression after invasive ventilation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Scientific Reports, 9, 1-9. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-019-48831-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nieves, J. W., Gennings, C., Factor-Litvak, P., Hupf, J., Singleton, J., Sharf, V., &#x2026; Mitsumoto, H. (2016). Association between dietary intake and function in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. JAMA Neurology, 73, 1425-1432. https://doi.org/10.1001/jamaneurol.2016.3401</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noristani, H. N., Sabourin, J. C., Gerber, Y. N., Teigell, M., Sommacal, A., Vivanco, M., &#x2026; Perrin, F. E. (2015). Brca1 is expressed in human microglia and is dysregulated in human and animal model of ALS. Molecular Neurodegeneration, 10, 1-13. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13024-015-0023-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okamoto, K., Kihira, T., Kondo, T., Kobashi, G., Washio, M., Sasaki, S., &#x2026; Nagai, M. (2007). Nutritional status and risk of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in Japan. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis, 8, 300-304. https://doi.org/10.1080/17482960701472249</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Rourke, J. G., Bogdanik, L., Yanez, A., Lall, D., Wolf, A. J., Muhammad, A. K., &#x2026; Baloh, R. H. (2016). C9orf72 is required for proper macrophage and microglial function in mice. Science, 351, 1324-1329. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.aaf1064</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ralli, M., Lambiase, A., Artico, M., de Vincentiis, M., &amp; Greco, A. (2019). Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Autoimmune pathogenic mechanisms, clinical features, and therapeutic perspectives. The Israel Medical Association Journal, 21, 438-443.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rentzos, M., Rombos, A., Nikolaou, C., Zoga, M., Zouvelou, V., Dimitrakopoulos, A., &#x2026; Evdokimidis, J. (2010). Interleukin-17 and interleukin-23 are elevated in serum and cerebrospinal fluid of patients with ALS: A reflection of Th17 cells activation? Acta Neurologica Scandinavica, 122, 425-429. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1600-0404.2010.01333.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riancho, J. (2016). Retinoids and PPAR agonists: Promising partners in neurodegenerative diseases? Free Radic. Biologie et M&#xe9;decine, 97, 616-617.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riancho, J., Berciano, M. T., Berciano, J., &amp; Lafarga, M. (2016). Relaunching an old drug: the potential role of bexarotene in neurodegenerative diseases. Journal of Neurology, 263, 177-178. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00415-015-8004-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riancho, J., Berciano, M. T., Ruiz-Soto, M., Berciano, J., Landreth, G., &amp; Lafarga, M. (2016). Retinoids and motor neuron disease: Potential role in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Journal of the Neurological Sciences, 360, 115-120. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jns.2015.11.058</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riancho, J., Bosque-Varela, P., Perez-Pereda, S., Povedano, M., de Munain, A. L., &amp; Santurtun, A. (2018). The increasing importance of environmental conditions in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. International Journal of Biometeorology, 62, 1361-1374. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00484-018-1550-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riancho, J., Gil-Bea, F. J., Castanedo-Vazquez, D., Sedano, M. J., Zufiria, M., de Eulate, G. F. G., &#x2026; de Munain, A. L. (2018). Clinical evidences supporting the Src/c-Abl pathway as potential therapeutic target in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Journal of the Neurological Sciences, 393, 80-82. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jns.2018.08.013</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riancho, J., Gil-Bea, F. J., Santurtun, A., &amp; de Muna&#xed;n, A. L. (2019). Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A complex syndrome that needs an integrated research approach. Neural Regeneration Research, 14, 193-196. https://doi.org/10.4103/1673-5374.244783</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riancho, J., Gonzalo, I., Ruiz-Soto, M., &amp; Berciano, J. (2019). Why do motor neurons degenerate? Actualization in the pathogenesis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurolog&#xed;a, 34, 27-37. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nrl.2015.12.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riancho, J., Lozano-Cuesta, P., Santurtun, A., Sanchez-Juan, P., Lopez-Vega, J. M., Berciano, J., &amp; Polo, J. M. (2016). Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in Northern Spain 40 years later: What has changed? Neurodegenerative Diseases, 16, 337-341. https://doi.org/10.1159/000445750</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riancho, J., Ruiz-Soto, M., Berciano, M. T., Berciano, J., &amp; Lafarga, M. (2015). Neuroprotective effect of bexarotene in the SOD1(G93A) mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Frontiers in Cellulassr Neuroscience, 9, 1-17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seelen, M., van Doormaal, P. T., Visser, A. E., Huisman, M. H., Roozekrans, M. H., de Jong, S. W., &#x2026; van den Berg, L. H. (2014). Prior medical conditions and the risk of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Journal of Neurology, 261, 1949-1956. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00415-014-7445-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serrano, A., Apolloni, S., Rossi, S., Lattante, S., Sabatelli, M., Peric, M., &#x2026; D'Ambrosi, N. (2019). The S100A4 Transcriptional Inhibitor Niclosamide Reduces Pro-Inflammatory and Migratory Phenotypes of Microglia: Implications for Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. Cell, 8, 1-19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah, P. P., Lockwood, W. W., Saurabh, K., Kurlawala, Z., Shannon, S. P., Waigel, S., &#x2026; Beverly, L. J. (2015). Ubiquilin1 represses migration and epithelial-to-mesenchymal transition of human non-small cell lung cancer cells. Oncogene, 34, 1709-1717. https://doi.org/10.1038/onc.2014.97</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sivandzade, F., Bhalerao, A., &amp; Cucullo, L. (2019). Cerebrovascular and neurological disorders: Protective role of NRF2. International Journal of Molecular Sciences, 20, 1-21. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms20143433</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stallings, N. R., Puttaparthi, K., Dowling, K. J., Luther, C. M., Burns, D. K., Davis, K., &amp; Elliott, J. L. (2013). TDP-43, an ALS linked protein, regulates fat deposition and glucose homeostasis. PLoS ONE, 8, 1-14, e71793. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0071793</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steyn, F. J., Ioannides, Z. A., van Eijk, R. P. A., Heggie, S., Thorpe, K. A., Ceslis, A., &#x2026; Ngo, S. T. (2018). Hypermetabolism in ALS is associated with greater functional decline and shorter survival. Journal of Neurology, Neurosurgery, and Psychiatry, 89, 1016-1023. https://doi.org/10.1136/jnnp-2017-317887</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudria-Lopez, E., Koppers, M., de Wit, M., van der Meer, C., Westeneng, H. J., Zundel, C. A., &#x2026; van Den Berg, L. H. (2016). Full ablation of C9orf72 in mice causes immune system-related pathology and neoplastic events but no motor neuron defects. Acta Neuropathologica, 132, 145-147. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00401-016-1581-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner, M. R., Goldacre, R., Ramagopalan, S., Talbot, K., &amp; Goldacre, M. J. (2013). Autoimmune disease preceding amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: An epidemiologic study. Neurology, 81, 1222-1225. https://doi.org/10.1212/WNL.0b013e3182a6cc13</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner, M. R., &amp; Talbot, K. (2013). Mimics and chameleons in motor neurone disease. Practical Neurology, 13, 153-164. https://doi.org/10.1136/practneurol-2013-000557</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaisman, N., Lusaus, M., Nefussy, B., Niv, E., Comaneshter, D., Hallack, R., &amp; Drory, V. E. (2009). Do patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) have increased energy needs? Journal of the Neurological Sciences, 279, 26-29. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jns.2008.12.027</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamamoto, I., Azuma, Y., &amp; Yamaguchi, M. (2019). Cancer-related genes and ALS. Frontiers in Bioscience (Landmark Edition), 24, 1241-1258.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng, P., Yu, X., &amp; Xu, H. (2019). Association between premorbid body mass index and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Causal inference through genetic approaches. Frontiers in Neurology, 10, 1-10. https://doi.org/10.3389/fneur.2019.00543</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, H., Liu, Y., Li, Z., Liang, N., Zhou, X., Nie, X., &#x2026; Qi, W. (2019). Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and primary biliary cirrhosis overlap syndrome: Two cases report. Frontiers in Neurology, 10, 1-6. https://doi.org/10.3389/fneur.2019.00890</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zufiria, M., Gil-Bea, F. J., Fernandez-Torron, R., Poza, J. J., Munoz-Blanco, J. L., Rojas-Garcia, R., &#x2026; de Munain, A. L. (2016). ALS: A bucket of genes, environment, metabolism and unknown ingredients. Progress in Neurobiology, 142, 104-129. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pneurobio.2016.05.004</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>