<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">32501947</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>09</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1537-1603</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>38</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of clinical neurophysiology : official publication of the American Electroencephalographic Society</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Clin Neurophysiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Corticomotor Excitability in Two Kinds of Motor Neuron Diseases: A Study on the Patients With Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis and Poliomyelitis Survivors.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>448</StartPage><EndPage>455</EndPage><MedlinePgn>448-455</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/WNP.0000000000000707</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To examine upper motor neuron functions comparatively in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) and poliomyelitis survivors using transcranial magnetic stimulation (TMS) methods.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Single- and paired-pulse TMS with conventional methods and the triple-stimulation technique were performed by recording from the abductor digiti minimi and abductor pollicis brevis muscles in 31 patients with ALS, 18 patients with poliomyelitis survivors, and 21 controls. Nine patients were diagnosed as having postpoliomyelitis syndrome after a 6-month follow-up.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Triple-stimulation technique and some of conventional TMS studies were able to distinguish ALS from both poliomyelitis survivors and controls. A reduced ipsilateral silent period in abductor pollicis brevis muscles was the only parameter to show a significant difference when comparing thenar and hypothenar muscles in ALS. No significant difference was present in any TMS parameters between the postpoliomyelitis syndrome and non-postpoliomyelitis syndrome groups.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Conventional TMS and particularly triple-stimulation technique studies are helpful in disclosing upper motor neuron dysfunction in ALS. The results of this study might favor the cortical hypothesis for split hand in ALS, but they revealed no significant indication for upper motor neuron dysfunction in postpoliomyelitis syndrome.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2020 by the American Clinical Neurophysiology Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sirin</LastName><ForeName>Nermin Gorkem</ForeName><Initials>NG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Istanbul Faculty of Medicine, Istanbul University, Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Erbas</LastName><ForeName>Bahar</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacology, Faculty of Medicine, Istanbul Bilim University, Istanbul, Turkey; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oguz-Akarsu</LastName><ForeName>Emel</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Istanbul Faculty of Medicine, Istanbul University, Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gula</LastName><ForeName>Gulsah</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, Istanbul Faculty of Medicine, Istanbul University, Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kocasoy-Orhan</LastName><ForeName>Elif</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Istanbul Faculty of Medicine, Istanbul University, Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dede</LastName><ForeName>Hava Ozlem</ForeName><Initials>HO</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Istanbul Faculty of Medicine, Istanbul University, Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Baslo</LastName><ForeName>Mehmet Baris</ForeName><Initials>MB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Istanbul Faculty of Medicine, Istanbul University, Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Idrisoglu</LastName><ForeName>Halil Atilla</ForeName><Initials>HA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Istanbul Faculty of Medicine, Istanbul University, Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ketenci</LastName><ForeName>Aysegul</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, Istanbul Faculty of Medicine, Istanbul University, Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oge</LastName><ForeName>Ali Emre</ForeName><Initials>AE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Istanbul Faculty of Medicine, Istanbul University, Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Clin Neurophysiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8506708</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0736-0258</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019054" MajorTopicYN="N">Evoked Potentials, Motor</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006225" MajorTopicYN="N">Hand</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016472" MajorTopicYN="Y">Motor Neuron Disease</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011051" MajorTopicYN="Y">Poliomyelitis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017741" MajorTopicYN="N">Survivors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D050781" MajorTopicYN="N">Transcranial Magnetic Stimulation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors have no funding or conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32501947</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/WNP.0000000000000707</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00004691-202109000-00015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Eisen A, Pant B, Stewart H. Cortical excitability in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a clue to pathogenesis. Can J Neurol Sci 1993;20:11&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S, Kiernan MC. Utility of transcranial magnetic stimulation in delineating amyotrophic lateral sclerosis pathophysiology. Handb Clin Neurol 2013;116:561&#x2013;575.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S, Nicholson GA, Kiernan MC. Cortical hyperexcitability may precede the onset of familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain 2008;131:1540&#x2013;1550.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S, Kiernan MC. Cortical excitability testing distinguishes Kennedy's disease from amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Neurophysiol 2008;119:1088&#x2013;1096.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Attarian S, Azulay JP, Lardillier D, Verschueren A, Pouget J. Transcranial magnetic stimulation in lower motor neuron diseases. Clin Neurophysiol 2005;116:35&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S, Ziemann U, Eisen A, Hallett M, Kiernan MC. Transcranial magnetic stimulation and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: pathophysiological insights. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2013;84:1161&#x2013;1170.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S, Rutkove SB. Neurophysiological biomarkers in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Curr Opin Neurol 2018;31:640&#x2013;647.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pouget J, Trefouret S, Attarian S. Transcranial magnetic stimulation (TMS): compared sensitivity of different motor response parameters in ALS. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Mot Neuron Disord 2000;1suppl 2:S45&#x2013;S49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchthal F, Pinelli P. Action potentials in muscular atrophy of neurogenic origin. Neurology 1953;3:591&#x2013;603.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bodian D. Poliomyelitis; neuropathologic observations in relation to motor symptoms. J Am Med Assoc 1947;134:1148&#x2013;1154.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabin AB, Ward R. The natural history of human poliomyelitis: I. Distribution of virus in nervous and non-nervous tissues. J Exp Med 1941;73:771&#x2013;793.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruno RL, Sapolsky R, Zimmerman JR, Frick NM. Pathophysiology of a central cause of post-polio fatigue. Ann N Y Acad Sci 1995;753:257&#x2013;275.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bodian D, Howe HA. Non-paralytic poliomyelitis in the chimpanzee. J Exp Med 1945;81:255&#x2013;274.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lupu VD, Danielian L, Johnsen JA, et al. Physiology of the motor cortex in polio survivors. Muscle Nerve 2008;37:177&#x2013;182.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliveri M, Brighina F, La Bua V, Buffa D, Aloisio A, Fierro B. Reorganization of cortical motor area in prior polio patients. Clin Neurophysiol 1999;110:806&#x2013;812.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allen GM, Gandevia AS, Middleton J. Quantitative assessments of elbow flexor muscle performance using twitch interpolation in post-polio patients: no evidence for deterioration. Brain 1997;120(pt 4):663&#x2013;672.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trojan DA, Cashman NR. Post-poliomyelitis syndrome. Muscle Nerve 2005;31:6&#x2013;19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jubelt B. Post-polio syndrome. Curr Treat Options Neurol 2004;6:87&#x2013;93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez H, Olsson T, Borg K. Management of postpolio syndrome. Lancet Neurol 2010;9:634&#x2013;642.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farbu E, Gilhus NE, Barnes MP, et al. EFNS guideline on diagnosis and management of post-polio syndrome. Report of an EFNS task force. Eur J Neurol 2006;13:795&#x2013;801.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gandevia SC, Allen GM, Middleton J. Post-polio syndrome: assessments, pathophysiology and progression. Disabil Rehabil 2000;22:38&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sunnerhagen KS, Carlsson U, Sandberg A, Stalberg E, Hedberg M, Grimby G. Electrophysiologic evaluation of muscle fatigue development and recovery in late polio. Arch Phys Med Rehabil 2000;81:770&#x2013;776.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Dengler R, Eisen A, et al. Electrodiagnostic criteria for diagnosis of ALS. Clin Neurophysiol 2008;119:497&#x2013;503.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum JM, Stambler N, Malta E, et al. The ALSFRS-R: a revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. BDNF ALS Study Group (Phase III). J Neurol Sci 1999;169:13&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner MR, Cagnin A, Turkheimer FE, et al. Evidence of widespread cerebral microglial activation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: an [11C](R)-PK11195 positron emission tomography study. Neurobiol Dis 2004;15:601&#x2013;609.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noymer A. The march of dimes. Am J Public Health 2002;92:158.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kleyweg RP, van der Meche FG, Schmitz PI. Interobserver agreement in the assessment of muscle strength and functional abilities in Guillain-Barre syndrome. Muscle Nerve 1991;14:1103&#x2013;1109.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuwabara S, Sonoo M, Komori T, et al. Dissociated small hand muscle atrophy in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: frequency, extent, and specificity. Muscle Nerve 2008;37:426&#x2013;430.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossini PM, Barker AT, Berardelli A, et al. Non-invasive electrical and magnetic stimulation of the brain, spinal cord and roots: basic principles and procedures for routine clinical application. Report of an IFCN committee. Electroencephalogr Clin Neurophysiol 1994;91:79&#x2013;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossini PM, Burke D, Chen R, et al. Non-invasive electrical and magnetic stimulation of the brain, spinal cord, roots and peripheral nerves: basic principles and procedures for routine clinical and research application. An updated report from an I.F.C.N. Committee. Clin Neurophysiol 2015;126:1071&#x2013;1107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wittstock M, Wolters A, Benecke R. Transcallosal inhibition in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Neurophysiol 2007;118:301&#x2013;307.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orhan EK, Yayla V, Cebeci Z, Baslo MB, Oval&#x131; T, &#xd6;ge AE. Excitability changes at brainstem and cortical levels in blind subjects. Clin Neurophysiol 2011;122:1827&#x2013;1833.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magistris MR, Rosler KM, Truffert A, Myers JP. Transcranial stimulation excites virtually all motor neurons supplying the target muscle. A demonstration and a method improving the study of motor evoked potentials. Brain 1998;121(pt 3):437&#x2013;450.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komissarow L, Rollnik JD, Bogdanova D, et al. Triple stimulation technique (TST) in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Neurophysiol 2004;115:356&#x2013;360.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosler KM, Truffert A, Hess CW, Magistris MR. Quantification of upper motor neuron loss in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Neurophysiol 2000;111:2208&#x2013;2218.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Wang H, Cui LY. Triple stimulation technique in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Clin Neurophysiol 2019;36:87&#x2013;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van den Bos MAJ, Higashihara M, Geevasinga N, Menon P, Kiernan MC, Vucic S. Imbalance of cortical facilitatory and inhibitory circuits underlies hyperexcitability in ALS. Neurology 2018;91:e1669&#x2013;e1676.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shibuya K, Park SB, Geevasinga N, et al. Motor cortical function determines prognosis in sporadic ALS. Neurology 2016;87:513&#x2013;520.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menon P, Kiernan MC, Vucic S. Cortical dysfunction underlies the development of the split-hand in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. PLoS One 2014;9:e87124.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eisen A, Kuwabara S. The split hand syndrome in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2012;83:399&#x2013;403.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eisen A, Kim S, Pant B. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS): a phylogenetic disease of the corticomotoneuron? Muscle Nerve 1992;15:219&#x2013;224.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bae JS, Sawai S, Misawa S, Kanai K, Isose S, Kuwabara S. Differences in excitability properties of FDI and ADM motor axons. Muscle Nerve 2009;39:350&#x2013;354.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer BU, Roricht S, Grafin von Einsiedel H, Kruggel F, Weindl A. Inhibitory and excitatory interhemispheric transfers between motor cortical areas in normal humans and patients with abnormalities of the corpus callosum. Brain 1995;118(pt 2):429&#x2013;440.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karandreas N, Papadopoulou M, Kokotis P, Papapostolou A, Tsivgoulis G, Zambelis T. Impaired interhemispheric inhibition in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler 2007;8:112&#x2013;118.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wittstock M, Meister S, Walter U, Benecke R, Wolters A. Mirror movements in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler 2011;12:393&#x2013;397.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ford DJ, Ropka SL, Collins GH, Jubelt B. The neuropathology observed in wild-type mice inoculated with human poliovirus mirrors human paralytic poliomyelitis. Microb Pathog 2002;33:97&#x2013;107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allen GM, Gandevia SC, Neering IR, Hickie I, Jones R, Middleton J. Muscle performance, voluntary activation and perceived effort in normal subjects and patients with prior poliomyelitis. Brain 1994;117(pt 4):661&#x2013;670.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trojan DA, Gendron D, Cashman NR. Electrophysiology and electrodiagnosis of the post-polio motor unit. Orthopedics 1991;14:1353&#x2013;1361.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiechers DO, Hubbell SL. Late changes in the motor unit after acute poliomyelitis. Muscle Nerve 1981;4:524&#x2013;528.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>