<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">32593977</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>25</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2213-1582</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>27</Volume><PubDate><Year>2020</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>NeuroImage. Clinical</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Neuroimage Clin</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Structural MRI outcomes and predictors of disease progression in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>102315</StartPage><MedlinePgn>102315</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">102315</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.nicl.2020.102315</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S2213-1582(20)30152-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND AIMS">Considering the great heterogeneity of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS), the identification of accurate prognostic predictors is fundamental for both the clinical practice and the design of treatment trials. This study aimed to explore the progression of clinical and structural brain changes in patients with ALS, and to assess magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) measures of brain damage as predictors of subsequent functional decline.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">50 ALS patients underwent clinical evaluations and 3&#xa0;T MRI scans at regular intervals for a maximum of 2&#xa0;years (total MRI scans&#xa0;=&#xa0;164). MRI measures of cortical thickness, as well as diffusion tensor (DT) metrics of microstructural damage along white matter (WM) tracts were obtained. Voxel-wise regression models and longitudinal mixed-effects models were used to test the relationship between clinical decline and baseline and longitudinal MRI features.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">The rate of decline of the ALS Functional Rating Scale revised (ALSFRS-r) was significantly associated with the rate of fractional anisotropy (FA) decrease in the body of the corpus callosum (CC). Corticospinal tract (CST) and CC-body alterations had a faster progression in patients with higher baseline ALSFRS-r scores and greater CC-body disruption at baseline. Lower FA of the cerebral peduncle was associated with faster subsequent clinical progression.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">In this longitudinal study, we identified a significant association between measures of WM damage of the motor tracts and functional decline in ALS patients. Our data suggest that a multiparametric approach including DT MRI measures of brain damage would provide an optimal method for an accurate stratification of ALS patients into prognostic classes.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2020 The Author(s). Published by Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Spinelli</LastName><ForeName>Edoardo G</ForeName><Initials>EG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neuroimaging Research Unit, Institute of Experimental Neurology, Division of Neuroscience, IRCCS San Raffaele Scientific Institute, Milan, Italy; Neurology Unit, IRCCS San Raffaele Scientific Institute, Milan, Italy; Vita-Salute San Raffaele University, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Riva</LastName><ForeName>Nilo</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurorehabilitation Unit, IRCCS San Raffaele Scientific Institute, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rancoita</LastName><ForeName>Paola M V</ForeName><Initials>PMV</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University Centre for Statistics in the Biomedical Sciences (CUSSB), Vita-Salute San Raffaele University, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schito</LastName><ForeName>Paride</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurology Unit, IRCCS San Raffaele Scientific Institute, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Doretti</LastName><ForeName>Alberto</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology and Laboratory of Neuroscience, IRCCS Istituto Auxologico Italiano, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Poletti</LastName><ForeName>Barbara</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology and Laboratory of Neuroscience, IRCCS Istituto Auxologico Italiano, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Di Serio</LastName><ForeName>Clelia</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University Centre for Statistics in the Biomedical Sciences (CUSSB), Vita-Salute San Raffaele University, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Silani</LastName><ForeName>Vincenzo</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology and Laboratory of Neuroscience, IRCCS Istituto Auxologico Italiano, Milan, Italy; "Dino Ferrari" Center, Department of Pathophysiology and Transplantation, Universit&#xe0; degli Studi di Milano, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Filippi</LastName><ForeName>Massimo</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neuroimaging Research Unit, Institute of Experimental Neurology, Division of Neuroscience, IRCCS San Raffaele Scientific Institute, Milan, Italy; Neurology Unit, IRCCS San Raffaele Scientific Institute, Milan, Italy; Neurophysiology Unit, IRCCS San Raffaele Scientific Institute, Milan, Italy; Vita-Salute San Raffaele University, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Agosta</LastName><ForeName>Federica</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neuroimaging Research Unit, Institute of Experimental Neurology, Division of Neuroscience, IRCCS San Raffaele Scientific Institute, Milan, Italy; Vita-Salute San Raffaele University, Milan, Italy. Electronic address: agosta.federica@hsr.it.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Neuroimage Clin</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101597070</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2213-1582</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D056324" MajorTopicYN="N">Diffusion Tensor Imaging</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018450" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Progression</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008137" MajorTopicYN="N">Longitudinal Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008279" MajorTopicYN="N">Magnetic Resonance Imaging</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011712" MajorTopicYN="N">Pyramidal Tracts</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cortical thickness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Diffusion tensor MRI</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Prognosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Structural MRI</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of Competing Interest The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32593977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7327879</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nicl.2020.102315</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2213-1582(20)30152-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Agosta F., Galantucci S., Canu E., Cappa S.F., Magnani G., Franceschi M., Falini A., Comi G., Filippi M. Disruption of structural connectivity along the dorsal and ventral language pathways in patients with nonfluent and semantic variant primary progressive aphasia: a DT MRI study and a literature review. Brain Lang. 2013;127:157&#x2013;166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23890877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agosta F., Galantucci S., Riva N., Chio A., Messina S., Iannaccone S., Calvo A., Silani V., Copetti M., Falini A., Comi G., Filippi M. Intrahemispheric and interhemispheric structural network abnormalities in PLS and ALS. Hum Brain Mapp. 2014;35:1710&#x2013;1722.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6869498</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23633431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agosta F., Rocca M.A., Valsasina P., Sala S., Caputo D., Perini M., Salvi F., Prelle A., Filippi M. A longitudinal diffusion tensor MRI study of the cervical cord and brain in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2009;80:53&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18931009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agosta F., Spinelli E.G., Filippi M. Neuroimaging in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: current and emerging uses. Expert Rev Neurother. 2018;18:395&#x2013;406.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29630421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agosta F., Spinelli E.G., Riva N., Fontana A., Basaia S., Canu E., Castelnovo V., Falzone Y., Carrera P., Comi G., Filippi M. Survival prediction models in motor neuron disease. Eur J Neurol. 2019;26:1143&#x2013;1152.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30920076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bede P., Elamin M., Byrne S., Hardiman O. Sexual dimorphism in ALS: exploring gender-specific neuroimaging signatures. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2014;15:235&#x2013;243.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24344910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bede P., Hardiman O. Longitudinal structural changes in ALS: a three time-point imaging study of white and gray matter degeneration. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2018;19:232&#x2013;241.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29214883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernal-Rusiel J.L., Reuter M., Greve D.N., Fischl B., Sabuncu M.R., Neuroimaging Alzheimer's Disease, I Spatiotemporal linear mixed effects modeling for the mass-univariate analysis of longitudinal neuroimage data. Neuroimage. 2013;81:358&#x2013;370.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3816382</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23702413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brettschneider J., Del Tredici K., Toledo J.B., Robinson J.L., Irwin D.J., Grossman M., Suh E., Van Deerlin V.M., Wood E.M., Baek Y., Kwong L., Lee E.B., Elman L., McCluskey L., Fang L., Feldengut S., Ludolph A.C., Lee V.M., Braak H., Trojanowski J.Q. Stages of pTDP-43 pathology in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol. 2013;74:20&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3785076</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23686809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks, B.R., Miller, R.G., Swash, M., Munsat, T.L., World Federation of Neurology Research Group on Motor Neuron, D., 2000. El Escorial revisited: revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord 1, 293-299.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11464847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calvo A., Moglia C., Lunetta C., Marinou K., Ticozzi N., Ferrante G.D., Scialo C., Soraru G., Trojsi F., Conte A., Falzone Y.M., Tortelli R., Russo M., Chio A., Sansone V.A., Mora G., Silani V., Volanti P., Caponnetto C., Querin G., Monsurro M.R., Sabatelli M., Riva N., Logroscino G., Messina S., Fini N., Mandrioli J. Factors predicting survival in ALS: a multicenter Italian study. J Neurol. 2017;264:54&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27778156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardenas-Blanco A., Machts J., Acosta-Cabronero J., Kaufmann J., Abdulla S., Kollewe K., Petri S., Schreiber S., Heinze H.J., Dengler R., Vielhaber S., Nestor P.J. Structural and diffusion imaging versus clinical assessment to monitor amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuroimage Clin. 2016;11:408&#x2013;414.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4827722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27104135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum J.M., Stambler N., Malta E., Fuller C., Hilt D., Thurmond B., Nakanishi A. The ALSFRS-R: a revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. BDNF ALS Study Group (Phase III) J Neurol Sci. 1999;169:13&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10540002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chio A., Moglia C., Canosa A., Manera U., D'Ovidio F., Vasta R., Grassano M., Brunetti M., Barberis M., Corrado L., D'Alfonso S., Iazzolino B., Peotta L., Sarnelli M.F., Solara V., Zucchetti J.P., De Marchi F., Mazzini L., Mora G., Calvo A. ALS phenotype is influenced by age, sex, and genetics: A population-based study. Neurology. 2020;94:e802&#x2013;e810.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31907290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dale A.M., Fischl B., Sereno M.I. Cortical surface-based analysis. I. Segmentation and surface reconstruction. Neuroimage. 1999;9:179&#x2013;194.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9931268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Albuquerque M., Branco L.M., Rezende T.J., de Andrade H.M., Nucci A., Franca M.C., Jr. Longitudinal evaluation of cerebral and spinal cord damage in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. Neuroimage Clin. 2017;14:269&#x2013;276.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5294732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28203530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fischl B., Dale A.M. Measuring the thickness of the human cerebral cortex from magnetic resonance images. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2000;97:11050&#x2013;11055.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC27146</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10984517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Folstein M.F., Folstein S.E., McHugh P.R. &#x201c;Mini-mental state&#x201d;. A practical method for grading the cognitive state of patients for the clinician. J Psychiatr Res. 1975;12:189&#x2013;198.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1202204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horsfield M.A. Mapping eddy current induced fields for the correction of diffusion-weighted echo planar images. Magn Reson Imaging. 1999;17:1335&#x2013;1345.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10576719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hua K., Zhang J., Wakana S., Jiang H., Li X., Reich D.S., Calabresi P.A., Pekar J.J., van Zijl P.C., Mori S. Tract probability maps in stereotaxic spaces: analyses of white matter anatomy and tract-specific quantification. Neuroimage. 2008;39:336&#x2013;347.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2724595</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17931890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kassubek J., Muller H.P., Del Tredici K., Lule D., Gorges M., Braak H., Ludolph A.C. Imaging the pathoanatomy of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in vivo: targeting a propagation-based biological marker. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2018;89:374&#x2013;381.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5869447</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29101254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keil C., Prell T., Peschel T., Hartung V., Dengler R., Grosskreutz J. Longitudinal diffusion tensor imaging in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. BMC Neurosci. 2012;13:141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3531302</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23134591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiernan M.C., Vucic S., Cheah B.C., Turner M.R., Eisen A., Hardiman O., Burrell J.R., Zoing M.C. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet. 2011;377:942&#x2013;955.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21296405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwan J.Y., Meoded A., Danielian L.E., Wu T., Floeter M.K. Structural imaging differences and longitudinal changes in primary lateral sclerosis and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuroimage Clin. 2012;2:151&#x2013;160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3778247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24179768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandelli M.L., Berger M.S., Bucci M., Berman J.I., Amirbekian B., Henry R.G. Quantifying accuracy and precision of diffusion MR tractography of the corticospinal tract in brain tumors. J Neurosurg. 2014;121:349&#x2013;358.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24905560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menke R.A., Agosta F., Grosskreutz J., Filippi M., Turner M.R. Neuroimaging Endpoints in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. Neurotherapeutics. 2017;14:11&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5233627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27752938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menke R.A.L., Proudfoot M., Talbot K., Turner M.R. The two-year progression of structural and functional cerebral MRI in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuroimage Clin. 2018;17:953&#x2013;961.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5752097</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29321969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muller, H.P., Turner, M.R., Grosskreutz, J., Abrahams, S., Bede, P., Govind, V., Prudlo, J., Ludolph, A.C., Filippi, M., Kassubek, J., Neuroimaging Society in, A.L.S.D.T.I.S.G., 2016. A large-scale multicentre cerebral diffusion tensor imaging study in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 87, 570-579.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26746186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Novelli, G., Papagno, C., Capitani, E., Laiacona, M., Vallar, G., Cappa, S., 1986. Tre test clinici di ricerca e produzione lessicale. Taratura su soggetti normali. Archivio di Psicologia, Neurologia e Psichiatria. oct-dec; vol 47 (4) : 477-506.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Dwyer L., Lamberton F., Bokde A.L., Ewers M., Faluyi Y.O., Tanner C., Mazoyer B., O'Neill D., Bartley M., Collins R., Coughlan T., Prvulovic D., Hampel H. Sexual dimorphism in healthy aging and mild cognitive impairment: a DTI study. PLoS One. 2012;7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3388101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22768288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rascovsky K., Hodges J.R., Knopman D., Mendez M.F., Kramer J.H., Neuhaus J., van Swieten J.C., Seelaar H., Dopper E.G., Onyike C.U., Hillis A.E., Josephs K.A., Boeve B.F., Kertesz A., Seeley W.W., Rankin K.P., Johnson J.K., Gorno-Tempini M.L., Rosen H., Prioleau-Latham C.E., Lee A., Kipps C.M., Lillo P., Piguet O., Rohrer J.D., Rossor M.N., Warren J.D., Fox N.C., Galasko D., Salmon D.P., Black S.E., Mesulam M., Weintraub S., Dickerson B.C., Diehl-Schmid J., Pasquier F., Deramecourt V., Lebert F., Pijnenburg Y., Chow T.W., Manes F., Grafman J., Cappa S.F., Freedman M., Grossman M., Miller B.L. Sensitivity of revised diagnostic criteria for the behavioural variant of frontotemporal dementia. Brain. 2011;134:2456&#x2013;2477.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3170532</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21810890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rathee R., Rallabandi V.P., Roy P.K. Age-Related Differences in White Matter Integrity in Healthy Human Brain: Evidence from Structural MRI and Diffusion Tensor Imaging. Magn Reson Insights. 2016;9:9&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4898444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27279747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reuter M., Schmansky N.J., Rosas H.D., Fischl B. Within-subject template estimation for unbiased longitudinal image analysis. Neuroimage. 2012;61:1402&#x2013;1418.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3389460</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22430496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuster C., Elamin M., Hardiman O., Bede P. The segmental diffusivity profile of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis associated white matter degeneration. Eur J Neurol. 2016;23:1361&#x2013;1371.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27207250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuster C., Hardiman O., Bede P. Survival prediction in Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis based on MRI measures and clinical characteristics. BMC Neurol. 2017;17:73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5393027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28412941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuster C., Kasper E., Machts J., Bittner D., Kaufmann J., Benecke R., Teipel S., Vielhaber S., Prudlo J. Longitudinal course of cortical thickness decline in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol. 2014;261:1871&#x2013;1880.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25022938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spinelli E.G., Agosta F., Ferraro P.M., Riva N., Lunetta C., Falzone Y.M., Comi G., Falini A., Filippi M. Brain MR Imaging in Patients with Lower Motor Neuron-Predominant Disease. Radiology. 2016;280:545&#x2013;556.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26963576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steinbach R., Loewe K., Kaufmann J., Machts J., Kollewe K., Petri S., Dengler R., Heinze H.J., Vielhaber S., Schoenfeld M.A., Stoppel C.M. Structural hallmarks of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis progression revealed by probabilistic fiber tractography. J Neurol. 2015;262:2257&#x2013;2270.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26159103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner M.R., Cagnin A., Turkheimer F.E., Miller C.C., Shaw C.E., Brooks D.J., Leigh P.N., Banati R.B. Evidence of widespread cerebral microglial activation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: an [11C](R)-PK11195 positron emission tomography study. Neurobiol Dis. 2004;15:601&#x2013;609.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15056468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Burgh H.K., Schmidt R., Westeneng H.J., de Reus M.A., van den Berg L.H., van den Heuvel M.P. Deep learning predictions of survival based on MRI in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuroimage Clin. 2017;13:361&#x2013;369.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5219634</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28070484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Graaff M.M., Sage C.A., Caan M.W., Akkerman E.M., Lavini C., Majoie C.B., Nederveen A.J., Zwinderman A.H., Vos F., Brugman F., van den Berg L.H., de Rijk M.C., van Doorn P.A., Van Hecke W., Peeters R.R., Robberecht W., Sunaert S., de Visser M. Upper and extra-motoneuron involvement in early motoneuron disease: a diffusion tensor imaging study. Brain. 2011;134:1211&#x2013;1228.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21362631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verstraete E., van den Heuvel M.P., Veldink J.H., Blanken N., Mandl R.C., Hulshoff Pol H.E., van den Berg L.H. Motor network degeneration in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a structural and functional connectivity study. PLoS One. 2010;5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2965124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21060689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verstraete E., Veldink J.H., van den Berg L.H., van den Heuvel M.P. Structural brain network imaging shows expanding disconnection of the motor system in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Hum Brain Mapp. 2014;35:1351&#x2013;1361.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6869230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23450820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>