<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">32654149</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>12</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-4159</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>156</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of neurochemistry</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Neurochem</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Pathogenic or protective? Neuropeptide Y in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>273</StartPage><EndPage>289</EndPage><MedlinePgn>273-289</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/jnc.15125</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Neuropeptide Y (NPY) is an endogenous peptide of the central and enteric nervous systems which has gained significant interest as a potential neuroprotective agent for treatment of neurodegenerative disease. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) is an aggressive and fatal neurodegenerative disease characterized by motor deficits and motor neuron loss. In ALS, recent evidence from ALS patients and animal models has indicated that NPY may have a role in the disease pathogenesis. Increased NPY levels were found to correlate with disease progression in ALS patients. Similarly, NPY expression is increased in the motor cortex of ALS mice by end stages of the disease. Although the functional consequence of increased NPY levels in ALS is currently unknown, NPY has been shown to exert a diverse range of neuroprotective roles in other neurodegenerative diseases; through modulation of potassium channel activity, increased production of neurotrophins, inhibition of endoplasmic reticulum stress and autophagy, reduction of excitotoxicity, oxidative stress, neuroinflammation and hyperexcitability. Several of these mechanisms and signalling pathways are heavily implicated in the pathogenesis of ALS. Therefore, in this review, we discuss possible effects of NPY and NPY-receptor signalling in the ALS disease context, as determining NPY's contribution to, or impact on, ALS disease mechanisms will be essential for future studies investigating the NPY system as a therapeutic strategy in this devastating disease.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020 International Society for Neurochemistry.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Clark</LastName><ForeName>Courtney M</ForeName><Initials>CM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0714-1063</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Menzies Institute for Medical Research, College of Health and Medicine, University of Tasmania, Hobart, TAS, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Clark</LastName><ForeName>Rosemary M</ForeName><Initials>RM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6156-6671</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Menzies Institute for Medical Research, College of Health and Medicine, University of Tasmania, Hobart, TAS, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hoyle</LastName><ForeName>Joshua A</ForeName><Initials>JA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Menzies Institute for Medical Research, College of Health and Medicine, University of Tasmania, Hobart, TAS, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dickson</LastName><ForeName>Tracey C</ForeName><Initials>TC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9196-1661</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Menzies Institute for Medical Research, College of Health and Medicine, University of Tasmania, Hobart, TAS, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Neurochem</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>2985190R</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0022-3042</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D009478">Neuropeptide Y</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D017476">Receptors, Neuropeptide Y</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009478" MajorTopicYN="N">Neuropeptide Y</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017476" MajorTopicYN="N">Receptors, Neuropeptide Y</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">interneurons</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neurodegeneration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neuropeptide Y</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neuroprotection</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32654149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jnc.15125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Abe, K., Itoyama, Y., Sobue, G., Tsuji, S., Aoki, M., Doyu, M., &#x2026; Yoshino, H. (2014). Confirmatory double-blind, parallel-group, placebo-controlled study of efficacy and safety of edaravone (MCI-186) in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis and Frontotemporal Degeneration, 15, 610-617. https://doi.org/10.3109/21678421.2014.959024</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abramzon, Y. A., Fratta, P., Traynor, B. J., &amp; Chia, R. (2020). The overlapping genetics of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal dementia. Frontiers in Neuroscience, 14, 42. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnins.2020.00042</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adrian, T. E., Allen, J. M., Bloom, S. R., Ghatei, M. A., Rossor, M. N., Roberts, G. W., &#x2026; Polak, J. M. (1983). Neuropeptide Y distribution in human brain. Nature, 306, 584-586. https://doi.org/10.1038/306584a0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed, R. M., Phan, K., Highton-Williamson, E., Strikwerda-Brown, C., Caga, J., Ramsey, E., &#x2026; Kiernan, M. C. (2019). Eating peptides: Biomarkers of neurodegeneration in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal dementia. Annals of Clinical and Translational Neurology. https://doi.org/10.1002/acn3.721</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alexianu, M. E., Ho, B. K., Mohamed, A. H., La Bella, V., Smith, R. G., &amp; Appel, S. H. (1994). The role of calcium-binding proteins in selective motoneuron vulnerability in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Annals of Neurology, 36, 846-858. https://doi.org/10.1002/ana.410360608</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allen, J. M., Gibson, S. J., Adrian, T. E., Polak, J. M., &amp; Bloom, S. R. (1984). Neuropeptide Y in human spinal cord. Brain Research, 308, 145-148. https://doi.org/10.1016/0006-8993(84)90926-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allen, Y. S., Adrian, T. E., Allen, J. M., Tatemoto, K., Crow, T. J., Bloom, S. R., &amp; Polak, J. M. (1983). Neuropeptide Y distribution in the rat brain. Science, 221, 877-879. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.6136091</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alvaro, A. R., Martins, J., Costa, A. C., Fernandes, E., Carvalho, F., Ambrosio, A. F., &amp; Cavadas, C. (2008). Neuropeptide Y protects retinal neural cells against cell death induced by ecstasy. Neuroscience, 152, 97-105. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuroscience.2007.12.027</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aveleira, C. A., Botelho, M., Carmo-Silva, S., Pascoal, J. F., Ferreira-Marques, M., N&#xf3;brega, C., &#x2026; Cavadas, C. (2015). Neuropeptide Y stimulates autophagy in hypothalamic neurons. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 112, E1642-E1651. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1416609112</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aveleira, C. A., Ferreira-Marques, M., Cortes, L., Valero, J., Pereira, D., Pereira de Almeida, L., &amp; Cavadas, C. (2020). Neuropeptide Y enhances progerin clearance and ameliorates the senescent phenotype of Human Hutchinson-Gilford Progeria Syndrome Cells. Journals of Gerontology. Series A, Biological Sciences and Medical Sciences, 75(6), 1073-1078. https://doi.org/10.1093/gerona/glz280</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bae, J. S., Simon, N. G., Menon, P., Vucic, S., &amp; Kiernan, M. C. (2013). The puzzling case of hyperexcitability in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Journal of Clinical Neurology, 9, 65-74. https://doi.org/10.3988/jcn.2013.9.2.65</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baptista, S., Bento, A. R., Gon&#xe7;alves, J., Bernardino, L., Summavielle, T., Lobo, A., &#x2026; Silva, A. P. (2012). Neuropeptide Y promotes neurogenesis and protection against methamphetamine-induced toxicity in mouse dentate gyrus-derived neurosphere cultures. Neuropharmacology, 62, 2413-2423. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuropharm.2012.02.015</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baraban, S. C., Hollopeter, G., Erickson, J. C., Schwartzkroin, P. A., &amp; Palmiter, R. D. (1997). Knock-out mice reveal a critical antiepileptic role for neuropeptide Y. Journal of Neuroscience, 17, 8927-8936. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.17-23-08927.1997</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barber, S. C., &amp; Shaw, P. J. (2010). Oxidative stress in ALS: Key role in motor neuron injury and therapeutic target. Free Radical Biology and Medicine, 48, 629-641. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.freeradbiomed.2009.11.018</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barmada, S. J., Serio, A., Arjun, A., Bilican, B., Daub, A., Ando, D. M., &#x2026; Finkbeiner, S. (2014). Autophagy induction enhances TDP43 turnover and survival in neuronal ALS models. Nature Chemical Biology, 10, 677-685. https://doi.org/10.1038/nchembio.1563</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>BDNF Study Group (1999). A controlled trial of recombinant methionyl human BDNF in ALS: The BDNF Study Group (Phase III). Neurology, 52, 1427-1433.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bedoui, S., Kawamura, N., Straub, R. H., Pabst, R., Yamamura, T., &amp; von Horsten, S. (2003). Relevance of neuropeptide Y for the neuroimmune crosstalk. Journal of Neuroimmunology, 134, 1-11. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0165-5728(02)00424-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bedoui, S., Kuhlmann, S., Nave, H., Drube, J., Pabst, R., &amp; von Horsten, S. (2001). Differential effects of neuropeptide Y (NPY) on leukocyte subsets in the blood: Mobilization of B-1-like B-lymphocytes and activated monocytes. Journal of Neuroimmunology, 117, 125-132. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0165-5728(01)00328-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beers, D. R., Henkel, J. S., Zhao, W., Wang, J., Huang, A., Wen, S., &#x2026; Appel, S. H. (2011). Endogenous regulatory T lymphocytes ameliorate amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in mice and correlate with disease progression in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain, 134, 1293-1314. https://doi.org/10.1093/brain/awr074</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benmaamar, R., Pham-Le, B. T., Marescaux, C., Pedrazzini, T., &amp; Depaulis, A. (2003). Induced down-regulation of neuropeptide Y-Y1 receptors delays initiation of kindling. European Journal of Neuroscience, 18, 768-774. https://doi.org/10.1046/j.1460-9568.2003.02810.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bijak, M. (1999). Neuropeptide Y suppresses epileptiform activity in rat frontal cortex and hippocampus in vitro via different NPY receptor subtypes. Neuroscience Letters, 268, 115-118. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0304-3940(99)00381-X</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bijak, M. (2000). Neuropeptide Y reduces epileptiform discharges and excitatory synaptic transmission in rat frontal cortex in vitro. Neuroscience, 96, 487-494. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0306-4522(99)00594-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bijak, M., &amp; Smialowska, M. (1995). Effects of neuropeptide Y on evoked potentials in the CA1 region and the dentate gyrus of the rat hippocampal slice. Polish Journal of Pharmacology, 47, 333-338.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blizzard, C. A., Southam, K. A., Dawkins, E., Lewis, K. E., King, A. E., Clark, J. A., &amp; Dickson, T. C. (2015). Identifying the primary site of pathogenesis in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis - vulnerability of lower motor neurons to proximal excitotoxicity. Disease Models and Mechanisms, 8, 215-224. https://doi.org/10.1242/dmm.018606</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bogdanov, M., Brown, R. H., Matson, W., Smart, R., Hayden, D., O'Donnell, H., &#x2026; Cudkowicz, M. (2000). Increased oxidative damage to DNA in ALS patients. Free Radical Biology and Medicine, 29, 652-658. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0891-5849(00)00349-X</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowerman, M., Vincent, T., Scamps, F., Perrin, F. E., Camu, W., &amp; Raoul, C. (2013). Neuroimmunity dynamics and the development of therapeutic strategies for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Frontiers in Cellular Neuroscience, 7, 214. https://doi.org/10.3389/fncel.2013.00214</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bozzo, F., Mirra, A., &amp; Carri, M. T. (2017). Oxidative stress and mitochondrial damage in the pathogenesis of ALS: New perspectives. Neuroscience Letters, 636, 3-8. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neulet.2016.04.065</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brenner, D., &amp; Weishaupt, J. H. (2019). Update on amyotrophic lateral sclerosis genetics. Current Opinion in Neurology, 32, 735-739. https://doi.org/10.1097/WCO.0000000000000737</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brettschneider, J., Toledo, J. B., Van Deerlin, V. M., Elman, L., McCluskey, L., Lee, V. M., &amp; Trojanowski, J. Q. (2012). Microglial activation correlates with disease progression and upper motor neuron clinical symptoms in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. PLoS One, 7, e39216. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0039216</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brothers, S. P., &amp; Wahlestedt, C. (2010). Therapeutic potential of neuropeptide Y (NPY) receptor ligands. EMBO Molecular Medicine, 2, 429-439. https://doi.org/10.1002/emmm.201000100</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brunet, A., Stuart-Lopez, G., Burg, T., Scekic-Zahirovic, J., &amp; Rouaux, C. (2020). Cortical circuit dysfunction as a potential driver of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Frontiers in Neuroscience, 14, 363. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnins.2020.00363</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bu, W., Zhao, W. Q., Li, W. L., Dong, C. Z., Zhang, Z., &amp; Li, Q. J. (2017). Neuropeptide Y suppresses epileptiform discharges by regulating AMPA receptor GluR2 subunit in rat hippocampal neurons. Molecular Medicine Reports, 16, 387-395. https://doi.org/10.3892/mmr.2017.6567</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Camp, R., Stier, C. T. Jr, Serova, L. I., McCloskey, J., Edwards, J. G., Reyes-Zaragoza, M., &amp; Sabban, E. L. (2018). Cardiovascular responses to intranasal neuropeptide Y in single prolonged stress rodent model of post-traumatic stress disorder. Neuropeptides, 67, 87-94. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.npep.2017.11.006</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardoso, A., Freitas-da-Costa, P., Carvalho, L. S., &amp; Lukoyanov, N. V. (2010). Seizure-induced changes in neuropeptide Y-containing cortical neurons: Potential role for seizure threshold and epileptogenesis. Epilepsy and Behavior, 19, 559-567. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.yebeh.2010.09.008</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carriedo, S. G., Yin, H. Z., &amp; Weiss, J. H. (1996). Motor neurons are selectively vulnerable to AMPA/kainate receptor-mediated injury in vitro. Journal of Neuroscience, 16, 4069-4079.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casillas-Espinosa, P. M., Powell, K. L., &amp; O'Brien, T. J. (2012). Regulators of synaptic transmission: Roles in the pathogenesis and treatment of epilepsy. Epilepsia, 53(Suppl 9), 41-58. https://doi.org/10.1111/epi.12034</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang, Y., Kong, Q., Shan, X., Tian, G., Ilieva, H., Cleveland, D. W., &#x2026; Lin, C.-L. (2008). Messenger RNA oxidation occurs early in disease pathogenesis and promotes motor neuron degeneration in ALS. PLoS One, 3, e2849. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0002849</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chia, R., Chio, A., &amp; Traynor, B. J. (2018). Novel genes associated with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Diagnostic and clinical implications. The Lancet Neurology, 17, 94-102. https://doi.org/10.1016/S1474-4422(17)30401-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chio, A., Logroscino, G., Traynor, B. J., Collins, J., Simeone, J. C., Goldstein, L. A., &amp; White, L. A. (2013). Global epidemiology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A systematic review of the published literature. Neuroepidemiology, 41, 118-130. https://doi.org/10.1159/000351153</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiodera, P., Volpi, R., Pilla, S., Cataldo, S., &amp; Coiro, V. (2000). Decline in circulating neuropeptide Y levels in normal elderly human subjects. European Journal of Endocrinology, 143, 715-716. https://doi.org/10.1530/eje.0.1430715</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark, R., Blizzard, C., &amp; Dickson, T. (2015). Inhibitory dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Future therapeutic opportunities. Neurodegenerative Disease Management, 5, 511-525. https://doi.org/10.2217/nmt.15.49</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark, R. M., Blizzard, C. A., Young, K. M., King, A. E., &amp; Dickson, T. C. (2017). Calretinin and Neuropeptide Y interneurons are differentially altered in the motor cortex of the SOD1(G93A) mouse model of ALS. Scientific Reports, 7, 44461. https://doi.org/10.1038/srep44461</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clement, A. M., Nguyen, M. D., Roberts, E. A. et al (2003). Wild-type nonneuronal cells extend survival of SOD1 mutant motor neurons in ALS mice. Science, 302, 113-117. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.1086071</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colmers, W. F., Lukowiak, K., &amp; Pittman, Q. J. (1985). Neuropeptide Y reduces orthodromically evoked population spike in rat hippocampal CA1 by a possibly presynaptic mechanism. Brain Research, 346, 404-408. https://doi.org/10.1016/0006-8993(85)90880-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colmers, W. F., Lukowiak, K., &amp; Pittman, Q. J. (1987). Presynaptic action of neuropeptide Y in area CA1 of the rat hippocampal slice. Journal of Physiology, 383, 285-299. https://doi.org/10.1113/jphysiol.1987.sp016409</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corvino, V., Marchese, E., Giannetti, S., Lattanzi, W., Bonvissuto, D., Biamonte, F., &#x2026; Geloso, M. C. (2012). The neuroprotective and neurogenic effects of neuropeptide Y administration in an animal model of hippocampal neurodegeneration and temporal lobe epilepsy induced by trimethyltin. Journal of Neurochemistry, 122, 415-426. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1471-4159.2012.07770.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cova, E., Bongioanni, P., Cereda, C., Metelli, M. R., Salvaneschi, L., Bernuzzi, S., &#x2026; Ceroni, M. (2010). Time course of oxidant markers and antioxidant defenses in subgroups of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. Neurochemistry International, 56, 687-693. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuint.2010.02.004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Croce, N., Ciotti, M. T., Gelfo, F., Cortelli, S., Federici, G., Caltagirone, C., &#x2026; Angelucci, F. (2012). Neuropeptide Y protects rat cortical neurons against beta-amyloid toxicity and re-establishes synthesis and release of nerve growth factor. ACS Chemical Neuroscience, 3, 312-318.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Croce, N., Gelfo, F., Ciotti, M. T., Federici, G., Caltagirone, C., Bernardini, S., &amp; Angelucci, F. (2013). NPY modulates miR-30a-5p and BDNF in opposite direction in an in vitro model of Alzheimer disease: A possible role in neuroprotection? Molecular and Cellular Biochemistry, 376, 189-195. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11010-013-1567-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dafinca, R., Barbagallo, P., Farrimond, L., Candalija, A., Scaber, J., Ababneh, N. A., &#x2026; Talbot, K. (2020). Impairment of mitochondrial calcium buffering links mutations in C9ORF72 and TARDBP in iPS-derived motor neurons from patients with ALS/FTD. Stem Cell Reports, 14, 892-908. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.stemcr.2020.03.023</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dafinca, R., Scaber, J., Ababneh, N., Lalic, T., Weir, G., Christian, H., &#x2026; Talbot, K. (2016). C9orf72 hexanucleotide expansions are associated with altered endoplasmic reticulum calcium homeostasis and stress granule formation in induced pluripotent stem cell-derived neurons from patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal dementia. Stem Cells, 34, 2063-2078. https://doi.org/10.1002/stem.2388</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De la Fuente, M., Bernaez, I., Del Rio, M., &amp; Hernanz, A. (1993). Stimulation of murine peritoneal macrophage functions by neuropeptide Y and peptide YY. Involvement of Protein Kinase C. Immunology, 80, 259-265.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Decressac, M., Prestoz, L., Veran, J., Cantereau, A., Jaber, M., &amp; Gaillard, A. (2009). Neuropeptide Y stimulates proliferation, migration and differentiation of neural precursors from the subventricular zone in adult mice. Neurobiology of Diseases, 34, 441-449. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nbd.2009.02.017</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Decressac, M., Wright, B., Tyers, P., Gaillard, A., &amp; Barker, R. A. (2010). Neuropeptide Y modifies the disease course in the R6/2 transgenic model of Huntington's disease. Experimental Neurology, 226, 24-32. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.expneurol.2010.07.022</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng, H.-X., Chen, W., Hong, S.-T., Boycott, K. M., Gorrie, G. H., Siddique, N., &#x2026; Siddique, T. (2011). Mutations in UBQLN2 cause dominant X-linked juvenile and adult-onset ALS and ALS/dementia. Nature, 477, 211-215. https://doi.org/10.1038/nature10353</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dervishi, I., &amp; Ozdinler, P. H. (2018). Incorporating upper motor neuron health in ALS drug discovery. Drug Discovery Today, 23, 696-703. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.drudis.2018.01.027</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devlin, A.-C., Burr, K., Borooah, S., Foster, J. D., Cleary, E. M., Geti, I., &#x2026; Miles, G. B. (2015). Human iPSC-derived motoneurons harbouring TARDBP or C9ORF72 ALS mutations are dysfunctional despite maintaining viability. Nature Communications, 6, 5999. https://doi.org/10.1038/ncomms6999</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Do-Ha, D., Buskila, Y., &amp; Ooi, L. (2018). Impairments in Motor Neurons, Interneurons and Astrocytes Contribute to Hyperexcitability in ALS: Underlying Mechanisms and Paths to Therapy. Molecular Neurobiology, 55, 1410-1418. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12035-017-0392-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dokladny, K., Myers, O. B., &amp; Moseley, P. L. (2015). Heat shock response and autophagy-cooperation and control. Autophagy, 11, 200-213. https://doi.org/10.1080/15548627.2015.1009776</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Domingues, M. F., de Assis, D. R., Piovesan, A. R., Belo, C. A. D., &amp; da Costa, J. C. (2018). Peptide YY (3-36) modulates intracellular calcium through activation of the phosphatidylinositol pathway in hippocampal neurons. Neuropeptides, 67, 1-8. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.npep.2017.11.003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>dos Santos, V. V., Santos, D. B., Lach, G., Rodrigues, A. L., Farina, M., De Lima, T. C., &amp; Prediger, R. D. (2013). Neuropeptide Y (NPY) prevents depressive-like behavior, spatial memory deficits and oxidative stress following amyloid-beta (Abeta(1-40)) administration in mice. Behavioral Brain Research, 244, 107-115.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doyle, K. L., Karl, T., Hort, Y., Duffy, L., Shine, J., &amp; Herzog, H. (2008). Y1 receptors are critical for the proliferation of adult mouse precursor cells in the olfactory neuroepithelium. Journal of Neurochemistry, 105, 641-652. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1471-4159.2007.05188.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drechsel, D. A., Estevez, A. G., Barbeito, L., &amp; Beckman, J. S. (2012). Nitric oxide-mediated oxidative damage and the progressive demise of motor neurons in ALS. Neurotoxicity Research, 22, 251-264. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12640-012-9322-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duarte-Neves, J., Goncalves, N., Cunha-Santos, J., Simoes, A. T., den Dunnen, W. F., Hirai, H., &#x2026; Pereira de Almeida, L. (2015). Neuropeptide Y mitigates neuropathology and motor deficits in mouse models of Machado-Joseph disease. Human Molecular Genetics, 24, 5451-5463. https://doi.org/10.1093/hmg/ddv271</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duarte-Neves, J., Pereira de Almeida, L., &amp; Cavadas, C. (2016). Neuropeptide Y (NPY) as a therapeutic target for neurodegenerative diseases. Neurobiology of Diseases, 95, 210-224. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nbd.2016.07.022</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dumont, Y., Fournier, A., St-Pierre, S., &amp; Quirion, R. (1993). Comparative characterization and autoradiographic distribution of neuropeptide Y receptor subtypes in the rat brain. Journal of Neuroscience, 13, 73-86. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.13-01-00073.1993</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dumont, Y., St-Pierre, J. A., &amp; Quirion, R. (1996). Comparative autoradiographic distribution of neuropeptide Y Y1 receptors visualized with the Y1 receptor agonist [125I][Leu31, Pro34]PYY and the non-peptide antagonist [3H]BIBP3226. NeuroReport, 7, 901-904.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>El Bahh, B., Balosso, S., Hamilton, T., Herzog, H., Beck-Sickinger, A. G., Sperk, G., &#x2026; Colmers, W. F. (2005). The anti-epileptic actions of neuropeptide Y in the hippocampus are mediated by Y and not Y receptors. European Journal of Neuroscience, 22, 1417-1430.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Endo, F., Komine, O., &amp; Yamanaka, K. (2016). Neuroinflammation in motor neuron disease. Clinical and Experimental Neuroimmunology, 7, 126-138. https://doi.org/10.1111/cen3.12309</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erickson, J. C., Clegg, K. E., &amp; Palmiter, R. D. (1996). Sensitivity to leptin and susceptibility to seizures of mice lacking neuropeptide Y. Nature, 381, 415-421. https://doi.org/10.1038/381415a0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang, C., Bourdette, D., &amp; Banker, G. (2012). Oxidative stress inhibits axonal transport: Implications for neurodegenerative diseases. Molecular Neurodegeneration, 7, 29. https://doi.org/10.1186/1750-1326-7-29</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fatoba, O., Kloster, E., Reick, C., Saft, C., Gold, R., Epplen, J. T., &#x2026; Ellrichmann, G. (2018). Activation of NPY-Y2 receptors ameliorates disease pathology in the R6/2 mouse and PC12 cell models of Huntington's disease. Experimental Neurology, 302, 112-128. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.expneurol.2018.01.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fecto, F., Yan, J., Vemula, S. P., Liu, E., Yang, Y., Chen, W., &#x2026; Donkervoort, S. (2011). SQSTM1 mutations in familial and sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Archives of Neurology, 68, 1440-1446.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferraiuolo, L., Kirby, J., Grierson, A. J., Sendtner, M., &amp; Shaw, P. J. (2011). Molecular pathways of motor neuron injury in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nature Reviews Neurology, 7, 616-630. https://doi.org/10.1038/nrneurol.2011.152</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferreira, R., Santos, T., Cortes, L., Cochaud, S., Agasse, F., Silva, A. P., &#x2026; Malva, J. O. (2012). Neuropeptide Y inhibits interleukin-1 beta-induced microglia motility. Journal of Neurochemistry, 120, 93-105. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1471-4159.2011.07541.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferreira, R., Santos, T., Viegas, M., Cortes, L., Bernardino, L., Vieira, O. V., &amp; Malva, J. O. (2011). Neuropeptide Y inhibits interleukin-1beta-induced phagocytosis by microglial cells. Journal of Neuroinflammation, 8, 169.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferreira, R., Xapelli, S., Santos, T., Silva, A. P., Cristovao, A., Cortes, L., &amp; Malva, J. O. (2010). Neuropeptide Y modulation of interleukin-1{beta} (IL-1{beta})-induced nitric oxide production in microglia. Journal of Biological Chemistry, 285, 41921-41934.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferreira-Marques, M., Aveleira, C. A., Carmo-Silva, S., Botelho, M., Pereira de Almeida, L., &amp; Cavadas, C. (2016). Caloric restriction stimulates autophagy in rat cortical neurons through neuropeptide Y and ghrelin receptors activation. Aging (Albany NY), 8, 1470-1484. https://doi.org/10.18632/aging.100996</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferreiro, E., Baldeiras, I., Ferreira, I. L., Costa, R. O., Rego, A. C., Pereira, C. F., &amp; Oliveira, C. R. (2012). Mitochondrial- and endoplasmic reticulum-associated oxidative stress in Alzheimer's disease: From pathogenesis to biomarkers. International Journal of Cell Biology, 2012, 735206. https://doi.org/10.1155/2012/735206</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finkelstein, A., Kunis, G., Seksenyan, A., Ronen, A., Berkutzki, T., Azoulay, D., &#x2026; Schwartz, M. (2011). Abnormal changes in NKT cells, the IGF-1 axis, and liver pathology in an animal model of ALS. PLoS One, 6, e22374. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0022374</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujimori, K., Ishikawa, M., Otomo, A., Atsuta, N., Nakamura, R., Akiyama, T., &#x2026; Okano, H. (2018). Modeling sporadic ALS in iPSC-derived motor neurons identifies a potential therapeutic agent. Nature Medicine, 24, 1579-1589. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41591-018-0140-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gamerdinger, M., Hajieva, P., Kaya, A. M., Wolfrum, U., Hartl, F. U., &amp; Behl, C. (2009). Protein quality control during aging involves recruitment of the macroautophagy pathway by BAG3. The EMBO Journal, 28, 889-901. https://doi.org/10.1038/emboj.2009.29</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gariboldi, M., Conti, M., Cavaleri, D., Samanin, R., &amp; Vezzani, A. (1998). Anticonvulsant properties of BIBP3226, a non-peptide selective antagonist at neuropeptide Y Y1 receptors. European Journal of Neuroscience, 10, 757-759.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geevasinga, N., Menon, P., Nicholson, G. A., Ng, K., Howells, J., Kril, J. J., &#x2026; Vucic, S. (2015). Cortical Function in Asymptomatic Carriers and Patients With C9orf72 Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. JAMA Neurol, 72, 1268-1274.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geevasinga, N., Menon, P., Ozdinler, P. H., Kiernan, M. C., &amp; Vucic, S. (2016). Pathophysiological and diagnostic implications of cortical dysfunction in ALS. Nature Reviews Neurology, 12, 651-661. https://doi.org/10.1038/nrneurol.2016.140</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gehrig, S. M., van der Poel, C., Sayer, T. A., Schertzer, J. D., Henstridge, D. C., Church, J. E., &#x2026; Lynch, G. S. (2012). Hsp72 preserves muscle function and slows progression of severe muscular dystrophy. Nature, 484, 394-398. https://doi.org/10.1038/nature10980</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geloso, M. C., Corvino, V., Di Maria, V., Marchese, E., &amp; Michetti, F. (2015). Cellular targets for neuropeptide Y-mediated control of adult neurogenesis. Frontiers in Cellular Neuroscience, 9, 85. https://doi.org/10.3389/fncel.2015.00085</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geloso, M. C., Corvino, V., Marchese, E., Serrano, A., Michetti, F., &amp; D'Ambrosi, N. (2017). The dual role of microglia in ALS: Mechanisms and therapeutic approaches. Frontiers in Aging Neuroscience, 9, 242. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnagi.2017.00242</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goncalves, J., Ribeiro, C. F., Malva, J. O., &amp; Silva, A. P. (2012). Protective role of neuropeptide Y Y(2) receptors in cell death and microglial response following methamphetamine injury. European Journal of Neuroscience, 36, 3173-3183.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goutman, S. A., Savelieff, M. G., Sakowski, S. A., &amp; Feldman, E. L. (2019). Stem cell treatments for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A critical overview of early phase trials. Expert Opinion on Investigational Drugs, 28, 525-543. https://doi.org/10.1080/13543784.2019.1627324</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grieve, S. M., Menon, P., Korgaonkar, M. S., Gomes, L., Foster, S., Kiernan, M. C., &amp; Vucic, S. (2015). Potential structural and functional biomarkers of upper motor neuron dysfunction in ALS. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener, 17, 85-92. https://doi.org/10.3109/21678421.2015.1074707</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grossman, M. (2019). Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis - a multisystem neurodegenerative disorder. Nature Reviews. Neurology, 15, 5-6. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41582-018-0103-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo, F., Liu, X., Cai, H., &amp; Le, W. (2018). Autophagy in neurodegenerative diseases: Pathogenesis and therapy. Brain Pathology, 28, 3-13. https://doi.org/10.1111/bpa.12545</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haidet-Phillips, A. M., Hester, M. E., Miranda, C. J., Meyer, K., Braun, L., Frakes, A., &#x2026; Kaspar, B. K. (2011). Astrocytes from familial and sporadic ALS patients are toxic to motor neurons. Nature Biotechnology, 29, 824-828. https://doi.org/10.1038/nbt.1957</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hansel, D. E., Eipper, B. A., &amp; Ronnett, G. V. (2001). Neuropeptide Y functions as a neuroproliferative factor. Nature, 410, 940-944. https://doi.org/10.1038/35073601</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henkel, J. S., Beers, D. R., Wen, S., Rivera, A. L., Toennis, K. M., Appel, J. E., &#x2026; Appel, S. H. (2013). Regulatory T-lymphocytes mediate amyotrophic lateral sclerosis progression and survival. EMBO Molecular Medicine, 5, 64-79. https://doi.org/10.1002/emmm.201201544</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hokfelt, T., Bartfai, T., &amp; Bloom, F. (2003). Neuropeptides: Opportunities for drug discovery. The Lancet Neurology, 2, 463-472. https://doi.org/10.1016/S1474-4422(03)00482-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Homma, T., Kobayashi, S., Sato, H., &amp; Fujii, J. (2019). Edaravone, a free radical scavenger, protects against ferroptotic cell death in vitro. Experimental Cell Research, 384, 111592. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.yexcr.2019.111592</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howland, D. S., Liu, J., She, Y., Goad, B., Maragakis, N. J., Kim, B., &#x2026; Rothstein, J. D. (2002). Focal loss of the glutamate transporter EAAT2 in a transgenic rat model of SOD1 mutant-mediated amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 99, 1604-1609. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.032539299</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu, P., &amp; Kalb, R. G. (2003). BDNF heightens the sensitivity of motor neurons to excitotoxic insults through activation of TrkB. Journal of Neurochemistry, 84, 1421-1430. https://doi.org/10.1046/j.1471-4159.2003.01599.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ikeda, K., Klinkosz, B., Greene, T., Cedarbaum, J. M., Wong, V., Lindsay, R. M., &amp; Mitsumoto, H. (1995). Effects of brain-derived neurotrophic factor on motor dysfunction in wobbler mouse motor neuron disease. Annals of Neurology, 37, 505-511. https://doi.org/10.1002/ana.410370413</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ince, P., Stout, N., Shaw, P., Slade, J., Hunziker, W., Heizmann, C. W., &amp; Baimbridge, K. G. (1993). Parvalbumin and calbindin D-28k in the human motor system and in motor neuron disease. Neuropathology and Applied Neurobiology, 19, 291-299. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2990.1993.tb00443.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Intondi, A. B., Dahlgren, M. N., Eilers, M. A., &amp; Taylor, B. K. (2008). Intrathecal neuropeptide Y reduces behavioral and molecular markers of inflammatory or neuropathic pain. Pain, 137, 352-365. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pain.2007.09.016</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izrael, M., Slutsky, S. G., Admoni, T., Cohen, L., Granit, A., Hasson, A., &#x2026; Revel, M. (2018). Safety and efficacy of human embryonic stem cell-derived astrocytes following intrathecal transplantation in SOD1(G93A) and NSG animal models. Stem Cell Research and Therapy, 9, 152. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13287-018-0890-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jazmati, D., Neubacher, U., &amp; Funke, K. (2018). Neuropeptide Y as a possible homeostatic element for changes in cortical excitability induced by repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation. Brain Stimulation, 11, 797-805. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.brs.2018.02.017</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joshi, A. U., Minhas, P. S., Liddelow, S. A., Haileselassie, B., Andreasson, K. I., Dorn, G. W. 2nd, &amp; Mochly-Rosen, D. (2019). Fragmented mitochondria released from microglia trigger A1 astrocytic response and propagate inflammatory neurodegeneration. Nature Neuroscience, 22, 1635-1648. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41593-019-0486-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jovanovic, J. N., Czernik, A. J., Fienberg, A. A., Greengard, P., &amp; Sihra, T. S. (2000). Synapsins as mediators of BDNF-enhanced neurotransmitter release. Nature Neuroscience, 3, 323-329. https://doi.org/10.1038/73888</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kafitz, K. W., Rose, C. R., Thoenen, H., &amp; Konnerth, A. (1999). Neurotrophin-evoked rapid excitation through TrkB receptors. Nature, 401, 918-921. https://doi.org/10.1038/44847</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kastin, A. J., &amp; Akerstrom, V. (1999). Nonsaturable entry of neuropeptide Y into brain. American Journal of Physiology, 276, E479-E482. https://doi.org/10.1152/ajpendo.1999.276.3.E479</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khademullah, C. S., Aqrabawi, A. J., Place, K. M., Dargaei, Z., Liang, X., Pressey, J. C., &#x2026; Woodin, M. A. (2020). Cortical interneuron-mediated inhibition delays the onset of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain, 143, 800-810. https://doi.org/10.1093/brain/awaa034</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kharlamov, E. A., Kharlamov, A., &amp; Kelly, K. M. (2007). Changes in neuropeptide Y protein expression following photothrombotic brain infarction and epileptogenesis. Brain Research, 1127, 151-162. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.brainres.2006.09.107</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>King, A. E., Woodhouse, A., Kirkcaldie, M. T., &amp; Vickers, J. C. (2016). Excitotoxicity in ALS: Overstimulation, or overreaction? Experimental Neurology, 275(Pt 1), 162-171. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.expneurol.2015.09.019</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kir, H. M., Sahin, D., Oztas, B., Musul, M., &amp; Kuskay, S. (2013). Effects of single-dose neuropeptide Y on levels of hippocampal BDNF, MDA, GSH, and NO in a rat model of pentylenetetrazole-induced epileptic seizure. Bosnian Journal of Basic Medical Sciences, 13, 242-247. https://doi.org/10.17305/bjbms.2013.2332</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kocaturk, N. M., &amp; Gozuacik, D. (2018). Crosstalk between mammalian autophagy and the ubiquitin-proteasome system. Frontiers in Cell and Developmental Biology, 6, 128. https://doi.org/10.3389/fcell.2018.00128</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komine, O., &amp; Yamanaka, K. (2015). Neuroinflammation in motor neuron disease. Nagoya Journal of Medical Science, 77, 537-549.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kowianski, P., Lietzau, G., Czuba, E., Waskow, M., Steliga, A., &amp; Morys, J. (2018). BDNF: A key factor with multipotent impact on brain signaling and synaptic plasticity. Cellular and Molecular Neurobiology, 38, 579-593. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10571-017-0510-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koyama, R., &amp; Ikegaya, Y. (2005). To BDNF or not to BDNF: That is the epileptic hippocampus. Neuroscientist, 11, 282-287. https://doi.org/10.1177/1073858405278266</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lacroix, J. S., Ricchetti, A. P., Morel, D., Mossimann, B., Waeber, B., &amp; Grouzmann, E. (1996). Intranasal administration of neuropeptide Y in man: Systemic absorption and functional effects. British Journal of Pharmacology, 118, 2079-2084. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1476-5381.1996.tb15647.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leal, S. S., &amp; Gomes, C. M. (2015). Calcium dysregulation links ALS defective proteins and motor neuron selective vulnerability. Frontiers in Cellular Neuroscience, 9, 225. https://doi.org/10.3389/fncel.2015.00225</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, A. H., Iwakoshi, N. N., &amp; Glimcher, L. H. (2003). XBP-1 regulates a subset of endoplasmic reticulum resident chaperone genes in the unfolded protein response. Molecular and Cellular Biology, 23, 7448-7459. https://doi.org/10.1128/MCB.23.21.7448-7459.2003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, D. Y., Hong, S. H., Kim, B., Lee, D.-S., Yu, K., &amp; Lee, K.-S. (2018). Neuropeptide Y mitigates ER stress-induced neuronal cell death by activating the PI3K-XBP1 pathway. European Journal of Cell Biology, 97, 339-348. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ejcb.2018.04.003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Q., Dong, C., Li, W., Bu, W., Wu, J., &amp; Zhao, W. (2014). Neuropeptide Y protects cerebral cortical neurons by regulating microglial immune function. Neural Regeneration Research, 9, 959-967. https://doi.org/10.4103/1673-5374.133140</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao, B., Zhao, W., Beers, D. R., Henkel, J. S., &amp; Appel, S. H. (2012). Transformation from a neuroprotective to a neurotoxic microglial phenotype in a mouse model of ALS. Experimental Neurology, 237, 147-152. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.expneurol.2012.06.011</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim, M. A., Selak, M. A., Xiang, Z., Krainc, D., Neve, R. L., Kraemer, B. C., &#x2026; Kalb, R. G. (2012). Reduced activity of AMP-activated protein kinase protects against genetic models of motor neuron disease. Journal of Neuroscience, 32, 1123-1141. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.6554-10.2012</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, J., &amp; Wang, F. (2017). Role of neuroinflammation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Cellular mechanisms and therapeutic implications. Frontiers in Immunology, 8, 1005. https://doi.org/10.3389/fimmu.2017.01005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Y., Hao, W., Dawson, A., Liu, S., &amp; Fassbender, K. (2009). Expression of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-linked SOD1 mutant increases the neurotoxic potential of microglia via TLR2. Journal of Biological Chemistry, 284, 3691-3699. https://doi.org/10.1074/jbc.M804446200</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Y. J., Ju, T. C., Chen, H. M., Jang, Y. S., Lee, L. M., Lai, H. L., &amp; Chern, Y. (2015). Activation of AMP-activated protein kinase alpha1 mediates mislocalization of TDP-43 in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Human Molecular Genetics, 24, 787-801.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loh, K., Herzog, H., &amp; Shi, Y.-C. (2015). Regulation of energy homeostasis by the NPY system. Trends in Endocrinology and Metabolism, 26, 125-135. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tem.2015.01.003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Gonzalez, R., Lu, Y., Gendron, T. F., Karydas, A., Tran, H., Yang, D., &#x2026; Gao, F.-B. (2016). Poly(GR) in C9ORF72-related ALS/FTD compromises mitochondrial function and increases oxidative stress and DNA damage in iPSC-derived motor neurons. Neuron, 92, 383-391. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2016.09.015</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madeo, F., Eisenberg, T., &amp; Kroemer, G. (2009). Autophagy for the avoidance of neurodegeneration. Genes and Development, 23, 2253-2259. https://doi.org/10.1101/gad.1858009</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandrioli, J., D&#x2019;Amico, R., Zucchi, E., Gessani, A., Fini, N., Fasano, A., &#x2026; Cossarizza, A. (2018). Rapamycin treatment for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Protocol for a phase II randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, multicenter, clinical trial (RAP-ALS trial). Medicine (Baltimore), 97, e11119. https://doi.org/10.1097/MD.0000000000011119</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mattson, M. P. (2000). Apoptosis in neurodegenerative disorders. Nature Reviews Molecular Cell Biology, 1, 120. https://doi.org/10.1038/35040009</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maurel, C., Dangoumau, A., Marouillat, S., Brulard, C., Chami, A., Hergesheimer, R., &#x2026; Vourc&#x2019;h, P. (2018). Causative genes in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and protein degradation pathways: A link to neurodegeneration. Molecular Neurobiology, 55, 6480-6499. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12035-017-0856-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Medina, S., Del Rio, M., Hernanz, A., &amp; De la Fuente, M. (2000). Age-related changes in the neuropeptide Y effects on murine lymphoproliferation and interleukin-2 production. Peptides, 21, 1403-1409. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0196-9781(00)00284-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mejzini, R., Flynn, L. L., Pitout, I. L., Fletcher, S., Wilton, S. D., &amp; Akkari, P. A. (2019). ALS genetics, mechanisms, and therapeutics: Where are we now? Frontiers in Neuroscience, 13, 1310. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnins.2019.01310</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mellios, N., Huang, H.-S., Grigorenko, A., Rogaev, E., &amp; Akbarian, S. (2008). A set of differentially expressed miRNAs, including miR-30a-5p, act as post-transcriptional inhibitors of BDNF in prefrontal cortex. Human Molecular Genetics, 17, 3030-3042. https://doi.org/10.1093/hmg/ddn201</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menon, P., Geevasinga, N., van den Bos, M., Yiannikas, C., Kiernan, M. C., &amp; Vucic, S. (2017). Cortical hyperexcitability and disease spread in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. European Journal of Neurology, 24, 816-824. https://doi.org/10.1111/ene.13295</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menon, P., Higashihara, M., van den Bos, M., Geevasinga, N., Kiernan, M. C., &amp; Vucic, S. (2020). Cortical hyperexcitability evolves with disease progression in ALS. Annals of Clinical and Translational Neurology, 7, 733-741. https://doi.org/10.1002/acn3.51039</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menon, P., Kiernan, M. C., &amp; Vucic, S. (2015). Cortical hyperexcitability precedes lower motor neuron dysfunction in ALS. Clinical Neurophysiology, 126, 803-809. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.clinph.2014.04.023</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller, R. G., Mitchell, J. D., &amp; Moore, D. H. ((2012). Riluzole for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS)/motor neuron disease (MND). Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews (3), CD001447. https://doi.org/10.1002/14651858.CD001447.pub3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Molosh, A. I., Sajdyk, T. J., Truitt, W. A., Zhu, W., Oxford, G. S., &amp; Shekhar, A. (2013). NPY Y1 receptors differentially modulate GABAA and NMDA receptors via divergent signal-transduction pathways to reduce excitability of amygdala neurons. Neuropsychopharmacology, 38, 1352-1364. https://doi.org/10.1038/npp.2013.33</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Movafagh, S., Hobson, J. P., Spiegel, S., Kleinman, H. K., Zukowska, Z., Movafagh, S., &#x2026; Zukowska, Z. (2006). Neuropeptide Y induces migration, proliferation, and tube formation of endothelial cells bimodally via Y1, Y2, and Y5 receptors. The FASEB Journal, 20, 1924-1926. https://doi.org/10.1096/fj.05-4770fje</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murdock, B. J., Zhou, T., Kashlan, S. R., Little, R. J., Goutman, S. A., &amp; Feldman, E. L. (2017). Correlation of peripheral immunity with rapid amyotrophic lateral sclerosis progression. JAMA Neurol, 74, 1446-1454. https://doi.org/10.1001/jamaneurol.2017.2255</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagai, M., Re, D. B., Nagata, T., Chalazonitis, A., Jessell, T. M., Wichterle, H., &amp; Przedborski, S. (2007). Astrocytes expressing ALS-linked mutated SOD1 release factors selectively toxic to motor neurons. Nature Neuroscience, 10, 615-622. https://doi.org/10.1038/nn1876</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nair, M. P., Schwartz, S. A., Wu, K., &amp; Kronfol, Z. (1993). Effect of neuropeptide Y on natural killer activity of normal human lymphocytes. Brain, Behavior, and Immunity, 7, 70-78. https://doi.org/10.1006/brbi.1993.1007</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nawa, H., Pelleymounter, M. A., &amp; Carnahan, J. (1994). Intraventricular administration of BDNF increases neuropeptide expression in newborn rat brain. Journal of Neuroscience, 14, 3751-3765. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.14-06-03751.1994</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nelson, T. S., Fu, W., Donahue, R. R., Corder, G. F., Hokfelt, T., Wiley, R. G., &amp; Taylor, B. K. (2019). Facilitation of neuropathic pain by the NPY Y1 receptor-expressing subpopulation of excitatory interneurons in the dorsal horn. Scientific Reports, 9, 7248. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-019-43493-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neumann, M. (2009). Molecular neuropathology of TDP-43 proteinopathies. International Journal of Molecular Sciences, 10, 232-246. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms10010232</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen, H. P., Van Broeckhoven, C., &amp; van der Zee, J. (2018). ALS genes in the genomic Era and their Implications for FTD. Trends in Genetics, 34(6), 404-423. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tig.2018.03.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nozdrachev, A. D., &amp; Masliukov, P. M. (2011). Neuropeptide Y and autonomic nervous system. Zhurnal Evoliutsionnoi Biokhimii I Fiziologii, 47, 105-112. https://doi.org/10.1134/S0022093011020010</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panossian, A., Wikman, G., Kaur, P., &amp; Asea, A. (2012). Adaptogens stimulate neuropeptide y and hsp72 expression and release in neuroglia cells. Frontiers in Neuroscience, 6, 6. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnins.2012.00006</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park, J.-H., Park, H.-S., Hong, S., &amp; Kang, S. (2016). Motor neurons derived from ALS-related mouse iPS cells recapitulate pathological features of ALS. Experimental and Molecular Medicine, 48, e276. https://doi.org/10.1038/emm.2016.113</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parker, S. L., &amp; Balasubramaniam, A. (2008). Neuropeptide Y Y2 receptor in health and disease. British Journal of Pharmacology, 153, 420-431. https://doi.org/10.1038/sj.bjp.0707445</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrov, D., Mansfield, C., Moussy, A., &amp; Hermine, O. (2017) ALS clinical trials review: 20 years of failure. Are we any closer to registering a new treatment? Frontiers in aging. Frontiers Aging Neuroscience, 9, 68.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pradhan, J., Noakes, P. G., &amp; Bellingham, M. C. (2019). The role of altered BDNF/TrkB signaling in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Frontiers in Cellular Neuroscience, 13, 368. https://doi.org/10.3389/fncel.2019.00368</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puerto, M., Guayerbas, N., Alvarez, P., &amp; De la Fuente, M. (2005). Modulation of neuropeptide Y and norepinephrine on several leucocyte functions in adult, old and very old mice. Journal of Neuroimmunology, 165, 33-40. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jneuroim.2005.03.021</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramamoorthy, P., &amp; Whim, M. D. (2008). Trafficking and fusion of neuropeptide Y-containing dense-core granules in astrocytes. Journal of Neuroscience, 28, 13815-13827. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.5361-07.2008</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramesh, N., &amp; Pandey, U. B. (2017). Autophagy dysregulation in ALS: When protein aggregates get out of hand. Frontiers in Molecular Neuroscience, 10, 263. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnmol.2017.00263</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renton, A. E., Chio, A., &amp; Traynor, B. J. (2014). State of play in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis genetics. Nature Neuroscience, 17, 17-23. https://doi.org/10.1038/nn.3584</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robberecht, W. (2000). Genetic markers of ALS. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis and Other Motor Neuron Disorders, 1(Suppl 2), S57-59. https://doi.org/10.1080/14660820052415835</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robberecht, W., &amp; Philips, T. (2013). The changing scene of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nature Reviews Neuroscience, 14, 248-264. https://doi.org/10.1038/nrn3430</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rojas, F., Cortes, N., Abarzua, S., Dyrda, A., &amp; van Zundert, B. (2014). Astrocytes expressing mutant SOD1 and TDP43 trigger motoneuron death that is mediated via sodium channels and nitroxidative stress. Frontiers in Molecular Neuroscience, 8, 24. https://doi.org/10.3389/fncel.2014.00024</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rothstein, J. D., Van Kammen, M., Levey, A. I., Martin, L. J., &amp; Kuncl, R. W. (1995). Selective loss of glial glutamate transporter GLT-1 in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Annals of Neurology, 38, 73-84. https://doi.org/10.1002/ana.410380114</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santos-Carvalho, A., Elvas, F., Alvaro, A. R., Ambrosio, A. F., &amp; Cavadas, C. (2013). Neuropeptide Y receptors activation protects rat retinal neural cells against necrotic and apoptotic cell death induced by glutamate. Cell Death and Disease, 4, e636. https://doi.org/10.1038/cddis.2013.160</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saurer, T. B., Ijames, S. G., &amp; Lysle, D. T. (2006). Neuropeptide Y Y1 receptors mediate morphine-induced reductions of natural killer cell activity. Journal of Neuroimmunology, 177, 18-26. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jneuroim.2006.05.002</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sayed, S., Van Dam, N. T., Horn, S. R., Kautz, M. M., Parides, M., Costi, S., &#x2026; Murrough, J. W. (2018). A randomized dose-ranging study of neuropeptide Y in patients with posttraumatic stress disorder. International Journal of Neuropsychopharmacology, 21, 3-11. https://doi.org/10.1093/ijnp/pyx109</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scotter, E. L., Vance, C., Nishimura, A. L., Lee, Y.-B., Chen, H.-J., Urwin, H., &#x2026; Shaw, C. E. (2014). Differential roles of the ubiquitin proteasome system and autophagy in the clearance of soluble and aggregated TDP-43 species. Journal of Cell Science, 127, 1263-1278. https://doi.org/10.1242/jcs.140087</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaw, P. J., Forrest, V., Ince, P. G., Richardson, J. P., &amp; Wastell, H. J. (1995). CSF and plasma amino acid levels in motor neuron disease: Elevation of CSF glutamate in a subset of patients. Neurodegeneration, 4, 209-216. https://doi.org/10.1006/neur.1995.0026</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi, Y., Hung, S.-T., Rocha, G., Lin, S., Linares, G. R., Staats, K. A., &#x2026; Ichida, J. K. (2019). Identification and therapeutic rescue of autophagosome and glutamate receptor defects in C9ORF72 and sporadic ALS neurons. JCI Insight, 4(15), 5. https://doi.org/10.1172/jci.insight.127736</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shibuya, K., Park, S. B., Geevasinga, N., Menon, P., Howells, J., Simon, N. G., &#x2026; Kiernan, M. C. (2016). Motor cortical function determines prognosis in sporadic ALS. Neurology, 87, 513-520. https://doi.org/10.1212/WNL.0000000000002912</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shruthi, S., Sumitha, R., Varghese, A. M., Ashok, S., Chandrasekhar Sagar, B. K., Sathyaprabha, T. N., &#x2026; Alladi, P. A. (2017). Brain-derived neurotrophic factor facilitates functional recovery from ALS-cerebral spinal fluid-induced neurodegenerative changes in the NSC-34 motor neuron cell line. Neurodegenerative Diseases, 17, 44-58. https://doi.org/10.1159/000447559</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva, A. P., Carvalho, A. P., Carvalho, C. M., &amp; Malva, J. O. (2001). Modulation of intracellular calcium changes and glutamate release by neuropeptide Y1 and Y2 receptors in the rat hippocampus: Differential effects in CA1, CA3 and dentate gyrus. Journal of Neurochemistry, 79, 286-296. https://doi.org/10.1046/j.1471-4159.2001.00560.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva, A. P., Pinheiro, P. S., Carvalho, A. P., Carvalho, C. M., Jakobsen, B., Zimmer, J., &amp; Malva, J. O. (2003). Activation of neuropeptide Y receptors is neuroprotective against excitotoxicity in organotypic hippocampal slice cultures. The FASEB Journal, 17, 1118-1120. https://doi.org/10.1096/fj.02-0885fje</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simpson, E. P., Henry, Y. K., Henkel, J. S., Smith, R. G., &amp; Appel, S. H. (2004). Increased lipid peroxidation in sera of ALS patients: A potential biomarker of disease burden. Neurology, 62, 1758-1765. https://doi.org/10.1212/WNL.62.10.1758</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spencer, B., Potkar, R., Metcalf, J., Thrin, I., Adame, A., Rockenstein, E., &amp; Masliah, E. (2016). Systemic central nervous system (CNS)-targeted delivery of neuropeptide Y (NPY) reduces neurodegeneration and increases neural precursor cell proliferation in a mouse model of Alzheimer disease. Journal of Biological Chemistry, 291, 1905-1920. https://doi.org/10.1074/jbc.M115.678185</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Statnick, M. A., Schober, D. A., &amp; Gehlert, D. R. (1997). Identification of multiple neuropeptide Y receptor subtypes in the human frontal cortex. European Journal of Pharmacology, 332, 299-305. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0014-2999(97)01031-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun, Q. Q., Huguenard, J. R., &amp; Prince, D. A. (2001). Neuropeptide Y receptors differentially modulate G-protein-activated inwardly rectifying K+ channels and high-voltage-activated Ca2+ channels in rat thalamic neurons. The Journal of Physiology, 531, 67-79.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takuma, H., Kwak, S., Yoshizawa, T., &amp; Kanazawa, I. (1999). Reduction of GluR2 RNA editing, a molecular change that increases calcium influx through AMPA receptors, selective in the spinal ventral gray of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Annals of Neurology, 46, 806-815. https://doi.org/10.1002/1531-8249(199912)46:6&lt;806:AID-ANA2&gt;3.0.CO;2-S</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Talme, T., Liu, Z., &amp; Sundqvist, K. G. (2008). The neuropeptide calcitonin gene-related peptide (CGRP) stimulates T cell migration into collagen matrices. Journal of Neuroimmunology, 196, 60-66. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jneuroim.2008.02.007</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor, J. P., Brown, R. H. Jr, &amp; Cleveland, D. W. (2016). Decoding ALS: From genes to mechanism. Nature, 539, 197-206. https://doi.org/10.1038/nature20413</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thakur, P., &amp; Nehru, B. (2014). Long-term heat shock proteins (HSPs) induction by carbenoxolone improves hallmark features of Parkinson's disease in a rotenone-based model. Neuropharmacology, 79, 190-200. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuropharm.2013.11.016</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thiriet, N., Deng, X., Solinas, M., Ladenheim, B., Curtis, W., Goldberg, S. R., &#x2026; Cadet, J. L. (2005). Neuropeptide Y protects against methamphetamine-induced neuronal apoptosis in the mouse striatum. Journal of Neuroscience, 25, 5273-5279. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.4893-04.2005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tilan, J., &amp; Kitlinska, J. (2016). Neuropeptide Y (NPY) in tumor growth and progression: Lessons learned from pediatric oncology. Neuropeptides, 55, 55-66. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.npep.2015.10.005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tovar, Y. R. L. B., Ramirez-Jarquin, U. N., Lazo-Gomez, R., &amp; Tapia, R. (2014). Trophic factors as modulators of motor neuron physiology and survival: Implications for ALS therapy. Frontiers in Cellular Neuroscience, 8, 61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsuzaka, K., Ishiyama, T., Pioro, E. P., &amp; Mitsumoto, H. (2001). Role of brain-derived neurotrophic factor in wobbler mouse motor neuron disease. Muscle and Nerve, 24, 474-480. https://doi.org/10.1002/mus.1029</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tydlacka, S., Wang, C. E., Wang, X., Li, S., &amp; Li, X. J. (2008). Differential activities of the ubiquitin-proteasome system in neurons versus glia may account for the preferential accumulation of misfolded proteins in neurons. Journal of Neuroscience, 28, 13285-13295. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.4393-08.2008</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ullman, B., Pernow, J., Lundberg, J. M., Astrom, H., &amp; Bergfeldt, L. (2002). Cardiovascular effects and cardiopulmonary plasma gradients following intravenous infusion of neuropeptide Y in humans: Negative dromotropic effect on atrioventricular node conduction. Clinical Science (Lond), 103, 535-542. https://doi.org/10.1042/cs1030535</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Damme, P., Bogaert, E., Dewil, M., Hersmus, N., Kiraly, D., Scheveneels, W., &#x2026; Robberecht, W. (2007). Astrocytes regulate GluR2 expression in motor neurons and their vulnerability to excitotoxicity. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 104, 14825-14830. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.0705046104</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Damme, P., Robberecht, W., &amp; Van Den Bosch, L. (2017). Modelling amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Progress and possibilities. Disease Models and Mechanisms, 10, 537-549. https://doi.org/10.1242/dmm.029058</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Leeuwen, F. W., &amp; Kampinga, H. H. (2018). Chapter 10 - Heat Shock Proteins and Protein Quality Control in Alzheimer&#x2019;s Disease. In M. S. Wolfe (Eds.), The Molecular and Cellular Basis of Neurodegenerative Diseases (269-298). Academic Press. https://doi.org/10.1016/B978-0-12-811304-2.00010-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Bos, M. A. J., Geevasinga, N., Higashihara, M., Menon, P., &amp; Vucic, S. (2019). Pathophysiology and diagnosis of ALS: Insights from advances in neurophysiological techniques. International Journal of Molecular Sciences, 20(11), 2818-https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms20112818</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van den Bos, M. A. J., Higashihara, M., Geevasinga, N., Menon, P., Kiernan, M. C., &amp; Vucic, S. (2018). Imbalance of cortical facilitatory and inhibitory circuits underlies hyperexcitability in ALS. Neurology, 91, e1669-e1676. https://doi.org/10.1212/WNL.0000000000006438</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van den Bos, M. A. J., Menon, P., Howells, J., Geevasinga, N., Kiernan, M. C., &amp; Vucic, S. (2018). Physiological processes underlying short interval intracortical facilitation in the human motor cortex. Frontiers in Neuroscience, 12, 240. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnins.2018.00240</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vollmer, L. L., Schmeltzer, S., Schurdak, J., Ahlbrand, R., Rush, J., Dolgas, C. M., &#x2026; Sah, R. (2016). Neuropeptide Y impairs retrieval of extinguished fear and modulates excitability of neurons in the infralimbic prefrontal cortex. Journal of Neuroscience, 36, 1306-1315. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.4955-13.2016</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic, S., &amp; Kiernan, M. C. (2017). Transcranial magnetic stimulation for the assessment of neurodegenerative disease. Neurotherapeutics: the Journal of the American Society for Experimental NeuroTherapeutics, 14, 91-106. https://doi.org/10.1007/s13311-016-0487-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, S. J. (2005). Activation of neuropeptide Y Y1 receptors inhibits glutamate release through reduction of voltage-dependent Ca2+ entry in the rat cerebral cortex nerve terminals: Suppression of this inhibitory effect by the protein kinase C-dependent facilitatory pathway. Neuroscience, 134, 987-1000. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuroscience.2005.04.053</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watts, G. D., Wymer, J., Kovach, M. J., Mehta, S. G., Mumm, S., Darvish, D., &#x2026; Kimonis, V. E. (2004). Inclusion body myopathy associated with Paget disease of bone and frontotemporal dementia is caused by mutant valosin-containing protein. Nature Genetics, 36, 377-381. https://doi.org/10.1038/ng1332</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weskamp, K., Tank, E. M., Miguez, R., McBride, J. P., G&#xf3;mez, N. B., White, M., &#x2026; Barmada, S. J. (2020). Shortened TDP43 isoforms upregulated by neuronal hyperactivity drive TDP43 pathology in ALS. Journal of Clinical Investigation, 130, 1139-1155. https://doi.org/10.1172/JCI130988</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wirth, M. J., Patz, S., &amp; Wahle, P. (2005). Transcellular induction of neuropeptide Y expression by NT4 and BDNF. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 102, 3064-3069. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.0404712102</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, G., Feder, A., Wegener, G., Bailey, C., Saxena, S., Charney, D., &amp; Math&#xe9;, A. A. (2011). Central functions of neuropeptide Y in mood and anxiety disorders. Expert Opinion on Therapeutic Targets, 15, 1317-1331. https://doi.org/10.1517/14728222.2011.628314</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yarosh, H. L., &amp; Angulo, J. A. (2012). Modulation of methamphetamine-induced nitric oxide production by neuropeptide Y in the murine striatum. Brain Research, 1483, 31-38. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.brainres.2012.09.013</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yi, M., Li, H., Wu, Z., Yan, J., Liu, Q., Ou, C., &amp; Chen, M. (2018). A promising therapeutic target for metabolic diseases: neuropeptide Y receptors in humans. Cellular Physiology and Biochemistry, 45, 88-107. https://doi.org/10.1159/000486225</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yokota, T., Yoshino, A., Inaba, A., &amp; Saito, Y. (1996). Double cortical stimulation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Journal of Neurology, Neurosurgery and Psychiatry, 61, 596-600. https://doi.org/10.1136/jnnp.61.6.596</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshida, H., Matsui, T., Yamamoto, A., Okada, T., &amp; Mori, K. (2001). XBP1 mRNA is induced by ATF6 and spliced by IRE1 in response to ER stress to produce a highly active transcription factor. Cell, 107, 881-891. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0092-8674(01)00611-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zanette, G., Tamburin, S., Manganotti, P., Refatti, N., Forgione, A., &amp; Rizzuto, N. (2002). Different mechanisms contribute to motor cortex hyperexcitability in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clinical Neurophysiology, 113, 1688-1697. https://doi.org/10.1016/S1388-2457(02)00288-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, W., Zhang, L., Liang, B., Schroeder, D., Zhang, Z. W., Cox, G. A., &#x2026; Lin, D. T. (2016). Hyperactive somatostatin interneurons contribute to excitotoxicity in neurodegenerative disorders. Nature Neuroscience, 19, 557-559. https://doi.org/10.1038/nn.4257</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, Y., &amp; Zhao, B. (2013). Oxidative stress and the pathogenesis of Alzheimer's disease. Oxidative Medicine and Cellular Longevity, 2013, 316523. https://doi.org/10.1155/2013/316523</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, J. R., Xu, Z., &amp; Jiang, C. L. (2008). Neuropeptide Y promotes TGF-beta1 production in RAW264.7 cells by activating PI3K pathway via Y1 receptor. Neurosci Bull, 24, 155-159.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ziemann, U., Rothwell, J. C., &amp; Ridding, M. C. (1996). Interaction between intracortical inhibition and facilitation in human motor cortex. Journal of Physiology, 496(Pt 3), 873-881. https://doi.org/10.1113/jphysiol.1996.sp021734</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ziv, Y., Ron, N., Butovsky, O., Landa, G., Sudai, E., Greenberg, N., &#x2026; Schwartz, M. (2006). Immune cells contribute to the maintenance of neurogenesis and spatial learning abilities in adulthood. Nature Neuroscience, 9, 268-275. https://doi.org/10.1038/nn1629</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>