<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">32657626</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>31</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2167-9223</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>22</Volume><Issue>1-2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis &amp; frontotemporal degeneration</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Longitudinal evaluation of upper motor neuron burden scales in primary lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>23</StartPage><EndPage>29</EndPage><MedlinePgn>23-29</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1080/21678421.2020.1790609</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>To assess whether published scales for measuring upper motor neuron burden (UMNB) show longitudinal change in patients with primary lateral sclerosis (PLS). <i>Design:</i> Retrospective calculation of three UMNB scales on a prospectively collected dataset from 53 patients with PLS enrolled in a longitudinal natural history study with at least 2 evaluation visits. UMNB scales were calculated according to their published descriptions. Non-linear trends over time of UMNB scale scores and slopes were calculated for each patient and correlations between UMNB scores and clinical measures were assessed. <i>Results:</i> All three UMNB scales exhibited increasing scores over the first 7.8 years of symptoms, with a flattening in slope after approximately 8 years. A scale used in imaging studies and the UPENN UMNS scale provided a better fit to the dataset than the MGH UMNB scale. All three UMNB scales exhibited moderate correlations with some clinical measures of movement, such as finger-tapping rate and timed gait. Correlations were strongest for the UPENN UMNS, which was also moderately correlated with the revised ALS functional rating scale. <i>Conclusion:</i> In a cohort of PLS patients enrolled in a natural history study, the three UMNB scales exhibited modest linear increases over the first 8 years of symptoms, followed by a plateau. Future clinical trials in PLS should consider stratification of patients by disease duration. UMNB scales may be useful secondary outcomes, but more sensitive primary outcome measures are needed for clinical trials for PLS.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Floeter</LastName><ForeName>Mary Kay</ForeName><Initials>MK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Motor Neuron Disorder Unit, National Institute of Neurological Disorders and Stroke, National Institutes of Health, Bethesda, MD, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Tianxia</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biostatistics Unit, Clinical Trials Unit, National Institute of Neurological Disorders and Stroke, National Institutes of Health, Bethesda, MD, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>Z01 NS002976</GrantID><Acronym>ImNIH</Acronym><Agency>Intramural NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>ZIA NS002976</GrantID><Acronym>ImNIH</Acronym><Agency>Intramural NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101587185</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2167-8421</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015331" MajorTopicYN="N">Cohort Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016472" MajorTopicYN="Y">Motor Neuron Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009046" MajorTopicYN="N">Motor Neurons</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Primary lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">natural history</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">outcome measures</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">spasticity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">upper motor neuron</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>DECLARATION OF INTEREST. The authors have no conflicts of interest to disclose. This study was supported by the intramural program of the National Institutes of Health, National Institute of Neurological Disorders and Stroke (Z01 NS002976).</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32657626</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS1675541</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7935469</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/21678421.2020.1790609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Turner MR, Cagnin A, Turkheimer FE, Miller CC, Shaw CE, Brooks DJ, Leigh PN, Banati RB. Evidence of widespread cerebral microglial activation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: an [11C](R)-PK11195 positron emission tomography study. Neurobiol Dis. 2004;15(3):601&#x2013;609.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15056468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quinn C, Edmundson C, Dahodwala N, Elman L. Reliable and efficient scale to assess upper motor neuron disease burden in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 2020;61(4):508&#x2013;511.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31743477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zurcher NR, Loggia ML, Lawson R, Chonde DB, Izquierdo-Garcia D, Yasek JE, Akeju O, Catana C, Rosen BR, Cudkowicz ME, et al. Increased in vivo glial activation in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: assessed with [(11)C]-PBR28. NeuroImage Clinical. 2015;7:409&#x2013;414.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4310932</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25685708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Statland JM, Barohn RJ, Dimachkie MM, Floeter MK, Mitsumoto H. Primary Lateral Sclerosis. Neurol Clin. 2015;33(4):749&#x2013;760.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4628724</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26515619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Chalabi A, Hardiman O, Kiernan MC, Chio A, Rix-Brooks B, van den Berg LH. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: moving towards a new classification system. Lancet Neurol. 2016;15(11):1182&#x2013;1194.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27647646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon PH, Cheng B, Katz IB, Pinto M, Hays AP, Mitsumoto H, Rowland LP. The natural history of primary lateral sclerosis. Neurology. 2006;66(5):647&#x2013;653.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16534101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singer MA, Statland JM, Wolfe GI, Barohn RJ. Primary lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 2007;35(3):291&#x2013;302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17212349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner MR, Barohn RJ, Corcia P, Fink JK, Harms MB, Kiernan MC, Ravits J, Silani V, Simmons Z, Statland J, et al. Primary lateral sclerosis: consensus diagnostic criteria. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2020. Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2020;91(4):373&#x2013;377.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7147236</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32029539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum JM, Stambler N, Malta E, Fuller C, Hilt D, Thurmond B, Nakanishi A. The ALSFRS-R: a revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. BDNF ALS Study Group (Phase III). J Neurol Sci. 1999;169(1&#x2013;2):13&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10540002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitsumoto H, Nagy PL, Gennings C, Murphy J, Andrews H, Goetz R, Floeter MK, Hupf J, Singleton J, Barohn RJ, et al. Phenotypic and molecular analyses of primary lateral sclerosis. Neurology Genetics. 2015;1(1):e3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4821084</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27066542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitsumoto H, Chiuzan C, Gilmore M, Zhang Y, Simmons Z, Paganoni S, Kisanuki YY, Zinman L, Jawdat O, Sorenson E, et al. Primary lateral sclerosis (PLS) functional rating scale: PLS-specific clinimetric scale. Muscle Nerve. 2020;61(2):163&#x2013;172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31758557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woo JH, Wang S, Melhem ER, Gee JC, Cucchiara A, McCluskey L, Elman L. Linear associations between clinically assessed upper motor neuron disease and diffusion tensor imaging metrics in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. PloS one. 2014;9(8):e105753.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4140827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25144708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pringle CE, Hudson AJ, Munoz DG, Kiernan JA, Brown WF, Ebers GC. Primary lateral sclerosis. Clinical features, neuropathology and diagnostic criteria. Brain. 1992;115(Pt 2):495&#x2013;520.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1606479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Litvan I, Mangone CA, Werden W, Bueri JA, Estol CJ, Garcea DO, Rey RC, Sica RE, Hallett M, Bartko JJ. Reliability of the NINDS Myotatic Reflex Scale. Neurology. 1996;47(4):969&#x2013;972.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8857728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bohannon RW, Smith MB. Interrater reliability of a modified Ashworth scale of muscle spasticity. Phys Ther. 1987;67(2):206&#x2013;207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3809245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Floeter MK, Katipally R, Kim MP, Schanz O, Stephen M, Danielian L, Wu T, Huey ED, Meoded A. Impaired corticopontocerebellar tracts underlie pseudobulbar affect in motor neuron disorders. Neurology. 2014;83(7):620&#x2013;627.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4141995</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25008395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Riper C Speech correction 4th ed. Englewoood Cliffs (NJ):Prentice Hall; 1963.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Folstein MF, Folstein SE, McHugh PR. &#x201c;Mini-mental state&#x201d;. A practical method for grading the cognitive state of patients for the clinician. J Psychiatr Res. 1975;12(3):189&#x2013;198.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1202204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bland JM, Altman DG. Calculating correlation coefficients with repeated observations: Part 1--Correlation within subjects. BMJ. 1995;310(6977):446.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2548822</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7873953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Floeter MK, Mills R. Progression in primary lateral sclerosis: a prospective analysis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2009;10(5&#x2013;6):339&#x2013;346.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3434688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19922121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finegan E, Chipika RH, Li Hi Shing S, Doherty MA, Hengeveld JC, Vajda A, Donaghy C, McLaughlin RL, Pender N, Hardiman O, et al. The clinical and radiological profile of primary lateral sclerosis: a population-based study. J Neurol. 2019;266(11):2718&#x2013;2733.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31325016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>