<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">32673410</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1476-5381</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>178</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>British journal of pharmacology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Br J Pharmacol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Clinical and preclinical evidence of somatosensory involvement in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1257</StartPage><EndPage>1268</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1257-1268</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/bph.15202</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) is the most common motor neuron neurodegenerative disease. Although it has been classically considered as a disease limited to the motor system, there is increasing evidence for the involvement of other neural and non-neuronal systems. In this review, we will discuss currently existing literature regarding the involvement of the sensory system in ALS. Human studies have reported intradermic small fibre loss, sensory axonal predominant neuropathy, as well as somatosensory cortex hyperexcitability. In line with this, ALS animal studies have demonstrated the involvement of several sensory components. Specifically, they have highlighted the impairment of sensory-motor networks as a potential mechanism for the disease. The elucidation of these "non-motor" systems involvement, which might also be part of the degeneration process, should prompt the scientific community to re-consider ALS as a pure motor neuron disease, which may in turn result in more holistic research approaches. LINKED ARTICLES: This article is part of a themed issue on Neurochemistry in Japan. To view the other articles in this section visit http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/bph.v178.6/issuetoc.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020 The British Pharmacological Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Riancho</LastName><ForeName>Javier</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Service of Neurology, Hospital Sierrallana-IDIVAL, Torrelavega, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine and Psychiatry, University of Cantabria, Santander, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centro de Investigaci&#xf3;n en Red de Enfermedades Neurodegenerativas, CIBERNED, Instituto Carlos III, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Paz-Fajardo</LastName><ForeName>Luc&#xed;a</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Service of Internal Medicine, Hospital Sierrallana-IDIVAL, Torrelavega, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>L&#xf3;pez de Muna&#xed;n</LastName><ForeName>Adolfo</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centro de Investigaci&#xf3;n en Red de Enfermedades Neurodegenerativas, CIBERNED, Instituto Carlos III, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurosciences Area, Biodonostia Research Institute, San Sebasti&#xe1;n, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurology Department, Donostia University Hospital-OSAKIDETZA, San Sebasti&#xe1;n, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurosciences Department, Basque Country University, San Sebasti&#xe1;n, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>NVAL 16/21</GrantID><Agency>Institute of Research Valdecilla (IDIVAL)</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Br J Pharmacol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7502536</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0007-1188</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009046" MajorTopicYN="N">Motor Neurons</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019636" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neurodegenerative Diseases</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010523" MajorTopicYN="Y">Peripheral Nervous System Diseases</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013003" MajorTopicYN="N">Somatosensory Cortex</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">clinical</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">preclinical</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sensory disorders</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32673410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bph.15202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Abe, K., Aoki, M., Ikeda, M., Watanabe, M., Hirai, S., &amp; Itoyama, Y. (1996). Clinical characteristics of familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with Cu/Zn superoxide dismutase gene mutations. Journal of the Neurological Sciences, 136, 108-116. https://doi.org/10.1016/0022-510X(95)00314-R</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al Chalabi, A., &amp; Hardiman, O. (2013). The epidemiology of ALS: A conspiracy of genes, environment and time. Nature Reviews Neurology, 9, 617-628. https://doi.org/10.1038/nrneurol.2013.203</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alexander, S. P. H., Cidlowski, J. A., Kelly, E., Mathie, A., Peters, J. A., Veale, E. L., &#x2026; Davies, J. A. (2019). The Concise Guide to PHARMACOLOGY 2019/20: Nuclear hormone receptors. British Journal of Pharmacology, 176(Suppl 1), S229-S246.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bosco, D. A., Morfini, G., Karabacak, N. M., Song, Y., Gros-Louis, F., Pasinelli, P., &#x2026; Brown, R. H. Jr. (2010). Wild-type and mutant SOD1 share an aberrant conformation and a common pathogenic pathway in ALS. Nature Neuroscience, 13, 1396-1403. https://doi.org/10.1038/nn.2660</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouvier, G., Laviolette, L., Kindler, F., et al. (1985). Dyspnea-pain counterirritation induced by inspiratory threshold loading: a laser-evoked potentials study. Journal of Applied Physiology, 112, 1166-1173.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brazis, P., Masdeu, J., &amp; Biller, J. (2011). Localization in clinical neurology (6th ed.). Philadelphia: Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caress, J. B., Ciarlone, S. L., Sullivan, E. A., Griffin L. P., &amp; Cartwright, M.S. (2016). Natural history of muscle cramps in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle &amp; Nerve, 53, 513-517. https://doi.org/10.1002/mus.24892</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chio, A., Logroscino, G., Traynor, B. J., Collins, J., Simeone, J. C., Goldstein, L. A., &amp; White, L. A. (2013). Global epidemiology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A systematic review of the published literature. Neuroepidemiology, 41, 118-130. https://doi.org/10.1159/000351153</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chio, A., Moglia, C., Canosa, A., Manera, U., Vasta, R., Brunetti, M., &#x2026; Calvo, A. (2019). Cognitive impairment across ALS clinical stages in a population-based cohort. Neurology, 93, e984-e994. https://doi.org/10.1212/WNL.0000000000008063</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chio, A., Mora, G., &amp; Lauria, G. (2016). Pain in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet Neurology, 16, 144-157.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen-Adad, J., El Mendili, M. M., Morizot-Koutlidis, R., Lehericy, S., Meininger, V., Blancho, S., &#x2026; Pradat, P. F. (2013). Involvement of spinal sensory pathway in ALS and specificity of cord atrophy to lower motor neuron degeneration. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis and Frontotemporal Degeneration, 14, 30-38. https://doi.org/10.3109/17482968.2012.701308</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cosi, V., Poloni, M., Mazzini, L., &amp; Callieco, R. (1984). Somatosensory evoked potentials in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Journal of Neurology, Neurosurgery, and Psychiatry, 47, 857-861. https://doi.org/10.1136/jnnp.47.8.857</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dalla, B. E., Lombardi, R., Porretta-Serapiglia, C., Ciano, C., Gellera, C., Pensato, V., &#x2026; Lauria, G. (2016). Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis causes small fiber pathology. European Journal of Neurology, 23, 416-420. https://doi.org/10.1111/ene.12936</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fincham, R. W., &amp; Vanallen, M. W. (1964). Sensory nerve conduction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology, 14, 31-33. https://doi.org/10.1212/WNL.14.1.31</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geser, F., Martinez-Lage, M., Robinson, J., Uryu, K., Neumann, M., Brandmeir, N. J., &#x2026; Trojanowski, J. Q. (2009). Clinical and pathological continuum of multisystem TDP-43 proteinopathies. Archives of Neurology, 66, 180-189. https://doi.org/10.1001/archneurol.2008.558</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gregory, R., Mills, K., &amp; Donaghy, M. (1993). Progressive sensory nerve dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A prospective clinical and neurophysiological study. Journal of Neurology, 240, 309-314. https://doi.org/10.1007/BF00838169</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo, Y. S., Wu, D. X., Wu, H. R., Wu, S. Y., Yang, C., Li, B., &#x2026; Li, C. Y. (2009). Sensory involvement in the SOD1-G93A mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Experimental &amp; Molecular Medicine, 41, 140-150. https://doi.org/10.3858/emm.2009.41.3.017</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gurney, M. E., Pu, H., Chiu, A. Y., Dal Canto, M. C., Polchow, C. Y., Alexander, D. D., &#x2026; Deng, H. X. (1994). Motor neuron degeneration in mice that express a human Cu,Zn superoxide dismutase mutation. Science, 264, 1772-1775. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.8209258</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haberberger, R. V., Barry, C., Dominguez, N., &amp; Matusica, D. (2019). Human dorsal root ganglia. Frontiers in Cellular Neuroscience, 19, 271. https://doi.org/10.3389/fncel.2019.00271</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamada, M., Hanajima, R., Terao, Y., Sato, F., Okano, T., Yuasa, K., &#x2026; Ugawa, Y. (2007). Median nerve somatosensory evoked potentials and their high-frequency oscillations in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clinical Neurophysiology, 118, 877-886. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.clinph.2006.12.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hammad, M., Silva, A., Glass, J., Sladky, J. T., &amp; Benatar, M. (2007). Clinical, electrophysiologic, and pathologic evidence for sensory abnormalities in ALS. Neurology, 69, 2236-2242. https://doi.org/10.1212/01.wnl.0000286948.99150.16</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harding, S. D., Sharman, J. L., Faccenda, E., Southan, C., Pawson, A. J., Ireland, S., &#x2026; NC-IUPHAR. (2018). The IUPHAR/BPS Guide to PHARMACOLOGY in 2018: Updates and expansion to encompass the new guide to IMMUNOPHARMACOLOGY. Nucleic Acids Research, 46, D1091-D1106. https://doi.org/10.1093/nar/gkx1121</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heads, T., Pollock, M., Robertson, A., Sutherland, W. H., &amp; Allpress, S. (1991). Sensory nerve pathology in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathologica, 82, 316-320. https://doi.org/10.1007/BF00308818</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Held, A., Major, P., Sahin, A., Reenan, R. A., Lipscombe, D., &amp; Wharton, K. A. (2019). Circuit dysfunction in SOD1-ALS model first detected in sensory feedback prior to motor neuron degeneration is alleviated by BMP signaling. The Journal of Neuroscience, 39, 2347-2364. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.1771-18.2019</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hodge, M. R., Horton, W., Brown, T., Herrick, R., Olsen, T., Hileman, M. E., &#x2026; Marcus, D. S. (2016). ConnectomeDB-Sharing human brain connectivity data. NeuroImage, 124, 1102-1107. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuroimage.2015.04.046</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iglesias, C., Sangari, S., El Mendili, M. M., Benali, H., Marchand-Pauvert, V., &amp; Pradat, P. F. (2015). Electrophysiological and spinal imaging evidences for sensory dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. BMJ Open, 5, e007659. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmjopen-2015-007659</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Imai, F., &amp; Yoshida, Y. (2018). Molecular mechanisms underlying monosynaptic sensory-motor circuit development in the spinal cord. Developmental Dynamics, 247, 581-587. https://doi.org/10.1002/dvdy.24611</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isaacs, J. D., Dean, A. F., Shaw, C. E., Al Chalabi, A., Mills, K. R., &amp; Leigh, P. N. (2007). Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with sensory neuropathy: Part of a multisystem disorder? Journal of Neurology, Neurosurgery, and Psychiatry, 78, 750-753.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isak, B., Pugdahl, K., Karlsson, P., Tankisi, H., Finnerup, N. B., Furtula, J., &#x2026; Fuglsang-Frederiksen, A. (2017). Quantitative sensory testing and structural assessment of sensory nerve fibres in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Journal of the Neurological Sciences, 373, 329-334. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jns.2017.01.005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isak, B., Tankisi, H., Johnsen, B., Pugdahl, K., Finnerup, N. B., &amp; Fuglsang-Frederiksen, A. (2016). Laser and somatosensory evoked potentials in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clinical Neurophysiology, 127, 3322-3328. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.clinph.2016.08.008</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isak, B., Tankisi, H., Johnsen, B., Pugdahl, K., Torvin, M. A., Finnerup, N. B., &#x2026; Fuglsang-Frederiksen, A. (2016). Involvement of distal sensory nerves in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle &amp; Nerve, 54, 1086-1092. https://doi.org/10.1002/mus.25157</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, J., Zhang, X., Ding, X., Song, M., &amp; Sui, K. (2019). Analysis of clinical and electrophysiological characteristics of 150 patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in China. Neurological Sciences, 40, 363-369. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10072-018-3633-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luigetti, M., Conte, A., Del Grande, A., Bisogni, G., Romano, A., &amp; Sabatelli, M. (2012). Sural nerve pathology in ALS patients: A single-centre experience. Neurological Sciences, 33, 1095-1099. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10072-011-0909-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matamala, J. M., Howells, J., Dharmadasa, T., Huynh, W., Park, S. B., Burke, D., &amp; Kiernan, M. C. (2018). Excitability of sensory axons in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clinical Neurophysiology, 129, 1472-1478. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.clinph.2018.03.014</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCombe, P. A., Wray, N. R., &amp; Henderson, R. D. (2017). Extra-motor abnormalities in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Another layer of heterogeneity. Expert Review of Neurotherapeutics, 17, 561-577. https://doi.org/10.1080/14737175.2017.1273772</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller, R. G., Jackson, C. E., Kasarskis, E. J., England, J. D., Forshew, D., Johnston, W., &#x2026; Shoesmith, C. (2009). Practice parameter update: The care of the patient with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Multidisciplinary care, symptom management, and cognitive/behavioral impairment (an evidence-based review): Report of the Quality Standards Subcommittee of the American Academy of Neurology. Neurology, 73, 1227-1233. https://doi.org/10.1212/WNL.0b013e3181bc01a4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mochizuki, Y., Mizutani, T., Shimizu, T., &amp; Kawata, A. (2011). Proportional neuronal loss between the primary motor and sensory cortex in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuroscience Letters, 503, 73-75. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neulet.2011.08.014</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nardone, R., Golaszewski, S., Thomschewski, A., Sebastianelli, L., Versace, V., Brigo, F., &#x2026; Trinka, E. (2020). Disinhibition of sensory cortex in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuroscience Letters, 722, 134860. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neulet.2020.134860</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nolano, M., Provitera, V., Manganelli, F., Iodice, R., Caporaso, G., Stancanelli, A., &#x2026; Mora, G. (2017). Non-motor involvement in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: New insight from nerve and vessel analysis in skin biopsy. Neuropathology and Applied Neurobiology, 43, 119-132. https://doi.org/10.1111/nan.12332</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phukan, J., Pender, N. P., &amp; Hardiman, O. (2007). Cognitive impairment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet Neurology, 6, 994-1003. https://doi.org/10.1016/S1474-4422(07)70265-X</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pugdahl, K., Fuglsang-Frederiksen, A., de Carvalho, M., Johnsen, B., Fawcett, P. R., Labarre-Vila, A., &#x2026; Schofield, I. S. (2007). Generalised sensory system abnormalities in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A European multicentre study. Journal of Neurology, Neurosurgery, and Psychiatry, 78, 746-749.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radtke, R. A., Erwin, A., &amp; Erwin, C. W. (1986). Abnormal sensory evoked potentials in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology, 36, 796-801. https://doi.org/10.1212/WNL.36.6.796</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren, Y., Liu, W., Li, Y., Sun, B., Li, Y., Yang, F., &#x2026; Huang, X. (2018). Cutaneous somatic and autonomic nerve TDP-43 deposition in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Journal of Neurology, 265, 1753-1763. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00415-018-8897-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riancho, J., Bosque-Varela, P., Perez-Pereda, S., Povedano, M., de Munain, A. L., &amp; Santurtun, A. (2018). The increasing importance of environmental conditions in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. International Journal of Biometeorology, 62, 1361-1374. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00484-018-1550-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riancho, J., Castanedo-V&#xe1;zquez, D., Gil-Bea, F., Tapia, O., Arozamena, J., Dur&#xe1;n-V&#xed;an, C., &#x2026; Lafarga, M. (2020). ALS-derived fibroblasts exhibit reduced proliferation rate, cytoplasmic TDP-43 aggregation and a higher susceptibility to DNA damage. Journal of Neurology, 267, 1291-1299. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00415-020-09704-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riancho, J., Gonzalo, I., Ruiz-Soto, M., &amp; Berciano, J. (2019). Why do motor neurons degenerate? Actualization in the pathogenesis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurolog&#xed;a, 34, 27-37. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nrl.2015.12.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riancho, J., Lozano-Cuesta, P., Santurtun, A., Sanchez-Juan, P., Lopez-Vega, J. M., Berciano, J., &amp; Polo, J. M. (2016). Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in Northern Spain 40 years later: What has changed? Neurodegenerative Diseases, 16, 337-341. https://doi.org/10.1159/000445750</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ringholz, G. M., Appel, S. H., Bradshaw, M., Cooke, N. A., Mosnik, D. M., &amp; Schulz, P. E. (2005). Prevalence and patterns of cognitive impairment in sporadic ALS. Neurology, 65, 586-590. https://doi.org/10.1212/01.wnl.0000172911.39167.b6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rubio, M. A., Herrando-Grabulosa, M., Vilches, J. J., &amp; Navarro, X. (2016). Involvement of sensory innervation in the skin of SOD1(G93A) ALS mice. Journal of the Peripheral Nervous System, 21, 88-95. https://doi.org/10.1111/jns.12164</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sangari, S., Giron, A., Marrelec, G., Pradat, P. F., &amp; Marchand-Pauvert, V. (2018). Abnormal cortical brain integration of somatosensory afferents in ALS. Clinical Neurophysiology, 129, 874-884. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.clinph.2017.12.008</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sangari, S., Iglesias, C., El Mendili, M. M., Benali, H., Pradat, P. F., &amp; Marchand-Pauvert, V. (2016). Impairment of sensory-motor integration at spinal level in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clinical Neurophysiology, 127, 1968-1977. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.clinph.2016.01.014</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sassone, J., Taiana, M., Lombardi, R., Porretta-Serapiglia, C., Freschi, M., Bonanno, S., &#x2026; Lauria, G. (2016). ALS mouse model SOD1G93A displays early pathology of sensory small fibers associated to accumulation of a neurotoxic splice variant of peripherin. Human Molecular Genetics, 25, 1588-1599. https://doi.org/10.1093/hmg/ddw035</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schafer, M. K., Bellouze, S., Jacquier, A., Schaller, S., Richard, L., Mathis, S., &#x2026; Haase, G. (2017). Sensory neuropathy in progressive motor neuronopathy (pmn) mice is associated with defects in microtubule polymerization and axonal transport. Brain Pathology, 27, 459-471. https://doi.org/10.1111/bpa.12422</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seki, S., Yamamoto, T., Quinn, K., Spigelman, I., Pantazis, A., Olcese, R., &#x2026; Venugopal, S. (2019). Circuit-specific early impairment of proprioceptive sensory neurons in the SOD1(G93A) mouse model for ALS. The Journal of Neuroscience, 39, 8798-8815. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.1214-19.2019</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimizu, T., Bokuda, K., Kimura, H., Kamiyama, T., Nakayama, Y., Kawata, A., &#x2026; Ugawa, Y. (2018). Sensory cortex hyperexcitability predicts short survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology, 90, e1578-e1587. https://doi.org/10.1212/WNL.0000000000005424</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimizu, T., Kawata, A., Kato, S., Hayashi, M., Takamoto, K., Hayashi, H., &#x2026; Oda, M. (2000). Autonomic failure in ALS with a novel SOD1 gene mutation. Neurology, 54, 1534-1537. https://doi.org/10.1212/WNL.54.7.1534</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimizu, T., Nakayama, Y., Funai, A., Morishima, R., Hayashi, K., Bokuda, K., &#x2026; Isozaki, E. (2020). Progressive deterioration of sensory cortex excitability in advanced amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with invasive ventilation. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis and Frontotemporal Degeneration, 21, 147-149. https://doi.org/10.1080/21678421.2019.1704015</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simone, I. L., Tortelli, R., Samarelli, V., D'Errico, E., Sardaro, M., Difruscolo, O., &#x2026; de Tommaso, M. (2010). Laser evoked potentials in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Journal of the Neurological Sciences, 288, 106-111. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jns.2009.09.023</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taiana, M., Sassone, J., &amp; Lauria, G. (2016). Mutant SOD1 accumulation in sensory neurons does not associate with endoplasmic reticulum stress features: Implications for differential vulnerability of sensory and motor neurons to SOD1 toxicity. Neuroscience Letters, 627, 107-114. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neulet.2016.05.057</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tao, Q. Q., Wei, Q., &amp; Wu, Z. Y. (2018). Sensory nerve disturbance in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Life Sciences, 203, 242-245. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.lfs.2018.04.052</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Theys, P. A., Peeters, E., &amp; Robberecht, W. (1999). Evolution of motor and sensory deficits in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis estimated by neurophysiological techniques. Journal of Neurology, 246, 438-442. https://doi.org/10.1007/s004150050379</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Truini, A., Biasiotta, A., Onesti, E., Di Stefano, G., Ceccanti, M., La Cesa, S., &#x2026; Inghilleri, M. (2015). Small-fibre neuropathy related to bulbar and spinal-onset in patients with ALS. Journal of Neurology, 262, 1014-1018. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00415-015-7672-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van der Graaff, M. M., de Jong, J. M. B. V., Baas, F., &amp; de Visser, M. (2009). Upper motor neuron and extra-motor neuron involvement in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A clinical and brain imaging review. Neuromuscular Disorders, 19, 53-58. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nmd.2008.10.002</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Es, M. A., Hardiman, O., Chio, A., Al Chalabi, A., Pasterkamp, R. J., Veldink, J. H., &amp; van den Berg, L. H. (2017). Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet, 390, 2084-2098. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0140-6736(17)31287-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaughan, S. K., Kemp, Z., Hatzipetros, T., Vieira, F., &amp; Valdez, G. (2015). Degeneration of proprioceptive sensory nerve endings in mice harboring amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-causing mutations. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 523, 2477-2494. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.23848</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaughan, S. K., Sutherland, N. M., Zhang, S., Hatzipetros, T., Vieira, F., &amp; Valdez, G. (2018). The ALS-inducing factors, TDP43(A315T) and SOD1(G93A), directly affect and sensitize sensory neurons to stress. Scientific Reports, 8, 16582. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-018-34510-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallace, V. C., Ellis, C. M., Burman, R., Knights, C., Shaw, C. E., &amp; Al-Chalabi, A. (2014). The evaluation of pain in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A case controlled observational study. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis and Frontotemporal Degeneration, 15, 520-527. https://doi.org/10.3109/21678421.2014.951944</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, F., Xu, R., Dowd, E., Zang, Y., Gong, H., &amp; Wang, Z. (2014). Alterations in regional functional coherence within the sensory-motor network in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuroscience Letters, 558, 192-196. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neulet.2013.11.022</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zufiria, M., Gil-Bea, F. J., Fernandez-Torron, R., Poza, J. J., Munoz-Blanco, J. L., Rojas-Garcia, R., &#x2026; de Munain, A. L. (2016). ALS: A bucket of genes, environment, metabolism and unknown ingredients. Progress in Neurobiology, 142, 104-129. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pneurobio.2016.05.004</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>