<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">32716521</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1469-7793</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>598</Volume><Issue>19</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Journal of physiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Physiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Spinal motoneurones are intrinsically more responsive in the adult G93A SOD1&#xa0;mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>4385</StartPage><EndPage>4403</EndPage><MedlinePgn>4385-4403</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1113/JP280097</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="KEY POINTS">Although in vitro recordings using neonatal preparations from mouse models of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) suggest increased motoneurone excitability, in vivo recordings in adult ALS mouse models have been conflicting. In adult G93A SOD1&#xa0;models, spinal motoneurones have previously been shown to have deficits in repetitive firing, in contrast to the G127X SOD1&#xa0;mouse model. Our in vivo intracellular recordings in barbiturate-anaesthetized adult male G93A SOD1&#xa0;mice reveal that the incidence of failure to fire with current injection was equally low in control and ALS mice (&#x223c;2%). We show that failure to fire repetitively can be a consequence of experimental protocol and should not be used alone to classify otherwise normal motoneurones as hypo-excitable. Motoneurones in the G93A SOD1&#xa0;mice showed an increased response to inputs, with lower rheobase, higher input-output gains and increased activation of persistent inward currents.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="ABSTRACT">In vitro studies from transgenic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis models have suggested an increased excitability of spinal motoneurones. However, in vivo intracellular recordings from adult amyotrophic lateral sclerosis mice models have produced conflicting findings. Previous investigations using barbiturate anaesthetized G93A SOD1&#xa0;mice have suggested that some motoneurones are hypo-excitable, defined by deficits in repetitive firing. Our own previous recordings in G127X SOD1&#xa0;mice using different anaesthesia, however, showed no repetitive firing deficits and increased persistent inward currents at symptom onset. These discrepancies may be a result of differences between models, symptomatic stage, anaesthesia or technical differences. To investigate this, we repeated our original experiments, but in adult male G93A SOD1&#xa0;mice, at both presymptomatic and symptomatic stages, under barbiturate anaesthesia. In vivo intracellular recordings from antidromically identified spinal motoneurones revealed that the incidence of failure to fire with current injection was equally low in control and G93A SOD1&#xa0;mice (&#x223c;2%). Motoneurones in G93A SOD1&#xa0;mice fired significantly more spontaneous action potentials. Rheobase was significantly lower and the input resistance and input-output gain were significantly higher in both presymptomatic and symptomatic G93A SOD1&#xa0;mice. This was despite a significant increase in the duration of the post-spike after-hyperpolarization in both presymptomatic and symptomatic G93A SOD1&#xa0;mice. Finally, evidence of increased activation of persistent inward currents was seen in both presymptomatic and symptomatic G93A SOD1&#xa0;mice. Our results do not confirm previous reports of hypo-excitability of spinal motoneurones in the G93A SOD1&#xa0;mouse and demonstrate that the motoneurones show an increased response to inputs.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020 The Authors. The Journal of Physiology &#xa9; 2020 The Physiological Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jensen</LastName><ForeName>Dennis B</ForeName><Initials>DB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience, University of Copenhagen, Panum Institute, Blegdamsvej 3, Copenhagen N, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kadlecova</LastName><ForeName>Marion</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience, University of Copenhagen, Panum Institute, Blegdamsvej 3, Copenhagen N, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Allodi</LastName><ForeName>Ilary</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience, University of Copenhagen, Panum Institute, Blegdamsvej 3, Copenhagen N, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Meehan</LastName><ForeName>Claire F</ForeName><Initials>CF</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4885-4326</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience, University of Copenhagen, Panum Institute, Blegdamsvej 3, Copenhagen N, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Physiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0266262</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0022-3751</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 1.15.1.1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D013482">Superoxide Dismutase</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 1.15.1.1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000072105">Superoxide Dismutase-1</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="CommentIn"><RefSource>J Physiol. 2021 Sep;599(17):4231-4232</RefSource><PMID Version="1">34192811</PMID></CommentsCorrections><CommentsCorrections RefType="CommentIn"><RefSource>J Physiol. 2021 Sep;599(17):4233-4236</RefSource><PMID Version="1">34254695</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004195" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Models, Animal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051379" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008822" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice, Transgenic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009046" MajorTopicYN="N">Motor Neurons</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013116" MajorTopicYN="N">Spinal Cord</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013482" MajorTopicYN="N">Superoxide Dismutase</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000072105" MajorTopicYN="N">Superoxide Dismutase-1</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ALS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">G93A SOD1</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">excitability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">motoneurones</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32716521</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/JP280097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Alves CJ, de Santana LP, dos Santos AJ, de Oliveira GP, Duobles T, Scorisa JM, Martins RS, Maximino JR &amp; Chadi G (2011). Early motor and electrophysiological changes in transgenic mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and gender differences on clinical outcome. Brain Res 1394, 90-104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellardita C, Caggiano V, Leiras R, Caldeira V, Fuchs A, Bouvier J, Low P &amp; Kiehn O (2017). Spatiotemporal correlation of spinal network dynamics underlying spasms in chronic spinalized mice. eLife 6, e23011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellingham MC (2013). Pre- and postsynaptic mechanisms underlying inhibition of hypoglossal motor neuron excitability by riluzole. J Neurophysiol 110, 1047-1061.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benavides J, Camelin JC, Mitrani N, Flamand F, Uzan A, Legrand JJ, Gueremy C &amp; Le Fur G (1985). 2-Amino-6-trifluoromethoxy benzothiazole, a possible antagonist of excitatory amino acid neurotransmission-II. Biochemical properties. Neuropharmacology 24, 1085-1092.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bensimon G, Lacomblez L &amp; Meininger V (1994). A controlled trial of riluzole in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. ALS/Riluzole Study Group. N Engl J Med 330, 585-591.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonnevie VS, Dimintiyanova KP, Hedegaard A, Lehnhoff J, Grondahl L, Moldovan M &amp; Meehan CF (2020). Shorter axon initial segments do not cause repetitive firing impairments in the adult presymptomatic G127X SOD-1 amyotrophic lateral sclerosis mouse. Sci Rep 10, 1280.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bui TV, Ter-Mikaelian M, Bedrossian D &amp; Rose PK (2006). Computational estimation of the distribution of L-type Ca(2+) channels in motoneurons based on variable threshold of activation of persistent inward currents. J Neurophysiol 95, 225-241.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Button DC, Gardiner K, Marqueste T &amp; Gardiner PF (2006). Frequency-current relationships of rat hindlimb alpha-motoneurones. J Physiol 573, 663-677.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casas C, Herrando-Grabulosa M, Manzano R, Mancuso R, Osta R &amp; Navarro X (2013). Early presymptomatic cholinergic dysfunction in a murine model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain Behav 3, 145-158.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centonze D, Calabresi P, Pisani A, Marinelli S, Marfia GA &amp; Bernardi G (1998). Electrophysiology of the neuroprotective agent riluzole on striatal spiny neurons. Neuropharmacology 37, 1063-1070.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang Q &amp; Martin LJ (2016). Voltage-gated calcium channels are abnormal in cultured spinal motoneurons in the G93A-SOD1 transgenic mouse model of ALS. Neurobiol Dis 93, 78-95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi CI, Lee YD, Gwag BJ, Cho SI, Kim SS &amp; Suh-Kim H (2008). Effects of estrogen on lifespan and motor functions in female hSOD1 G93A transgenic mice. J Neurol Sci 268, 40-47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delestree N, Manuel M, Iglesias C, Elbasiouny SM, Heckman CJ &amp; Zytnicki D (2014). Adult spinal motoneurones are not hyperexcitable in a mouse model of inherited amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Physiol 592, 1687-1703.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devlin AC, Burr K, Borooah S, Foster JD, Cleary EM, Geti I, Vallier L, Shaw CE, Chandran S &amp; Miles GB (2015). Human iPSC-derived motoneurons harbouring TARDBP or C9ORF72 ALS mutations are dysfunctional despite maintaining viability. Nat Commun 6, 5999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dimintiyanova KP, Wienecke J, Jensen DB &amp; Meehan CF (2016). Time course of axon initial segment plasticity caudal to a complete spinal cord transection in rats. Society for Neuroscience Abstracts, Program No. 142.117. 2016 Neuroscience Meetin Planer. San Diego, CA: Society for Neuroscience. Online.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dukkipati SS, Garrett TL &amp; Elbasiouny SM (2018). The vulnerability of spinal motoneurons and soma size plasticity in a mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Physiol 596, 1723-1745.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elbasiouny SM, Bennett DJ &amp; Mushahwar VK (2005). Simulation of dendritic CaV1.3 channels in cat lumbar motoneurons: spatial distribution. J Neurophysiol 94, 3961-3974.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fischer LR, Culver DG, Tennant P, Davis AA, Wang M, Castellano-Sanchez A, Khan J, Polak MA &amp; Glass JD (2004). Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis is a distal axonopathy: evidence in mice and man. Exp Neurol 185, 232-240.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guertin PA &amp; Hounsgaard J (1999). Non-volatile general anaesthetics reduce spinal activity by suppressing plateau potentials. Neuroscience 88, 353-358.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gurney ME, Pu H, Chiu AY, Dal Canto MC, Polchow CY, Alexander DD, Caliendo J, Hentati A, Kwon YW &amp; Deng HX, et&#xa0;al (1994). Motor neuron degeneration in mice that express a human Cu,Zn superoxide dismutase mutation. Science 264, 1772-1775.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hebert T, Drapeau P, Pradier L &amp; Dunn RJ (1994). Block of the rat brain IIA sodium channel alpha subunit by the neuroprotective drug riluzole. Mol Pharmacol 45, 1055-1060.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herron LR &amp; Miles GB (2012). Gender-specific perturbations in modulatory inputs to motoneurons in a mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuroscience 226, 313-323.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jensen DB &amp; Meehan CF (2018). Spinal motoneurones are not hypoexcitable in the G93A SOD1 mouse model of Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. Society for Neuroscience Abstracts, Program No. 771.711. 2018 Neuroscience Meetin Planer. San Diego, CA: Society for Neuroscience. Online.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jonsson PA, Ernhill K, Andersen PM, Bergemalm D, Brannstrom T, Gredal O, Nilsson P &amp; Marklund SL (2004). Minute quantities of misfolded mutant superoxide dismutase-1 cause amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain 127, 73-88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J&#xf8;rgensen HS, Jensen DB, Dimintiyanova KP, Bonnevie VS, Hedegaard A, Lehnhoff J, Moldovan M, Grondahl L &amp; Meehan CF (2020). Increased axon initial segment length results in increased Na+ currents in spinal motoneurones at symptom onset in the G127X SOD1 mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. bioRxiv, 2020.2006.2025.096552.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuo JJ, Schonewille M, Siddique T, Schults AN, Fu R, Bar PR, Anelli R, Heckman CJ &amp; Kroese AB (2004). Hyperexcitability of cultured spinal motoneurons from presymptomatic ALS mice. J Neurophysiol 91, 571-575.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuo JJ, Siddique T, Fu R &amp; Heckman CJ (2005). Increased persistent Na(+) current and its effect on excitability in motoneurones cultured from mutant SOD1 mice. J Physiol 563, 843-854.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lamanauskas N &amp; Nistri A (2008). Riluzole blocks persistent Na+ and Ca2+ currents and modulates release of glutamate via presynaptic NMDA receptors on neonatal rat hypoglossal motoneurons in vitro. Eur J Neurosci 27, 2501-2514.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee RH &amp; Heckman CJ (1996). Influence of voltage-sensitive dendritic conductances on bistable firing and effective synaptic current in cat spinal motoneurons in vivo. J Neurophysiol 76, 2107-2110.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maglemose R, Hedegaard A, Lehnhoff J, Dimintiyanova KP, Moldovan M, Grondahl L &amp; Meehan CF (2017). Potassium channel abnormalities are consistent with early axon degeneration of motor axons in the G127X SOD1 mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Exp Neurol 292, 154-167.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martinez-Silva ML, Imhoff-Manuel RD, Sharma A, Heckman CJ, Shneider NA, Roselli F, Zytnicki D &amp; Manuel M (2018). Hypoexcitability precedes denervation in the large fast-contracting motor units in two unrelated mouse models of ALS. eLife 7, e30955.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meehan CF, Mayr KA, Manuel M, Nakanishi ST &amp; Whelan PJ (2017). Decerebrate mouse model for studies of the spinal cord circuits. Nat Protoc 12, 732-747.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meehan CF, Moldovan M, Marklund SL, Graffmo KS, Nielsen JB &amp; Hultborn H (2010a). Intrinsic properties of lumbar motor neurones in the adult G127insTGGG superoxide dismutase-1 mutant mouse in vivo: evidence for increased persistent inward currents. Acta Physiol 200, 361-376.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meehan CF, Sukiasyan N, Zhang M, Nielsen JB &amp; Hultborn H (2010b). Intrinsic properties of mouse lumbar motoneurons revealed by intracellular recording in vivo. J Neurophysiol 103, 2599-2610.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller RG, Mitchell JD &amp; Moore DH (2012). Riluzole for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS)/motor neuron disease (MND). The Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews, Cd001447.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noto Y, Shibuya K, Vucic S &amp; Kiernan MC (2016). Novel therapies in development that inhibit motor neuron hyperexcitability in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Expert Rev Neurother 16, 1147-1154.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piotrkiewicz M &amp; Hausmanowa-Petrusewicz I (2011). Motoneuron afterhyperpolarisation duration in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Physiol 589, 2745-2754.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pullen AH &amp; Athanasiou D (2009). Increase in presynaptic territory of C-terminals on lumbar motoneurons of G93A SOD1 mice during disease progression. Eur J Neurosci 29, 551-561.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quinlan KA, Schuster JE, Fu R, Siddique T &amp; Heckman CJ (2011). Altered postnatal maturation of electrical properties in spinal motoneurons in a mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Physiol 589, 2245-2260.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sareen D, O'Rourke JG, Meera P, Muhammad AK, Grant S, Simpkinson M, Bell S, Carmona S, Ornelas L, Sahabian A, Gendron T, Petrucelli L, Baughn M, Ravits J, Harms MB, Rigo F, Bennett CF, Otis TS, Svendsen CN &amp; Baloh RH (2013). Targeting RNA foci in iPSC-derived motor neurons from ALS patients with a C9ORF72 repeat expansion. Sci Transl Med 5, 208ra149.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuster JE, Fu R, Siddique T &amp; Heckman CJ (2012). Effect of prolonged riluzole exposure on cultured motoneurons in a mouse model of ALS. J Neurophysiol 107, 484-492.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turkin VV, O'Neill D, Jung R, Iarkov A &amp; Hamm TM (2010). Characteristics and organization of discharge properties in rat hindlimb motoneurons. J Neurophysiol 104, 1549-1565.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Urbani A &amp; Belluzzi O (2000). Riluzole inhibits the persistent sodium current in mammalian CNS neurons. Eur J Neurosci 12, 3567-3574.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wainger BJ, Kiskinis E, Mellin C, Wiskow O, Han SS, Sandoe J, Perez NP, Williams LA, Lee S, Boulting G, Berry JD, Brown RH, Jr., Cudkowicz ME, Bean BP, Eggan K &amp; Woolf CJ (2014). Intrinsic membrane hyperexcitability of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patient-derived motor neurons. Cell Rep 7, 1-11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang YJ, Lin MW, Lin AA &amp; Wu SN (2008). Riluzole-induced block of voltage-gated Na+ current and activation of BKCa channels in cultured differentiated human skeletal muscle cells. Life Sci 82, 11-20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu SN &amp; Li HF (1999). Characterization of riluzole-induced stimulation of large-conductance calcium-activated potassium channels in rat pituitary GH3 cells. J Investig Med 47, 484-495.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>