<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">32725316</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2629-3277</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Stem cell reviews and reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Stem Cell Rev Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Umbilical Cord Mesenchymal Stem Cells in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis: an Original Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>922</StartPage><EndPage>932</EndPage><MedlinePgn>922-932</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s12015-020-10016-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) is still incurable. Although different therapies can affect the health and survival of patients. Our aim is to evaluate the effect of umbilical mesenchymal stem cells administrated intrathecally to patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis on disability development and survival.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">This case-control study involved 67 patients treated with Wharton's jelly mesenchymal stem cells (WJ-MSC). The treated patients were paired with 67 reference patients from the PRO-ACT database which contains patient records from 23 ALS clinical studies (phase 2/3). Patients in the treatment and reference groups were fully matched in terms of race, sex, onset of symptoms (bulbar/spinal), FT9 disease stage at the beginning of therapy and concomitant amyotrophic lateral sclerosis medications. Progression rates prior to treatment varied within a range of &#xb1;&#x2009;0.5 points. All patients received three intrathecal injections of Wharton's jelly-derived mesenchymal stem cells every two months at a dose of 30&#x2009;&#xd7;&#x2009;10<sup>6</sup> cells. Patients were assessed using the ALSFRS-R scale. Survival times were followed-up until March 2020.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Median survival time increased two-fold in all groups. In terms of progression, three response types measured in ALSFRS-R were observed: decreased progression rate (n&#xa0;=&#x2009;21, 31.3%), no change in progression rate (n&#xa0;=&#x2009;33, 49.3%) and increased progression rate (n&#xa0;=&#x2009;13, 19.4%). Risk-benefit ratios were favorable in all groups. No serious adverse drug reactions were observed.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="INTERPRETATION">Wharton's jelly-derived mesenchymal stem cells therapy is safe and effective in some ALS patients, regardless of the clinical features and demographic factors excluding sex. The female sex and a good therapeutic response to the first administration are significant predictors of efficacy following further administrations. Graphical Abstract Medical therapeutic experiment with retrospective case-control analyses.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Barczewska</LastName><ForeName>Monika</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, University of Warmia and Mazury, Olsztyn, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Instytut Terapii Kom&#xf3;rkowych S.A., FamiCord Group, Olsztyn, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University Clinical Hospital, Olsztyn, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maksymowicz</LastName><ForeName>Stanis&#x142;aw</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6606-9575</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Instytut Terapii Kom&#xf3;rkowych S.A., FamiCord Group, Olsztyn, Poland. stanislaw.maksymowicz@uwm.edu.pl.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology and Sociology of Health and Public Health, Collegium Medicum, University of Warmia and Mazury, Warszawska 30, 10-082, Olsztyn, Poland. stanislaw.maksymowicz@uwm.edu.pl.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zdoli&#x144;ska-Malinowska</LastName><ForeName>Izabela</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Polski Bank Kom&#xf3;rek Macierzystych S.A., FamiCord Group, Warsaw, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Siwek</LastName><ForeName>Tomasz</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Instytut Terapii Kom&#xf3;rkowych S.A., FamiCord Group, Olsztyn, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University Clinical Hospital, Olsztyn, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of Warmia and Mazury, Olsztyn, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Grudniak</LastName><ForeName>Mariusz</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Polski Bank Kom&#xf3;rek Macierzystych S.A., FamiCord Group, Warsaw, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016430">Clinical Trial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Stem Cell Rev Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101752767</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2629-3277</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018450" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Progression</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D045164" MajorTopicYN="Y">Mesenchymal Stem Cell Transplantation</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D059630" MajorTopicYN="N">Mesenchymal Stem Cells</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000166" MajorTopicYN="Y">cytology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016019" MajorTopicYN="N">Survival Analysis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014470" MajorTopicYN="N">Umbilical Cord</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000166" MajorTopicYN="Y">cytology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ALS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Medical experiment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Progression rate</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Survival</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Umbilical cord</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">WJ-MSC</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Instytut Terapii Kom&#xf3;rkowych S.A. (ITK) in Olsztyn is a private medical institution specialized in innovative commercial therapy which uses MSC. The Institute is partially owned by the University of Warmia and Mazury and controlled by Polski Bank Kom&#xf3;rek Macierzystych S.A. (PBKM). M.B., S.M. and T.S. are employees of the Instytut Terapii Kom&#xf3;rkowych S.A. I.Z.-M. and M.G. are employees of the Polski Bank Kom&#xf3;rek Macierzystych S.A. The management of the ITK and PBKM had no influence on the collection, analysis and interpretation of data.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32725316</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7456414</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12015-020-10016-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s12015-020-10016-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2; A, Mora G, Moglia C, Manera U, Canosa A, Cammarosano S, Ilardi A, Bertuzzo D, Bersano E, Cugnasco P, Grassano M, Pisano F, Mazzini L, Calvo A, for the Piemonte and Valle d&#x2019;Aosta Register for ALS (PARALS) Secular trends of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: The Piemonte and Valle d&#x2019;Aosta register. JAMA Neurology. 2017;74(9):1097&#x2013;1104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5710181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28692730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu G, David BT, Trawczynski M, Fessler RG. Advances in pluripotent stem cells: History, mechanisms, technologies, and applications. Stem Cell Reviews and Reports. 2020;16:3&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6987053</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31760627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao A, Pan Y, Cai S. Patient-specific cells for modeling and decoding amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Advances and challenges. Stem Cell Reviews and Reports. 2020;16:482&#x2013;502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31916190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bensimon G, Lacomblez L, Meininger V. A controlled trial of riluzole in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. ALS/Riluzole study group. The New England Journal of Medicine. 1994;330(9):585&#x2013;591.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8302340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen HKS, Sakowski SA, Feldman EL. Intraspinal stem cell transplantation for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Annals of Neurology. 2016;3:342&#x2013;353.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4789073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26696091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>George S, Hamblin MR, Abrahamse H. Differentiation of Mesenchymal stem cells to neuroglia: In the context of cell Signalling. Stem Cell Reviews and Reports. 2019;15:814&#x2013;826.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6925073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31515658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao CP, Zhang C, Zhouet S-N, et al. Human mesenchymal stromal cells ameliorate the phenotype of SOD1-G93A ALS mice. Cytotherapy. 2007;9(5):414&#x2013;426.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17786603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang C, Zhou C, Teng J-J, Zhao RL, Song YQ, Zhang C. Multiple administrations of human marrow stromal cells through cerebrospinal fluid prolong survival in a transgenic mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Cytotherapy. 2009;11(3):299&#x2013;306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19333801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marconi S, Bonaconsa M, Scambi I, Squintani GM, Rui W, Turano E, Ungaro D, D&#x2019;Agostino S, Barbieri F, Angiari S, Farinazzo A, Constantin G, del Carro U, Bonetti B, Mariotti R. Systemic treatment with adipose-derived mesenchymal stem cells ameliorates clinical and pathological features in the amyotrophic lateral sclerosis murine model. Neuroscience. 2013;248:333&#x2013;343.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23727509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boruczkowski D, Zdoli&#x144;ska-Malinowska I. A retrospective analysis of safety and efficacy of Wharton&#x2019;s jelly stem cell Administration in Children with Spina bifida. Stem Cell Reviews and Reports. 2019;15:717&#x2013;729.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31222411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El Brooks BR. Escorial world federation of neurology criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Subcommittee on motor neuron diseases/amyotrophic lateral sclerosis of the world federation of neurology research group on neuromuscular diseases and the El Escorial "Clinical limits of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis" workshop contributors. Journal of the Neurological Sciences. 1994;124:96&#x2013;107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7807156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dominici M, le Blanc K, Mueller I, et al. Minimal criteria for defining multipotent mesenchymal stromal cells. The International Society for Cellular Therapy position statement. Cytotherapy. 2006;8(4):315&#x2013;317.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16923606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goutman SA, Brown MB, Glass JD, Boulis NM, Johe K, Hazel T, Cudkowicz M, Atassi N, Borges L, Patil PG, Sakowski SA, Feldman EL. Long-term phase 1/2 intraspinal stem cell transplantation outcomes in ALS. Annals of Clinical Translational Neurology. 2018;5(6):730&#x2013;740.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5989736</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29928656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor AA, Fournier C, Polak M, Wang L, Zach N, Keymer M, Glass JD, Ennist DL, The Pooled Resource Open-Access ALS Clinical Trials Consortium Predicting disease progression in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Annals of Clinical Translational Neurology. 2016;3(11):866&#x2013;875.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5099532</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27844032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siwek T, Barczewska M, Grabarczyk L, et al. Mesenchymal stem cell (MSC) transplantation in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS): Is there a &#x201c;responder population&#x201d;? Journal of Neurology and Neuroscience. 2018;9(3):260.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miano B, Stoddard GJ, Davis S, et al. Inter-evaluator reliability of the ALS functional rating scale. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis and Other Motor Neuron Disorders. 2004;5(4):235&#x2013;239.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15799553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon, P.H., Miller, R.G., Moore. D.H. ALSFRS-R. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord 5(Suppl 1), 90&#x2013;3 (2004).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15512883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thakore NJ, Lapin BR, Kinzy TG, Pioro EP. Deconstructing progression of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in stages: A Markov modeling approach. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2018;19(7&#x2013;8):483&#x2013;494.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30001159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vijayaraghavan M. Improving access to clinical trials for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis treatment. JAMA Neurology. 2020;77:671. doi: 10.1001/jamaneurol.2020.0421.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamaneurol.2020.0421</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32227134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voelker R. Crackdown on stem cell product. JAMA. 2018;319(7):649.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29466576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voelker R. Another stem cell company is put on notice. JAMA. 2019;322(1):19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31265086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Australian Stem Cell Handbook (2015) http://www.stemcellsaustralia.edu.au/AboutUs/Document-Library.aspx</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu W, Smith C, Turner L, Fojtik J, et al. Characteristics and Scope of Training of Clinicians Participating in the US Direct-to-Consumer Marketplace for Unproven Stem Cell Interventions. JAMA. 2019;321(24):2463&#x2013;2464.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6593626</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31237628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cossu G, Birchall M, Brown T, de Coppi P, Culme-Seymour E, Gibbon S, Hitchcock J, Mason C, Montgomery J, Morris S, Muntoni F, Napier D, Owji N, Prasad A, Round J, Saprai P, Stilgoe J, Thrasher A, Wilson J. Lancet commission: Stem cells and regenerative medicine. The Lancet Commissions. 2018;391(10123):883&#x2013;910.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28987452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okada M, Yamashita S, Ueyama H, Ishizaki M, Maeda Y, Ando Y. Long-term effects of edaravone on survival of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. eNeurologicalSci. 2018;11:11&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6006910</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29928711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karussis D, Karageorgiou C, Vaknin-Dembinsky A, Gowda-Kurkalli B, Gomori JM, Kassis I, Bulte JW, Petrou P, Ben-Hur T, Abramsky O, Slavin S. Safety and immunological effects of Mesenchymal stem cell transplantation in patients with multiple sclerosis and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Archives of Neurology. 2010;67(10):1187&#x2013;1194.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3036569</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20937945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazzini L, Ferrero I, Luparello V, Rustichelli D, Gunetti M, Mareschi K, Testa L, Stecco A, Tarletti R, Miglioretti M, Fava E, Nasuelli N, Cisari C, Massara M, Vercelli R, Oggioni GD, Carriero A, Cantello R, Monaco F, Fagioli F. Mesenchymal stem cell transplantation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A phase I clinical trial. Experimental Neurology. 2010;223(1):229&#x2013;237.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19682989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazzini L, Mareschi K, Ferrero I, Miglioretti M, Stecco A, Servo S, Carriero A, Monaco F, Fagioli F. Mesenchymal stromal cell transplantation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A long-term safety study. Cytotherapy. 2012;14(1):56&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21954839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prabhakar S, Marwaha N, Lal V, et al. Autologous bone marrow-derived stem cells in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A pilot study. Neurology India. 2012;60(5):465&#x2013;469.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23135021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh KW, Moon C, Kim HY, Oh SI, Park J, Lee JH, Chang IY, Kim KS, Kim SH. Phase I trial of repeated intrathecal autologous bone marrow-derived mesenchymal stromal cells in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Stem Cells Translational Medicine. 2015;4(6):590&#x2013;597.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4449093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25934946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang R, Chen H, Zheng Z, et al. Umbilical cord-derived mesenchymal stem cell therapy for neurological disorders via inhibition of mitogen-activated protein kinase pathway-mediated apoptosis. Molecular Medicine Reports. 2015;11(3):1807&#x2013;1812.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25412281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrou P, Gothelf Y, Argov Z, Gotkine M, Levy YS, Kassis I, Vaknin-Dembinsky A, Ben-Hur T, Offen D, Abramsky O, Melamed E, Karussis D. Safety and clinical effects of Mesenchymal stem cells secreting Neurotrophic factor transplantation in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Results of phase 1/2 and 2a clinical trials. JAMA Neurology. 2016;73(3):337&#x2013;344.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26751635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Staff, N.P. Madigan NN, Morris J, et al. Safety of intrathecal autologous adipose-derived mesenchymal stromal cells in patients with ALS. Neurology. 2016;87(21):2230&#x2013;2234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5123559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27784774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sykova E, Rychmach P, Drahor&#xe1;dov&#xe1; I, et al. Transplantation of Mesenchymal stromal cells in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Results of phase I/IIa clinical trial. Cell Transplantation. 2017;26(4):647&#x2013;658.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5661219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27938483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barczewska M, Grudniak M, Maksymowicz S, Siwek T, O&#x142;dak T, Jezierska-Wo&#x17a;niak K, G&#x142;adysz D, Maksymowicz W. Safety of intrathecal injection of Wharton's jelly-derived mesenchymal stem cells in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis therapy. Neural Regeneration Research. 2019;14(2):313&#x2013;318.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6301165</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30531015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>US Department of Health and Human Services Food and Drug Administration. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: developing drugs for treatment guidance for industry. Published September 2019. Accessed May 8, 2020. https://www.fda.gov/media/130964/download</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh K-W, Noh M-Y, Kwon M-S, Kim HY, Oh SI, Park J, Kim HJ, Ki CS, Kim SH. Repeated Intrathecal Mesenchymal stem cells for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Annals of Neurology. 2018;84(3):361&#x2013;373.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6175096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30048006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Berg LH, Sorenson E, Gronseth G, et al. Airlie house ALS clinical trials guidelines group. Revised Airlie House consensus guidelines for design and implementation of ALS clinical trials. Neurology. 2019;92(14):e1610&#x2013;e1623.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6448453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30850440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowman M, Racke M, Kissel J, Imitola J. Responsibilities of health care professionals in counseling and educating patients with incurable neurological diseases regarding &#x201c;stem cell tourism&#x201d;: Caveat emptor. JAMA Neurology. 2015;72(11):1342&#x2013;1345.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26322563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowman M, Racke M, Kissel J, Imitola J. Responsibilities of health care professionals in counseling and educating patients with incurable neurological diseases regarding &#x201c;stem cell tourism.&#x201d;. JAMA Neurology. 2015;72(11):1342&#x2013;1345.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26322563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sugarman J, Barker RA, Charo RA. A professional standard for informed consent for stem cell therapies. JAMA. 2019;322(17):1651&#x2013;1652.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fogh I, Lin K, Tiloca C, Rooney J, Gellera C, Diekstra FP, Ratti A, Shatunov A, van Es MA, Proitsi P, Jones A, Sproviero W, Chi&#xf2; A, McLaughlin RL, Sorar&#xf9; G, Corrado L, Stahl D, del Bo R, Cereda C, Castellotti B, Glass JD, Newhouse S, Dobson R, Smith BN, Topp S, van Rheenen W, Meininger V, Melki J, Morrison KE, Shaw PJ, Leigh PN, Andersen PM, Comi GP, Ticozzi N, Mazzini L, D&#x2019;Alfonso S, Traynor BJ, van Damme P, Robberecht W, Brown RH, Landers JE, Hardiman O, Lewis CM, van den Berg LH, Shaw CE, Veldink JH, Silani V, al-Chalabi A, Powell J. Association of a Locus in the CAMTA1 gene with survival in patients with sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. JAMA Neurology. 2016;73(7):812&#x2013;820.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5556366</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27244217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan M, Heverin M, McLaughlin RL, Hardiman O. Lifetime risk and heritability of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. JAMA Neurology. 2019;76(11):1367&#x2013;1374.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6646974</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31329211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garofalo S, Cocozza G, Porzia A, Inghilleri M, Raspa M, Scavizzi F, Aronica E, Bernardini G, Peng L, Ransohoff RM, Santoni A, Limatola C. Natural killer cells modulate motor neuron-immune cell cross talk in models of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nature Communications. 2020;11:1773.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7156729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32286313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beers DR, Zhao W, Appel SH. The role of regulatory T lymphocytes in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. JAMA Neurology. 2018;75(6):656&#x2013;658.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29507936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheean RK, McKay FC, Cretney E, Bye CR, Perera ND, Tomas D, Weston RA, Scheller KJ, Djouma E, Menon P, Schibeci SD, Marmash N, Yerbury JJ, Nutt SL, Booth DR, Stewart GJ, Kiernan MC, Vucic S, Turner BJ. Association of Regulatory T-cell expansion with progression of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A study of humans and a transgenic mouse model. JAMA Neurology. 2018;75(6):681&#x2013;689.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5885208</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29507931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corsello T, Amico G, Corrao S, Anzalone R, Timoneri F, Lo Iacono M, Russo E, Spatola GF, Uzzo ML, Giuffr&#xe8; M, Caprnda M, Kubatka P, Kruzliak P, Conaldi PG, la Rocca G. Wharton&#x2019;s jelly Mesenchymal stromal cells from human umbilical cord: A close-up on Immunomodulatory molecules featured in situ and in vitro. Stem Cell Reviews and Reports. 2019;15:900&#x2013;918.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31741193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zou X, Gu D, Zhang G, Zhong L, Cheng Z, Liu G, Zhu Y. NK cell regulatory property is involved in the protective role of MSC-derived extracellular vesicles in renal ischemic reperfusion injury. Human Gene Therapy. 2016;27:926&#x2013;935.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27510907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kordelas L, Rebmann V, Ludwig A-K, Radtke S, Ruesing J, Doeppner TR, Epple M, Horn PA, Beelen DW, Giebel B. MSC-derived exosomes: A novel tool to treat therapy-refractory graft-versus-host disease. Leukemia. 2014;28:970&#x2013;973.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24445866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rostami Z, Khorashadizadeh M, Naseri M. Immunoregulatory properties of mesenchymal stem cells: Micro-RNAs. Immunology Letters. 2020;219:34&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31917251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tadesse T, Gearing M, Senitzer D, Saxe D, Brat DJ, Bray R, Gebel H, Hill C, Boulis N, Riley J, Feldman E, Johe K, Hazel T, Polak M, Bordeau J, Federici T, Glass JD. Analysis of graft survival in a trial of stem cell transplant in ALS. Annals of Clinical Translational Neurology. 2014;1(11):900&#x2013;908.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4265061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25540804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murdock BJ, Zhou T, Kashlan SR, Little RJ, Goutman SA, Feldman EL. Correlation of peripheral immunity with rapid amyotrophic lateral sclerosis progression. JAMA Neurology. 2017;74(12):1446&#x2013;1454.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5822195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28973548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenbohm A, Nagel G, Peter RS, Brehme T, Koenig W, Dupuis L, Rothenbacher D, Ludolph AC, for the ALS Registry Study Group Association of Serum Retinol-Binding Protein 4 concentration with risk for and prognosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. JAMA Neurology. 2018;75(5):600&#x2013;607.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5885207</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29482216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lunetta C, Lizio A, Maestri E, Sansone VA, Mora G, Miller RG, Appel SH, Chi&#xf2; A. Serum C-reactive protein as a prognostic biomarker in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. JAMA Neurology. 2017;74(6):660&#x2013;667.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5822215</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28384752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao W, Beers DR, Hooten KG, Sieglaff DH, Zhang A, Kalyana-Sundaram S, Traini CM, Halsey WS, Hughes AM, Sathe GM, Livi GP, Fan GH, Appel SH. Characterization of gene expression phenotype in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis monocytes. JAMA Neurology. 2017;74(6):677&#x2013;685.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5822209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28437540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>