<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">32725835</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>17</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1460-6984</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>55</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of language &amp; communication disorders</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Lang Commun Disord</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Beyond the motor account of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Verbal humour and its relationship with the cognitive and pragmatic profile.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>751</StartPage><EndPage>764</EndPage><MedlinePgn>751-764</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/1460-6984.12561</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis (ALS) was traditionally described as a disease restricted to the motor system. However, recent findings suggested that it also affects cognition, especially executive functions, social cognition, language and pragmatics. A relevant issue in current research is thus the description of the cognitive phenotype of ALS and the identification of the most vulnerable aspects.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="AIMS">The focus was on a communicative phenomenon placed at the crossroads of pragmatic and other cognitive domains, namely humour, which till now has been poorly explored in ALS. The first aim was to investigate whether ALS is associated with impairments in understanding and appreciating jokes. The second aim was to explore the predictors of humour comprehension and appreciation in patients, to confirm the involvement of pragmatic skills and to explore the role of other cognitive and clinical aspects.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS &amp; PROCEDURES">A total of 30 non-demented patients with ALS and 27 controls were assessed with a task of verbal humour comprehension and appreciation, including two types of jokes: phonological and mental. We also administered a battery of pragmatic and other language tasks, and cognitive and socio-cognitive tasks. Mixed-effects models were used to test differences in the humour task between the two groups. Multiple regressions determined the best predictors of humour comprehension and appreciation in patients.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OUTCOMES &amp; RESULTS">Patients obtained lower comprehension accuracy scores than controls in the humour task, independently of the type of joke. Conversely, patients and controls did not differ in joke appreciation and both rated mental jokes as funnier than the phonological ones. Patients' comprehension accuracy was predicted by pragmatic skills and ALS severity, whereas appreciation was predicted by several clinical variables and, to a smaller extent, by language skills.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS &amp; IMPLICATIONS">The findings suggest that humour is a very vulnerable aspect in ALS, and that impairment in humour comprehension might be part of the larger cognitive impairment, being linked to pragmatic impairment. Clinical variables were also important, especially in relation to humour appreciation. More generally, these data speak in favour of pragmatics as a relevant aspect to sketch the cognitive phenotype of ALS. On the practical level, these findings point to the need of supporting communication at large, not only motor-related aspects such as dysarthria but also social-pragmatic aspects such as understanding jokes, to increase well-being in ALS. What this paper adds What is already known on this subject The literature of the last decades has shown that ALS comes with impairment in several cognitive domains, affecting especially executive functions as well as language. There is also initial evidence that the pragmatics of communication and humour comprehension are impaired, although non-serious talk has been documented in conversational interaction among people with ALS. What this paper adds to existing knowledge This study offers compelling evidence of an impairment in the comprehension of jokes in ALS, whereas the appreciation of joke funniness seems to be spared. The study also highlights the interplay of cognitive factors (especially pragmatics) and clinical factors (related to disease severity) in predicting the patients' performance in the humour task. What are the potential or actual clinical implications of this work? The study's findings call for the need of increased awareness among scholars as well as practitioners and caregivers of the profile of humour comprehension and appreciation in ALS. On a practical level, we highlight the need of assessing humour comprehension and adapting the communicative style accordingly. Second, we recommend that intervention programmes targeting communication in ALS go beyond speech-related difficulties and include pragmatic aspects such as humour. Considering the important communicative and social function of humour, as well as its use as a coping strategy, humour interventions are key to improve the quality of life of individuals with ALS.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020 Royal College of Speech and Language Therapists.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bambini</LastName><ForeName>Valentina</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5770-228X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Neurocognition, Epistemology and Theoretical Syntax, University School for Advanced Studies IUSS, Pavia, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bischetti</LastName><ForeName>Luca</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8875-1092</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Neurocognition, Epistemology and Theoretical Syntax, University School for Advanced Studies IUSS, Pavia, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bonomi</LastName><ForeName>Chiara Giuseppina</ForeName><Initials>CG</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0881-8435</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Brain and Behavioral Science, University of Pavia, Pavia, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Arcara</LastName><ForeName>Giorgio</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6270-6883</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>IRCCS San Camillo Hospital, Venice, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lecce</LastName><ForeName>Serena</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2745-3574</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Brain and Behavioral Science, University of Pavia, Pavia, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ceroni</LastName><ForeName>Mauro</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8947-5007</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Brain and Behavioral Science, University of Pavia, Pavia, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurological Institute Mondino Foundation, Pavia, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Lang Commun Disord</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9803709</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1368-2822</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="Y">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003072" MajorTopicYN="N">Cognition Disorders</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="Y">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D032882" MajorTopicYN="N">Comprehension</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D056344" MajorTopicYN="N">Executive Function</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007807" MajorTopicYN="N">Language Tests</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008037" MajorTopicYN="N">Linguistics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010641" MajorTopicYN="N">Phenotype</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000083282" MajorTopicYN="N">Social Cognition</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000067404" MajorTopicYN="N">Social Communication Disorder</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="Y">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014705" MajorTopicYN="N">Verbal Behavior</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014925" MajorTopicYN="N">Wit and Humor as Topic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="Y">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">humour</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neurodegenerative diseases</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pragmatics</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32725835</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1460-6984.12561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Abell, F., Happ&#xe9;, F., and Frith, U., 2000, Do triangles play tricks? Attribution of mental states to animated shapes in normal and abnormal development. Cognitive Development, 15(1), 1-16. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0885-2014(00)00014-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arcara, G., and Bambini, V., 2016, A test for the Assessment of Pragmatic Abilities and Cognitive Substrates (APACS): Normative data and psychometric properties. Frontiers in Psychology, 7, 70. https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2016.00070</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Archer, B., Azios, J. H., and Moody, S., 2019, Humour in clinical-educational interactions between graduate student clinicians and people with aphasia. International Journal of Language and Communication Disorders, 54(4), 580-595. https://doi.org/10.1111/1460-6984.12461</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Attardo, S., 1994, Linguistic theories of humor. Berlin, New York: Mouton de Gruyter.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Attardo, S., 2003, Introduction: The pragmatics of humor. Journal of Pragmatics, 35(9), 1287-1294. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0378-2166(02)00178-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Austin, P. C., and Steyerberg, E. W., 2015, The number of subjects per variable required in linear regression analyses. Journal of Clinical Epidemiology, 68(6), 627-636. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclinepi.2014.12.014</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bambini, V., Arcara, G., Martinelli, I., Bernini, S., Alvisi, E., Moro, A., and Ceroni, M., 2016, Communication and pragmatic breakdowns in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. Brain and Language, 153-154, 1-12. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bandl.2015.12.002</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bambini, V., and Ceroni, M., 2021, Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. In L. Cummings (Ed.), Pragmatic Language Disorders: Complex and Underserved Populations. Cham, Switzerland: Springer International Publishing AG.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beeman, W. O., 2000, Humor. Journal of Linguistic Anthropology, 9, 103-106. https://doi.org/10.1525/jlin.1999.9.1-2.103</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bischetti, L., Ceccato, I., Lecce, S., Cavallini, E., and Bambini, V., 2019, Pragmatics and theory of mind in older adults&#x2019; humor comprehension. Current Psychology, 1-17. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12144-019-00295-w</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bloch, S., and Tuomainen, J., 2017, Progressive dysarthria and augmentative and alternative communication in conversation: establishing the reliability of the Dysarthria-in-Interaction Profile. International Journal of Language and Communication Disorders, 52(1), 3-9. https://doi.org/10.1111/1460-6984.12258</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bloch, S., and Wilkinson, R., 2013, The accomplishment of nonserious talk in severe speech disability: An examination of recipient uptake and delayed other-initiated repair. Journal of Interactional Research in Communication Disorders, 4(1), 45-70. https://doi.org/10.1558/jircd.v4i1.45</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bora, E., 2017, Meta-analysis of social cognition in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Cortex, 88, 1-7. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cortex.2016.11.012</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bosco, F. M., Tirassa, M., and Gabbatore, I., 2018, Why pragmatics and Theory of Mind do not (completely) overlap. Frontiers in Psychology, 9, 1453. https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2018.01453</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canal, P., Bischetti, L., Di Paola, S., Bertini, C., Ricci, I., and Bambini, V., 2019, &#x2018;Honey, shall I change the baby? - Well done, choose another one&#x2019;: ERP and time-frequency correlates of humor processing. Brain and Cognition, 132, 41-55. https://doi.org/10.1016/J.BANDC.2019.02.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carotenuto, A., Arcara, G., Orefice, G., Cerillo, I., Giannino, V., Rasulo, M., and Bambini, V., 2018, Communication in multiple sclerosis: Pragmatic deficit and its relation with cognition and social cognition. Archives of Clinical Neuropsychology, 33(2), 194-205. https://doi.org/10.1093/arclin/acx061</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Catrical&#xe0;, E., Della Rosa, P. A., Ginex, V., Mussetti, Z., Plebani, V., and Cappa, S. F., 2013, An Italian battery for the assessment of semantic memory disorders. Neurological Sciences, 34(6), 985-993. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10072-012-1181-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cecchetto, C., Di Domenico, A., Garraffa, M., and Papagno, C., 2012, Comprendo: batteria per la comprensione di frasi negli adulti. Milano: Raffaele Cortina Editore.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum, J. M., Stambler, N., Malta, E., Fuller, C., Hilt, D., Thurmond, B., and Nakanishi, A., 1999, The ALSFRS-R: A revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. Journal of the Neurological Sciences, 169(1-2), 13-21. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0022-510X(99)00210-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark, C. N., Nicholas, J. M., Henley, S. M. D., Downey, L. E., Woollacott, I. O., Golden, H. L., and Warren, J. D., 2015, Humour processing in frontotemporal lobar degeneration: A behavioural and neuroanatomical analysis. Cortex, 69, 47-59. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cortex.2015.03.024</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crockford, C., Newton, J., Lonergan, K., Chiwera, T., Booth, T., Chandran, S., and Abrahams, S., 2018, ALS-specific cognitive and behavior changes associated with advancing disease stage in ALS. Neurology, 91(15), e1370-e1380. https://doi.org/10.1212/WNL.0000000000006317</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho, M., Dengler, R., Eisen, A., England, J. D., Kaji, R., Kimura, J., and Swash, M., 2008, Electrodiagnostic criteria for diagnosis of ALS. Clinical Neurophysiology&#x202f;: Official Journal of the International Federation of Clinical Neurophysiology, 119(3), 497-503. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.clinph.2007.09.143</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dunbar, R. I. M., Launay, J., and Curry, O., 2016, The Complexity of Jokes Is Limited by Cognitive Constraints on Mentalizing. Human Nature (Hawthorne, N.Y.), 27(2), 130-140. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12110-015-9251-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dynel, M., 2009, Humorous garden-paths: A pragmatic-cognitive study. Newcastle upon Tyne: Cambridge Scholars Publishing.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ehrl&#xe9;, N., Espi, P., Labire, J., Loizeau, A., Menard, C., and Bakchine, S., 2020, Impairments of humour comprehension in multiple sclerosis. Multiple Sclerosis and Related Disorders, 39, 101443. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.msard.2019.101443</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibbons, Z. C., Snowden, J. S., Thompson, J. C., Happ&#xe9;, F., Richardson, A., and Neary, D., 2007, Inferring thought and action in motor neurone disease. Neuropsychologia, 45(6), 1196-1207. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuropsychologia.2006.10.008</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ludolph, A., Drory, V., Hardiman, O., Nakano, I., Ravits, J., Robberecht, W., and Shefner, J., 2015, A revision of the El Escorial criteria-2015. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis and Frontotemporal Degeneration, 16(5-6), 291-292. https://doi.org/10.3109/21678421.2015.1049183</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lul&#xe9;, D., Diekmann, V., Anders, S., Kassubek, J., K&#xfc;bler, A., Ludolph, A. C., and Birbaumer, N., 2007, Brain responses to emotional stimuli in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). Journal of Neurology, 254(4), 519-527. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00415-006-0409-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin, I., and McDonald, S., 2003, Weak coherence, no theory of mind, or executive dysfunction? Solving the puzzle of pragmatic language disorders. Brain and Language, 85(3), 451-466. https://doi.org/10.1016/s0093-934x(03)00070-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin, R. A., and Ford, T. E., 2018, The psychology of humor: an integrative approach (second edition). New York: Academic Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montel, S., Albertini, L., Desnuelle, C., and Spitz, E., 2012, Evolution of quality of life, mental health, and coping strategies in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A pilot study. Journal of Palliative Medicine, 15(11), 1181-1184. https://doi.org/10.1089/jpm.2012.0162</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montemurro, S., Mondini, S., Signorini, M., Marchetto, A., Bambini, V., and Arcara, G., 2019, Pragmatic language disorder in Parkinson's disease and the potential effect of cognitive reserve. Frontiers in Psychology, 10, 1220. https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2019.01220</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neary, D., Snowden, J. S., Gustafson, L., Passant, U., Stuss, D., Black, S., &#x2026; Benson, D. F., 1998, Frontotemporal lobar degeneration: a consensus on clinical diagnostic criteria. Neurology, 51(6), 1546-1554.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nelson, N. D., Trail, M., Van, J. N., Appel, S. H., and Lai, E. C., 2003, Quality of life in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Perceptions, coping resources, and illness characteristics. Journal of Palliative Medicine, 6(3), 417-424. https://doi.org/10.1089/109662103322144736</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norrick, N. R., 2010, Humor in Interaction. Language and Linguistics Compass, 4(4), 232-244. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1749-818X.2010.00189.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osborne, R. A., Sekhon, R., Johnston, W., and Kalra, S., 2014, Screening for frontal lobe and general cognitive impairment in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Journal of the Neurological Sciences, 336(1-2), 191-196. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jns.2013.10.038</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poletti, B., Solca, F., Carelli, L., Madotto, F., Lafronza, A., Faini, A., and Silani, V., 2016, The validation of the Italian Edinburgh Cognitive and Behavioural ALS Screen (ECAS). Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis and Frontotemporal Degeneration, 17(7-8), 489-498. https://doi.org/10.1080/21678421.2016.1183679</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samson, A. C., 2012, The influence of empathizing and systemizing on humor processing: Theory of Mind and humor. Humor, 25(1), 75-98. https://doi.org/10.1515/humor-2012-0005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Staios, M., Fisher, F., Lindell, A. K., Ong, B., Howe, J., and Reardon, K., 2013, Exploring sarcasm detection in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis using ecologically valid measures. Frontiers in Human Neuroscience, 7, 178. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnhum.2013.00178</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stone, V. E., Baron-Cohen, S., and Knight, R. T., 1998, Frontal Lobe Contributions to Theory of Mind. Journal of Cognitive Neuroscience, 10(5), 640-656. https://doi.org/10.1162/089892998562942</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strong, M. J., Abrahams, S., Goldstein, L. H., Woolley, S., Mclaughlin, P., Snowden, J., &#x2026; Turner, M. R., 2017, Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-frontotemporal spectrum disorder (ALS-FTSD): Revised diagnostic criteria. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis and Frontotemporal Degeneration, 18(3-4), 153-174. https://doi.org/10.1080/21678421.2016.1267768</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thaler, A., Posen, J., Giladi, N., Manor, Y., Mayanz, C., Mirelman, A., and Gurevich, T., 2012, Appreciation of humor is decreased among patients with Parkinson's disease. Parkinsonism and Related Disorders, 18(2), 144-148. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.parkreldis.2011.09.004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uekermann, J., Channon, S., and Daum, I., 2006, Humor processing, mentalizing, and executive function in normal aging. Journal of the International Neuropsychological Society&#x202f;: JINS, 12(2), 184-191. https://doi.org/10.1017/S1355617706060280</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Es, M. A., Hardiman, O., Chio, A., Al-Chalabi, A., Pasterkamp, R. J., Veldink, J. H., and van den Berg, L. H., 2017, November 4, Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. The Lancet, 390(10107), 2084-2098. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0140-6736(17)31287-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vrticka, P., Black, J. M., and Reiss, A. L., 2013, The neural basis of humour processing. Nature Reviews Neuroscience, 14(12), 860-868. https://doi.org/10.1038/nrn3566</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woolley, S. C., and Rush, B. K., 2017, Considerations for Clinical Neuropsychological Evaluation in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. Archives of Clinical Neuropsychology, 32(7), 906-916. https://doi.org/10.1093/arclin/acx089</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wyer, R. S., and Collins, J. E., 1992, A theory of humor elicitation. Psychological Review, 99(4), 663-688. https://doi.org/10.1037/0033-295X.99.4.663</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yus, F., 2016, Humour and relevance. Amsterdam: John Benjamins. https://doi.org/10.1075/thr.4</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>