<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">32741003</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>04</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1531-8249</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>88</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Annals of neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Ann Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis: Fuel for the Corticofugal Feud.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>682</StartPage><EndPage>684</EndPage><MedlinePgn>682-684</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/ana.25861</ELocationID><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wainger</LastName><ForeName>Brian J</ForeName><Initials>BJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departments of Anesthesiology and Neurology, Massachusetts General Hospital, Boston, MA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brown</LastName><ForeName>Robert H</ForeName><Initials>RH</Initials><Suffix>Jr</Suffix><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6062-1528</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of Massachusetts Medical School, Worcester, MA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016420">Comment</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Ann Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7707449</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0364-5134</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="CommentOn"><RefSource>Ann Neurol. 2020 Oct;88(4):688-702</RefSource><PMID Version="1">32588450</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32741003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.25861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Chou SM, Norris FH. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: lower motor neuron disease spreading to upper motor neurons. Muscle Nerve 1993;16:864-869.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burg T, Bichara C, Scekic-Zahirovic J, et al. Absence of subcerebral projection neurons is beneficial in a mouse model of ALS. Ann Neurol 2020 (in press). https://doi.org/10.1002/ana25833.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gowers WR. Manual of Diseases of the Nervous System. London, UK: Churchill, 1886-1888 (reprinted special edition: Birmingham, AL: Classics of Medicine Library; 1981).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ravits JM, La Spada AR. ALS motor phenotype heterogeneity, focality, and spread: deconstructing motor neuron degeneration. Neurology 2009;73:805-811.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomsen GM, Gowing G, Latter J, et al. Delayed disease onset and extended survival in the SOD1G93A rat model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis after suppression of mutant SOD1 in the motor cortex. J Neurosci 2014;34:15587-15600.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saxena S, Roselli F, Singh K, et al. Neuroprotection through excitability and mTOR required in ALS motoneurons to delay disease and extend survival. Neuron 2013;80:80-96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saper CB, Wainer BH, German DC. Axonal and transneuronal transport in the transmission of neurological disease: potential role in system degenerations, including Alzheimer's disease. Neuroscience 1987;23:389-398.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S, Ziemann U, Eisen A, et al. Transcranial magnetic stimulation and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: pathophysiological insights. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2013;84:1161-1170.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rothstein JD, Martin LJ, Kuncl RW. Decreased glutamate transport by the brain and spinal cord in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. N Engl J Med 1992;326:1464-1468.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mogyoros I, Kiernan MC, Burke D, Bostock H. Strength-duration properties of sensory and motor axons in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain 1998;121 ( Pt 5:851-859.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuo JJ, Schonewille M, Siddique T, et al. Hyperexcitability of cultured spinal motoneurons from presymptomatic ALS mice. J Neurophysiol 2004;91:571-575.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sareen D, O'Rourke JG, Meera P, et al. Targeting RNA foci in iPSC-derived motor neurons from ALS patients with a C9ORF72 repeat expansion. Sci Transl Med 2013;5:208ra149.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wainger BJ, Kiskinis E, Mellin C, et al. Intrinsic membrane hyperexcitability of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patient-derived motor neurons. Cell Rep 2014;7:1-11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naujock M, Stanslowsky N, Bufler S, et al. 4-Aminopyridine induced activity rescues Hypoexcitable motor neurons from amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patient-derived induced pluripotent stem cells. Stem Cells 2016;34:1563-1575.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;nez-Silva M d L, Imhoff-Manuel RD, Sharma A, et al. Hypoexcitability precedes denervation in the large fast-contracting motor units in two unrelated mouse models of ALS. eLife 2018;7:1958.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brettschneider J, Del Tredici K, Toledo JB, et al. Stages of pTDP-43 pathology in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol 2013;74:20-38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pokrishevsky E, Grad LI, Cashman NR. TDP-43 or FUS-induced misfolded human wild-type SOD1 can propagate intercellularly in a prion-like fashion. Sci Rep 2016;6:22155.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayers JI, Fromholt SE, O'Neal VM, et al. Prion-like propagation of mutant SOD1 misfolding and motor neuron disease spread along neuroanatomical pathways. Acta Neuropathol 2016;131:103-114.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirata T, Suda Y, Nakao K, et al. Zinc finger gene fez-like functions in the formation of subplate neurons and thalamocortical axons. Dev Dyn 2004;230:546-556.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boill&#xe9;e S, Yamanaka K, Lobsiger CS, et al. Onset and progression in inherited ALS determined by motor neurons and microglia. Science 2006;312:1389-1392.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamanaka K, Chun SJ, Boillee S, et al. Astrocytes as determinants of disease progression in inherited amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat Neurosci 2008;11:251-253.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>