<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">32779757</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>04</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-4598</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>62</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Muscle &amp; nerve</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Muscle Nerve</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Textural markers of ultrasonographic nerve alterations in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>601</StartPage><EndPage>610</EndPage><MedlinePgn>601-610</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/mus.27043</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Ultrasound has revealed cross-sectional nerve area (CSA) reduction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS), but little is known about the sonographic nerve texture beyond CSA alterations. In a large cohort of 177 ALS patients and 57 control subjects, we investigated the covariance and disease-specific signature of several sonographic texture features of the median and ulnar nerves and their relationship to the patients' clinical characteristics. ALS patients showed atrophic nerves, a loss of the intranerve structures' echoic contrast, elevated coarseness, and a trend toward lower cluster shading compared with controls. A reduction in intranerve echoic contrast was related to longer disease duration and poorer functional status in ALS. Sonographic texture markers point toward a significant reorganization of the deep nerve microstructure in ALS. Future studies will be needed to further substantiate the markers' potential to assess peripheral nerve alterations in ALS.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020 The Authors. Muscle &amp; Nerve published by Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schreiber</LastName><ForeName>Frank</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9484-8613</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Otto von Guericke University, Magdeburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>German Center for Neurodegenerative Diseases within the Helmholtz Association, Magdeburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Garz</LastName><ForeName>Cornelia</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Otto von Guericke University, Magdeburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>German Center for Neurodegenerative Diseases within the Helmholtz Association, Magdeburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Heinze</LastName><ForeName>Hans-Jochen</ForeName><Initials>HJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Otto von Guericke University, Magdeburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>German Center for Neurodegenerative Diseases within the Helmholtz Association, Magdeburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Leibniz Institute for Neurobiology, Magdeburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Behavioral Brain Sciences, Magdeburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Petri</LastName><ForeName>Susanne</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9783-8584</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Hannover Medical School, Hannover, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vielhaber</LastName><ForeName>Stefan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Otto von Guericke University, Magdeburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>German Center for Neurodegenerative Diseases within the Helmholtz Association, Magdeburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Behavioral Brain Sciences, Magdeburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schreiber</LastName><ForeName>Stefanie</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4439-4374</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Otto von Guericke University, Magdeburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>German Center for Neurodegenerative Diseases within the Helmholtz Association, Magdeburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Behavioral Brain Sciences, Magdeburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Muscle Nerve</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7803146</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0148-639X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="Y">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="Y">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005542" MajorTopicYN="N">Forearm</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000294" MajorTopicYN="N">innervation</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008475" MajorTopicYN="N">Median Nerve</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="Y">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014459" MajorTopicYN="N">Ulnar Nerve</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="Y">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014463" MajorTopicYN="Y">Ultrasonography</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014925" MajorTopicYN="N">Wit and Humor as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, biomarker, nerve ultrasound, sonographic texture, texture analysis</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32779757</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.27043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Grimm A, Decard BF, Athanasopoulou I, Schweikert K, Sinnreich M, Axer H. Nerve ultrasound for differentiation between amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and multifocal motor neuropathy. J Neurol. 2015;262:870-880.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loewenbruck KF, Liesenberg J, Dittrich M, et al. Nerve ultrasound in the differentiation of multifocal motor neuropathy (MMN) and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with predominant lower motor neuron disease (ALS/LMND). J Neurol. 2016;263:35-44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goedee HS, van der Pol WL, van Asseldonk J-TH, et al. Diagnostic value of sonography in treatment-naive chronic inflammatory neuropathies. Neurology. 2017;88:143-151.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cartwright MS, Walker FO, Griffin LP, Caress JB. Peripheral nerve and muscle ultrasound in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 2011;44:346-351.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nodera H, Takamatsu N, Shimatani Y, et al. Thinning of cervical nerve roots and peripheral nerves in ALS as measured by sonography. Clin Neurophysiol. 2014;125:1906-1911.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schreiber S, Abdulla S, Debska-Vielhaber G, et al. Peripheral nerve ultrasound in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis phenotypes. Muscle Nerve. 2015;51:669-675.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schreiber S, Vielhaber S, Schreiber F, Cartwright MS. Peripheral nerve imaging in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Neurophysiol. 2020;131(9):2315-2326.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schreiber S, Dannhardt-Stieger V, Henkel D, et al. Quantifying disease progression in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis using peripheral nerve sonography. Muscle Nerve. 2016;54:391-397.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xed;os-D&#xed;az J, Del Ba&#xf1;o-Aledo ME, Tembl-Ferrair&#xf3; JI, Chumillas MJ, V&#xe1;zquez-Costa JF, Mart&#xed;nez-Pay&#xe1; JJ. Quantitative neuromuscular ultrasound analysis as biomarkers in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Eur Radiol. 2019;29:4266-4275.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schreiber S, Schreiber F, Debska-Vielhaber G, et al. Differential involvement of forearm muscles in ALS does not relate to sonographic structural nerve alterations. Clin Neurophysiol. 2018;129:1438-1443.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, Miller RG, Swash M, Munsat TL. El Escorial revisited: revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2000;1:293-299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR. El Escorial world Federation of Neurology criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Sci. 1994;124:96-107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joint Task Force of the EFNS and the PNS. European Federation of Neurological Societies/Peripheral Nerve Society guideline on management of paraproteinemic demyelinating neuropathies. Report of a joint task force of the European Federation of Neurological Societies and the Peripheral Nerve Society-first revision. J Peripher Nerv Syst. 2010;15:185-195.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajabally YA, Nicolas G, Pi&#xe9;ret F, Bouche P, van den Bergh PYK. Validity of diagnostic criteria for chronic inflammatory demyelinating polyneuropathy: a multicentre European study. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2009;80:1364-1368.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chio A, Calvo A, Moglia C, Mazzini L, Mora G. Phenotypic heterogeneity of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a population based study. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2011;82:740-746.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum JM, Stambler N, Malta E, et al. The ALSFRS-R: a revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. J Neurol Sci. 1999;169:13-21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang X, Tridandapani S, Beitler JJ, et al. Ultrasound GLCM texture analysis of radiation-induced parotid-gland injury in head-and-neck cancer radiotherapy: an in vivo study of late toxicity. Med Phys. 2012;39:5732-5739.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haralick RM, Shanmugam K, Dinstein I. Textural features for image classification. IEEE Trans Syst Man Cybern. 1973;SMC-3:610-621.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brill NA, Tyler DJ. Quantification of human upper extremity nerves and fascicular anatomy. Muscle Nerve. 2017;56:463-471.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang X. Texture information in run-length matrices. IEEE Trans Image Proc. 1998;7:1602-1609.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chu A, Sehgal CM, Greenleaf JF. Use of gray value distribution of run lengths for texture analysis. Pattern Recogn Lett. 1990;11:415-419.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amadasun M, King R. Textural features corresponding to textural properties. IEEE Trans Syst Man Cybern. 1989;19:1264-1274.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valli&#xe8;res M, Freeman CR, Skamene SR, El Naqa I. A radiomics model from joint FDG-PET and MRI texture features for the prediction of lung metastases in soft-tissue sarcomas of the extremities. Phys Med Biol. 2015;60:5471-5496.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brysbaert M, Stevens M. Power analysis and effect size in mixed effects models: a tutorial. J Cogn. 2018;1:9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diedenhofen B, Musch J. Cocor: a comprehensive solution for the statistical comparison of correlations. PLoS One. 2015;10:e0121945.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schreiber S, Debska-Vielhaber G, Abdulla S, et al. Peripheral nerve atrophy together with higher cerebrospinal fluid progranulin indicate axonal damage in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 2018;57:273-278.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hobson-Webb LD, Simmons Z. Ultrasound in the diagnosis and monitoring of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a review. Muscle Nerve. 2019;60:114-123.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atsumi T, Miyatake T. Morphometry of the degenerative process in the hypoglossal nerves in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathol. 1987;73:25-31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bradley WG, Good P, Rasool CG, Adelman LS. Morphometric and biochemical studies of peripheral nerves in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol. 1983;14:267-277.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silvestri E, Martinoli C, Derchi LE, Bertolotto M, Chiaramondia M, Rosenberg I. Echotexture of peripheral nerves: correlation between US and histologic findings and criteria to differentiate tendons. Radiology. 1995;197:291-296.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jongbloed BA, Haakma W, Goedee HS, et al. Comparative study of peripheral nerve MRI and ultrasound in multifocal motor neuropathy and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 2016;54:1133-1135.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schreiber S, Schreiber F, Garz C, et al. Toward in vivo determination of peripheral nervous system immune activity in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 2019;59:567-576.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;nez-Pay&#xe1; JJ, R&#xed;os-D&#xed;az J, Del Ba&#xf1;o-Aledo ME, Tembl-Ferrair&#xf3; JI, Vazquez-Costa JF, Medina-Mirapeix F. Quantitative muscle ultrasonography using textural analysis in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ultrason Imaging. 2017;39(6):357-368.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martini R, Toyka KV. Immune-mediated components of hereditary demyelinating neuropathies: lessons from animal models and patients. Lancet Neurol. 2004;3:457-465.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Padua L, Granata G, Sabatelli M, et al. Heterogeneity of root and nerve ultrasound pattern in CIDP patients. Clin Neurophysiol. 2014;125:160-165.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe4;rtig F, Ross M, Dammeier NM, et al. Nerve ultrasound predicts treatment response in chronic inflammatory demyelinating polyradiculoneuropathy-a prospective follow-up. Neurotherapeutics. 2018;15:439-451.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>