<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">32796282</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>07</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1473-6551</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>33</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Current opinion in neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Curr Opin Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Current trends in the clinical trial landscape for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>655</StartPage><EndPage>661</EndPage><MedlinePgn>655-661</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/WCO.0000000000000861</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE OF REVIEW">To review the current developments in the design and conduct of clinical trials for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS), illustrated by a critical appraisal of ClinicalTrials.gov.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RECENT FINDINGS">In total, 63 clinical trials were included in the analysis, of which 13 phase 1, 35 phase 2 and 15 phase 3. Virtually all phase 3 clinical trials can be classified as randomized, placebo controlled, whereas this is only true for 57% of the phase 2 clinical trials. There are promising developments in the routes of drug administration, eligibility criteria, efficacy endpoints and overall trial design. Some of these innovative approaches may, however, not fulfil clinical trial guidelines or regulatory requirements. This could delay the development of effective therapy or hamper our ability to determine whether a treatment is truly (in)effective. The initiation of trial consortia comprising patient organizations, academia, industry and funding bodies may significantly strengthen the future clinical trial landscape for ALS.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUMMARY">The ALS clinical trial landscape is currently highly active with several promising innovative developments and therapeutic options. By further refinement of evidence-based guidelines, and alignment of our current endeavours, we may soon be able to positively impact the lives of people living with ALS.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>van Eijk</LastName><ForeName>Ruben P A</ForeName><Initials>RPA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, UMC Utrecht Brain Centre.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biostatistics &amp; Research Support, Julius Centre for Health Sciences and Primary Care, University Medical Centre Utrecht, Utrecht, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kliest</LastName><ForeName>Tessa</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, UMC Utrecht Brain Centre.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>van den Berg</LastName><ForeName>Leonard H</ForeName><Initials>LH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, UMC Utrecht Brain Centre.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Curr Opin Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9319162</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1350-7540</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="Y">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002986" MajorTopicYN="Y">Clinical Trials as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012107" MajorTopicYN="N">Research Design</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32796282</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/WCO.0000000000000861</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00019052-202010000-00017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Wobst HJ, Mack KL, Brown DG, et al. The clinical trial landscape in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis &#x2013; past, present, and future. Med Res Rev 2020; 40:13521384.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chio A, Mazzini L, Mora G. Disease-modifying therapies in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuropharmacology 2020; 167:107986.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hergesheimer R, Lanznaster D, Vourc&#x2019;h P, et al. Advances in disease-modifying pharmacotherapies for the treatment of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Expert Opin Pharmacother 2020; 21:11031110.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Berg LH, Sorenson E, Gronseth G, et al. Revised Airlie House consensus guidelines for design and implementation of ALS clinical trials. Neurology 2019; 92:e1610e1623.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDermott CJ. Clinical trials in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Curr Opin Neurol 2019; 32:758763.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrews JA, Bruijn LI, Shefner JM. ALS drug development guidances and trial guidelines: consensus and opportunities for alignment. Neurology 2019; 93:6671.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goutman SA, Savelieff MG, Sakowski SA, Feldman EL. Stem cell treatments for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a critical overview of early phase trials. Expert Opin Investig Drugs 2019; 28:525543.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazzini L, Gelati M, Profico DC, et al. Results from phase I clinical trial with intraspinal injection of neural stem cells in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a long-term outcome. Stem Cells Transl Med 2019; 8:887897.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berry JD, Cudkowicz ME, Windebank AJ, et al. NurOwn, phase 2, randomized, clinical trial in patients with ALS: safety, clinical, and biomarker results. Neurology 2019; 93:e2294e2305.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turnbull J. Author response to a Letter to the Editor entitled: edaravone administration in pivotal clinical study 19 (Authors: Genge, Angela; Brooks, Benjamin). Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2019; 20:300302.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld DA, Finkelstein DM, Macklin E, et al. Design and analysis of a clinical trial using previous trials as historical control. Clin Trials 2019; 16:531538.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abrahao A, Meng Y, Llinas M, et al. First-in-human trial of blood&#x2013;brain barrier opening in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis using MR-guided focused ultrasound. Nat Commun 2019; 10:4373.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Eijk RPA, Westeneng HJ, Nikolakopoulos S, et al. Refining eligibility criteria for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis clinical trials. Neurology 2019; 92:e451e460.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palumbo JM, Hubble J, Apple S, et al. Posthoc analyses of the edaravone clinical trials Study 16 and Study 19: a step toward more efficient clinical trial designs in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2019; 20:421431.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaji R, Imai T, Iwasaki Y, et al. Ultra-high-dose methylcobalamin in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a long-term phase II/III randomised controlled study. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2019; 90:451457.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mora JS, Genge A, Chio A, et al. Masitinib as an add-on therapy to riluzole in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a randomized clinical trial. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2020; 21:514.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morimoto S, Takahashi S, Fukushima K, et al. Ropinirole hydrochloride remedy for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis &#x2013; protocol for a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, single-center, and open-label continuation phase I/IIa clinical trial (ROPALS trial). Regen Ther 2019; 11:143166.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Eijk RPA, van den Berg LH. In pursuit of the normal progressor: the holy grail for ALS clinical trial design? Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2020; 21:12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vijayaraghavan M. Improving access to clinical trials for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis treatment. JAMA Neurol 2020; 77:671672.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goyal NA, Berry JD, Windebank A, et al. Addressing heterogeneity in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis clinical trials. Muscle Nerve 2020; 62:156166.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karam C, Berry JD. Heterogeneity, urgency, generalizability, and enrollment: the HUGE balance in ALS trials. Neurology 2019; 92:12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakker LA, Schroder CD, Tan HHG, et al. Development and assessment of the inter-rater and intra-rater reproducibility of a self-administration version of the ALSFRS-R. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2020; 91:7581.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gosselt IK, Nijboer TCW, Van Es MA. An overview of screening instruments for cognition and behavior in patients with ALS: selecting the appropriate tool for clinical practice. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2020; 113. DOI: 10.1080/21678421.2020.1732424.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/21678421.2020.1732424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chio A, Moglia C, Canosa A, et al. Cognitive impairment across ALS clinical stages in a population-based cohort. Neurology 2019; 93:e984e994.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huynh W, Ahmed R, Mahoney CJ, et al. The impact of cognitive and behavioral impairment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Expert Rev Neurother 2020; 20:281293.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Schaepdryver M, Lunetta C, Tarlarini C, et al. Neurofilament light chain and C reactive protein explored as predictors of survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2020; 91:436437.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Falzone YM, Domi T, Agosta F, et al. Serum phosphorylated neurofilament heavy-chain levels reflect phenotypic heterogeneity and are an independent predictor of survival in motor neuron disease. J Neurol 2020; 267:22722280.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vu L, An J, Kovalik T, et al. Cross-sectional and longitudinal measures of chitinase proteins in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and expression of CHI3L1 in activated astrocytes. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2020; 91:350358.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benatar M, Zhang L, Wang L, et al. Validation of serum neurofilaments as prognostic and potential pharmacodynamic biomarkers for ALS. Neurology 2020; 95:e59e69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faravelli I, Meneri M, Saccomanno D, et al. Nusinersen treatment and cerebrospinal fluid neurofilaments: an explorative study on spinal muscular atrophy type 3 patients. J Cell Mol Med 2020; 24:30343039.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Food Drug Administration Center for Drugs Evaluation Research. Guidance for industry: amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: developing drugs for treatment. 2019; https://www.fda.gov/downloads/Drugs/GuidanceComplianceRegulatoryInformation/Guidances/UCM596718.pdfhttps://www.fda.gov/downloads/Drugs/GuidanceComplianceRegulatoryInformation/Guidances/UCM596718.pdf. [Accessed 4 May 2020].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Eijk RPA, Nikolakopoulos S, Roes KCB, et al. Critical design considerations for time-to-event endpoints in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis clinical trials. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2019; 90:13311337.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Eijk RPA, Rooney J, Hardiman O, van den Berg LH. Two heads are better than one: benefits of joint models for ALS trials. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2019; 90:10711072.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schiavone F, Bathia R, Letchemanan K, et al. This is a platform alteration: a trial management perspective on the operational aspects of adaptive and platform and umbrella protocols. Trials 2019; 20:264.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collignon O, Gartner C, Haidich AB, et al. Current statistical considerations and regulatory perspectives on the planning of confirmatory basket, umbrella, and platform trials. Clin Pharmacol Ther 2020; 107:10591067.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cudkowicz M, Chase MK, Coffey CS, et al. Seven-year experience from the national institute of neurological disorders and stroke-supported network for excellence in neuroscience clinical trials. JAMA Neurol 2020; 77:755763.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>