<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">32796280</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>07</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1473-6551</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>33</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Current opinion in neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Curr Opin Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Biomarkers in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a review of new developments.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>662</StartPage><EndPage>668</EndPage><MedlinePgn>662-668</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/WCO.0000000000000854</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE OF REVIEW">This review draws together the most recent findings in ALS biomarker research from biochemical, imaging and neurophysiology techniques.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RECENT FINDINGS">The potential of circulating RNA is highlighted, including new retrieval techniques. With ongoing genetic clinical trials, the need for pharmacodynamic biomarkers is essential. There is a strong case for neurofilament proteins being validated in ALS; their biomarker profile is discussed. Oxidative stress and neuroinflammation studies offer insight into disease mechanisms and offer good biomarker potential. Recent metabolic studies include investigation of lipid profiles, creatinine and ferritin. The potential of chitinase proteins as pharmacodynamic and prognostic biomarkers is highlighted. The role of tau and amyloid&#x3b2; is debated, as evidenced by the articles presented here. Proteomic approaches provide unbiased discoveries of novel biomarkers, together with confirmation of previous findings. The use of imaging techniques is outlined to demonstrate selective atrophy, volume loss, muscle and tract involvement. In-vivo imaging is discussed with reference to histone deacetylase, oxidative stress, neuroinflammation and metabolic changes. New applications of electrophysiology demonstrate objective muscle biomarkers and brain network perturbations.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUMMARY">The biomarker research field continues to provide insight into the disease. Multicentre collaborations are needed to validate these promising recent findings.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Verber</LastName><ForeName>Nick</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sheffield Institute for Translational Neuroscience (SITraN), University of Sheffield, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shaw</LastName><ForeName>Pamela J</ForeName><Initials>PJ</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Curr Opin Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9319162</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1350-7540</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D015415">Biomarkers</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D016900">Neurofilament Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="Y">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015415" MajorTopicYN="N">Biomarkers</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="Y">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001921" MajorTopicYN="N">Brain</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="Y">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016900" MajorTopicYN="N">Neurofilament Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D040901" MajorTopicYN="Y">Proteomics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32796280</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/WCO.0000000000000854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00019052-202010000-00018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Joilin G, Leigh PN, Newbury SF, Hafezparast M. An overview of microRNAs as biomarkers of ALS. Front Neurol 2019; 10:186.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saucier D, Wajnberg G, Roy J, et al. Identification of a circulating miRNA signature in extracellular vesicles collected from amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. Brain Res 2019; 1708:100108.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katsu M, Hama Y, Utsumi J, et al. MicroRNA expression profiles of neuron-derived extracellular vesicles in plasma from patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurosci Lett 2019; 708:134176.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Otake K, Kamiguchi H, Hirozane Y. Identification of biomarkers for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis by comprehensive analysis of exosomal mRNAs in human cerebrospinal fluid. BMC Med Genomics 2019; 12:7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dolinar A, Koritnik B, Glava&#x10d; D, Ravnik-Glava&#x10d; M. Circular RNAs as potential blood biomarkers in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Mol Neurobiol 2019; 56:80528062.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cammack AJ, Atassi N, Hyman T, et al. Prospective natural history study of C9orf72 ALS clinical characteristics and biomarkers. Neurology 2019; 93:e1605-e1617.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gendron TF, Chew J, Stankowski JN, et al. Poly(GP) proteins are a useful pharmacodynamic marker for C9ORF72-associated amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Sci Transl Med 2017; 9:eaai7866.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gertsman I, Wuu J, McAlonis-Downes M, et al. An endogenous peptide marker differentiates SOD1 stability and facilitates pharmacodynamic monitoring in SOD1 amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. JCI Insight 2019; 4:e122768.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sproviero D, La Salvia S, Colombo F, et al. Leukocyte derived microvesicles as disease progression biomarkers in slow progressing amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. Front Neurosci 2019; 13:344.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hishizawa M, Yamashita H, Akizuki M, et al. TDP-43 levels are higher in platelets from patients with sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis than in healthy controls. Neurochem Int 2019; 124:4145.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasai T, Kojima Y, Ohmichi T, et al. Combined use of CSF NfL and CSF TDP-43 improves diagnostic performance in ALS. Ann Clin Transl Neurol 2019; 6:24892502.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gagliardi D, Meneri M, Saccomanno D, et al. Diagnostic and prognostic role of blood and cerebrospinal fluid and blood neurofilaments in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a review of the literature. Int J Mol Sci 2019; 20:4152.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forgrave LM, Ma M, Best JR, DeMarco ML. The diagnostic performance of neurofilament light chain in CSF and blood for Alzheimer's disease, frontotemporal dementia, and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Alzheimers Dement (Amst) 2019; 11:730743.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verde F, Steinacker P, Weishaupt JH, et al. Neurofilament light chain in serum for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2019; 90:157164.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thouvenot E, Demattei C, Lehmann S, et al. Serum neurofilament light chain at time of diagnosis is an independent prognostic factor of survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Eur J Neurol 2020; 27:251257.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abu-Rumeileh S, Vacchiano V, Zenesini C, et al. BoReALS. Diagnostic-prognostic value and electrophysiological correlates of CSF biomarkers of neurodegeneration and neuroinflammation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol 2020; 16991708.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilke C, Pujol-Calder&#xf3;n F, Barro C, et al. Correlations between serum and CSF pNfH levels in ALS, FTD and controls: a comparison of three analytical approaches. Clin Chem Lab Med 2019; 57:15561564.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benatar M, Zhang L, Wang L, et al. CReATe Consortium. Validation of serum neurofilaments as prognostic and potential pharmacodynamic biomarkers for ALS. Neurology 2020; 95:e59e69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Falzone YM, Domi T, Agosta F, et al. Serum phosphorylated neurofilament heavy-chain levels reflect phenotypic heterogeneity and are an independent predictor of survival in motor neuron disease. J Neurol 2020; 267:22722280.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devos D, Moreau C, Kyheng M, et al. A ferroptosis-based panel of prognostic biomarkers for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Sci Rep 2019; 9:2918.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oeckl P, Weydt P, Thal DR, et al. Proteomics in cerebrospinal fluid and spinal cord suggests UCHL1, MAP2 and GPNMB as biomarkers and underpins importance of transcriptional pathways in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathol 2020; 139:119134.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitsumoto H, Garofalo DC, Santella RM, et al. Plasma creatinine and oxidative stress biomarkers in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2020; 21:263272.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yazdani S, Mariosa D, Hammar N, et al. Peripheral immune biomarkers and neurodegenerative diseases: a prospective cohort study with 20 years of follow-up. Ann Neurol 2019; 86:913926.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wosiski-Kuhn M, Robinson M, Strupe J, et al. IL6 receptor(358)Ala variant and trans-signaling are disease modifiers in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurol Neuroimmunol Neuroinflamm 2019; 6:e631.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y, Xia K, Chen L, Fan D. Increased interleukin-6 levels in the astrocyte-derived exosomes of sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. Front Neurosci 2019; 13:574.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pronto-Laborinho A, Pinto S, Gromicho M, et al. Interleukin-6 and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Sci 2019; 398:5053.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olesen MN, Wuolikainen A, Nilsson AC, et al. Inflammatory profiles relate to survival in subtypes of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurol Neuroimmunol Neuroinflamm 2020; 7:e697.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin M, G&#xfc;nther R, Akg&#xfc;n K, et al. Peripheral proinflammatory Th1/Th17 immune cell shift is linked to disease severity in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Sci Rep 2020; 10:5941.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ingre C, Chen L, Zhan Y, et al. Lipids apolipoproteins, and prognosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology 2020; 94:e1835e1844.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J&#xe9;sus P, Blasco H, Patin F, et al. Ferritin and LDL-cholesterol as biomarkers of fat-free mass loss in ALS. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2019; 20:441444.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lanznaster D, Bejan-Angoulvant T, Patin F, et al. Plasma creatinine and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis prognosis: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2019; 20:199206.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petillon C, Hergesheimer R, Puy H, et al. The relevancy of data regarding the metabolism of iron to our understanding of deregulated mechanisms in ALS; hypotheses and pitfalls. Fron Neurosci 2018; 12:1031.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun Q, Yang F, Wang H, et al. Elevated serum ferritin level as a predictor of reduced survival in patients with sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in China: a retrospective study. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2019; 20:186191.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson AG, Gray E, Bampton A, et al. CSF chitinase proteins in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychitry 2019; 90:1215.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gille B, De Schaepdryver M, Dedeene L, et al. Inflammatory markers in cerebrospinal fluid: independent prognostic biomarkers in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis? J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2019; 90:13381346.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vu L, An J, Kovalik T, et al. Cross-sectional and longitudinal measures of chitinase proteins in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and expression of CHI3L1 in activated astrocytes. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2020; 91:350358.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lanznaster D, Hergesheimer RC, Bakkouche SE, et al. A&#x3b2;1-42 and Tau as potential biomarkers for diagnosis and prognosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. IntJ Mol Sci 2020; 21:2911.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hedl TJ, San Gil R, Cheng F, et al. Proteomics approaches for biomarker and drug target discovery in ALS and FTD. Front Neurosci 2019; 13:548.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayashi N, Doi H, Kurata Y, et al. Proteomic analysis of exosome-enriched fractions derived from cerebrospinal fluid of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. Neurosci Res 2019; S0168-0102(19)30487-0.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu S, Wuolikainen A, Wu J, et al. Targeted multiple reaction monitoring analysis of CSF identifies UCHL1 and GPNMB as candidate biomarkers for ALS. J Mol Neurosci 2019; 69:643657.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leoni E, Bremang M, Mitra V, et al. Combined tissue-fluid proteomics to unravel phenotypic variability in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Sci Rep 2019; 9:4478.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klickovic U, Zampedri L, Sinclair CDJ, et al. Skeletal muscle MRI differentiates SBMA and ALS and correlates with disease severity. Neurology 2019; 93:e895e907.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Burgh HK, Westeneng HJ, Meier JM, et al. Cross-sectional and longitudinal assessment of the upper cervical spinal cord in motor neuron disease. Neuroimage Clin 2019; 24:101984.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Welton T, Maller JJ, Lebel RM, et al. Diffusion kurtosis and quantitative susceptibility mapping MRI are sensitive to structural abnormalities in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuroimage Clin 2019; 24:101953.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bede P, Chipika RH, Finegan E, et al. Brainstem pathology in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and primary lateral sclerosis: a longitudinal neuroimaging study. Neuroimage Clin 2019; 24:102054.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baek SH, Park J, Kim YH, et al. Usefulness of diffusion tensor imaging findings as biomarkers for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Sci Rep 2020; 10:5199.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sako W, Abe T, Izumi Y, et al. Deterministic-tractography-based approach for diagnosis and disease monitoring of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Neurol Neurosurg 2019; 181:7375.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Contarino VE, Conte G, Morelli C, et al. Toward a marker of upper motor neuron impairment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A fully automatic investigation of the magnetic susceptibility in the precentral cortex. Eur J Radiol 2020; 124:108815.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xed;os-D&#xed;az J, Del Ba&#xf1;o-Aledo ME, Tembl-Ferrair&#xf3; JI, et al. Quantitative neuromuscular ultrasound analysis as biomarkers in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Eur Radiol 2019; 29:42664275.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pathak S, Caress JB, Wosiski-Kuhn M, et al. A pilot study of neuromuscular ultrasound as a biomarker for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve 2019; 59:181186.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hensiek N, Schreiber F, Wimmer T, et al. Sonographic and 3T-MRI-based evaluation of the tongue in ALS. Neuroimage Clin 2020; 26:102233.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Vocht J, Blommaert J, Devrome M, et al. Use of multimodal imaging and clinical biomarkers in presymptomatic carriers of C9orf72 repeat expansion. JAMA Neurol 2020; EPub May 18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dios AM, Babu S, Granucci EJ, et al. Class I and II histone deacetylase expression is not altered in human amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Neuropathological and positron emission tomography molecular neuroimaging evidence. Muscle Nerve 2019; 60:443452.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ikawa M, Okazawa H, Yoneda M. Positron emission tomography imaging for oxidative stress in mitochondrial and neurodegenerative diseases. Brain Nerve 2019; 71:161166.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Weehaeghe D, Babu S, De Vocht J, et al. Moving towards multicenter therapeutic trials in ALS: feasibility of data pooling using different TSPO positron emission tomography (PET) radioligands. J Nucl Med 2020; EPub Mar 13 (jnumed.119.241059).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blicher JU, Eskildsen SF, St&#xe6;rmose TG, et al. Short echo-time magnetic resonance spectroscopy in ALS, simultaneous quantification of glutamate and GABA at 3 T. Sci Rep 2019; 9:17593.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Srivastava O, Hanstock C, Chenji S, et al. Cerebral degeneration in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. A prospective multicenter magnetic resonance spectroscopy study. Neurol Clin Pract 2019; 9:400407.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheong I, Deelchand DK, Eberly LE, et al. Neurochemical correlates of functional decline in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2019; 90:294301.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMackin R, Dukic S, Broderick M, et al. Dysfunction of attention switching networks in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuroimage Clin 2019; 22:101707.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dukic S, McMackin R, Buxo T, et al. Patterned functional network disruption in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Human Brain Mapp 2019; 40:48274842.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jenkins TM, Alix JJP, Fingret J, et al. Longitudinal multimodal muscle-based biomarker assessment in motor neuron disease. J Neurol 2020; 267:244256.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bashford J, Wickham A, Iniesta R, et al. SPiQE: an automated analytical tool for detecting and characterising fasciculations in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Neurophysiol 2019; 130:10831090.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bashford J, Masood U, Wickham A, et al. Fasciculations demonstrate daytime consistency in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve 2020; 61:745750.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alix JJP, Neuwirth C, Gelder L, et al. Assessment of the reliability of the motor unit size index (MUSIX) in single subject &#x2018;round-robin&#x2019; and multicentre settings. Clin Neurophysiol 2019; 130:666674.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alix JJP, McDonough HE, Sonbas B, et al. Multidimensional electrical impedance myography of the tongue as a potential biomarker for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Neurophysiol 2020; 131:799808.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>