<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">32807149</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>24</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2466</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>20</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>17</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC pulmonary medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Pulm Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Home mechanical ventilation: quality of life patterns after six months of treatment.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>221</StartPage><MedlinePgn>221</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">221</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12890-020-01262-z</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">It has been shown that home mechanical ventilation improves quality of life, but it has not been widely studied which particular patient groups benefit the most from starting this type of therapy. The purpose of this prospective observational study was to evaluate quality of life change patterns 6 months after initiation of home mechanical ventilation in patients suffering from chronic respiratory failure using patient reported outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We enrolled 74 chronic respiratory failure patients starting invasive or noninvasive home mechanical ventilation through the Semmelweis University Home Mechanical Ventilation Program. Quality of life was evaluated at baseline and at 6 months after initiation of home mechanical ventilation using the Severe Respiratory Insufficiency Questionnaire.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Overall quality of life showed 10.5% improvement 6 months after initiation of home mechanical ventilation (p&#xa0;&lt;&#x2009;0.001). The greatest improvement was observed in Respiratory complaint (20.4%, p&#xa0;=&#x2009;0.015), Sleep and attendant symptoms (19.3%, p&#xa0;&lt;&#x2009;0.001), and Anxiety related subscales (14.4%, p&#xa0;&lt;&#x2009;0.001). Interface (invasive versus noninvasive ventilation) was not associated with improvement in quality of life (p&#xa0;=&#x2009;0.660). Severely impaired patients showed the greatest improvement (CC&#x2009;=&#x2009;-0.328, p&#xa0;&lt;&#x2009;0.001). Initial diagnosis contributed to the observed change (p&#xa0;=&#x2009;0.025), with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease and obesity hypoventilation syndrome patients showing the greatest improvement, while amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients showed no improvement in quality of life. We found that patients who were started on long term ventilation in an acute setting, required oxygen supplementation and had low baseline quality of life, showed the most improvement during the six-month study period.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Our study highlights the profound effect of home mechanical ventilation on quality of life in chronic respiratory failure patients that is indifferent of ventilation interface but is dependent on initial diagnosis and some baseline characteristics, like acute initiation, oxygen supplementation need and baseline quality of life.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">This study was approved by and registered at the ethics committee of Semmelweis University (SE TUKEB 251/2017; 20th of December, 2017).</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Valko</LastName><ForeName>Luca</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4046-4681</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology and Intensive Therapy, Semmelweis University, Ulloi ut 78/B, Budapest, 1082, Hungary. valko.luca@med.semmelweis-univ.hu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Baglyas</LastName><ForeName>Szabolcs</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology and Intensive Therapy, Semmelweis University, Ulloi ut 78/B, Budapest, 1082, Hungary.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gyarmathy</LastName><ForeName>V Anna</ForeName><Initials>VA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>EpiConsult, Dover, DE, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Johns Hopkins Bloomberg School of Public Health, K&#xe1;roly Racz School of PhD Studies, Semmelweis University, 8 the Green, STE A, Dover, DE, 19904, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gal</LastName><ForeName>Janos</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology and Intensive Therapy, Semmelweis University, Ulloi ut 78/B, Budapest, 1082, Hungary.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lorx</LastName><ForeName>Andras</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology and Intensive Therapy, Semmelweis University, Ulloi ut 78/B, Budapest, 1082, Hungary.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D064888">Observational Study</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Pulm Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100968563</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2466</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018575" MajorTopicYN="Y">Home Care Services, Hospital-Based</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006814" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Hungary</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010845" MajorTopicYN="N">Obesity Hypoventilation Syndrome</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011446" MajorTopicYN="N">Prospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D029424" MajorTopicYN="N">Pulmonary Disease, Chronic Obstructive</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="Y">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012121" MajorTopicYN="N">Respiration, Artificial</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012129" MajorTopicYN="N">Respiratory Function Tests</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012131" MajorTopicYN="N">Respiratory Insufficiency</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011795" MajorTopicYN="N">Surveys and Questionnaires</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Chronic respiratory failure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Domiciliary ventilation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Home mechanical ventilation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long term ventilation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of life change</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32807149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7433042</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12890-020-01262-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12890-020-01262-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>McKim DA, Road J, Avendano M, Abdool S, Cote F, Duguid N, Fraser J, Maltais F, Morrison DL, O'Connell C, et al. Home mechanical ventilation: a Canadian thoracic society clinical practice guideline. Can Respir J. 2011;18(4):197&#x2013;215.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3205101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22059178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Windisch W, Geiseler J, Simon K, Walterspacher S, Dreher M. German National Guideline for treating chronic respiratory failure with invasive and non-invasive ventilation: revised edition 2017 - part 1. Respiration. 2018;96(1):66&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29945148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Windisch W, Geiseler J, Simon K, Walterspacher S, Dreher M. German National Guideline for treating chronic respiratory failure with invasive and non-invasive ventilation - revised edition 2017: part 2. Respiration. 2018;96(2):171&#x2013;203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29945156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacIntyre EJ, Asadi L, McKim DA, Bagshaw SM. Clinical outcomes associated with home mechanical ventilation: a systematic review. Can Respir J. 2016;2016:6547180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4904519</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27445559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lloyd-Owen SJ, Donaldson GC, Ambrosino N, Escarabill J, Farre R, Fauroux B, Robert D, Schoenhofer B, Simonds AK, Wedzicha JA. Patterns of home mechanical ventilation use in Europe: results from the Eurovent survey. Eur Respir J. 2005;25(6):1025&#x2013;1031.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15929957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodwin S, Smith H, Langton Hewer S, Fleming P, Henderson AJ, Hilliard T, Fraser J. Increasing prevalence of domiciliary ventilation: changes in service demand and provision in the south west of the UK. Eur J Pediatr. 2011;170(9):1187&#x2013;1192.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21360027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hannan LM, Sahi H, Road JD, McDonald CF, Berlowitz DJ, Howard ME. Care practices and health-related quality of life for individuals receiving assisted ventilation. A cross-National Study. Ann Am Thorac Soc. 2016;13(6):894&#x2013;903.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27295155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Budweiser S, Hitzl AP, Jorres RA, Schmidbauer K, Heinemann F, Pfeifer M. Health-related quality of life and long-term prognosis in chronic hypercapnic respiratory failure: a prospective survival analysis. Respir Res. 2007;8(1):92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2222604</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18086309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Struik FM, Kerstjens HA, Bladder G, Sprooten R, Zijnen M, Asin J, van der Molen T, Wijkstra PJ. The severe respiratory insufficiency questionnaire scored best in the assessment of health-related quality of life in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. J Clin Epidemiol. 2013;66(10):1166&#x2013;1174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23835311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oga T, Windisch W, Handa T, Hirai T, Chin K. Health-related quality of life measurement in patients with chronic respiratory failure. Respir Investig. 2018;56(3):214&#x2013;221.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29773292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oga T, Taniguchi H, Kita H, Tsuboi T, Tomii K, Ando M, Kojima E, Tomioka H, Taguchi Y, Kaji Y, et al. Comparison of different disease-specific health-related quality of life measurements in patients with long-term noninvasive ventilation. Can Respir J. 2017;2017:8295079.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5447275</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28588383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Windisch W, Freidel K, Schucher B, Baumann H, Wiebel M, Matthys H, Petermann F. The severe respiratory insufficiency (SRI) questionnaire: a specific measure of health-related quality of life in patients receiving home mechanical ventilation. J Clin Epidemiol. 2003;56(8):752&#x2013;759.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12954467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Windisch W. Impact of home mechanical ventilation on health-related quality of life. Eur Respir J. 2008;32(5):1328&#x2013;1336.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18579546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huttmann SE, Windisch W, Storre JH. Invasive home mechanical ventilation: living conditions and health-related quality of life. Respiration. 2015;89(4):312&#x2013;321.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25791249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Campos JL, Failde I, Masa JF, Benitez-Moya JM, Barrot E, Ayerbe R, Leon-Jimenez A, Windisch W. Transculturally adapted Spanish SRI questionnaire for home mechanically ventilated patients was viable, valid, and reliable. J Clin Epidemiol. 2008;61(10):1061&#x2013;1066.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18367377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghosh D, Rzehak P, Elliott MW, Windisch W. Validation of the English severe respiratory insufficiency questionnaire. Eur Respir J. 2012;40(2):408&#x2013;415.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22183492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Markussen H, Lehmann S, Nilsen RM, Natvig GK. The Norwegian version of the severe respiratory insufficiency questionnaire. Int J Nurs Pract. 2015;21(3):229&#x2013;238.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24762168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen R, Guan L, Wu W, Yang Z, Li X, Luo Q, Liang Z, Wang F, Guo B, Huo Y, et al. The Chinese version of the severe respiratory insufficiency questionnaire for patients with chronic hypercapnic chronic obstructive pulmonary disease receiving non-invasive positive pressure ventilation. BMJ Open. 2017;7(8):e017712.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5724189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28851800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oga T, Taniguchi H, Kita H, Tsuboi T, Tomii K, Ando M, Kojima E, Tomioka H, Taguchi Y, Kaji Y, et al. Validation of the Japanese severe respiratory insufficiency questionnaire in hypercapnic patients with noninvasive ventilation. Respir Investig. 2017;55(2):166&#x2013;172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28274533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro C, Ferreira D, Conde S, Oliveira P, Windisch W. Validation of the Portuguese severe respiratory insufficiency questionnaire for home mechanically ventilated patients. Rev Port Pneumol. 2017;23(3):139&#x2013;145.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28238622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valko L, Baglyas S, Kunos L, Terray-Horvath A, Lorx A, Gal J, Windisch W. Validation of the Hungarian version of the SRI questionnaire. BMC Pulm Med. 2020;20(1):130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7204221</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32380984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsolaki V, Pastaka C, Kostikas K, Karetsi E, Dimoulis A, Zikiri A, Koutsokera A, Gourgoulianis KI. Noninvasive ventilation in chronic respiratory failure: effects on quality of life. Respiration. 2011;81(5):402&#x2013;410.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20588002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Struik FM, Sprooten RT, Kerstjens HA, Bladder G, Zijnen M, Asin J, Cobben NA, Vonk JM, Wijkstra PJ. Nocturnal non-invasive ventilation in COPD patients with prolonged hypercapnia after ventilatory support for acute respiratory failure: a randomised, controlled, parallel-group study. Thorax. 2014;69(9):826&#x2013;834.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24781217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy PB, Rehal S, Arbane G, Bourke S, Calverley PMA, Crook AM, Dowson L, Duffy N, Gibson GJ, Hughes PD, et al. Effect of home noninvasive ventilation with oxygen therapy vs oxygen therapy alone on hospital readmission or death after an acute COPD exacerbation: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA. 2017;317(21):2177&#x2013;2186.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5710342</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28528348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howard ME, Piper AJ, Stevens B, Holland AE, Yee BJ, Dabscheck E, Mortimer D, Burge AT, Flunt D, Buchan C, et al. A randomised controlled trial of CPAP versus non-invasive ventilation for initial treatment of obesity hypoventilation syndrome. Thorax. 2017;72(5):437&#x2013;444.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27852952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Storre JH, Seuthe B, Fiechter R, Milioglou S, Dreher M, Sorichter S, Windisch W. Average volume-assured pressure support in obesity hypoventilation: a randomized crossover trial. Chest. 2006;130(3):815&#x2013;821.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16963680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy PB, Brignall K, Moxham J, Polkey MI, Davidson AC, Hart N. High pressure versus high intensity noninvasive ventilation in stable hypercapnic chronic obstructive pulmonary disease: a randomized crossover trial. Int J Chron Obstruct Pulmon Dis. 2012;7:811&#x2013;818.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3526870</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23271905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Storre JH, Matrosovich E, Ekkernkamp E, Walker DJ, Schmoor C, Dreher M, Windisch W. Home mechanical ventilation for COPD: high-intensity versus target volume noninvasive ventilation. Respir Care. 2014;59(9):1389&#x2013;1397.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25074944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arellano-Maric MP, Hamm C, Duiverman ML, Schwarz S, Callegari J, Storre JH, Schmoor C, Spielmanns M, Galetke W, Windisch W. Obesity hypoventilation syndrome treated with non-invasive ventilation: Is a switch to CPAP therapy feasible? Respirology. 2020;25(4):435&#x2013;442.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31597227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Windisch W, Budweiser S, Heinemann F, Pfeifer M, Rzehak P. The severe respiratory insufficiency questionnaire was valid for COPD patients with severe chronic respiratory failure. J Clin Epidemiol. 2008;61(8):848&#x2013;853.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18367376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walterspacher S, July J, Kohlh&#xe4;ufl M, Rzehak P, Windisch W. The severe respiratory insufficiency questionnaire for subjects with COPD with long-term oxygen therapy. Respir Care. 2016;61(9):1186&#x2013;1191.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27118875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huttmann SE, Magnet FS, Karagiannidis C, Storre JH, Windisch W. Quality of life and life satisfaction are severely impaired in patients with long-term invasive ventilation following ICU treatment and unsuccessful weaning. Ann Intensive Care. 2018;8(1):38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5856853</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29549456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raveling T, Bladder G, Vonk JM, Nieuwenhuis JA, Verdonk-Struik FM, Wijkstra PJ, Duiverman ML. Improvement in hypercapnia does not predict survival in COPD patients on chronic noninvasive ventilation. Int J Chron Obstruct Pulmon Dis. 2018;13:3625&#x2013;3634.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6219270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30464445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marchese S, Lo Coco D, Lo Coco A. Outcome and attitudes toward home tracheostomy ventilation of consecutive patients: a 10-year experience. Respir Med. 2008;102(3):430&#x2013;436.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18023334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Markstrom A, Sundell K, Lysdahl M, Andersson G, Schedin U, Klang B. Quality-of-life evaluation of patients with neuromuscular and skeletal diseases treated with noninvasive and invasive home mechanical ventilation. Chest. 2002;122(5):1695&#x2013;1700.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12426273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rabkin J, Ogino M, Goetz R, McElhiney M, Hupf J, Heitzman D, Heiman-Patterson T, Miller R, Katz J, Lomen-Hoerth C, et al. Japanese and American ALS patient preferences regarding TIV (tracheostomy with invasive ventilation): a cross-national survey. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2014;15(3&#x2013;4):185&#x2013;191.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24720451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valko L, Baglyas S, Gal J, Lorx A. National survey: current prevalence and characteristics of home mechanical ventilation in Hungary. BMC Pulmon Med. 2018;18(1):190.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6282340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30522473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kohnlein T, Windisch W, Kohler D, Drabik A, Geiseler J, Hartl S, Karg O, Laier-Groeneveld G, Nava S, Schonhofer B, et al. Non-invasive positive pressure ventilation for the treatment of severe stable chronic obstructive pulmonary disease: a prospective, multicentre, randomised, controlled clinical trial. Lancet Respir Med. 2014;2(9):698&#x2013;705.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25066329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ankjaergaard KL, Tonnesen P, Laursen LC, Hansen EF, Andreassen HF, Wilcke JT. Home non invasive ventilation (NIV) treatment for COPD patients with a history of NIV-treated exacerbation; a randomized, controlled, multi-center study. BMC Pulmon Med. 2016;16:32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4751632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26867542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dretzke J, Moore D, Dave C, Mukherjee R, Price MJ, Bayliss S, Wu X, Jordan RE, Turner AM. The effect of domiciliary noninvasive ventilation on clinical outcomes in stable and recently hospitalized patients with COPD: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Int J Chron Obstruct Pulmon Dis. 2016;11:2269&#x2013;2286.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5034919</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27698560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Randerath W, Verbraecken J, Andreas S, Arzt M, Bloch KE, Brack T, Buyse B, De Backer W, Eckert DJ, Grote L, et al. Definition, discrimination, diagnosis and treatment of central breathing disturbances during sleep. Eur Respir J. 2017;49(1):1600959.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27920092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piper A. Obesity hypoventilation syndrome: weighing in on therapy options. Chest. 2016;149(3):856&#x2013;868.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26292036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ng L, Khan F, Young CA, Galea M. Symptomatic treatments for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis/motor neuron disease. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2017;1:Cd011776.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6469543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28072907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bourke SC, Tomlinson M, Williams TL, Bullock RE, Shaw PJ, Gibson GJ. Effects of non-invasive ventilation on survival and quality of life in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a randomised controlled trial. Lancet Neurol. 2006;5(2):140&#x2013;147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16426990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>