<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">32819346</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>10</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1472-6947</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>20</Volume><Issue>Suppl 5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>20</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC medical informatics and decision making</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Med Inform Decis Mak</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Exploiting mutual information for the imputation of static and dynamic mixed-type clinical data with an adaptive k-nearest neighbours approach.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>174</StartPage><MedlinePgn>174</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">174</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12911-020-01166-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Clinical registers constitute an invaluable resource in the medical data-driven decision making context. Accurate machine learning and data mining approaches on these data can lead to faster diagnosis, definition of tailored interventions, and improved outcome prediction. A typical issue when implementing such approaches is the almost unavoidable presence of missing values in the collected data. In this work, we propose an imputation algorithm based on a mutual information-weighted k-nearest neighbours approach, able to handle the simultaneous presence of missing information in different types of variables. We developed and validated the method on a clinical register, constituted by the information collected over subsequent screening visits of a cohort of patients affected by amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">For each subject with missing data to be imputed, we create a feature vector constituted by the information collected over his/her first three months of visits. This vector is used as sample in a k-nearest neighbours procedure, in order to select, among the other patients, the ones with the most similar temporal evolution of the disease over time. An ad hoc similarity metric was implemented for the sample comparison, capable of handling the different nature of the data, the presence of multiple missing values and include the cross-information among features captured by the mutual information statistic.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">We validated the proposed imputation method on an independent test set, comparing its performance with those of three state-of-the-art competitors, resulting in better performance. We further assessed the validity of our algorithm by comparing the performance of a survival classifier built on the data imputed with our method versus the one built on the data imputed with the best-performing competitor.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Imputation of missing data is a crucial -and often mandatory- step when working with real-world datasets. The algorithm proposed in this work could effectively impute an amyotrophic lateral sclerosis clinical dataset, by handling the temporal and the mixed-type nature of the data and by exploiting the cross-information among features. We also showed how the imputation quality can affect a machine learning task.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tavazzi</LastName><ForeName>Erica</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Information Engineering, University of Padua, Via Gradenigo 6/A, Padua, 35131, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Daberdaku</LastName><ForeName>Sebastian</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Information Engineering, University of Padua, Via Gradenigo 6/A, Padua, 35131, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vasta</LastName><ForeName>Rosario</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosciences "Rita Levi Montalcini", University of Turin, Via Cherasco 15, Turin, 10124, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Calvo</LastName><ForeName>Andrea</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosciences "Rita Levi Montalcini", University of Turin, Via Cherasco 15, Turin, 10124, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chi&#xf2;</LastName><ForeName>Adriano</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosciences "Rita Levi Montalcini", University of Turin, Via Cherasco 15, Turin, 10124, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Di Camillo</LastName><ForeName>Barbara</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8415-4688</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Information Engineering, University of Padua, Via Gradenigo 6/A, Padua, 35131, Italy. barbara.dicamillo@unipd.it.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Med Inform Decis Mak</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101088682</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1472-6947</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000465" MajorTopicYN="Y">Algorithms</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001499" MajorTopicYN="N">Bayes Theorem</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019295" MajorTopicYN="N">Computational Biology</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057225" MajorTopicYN="Y">Data Mining</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D066264" MajorTopicYN="Y">Datasets as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004194" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000145" MajorTopicYN="N">classification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016247" MajorTopicYN="N">Information Storage and Retrieval</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Clinical datasets</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Imputation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">K-nearest neighbours</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Missing data</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mutual information</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Na&#xef;ve Bayes</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32819346</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7439551</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12911-020-01166-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12911-020-01166-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>El Morr C, Ali-Hassan H. Analytics in Healthcare: A Practical Introduction. Cham: Springer; 2019. Healthcare analytics applications.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Islam M, Hasan M, Wang X, Germack H, Noor-E-Alam M. A systematic review on healthcare analytics: Application and theoretical perspective of data mining.Healthcare. 2018; 6(2).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6023432</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29882866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Editorial. Ascent of machine learning in medicine.Nature Materials. 2019; 18(407).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31000807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davenport T, Kalakota R. The potential for artificial intelligence in healthcare. Future Healthc J. 2019;6(2):94&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6616181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31363513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gogtay N, Thatte U. Survival analysis. J Assoc Physicians India. 2017;65:80&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28782317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao C, Choi E, Sun J. Opportunities and challenges in developing deep learning models using electronic health records data: a systematic review. J Am Med Inform Assoc. 2018;25(10):1419&#x2013;1428.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6188527</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29893864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waljee A, Mukherjee A, Singal A, Zhang Y, Warren J, Balis U, Marrero J, Zhu J, Higgins P. Comparison of imputation methods for missing laboratory data in medicine.Br Med J (BMJ) Open. 2013; 3(8).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3733317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23906948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham J. Missing data analysis: Making it work in the real world. Annu Rev Psychol. 2009;60(1):549&#x2013;576.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18652544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rombach I, Gray A, Jenkinson C, Murray D, Rivero-Arias O. Multiple imputation for patient reported outcome measures in randomised controlled trials: advantages and disadvantages of imputing at the item, subscale or composite score level. BioMed Cent (BMC) Med Res Methodol. 2018;18(1):87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6114240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30153796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Buuren S, Boshuizen H, Knook D. Multiple imputation of missing blood pressure covariates in survival analysis. Statistics in Medicine. 1999;18(6):681&#x2013;694.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10204197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azimi I, Pahikkala T, Rahmani A, Niela-Vil&#xe9;n H, Axelin A, Liljeberg P. Missing data resilient decision-making for healthcare iot through personalization: A case study on maternal health. Futur Gener Comput Syst. 2019;96:297&#x2013;308.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beaulieu-Jones B, Lavage D, Snyder J, Moore J, Pendergrass S, Bauer C. Characterizing and managing missing structured data in electronic health records: data analysis. J Med Internet Res (JMIR) Med Inform. 2018;6(1):11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5845101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29475824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donders A, van der Heijden G. J. M. G., Stijnen T, Moons K. Review: A gentle introduction to imputation of missing values. J Clin Epidemiol. 2006;59(10):1087&#x2013;1091.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16980149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hori T, Montcho D, Agbangla C, Ebana K, Futakuchi K, Iwata H. Multi-task gaussian process for imputing missing data in multi-trait and multi-environment trials. Theor Appl Genet. 2016;129(11):2101&#x2013;2115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27540725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu H-F, Rao N, Dhillon I. Temporal regularized matrix factorization for high-dimensional time series prediction. In: Lee D, Sugiyama M, Luxburg U, Guyon I, Garnett R, editors. Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems 29. Barcelona, Spain: Curran Associates, Inc.; 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Honaker J, King G, Blackwell M. Amelia II: A Program for Missing Data. J Stat Softw. 2011;45(7):1&#x2013;47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo Y, Szolovits P, Dighe A, Baron J. 3D-MICE: integration of cross-sectional and longitudinal imputation for multi-analyte longitudinal clinical data. J Am Med Inform Assoc. 2017;25(6):645&#x2013;653.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7646951</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29202205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2; A, Mora G, Moglia C, Manera U, Canosa A, Cammarosano S, Ilardi A, Bertuzzo D, Bersano E, Cugnasco P, Grassano M, Pisano F, Mazzini L, Calvo A. Secular Trends of Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis: The Piemonte and Valle d&#x2019;Aosta Register. J Am Med Assoc (JAMA) Neurol. 2017;74(9):1097&#x2013;1104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5710181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28692730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenland S, Finkle W. A critical look at methods for handling missing covariates in epidemiologic regression analyses. Am J Epidemiol. 1995;142(12):1255&#x2013;1264.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7503045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beretta L, Santaniello A. Nearest neighbor imputation algorithms: a critical evaluation. BioMed Central (BMC) Med Inform Decis Mak. 2016;16(3):74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4959387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27454392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bell M, Fiero M, Horton N, Hsu C-H. Handling missing data in rcts; a review of the top medical journals. BioMed Central (BMC) Med Res Methodol. 2014;14(1):118.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4247714</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25407057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng C-Y, Harwell M, Liou S-M, Ehman L. Advances in missing data methods and implications for educational research. Chap. 3. In: Sawilowsky S, editor. Real Data Analysis. Quantitative Methods in Education and the Behavioral Sciences: Issues, Research, and Teaching. New York: Information Age Publishing; 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weber G, Adams W, Bernstam E, Bickel J, Fox K, Marsolo K, Raghavan V, Turchin A, Zhou X, Murphy S, Mandl K. Biases introduced by filtering electronic health records for patients with &#x201c;complete data&#x201d;. J Am Med Inform Assoc. 2017;24(6):1134&#x2013;1141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6080680</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29016972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo Y, Xin Y, Joshi R, Celi L, Szolovits P. Proceedings of the Thirtieth Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence (AAAI) Conference on Artificial Intelligence. AAAI&#x2019;16. Phoenix, Arizona, USA: AAAI Press; 2016. Predicting ICU mortality risk by grouping temporal trends from a multivariate panel of physiologic measurements.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Z. Missing data imputation: focusing on single imputation.Annals of Translational Medicine. 2016; 4(1).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4716933</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26855945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moritz S, Bartz-Beielstein T. imputeTS: Time Series Missing Value Imputation in R. The R Journal. 2017;9(1):207&#x2013;218.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ray E, Qian J, Brecha R, Reilly M, Foulkes A. Stochastic imputation for integrated transcriptome association analysis of a longitudinally measured trait.Stat Methods Med Res. 2019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31172883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Buuren S, Groothuis-Oudshoorn K. mice: Multivariate Imputation by Chained Equations in R. J Stat Softw. 2011;45(3):1&#x2013;67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azur M, Stuart E, Frangakis C, Leaf P. Multiple imputation by chained equations: what is it and how does it work? Int J Methods Psychiatr Res. 2011;20(1):40&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3074241</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21499542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rasmussen C. Gaussian processes in machine learning. In: Bousquet O, von Luxburg U., R&#xe4;tsch G, editors. Advanced Lectures on Machine Learning: ML Summer Schools 2003, Canberra, Australia, February 2 - 14, 2003, T&#xfc;bingen, Germany, August 4 - 16, 2003, Revised Lectures. Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer; 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stekhoven D, B&#xfc;hlmann P. MissForest&#x2013;non-parametric missing value imputation for mixed-type data. Bioinformatics. 2011;28(1):112&#x2013;118.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22039212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao W, Wang D, Li J, Zhou H, Li L, Li Y. Brits: bidirectional recurrent imputation for time series In: Bengio S, Wallach H, Larochelle H, Grauman K, Cesa-Bianchi N, Garnett R, editors. Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems 31 Curran Associates Inc.Montr&#xe9;al, Canada: 2018. p. 6775&#x2013;6785.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo Y, Cai X, Zhang Y, Xu J, Yuan X. Multivariate time series imputation with generative adversarial networks In: Bengio S, Wallach H, Larochelle H, Grauman K, Cesa-Bianchi N, Garnett R, editors. Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems 31 Curran Associates Inc.Montr&#xe9;al, Canada: 2018. p. 1603&#x2013;1614.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoon J, Zame W, van der Schaar M. Estimating missing data in temporal data streams using multi-directional recurrent neural networks. (IEEE) Trans Biomed Eng. 2019;66(5):1477&#x2013;1490.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30296210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andridge R, Little R. A review of hot deck imputation for survey non-response. Int Stat Rev. 2010;78(1):40&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3130338</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21743766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yenduri S, Iyengar S. Int J Softw Eng Knowl Eng. 2007; 17(01):127&#x2013;152.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fournier C, Glass J. Modeling the course of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat Biotechnol. 2015;33(1):45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25574636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Es M, Hardiman O, Chio A, Al-Chalabi A, Pasterkamp R, Veldink J, Van den Berg LH. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.The Lancet. 2017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28552366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huisman M, de Jong S, van Doormaal P, Weinreich S, Schelhaas H, van der Kooi AJ, de Visser M, Veldink J, van den Berg LH. Population based epidemiology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis using capture&#x2013;recapture methodology. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2011;82(10):1165&#x2013;1170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21622937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atassi N, Berry J, Shui A, Zach N, Sherman A, Sinani E, Walker J, Katsovskiy I, Schoenfeld D, Cudkowicz M, Leitner M. The PRO-ACT database design, initial analyses, and predictive features. Neurology. 2014;83(19):1719&#x2013;1725.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4239834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25298304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xfc;ffner R, Zach N, Norel R, Hawe J, Schoenfeld D, Wang L, Li G, Fang L, Mackey L, Hardiman O, Cudkowicz M, Sherman A, Ertaylan G, Grosse-Wentrup M, Hothorn T, van Ligtenberg J, Macke J, Meyer T, Sch&#xf6;lkopf B, Tran L, Vaughan R, Stolovitzky G, Leitner M. Crowdsourced analysis of clinical trial data to predict amyotrophic lateral sclerosis progression. Nat Biotechnol. 2015;33(1):51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25362243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor A, Fournier C, Polak M, Wang L, Zach N, Keymer M, Glass J, Ennist D. The Pooled Resource Open-Access ALS Clinical Trials Consortium: Predicting disease progression in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Clin Transl Neurol. 2016;3(11):866&#x2013;875.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5099532</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27844032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ong M-L, Tan P, Holbrook J. Predicting functional decline and survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Public Library of Science (PloS) One. 2017;12(4):0174925.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5390993</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28406915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kueffner R, Zach N, Bronfeld M, Norel R, Atassi N, Balagurusamy V, Di Camillo B, Chi&#xf2; A, Cudkowicz M, Dillenberger D, Garcia-Garcia J, Hardiman O, Hoff B, Knight J, Leitner M, Li G, Mangravite L, Norman T, Wang L, The ALS Stratification Consortium. Xiao J, Fang W-C, Peng J, Yang C, Chang H-J, Stolovitzky G. Stratification of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients: a crowdsourcing approach. Scientific Reports. 2019;9(1):690.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6345935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30679616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardiman O, Al Chalabi A, Brayne C, Beghi E, van den Berg LH, Chio A, Martin S, Logroscino G, Rooney J. The changing picture of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: lessons from European registers.J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2017; 2016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28285264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grus J. Data Science from Scratch: First Principles with Python 2nd edn. Sebastopol, CA, USA: O&#x2019;Reilly Media; 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum J, Stambler N, Malta E, Fuller C, Hilt D, Thurmond B, Nakanishi A. The ALSFRS-R: a revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. J Neurol Sci. 1999;169(1):13&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10540002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer P. infotheo: Information-Theoretic Measures. R package version 1.2.0.https://cran.r-project.org/package=infotheo. Accessed 27 Apr 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beghi E, Chi&#xf2; A, Couratier P, Esteban J, Hardiman O, Logroscino G, Millul A, Mitchell D, Preux P-M, Pupillo E, Stevic Z, Swingler R, Traynor B, Van den Berg LH, Veldink J, Zoccolella S. The Eurals Consortium: The epidemiology and treatment of ALS: focus on the heterogeneity of the disease and critical appraisal of therapeutic trials. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2011;12(1):1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3513399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20698807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rutkove S. Clinical measures of disease progression in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurotherapeutics. 2015;12(2):384&#x2013;393.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4404434</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25582382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hand D, Yu K. Idiot&#x2019;s Bayes&#x2013;not so stupid after all? Int Stat Rev. 2001;69(3):385&#x2013;398.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer D, Dimitriadou E, Hornik K, Weingessel A, Leisch F. Misc Functions of the Department of Statistics, Probability Theory Group (Formerly: E1071). TU Wien. R package version 1.7-2.:e1071. https://cran.r-project.org/package=e1071 Accessed 27 Apr 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H. The optimality of naive bayes. In: Barr V, Markov Z, editors. Proceedings of the Seventeenth International Florida Artificial Intelligence Research Society Conference (FLAIRS 2004) Miami Beach, Florida, USA: AAAI Press; 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilcoxon F. Individual comparisons by ranking methods. Biometrics Bulletin. 1945;1(6):80&#x2013;83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNemar Q. Note on the sampling error of the difference between correlated proportions or percentages. Psychometrika. 1947;12(2):153&#x2013;157.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20254758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>