<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">32811540</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>19</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2047-9158</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>9</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>19</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Translational neurodegeneration</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Transl Neurodegener</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Does wild-type Cu/Zn-superoxide dismutase have pathogenic roles in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis?</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>33</StartPage><MedlinePgn>33</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">33</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s40035-020-00209-y</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) is characterized by adult-onset progressive degeneration of upper and lower motor neurons. Increasing numbers of genes are found to be associated with ALS; among those, the first identified gene, SOD1 coding a Cu/Zn-superoxide dismutase protein (SOD1), has been regarded as the gold standard in the research on a pathomechanism of ALS. Abnormal accumulation of misfolded SOD1 in affected spinal motor neurons has been established as a pathological hallmark of ALS caused by mutations in SOD1 (SOD1-ALS). Nonetheless, involvement of wild-type SOD1 remains quite controversial in the pathology of ALS with no SOD1 mutations (non-SOD1 ALS), which occupies more than 90% of total ALS cases. In vitro studies have revealed post-translationally controlled misfolding and aggregation of wild-type as well as of mutant SOD1 proteins; therefore, SOD1 proteins could be a therapeutic target not only in SOD1-ALS but also in more prevailing cases, non-SOD1 ALS. In order to search for evidence on misfolding and aggregation of wild-type SOD1 in vivo, we reviewed pathological studies using mouse models and patients and then summarized arguments for and against possible involvement of wild-type SOD1 in non-SOD1 ALS as well as in SOD1-ALS.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Furukawa</LastName><ForeName>Yoshiaki</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1918-372X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, Laboratory for Mechanistic Chemistry of Biomolecules, Keio University, 3-14-1 Hiyoshi, Kohoku, Yokohama, Kanagawa, 223-8522, Japan. furukawa@chem.keio.ac.jp.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tokuda</LastName><ForeName>Eiichi</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, Laboratory for Mechanistic Chemistry of Biomolecules, Keio University, 3-14-1 Hiyoshi, Kohoku, Yokohama, Kanagawa, 223-8522, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Present address: Laboratory of Clinical Medicine, School of Pharmacy, Nihon University, 7-7-1 Narashinodai, Funabashi, Chiba, 274-8555, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>16H04768</GrantID><Agency>Japan Society for the Promotion of Science</Agency><Country>International</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>19H05765</GrantID><Agency>Japan Society for the Promotion of Science</Agency><Country>International</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>Not applicable</GrantID><Agency>Pharmacological Research Foundation (JP)</Agency><Country>International</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Transl Neurodegener</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101591861</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2047-9158</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 1.15.1.1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000072105">Superoxide Dismutase-1</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000201" MajorTopicYN="Y">enzymology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="Y">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D045604" MajorTopicYN="N">Extracellular Fluid</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000201" MajorTopicYN="N">enzymology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009046" MajorTopicYN="N">Motor Neurons</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000201" MajorTopicYN="N">enzymology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017510" MajorTopicYN="Y">Protein Folding</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000072105" MajorTopicYN="N">Superoxide Dismutase-1</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cu/Zn-superoxide dismutase</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Protein misfolding</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32811540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7437001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40035-020-00209-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s40035-020-00209-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Andersen PM, Al-Chalabi A. Clinical genetics of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: what do we really know? Nat Rev Neurol. 2011;7:603&#x2013;615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21989245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaiswal MK. Riluzole and edaravone: a tale of two amyotrophic lateral sclerosis drugs. Med Res Rev. 2019;39:733&#x2013;748.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30101496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosen DR, Siddique T, Patterson D, Figlewicz DA, Sapp P, Hentati A, et al. Mutations in Cu/Zn superoxide dismutase gene are associated with familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nature. 1993;362:59&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8446170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robberecht W, Philips T. The changing scene of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat Rev Neurosci. 2013;14:248&#x2013;264.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23463272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruijn LI, Houseweart MK, Kato S, Anderson KL, Anderson SD, Ohama E, et al. Aggregation and motor neuron toxicity of an ALS-linked SOD1 mutant independent from wild-type SOD1. Science. 1998;281:1851&#x2013;1854.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9743498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trist B, Hilton JB, Crouch PJ, Hare DJ, Double KL. Superoxide dismutase 1 in health and disease: How a front-line antioxidant becomes neurotoxic. Angew Chem Int Ed Engl. 2020;in press.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32144830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCord JM, Fridovich I. Superoxide dismutase. An enzymic function for erythrocuprein (hemocuprein) J Biol Chem. 1969;244:6049&#x2013;6055.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5389100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saccon RA, Bunton-Stasyshyn RK, Fisher EM, Fratta P. Is SOD1 loss of function involved in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis? Brain. 2013;136:2342&#x2013;2358.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3722346</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23687121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen PM, Nordstrom U, Tsiakas K, Johannsen J, Volk AE, Bierhals T, et al. Phenotype in an infant with SOD1 homozygous truncating mutation. N Engl J Med. 2019;381:486&#x2013;488.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31314961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park JH, Elpers C, Reunert J, McCormick ML, Mohr J, Biskup S, et al. SOD1 deficiency: a novel syndrome distinct from amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain. 2019;142:2230&#x2013;2237.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6658856</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31332433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner BJ, Talbot K. Transgenics, toxicity and therapeutics in rodent models of mutant SOD1-mediated familial ALS. Prog Neurobiol. 2008;85:94&#x2013;134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18282652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furukawa Y, O'Halloran TV. Posttranslational modifications in Cu,Zn-superoxide dismutase and mutations associated with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Antioxid Redox Signal. 2006;8:847&#x2013;867.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1633719</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16771675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forman HJ, Fridovich I. On the stability of bovine superoxide dismutase. The effects of metals. J Biol Chem. 1973;248:2645&#x2013;2649.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4697386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furukawa Y, O'Halloran TV. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis mutations have the greatest destabilizing effect on the apo, reduced form of SOD1, leading to unfolding and oxidative aggregation. J Biol Chem. 2005;280:17266&#x2013;17274.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15691826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stathopulos PB, Rumfeldt JA, Scholz GA, Irani RA, Frey HE, Hallewell RA, et al. Cu/Zn superoxide dismutase mutants associated with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis show enhanced formation of aggregates in vitro. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2003;100:7021&#x2013;7026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC165823</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12773627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayward LJ, Rodriguez JA, Kim JW, Tiwari A, Goto JJ, Cabelli DE, et al. Decreased metallation and activity in subsets of mutant superoxide dismutases associated with familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Biol Chem. 2002;277:15923&#x2013;15931.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11854284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tiwari A, Hayward LJ. Familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis mutants of copper/zinc superoxide dismutase are susceptible to disulfide reduction. J Biol Chem. 2003;278:5984&#x2013;5992.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12458194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hilton JB, Mercer SW, Lim NK, Faux NG, Buncic G, Beckman JS, et al. CuII (atsm) improves the neurological phenotype and survival of SOD1G93A mice and selectively increases enzymatically active SOD1 in the spinal cord. Sci Rep. 2017;7:42292.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5304223</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28205575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts BR, Lim NK, McAllum EJ, Donnelly PS, Hare DJ, Doble PA, et al. Oral treatment with Cu(II)(atsm) increases mutant SOD1 in vivo but protects motor neurons and improves the phenotype of a transgenic mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurosci. 2014;34:8021&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6608261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24899723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soon CP, Donnelly PS, Turner BJ, Hung LW, Crouch PJ, Sherratt NA, et al. Diacetylbis(N(4)-methylthiosemicarbazonato) copper (II) (CuII (atsm)) protects against peroxynitrite-induced nitrosative damage and prolongs survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis mouse model. J Biol Chem. 2011;286:44035&#x2013;44044.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3243559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22033929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Culotta VC, Klomp LWJ, Strain J, Casareno RLB, Krems B, Gitlin JD. The copper chaperone for superoxide dismutase. J Biol Chem. 1997;272:23469&#x2013;23472.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9295278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong PC, Waggoner D, Subramaniam JR, Tessarollo L, Bartnikas TB, Culotta VC, et al. Copper chaperone for superoxide dismutase is essential to activate mammalian Cu/Zn superoxide dismutase. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2000;97:2886&#x2013;2891.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC16025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10694572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams JR, Trias E, Beilby PR, Lopez NI, Labut EM, Bradford CS, et al. Copper delivery to the CNS by CuATSM effectively treats motor neuron disease in SOD(G93A) mice co-expressing the copper-chaperone-for-SOD. Neurobiol Dis. 2016;89:1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4785045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26826269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Son M, Fu Q, Puttaparthi K, Matthews CM, Elliott JL. Redox susceptibility of SOD1 mutants is associated with the differential response to CCS over-expression in vivo. Neurobiol Dis. 2009;34:155&#x2013;162.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2835407</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19320055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Son M, Puttaparthi K, Kawamata H, Rajendran B, Boyer PJ, Manfredi G, et al. Overexpression of CCS in G93A-SOD1 mice leads to accelerated neurological deficits with severe mitochondrial pathology. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2007;104:6072&#x2013;6077.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1851618</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17389365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Son M, Srikanth U, Puttaparthi K, Luther C, Elliott JL. Biochemical properties and in vivo effects of the SOD1 zinc-binding site mutant (H80G) J Neurochem. 2011;118:891&#x2013;901.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3155629</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21692800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furukawa Y, Anzai I, Akiyama S, Imai M, Cruz FJ, Saio T, et al. Conformational disorder of the most immature Cu,Zn-superoxide dismutase leading to amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Biol Chem. 2016;291:4144&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4759189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26694608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furukawa Y. Protein aggregates in pathological inclusions of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. In: Maurer MH. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. InTech; 2012. p. 335&#x2013;356.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng HX, Shi Y, Furukawa Y, Zhai H, Fu R, Liu E, et al. Conversion to the amyotrophic lateral sclerosis phenotype is associated with intermolecular linked insoluble aggregates of SOD1 in mitochondria. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2006;103:7142&#x2013;7147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1447523</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16636275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fukada K, Nagano S, Satoh M, Tohyama C, Nakanishi T, Shimizu A, et al. Stabilization of mutant cu/Zn superoxide dismutase (SOD1) protein by coexpressed wild SOD1 protein accelerates the disease progression in familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis mice. Eur J Neurosci. 2001;14:2032&#x2013;2036.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11860498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furukawa Y, Fu R, Deng HX, Siddique T, O'Halloran TV. Disulfide cross-linked protein represents a significant fraction of ALS-associated Cu,Zn-superoxide dismutase aggregates in spinal cords of model mice. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2006;103:7148&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1447524</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16636274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaarsma D, Haasdijk ED, Grashorn JA, Hawkins R, van Duijn W, Verspaget HW, et al. Human Cu/Zn superoxide dismutase (SOD1) overexpression in mice causes mitochondrial vacuolization, axonal degeneration, and premature motoneuron death and accelerates motoneuron disease in mice expressing a familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis mutant SOD1. Neurobiol Dis. 2000;7:623&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11114261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prudencio M, Durazo A, Whitelegge JP, Borchelt DR. An examination of wild-type SOD1 in modulating the toxicity and aggregation of ALS-associated mutant SOD1. Hum Mol Genet. 2010;19:4774&#x2013;4789.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2989888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20871097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L, Deng HX, Grisotti G, Zhai H, Siddique T, Roos RP. Wild-type SOD1 overexpression accelerates disease onset of a G85R SOD1 mouse. Hum Mol Genet. 2009;18:1642&#x2013;1651.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2667291</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19233858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prudencio M, Lelie H, Brown HH, Whitelegge JP, Valentine JS, Borchelt DR. A novel variant of human superoxide dismutase 1 harboring amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-associated and experimental mutations in metal-binding residues and free cysteines lacks toxicity in vivo. J Neurochem. 2012;121:475&#x2013;485.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3705958</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22332887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brasil AA, de Carvalho MDC, Gerhardt E, Queiroz DD, Pereira MD, Outeiro TF, et al. Characterization of the activity, aggregation, and toxicity of heterodimers of WT and ALS-associated mutant Sod1. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2019;116:25991&#x2013;26000.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6926019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31796595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi Y, Acerson MJ, Abdolvahabi A, Mowery RA, Shaw BF. Gibbs energy of superoxide dismutase Heterodimerization accounts for variable survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Am Chem Soc. 2016;138:5351&#x2013;5362.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27054659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Audet JN, Gowing G, Julien JP. Wild-type human SOD1 overexpression does not accelerate motor neuron disease in mice expressing murine Sod1(G86R) Neurobiol Dis. 2010;40:245&#x2013;250.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20573565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gurney ME, Pu H, Chiu AY, Dal Canto MC, Polchow CY, Alexander DD, et al. Motor neuron degeneration in mice that express a human Cu,Zn superoxide dismutase mutation. Science. 1994;264:1772&#x2013;1775.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8209258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jonsson PA, Graffmo KS, Brannstrom T, Nilsson P, Andersen PM, Marklund SL. Motor neuron disease in mice expressing the wild type-like D90A mutant superoxide dismutase-1. J Neuropathol Exp Neurol. 2006;65:1126&#x2013;1136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17146286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Killoy KM, Harlan BA, Pehar M, Helke KL, Johnson JA, Vargas MR. Decreased glutathione levels cause overt motor neuron degeneration in hSOD1(WT) over-expressing mice. Exp Neurol. 2018;302:129&#x2013;135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5849514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29307609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Medinas DB, Rozas P, Martinez Traub F, Woehlbier U, Brown RH, Bosco DA, et al. Endoplasmic reticulum stress leads to accumulation of wild-type SOD1 aggregates associated with sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2018;115:8209&#x2013;8214.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6094144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30038021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graffmo KS, Forsberg K, Bergh J, Birve A, Zetterstrom P, Andersen PM, et al. Expression of wild-type human superoxide dismutase-1 in mice causes amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Hum Mol Genet. 2013;22:51&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23026746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jonsson PA, Bergemalm D, Andersen PM, Gredal O, Brannstrom T, Marklund SL. Inclusions of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-linked superoxide dismutase in ventral horns, liver, and kidney. Ann Neurol. 2008;63:671&#x2013;675.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18409196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jonsson PA, Ernhill K, Andersen PM, Bergemalm D, Brannstrom T, Gredal O, et al. Minute quantities of misfolded mutant superoxide dismutase-1 cause amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain. 2004;127:73&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14534160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forsberg K, Andersen PM, Marklund SL, Brannstrom T. Glial nuclear aggregates of superoxide dismutase-1 are regularly present in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathol. 2011;121:623&#x2013;634.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3085063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21287393</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jonsson PA, Graffmo KS, Andersen PM, Marklund SL, Brannstrom T. Superoxide dismutase in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients homozygous for the D90A mutation. Neurobiol Dis. 2009;36:421&#x2013;424.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19703565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujisawa T, Homma K, Yamaguchi N, Kadowaki H, Tsuburaya N, Naguro I, et al. A novel monoclonal antibody reveals a conformational alteration shared by amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-linked SOD1 mutants. Ann Neurol. 2012;72:739&#x2013;749.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23280792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowling AC, Schulz JB, Brown RH, Jr, Beal MF. Superoxide dismutase activity, oxidative damage, and mitochondrial energy metabolism in familial and sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurochem. 1993;61:2322&#x2013;2325.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8245985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forsberg K, Jonsson PA, Andersen PM, Bergemalm D, Graffmo KS, Hultdin M, et al. Novel antibodies reveal inclusions containing non-native SOD1 in sporadic ALS patients. PLoS One. 2010;5:e11552.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2904380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20644736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uhlen M, Fagerberg L, Hallstrom BM, Lindskog C, Oksvold P, Mardinoglu A, et al. Proteomics. Tissue-based map of the human proteome. Science. 2015;347:1260419.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25613900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thul PJ, Akesson L, Wiking M, Mahdessian D, Geladaki A, Ait Blal H, et al. A subcellular map of the human proteome. Science. 2017;356:eaal3321.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28495876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uhlen M, Zhang C, Lee S, Sjostedt E, Fagerberg L, Bidkhori G, et al. A pathology atlas of the human cancer transcriptome. Science. 2017;357:eaan2507.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28818916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zelko IN, Mariani TJ, Folz RJ. Superoxide dismutase multigene family: a comparison of the CuZn-SOD (SOD1), Mn-SOD (SOD2), and EC-SOD (SOD3) gene structures, evolution, and expression. Free Radic Biol Med. 2002;33:337&#x2013;349.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12126755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sturtz LA, Diekert K, Jensen LT, Lill R, Culotta VC. A fraction of yeast Cu,Zn-superoxide dismutase and its metallochaperone, CCS, localize to the intermembrane space of mitochondria - A physiological role for SOD1 in guarding against mitochondrial oxidative damage. J Biol Chem. 2001;276:38084&#x2013;38089.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11500508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsang CK, Liu Y, Thomas J, Zhang Y, Zheng XF. Superoxide dismutase 1 acts as a nuclear transcription factor to regulate oxidative stress resistance. Nat Commun. 2014;5:3446.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4678626</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24647101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mondola P, Ruggiero G, Seru R, Damiano S, Grimaldi S, Garbi C, et al. The Cu,Zn superoxide dismutase in neuroblastoma SK-N-BE cells is exported by a microvesicles dependent pathway. Brain Res Mol Brain Res. 2003;110:45&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12573532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jonsson PA, Graffmo KS, Andersen PM, Brannstrom T, Lindberg M, Oliveberg M, et al. Disulphide-reduced superoxide dismutase-1 in CNS of transgenic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis models. Brain. 2006;129:451&#x2013;464.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16330499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bosco DA, Morfini G, Karabacak NM, Song Y, Gros-Louis F, Pasinelli P, et al. Wild-type and mutant SOD1 share an aberrant conformation and a common pathogenic pathway in ALS. Nat Neurosci. 2010;13:1396&#x2013;1403.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2967729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20953194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Slunt H, Gonzales V, Fromholt D, Coonfield M, Copeland NG, et al. Copper-binding-site-null SOD1 causes ALS in transgenic mice: aggregates of non-native SOD1 delineate a common feature. Hum Mol Genet. 2003;12:2753&#x2013;2764.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12966034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grad LI, Yerbury JJ, Turner BJ, Guest WC, Pokrishevsky E, O'Neill MA, et al. Intercellular propagated misfolding of wild-type Cu/Zn superoxide dismutase occurs via exosome-dependent and -independent mechanisms. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2014;111:3620&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3948312</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24550511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsumoto S, Kusaka H, Ito H, Shibata N, Asayama T, Imai T. Sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with dementia and Cu/Zn superoxide dismutase-positive Lewy body-like inclusions. Clin Neuropathol. 1996;15:41&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8998856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shibata N, Asayama K, Hirano A, Kobayashi M. Immunohistochemical study on superoxide dismutases in spinal cords from autopsied patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Dev Neurosci. 1996;18:492&#x2013;498.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8940623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shibata N, Hirano A, Kobayashi M, Sasaki S, Kato T, Matsumoto S, et al. Cu/Zn superoxide dismutase-like immunoreactivity in Lewy body-like inclusions of sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurosci Lett. 1994;179:149&#x2013;152.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7845611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watanabe M, Dykes-Hoberg M, Culotta VC, Price DL, Wong PC, Rothstein JD. Histological evidence of protein aggregation in mutant SOD1 transgenic mice and in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis neural tissues. Neurobiol Dis. 2001;8:933&#x2013;941.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11741389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asayama K, Janco RL, Burr IM. Selective induction of manganous superoxide dismutase in human monocytes. Am J Phys. 1985;249:C393&#x2013;C397.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4061626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pardo CA, Xu Z, Borchelt DR, Price DL, Sisodia SS, Cleveland DW. Superoxide dismutase is an abundant component in cell bodies, dendrites, and axons of motor neurons and in a subset of other neurons. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 1995;92:954&#x2013;958.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC42615</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7862672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keller BA, Volkening K, Droppelmann CA, Ang LC, Rademakers R, Strong MJ. Co-aggregation of RNA binding proteins in ALS spinal motor neurons: evidence of a common pathogenic mechanism. Acta Neuropathol. 2012;124:733&#x2013;747.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22941224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pare B, Lehmann M, Beaudin M, Nordstrom U, Saikali S, Julien JP, et al. Misfolded SOD1 pathology in sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Sci Rep. 2018;8:14223.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6155098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30242181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rotunno MS, Bosco DA. An emerging role for misfolded wild-type SOD1 in sporadic ALS pathogenesis. Front Cell Neurosci. 2013;7:253.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3863749</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24379756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maier M, Welt T, Wirth F, Montrasio F, Preisig D, McAfoose J, et al. A human-derived antibody targets misfolded SOD1 and ameliorates motor symptoms in mouse models of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Sci Transl Med. 2018;10:eaah3924.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30518612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayers JI, Xu G, Pletnikova O, Troncoso JC, Hart PJ, Borchelt DR. Conformational specificity of the C4F6 SOD1 antibody; low frequency of reactivity in sporadic ALS cases. Acta Neuropathol Commun. 2014;2:55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4035506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24887207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forsberg K, Graffmo K, Pakkenberg B, Weber M, Nielsen M, Marklund S, et al. Misfolded SOD1 inclusions in patients with mutations in C9orf72 and other ALS/FTD-associated genes. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2019;90:861&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6691870</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30992335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brotherton TE, Li Y, Cooper D, Gearing M, Julien JP, Rothstein JD, et al. Localization of a toxic form of superoxide dismutase 1 protein to pathologically affected tissues in familial ALS. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2012;109:5505&#x2013;5510.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3325721</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22431618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pokrishevsky E, Grad LI, Yousefi M, Wang J, Mackenzie IR, Cashman NR. Aberrant localization of FUS and TDP43 is associated with misfolding of SOD1 in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. PLoS One. 2012;7:e35050.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3320864</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22493728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerman A, Liu HN, Croul S, Bilbao J, Rogaeva E, Zinman L, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis is a non-amyloid disease in which extensive misfolding of SOD1 is unique to the familial form. Acta Neuropathol. 2010;119:335&#x2013;344.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20111867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Da Cruz S, Bui A, Saberi S, Lee SK, Stauffer J, McAlonis-Downes M, et al. Misfolded SOD1 is not a primary component of sporadic ALS. Acta Neuropathol. 2017;134:97&#x2013;111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5472502</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28247063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu HN, Sanelli T, Horne P, Pioro EP, Strong MJ, Rogaeva E, et al. Lack of evidence of monomer/misfolded superoxide dismutase-1 in sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol. 2009;66:75&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19670443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabado J, Casanovas A, Hernandez S, Piedrafita L, Hereu M, Esquerda JE. Immunodetection of disease-associated conformers of mutant cu/zn superoxide dismutase 1 selectively expressed in degenerating neurons in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neuropathol Exp Neurol. 2013;72:646&#x2013;661.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23771221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cruz-Garcia D, Brouwers N, Duran JM, Mora G, Curwin AJ, Malhotra V. A diacidic motif determines unconventional secretion of wild-type and ALS-linked mutant SOD1. J Cell Biol. 2017;216:2691&#x2013;2700.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5584182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28794127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mondola P, Damiano S, Sasso A, Santillo M. The Cu, Zn superoxide dismutase: not only a dismutase enzyme. Front Physiol. 2016;7:594.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5126113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27965593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayers JI, Diamond J, Sari A, Fromholt S, Galaleldeen A, Ostrow LW, et al. Distinct conformers of transmissible misfolded SOD1 distinguish human SOD1-FALS from other forms of familial and sporadic ALS. Acta Neuropathol. 2016;132:827&#x2013;840.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5107152</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27704280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekhtiari Bidhendi E, Bergh J, Zetterstrom P, Forsberg K, Pakkenberg B, Andersen PM, et al. Mutant superoxide dismutase aggregates from human spinal cord transmit amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathol. 2018;136:939&#x2013;953.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6280858</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30284034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grad LI, Guest WC, Yanai A, Pokrishevsky E, O'Neill MA, Gibbs E, et al. Intermolecular transmission of superoxide dismutase 1 misfolding in living cells. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2011;108:16398&#x2013;16403.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3182705</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21930926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polymenidou M, Cleveland DW. The seeds of neurodegeneration: prion-like spreading in ALS. Cell. 2011;147:498&#x2013;508.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3220614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22036560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soto C. Transmissible proteins: expanding the prion heresy. Cell. 2012;149:968&#x2013;977.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3367461</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22632966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iliff JJ, Wang M, Liao Y, Plogg BA, Peng W, Gundersen GA, et al. A paravascular pathway facilitates CSF flow through the brain parenchyma and the clearance of interstitial solutes, including amyloid beta. Sci Transl Med. 2012;4:147ra111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3551275</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22896675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carare RO, Bernardes-Silva M, Newman TA, Page AM, Nicoll JA, Perry VH, et al. Solutes, but not cells, drain from the brain parenchyma along basement membranes of capillaries and arteries: significance for cerebral amyloid angiopathy and neuroimmunology. Neuropathol Appl Neurobiol. 2008;34:131&#x2013;144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18208483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng W, Achariyar TM, Li B, Liao Y, Mestre H, Hitomi E, et al. Suppression of glymphatic fluid transport in a mouse model of Alzheimer's disease. Neurobiol Dis. 2016;93:215&#x2013;225.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4980916</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27234656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watanabe-Matsumoto S, Moriwaki Y, Okuda T, Ohara S, Yamanaka K, Abe Y, et al. Dissociation of blood-brain barrier disruption and disease manifestation in an aquaporin-4-deficient mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurosci Res. 2018;133:48&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29154923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Da Mesquita S, Louveau A, Vaccari A, Smirnov I, Cornelison RC, Kingsmore KM, et al. Functional aspects of meningeal lymphatics in ageing and Alzheimer's disease. Nature. 2018;560:185&#x2013;191.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6085146</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30046111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frutiger K, Lukas TJ, Gorrie G, Ajroud-Driss S, Siddique T. Gender difference in levels of cu/Zn superoxide dismutase (SOD1) in cerebrospinal fluid of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2008;9:184&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18574763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobsson J, Jonsson PA, Andersen PM, Forsgren L, Marklund SL. Superoxide dismutase in CSF from amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients with and without CuZn-superoxide dismutase mutations. Brain. 2001;124:1461&#x2013;1466.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11408340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zetterstrom P, Andersen PM, Brannstrom T, Marklund SL. Misfolded superoxide dismutase-1 in CSF from amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. J Neurochem. 2011;117:91&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21226712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tokuda E, Takei Y, Ohara S, Fujiwara N, Hozumi I, Furukawa Y. Wild-type Cu/Zn-superoxide dismutase is misfolded in cerebrospinal fluid of sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Mol Neurodegener. 2019;14:42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6862823</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31744522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshida E, Mokuno K, Aoki S, Takahashi A, Riku S, Murayama T, et al. Cerebrospinal fluid levels of superoxide dismutases in neurological diseases detected by sensitive enzyme immunoassays. J Neurol Sci. 1994;124:25&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7931417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winer L, Srinivasan D, Chun S, Lacomis D, Jaffa M, Fagan A, et al. SOD1 in cerebral spinal fluid as a pharmacodynamic marker for antisense oligonucleotide therapy. JAMA Neurol. 2013;70:201&#x2013;207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3812918</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23147550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crisp MJ, Mawuenyega KG, Patterson BW, Reddy NC, Chott R, Self WK, et al. In vivo kinetic approach reveals slow SOD1 turnover in the CNS. J Clin Invest. 2015;125:2772&#x2013;2780.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4563686</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26075819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vijayalakshmi K, Alladi PA, Sathyaprabha TN, Subramaniam JR, Nalini A, Raju TR. Cerebrospinal fluid from sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients induces degeneration of a cultured motor neuron cell line. Brain Res. 2009;1263:122&#x2013;133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19368830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lange DJ, Shahbazi M, Silani V, Ludolph AC, Weishaupt JH, Ajroud-Driss S, et al. Pyrimethamine significantly lowers cerebrospinal fluid Cu/Zn superoxide dismutase in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients with SOD1 mutations. Ann Neurol. 2017;81:837&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5518287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28480639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barber SC, Shaw PJ. Oxidative stress in ALS: key role in motor neuron injury and therapeutic target. Free Radic Biol Med. 2010;48:629&#x2013;641.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19969067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tokuda E, Anzai I, Nomura T, Toichi K, Watanabe M, Ohara S, et al. Immunochemical characterization on pathological oligomers of mutant Cu/Zn-superoxide dismutase in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Mol Neurodegener. 2017;12:2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5216565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28057013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu WC, Liang JZ, Li C, He ZX, Yuan HY, Huang BY, et al. Pathological hydrogen peroxide triggers the fibrillization of wild-type SOD1 via sulfenic acid modification of Cys-111. Cell Death Dis. 2018;9:67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5833406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29358575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anzai I, Tokuda E, Handa S, Misawa H, Akiyama S, Furukawa Y. Oxidative misfolding of Cu/Zn-superoxide dismutase triggered by non-canonical intramolecular disulfide formation. Free Radic Biol Med. 2020;147:187&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31863908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guareschi S, Cova E, Cereda C, Ceroni M, Donetti E, Bosco DA, et al. An over-oxidized form of superoxide dismutase found in sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with bulbar onset shares a toxic mechanism with mutant SOD1. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2012;109:5074&#x2013;5079.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3324021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22416121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor DM, Gibbs BF, Kabashi E, Minotti S, Durham HD, Agar JN. Tryptophan 32 potentiates aggregation and cytotoxicity of a copper/zinc superoxide dismutase mutant associated with familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Biol Chem. 2007;282:16329&#x2013;16335.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17389599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coelho FR, Iqbal A, Linares E, Silva DF, Lima FS, Cuccovia IM, et al. Oxidation of the tryptophan 32 residue of human superoxide dismutase 1 caused by its bicarbonate-dependent peroxidase activity triggers the non-amyloid aggregation of the enzyme. J Biol Chem. 2014;289:30690&#x2013;30701.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4215247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25237191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mulligan VK, Kerman A, Laister RC, Sharda PR, Arslan PE, Chakrabartty A. Early steps in oxidation-induced SOD1 misfolding: implications for non-amyloid protein aggregation in familial ALS. J Mol Biol. 2012;421:631&#x2013;652.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22542526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rakhit R, Cunningham P, Furtos-Matei A, Dahan S, Qi XF, Crow JP, et al. Oxidation-induced misfolding and aggregation of superoxide dismutase and its implications for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Biol Chem. 2002;277:47551&#x2013;47556.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12356748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H, Andrekopoulos C, Joseph J, Chandran K, Karoui H, Crow JP, et al. Bicarbonate-dependent peroxidase activity of human Cu,Zn-superoxide dismutase induces covalent aggregation of protein: intermediacy of tryptophan-derived oxidation products. J Biol Chem. 2003;278:24078&#x2013;24089.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12686560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takeuchi S, Fujiwara N, Ido A, Oono M, Takeuchi Y, Tateno M, et al. Induction of protective immunity by vaccination with wild-type apo superoxide dismutase 1 in mutant SOD1 transgenic mice. J Neuropathol Exp Neurol. 2010;69:1044&#x2013;1056.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20838241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Urushitani M, Ezzi SA, Julien JP. Therapeutic effects of immunization with mutant superoxide dismutase in mice models of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2007;104:2495&#x2013;2500.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1790867</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17277077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu HN, Tjostheim S, Dasilva K, Taylor D, Zhao B, Rakhit R, et al. Targeting of monomer/misfolded SOD1 as a therapeutic strategy for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurosci. 2012;32:8791&#x2013;8799.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6622344</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22745481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao B, Marciniuk K, Gibbs E, Yousefi M, Napper S, Cashman NR. Therapeutic vaccines for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis directed against disease specific epitopes of superoxide dismutase 1. Vaccine. 2019;37:4920&#x2013;4927.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31324499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong QX, Zhu J, Liu SY, Yu XL, Liu RT. An oligomer-specific antibody improved motor function and attenuated neuropathology in the SOD1-G93A transgenic mouse model of ALS. Int Immunopharmacol. 2018;65:413&#x2013;421.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30388515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghadge GD, Kay BK, Drigotas C, Roos RP. Single chain variable fragment antibodies directed against SOD1 ameliorate disease in mutant SOD1 transgenic mice. Neurobiol Dis. 2019;121:131&#x2013;137.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30176351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gros-Louis F, Soucy G, Lariviere R, Julien JP. Intracerebroventricular infusion of monoclonal antibody or its derived fab fragment against misfolded forms of SOD1 mutant delays mortality in a mouse model of ALS. J Neurochem. 2010;113:1188&#x2013;1199.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20345765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Broering TJ, Wang H, Boatright NK, Wang Y, Baptista K, Shayan G, et al. Identification of human monoclonal antibodies specific for human SOD1 recognizing distinct epitopes and forms of SOD1. PLoS One. 2013;8:e61210.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3629177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23613814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Blitterswijk M, Gulati S, Smoot E, Jaffa M, Maher N, Hyman BT, et al. Anti-superoxide dismutase antibodies are associated with survival in patients with sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. 2011;12:430&#x2013;438.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3446817</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22023190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>