<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">32833751</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>07</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1473-6551</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>33</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Current opinion in neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Curr Opin Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Cognitive and behavioural impairment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>649</StartPage><EndPage>654</EndPage><MedlinePgn>649-654</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/WCO.0000000000000862</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE OF REVIEW">The current review provides an up to date overview of the nature and progression of the cognitive and behavioural impairment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). Understanding these symptoms has implications for the management of the disease and the design of clinical trials, in addition to the support of patient and caregiver regarding mental capacity and end of life decision-making.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RECENT FINDINGS">Cognitive and behavioural change in ALS are best characterized as the consequence of extensive network dysfunction. 35-45% of ALS patients present with mild-moderate cognitive impairment and comorbid dementia occurs in approximately 14% of patients, the majority of these meeting diagnostic criteria for frontotemporal dementia (FTD). Cognitive change in ALS manifests most commonly as executive dysfunction and language impairment. Behavioural change in the form of apathy, disinhibition, loss of sympathy and empathy, stereotyped behaviours and dietary changes occur.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUMMARY">Cognitive and behavioural impairment is an important feature of ALS, and reflects broad network dysfunction of frontostriatal and frontotemporal systems. Cognition and behaviour should be assessed early in the diagnostic process, and data driven approaches should be developed to enable reliable quantitative outcome assessment suitable for clinical trials.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pender</LastName><ForeName>Niall</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Academic Unit of Neurology, Trinity Biomedical Sciences Institute, Trinity College Dublin.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pinto-Grau</LastName><ForeName>Marta</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Academic Unit of Neurology, Trinity Biomedical Sciences Institute, Trinity College Dublin.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hardiman</LastName><ForeName>Orla</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Academic Unit of Neurology, Trinity Biomedical Sciences Institute, Trinity College Dublin.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Beaumont Hospital, Dublin, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013487">Research Support, U.S. Gov't, P.H.S.</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Curr Opin Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9319162</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1350-7540</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="Y">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057565" MajorTopicYN="N">Apathy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003071" MajorTopicYN="N">Cognition</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D060825" MajorTopicYN="N">Cognitive Dysfunction</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="Y">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018450" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Progression</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009483" MajorTopicYN="N">Neuropsychological Tests</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32833751</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/WCO.0000000000000862</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00019052-202010000-00016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Hardiman O, Al-Chalabi A, Chio A, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat Rev Dis Primers 2017; 3:17071.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strong MJ, Abrahams S, Goldstein LH, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis &#x2013; frontotemporal spectrum disorder (ALS-FTSD): revised diagnostic criteria. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2017; 18:153174.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Springer, Katz JS, Woolley SC. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Physician's field guide to neuropsychology. 2019; 255&#x2013;265.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ringholz GM, Appel SH, Bradshaw M, et al. Prevalence and patterns of cognitive impairment in sporadic ALS. Neurology 2005; 65:586590.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phukan J, Elamin M, Bede P, et al. The syndrome of cognitive impairment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a population-based study. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2012; 83:102108.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montuschi A, Iazzolino B, Calvo A, et al. Cognitive correlates in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a population-based study in Italy. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2015; 86:168173.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh SI, Park A, Kim HJ, et al. Spectrum of cognitive impairment in Korean ALS patients without known genetic mutations. PLoS One 2014; 9:e87163.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crockford CJ, Newton J, Lonergan K, et al. ALS-specific cognitive and behavior changes associated with advancing disease stage in ALS. Neurology 2018; 91:e1370e1380.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elamin M, Bede P, Byrne S, et al. Cognitive changes predict functional decline in ALS: a population-based longitudinal study. Neurology 2013; 80:15901597.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bersano E, Sarnelli MF, Solara V, et al. Decline of cognitive and behavioral functions in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a longitudinal study. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2020; 17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brettschneider J, Del Tredici K, Toledo JB, et al. Stages of pTDP-43 pathology in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol 2013; 74:2038.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldstein LH, Abrahams S. Changes in cognition and behaviour in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: nature of impairment and implications for assessment. Lancet Neurol 2013; 12:368380.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phukan J, Pender NP, Hardiman O. Cognitive impairment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet Neurol 2007; 6:9941003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor LJ, Brown RG, Tsermentseli S, et al. Is language impairment more common than executive dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis? J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2013; 84:494498.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ash S, Olm C, McMillan CT, et al. Deficits in sentence expression in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2015; 16:3139.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Consonni M, Catrical&#xe0; E, Dalla Bella E, et al. Beyond the consensus criteria: multiple cognitive profiles in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis? Cortex 2016; 81:162167.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinto-Grau M, Hardiman O, Pender N. The study of language in the amyotrophic lateral sclerosis &#x2013; frontotemporal spectrum disorder: a systematic review of findings and new perspectives. Neuropsychol Rev 2018; 28:251268.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abrahams S, Goldstein LH, Simmons A, et al. Word retrieval in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a functional magnetic resonance imaging study. Brain 2004; 127 (Pt 7):15071517.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lepow L, Van Sweringen J, Strutt AM, et al. Frontal and temporal lobe involvement on verbal fluency measures in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Clin Exp Neuropsychol 2010; 32:913922.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsermentseli S, Leigh PN, Taylor LJ, et al. Syntactic processing as a marker for cognitive impairment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2015; 17:6976.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamminga J, Leslie FV, Hsieh S, et al. Syntactic comprehension deficits across the FTD-ALS continuum. Neurobiol Aging 2016; 41:1118.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshizawa K, Yasuda N, Fukuda M, et al. Syntactic comprehension in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Behav Neurol 2014; 2014:230578.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Massman PJ, Sims J, Cooke N, et al. Prevalence and correlates of neuropsychological deficits in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 1996; 61:450455.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rakowicz WP, Hodges JR. Dementia and aphasia in motor neuron disease: an underrecognised association? J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 1998; 65:881889.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kew JJ, Goldstein LH, Leigh PN, et al. The relationship between abnormalities of cognitive function and cerebral activation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. A neuropsychological and positron emission tomography study. Brain 1993; 116 (Pt 6):13991423.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finegan E, Chipika RH, Li Hi Shing S, et al. Pathological crying and laughing in motor neuron disease: pathobiology, screening, intervention. Front Neurol 2019; 10:260.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke T, Pinto-Grau M, Lonergan K, et al. Measurement of social cognition in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a population based study. PLoS One 2016; 11:e0160850.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibbons ZC, Richardson A, Neary D, Snowden J. Behaviour in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis 2008; 9:6774.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grossman AB, Woolley-Levine S, Bradley WG, Miller RG. Detecting neurobehavioral changes in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis 2007; 8:5661.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lomen-Hoerth C, Murphy J, Langmore S, et al. Are amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients cognitively normal? Neurology 2003; 60:10941097.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehl T, Jordan B, Zierz S. &#x2018;Patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) are usually nice persons&#x2019; &#x2013; how physicians experienced in ALS see the personality characteristics of their patients. Brain Behav 2017; 7:e00599.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke T, Pinto-Grau M, Lonergan K, et al. A cross-sectional population-based investigation into behavioral change in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: subphenotypes, staging, cognitive predictors, and survival. Ann Clin Transl Neurol 2017; 4:305317.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elamin M, Phukan J, Bede P, et al. Executive dysfunction is a negative prognostic indicator in patients with ALS without dementia. Neurology 2011; 76:12631269.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsermentseli S, Leigh PN, Goldstein LH. The anatomy of cognitive impairment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: more than frontal lobe dysfunction. Cortex 2012; 48:166182.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kansal K, Mareddy M, Sloane KL, et al. Survival in frontotemporal dementia phenotypes: a meta-analysis. Dement Geriatr Cogn Disord 2016; 41:109122.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strong MJ, Grace GM, Freedman M, et al. Consensus criteria for the diagnosis of frontotemporal cognitive and behavioural syndromes in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler 2009; 10:131146.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Motor neurone disease: assessment and management. NICE guideline. 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abrahams S, Newton J, Niven E, et al. Screening for cognition and behaviour changes in ALS. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2014; 15:914.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niven E, Newton J, Foley J, et al. Validation of the Edinburgh Cognitive and Behavioural Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Screen (ECAS): a cognitive tool for motor disorders. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2015; 16:172179.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinto-Grau M, Burke T, Lonergan K, et al. Screening for cognitive dysfunction in ALS: validation of the Edinburgh Cognitive and Behavioural ALS Screen (ECAS) using age and education adjusted normative data. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2017; 18:99106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radakovic R, Stephenson L, Newton J, et al. Multidimensional apathy and executive dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Cortex 2017; 94:142151.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cummings JL, Mega M, Gray K, et al. The Neuropsychiatric Inventory: comprehensive assessment of psychopathology in dementia. Neurology 1994; 44:2308.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaufer DI, Cummings JL, Ketchel P, et al. Validation of the NPI-Q, a brief clinical form of the Neuropsychiatric Inventory. J Neuropsychiatry Clin Neurosci 2000; 12:233239.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kertesz A, Davidson W, McCabe P, Munoz D. Behavioral quantitation is more sensitive than cognitive testing in frontotemporal dementia. Alzheimer Dis Assoc Disord 2003; 17:223229.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elamin M, Pinto-Grau M, Burke T, et al. Identifying behavioural changes in ALS: validation of the Beaumont Behavioural Inventory (BBI). Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2017; 18:6873.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinto-Grau M, Costello E, O&#x2019;Connor S, et al. Assessing behavioural changes in ALS: cross-validation of ALS-specific measures. J Neurol 2017; 264:13971401.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khin EK, Minor D, Holloway A, Pelleg A. Decisional capacity in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Am Acad Psychiatry Law 2015; 43:210217.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke T, Hardiman O, Pinto-Grau M, et al. Longitudinal predictors of caregiver burden in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a population-based cohort of patient&#x2013;caregiver dyads. J Neurol 2018; 265:793808.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meier JM, van der Burgh HK, Nitert AD, et al. Connectome-based propagation model in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol 2020; 87:725738.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hallett M, de Haan W, Deco G, et al. Human brain connectivity: clinical applications for clinical neurophysiology. Clin Neurophysiol 2020; 131:16211651.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMackin R, Muthuraman M, Groppa S, et al. Measuring network disruption in neurodegenerative diseases: new approaches using signal analysis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatr 2019; 90:10111020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMackin R, Dukic S, Costello E, et al. Localization of brain networks engaged by the sustained attention to response task provides quantitative markers of executive impairment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Cereb Cortex 2020; 30:48344846.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMackin R, Dukic S, Broderick M, et al. Dysfunction of attention switching networks in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuroimage Clin 2019; 22:101707.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>