<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">32868602</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1473-6551</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>33</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Current opinion in neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Curr Opin Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: update on clinical management.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>641</StartPage><EndPage>648</EndPage><MedlinePgn>641-648</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/WCO.0000000000000864</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE OF REVIEW">The current review will provide recent updates in the clinical management of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RECENT FINDINGS">Although there is no cure for ALS, there are new treatments, growing knowledge of genetics, development of clinical staging systems, and the recent coronavirus disease 2019 pandemic that have recently impacted the clinical management of ALS. Increased understanding of genetics has helped provide insights into pathophysiology, the staging systems and clinical measures help to provide tools for monitoring disease clinically, and the recent coronavirus disease 2019 pandemic has provided opportunities to develop telemedicine and remote monitoring of disease thereby increasing accessibility to care and reducing burden of travel to centers for people living with the disease and their caregivers.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUMMARY">ALS is a progressive neurodegenerative disease that causes degeneration of the motor neurons which leads to paralysis and respiratory failure. Despite the lack of a cure, multidisciplinary care, proactive respiratory management, nutritional care and management of symptoms as well as pharmacological interventions that can improve quality of life and survival.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Norris</LastName><ForeName>Simone P</ForeName><Initials>SP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Eleanor and Lou Gehrig ALS Center, Columbia University Irving Medical Center, The Neurological Institute, New York, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Likanje</LastName><ForeName>Marie-France N</ForeName><Initials>MN</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Andrews</LastName><ForeName>Jinsy A</ForeName><Initials>JA</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Curr Opin Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9319162</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1350-7540</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="Y">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018352" MajorTopicYN="N">Coronavirus Infections</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058873" MajorTopicYN="N">Pandemics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011024" MajorTopicYN="N">Pneumonia, Viral</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017216" MajorTopicYN="Y">Telemedicine</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32868602</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/WCO.0000000000000864</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00019052-202010000-00015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Hardiman O, Al-Chalabi A, Chio A, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat Rev Dis Primers 2017; 3:17085.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown RH, Al-Chalabi A. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. N Engl J Med 2017; 377:162172.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Es MA, Hardiman O, Chio A, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet 2017; 390:20842098.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robberecht W, Philips T. The changing scene of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat Rev Neurosci 2013; 14:248264.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2; A, Logroscino G, Traynor BJ, et al. Global epidemiology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a systematic review of the published literature. Neuroepidemiology 2013; 41:118130.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnston CA, Stanton BR, Turner MR, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in an urban setting: a population based study of inner city London. J Neurol 2006; 253:16421643.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Philips T, Rothstein JD. Glial cells in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Exp Neurol 2014; 262 (Pt B):111120.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang SH, Li Y, Fukaya M, et al. Degeneration and impaired regeneration of gray matter oligodendrocytes in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat Neurosci 2013; 16:571579.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neumann M, Sampathu DM, Kwong LK, et al. Ubiquitinated TDP-43 in frontotemporal lobar degeneration and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Science 2006; 314:130133.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng HX, Chen W, Hong ST, et al. Mutations in UBQLN2 cause dominant X-linked juvenile and adult-onset ALS and ALS/dementia. Nature 2011; 477:211215.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bosco DA, Morfini G, Karabacak NM, et al. Wild-type and mutant SOD1 share an aberrant conformation and a common pathogenic pathway in ALS. Nat Neurosci 2010; 13:13961403.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner MR, Hardiman O, Benatar M, et al. Controversies and priorities in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet Neurol 2013; 12:310322.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masrori P, Van Damme P. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a clinical review. Eur J Neurol 2020; 0:112.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrews J. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: clinical management and research update. Curr Neurol Neurosci Rep 2009; 9:5968.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pringle CE, Hudson AJ, Munoz DG, et al. Primary lateral sclerosis: clinical features, neuropathology and diagnostic criteria. Brain 1992; 115:495552.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner MR, Talbot K. Primary lateral sclerosis: diagnosis and management. Pract Neurol 2020; 20:262269.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liewluck T, Sapertein DS. Progressive muscular atrophy. Neurol Clin 2015; 33:761773.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang H, Liu M, Li X, et al. Neurophysiological differences between flail arm syndrome and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. PLoS One 2015; 10:e0127601.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xe4;umer D, Butterworth R, Menke RA, et al. Progressive hemiparesis (Mills syndrome) with aphasia in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology 2014; 82:457458.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, Miller RG, Swash M, Munsat TL. Diseases World Federation of Neurology Research Group on Motor Neuron El Escorial revisited: revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord 2000; 1:293299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Dengler R, Eisen A, et al. Electrodiagnostic criteria for diagnosis of ALS. Clin Neurophysiol 2008; 119:497503.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnsen B, Pugdahl K, Fuglsang-Frederiksen A, et al. Diagnostic criteria for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a multicentre study of inter-rater variation and sensitivity. Clin Neurophysiol 2009; 130:307314.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shefner JM, Al-Chalabi A, Baker MR, et al. A proposal for new diagnostic criteria for ALS. Clin Neurophysiol 2020; 131:19751978.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Blitterswijk M, van Es MA, Hennekam EA, et al. Evidence of oligogenic basis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Hum Mol Genet 2012; 21:37763784.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kenna KP, McLaughline RL, Byrne S, et al. Delineating the genetic heterogeneity of ALS using targeted high-throughput sequencing. J Med Genet 2013; 50:776783.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosen DR, Siddique T, Patterson D, et al. Mutations in Cu/Zn superoxide dismutase gene are associated with familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nature 1993; 362:5962.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dejesus-Hernandez M, Mackenzie IR, Boeve BF, et al. Expanded GGGGCC hexanucleotide repeat in noncoding region of C9ORF72 causes chromosome 9p-linked FTD and ALS. Neuron 2011; 72:245256.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zou ZY, Zhou ZR, Che CH, et al. Genetic epidemiology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Neurol Neurosurg Pscyhiatry 2017; 88:540549.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Es MA, Veldink JH, Saris CG, et al. Genome wide association study identified 19p13.3 (UNC13A) and 9p21.2 as susceptibility loci for sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat Genet 2009; 41:10831087.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elden AC, Kim HJ, Hart MP, et al. Ataxin-2 intermediate length polyglutamine expansions are associated with increased risk for ALS. Nature 2010; 466:10691075.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Damme P, Veldink JH, van Blitterswijk M, et al. Expanded ATXN2 CAG repeat size in ALS identifies overlap between ALS and SCA2. Neurology 2011; 76:20662072.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vajda A, McLaughlin RL, Haverin M, et al. Genetic testing in ALS: a survey of current practices. Neurology 2017; 88:991999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chio A, Hammond ER, Mora G, et al. Development and evaluation of a clinical staging system for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2015; 86:3844.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roche JC, Rojas-Garcia R, Scott KM, et al. A proposed staging system for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain 2012; 135:847852.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum JM, Stambler N, Malta E, et al. The ALSFRS-R: a revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. BDNF ALS Study Group (Phase III). J Neurol Sci 1999; 169:1321.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang T, Al Khleifat A, Stahl DR, et al. Comparison of the King's and MiToS staging systems for ALS. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2017; 18:227232.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrews JA, Meng L, Kulke SF, et al. Association between decline in slow vital capacity and respiratory insufficiency, use of assisted ventilation, tracheostomy, or death in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. JAMA Neurol 2018; 75:5864.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diekstra FP, van Vught PW, van Rheenen W, et al. UNC13a is a modifier of survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurobiol Aging 2012; 33:630.e3630.e8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathis S, Couratier P, Julian A, et al. Management and therapeutic perspective in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Expert Rev Neurother 2016; 17:263276.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bensimon G, Lacomblez L, Meninger V. ALS/Riluzole Study Group. A controlled trial of riluzole in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. N Eng J Med 1994; 300:585659.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lacomblez L, Bensimon G, Leigh PN, et al. A confirmatory dose ranging study of riluzole in ALS. ALS/Riluzole Study Group-II. Neurology 1996; 47:242250.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrews JA, Jackson CE, Heiman-Patterson TD, et al. Real-world evidence of riluzole effectiveness in treating amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2020; 23:110.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Writing Group; Edaravone (MCI-186) ALS 19 Study Group. Safety and efficacy of edaravone in well defined patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Lancet Neurol 2017; 16:505512.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, Thisted RA, Appel SH, et al. Treatment of pseudobulbar affect in ALS with dextromethorphan/quinidine: a randomized trial. Neurology 2004; 63:13641370.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith R, Pioro E, Myers K, et al. Enhanced bulbar function in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: the Nuedexta treatment trial. Neurotherapeutics 2017; 14:762772.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lechtzin N, Cudkowicz ME, de Carvalho M, et al. Respiratory measures in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2018; 19:321330.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russo M, Bonanno C, Profazio C, et al. Which are the factors influencing NIV adaptation and tolerance in ALS? Neurol Sci 2020; Jul 24. doi: 10.1007/s10072-020-04624-x. [Epub ahead of print].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10072-020-04624-x.</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barone M, Viggiani MT, Introna A, et al. Nutritional prognostic factors for survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients undergone percutaneous endoscopic gastrostomy placement. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2019; 20:490496.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrews JA, Berry JD, Baloh RH, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis care and research in the United States during the COVID-19 pandemic: challenges and opportunities. Muscle Nerve 2020; 62:182186.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Connolly S, Galvin M, Hardiman O. End-of-life management in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet Neurol 2015; 14:435442.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maessen M, Veldink JH, Onwuteaka-Philipsen BD, et al. Trends and determinants of end-of-life practices in ALS in the Netherlands. Neurology 2009; 73:954961.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bascom PB, Tolle SW. Responding to requests for physician assisted suicide: &#x2018;These are uncharted waters for both of us&#x2026;&#x2019;. JAMA 2002; 288:9198.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>