<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">32868699</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1945-2810</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>52</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Journal of neuroscience nursing : journal of the American Association of Neuroscience Nurses</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Neurosci Nurs</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Information Needs and Preferences of Family Caregivers of Patients With Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>207</StartPage><EndPage>213</EndPage><MedlinePgn>207-213</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/JNN.0000000000000534</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The aim of this study was to explore the information needs and preferred sources of information of Korean family caregivers of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Family caregivers of patients with ALS (n = 108) completed a structured questionnaire to assess their information needs and preferred sources of information.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Most of the caregivers obtained health information from Internet searches (89.8%) and healthcare professionals (85.2%). The source rated most helpful was healthcare professionals, and that rated least helpful was broadcast media. Family caregivers who were younger than 50 years and well educated and caregivers of bulbar-onset ALS patients had higher scores of information needs.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Providing information through healthcare professionals and self-support groups could enhance family caregiver satisfaction. Family caregivers who are older and less educated need to be more empowered to be involved in information-based caring, and caregivers of patients with bulbar-onset ALS have substantial information needs.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chu</LastName><ForeName>Hyeon Sik</ForeName><Initials>HS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hyeon Sik Chu, MSN RN CNRN, is a Doctoral Student, School of Nursing, Hanyang University, Seoul, South Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oh</LastName><ForeName>Juyeon</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Neurosci Nurs</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8603596</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0888-0395</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000451" MajorTopicYN="Y">nursing</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017028" MajorTopicYN="N">Caregivers</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="Y">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006282" MajorTopicYN="N">Health Personnel</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="Y">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057226" MajorTopicYN="Y">Information Seeking Behavior</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020407" MajorTopicYN="N">Internet</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D056910" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Republic of Korea</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011795" MajorTopicYN="N">Surveys and Questionnaires</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32868699</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/JNN.0000000000000534</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">01376517-202010000-00003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Jaffa JL, Dufault M, Lavin M. An interprofessional approach to amyotrophic lateral sclerosis care. J Neurosci Nurs. 2017;49(5):318&#x2013;323.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rowland LP, Shneider NA. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. N Engl J Med. 2001;344(22):1688&#x2013;1700.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen PM, Abrahams S, Borasio GD, et al. EFNS guidelines on the clinical management of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (MALS)&#x2014;revised report of an EFNS task force. Eur J Neurol. 2012;19(3):360&#x2013;375.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chio A, Logroscino G, Hardiman O, et al. Prognostic factors in ALS: a critical review. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2009;10(5&#x2013;6):310&#x2013;323.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beeldman E, Raaphorst J, Klein Twennaar M, de Visser M, Schmand BA, de Haan RJ. The cognitive profile of ALS: a systematic review and meta-analysis update. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2016;87(6):611&#x2013;619.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bassola B, Sansone VA, Lusignani M. Being yourself and thinking about the future in people with motor neuron disease: a grounded theory of self-care processes. J Neurosci Nurs. 2018;50(3):138&#x2013;143.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peters M, Fitzpatrick R, Doll H, Playford ED, Jenkinson C. The impact of perceived lack of support provided by health and social care services to caregivers of people with motor neuron disease. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2012;13(2):223&#x2013;228.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galvin M, Carney S, Corr B, Mays I, Pender N, Hardiman O. Needs of informal caregivers across the caregiving course in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a qualitative analysis. BMJ Open. 2018;8(1):e018721.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galvin M, Gaffney R, Corr B, Mays I, Hardiman O. From first symptoms to diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: perspectives of an Irish informal caregiver cohort-a thematic analysis. BMJ Open. 2017;7(3):e014985.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh J, Kim JA. Information-seeking behavior and information needs in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: analyzing an online patient community. Comput Inform Nurs. 2017;35(7):345&#x2013;351.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh J, Kim JA. Supportive care needs of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis/motor neuron disease and their caregivers: a scoping review. J Clin Nurs. 2017;26(23&#x2013;24):4129&#x2013;4152.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chio A, Montuschi A, Cammarosano S, et al. ALS patients and caregivers communication preferences and information seeking behaviour. Eur J Neurol. 2008;15(1):55&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdulla S, Vielhaber S, Machts J, Heinze HJ, Dengler R, Petri S. Information needs and information-seeking preferences of ALS patients and their carers. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2014;15(7&#x2013;8):505&#x2013;512.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu L, Liu T, Liu L, et al. Global variation in prevalence and incidence of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Neurol. 2020;267(4):944&#x2013;953.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koenig KN, Steiner V, Pierce LL. Information needs of family caregivers of persons with cognitive versus physical deficits. Gerontol Geriatr Educ. 2011;32(4):396&#x2013;413.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan SS, Goonawardene N. Internet health information seeking and the patient-physician relationship: a systematic review. J Med Internet Res. 2017;19(1):e9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim H, Park KH, Koh SH, et al. Korean version of Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Functional Rating Scale-Revised: a pilot study on the reliability and validity. J Korean Neurol Assoc. 2007;25(2):149&#x2013;154.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The ALS Association. Living with ALS resource guides. Available at: http://www.alsa.org/als-care/resources. Accessed February 2, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. A power primer. Psychol Bull. 1992;112(1):155&#x2013;159.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cipolletta S, Gammino GR, Francescon P, Palmieri A. Mutual support groups for family caregivers of people with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in Italy: a pilot study. Health Soc Care Community. 2018;26(4):556&#x2013;563.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ushikubo M. Circumstances and signs of approaching death in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis undergoing noninvasive ventilation in home care settings. J Neurosci Nurs. 2018;50(3):182&#x2013;186.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pluye P, El Sherif R, Granikov V, et al. Health outcomes of online consumer health information: a systematic mixed studies review with framework synthesis. J Assoc Inf Sci Technol. 2019;70(7):643&#x2013;659.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zarei S, Carr K, Reiley L, et al. A comprehensive review of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Surg Neurol Int. 2015;6:171.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qureshi MM, Hayden D, Urbinelli L, et al. Analysis of factors that modify susceptibility and rate of progression in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2006;7(3):173&#x2013;182.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halbach SM, Ernstmann N, Kowalski C, et al. Unmet information needs and limited health literacy in newly diagnosed breast cancer patients over the course of cancer treatment. Patient Educ Couns. 2016;99(9):1511&#x2013;1518.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oberoi DV, White V, Jefford M, et al. Caregivers' information needs and their 'experiences of care' during treatment are associated with elevated anxiety and depression: a cross-sectional study of the caregivers of renal cancer survivors. Support Care Cancer. 2016;24(10):4177&#x2013;4186.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh J, Oh SI, Kim JA. The amyotrophic lateral sclerosis supportive care needs assessment instrument: development and psychometric evaluation. Palliat Support Care. 2018;16(6):692&#x2013;697.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim MS, Shin HI, Min Y, Kim JY, Kim JS. Correlation between severe ALS patient-caregiver couples' characteristics and caregivers' health related quality of life. J Korean Acad Nurs. 2011;41(3):354&#x2013;363.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>