<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">32871387</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>25</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2213-1582</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>28</Volume><PubDate><Year>2020</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>NeuroImage. Clinical</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Neuroimage Clin</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Involvement of the dentate nucleus in the pathophysiology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A multi-center and multi-modal neuroimaging study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>102385</StartPage><MedlinePgn>102385</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">102385</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.nicl.2020.102385</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S2213-1582(20)30222-9</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) is characterized primarily by motor neuron but also frontotemporal lobar degeneration. Although the cerebellum is involved in both motor and cognitive functions, little is known of its role in ALS. We targeted the dentate nucleus (DN) in the cerebellum and the associated white matter fibers tracts connecting the DN to the rest of the brain using multimodal imaging techniques to examine the cerebellar structural and functional connectivity patterns in ALS patients and hypothesized that the DN is implicated in the pathophysiology of ALS. A cohort of 127 participants (56 healthy subjects (HS); 71 ALS patients) were recruited across Canada through the Canadian ALS Neuroimaging Consortium (CALSNIC). Resting state functional MRI, diffusion tensor imaging (DTI), and 3D weighted T1 structural images were acquired on a 3-tesla scanner. The DN in the cerebellum was used as a seed to evaluate the whole brain cerebral resting-state functional connectivity (rsFC). The superior cerebellar peduncle (SCP), middle cerebellar peduncle (MCP) and inferior cerebellar peduncle (ICP) were used as a region of interest in DTI to evaluate the structural integrity of the DN with the cortex and brain stem. Cerebellar volumetric analysis was done to examine the lobular and DN grey matter (GM) changes in ALS patients. Lastly, an association between DN rsFC and structural alterations were explored. DN rsFC was reduced with cerebrum (supplementary motor area, precentral gyrus, frontal, posterior parietal, temporal), lobule IV, and brain stem, and increased with parieto-occipital region. DN rsFC and white matter (WM) diffusivity alterations at SCP, MCP, and ICP were accompanied by correlations with ALSFRS-R. There were no DN volumetric changes. Notably, DN rsFC correlated with WM abnormalities at superior cerebellar peduncle. The DN plays a pathophysiological role in ALS. Impaired rsFC is likely due to the observed cerebellar peduncular WM damage given the lack of GM atrophy of the DN. This study demonstrates altered cerebellar rsFC connectivity with motor and extra-motor regions in ALS, and impaired rsFC is likely due to the observed cerebellar peduncular WM damage given the lack of GM atrophy of the DN. The correlation between the altered DN connectivity, and the behavioral data support the hypothesis that the DN plays a pathophysiological role in ALS.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2020 The Authors. Published by Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bharti</LastName><ForeName>Komal</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Divison of Neurology, University of Alberta, Edmonton, Alberta, AB, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khan</LastName><ForeName>Muhammad</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Divison of Neurology, University of Alberta, Edmonton, Alberta, AB, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Beaulieu</LastName><ForeName>Christian</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Engineering, University of Alberta, Edmonton, Alberta, AB, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Graham</LastName><ForeName>Simon J</ForeName><Initials>SJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sunnybrook Health Sciences Centre, University of Toronto, Toronto, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Briemberg</LastName><ForeName>Hannah</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Divison of Neurology, University of British Columbia, Vancouver, BC, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Frayne</LastName><ForeName>Richard</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departments of Radiology and Clinical Neurosciences, Hotchkiss Brain Institute, University of Calgary, and Seaman Family MR Research Centre, Foothills Medical Centre, Calgary, Alberta, AB, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Genge</LastName><ForeName>Angela</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Montreal Neurological Institute and Hospital, McGill University, Montreal, Quebec, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Korngut</LastName><ForeName>Lawrence</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Neurosciences, Hotchkiss Brain Institute, University of Calgary, Foothills Medical Centre, Calgary, Alberta, AB, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zinman</LastName><ForeName>Lorne</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sunnybrook Health Sciences Centre, University of Toronto, Toronto, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kalra</LastName><ForeName>Sanjay</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Divison of Neurology, University of Alberta, Edmonton, Alberta, AB, Canada; Department of Biomedical Engineering, University of Alberta, Edmonton, Alberta, AB, Canada. Electronic address: kalra@ualberta.ca.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><CollectiveName>Canadian ALS Neuroimaging Consortium</CollectiveName></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>CIHR</Agency><Country>Canada</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Neuroimage Clin</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101597070</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2213-1582</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002170" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Canada</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002529" MajorTopicYN="N">Cerebellar Nuclei</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D056324" MajorTopicYN="Y">Diffusion Tensor Imaging</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008279" MajorTopicYN="N">Magnetic Resonance Imaging</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D059906" MajorTopicYN="N">Neuroimaging</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dentate nucleus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Diffusion tensor imaging</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Resting-state functional connectivity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Resting-state functional magnetic resonance imaging</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32871387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7476068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nicl.2020.102385</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2213-1582(20)30222-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abrahams S., Leigh P.N., Harvey A., Vythelingum G.N., Gris&#xe9; D., Goldstein L.H. Verbal fluency and executive dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) Neuropsychologia. 2000;38:734&#x2013;747.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10689049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abrahams S., Newton J., Niven E., Foley J., Bak T.H. Screening for cognition and behaviour changes in ALS. Amyotroph. Lateral Scler. Front. Degener. 2014;15:9&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23781974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agosta F., Canu E., Valsasina P., Riva N., Prelle A., Comi G., Filippi M. Divergent brain network connectivity in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurobiol. Aging. 2013;34:419&#x2013;427.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22608240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agosta F., Pagani E., Rocca M.A., Caputo D., Perini M., Salvi F., Prelle A., Filippi M. Voxel-based morphometry study of brain volumetry and diffusivity in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients with mild disability. Hum. Brain Mapp. 2007;28:1430&#x2013;1438.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6871473</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17370339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agosta F., Valsasina P., Absinta M., Riva N., Sala S., Prelle A., Copetti M., Comola M., Comi G., Filippi M. Sensorimotor functional connectivity changes in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Cereb. Cortex. 2011;21:2291&#x2013;2298.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21368084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agosta F., Valsasina P., Riva N., Copetti M., Messina M.J., Prelle A., Comi G., Filippi M. The cortical signature of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. PLOS One. 2012;7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3412820</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22880116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akakin A., Peris-Celda M., Kilic T., Seker A., Gutierrez-Martin A., Rhoton A. The dentate nucleus and its projection system in the human cerebellumthe dentate nucleus microsurgical anatomical study. Neurosurgery. 2014;74:401&#x2013;425.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24448179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alonso A., Logroscino G., Jick S.S., Hern&#xe1;n M.A. Incidence and lifetime risk of motor neuron disease in the United Kingdom: a population-based study. Eur. J. Neurol. 2009;16:745&#x2013;751.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3093130</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19475756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asanuma C., Thach W.T., Jones E.G. Distribution of cerebellar terminations and their relation to other afferent terminations in the ventral lateral thalamic region of the monkey. Brain Res. Rev. 1983;5:237&#x2013;265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6189561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bede P., Chipika R.H., Finegan E., Li Hi Shing S., Doherty M.A., Hengeveld J.C., Vajda A., Hutchinson S., Donaghy C., McLaughlin R.L., Hardiman O. Brainstem pathology in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and primary lateral sclerosis: a longitudinal neuroimaging study. NeuroImage Clin. 2019;24</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6849418</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31711033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bede P., Elamin M., Byrne S., McLaughlin R.L., Kenna K., Vajda A., Fagan A., Bradley D.G., Hardiman O. Patterns of cerebral and cerebellar white matter degeneration in ALS. J. Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatry. 2015;86:468&#x2013;470.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4392231</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25053771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beghi, E., Logroscino, G., Chi&#xf2;, A., Hardiman, O., Mitchell, D., Swingler, R., Traynor, B.J., EURALS Consortium, 2006. The epidemiology of ALS and the role of population-based registries. Biochim, Biophys, Acta 1762, 1150&#x2013;1157.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17071060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behrens T.E.J., Johansen-Berg H., Woolrich M.W., Smith S.M., Wheeler-Kingshott C.A.M., Boulby P.A., Barker G.J., Sillery E.L., Sheehan K., Ciccarelli O., Thompson A.J., Brady J.M., Matthews P.M. Non-invasive mapping of connections between human thalamus and cortex using diffusion imaging. Nat. Neurosci. 2003;6:750&#x2013;757.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12808459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernard J.A., Peltier S.J., Benson B.L., Wiggins J.L., Jaeggi S.M., Buschkuehl M., Jonides J., Monk C.S., Seidler R.D. Dissociable functional networks of the human dentate nucleus. Cereb. Cortex. 2014;24:2151&#x2013;2159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4089384</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23513045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bharti K., Suppa A., Pietracupa S., Upadhyay N., Giann&#xec; C., Leodori G., Di Biasio F., Modugno N., Petsas N., Grillea G., Zampogna A., Berardelli A., Pantano P. Abnormal cerebellar connectivity patterns in patients with parkinson&#x2019;s disease and freezing of gait. Cerebellum. 2019;18:298&#x2013;308.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30392037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biswal B., Yetkin F.Z., Haughton V.M., Hyde J.S. Functional connectivity in the motor cortex of resting human brain using echo-planar MRI. Magn. Reson. Med. 1995;34:537&#x2013;541.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8524021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biswal, B.B., 2012. Resting state fMRI: a personal history. NeuroImage, 20 YEARS OF fMRI20 YEARS OF fMRI. 62, 938&#x2013;944.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22326802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brazis P.W., Biller J., Fine M., Palacios E., Pagano R.J. Cerebellar degeneration with Hodgkin&#x2019;s disease: computed tomographic correlation and literature review. Arch. Neurol. 1981;38:253&#x2013;256.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7011281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks B.R. El Escorial World Federation of Neurology criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Subcommittee on Motor Neuron Diseases/Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis of the World Federation of Neurology Research Group on Neuromuscular Diseases and the El Escorial &#x201c;Clinical limits of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis&#x201d; workshop contributors. J. Neurol. Sci. 1994;124(Suppl):96&#x2013;107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7807156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckner R.L. The brain&#x2019;s default network: origins and implications for the study of psychosis. Dialogues Clin. Neurosci. 2013;15:351&#x2013;358.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3811106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24174906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cabeza R., Nyberg L. Imaging cognition II: an empirical review of 275 PET and fMRI studies. J. Cogn. Neurosci. 2000;12:1&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10769304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canu E., Agosta F., Riva N., Sala S., Prelle A., Caputo D., Perini M., Comi G., Filippi M. The topography of brain microstructural damage in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis assessed using diffusion tensor MR imaging. Am. J. Neuroradiol. 2011;32:1307&#x2013;1314.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21680655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum J.M., Stambler N., Malta E., Fuller C., Hilt D., Thurmond B., Nakanishi A. The ALSFRS-R: a revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. BDNF ALS Study Group (Phase III) J. Neurol. Sci. 1999;169:13&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10540002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan-Palay V., Palay S.L., Brown J.T., Van Itallie C. Sagittal organization of olivocerebellar and reticulocerebellar projections: autoradiographic studies with 35S-methionine. Exp. Brain Res. 1977;30:561&#x2013;576.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">598441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chenji S., Jha S., Lee D., Brown M., Seres P., Mah D., Kalra S. Investigating default mode and sensorimotor network connectivity in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. PLoS One. 2016;11</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4913931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27322194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2; A., Pagani M., Agosta F., Calvo A., Cistaro A., Filippi M. Neuroimaging in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: insights into structural and functional changes. Lancet Neurol. 2014;13:1228&#x2013;1240.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25453462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cirillo M., Esposito F., Tedeschi G., Caiazzo G., Sagnelli A., Piccirillo G., Conforti R., Tortora F., Monsurr&#xf2; M.R., Cirillo S., Trojsi F. Widespread microstructural white matter involvement in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a whole-brain DTI study. AJNR Am. J. Neuroradiol. 2012;33:1102&#x2013;1108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22300932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>del Aguila M.A., Longstreth W.T., McGuire V., Koepsell T.D., van Belle G. Prognosis in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a population-based study. Neurology. 2003;60:813&#x2013;819.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12629239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diedrichsen J. A spatially unbiased atlas template of the human cerebellum. NeuroImage. 2006;33:127&#x2013;138.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16904911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diedrichsen J., Maderwald S., K&#xfc;per M., Th&#xfc;rling M., Rabe K., Gizewski E.R., Ladd M.E., Timmann D. Imaging the deep cerebellar nuclei: a probabilistic atlas and normalization procedure. NeuroImage. 2011;54:1786&#x2013;1794.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20965257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Douaud G., Filippini N., Knight S., Talbot K., Turner M.R. Integration of structural and functional magnetic resonance imaging in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain. 2011;134:3470&#x2013;3479.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22075069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dum R.P., Li C., Strick P.L. Motor and nonmotor domains in the monkey dentate. Ann. N. Y. Acad. Sci. 2002;978:289&#x2013;301.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12582061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dum R.P., Strick P.L. An unfolded map of the cerebellar dentate nucleus and its projections to the cerebral cortex. J. Neurophysiol. 2003;89:634&#x2013;639.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12522208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Easterling C., Antinoja J., Cashin S., Barkhaus P.E. Changes in tongue pressure, pulmonary function, and salivary flow in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Dysphagia. 2013;28:217&#x2013;225.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23242462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang X., Zhang Y., Wang Y., Zhang Y., Hu J., Wang J., Zhang J., Jiang T. Disrupted effective connectivity of the sensorimotor network in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J. Neurol. 2016;263:508&#x2013;516.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26743627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fasano A., Laganiere S.E., Lam S., Fox M.D. Lesions causing freezing of gait localize to a cerebellar functional network. Ann. Neurol. 2017;81:129&#x2013;141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5266642</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28009063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Femiano C., Trojsi F., Caiazzo G., Siciliano M., Passaniti C., Russo A., Bisecco A., Cirillo M., Monsurr&#xf2; M.R., Esposito F., Tedeschi G., Santangelo G. Apathy is correlated with widespread diffusion tensor imaging (DTI) impairment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis [WWW Document] Behav. Neurol. 2018 https://www.hindawi.com/journals/bn/2018/2635202/</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6217902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30425751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferraro P.M., Agosta F., Riva N., Copetti M., Spinelli E.G., Falzone Y., Sorar&#xf9; G., Comi G., Chi&#xf2; A., Filippi M. Multimodal structural MRI in the diagnosis of motor neuron diseases. NeuroImage Clin. 2017;16:240&#x2013;247.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5545829</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28794983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gavrilescu M., Shaw M.E., Stuart G.W., Eckersley P., Svalbe I.D., Egan G.F. Simulation of the effects of global normalization procedures in functional MRI. NeuroImage. 2002;17:532&#x2013;542.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12377132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geborek P., Bengtsson F., J&#xf6;rntell H. Properties of bilateral spinocerebellar activation of cerebellar cortical neurons. Front. Neural Circ. 2014;8:128.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4209862</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25386122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geser F., Brandmeir N.J., Kwong L.K., Martinez-Lage M., Elman L., McCluskey L., Xie S.X., Lee V.M.-Y., Trojanowski J.Q. Evidence of multisystem disorder in whole-brain map of pathological TDP-43 in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Arch. Neurol. 2008;65:636&#x2013;641.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18474740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldstein L.H., Abrahams S. Changes in cognition and behaviour in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: nature of impairment and implications for assessment. Lancet Neurol. 2013;12:368&#x2013;380.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23518330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Granziera C., Schmahmann J.D., Hadjikhani N., Meyer H., Meuli R., Wedeen V., Krueger G. Diffusion spectrum imaging shows the structural basis of functional cerebellar circuits in the human cerebellum in vivo. PLOS One. 2009;4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2659746</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19340289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo X., Zheng L., Zhang W., Zhu L., Li J., Wang Q., Dienes Z., Yang Z. Empathic neural responses to others&#x2019; pain depend on monetary reward. Soc. Cogn. Affect. Neurosci. 2012;7:535&#x2013;541.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3375886</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21737435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haines D.E., Dietrichs E. The cerebellum &#x2013; structure and connections. Handb Clin. Neurol. 2012;103:3&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21827879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardiman O., van den Berg L.H., Kiernan M.C. Clinical diagnosis and management of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat. Rev. Neurol. 2011;7:639&#x2013;649.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21989247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heimrath J., Gorges M., Kassubek J., M&#xfc;ller H.-P., Birbaumer N., Ludolph A.C., Lul&#xe9; D. Additional resources and the default mode network: evidence of increased connectivity and decreased white matter integrity in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph. Lateral Scler. Front. Degener. 2014;15:537&#x2013;545.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24862983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hillary F.G., Roman C.A., Venkatesan U., Rajtmajer S.M., Bajo R., Castellanos N.D. Hyperconnectivity is a fundamental response to neurological disruption. Neuropsychology. 2015;29:59&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24933491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoover J.E., Strick P.L. The organization of cerebellar and basal ganglia outputs to primary motor cortex as revealed by retrograde transneuronal transport of herpes simplex virus type 1. J. Neurosci. J. Soc. Neurosci. 1999;19:1446&#x2013;1463.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6786031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9952421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horne M.K., Butler E.G. The role of the cerebello-thalamo-cortical pathway in skilled movement. Prog. Neurobiol. 1995;46:199&#x2013;213.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7568913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huynh W., Simon N.G., Grosskreutz J., Turner M.R., Vucic S., Kiernan M.C. Assessment of the upper motor neuron in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2016;127:2643&#x2013;2660.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27291884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jelsone-Swain L.M., Fling B.W., Seidler R.D., Hovatter R., Gruis K., Welsh R.C. Reduced interhemispheric functional connectivity in the motor cortex during rest in limb-onset amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Front. Syst. Neurosci. 2010;4:158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3018774</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21228916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jenkinson M., Beckmann C.F., Behrens T.E.J., Woolrich M.W., Smith S.M. FSL. NeuroImage. 2012;62:782&#x2013;790.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21979382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kakei S., Hoffman D.S., Strick P.L. Muscle and movement representations in the primary motor cortex. Scienc. 1999;285:2136&#x2013;2139.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10497133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kassubek J., Unrath A., Huppertz H.-J., Lul&#xe9; D., Ethofer T., Sperfeld A.-D., Ludolph A.C. Global brain atrophy and corticospinal tract alterations in ALS, as investigated by voxel-based morphometry of 3-D MRI. Amyotroph. Lateral Scler. Mot. Neuron Disord. Off. Publ. World Fed. Neurol. Res. Group Mot. Neuron Dis. 2005;6:213&#x2013;220.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16319024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelly R.M., Strick P.L. Cerebellar loops with motor cortex and prefrontal cortex of a nonhuman primate. J. Neurosci. 2003;23:8432&#x2013;8444.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6740694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12968006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khoyratty F., Wilson T. The dentato-rubro-olivary tract: clinical dimension of this anatomical pathway [WWW Document] Case Rep. Otolaryngol. 2013 https://www.hindawi.com/journals/criot/2013/934386/</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3639700</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23662232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kimura F., Fujimura C., Ishida S., Nakajima H., Furutama D., Uehara H., Shinoda K., Sugino M., Hanafusa T. Progression rate of ALSFRS-R at time of diagnosis predicts survival time in ALS. Neurology. 2006;66:265&#x2013;267.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16434671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koechlin E., Summerfield C. An information theoretical approach to prefrontal executive function. Trends Cogn. Sci. 2007;11:229&#x2013;235.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17475536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konrad C., Henningsen H., Bremer J., Mock B., Deppe M., Buchinger C., Turski P., Knecht S., Brooks B. Pattern of cortical reorganization in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a functional magnetic resonance imaging study. Exp. Brain Res. 2002;143:51&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11907690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koziol L.F., Budding D., Andreasen N., D&#x2019;Arrigo S., Bulgheroni S., Imamizu H., Ito M., Manto M., Marvel C., Parker K., Pezzulo G., Ramnani N., Riva D., Schmahmann J., Vandervert L., Yamazaki T. Consensus paper: the cerebellum&#x2019;s role in movement and cognition. Cerebellum Lond. Engl. 2014;13:151&#x2013;177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4089997</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23996631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwon H.G., Hong J.H., Hong C.P., Lee D.H., Ahn S.H., Jang S.H. Dentatorubrothalamic tract in human brain: diffusion tensor tractography study. Neuroradiology. 2011;53:787&#x2013;791.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21547376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lemon R.N. Descending pathways in motor control. Annu. Rev. Neurosci. 2008;31:195&#x2013;218.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18558853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lenka A., Bhalsing K.S., Panda R., Jhunjhunwala K., Naduthota R.M., Saini J., Bharath R.D., Yadav R., Pal P.K. Role of altered cerebello-thalamo-cortical network in the neurobiology of essential tremor. Neuroradiolog. 2017;59:157&#x2013;168.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28062908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loewe K., Machts J., Kaufmann J., Petri S., Heinze H.-J., Borgelt C., Harris J.A., Vielhaber S., Schoenfeld M.A. Widespread temporo-occipital lobe dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Sci. Rep. 2017;7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5220336</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28067298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo C., Chen Q., Huang R., Chen X., Chen K., Huang X., Tang H., Gong Q., Shang H.-F. Patterns of spontaneous brain activity in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a resting-state FMRI study. PloS One. 2012;7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3447931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23029031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macey P.M., Macey K.E., Kumar R., Harper R.M. A method for removal of global effects from fMRI time series. NeuroImage. 2004;22:360&#x2013;366.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15110027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maknojia S., Churchill N.W., Schweizer T.A., Graham S.J. Resting state fMRI: going through the motions. Front. Neurosci. 2019;13</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6700228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31456656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menke R.A.L., Proudfoot M., Talbot K., Turner M.R. The two-year progression of structural and functional cerebral MRI in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. NeuroImage Clin. 2017;17:953&#x2013;961.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5752097</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29321969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menke R.A.L., Proudfoot M., Wuu J., Andersen P.M., Talbot K., Benatar M., Turner M.R. Increased functional connectivity common to symptomatic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and those at genetic risk. J. Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatry. 2016;87:580&#x2013;588.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4893149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26733601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meola A., Comert A., Yeh F.-C., Sivakanthan S., Fernandez-Miranda J.C. The nondecussating pathway of the dentatorubrothalamic tract in humans: human connectome-based tractographic study and microdissection validation. J. Neurosurg. 2016;124:1406&#x2013;1412.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26452117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Middleton F.A., Strick P.L. Basal ganglia and cerebellar output influences non-motor function. Mol. Psychiatry. 1996;1:429&#x2013;433.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9154241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Middleton F.A., Strick P.L. Basal ganglia and cerebellar loops: motor and cognitive circuits. Brain Res. Rev. 2000;31:236&#x2013;250.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10719151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Middleton F.A., Strick P.L. Cerebellar projections to the prefrontal cortex of the primate. J. Neurosci. 2001;21:700&#x2013;712.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6763818</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11160449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moberget T., Ivry R.B. Prediction, psychosis, and the cerebellum. Biol. Psychiatry Cogn. Neurosci. Neuroimag. 2019;4:820&#x2013;831.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31495402</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mochizuki Y., Isozaki E., Takao M., Hashimoto T., Shibuya M., Arai M., Hosokawa M., Kawata A., Oyanagi K., Mihara B., Mizutani T. Familial ALS with FUS P525L mutation: two Japanese sisters with multiple systems involvement. J. Neurol. Sci. 2012;323:85&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22980027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammadi B., Kollewe K., Samii A., Krampfl K., Dengler R., M&#xfc;nte T.F. Changes of resting state brain networks in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Exp. Neurol. 2009;217:147&#x2013;153.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19416664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mormina E., Petracca M., Bommarito G., Piaggio N., Cocozza S., Inglese M. Cerebellum and neurodegenerative diseases: beyond conventional magnetic resonance imaging. World J. Radiol. 2017;9:371&#x2013;388.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5661166</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29104740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakano T., Nakaso K., Nakashima K., Ohama E. Expression of ubiquitin-binding protein p62 in ubiquitin-immunoreactive intraneuronal inclusions in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with dementia: analysis of five autopsy cases with broad clinicopathological spectrum. Acta Neuropathol. (Berl.) 2004;107:359&#x2013;364.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14762676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niven E., Newton J., Foley J., Colville S., Swingler R., Chandran S., Bak T.H., Abrahams S. Validation of the Edinburgh cognitive and behavioural amyotrophic lateral sclerosis screen (ECAS): a cognitive tool for motor disorders. Amyotroph. Lateral Scler. Front. Degener. 2015;16:172&#x2013;179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25967542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palesi F., Tournier J.-D., Calamante F., Muhlert N., Castellazzi G., Chard D., D&#x2019;Angelo E., Wheeler-Kingshott C.A.M. Contralateral cerebello-thalamo-cortical pathways with prominent involvement of associative areas in humans in vivo. Brain Struct. Funct. 2015;220:3369&#x2013;3384.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4575696</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25134682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phukan J., Elamin M., Bede P., Jordan N., Gallagher L., Byrne S., Lynch C., Pender N., Hardiman O. The syndrome of cognitive impairment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a population-based study. J. Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatry. 2012;83:102&#x2013;108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21836033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phukan J., Pender N.P., Hardiman O. Cognitive impairment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet Neurol. 2007;6:994&#x2013;1003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17945153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinto A.D., Lang A.E., Chen R. The cerebellothalamocortical pathway in essential tremor. Neurology. 2003;60:1985&#x2013;1987.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12821747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiu T., Zhang Y., Tang X., Liu X., Wang Y., Zhou C., Luo C., Zhang J. Precentral degeneration and cerebellar compensation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a multimodal MRI analysis. Hum. Brain Mapp. 2019;40:3464&#x2013;3474.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6865414</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31020731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ragagnin A.M.G., Shadfar S., Vidal M., Jamali M.S., Atkin J.D. Motor neuron susceptibility in ALS/FTD. Front. Neurosci. 2019;13</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6610326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31316328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rowland L.P., Shneider N.A. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. N. Engl. J. Med. 2001;344:1688&#x2013;1700.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11386269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salamon N., Sicotte N., Drain A., Frew A., Alger J.R., Jen J., Perlman S., Salamon G. White matter fiber tractography and color mapping of the normal human cerebellum with diffusion tensor imaging. J. Neuroradiol. J. Neuroradiol. 2007;34:115&#x2013;128.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17481730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmahmann J.D., Sherman J.C. The cerebellar cognitive affective syndrome. Brain J. Neurol. 1998;121(Pt 4):561&#x2013;579.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9577385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seo D., Olman C.A., Haut K.M., Sinha R., MacDonald A.W., Patrick C.J. Neural correlates of preparatory and regulatory control over positive and negative emotion. Soc. Cogn. Affect. Neurosci. 2014;9:494&#x2013;504.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3989138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23887812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen D., Hou B., Xu Y., Cui B., Peng P., Li X., Tai H., Zhang K., Liu S., Fu H., Gao J., Liu M., Feng F., Cui L. Brain structural and perfusion signature of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with varying levels of cognitive deficit. Front. Neurol. 2018;9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5976730</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29881369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith S.M., Fox P.T., Miller K.L., Glahn D.C., Fox P.M., Mackay C.E., Filippini N., Watkins K.E., Toro R., Laird A.R., Beckmann C.F. Correspondence of the brain&#x2019;s functional architecture during activation and rest. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA. 2009;106:13040&#x2013;13045.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2722273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19620724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith S.M., Jenkinson M., Johansen-Berg H., Rueckert D., Nichols T.E., Mackay C.E., Watkins K.E., Ciccarelli O., Cader M.Z., Matthews P.M., Behrens T.E.J. Tract-based spatial statistics: voxelwise analysis of multi-subject diffusion data. NeuroImage. 2006;31:1487&#x2013;1505.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16624579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith S.M., Jenkinson M., Woolrich M.W., Beckmann C.F., Behrens T.E.J., Johansen-Berg H., Bannister P.R., De Luca M., Drobnjak I., Flitney D.E., Niazy R.K., Saunders J., Vickers J., Zhang Y., De Stefano N., Brady J.M., Matthews P.M. Advances in functional and structural MR image analysis and implementation as FSL. NeuroImage. 2004;23(Suppl. 1):S208&#x2013;219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15501092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith S.M., Nichols T.E. Threshold-free cluster enhancement: addressing problems of smoothing, threshold dependence and localisation in cluster inference. Neuroimage. 2009;44:83&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18501637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stoodley C.J., Schmahmann J.D. Evidence for topographic organization in the cerebellum of motor control versus cognitive and affective processing. Cortex J. Devoted Study Nerv. Syst. Behav. 2010;46:831&#x2013;844.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2873095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20152963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stoodley C.J., Valera E.M., Schmahmann J.D. Functional topography of the cerebellum for motor and cognitive tasks: an fMRI study. NeuroImage. 2012;59:1560&#x2013;1570.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3230671</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21907811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strick P.L., Dum R.P., Fiez J.A. Cerebellum and nonmotor function. Annu. Rev. Neurosci. 2009;32:413&#x2013;434.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19555291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suzuki L., Coulon P., Sabel-Goedknegt E.H., Ruigrok T.J.H. Organization of cerebral projections to identified cerebellar zones in the posterior cerebellum of the rat. J. Neurosci. 2012;32:10854&#x2013;10869.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6621006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22875920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan R.H., Devenney E., Dobson-Stone C., Kwok J.B., Hodges J.R., Kiernan M.C., Halliday G.M., Hornberger M. Cerebellar integrity in the amyotrophic lateral sclerosis &#x2013; frontotemporal dementia continuum. PLoS One. 2014;9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4140802</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25144223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tedeschi G., Trojsi F., Tessitore A., Corbo D., Sagnelli A., Paccone A., D&#x2019;Ambrosio A., Piccirillo G., Cirillo M., Cirillo S., Monsurr&#xf2; M.R., Esposito F. Interaction between aging and neurodegeneration in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurobiol. Aging. 2012;33:886&#x2013;898.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20739098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thivard L., Pradat P.-F., Leh&#xe9;ricy S., Lacomblez L., Dormont D., Chiras J., Benali H., Meininger V. Diffusion tensor imaging and voxel based morphometry study in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: relationships with motor disability. J. Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatry. 2007;78:889&#x2013;892.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2117724</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17635981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tona F., De Giglio L., Petsas N., Sbardella E., Prosperini L., Upadhyay N., Giann&#xec; C., Pozzilli C., Pantano P. Role of cerebellar dentate functional connectivity in balance deficits in patients with multiple sclerosis. Radiology. 2017;287:267&#x2013;275.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29272214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trojsi F., Caiazzo G., Corbo D., Piccirillo G., Cristillo V., Femiano C., Ferrantino T., Cirillo M., Monsurr&#xf2; M.R., Esposito F., Tedeschi G. Microstructural changes across different clinical milestones of disease in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. PLOS One. 2015;10</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4368555</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25793718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner M.R. MRI as a frontrunner in the search for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis biomarkers? Biomark Med. 2011;5:79&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3182543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21319968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verstraete E., van den Heuvel M.P., Veldink J.H., Blanken N., Mandl R.C., Hulshoff Pol H.E., van den Berg L.H. Motor network degeneration in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a structural and functional connectivity study. PloS One. 2010;5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2965124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21060689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou C., Hu X., Hu J., Liang M., Yin X., Chen L., Zhang J., Wang J. Altered brain network in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a resting graph theory-based network study at voxel-wise level. Front. Neurosci. 2016;10</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4861727</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27242409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou F., Gong H., Li F., Zhuang Y., Zang Y., Xu R., Wang Z. Altered motor network functional connectivity in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a resting-state functional magnetic resonance imaging study. Neuroreport. 2013;24:657&#x2013;662.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23839257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>