<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">32888367</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>11</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1468-1331</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>28</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Incidence of motor neuron disease/amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in South Africa: a 4-year prospective study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>81</StartPage><EndPage>89</EndPage><MedlinePgn>81-89</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/ene.14499</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND PURPOSE">Little is known about the epidemiological features of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) in sub-Saharan Africa, and data from the region are limited to clinical series or case reports. The aim of the study was to investigate the incidence rate and presentation of ALS in an ethnically diverse region of South Africa.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">We performed a 4-year prospective incidence study in the Western Cape Province of South Africa between 1 July 2014 and 30 June 2018, and used a two-source capture-recapture method for case ascertainment. Age- and sex-adjusted incidence rates (ASAIRs) were calculated using the 2010 US population as the reference.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">A total of 203 incident cases were identified over the study period, resulting in a crude incidence rate (IR) of 1.09 [95% confidence interval (CI) 0.94-1.24] per 100&#xa0;000 person-years in the at-risk population (aged &gt;15&#xa0;years). Capture-recapture analysis resulted in an estimated IR of 1.11 (95% CI 1.01-1.22) per 100&#xa0;000 person-years. The ASAIR was 1.67 (95% CI 1.09-2.26) overall; 1.99 (95% CI 1.60-2.39) for men and 1.37 (95% CI 1.06-1.68) for women. When analysed separately, there was a substantial difference in ASAIRs between the different population groups, with the highest in the European ancestry group (2.62; 95% CI 2.49-2.75), the lowest in the African ancestry group (0.56, 95% CI 0.0-1.23), and an ASAIR in between these two in the mixed ancestry group (1.09, 95% CI 0.80-1.37).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">The overall incidence of ALS in the Western Cape Province of South Africa appears to be lower than in North African and Western countries, but higher than in Asian countries. As suggested by previous epidemiological studies, ALS may be less frequent in people of African ancestry.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020 European Academy of Neurology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Henning</LastName><ForeName>F</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4006-8101</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Neurology, Department of Medicine, Faculty of Medicine and Health Sciences, Stellenbosch University, Cape Town, South Africa.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Heckmann</LastName><ForeName>J M</ForeName><Initials>JM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Neurology, Department of Medicine, Faculty of Health Sciences, University of Cape Town, Cape Town, South Africa.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Naidu</LastName><ForeName>K</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Neurology, Department of Medicine, Faculty of Medicine and Health Sciences, Stellenbosch University, Cape Town, South Africa.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vlok</LastName><ForeName>L</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Neurology, Department of Medicine, Faculty of Medicine and Health Sciences, Stellenbosch University, Cape Town, South Africa.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cross</LastName><ForeName>H M</ForeName><Initials>HM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Neurology, Department of Medicine, Faculty of Health Sciences, University of Cape Town, Cape Town, South Africa.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Marin</LastName><ForeName>B</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ministere de la Sante et des Solidarites, Cellule Interminist&#xe9;rielle Recherche MSS/MESRI, Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9506311</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1351-5101</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015994" MajorTopicYN="N">Incidence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016472" MajorTopicYN="Y">Motor Neuron Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011446" MajorTopicYN="N">Prospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013019" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">South Africa</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">South Africa</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">incidence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">motor neuron disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neurodegenerative disorders</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sub-Saharan Africa</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32888367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ene.14499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Forbes RB, Colville S, Parratt J, Swingler RJ. The incidence of motor neuron disease in Scotland. J Neurol 2007; 254: 866-869.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huisman MH, de Jong SW, van Doormaal PT, et al. Population based epidemiology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis using capture-recapture methodology. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2011; 82: 1165-1170.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Logroscino G, Beghi E, Zoccolella S, et al. Incidence of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in southern Italy: a population based study. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2005; 76: 1094-1098.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marin B, Boumediene F, Logroscino G, et al. Variation in worldwide incidence of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a meta-analysis. Int J Epidemiol 2017; 46: 57-74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braga AC, Gromicho M, Pinto S, de Carvalho M, Henning F. A comparative study of South African and Portuguese amyotrophic lateral sclerosis cohorts. J Neurol Sci 2020; 414: 116857.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rechtman L, Jordan H, Wagner L, Horton DK, Kaye W. Racial and ethnic differences among amyotrophic lateral sclerosis cases in the United States. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2015; 16: 65-71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Annegers JF, Appel S, Lee JR, Perkins P. Incidence and prevalence of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in Harris County, Texas, 1985-1988. Arch Neurol 1991; 48: 589-593.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGuire V, Longstreth WT Jr, Koepsell TD, van Belle G. Incidence of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in three counties in western Washington state. Neurology 1996; 47: 571-573.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdulla MN, Sokrab TE, el Tahir A, Siddig HE, Ali ME. Motor neurone disease in the tropics: findings from Sudan. East Afr Med J 1997; 74: 46-48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cosnett JE, Bill PL, Bhigjee AI. Motor neuron disease in blacks. Epidemiological observations in Natal. S Afr Med J 1989; 76: 155-157.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marin B, Kacem I, Diagana M, et al. Juvenile and adult-onset ALS/MND among Africans: incidence, phenotype, survival: a review. Amyotroph Lateral Scler 2012; 13: 276-283.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The World Bank - Life expectancy at birth. https://data.worldbank.org/indicator/SP.DYN.LE00.IN?name_desc=false (Accessed 6 June 2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Statistics South Africa - Mid-year population estimates, 2016. https://www.statssa.gov.za/publications/P0302/P03022016.pdf (Accessed 6 June 2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daya M, van der Merwe L, Galal U, et al. A panel of ancestry informative markers for the complex five-way admixed South African coloured population. PLoS One 2013; 8: e82224.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Wit E, Delport W, Rugamika CE, et al. Genome-wide analysis of the structure of the South African Coloured Population in the Western Cape. Hum Genet 2010; 128: 145-153.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Statistics South Africa - General Household Survey. https://www.statssa.gov.za/publications/P0318/P03182016.pdf (Accessed 6 June 2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR. El Escorial World Federation of Neurology criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Subcommittee on Motor Neuron Diseases/Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis of the World Federation of Neurology Research Group on Neuromuscular Diseases and the El Escorial "Clinical limits of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis" workshop contributors. J Neurol Sci 1994; 124(Suppl.): 96-107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kimura F, Fujimura C, Ishida S, et al. Progression rate of ALSFRS-R at time of diagnosis predicts survival time in ALS. Neurology 2006; 66: 265-267.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byrne S, Bede P, Elamin M, et al. Proposed criteria for familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler 2011; 12: 157-159.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris PA, Taylor R, Thielke R, Payne J, Gonzalez N, Conde JG. Research electronic data capture (REDCap)-a metadata-driven methodology and workflow process for providing translational research informatics support. J Biomed Inform 2009; 42: 377-381.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris PA, Taylor R, Minor BL, et al. The REDCap consortium: Building an international community of software platform partners. J Biomed Inform 2019; 95: 103208.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chapman DG. University of California B. Some properties of the hypergeometric distribution with applications to zoological sample censuses. Berkeley: University of California Press, 1951.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wittie M, Nelson LM, Usher S, Ward K, Benatar M. Utility of capture-recapture methodology to assess completeness of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis case ascertainment. Neuroepidemiology 2013; 40: 133-141.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>von Elm E, Altman DG, Egger M, Pocock SJ, Gotzsche PC, Vandenbroucke JP. Strengthening the Reporting of Observational Studies in Epidemiology (STROBE) statement: guidelines for reporting observational studies. BMJ 2007; 335: 806-808.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bennett DA, Brayne C, Feigin VL, et al. Development of the standards of reporting of neurological disorders (STROND) checklist: a guideline for the reporting of incidence and prevalence studies in neuroepidemiology. Eur J Epidemiol 2015; 30: 569-576.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beghi E, Millul A, Micheli A, Vitelli E, Logroscino G. Incidence of ALS in Lombardy, Italy. Neurology 2007; 68: 141-145.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Traynor BJ, Codd MB, Corr B, Forde C, Frost E, Hardiman O. Incidence and prevalence of ALS in Ireland, 1995-1997: a population-based study. Neurology 1999; 52: 504-509.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allen KD, Kasarskis EJ, Bedlack RS, et al. The National Registry of Veterans with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuroepidemiology 2008; 30: 180-190.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abhinav K, Stanton B, Johnston C, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in South-East England: a population-based study. The South-East England register for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (SEALS Registry). Neuroepidemiology 2007; 29: 44-48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patterson N, Petersen DC, van der Ross RE, et al. Genetic structure of a unique admixed population: implications for medical research. Hum Mol Genet 2010; 19: 411-419.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tishkoff SA, Reed FA, Friedlaender FR, et al. The genetic structure and history of Africans and African Americans. Science 2009; 324: 1035-1044.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chimusa ER, Meintjies A, Tchanga M, et al. A genomic portrait of haplotype diversity and signatures of selection in indigenous southern African populations. PLoS Genet 2015; 11: e1005052.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nel M, Agenbag GM, Henning F, Cross HM, Esterhuizen A, Heckmann JM. C9orf72 repeat expansions in South Africans with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Sci 2019; 401: 51-54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collomb HVR, Dumas M, Lemercier G. Maladie de Charcot et syndromes de scl&#xe9;rose lat&#xe9;rale amyotrophique au S&#xe9;n&#xe9;gal. Etude clinique de 27 observations. Bull Soc M&#xe9;d Afr Noire Lgue fr 1968; 13: 785-804.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dorst J, Chen L, Rosenbohm A, et al. Prognostic factors in ALS: a comparison between Germany and China. J Neurol 2019; 266: 1516-1525.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leighton DJ, Newton J, Stephenson LJ, et al. Changing epidemiology of motor neurone disease in Scotland. J Neurol 2019; 266: 817-825.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longinetti E, Regodon Wallin A, Samuelsson K, et al. The Swedish motor neuron disease quality registry. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2018; 19: 528-537.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kacem I, Sghaier I, Bougatef S, et al. Epidemiological and clinical features of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in a Tunisian cohort. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2020; 21: 131-139.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chio A. ISIS Survey: an international study on the diagnostic process and its implications in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol 1999; 246(Suppl. 3): Iii1-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benjaminsen E, Alstadhaug KB, Gulsvik M, Baloch FK, Odeh F. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in Nordland county, Norway, 2000-2015: prevalence, incidence, and clinical features. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2018; 19: 522-527.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luna J, Diagana M, Ait Aissa L, et al. Clinical features and prognosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in Africa: the TROPALS study. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2019; 90: 20-29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The fifth South African national HIV prevalence, incidence, behaviour and communication survey. http://www.hsrc.ac.za/uploads/pageContent/9234/SABSSMV_Impact_Assessment_Summary_ZA_ADS_cleared_PDFA4.pdf (Accessed 27 July 2020).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>