<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">32882437</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>04</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1878-5883</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>418</Volume><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>15</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of the neurological sciences</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Neurol Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>New technologies and Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis - Which step forward rushed by the COVID-19 pandemic?</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>117081</StartPage><MedlinePgn>117081</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.jns.2020.117081</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0022-510X(20)30418-4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis (ALS) is a fast-progressive neurodegenerative disease leading to progressive physical immobility with usually normal or mild cognitive and/or behavioural involvement. Many patients are relatively young, instructed, sensitive to new technologies, and professionally active when developing the first symptoms. Older patients usually require more time, encouragement, reinforcement and a closer support but, nevertheless, selecting user-friendly devices, provided earlier in the course of the disease, and engaging motivated carers may overcome many technological barriers. ALS may be considered a model for neurodegenerative diseases to further develop and test new technologies. From multidisciplinary teleconsults to telemonitoring of the respiratory function, telemedicine has the potentiality to embrace other fields, including nutrition, physical mobility, and the interaction with the environment. Brain-computer interfaces and eye tracking expanded the field of augmentative and alternative communication in ALS but their potentialities go beyond communication, to cognition and robotics. Virtual reality and different forms of artificial intelligence present further interesting possibilities that deserve to be investigated. COVID-19 pandemic is an unprecedented opportunity to speed up the development and implementation of new technologies in clinical practice, improving the daily living of both ALS patients and carers. The present work reviews the current technologies for ALS patients already in place or being under evaluation with published publications, prompted by the COVID-19 pandemic.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2020. Published by Elsevier B.V.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pinto</LastName><ForeName>Susana</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Translational and Clinical Physiology Unit, Instituto de Medicina Molecular, Lisbon, Portugal. Electronic address: susana.c.pinto@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Quintarelli</LastName><ForeName>Stefano</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>AgID - Italian digital agency and Clusit - Italian Computer Security Association, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Silani</LastName><ForeName>Vincenzo</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology-Stroke Unit and Laboratory of Neuroscience, Istituto Auxologico Italiano IRCCS - Department of Pathophysiology and Transplantation, "Dino Ferrari" Center and Center for Neurotechnology and Brain Therapeutics, Universit&#xe0; degli Studi di Milano, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>J Neurol Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0375403</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0022-510X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006297" MajorTopicYN="N">Health Services Accessibility</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D062069" MajorTopicYN="N">Inventions</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000331" MajorTopicYN="N">legislation &amp; jurisprudence</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058873" MajorTopicYN="N">Pandemics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017216" MajorTopicYN="N">Telemedicine</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Artificial intelligence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Brain-computer interfaces</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Eye-tracking</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Robotics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Telemedicine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Virtual reality</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32882437</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7403097</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jns.2020.117081</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0022-510X(20)30418-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>EFNS Task Force on Diagnosis and Management of Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis, Andersen P.M., Abrahams S., Borasio G.D., de Carvalho M., Chio A., Van Damme P., Hardiman O., Kollewe K., Morrison K.E., Petri S., Pradat P.F., Silani V., Tomik B., Wasner M., Weber M. EFNS guidelines on the clinical management of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (MALS)- revised report of an EFNS task force. Eur. J. Neurol. 2012;19(3):360&#x2013;375.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21914052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brownlee A., Bruening L. Methods of communication at end of life for the person with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Top. Lang. Disord. 2012;32:168&#x2013;185.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beukelman D, Fager S, Nordness A. Communication support for people with ALS. Neurol Res Int 2011;2011:714693.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3096454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21603029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Londral A., Pinto A., Pinto S., Azevedo L., de Carvalho M. Quality of life in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients and caregivers: impact of assistive communication from early stages. Muscle Nerve. 2015;52(6):933&#x2013;941.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25808635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ball L., Schardt K., Beukelman D. Primary communication facilitators. Augment Commun News. 2005;17:6&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hodson R. Digital Revolution. Nature. 2018;563(7733):S131.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30487631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rotolo D., Hicks D., Martin B. What is an emerging Technology? Res. Policy. 2015;44(10):1827&#x2013;1843.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strehle E.M., Shabde N. One hundred years of telemedicine: does this new technology have a place in paediatrics? Arch. Dis. Child. 2006;91(12):956&#x2013;959.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2082971</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17119071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO . 1997. A health telematics policy in support of WHO&#x2019;s Health-fos-all strategy for global health development: report of the WHO group consultation on health telematics.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galea M.D. Telemedicine in rehabilitation. Phys. Med. Rehabil. Clin. N. Am. 2019;(30):473&#x2013;483.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30954160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO Telemedicine Opportunities and Developments in State Members. 2010. https://www.who.int/goe/publications/goe_telemedicine_2010.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henderson R.D., Hutchinson N., Douglas J.A., Douglas C. Telehealth for motor neurone disease. Med. J. Aust. 2014;201(1):31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24999893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van De Rijn M., Paganoni S., Levine-Weinberg M., Campbell K., Swartz Ellrodt A., Estrada J., et al. Experience with telemedicine in a multi-disciplinary ALS clinic. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2018;19:143&#x2013;148.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29250986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paganoni S., Van de Rijn M., Drake K., Burke K., Doyle M., Ellrodt A.S., Nicholson K., Atassi N., De Marchi F., Babu S., Estrada J., Schwamm L.H., Berry J.D. Adjusted cost analyses of video televisits for the care of prople with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 2019;60:147&#x2013;154.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6772103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31136007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selkirk S.M., Washington M.O., McClellan F., Flynn B., Seton J.M., Strozewski R. Delivering tertiary Centre specialty care to ALS patients via telemedicine: a retrospective cohort analysis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2017;18:324&#x2013;332.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28427284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geronimo A., Wright C., Morris A., Walsh S., Snyder B., Simmons Z. Incorporation of telehealth into a multidisciplinary ALS clinic: feasibility and acceptability. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2017;18:555&#x2013;561.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28678542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haulman A, Geronimo A, Chahwala A, Simmons Z. The use of telehealth to enhance care in ALS and other neuromuscular disorders. Muscle Nerve 2020 ((epub aheand of print).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32297678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hobson E.V., Baird W.O., Partridge R., Cooper C., Mawson S., Quinn A., Shaw P., Walsh T., Wolstenholme D., Mcdermott C.J. The TiM system: developing a novel telehealth service to improve access to specialist care in motor neurone disease using user-centered design. Amyotroph Lateral Scler and Frontotemporal Degener. 2018;19(5&#x2013;6):351&#x2013;361.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29451026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hobson E.V., Baird W.O., Bradburn M., Cooper C., Mawson S., Quinn A., Shaw P., Walsh T., Mcdermott C.J. Process evaluation and explotation of telehealth in motor neuron disease in a UK specialist Centre. BMJ Open. 2019;9(10)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6830641</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31640994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nijeweme-d&#x2019;Hollosy W.O., Janssen E.P.F. Huis in&#x2019;t veld RMHA, Spoelstra J, Vollenbroek-Hutten MMR, Hermens HJ. Tele-treatment of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) J. Telemed. Telecare. 2006;12(Suppl. 1):31&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16884573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelsen L., McCoy S., Hoffman P., Patwa H. Comprehensive care and home telehealth to veterans with ALS. Amyotroph. Lateral Scler. 2013;14(Suppl. 2):64&#x2013;83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McClellan F., Washington M., Ruff R., Selkirk S.M. Early and innovative symptomatic care to improve quality of life of ALS patients at Cleveland VA ALS Center. J. Rehabil. Res. Dev. 2013;50:vii&#x2013;xvi.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23934878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Capozzo R, Zoccolella S, Musio M, Barone R, Accogli M, Logroscino G. Telemedicine is a useful tool to deliver care to patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis during COVID-19 pandemic: results from southern Italy. Amyotroph Lateral Scler and Frontotemporal Degener 2020 ((epub ahead of print)).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32530314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrews JA, Berry JD, Baloh RH, Carberry N, Cudkowicz ME, Dedi B, Glass J, Maragakis NJ, Miller TM, Paganoni S, Rothstein JD, Shefner JM, Simmons Z, Weiss MD; Bedlack RS. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis care and research in the United States during the COVID-19 pandemic: challenges and opportunities. Muscle Nerve 2020 ((epub ahead of print)).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7283687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32445195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pulley M.T., Brittain R., Hodges W., Frazier C., Miller L., Matyjasik-Liggett M., et al. Multidisciplinary ALS telemedicine care: the store and forward method. Muscle Nerve. 2018;59:34&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29802746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller R.G., Brooks B.R., Swain-Eng R.J., et al. Quality improvement in neurology: amyotrophic lateral sclerosis quality measures: report of the quality measurement and reporting subcommittee of the Ameri- can academy of neurology. Neurology. 2013;81:2136&#x2013;2140.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3863352</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24271651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopes de Almeida JP, Pinto AC, Pereira J, Pinto S, de Carvalho M. Implementation of a wireless device for real-time Telemedical assistance of home-ventilated amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients: a feasibility study. Telemed. J. E Health 2010;16(8):883&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20925565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinto A., Almeida J.P., Pinto S., Pereira J., Oliveira A.G., de Carvalho M. Home telemonitoring of non-invasive ventilation decreases healthcare utilisation in a prospective controlled trial of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J. Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatry. 2010;81(11):1238&#x2013;1242.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20826878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopes de Almeida J.P., Pinto A., Pinto S., Ohana B., de Carvalho M. Economic cost of home-telemonitoring care for BiPAP-assisted ALS individuals. Amyotroph. Lateral Scler. 2012;13(6):533&#x2013;537.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22873565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vitacca M., Assoni G., Pizzocaro P., Guerra A., Marchina L., Scalvini S., Glisenti F., Spanevello A., Bianchi L., Barbano L., Giordano A., Balbi B. A pilot study of nurse-led, home monitoring for patients with chronic respiratory failure and with mechanical ventilation assistance. J. Telemed. Telecare. 2006;12:337&#x2013;342.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17059649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vitacca M., Comini L., Tentorio M., Assoni G., Trainini D., Fiorenza D., Morini R., Bruletti G., Scalvini S. A pilot trial of telemedicine-assisted, integrated care for patients with advanced amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and their caregivers. J. Telemed. Telecare. 2010;16:83&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20139136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vitacca M., Comini L., Assoni G., Fiorenza D., Gil&#xe8; S., Bernocchi P., Scalvini S. Tele-assistance in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: long term activity and costs. Disabil Rehabil Assist Technol. 2012;7(6):494&#x2013;500.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22309823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vitacca M., Paneroni M., Trainini D., Bianchi L., Assoni G., Saleri M., Gil&#xe8; S., Winck J.C., Gon&#xe7;alves M.R. At home and on-demand mechanical cough assistance program for patients with ALS. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2010;89(5):401&#x2013;406.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20407305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garuti G., Bagatti E., Verucchi, Massobrio M., Spagnolatti L., Vezzani G., Lusuardi M. Pulmonary rehabilitation at home guided by telemonitoring and access to healthcare facilities for respiratory complications in patients with neuromuscular disease. Eur J Phys Rehabil Med. 2013;49:51&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22820817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hazenberg A., Kerstjens H.A.M., Prins S.C.L., Vermeulen K.M., Wijkstra P.J. Initiation of home mechanical ventilation at home: a randomised controlled trial of efficacy, feasibility and costs. Respir. Med. 2014;108(9):1387&#x2013;1395.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25081652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geronimo A., Simmons Z. Evaluation of remote pulmonary function testing in motor neuron disease. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2019;20:348&#x2013;355.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30957547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ando H., Ashcroft-Kelso H., Halhead R., Young CAChakrabarti B., Levene P., Cousins R., Angus R.M. Incorporating self-reported questions for Telemonitoring to optimize Care of Patients with MND on noninvasive ventilation (MND OptNIVent) Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2019;20(5&#x2013;6):336&#x2013;347.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30912468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zamarr&#xf3;n C., Morete E., Gonz&#xe1;lez F. Telemedicine system for the care of patients with neuromuscular disease and chronic respiratory failure. Arch. Med. Sci. 2014;27(10(5)):1047&#x2013;1051.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4223148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25395959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Portaro S., Calabr&#xf2; R.S., Bramanti P., Silvestri G., Torrisi M., Conti-Nibali V., Caliri S., Lunetta C., Alagna B., Naro A., Bramanti A. Telemedicine for Facio-Scapulo-humeral muscular dystrophy: a multidisciplinary approach to improve quality of life and reduce hospitalization rate? Disabil Health J. 2018;11(2):306&#x2013;309.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28967584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Unnikrishnan D, Raman D, Joshi D, Ajaikumar BS. Use of home telemedicine for critical illness rehabilitation: an Indian success story. BMJ Case Rep. (2019 21;12(2).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6388885</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30796070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ambrosino N., Vitacca M., Dreher M., Isetta V., Montserrat J.M., Tonia T., Turchetti G., Winck J.C., Burgos F., Kampelmacher M., Vagheggini G. ERS Tele-monitoring of ventilator-dependent patients task force. Tele-monitoring of ventilator-dependent patients: a European Respiratory Society statement. Eur. Respir. J. 2016;48(3):648&#x2013;663.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27390283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borel J.-C., Palot A., Patout M. Technological advances in home non-invasive ventilation monitoring: reliability of data and effect on patient outcomes. Respirology. 2019 Feb:10. (Epub ahead of print)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30739370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinto S., Swash M., de Carvalho M. Respiratory exercise in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph. Lateral Scler. 2012;13(1):33&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22214352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braga ACM, Pinto A, Pinto S, de Carvalho M. The role of moderate aerobic exercise as determined by cardiopulmonary exercise testing in ALS. Neurol Res Int 2018; 8218697.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5832023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29666705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Eijk R.P.A., Bakers J.N.E., Bunte T.M., de Fockert A.J., Eijkemans M.J.C., van den Berg L.H. Accelerometry for remote monitoring of physical activity in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a longitudinal cohort study. J. Neurol. 2019;266:2387&#x2013;2395.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6765690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31187191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia-Gancedo L., Kelly M.L., Lavrov A., Parr J., Hart R., Marsden R., Turner M.R., Talbot K., Chiwera T., Shaw C.E., Al-Chalabi A. Objectively monitoring amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patient symptoms during clinical trials with sensors: observational study. JMIR Mhealth Uhealth. 2019;7(12)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6942190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31859676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wills A.M., Garry J., Hubbard J., Mezoian T., Breen C.T., Ortiz-Miller C., Nalipinski P., Sullivan S., Berry J.D., Cudkowicz M., Paganoni S., Chan J., Macklin E.A. Nutritional counseling with or without mobile health technology: a randomized open-label standard-of-care-controlled trial in ALS. BMC Neurol. 2019;19:104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6540456</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31142272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helleman J., van Eenennaam R., Kruitwagen E.T., Kruithof W.J., Slappendel M.J., van Den Berg, Visser-Meily J.M.A., Beelen A. Telehealth as part of specialized ALS care: feasibility and user experiences with ALS home-monitoring and coaching. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2020:31;1&#x2013;10. (epub ahead of print)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32003245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hobson E.V., Fazal S., Shaw P.J., McDermott C.J. Anything that makes life&#x2019;s journey better. Exploring the use of digital technology by people living with motor neurone disease. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2017;18(5&#x2013;6):378&#x2013;387.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28631958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackenzie L., Bhuta P., Rusten K., Devine J., Love A., Communications Technology Waterson P. Motor neuron disease: an australian survey of people with motor neuron disease. JMIR Rehabil Assist Technol. 2016;25;3(1) e2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5454550</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28582251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>James N., Power E., Hogden A., Vucic S. Patients&#x2019; perspectives of multidisciplinary home-based e-health service delivery for motor neurone disease. Disabil Rehabil Assist Technol. 2019 Oct;14(7):737&#x2013;743.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30182780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>https://www.patientslikeme.com</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rutkove S.B., Qi K., Shelton K., Liss J., Berisha V., Shefner J.M. ALS longitudinal studies with frequent data collection at home: study design and baseline data. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2019;20:61&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6513689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30486680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ball L.J., Nordness A., Fager S., et al. Eye-gaze access of AAC technology for persons with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Med Speech Lang Pathol. 2010;18:11&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spataro R., Ciriacono M., Manno C., La Bella V. The eye-tracking computer device for communication in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neurol. Scand. 2014;130(1):40&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24350578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caligari M., Godi M., Guglielmetti S., Franchignoni F., Nardone A. Eye tracking communication devices in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: impact on disability and quality of life. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2013;14(7&#x2013;8):546&#x2013;552.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23834069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hwang C.S., Weng H.H., Wang L.F., Tsai C.H., Chang H.T. An eye-tracking assistive device improves the quality of life for ALS patients and reduces the caregivers&#x2019; burden. J. Mot. Behav. 2014;46(4):233&#x2013;238.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24731126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linse K., R&#xfc;ger W., Joos M., Schmitz-Peiffer H., Storch A., Hermann A. Eye-tracking-based assessment suggests preserved well-being in locked-in patients. Ann. Neurol. 2017;81(2):310&#x2013;315.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28074605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuzma-Kozakiewicz M., Andersen P.A., Ciecwierska K., V&#xe1;zquez C., Helczyk O., Loose M., Uttner I., Ludolph A.C., Lul&#xe9; D. An observational study on quality of life and preferences to sustain life in locked-in state. Neurology. 2019;93(10):e938&#x2013;e945. 3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6745736</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31391247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keller J., Gorges M., Horn H.T., Aho-&#xd6;zhan H.E.A., Pinkhardt E.H., Uttner I., Kassubek J., Ludolph A.C., Lul&#xe9; D. Eye-tracking controlled cognitive function tests in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a controlled proof-of-principle study. J. Neurol. 2015;262(8):1918&#x2013;1926.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26041615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keller J., Krimly A., Bauer L., Schulenburg S., B&#xf6;hm S., Aho-&#xd6;zhan H.E.A., Uttner I., Gorges M., Kassubek J., Pinkhardt E.H., Abrahams S., Ludolph A.C., Lul&#xe9; D. A first approach to a neuropsychological screening tool using eye-tracking for bedside cognitive testing based on the Edinburgh cognitive and behavioural ALS screen. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2017;18(5&#x2013;6):443&#x2013;450.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28420245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poletti B., Carelli L., Solca F., Lafronza A., Pedroli E., Faini A., Ticozzi N., Ciammola A., Meriggi P., Cipresso P., Lul&#xe9; D., Ludolph A.C., Riva G., Silani V. An eye-tracker controlled cognitive battery: overcoming verbal-motor limitations in ALS. J. Neurol. 2017;264(6):1136&#x2013;1145.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28503706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poletti B., Carelli L., Faini A., Solca F., Meriggi P., Lafronza A., Ciringione L., Pedroli E., Ticozzi N., Ciammola A., Cipresso P., Riva G., Silani V. The arrows and Colors cognitive test (ACCT): a new verbal-motor free cognitive measure for executive functions in ALS. PLoS One. 2018;9(13):8. e0200953.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6084851</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30091987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma R., Hicks S., Berna C.M., Kennard C., Talbot K., Turner M.R. Oculomotor dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a comprehensive review. Arch. Neurol. 2011;68(7):857&#x2013;861.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21747027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCane L.M., Sellers E.W., McFarland D.J., Mak J.N., Carmack C.S., Zeitlin D., Wolpaw J.R., Vaughan T.M. Brain computer interface (BCI) evaluation in people with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2014 Jun;15(3&#x2013;4):207&#x2013;215.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4427912</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24555843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sellers E.W., Donchin E. A P300-based brain-computer interface: initial tests by ALS patients. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2006;117:538&#x2013;548.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16461003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nijboer F., Sellers E.W., Mellinger J., Jordan M.A., Matuz T., Furdea A., Halder S., Mochty U., Krusienski D.J., Vaughan T.M., Wolpaw J.R., Birbaumer N., K&#xfc;bler A. A P300-based brain-computer Interface for people with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurophysiol. 2008;119(8):1909&#x2013;1916.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2853977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18571984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silvoni S., Volpato C., Cavinato M., Marchetti M., Priftis K., Merico A., Tonin P., Koutsikos K., Beverina F., Piccione F. Based brain&#x2013;computer Interface communication: evaluation and follow-up in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Front. Neurosci. 2009;3:60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2858557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20582284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolpaw J.R., Bedlack R.S., Reda D.J., Ringer R.J., Banks P.G., Vaughan T.M., Heckman S.M., McCane L.M., Carmack C.S., Winden S., McFarland D.J., Sellers E.W., Shi H., Paine T., Higgins D.S., Lo A.C., Patwa H.S., Hill K.J., Huang G.D., Ruff R.L. Independent home use of a brain computer interface by people with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology. 2018;91(3):e258&#x2013;e267. 17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6059033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29950436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vansteensel M.J., Pels E.G., Bleichner M.G., Branco M.P., Denison T., Freudenburg Z.V., et al. Fully implanted brain-computer interface in a locked-in patient with ALS NEJMoa1608085. N. Engl. J. Med. 2016;375:21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5326682</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27959736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pels E. Stability of a chronic implanted brain-computer Interface in late-stage amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2019;130(10):1798&#x2013;1803.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6880281</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31401488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iversen I.H., Ghanayim N., Kubler A., Neumann N., Birbaumer N., Kaiser J. A brain-computer interface tool to assess cognitive functions in completely paralyzed patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2008;119:2214&#x2013;2223.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18762448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iversen IH, Ghanayim N, A. Kubler A, Neumann N, Birbaumer N, Kaiser J. Conditional associative learning examined in a paralyzed patient with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis using brain-computer interface technology. Behav. Brain Funct.. 2008b;4:53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2599893</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19025641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cipresso P., Meriggi P., Carelli L., et al. Cognitive assessment of executive functions using brain computer interface and eye-tracking. ICST Transactions on Ambient Systems. 2013;13(01&#x2013;06)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poletti B., Carelli L., Solca F., et al. Cognitive assessment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis by means of P300-brain computer Interface: a preliminary study. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis and Frontotemporal Degeneration. 2016;17(7&#x2013;8):473&#x2013;481.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27169693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pasqualotto E., Matuz T., Federici S., Ruf C.A., Bartl M., Belardinelli M.O., Birbaumer N., Halder S. Usability and workload of access Technology for People with Severe Motor Impairment: a comparison of brain-computer interfacing and eye tracking. Neurorehabil. Neural Repair. 2015;29(10):950&#x2013;957.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25753951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xe4;thner I., Andrea K&#xfc;bler A., Sebastian Halder S. Comparison of eye tracking, electrooculography and an auditory brain-computer interface for binary communication: a case study with a participant in the locked-in state. J Neuroeng Rehabil. 2015;12</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4560087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26338101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>King C.-H., Chen T.L., Fan Z., Glass J.D., Kemp C.C. Dusty: an assistive Mobile manipulator that retrieves dropped objects for people with motor impairments. Disabil Rehabil Assist Technol. 2012;7(2):168&#x2013;179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3296521</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22013888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spataro R., Chella A., Allison B.M., Sorbello R., Guger C., La Bella V. Reaching and Grasping a Glass of Water by Locked-In ALS Patients through a BCI-Controlled Humanoid Robot. Front. Hum. Neurosci. 2017;11:68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5331030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28298888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elliott M.A., Malvar H., Maassel L.L., Campbell J., Sophy N., Rifley J., M2 | Duffield, Crawford J., Cox E.J., Scanlan J.M. Eye-controlled, power wheelchair performs well for ALS patients. Muscle Nerve. 2019;60(5):513&#x2013;519.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6851551</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31397910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H., Chang B.-C., Andrews J., Mitsumoto H., Agrawal S. A robotic neck brace to characterize head-neck motion and muscle electromyography in subjects with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann. Clin. Transl. Neurol. 2019;6(9):1671&#x2013;1680.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6764623</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31392848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simmatis L., Atallah G., Scott S.H., Taylor S. The feasibility of using robotic Technology to quantify sensory, motor, and cognitive impairments associated with ALS. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2019;20(1&#x2013;2):43&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30688092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Portaro S., Cimino V., Accorinti M., Pidal&#xe0; A., Naro A., Calabr&#xf2; R.S. A promising tool for flail arm in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis rehabilitation: a case report. Eur J Phys Rehabil Med. 2019;55(4):515&#x2013;518.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29904049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>https://www.eanpages.org/2020/04/15/amyotrophic-lateral-sclerosis-and-covid-19-recommendations-to-patients-and-caregivers/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calabr&#xf2; R.S., Cacciola A., Bert&#xe8; F., et al. Robotic gait rehabilitation and substitution devices in neurological disorders: where are we now? Neurol. Sci. 2016;37(4):503&#x2013;514.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26781943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bertani R., Melegari C., De Cola M.C., et al. Effects of robot-assisted upper limb rehabilitation in stroke patients: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Neurol. Sci. 2017;38:1561&#x2013;1569.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28540536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calabr&#xf2; R.S., Naro A., Russo M., et al. The role of virtual reality in improving motor performance as revealed by EEG: a randomized clinical trial. J Neuroeng Rehabil. 2017;14</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5463350</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28592282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Massetti T., da Silva T.D., Crocetta T.B., Guarnieri R., de Freitas B.L., Lopes P.B., Watson S., Tonks J., de Mello Monteiro C.B. The clinical utility if virtual reality in Neurorehabilitation: a systematic review. J Cent Nerv Syst Dis. 2018;10 1179573518813541.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6262495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30515028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grollemund V., Pradat P.-F., Querin G., Delbot F., Le Chat G., Pradat-Peyre J.-F., Bede P. Machine learning in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: achievements, pitfalls, and future directions. Front. Neurosci. 2019;13:135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6403867</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30872992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum J.M., Stambler N., Malta E., Fuller C., Hilt D., Thurmond B., Nakanishi A. The ALSFRS-R: A revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function.BDNF ALS study group (phase III) Neurol. Sci. 1999;169(1&#x2013;2):13&#x2013;21. 31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10540002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roche J.C., Rojas-Garcia R., Scott K.M., Scotton W., Ellis C.E., Burman R., Wijesekera L., Turner M.R., Nigel Leigh P., Shaw C.E., Al-Chalabi A. A proposed staging system for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain. 2012;135(3):847&#x2013;852.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3286327</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22271664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chio A., Hammond E.R., Mora G., Bonito V., Filippini G. Development and evaluation of a clinical staging system for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J. Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatry. 2015;86:38&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24336810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/en/ALL/?uri=CELEX%3A31995L0046</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/PDF/?uri=CELEX:32016R0679</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>https://gdpr-info.eu</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Directive 2011/24/EU of the European Parliament and of the Council of 9 March 2011 on the application of patients&#x2019; rights in cross-border healthcare (OJ L) 88, 42011, 45).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>https://www.eu2020.de/blob/2360248/978a43ce17c65efa8f506c2a484c8f2c/pdf-programm-en-data.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#x2019;Acquisto G., Mazzoccoli A., Ciminelli F., Naldi M. Privacy through Data Recolouring. Proceedings of the Annual Privacy Forum. 2020</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poletti B1, Carelli L, Lunetta C, Ticozzi N, Silani V. Advance care planning and mental capacity in ALS: a current challenge for an unsolved matter. Neurol. Sci. (epub ahead of print)).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32435995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>