<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">32896088</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1522-2586</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>53</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of magnetic resonance imaging : JMRI</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Magn Reson Imaging</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Neural Correlates of Motor Imagery of Gait in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>223</StartPage><EndPage>233</EndPage><MedlinePgn>223-233</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jmri.27335</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Gait impairment is poorly characterized in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS), despite increasing evidence of extrapyramidal and cerebellar dysfunction. Gait impairment adds to the considerable motor disability of ALS patients and requires targeted multidisciplinary interventions.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE">To assess gait imagery-specific networks and functional adaptation in ALS.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="STUDY TYPE">Prospective.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="POPULATION">Seventeen ALS patients with lower motor neuron predominant (LMNp) disability, 14 patients with upper motor neurons predominant (UMNp) disease, and 14 healthy controls were included.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="FIELD STRENGTH/SEQUENCES">3T / gradient echo echo planar (GE-EPI).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="ASSESSMENT">Subjects performed a dual motor imagery task: normal and precision gait. The Movement Imagery Questionnaire - Revised Second Version (MIQ-rs) was used to appraise movement imagery in each participant. Study group-specific activation patterns were evaluated during motor imagery of gait. Additional generalized psychophysiological interaction analyses were carried out using the supplementary motor area, caudate, cerebellum, and superior parietal lobule as seed regions.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="STATISTICAL TESTS">Repeated-measures analysis of variance (ANOVA) was used to compare time imagery and MIQ-rs scores between groups. Size effects were also reported as partial eta squared (&#x3b7;2). One-way ANOVA was performed to explore differences in terms of connexions during motor imagery tasks.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">A significant increase in imagery time in UMNp patients compared to controls (P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05) and LMNp (P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05) during imagined gait was demonstrated. UMNp patients exhibited altered supplementary motor area, precentral gyrus, superior parietal lobule, and dorsolateral prefrontal cortex activation and increased orbitofrontal (pFDR<sub>(False Discovery Rate)</sub> &#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05), posterior parietal (pFDR&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05) caudate (pFDR&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05), and cerebellar (pFDR&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05) signal during imagined locomotion. Increased effective connectivity of the striato-cerebellar and parieto-cerebellar circuits was also demonstrated. Additional activation was detected in the insula and cingulate cortex.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DATA CONCLUSION">Enhanced striato- and parieto-cerebellar networks in UMNp ALS patients are likely to represent a compensatory response to impaired postural control.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="LEVEL OF EVIDENCE">2 TECHNICAL EFFICACY STAGE: 5.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020 International Society for Magnetic Resonance in Medicine.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Abidi</LastName><ForeName>Malek</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0833-4323</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>LINP2-AAPS Laboratory, UPL, Paris Nanterre University, Nanterre, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>de Marco</LastName><ForeName>Giovanni</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1469-1044</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>LINP2-AAPS Laboratory, UPL, Paris Nanterre University, Nanterre, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>COMUE Paris Lumi&#xe8;res University, Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Grami</LastName><ForeName>Fatma</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>LINP2-AAPS Laboratory, UPL, Paris Nanterre University, Nanterre, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Termoz</LastName><ForeName>Nicolas</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>LINP2-AAPS Laboratory, UPL, Paris Nanterre University, Nanterre, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>COMUE Paris Lumi&#xe8;res University, Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Couillandre</LastName><ForeName>Annabelle</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>LINP2-AAPS Laboratory, UPL, Paris Nanterre University, Nanterre, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>COMUE Paris Lumi&#xe8;res University, Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Querin</LastName><ForeName>Giorgia</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Piti&#xe9;-Salp&#xea;tri&#xe8;re University Hospital, Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biomedical Imaging Laboratory, Sorbonne University, CNRS, INSERM, Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bede</LastName><ForeName>Peter</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Piti&#xe9;-Salp&#xea;tri&#xe8;re University Hospital, Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biomedical Imaging Laboratory, Sorbonne University, CNRS, INSERM, Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Computational Neuroimaging Group, Trinity College Dublin, Dublin, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pradat</LastName><ForeName>Pierre-Francois</ForeName><Initials>PF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Piti&#xe9;-Salp&#xea;tri&#xe8;re University Hospital, Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biomedical Imaging Laboratory, Sorbonne University, CNRS, INSERM, Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biomedical Sciences Research Institute, Northern Ireland Centre for Stratified Medicine, Ulster University, Londonderry, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>INSERM</Agency><Country>International</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>ANR-10-IAIHU-06</GrantID><Agency>Irish Institute of Clinical Neuroscience (IICN)</Agency><Country>International</Country></Grant><Grant><Agency>the Iris O'Brien Foundation</Agency><Country>International</Country></Grant><Grant><Agency>Andrew Lydon scholarship, the Irish Institute of Clinical Neuroscience (IICN)</Agency><Country>International</Country></Grant><Grant><Agency>EU Joint Programme - Neurodegenerative Disease Research (JPND)</Agency><Country>International</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>HRB EIA-2017-019</GrantID><Agency>the Health Research Board</Agency><Country>International</Country></Grant><Grant><Agency>Spastic Paraplegia Foundation (SPF)</Agency><Country>International</Country></Grant><Grant><Agency>Institut National pour la Sant&#xe9; et la Recherche M&#xe9;dicale (INSERM).</Agency><Country>International</Country></Grant><Grant><Agency>Association for Research on ALS (ARSLA)</Agency><Country>International</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>EIA-2017-019</GrantID><Agency>Health Research Board</Agency><Country>Ireland</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Magn Reson Imaging</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9105850</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1053-1807</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001931" MajorTopicYN="N">Brain Mapping</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006233" MajorTopicYN="Y">Disabled Persons</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005684" MajorTopicYN="N">Gait</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008279" MajorTopicYN="N">Magnetic Resonance Imaging</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000068079" MajorTopicYN="Y">Motor Disorders</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011446" MajorTopicYN="N">Prospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32896088</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmri.27335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Chipika RH, Finegan E, Li Hi Shing S, Hardiman O, Bede P. Tracking a fast-moving disease: Longitudinal markers, monitoring, and clinical trial endpoints in ALS. Front Neurol 2019;10:229.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bede P, Omer T, Finegan E, et al. Connectivity-based characterisation of subcortical grey matter pathology in frontotemporal dementia and ALS: A multimodal neuroimaging study. Brain Imaging Behav 2018;12(6):1696-1707.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bede P, Elamin M, Byrne S, et al. Patterns of cerebral and cerebellar white matter degeneration in ALS. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2015;86(4):468-470.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lechtzin N. Respiratory effects of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Problems and solutions. Respir Care 2006;51(8):871-881. discussion 881-4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke T, Pinto-Grau M, Lonergan K, et al. Measurement of social cognition in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A population based study. PLoS One 2016;11(8):e0160850.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elamin M, Pinto-Grau M, Burke T, et al. Identifying behavioral changes in ALS: Validation of the Beaumont Behavioral Inventory (BBI). Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2017;18(1-2):68-73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feron M, Couillandre A, Mseddi E, et al. Extrapyramidal deficits in ALS: A combined biomechanical and neuroimaging study. J Neurol 2018;265(9):2125-2136.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olney RK, Murphy J, Forshew D, et al. The effects of executive and behavioral dysfunction on the course of ALS. Neurology 2005;65(11):1774-1777.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desai J, Swash M. Extrapyramidal involvement in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Backward falls and retropulsion. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 1999;67(2):214-216.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D'Ascenzo C, Cecchin D, Santelli L, et al. Parkinson-like features in ALS with predominant upper motor neuron involvement. Amyotroph Lateral Scler 2012;13(1):137-143.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pradat PF, Bruneteau G, Munerati E, et al. Extrapyramidal stiffness in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Mov Disord 2009;24(14):2143-2148.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jahn K, Deutschl&#xe4;nder A, Stephan T, et al. Imaging human supraspinal locomotor centers in brainstem and cerebellum. Neuroimage 2008;39(2):786-792.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>la Fougere C, Zwergal A, Rominger A, et al. Real versus imagined locomotion: A [18F]-FDG PET-fMRI comparison. Neuroimage 2010;50(4):1589-1598.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lotze M, Halsband U. Motor imagery. J Physiol Paris 2006;99(4-6):386-395.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeannerod M. Neural simulation of action: A unifying mechanism for motor cognition. Neuroimage 2001;14(1) Pt 2:S103-S109.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lule D, Diekmann V, Kassubek J, et al. Cortical plasticity in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Motor imagery and function. Neurorehabil Neural Repair 2007;21(6):518-526.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alkadhi H, Brugger P, Boendermaker SH, et al. What disconnection tells about motor imagery: Evidence from paraplegic patients. Cereb Cortex 2005;15(2):131-140.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakker M, De Lange FP, Helmich RC, Scheeringa R, Bloem BR, Toni I. Cerebral correlates of motor imagery of normal and precision gait. Neuroimage 2008;41(3):998-1010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simon NG, Lin CSY, Lee M, et al. Segmental motoneuronal dysfunction is a feature of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Neurophysiol 2015;126(4):828-836.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaufmann P, Pullman SL, Shungu DC, et al. Objective tests for upper motor neuron involvement in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). Neurology 2004;62(10):1753-1757.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, Miller RG, Swash M, Munsat TL. El Escorial revisited: Revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord 2000;1(5):293-299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rascovsky K, Hodges JR, Knopman D, et al. Sensitivity of revised diagnostic criteria for the behavioral variant of frontotemporal dementia. Brain 2011;134(Pt 9):2456-2477.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum JM, Stambler N, Malta E, et al. The ALSFRS-R: A revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. BDNF ALS study group (phase III). J Neurol Sci 1999;169(1-2):13-21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loison B, Moussaddaq A-S, Cormier J, et al. Translation and validation of the French movement imagery questionnaire - Revised second version (MIQ-RS). Ann Phys Rehabil Med 2013;56(3):157-173.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitfield-Gabrieli S, Nieto-Castanon A. Conn: A functional connectivity toolbox for correlated and anticorrelated brain networks. Brain Connect 2012;2(3):125-141.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLaren DG, Ries ML, Xu G, Johnson SC. A generalized form of context-dependent psychophysiological interactions (gPPI): A comparison to standard approaches. Neuroimage 2012;61(4):1277-1286.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nijssen J, Comley LH, Hedlund E. Motor neuron vulnerability and resistance in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathol 2017;133(6):863-885.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ragagnin AMG, Shadfar S, Vidal M, Jamali MS, Atkin JD. Motor neuron susceptibility in ALS/FTD. Front Neurosci 2019;13:532.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chou SM, Norris FH. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Lower motor neuron disease spreading to upper motor neurons. Muscle Nerve 1993;16(8):864-869.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner MR, Eisen A, Kiernan MC, Ravits J, Swash M. Kinnier Wilson's puzzling features of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2018;89(6):657-666.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakagawa K, Kawashima S, Mizuguchi N, Kanosue K. Difference in activity in the supplementary motor area depending on limb combination of hand-foot coordinated movements. Front Hum Neurosci 2016;10:499.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nutt JG, Marsden CD, Thompson PD. Human walking and higher-level gait disorders, particularly in the elderly. Neurology 1993;43(2):268-279.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cavanna AE, Trimble MR. The precuneus: A review of its functional anatomy and behavioral correlates. Brain 2006;129(Pt 3):564-583.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Labriffe M, Annweiler C, Amirova L, et al. Brain activity during mental imagery of gait versus gait-like plantar stimulation: A novel combined functional MRI paradigm to better understand cerebral gait control. Front Hum Neurosci 2017;11:106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goel R, Nakagome S, Rao N, Paloski WH, Contreras-Vidal JL, Parikh PJ. Fronto-parietal brain areas contribute to the online control of posture during a continuous balance task. Neuroscience 2019;413:135-153.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blakemore SJ, Sirigu A. Action prediction in the cerebellum and in the parietal lobe. Exp Brain Res 2003;153(2):239-245.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hollands MA, Marple-Horvat DE. Visually guided stepping under conditions of step cycle-related denial of visual information. Exp Brain Res 1996;109(2):343-356.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Price DD. Psychological and neural mechanisms of the affective dimension of pain. Science 2000;288(5472):1769-1772.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Z, Jackson T, Huang C. Neural activation during anticipation of near pain-threshold stimulation among the pain-fearful. Front Neurosci 2016;10:342.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schell WE, Mar VS, Da Silva CP. Correlation of falls in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with objective measures of balance, strength, and spasticity. NeuroRehabilitation 2019;44(1):85-93.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>