<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">32890771</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>12</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1095-953X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>145</Volume><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Neurobiology of disease</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Neurobiol Dis</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Neuroimaging in genetic frontotemporal dementia and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>105063</StartPage><MedlinePgn>105063</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.nbd.2020.105063</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0969-9961(20)30338-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Frontotemporal dementia (FTD) and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) have a strong clinical, genetic and pathological overlap. This review focuses on the current understanding of structural, functional and molecular neuroimaging signatures of genetic FTD and ALS. We overview quantitative neuroimaging studies on the most common genes associated with FTD (MAPT, GRN), ALS (SOD1), and both (C9orf72), and summarize visual observations of images reported in the rarer genes (CHMP2B, TARDBP, FUS, OPTN, VCP, UBQLN2, SQSTM1, TREM2, CHCHD10, TBK1).</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2020 The Authors. Published by Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>H&#xe4;kkinen</LastName><ForeName>Suvi</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Memory and Aging Center, Department of Neurology, University of California, San Francisco, San Francisco, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chu</LastName><ForeName>Stephanie A</ForeName><Initials>SA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Memory and Aging Center, Department of Neurology, University of California, San Francisco, San Francisco, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Suzee E</ForeName><Initials>SE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Memory and Aging Center, Department of Neurology, University of California, San Francisco, San Francisco, CA, USA. Electronic address: suzee.lee@ucsf.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R01 AG058233</GrantID><Acronym>AG</Acronym><Agency>NIA NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Neurobiol Dis</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9500169</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0969-9961</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="Y">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057180" MajorTopicYN="N">Frontotemporal Dementia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="Y">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D059906" MajorTopicYN="N">Neuroimaging</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Frontotemporal dementia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Genetics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Motor neuron disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neuroimaging</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Presymptomatic</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of Competing Interest None.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>8</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32890771</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS1628089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7572920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nbd.2020.105063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0969-9961(20)30338-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abidi M, de Marco G, Couillandre A, Feron M, Mseddi E, Termoz N, Querin G, Pradat P, Bede P, 2019. Adaptive functional reorganisation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: coexisting degenerative and compensatory changes. Eur J Neurol. doi:10.1111/ene.14042</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ene.14042</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31310452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abramzon Y, Johnson JO, Scholz SW, Taylor JP, Brunetti M, Calvo A, Mandrioli J, Benatar M, Mora G, Restagno G, Chi&#xf2; A, Traynor BJ, 2012. Valosin-containing protein (VCP) mutations in sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurobiol Aging 33, 2231.e1&#x2013;2231.e6. doi:10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2012.04.005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2012.04.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3391327</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22572540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aggarwal A, Nicholson G, 2005. Age-dependent penetrance of three different superoxide dismutase 1 (SOD1) mutations. Int J Neurosci 115, 1119&#x2013;1130. doi:10.1080/00207450590914392</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00207450590914392</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16040355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agosta F, Canu E, Valsasina P, Riva N, Prelle A, Comi G, Filippi M, 2013. Divergent brain network connectivity in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurobiol Aging 34, 419&#x2013;427. doi:10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2012.04.015</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2012.04.015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22608240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agosta F, Ferraro PM, Riva N, Spinelli EG, Chi&#xf2; A, Canu E, Valsasina P, Lunetta C, Iannaccone S, Copetti M, Prudente E, Comi G, Falini A, Filippi M, 2016. Structural brain correlates of cognitive and behavioral impairment in MND. Hum Brain Mapp 37, 1614&#x2013;1626. doi:10.1002/hbm.23124</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hbm.23124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6867462</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26833930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agosta F, Ferraro PM, Riva N, Spinelli EG, Domi T, Carrera P, Copetti M, Falzone Y, Ferrari M, Lunetta C, Comi G, Falini A, Quattrini A, Filippi M, 2017. Structural and functional brain signatures of C9orf72 in motor neuron disease. Neurobiol Aging 57, 206&#x2013;219. doi:10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2017.05.024</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2017.05.024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28666709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agosta F, Galantucci S, Magnani G, Marcone A, Martinelli D, Antonietta Volont&#xe8; M, Riva N, Iannaccone S, Ferraro PM, Caso F, Chi&#xf2; A, Comi G, Falini A, Filippi M, 2015. MRI signatures of the frontotemporal lobar degeneration continuum. Hum Brain Mapp 36, 2602&#x2013;2614. doi:10.1002/hbm.22794</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hbm.22794</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6869605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25821176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agosta F, Galantucci S, Riva N, Chi&#xf2; A, Messina S, Iannaccone S, Calvo A, Silani V, Copetti M, Falini A, Comi G, Filippi M, 2014a. Intrahemispheric and interhemispheric structural network abnormalities in PLS and ALS. Hum Brain Mapp 35, 1710&#x2013;1722. doi:10.1002/hbm.22286</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hbm.22286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6869498</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23633431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agosta F, Galantucci S, Valsasina P, Canu E, Meani A, Marcone A, Magnani G, Falini A, Comi G, Filippi M, 2014b. Disrupted brain connectome in semantic variant of primary progressive aphasia. Neurobiol Aging 35, 2646&#x2013;2655. doi:10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2014.05.017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2014.05.017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24970567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agosta F, Rocca MA, Valsasina P, Sala S, Caputo D, Perini M, Salvi F, Prelle A, Filippi M, 2009. A longitudinal diffusion tensor MRI study of the cervical cord and brain in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 80, 53&#x2013;55. doi:10.1136/jnnp.2008.154252</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp.2008.154252</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18931009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agosta F, Scola E, Canu E, Marcone A, Magnani G, Sarro L, Copetti M, Caso F, Cerami C, Comi G, Cappa SF, Falini A, Filippi M, 2012. White matter damage in frontotemporal lobar degeneration spectrum. Cereb Cortex 22, 2705&#x2013;2714. doi:10.1093/cercor/bhr288</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cercor/bhr288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21988828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agosta F, Spinelli E, Ghirelli A, Riva N, Magnani G, Caso F, Caroppo P, Prioni S, Tremolizzo L, Appollonio I, Silani V, Carrera P, Filippi M, 2020. Deep grey matter and hippocampal involvement in genetic cases of frontotemporal lobar degeneration (1508). Neurology 94, 1508.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agosta F, Spinelli EG, Marjanovic IV, Stevic Z, Pagani E, Valsasina P, Salak-Djokic B, Jankovic M, Lavrnic D, Kostic VS, Filippi M, 2018. Unraveling ALS due to SOD1 mutation through the combination of brain and cervical cord MRI. Neurology 90, e707&#x2013;e716. doi:10.1212/WNL.0000000000005002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000005002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29367447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ajroud-Driss S, Fecto F, Ajroud K, Lalani I, Calvo SE, Mootha VK, Deng H-X, Siddique N, Tahmoush AJ, Heiman-Patterson TD, Siddique T, 2015. Mutation in the novel nuclear-encoded mitochondrial protein CHCHD10 in a family with autosomal dominant mitochondrial myopathy. Neurogenetics 16, 1&#x2013;9. doi:10.1007/s10048-014-0421-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10048-014-0421-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4796476</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25193783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akiyama T, Warita H, Kato M, Nishiyama A, Izumi R, Ikeda C, Kamada M, Suzuki N, Aoki M, 2016. Genotype-phenotype relationships in familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with FUS/TLS mutations in Japan: FUS/TLS linked FALS in Japan. Muscle Nerve 54, 398&#x2013;404. doi:10.1002/mus.25061</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.25061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26823199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Albagha OME, Visconti MR, Alonso N, Langston AL, Cundy T, Dargie R, Dunlop MG, Fraser WD, Hooper MJ, Isaia G, Nicholson GC, del Pino Montes J, Gonzalez-Sarmiento R, di Stefano M, Tenesa A, Walsh JP, Ralston SH, 2010. Genome-wide association study identifies variants at CSF1, OPTN and TNFRSF11A as genetic risk factors for Paget&#x2019;s disease of bone. Nat Genet 42, 520&#x2013;524. doi:10.1038/ng.562</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ng.562</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3217192</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20436471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alexander C, Pisner D, Jacova C, 2019. Predementia brain changes in progranulin mutation: a systematic review of neuroimaging evidence. Dement Geriatr Cogn Disord 47, 1&#x2013;18. doi:10.1159/000494968</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000494968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30630176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alexander C, Zeithamova D, Hsiung G-YR, Mackenzie IR, Jacova C, 2018. Decreased prefrontal activation during matrix reasoning in predementia progranulin mutation carriers. J Alzheimers Dis 62, 583&#x2013;589. doi:10.3233/JAD-170716</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/JAD-170716</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29480174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Obeidi E, Al-Tahan S, Surampalli A, Goyal N, Wang AK, Hermann A, Omizo M, Smith C, Mozaffar T, Kimonis V, 2018. Genotype-phenotype study in patients with valosin-containing protein mutations associated with multisystem proteinopathy. Clin Genet 93, 119&#x2013;125. doi:10.1111/cge.13095</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cge.13095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5739971</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28692196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ameur F, Colliot O, Caroppo P, Str&#xf6;er S, Dormont D, Brice A, Azuar C, Dubois B, Le Ber I, Bertrand A, 2016. White matter lesions in FTLD: distinct phenotypes characterize GRN and C9ORF72 mutations. Neurol Genet 2, e47. doi:10.1212/NXG.0000000000000047</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/NXG.0000000000000047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4817905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27066584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen PM, Forsgren L, Binzer M, Nilsson P, Ala-Hurula V, Keranen ML, Bergmark L, Saarinen A, Haltia T, Tarvainen I, Kinnunen E, Udd B, Marklund SL, 1996. Autosomal recessive adult-onset amyotrophic lateral sclerosis associated with homozygosity for Asp90Ala CuZn-superoxide dismutase mutation. A clinical and genealogical study of 36 patients. Brain 119 ( Pt 4), 1153&#x2013;1172. doi:10.1093/brain/119.4.1153</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/119.4.1153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8813280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anor CJ, Xi Z, Zhang M, Moreno D, Sato C, Rogaeva E, Tartaglia MC, 2015. Mutation analysis of C9orf72 in patients with corticobasal syndrome. Neurobiol Aging 36, 2905.e1&#x2013;2905.e5. doi:10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2015.06.008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2015.06.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26166205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arvanitakis Z, Witte RJ, Dickson DW, Tsuboi Y, Uitti RJ, Slowinski J, Hutton ML, Lin S-C, Boeve BF, Cheshire WP, Pooley RA, Liss JM, Caviness JN, Strongosky AJ, Wszolek ZK, 2007. Clinical-pathologic study of biomarkers in FTDP-17 (PPND family with N279K tau mutation). Parkinsonism Relat Disord 13, 230&#x2013;239. doi:10.1016/j.parkreldis.2006.10.007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.parkreldis.2006.10.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17196872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atassi N, Xu M, Triantafyllou C, Keil B, Lawson R, Cernasov P, Ratti E, Long CJ, Paganoni S, Murphy A, Salibi N, Seethamraju R, Rosen B, Ratai E-M, 2017. Ultra high-field (7tesla) magnetic resonance spectroscopy in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. PLoS One 12, e0177680. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0177680</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0177680</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5428977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28498852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker M, Mackenzie IR, Pickering-Brown SM, Gass J, Rademakers R, Lindholm C, Snowden J, Adamson J, Sadovnick AD, Rollinson S, Cannon A, Dwosh E, Neary D, Melquist S, Richardson A, Dickson D, Berger Z, Eriksen J, Robinson T, Zehr C, Dickey CA, Crook R, McGowan E, Mann D, Boeve B, Feldman H, Hutton M, 2006. Mutations in progranulin cause tau-negative frontotemporal dementia linked to chromosome 17. Nature 442, 916&#x2013;919. doi:10.1038/nature05016</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nature05016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16862116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bannwarth S, Ait-El-Mkadem S, Chaussenot A, Genin EC, Lacas-Gervais S, Fragaki K, Berg-Alonso L, Kageyama Y, Serre V, Moore DG, Verschueren A, Rouzier C, Le Ber I, Aug&#xe9; G, Cochaud C, Lespinasse F, N&#x2019;Guyen K, de Septenville A, Brice A, Yu-Wai-Man P, Sesaki H, Pouget J, Paquis-Flucklinger V, 2014. A mitochondrial origin for frontotemporal dementia and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis through CHCHD10 involvement. Brain 137, 2329&#x2013;2345. doi:10.1093/brain/awu138</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awu138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4107737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24934289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Battistella G, Borghesani V, Henry M, Shwe W, Lauricella M, Miller Z, Deleon J, Miller BL, Dronkers N, Brambati SM, Seeley WW, Mandelli ML, Gorno-Tempini ML, 2020. Task-free functional language networks: reproducibility and clinical application. J Neurosci 40, 1311&#x2013;1320. doi:10.1523/JNEUROSCI.1485-19.2019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1523/JNEUROSCI.1485-19.2019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7002153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31852732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beck J, Rohrer JD, Campbell T, Isaacs A, Morrison KE, Goodall EF, Warrington EK, Stevens J, Revesz T, Holton J, Al-Sarraj S, King A, Scahill R, Warren JD, Fox NC, Rossor MN, Collinge J, Mead S, 2008. A distinct clinical, neuropsychological and radiological phenotype is associated with progranulin gene mutations in a large UK series. Brain 131, 706&#x2013;720. doi:10.1093/brain/awm320</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awm320</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2577762</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18234697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bede P, Bokde A, Elamin M, Byrne S, McLaughlin RL, Jordan N, Hampel H, Gallagher L, Lynch C, Fagan AJ, Pender N, Hardiman O, 2013a. Grey matter correlates of clinical variables in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS): a neuroimaging study of ALS motor phenotype heterogeneity and cortical focality. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 84, 766&#x2013;773. doi:10.1136/jnnp-2012-302674</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp-2012-302674</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23085933</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bede P, Bokde ALW, Byrne S, Elamin M, McLaughlin RL, Kenna K, Fagan AJ, Pender N, Bradley DG, Hardiman O, 2013b. Multiparametric MRI study of ALS stratified for the C9orf72 genotype. Neurology 81, 361&#x2013;369. doi:10.1212/WNL.0b013e31829c5eee</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0b013e31829c5eee</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3772833</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23771489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bede P, Elamin M, Byrne S, McLaughlin RL, Kenna K, Vajda A, Pender N, Bradley DG, Hardiman O, 2013c. Basal ganglia involvement in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology 81, 2107&#x2013;2115. doi:10.1212/01.wnl.0000437313.80913.2c</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/01.wnl.0000437313.80913.2c</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24212388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bede P, Hardiman O, 2018. Longitudinal structural changes in ALS: a three time-point imaging study of white and gray matter degeneration. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 19, 232&#x2013;241. doi:10.1080/21678421.2017.1407795</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/21678421.2017.1407795</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29214883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bede P, Omer T, Finegan E, Chipika RH, Iyer PM, Doherty MA, Vajda A, Pender N, McLaughlin RL, Hutchinson S, Hardiman O, 2018. Connectivity-based characterisation of subcortical grey matter pathology in frontotemporal dementia and ALS: a multimodal neuroimaging study. Brain Imaging Behav 12, 1696&#x2013;1707. doi:10.1007/s11682-018-9837-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11682-018-9837-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29423814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belzil VV, Daoud H, Desjarlais A, Bouchard J-P, Dupr&#xe9; N, Camu W, Dion PA, Rouleau GA, 2011. Analysis of OPTN as a causative gene for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurobiol Aging 32, 555.e13&#x2013;555.e14. doi:10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2010.10.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2010.10.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21074290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benajiba L, Le Ber I, Camuzat A, Lacoste M, Thomas-Anterion C, Couratier P, Legallic S, Salachas F, Hannequin D, Decousus M, Lacomblez L, Guedj E, Golfier V, Camu W, Dubois B, Campion D, Meininger V, Brice A, French Clinical and Genetic Research Network on Frontotemporal Lobar Degeneration/Frontotemporal Lobar Degeneration with Motoneuron Disease, 2009. TARDBP mutations in motoneuron disease with frontotemporal lobar degeneration. Ann Neurol 65, 470&#x2013;473. doi:10.1002/ana.21612</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.21612</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19350673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benussi A, Gazzina S, Premi E, Cosseddu M, Archetti S, Dell&#x2019;Era V, Cantoni V, Cotelli MS, Alberici A, Micheli A, Benussi L, Ghidoni R, Padovani A, Borroni B, 2019. Clinical and biomarker changes in presymptomatic genetic frontotemporal dementia. Neurobiol Aging 76, 133&#x2013;140. doi:10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2018.12.018</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2018.12.018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30711676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ber IL, Guedj E, Gabelle A, Verpillat P, Volteau M, Thomas-Anterion C, Decousus M, Hannequin D, Vera P, Lacomblez L, Camuzat A, Didic M, Puel M, Lotterie JA, Golfier V, Bernard A-M, Vercelletto M, Magne C, Sellal F, Namer I, Michel BF, Pasquier J, Salachas F, Bochet J, Brice A, Habert MO, Dubois B, 2006. Demographic, neurological and behavioural characteristics and brain perfusion SPECT in frontal variant of frontotemporal dementia. Brain 129, 3051&#x2013;3065. doi:10.1093/brain/awl288</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awl288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17071924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bertrand A, Wen J, Rinaldi D, Houot M, Sayah S, Camuzat A, Fournier C, Fontanella S, Routier A, Couratier P, Pasquier F, Habert M-O, Hannequin D, Martinaud O, Caroppo P, Levy R, Dubois B, Brice A, Durrleman S, Colliot O, Le Ber I, for the Predict to Prevent Frontotemporal Lobar Degeneration and Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis (PREV-DEMALS) Study Group, 2018. Early cognitive, structural, and microstructural changes in presymptomatic C9orf72 carriers younger than 40 years. JAMA Neurol 75, 236. doi:10.1001/jamaneurol.2017.4266</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamaneurol.2017.4266</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5838615</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29197216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bevan-Jones WR, Cope TE, Jones PS, Passamonti L, Hong YT, Fryer T, Arnold R, Coles JP, Aigbirhio FI, O&#x2019;Brien JT, Rowe JB, 2019. In vivo evidence for presymptomatic neuroinflammation in a MAPT mutation carrier. Ann Clin Transl Neurol 6, 373&#x2013;378. doi:10.1002/acn3.683</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/acn3.683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6389753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30847369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blain CRV, Brunton S, Williams VC, Leemans A, Turner MR, Andersen PM, Catani M, Stanton BR, Ganesalingham J, Jones DK, Williams SCR, Leigh PN, Simmons A, 2011. Differential corticospinal tract degeneration in homozygous &#x201c;D90A&#x201d; SOD-1 ALS and sporadic ALS. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 82, 843&#x2013;849. doi:10.1136/jnnp.2010.236018</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp.2010.236018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3134064</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21515558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blair IP, Williams KL, Warraich ST, Durnall JC, Thoeng AD, Manavis J, Blumbergs PC, Vucic S, Kiernan MC, Nicholson GA, 2010. FUS mutations in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: clinical, pathological, neurophysiological and genetic analysis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 81, 639&#x2013;645. doi:10.1136/jnnp.2009.194399</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp.2009.194399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19965854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bocchetta M, Iglesias JE, Neason M, Cash DM, Warren JD, Rohrer JD, 2020. Thalamic nuclei in frontotemporal dementia: Mediodorsal nucleus involvement is universal but pulvinar atrophy is unique to C9orf72. Hum Brain Mapp 41, 1006&#x2013;1016. doi:10.1002/hbm.24856</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hbm.24856</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7267940</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31696638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boeve BF, 2005. Longitudinal characterization of two siblings with frontotemporal dementia and parkinsonism linked to chromosome 17 associated with the S305N tau mutation. Brain 128, 752&#x2013;772. doi:10.1093/brain/awh356</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awh356</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15615814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boeve BF, Boylan KB, Graff-Radford NR, DeJesus-Hernandez M, Knopman DS, Pedraza O, Vemuri P, Jones D, Lowe V, Murray ME, Dickson DW, Josephs KA, Rush BK, Machulda MM, Fields JA, Ferman TJ, Baker M, Rutherford NJ, Adamson J, Wszolek ZK, Adeli A, Savica R, Boot B, Kuntz KM, Gavrilova R, Reeves A, Whitwell J, Kantarci K, Jack CR, Parisi JE, Lucas JA, Petersen RC, Rademakers R, 2012. Characterization of frontotemporal dementia and/or amyotrophic lateral sclerosis associated with the GGGGCC repeat expansion in C9ORF72. Brain 135, 765&#x2013;783. doi:10.1093/brain/aws004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/aws004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3286335</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22366793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borghero G, Floris G, Cannas A, Marrosu MG, Murru MR, Costantino E, Parish LD, Pugliatti M, Ticca A, Traynor BJ, Calvo A, Cammarosano S, Moglia C, Cistaro A, Brunetti M, Restagno G, Chi&#xf2; A, 2011. A patient carrying a homozygous p.A382T TARDBP missense mutation shows a syndrome including ALS, extrapyramidal symptoms, and FTD. Neurobiol Aging 32, 2327.e1&#x2013;2327.e5. doi:10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2011.06.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2011.06.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3192246</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21803454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borroni B, Alberici A, Cercignani M, Premi E, Serra L, Cerini C, Cosseddu M, Pettenati C, Turla M, Archetti S, Gasparotti R, Caltagirone C, Padovani A, Bozzali M, 2012. Granulin mutation drives brain damage and reorganization from preclinical to symptomatic FTLD. Neurobiol Aging 33, 2506&#x2013;2520. doi:10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2011.10.031</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2011.10.031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22130207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borroni B, Alberici A, Premi E, Archetti S, Garibotto V, Agosti C, Gasparotti R, Di Luca M, Perani D, Padovani A, 2008. Brain magnetic resonance imaging structural changes in a pedigree of asymptomatic progranulin mutation carriers. Rejuvenation Res 11, 585&#x2013;595. doi:10.1089/rej.2007.0623</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/rej.2007.0623</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18593276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borroni B, Bonvicini C, Alberici A, Buratti E, Agosti C, Archetti S, Papetti A, Stuani C, Di Luca M, Gennarelli M, Padovani A, 2009. Mutation within TARDBP leads to frontotemporal dementia without motor neuron disease. Hum Mutat 30, E974&#x2013;E983. doi:10.1002/humu.21100</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/humu.21100</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19655382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borroni B, Ferrari F, Galimberti D, Nacmias B, Barone C, Bagnoli S, Fenoglio C, Piaceri I, Archetti S, Bonvicini C, Gennarelli M, Turla M, Scarpini E, Sorbi S, Padovani A, 2014. Heterozygous TREM2 mutations in frontotemporal dementia. Neurobiol Aging 35, 934.e7&#x2013;-934.e10.. doi:10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2013.09.017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2013.09.017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24139279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boxer AL, Mackenzie IR, Boeve BF, Baker M, Seeley WW, Crook R, Feldman H, Hsiung G-YR, Rutherford N, Laluz V, Whitwell J, Foti D, McDade E, Molano J, Karydas A, Wojtas A, Goldman J, Mirsky J, Sengdy P, DeArmond S, Miller BL, Rademakers R, 2011. Clinical, neuroimaging and neuropathological features of a new chromosome 9p-linked FTD-ALS family. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 82, 196&#x2013;203. doi:10.1136/jnnp.2009.204081</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp.2009.204081</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3017222</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20562461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bozzali M, Battistoni V, Premi E, Alberici A, Giulietti G, Archetti S, Turla M, Gasparotti R, Cercignani M, Padovani A, Borroni B, 2013. Structural brain signature of FTLD driven by Granulin mutation. J Alzheimers Dis 33, 483&#x2013;494. doi:10.3233/JAD-2012-121273</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/JAD-2012-121273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22986778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Broad RJ, Gabel MC, Dowell NG, Schwartzman DJ, Seth AK, Zhang H, Alexander DC, Cercignani M, Leigh PN, 2019. Neurite orientation and dispersion density imaging (NODDI) detects cortical and corticospinal tract degeneration in ALS. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 90, 404&#x2013;411. doi:10.1136/jnnp-2018-318830</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp-2018-318830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6581155</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30361295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Broe M, Hodges JR, Schofield E, Shepherd CE, Kril JJ, Halliday GM, 2003. Staging disease severity in pathologically confirmed cases of frontotemporal dementia. Neurology 60, 1005&#x2013;1011. doi:10.1212/01.WNL.0000052685.09194.39</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/01.WNL.0000052685.09194.39</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12654969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, Miller RG, Swash M, Munsat TL, 2000. El Escorial revisited: Revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord 1, 293&#x2013;299. doi:10.1080/146608200300079536</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/146608200300079536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11464847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Broustal O, Camuzat A, Guillot-Noel L, Guy N, Millecamps S, Deffond D, Lacomblez L, Golfier V, Hannequin D, Salachas F, Camu W, Didic M, Dubois B, Meininger V, Le Ber I, Brice A, French clinical and genetic research network on FTD/FTD-MND., 2010. FUS mutations in frontotemporal lobar degeneration with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Alzheimers Dis 22, 765&#x2013;769.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21158017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buhour M-S, Doidy F, Laisney M, Pitel AL, de La Sayette V, Viader F, Eustache F, Desgranges B, 2017a. Pathophysiology of the behavioral variant of frontotemporal lobar degeneration: a study combining MRI and FDG-PET. Brain Imaging Behav 11, 240&#x2013;252. doi:10.1007/s11682-016-9521-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11682-016-9521-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26852326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buhour M-S, Doidy F, Mondou A, P&#xe9;lerin A, Carluer L, Eustache F, Viader F, Desgranges B, 2017b. Voxel-based mapping of grey matter volume and glucose metabolism profiles in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. EJNMMI Res 7. doi:10.1186/s13550-017-0267-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13550-017-0267-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5339262</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28266002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burrell JR, Kiernan MC, Vucic S, Hodges JR, 2011. Motor Neuron dysfunction in frontotemporal dementia. Brain 134, 2582&#x2013;2594. doi:10.1093/brain/awr195</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awr195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21840887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byrne S, Elamin M, Bede P, Shatunov A, Walsh C, Corr B, Heverin M, Jordan N, Kenna K, Lynch C, McLaughlin RL, Iyer PM, O&#x2019;Brien C, Phukan J, Wynne B, Bokde AL, Bradley DG, Pender N, Al-Chalabi A, Hardiman O, 2012. Cognitive and clinical characteristics of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis carrying a C9orf72 repeat expansion: a population-based cohort study. Lancet Neurol 11, 232&#x2013;240. doi:10.1016/S1474-4422(12)70014-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1474-4422(12)70014-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3315021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22305801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carew JD, Nair G, Andersen PM, Wuu J, Gronka S, Hu X, Benatar M, 2011a. Presymptomatic spinal cord neurometabolic findings in SOD1-positive people at risk for familial ALS. Neurology 77, 1370&#x2013;1375. doi:10.1212/WNL.0b013e318231526a</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0b013e318231526a</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3182757</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21940617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carew JD, Nair G, Pineda-Alonso N, Usher S, Hu X, Benatar M, 2011b. Magnetic resonance spectroscopy of the cervical cord in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler 12, 185&#x2013;191. doi:10.3109/17482968.2010.515223</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/17482968.2010.515223</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21143004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caroppo P, Camuzat A, De Septenville A, Couratier P, Lacomblez L, Auriacombe S, Flabeau O, Jorn&#xe9;a L, Blanc F, Sellal F, Cretin B, Meininger V, Fleury M-C, Couarch P, Dubois B, Brice A, Le Ber I, 2015a. Semantic and nonfluent aphasic variants, secondarily associated with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, are predominant frontotemporal lobar degeneration phenotypes in TBK1 carriers. Alzheimers Dement (Amst) 1, 481&#x2013;486. doi:10.1016/j.dadm.2015.10.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.dadm.2015.10.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4879495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27239526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caroppo P, Camuzat A, Guillot-Noel L, Thomas-Ant&#xe9;rion C, Couratier P, Wong TH, Teichmann M, Golfier V, Auriacombe S, Belliard S, Laurent B, Lattante S, Millecamps S, Clot F, Dubois B, van Swieten JC, Brice A, Le Ber I, 2016. Defining the spectrum of frontotemporal dementias associated with TARDBP mutations. Neurol Genet 2, e80. doi:10.1212/NXG.0000000000000080</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/NXG.0000000000000080</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4882769</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27280171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caroppo P, Durrleman S, Funkiewiez A, Perlbarg V, Hahn V, Bertin H, Gaubert M, Routier A, Hannequin D, Deramecourt V, Pasquier F, Rivaud-Pechoux S, Vercelletto M, Edouart G, Valabregue R, Lejeune P, Didic M, Corvol J-C, Benali H, Lehericy S, Dubois B, Colliot O, Brice A, Le Ber I, 2015b. Lateral temporal lobe: an early imaging marker of the presymptomatic GRN disease? J Alzheimers Dis 47, 751&#x2013;759. doi:10.3233/JAD-150270</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/JAD-150270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4923734</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26401709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caroppo P, Le Ber I, Camuzat A, Clot F, Naccache L, Lamari F, De Septenville A, Bertrand A, Belliard S, Hannequin D, Colliot O, Brice A, 2014. Extensive white matter involvement in patients with frontotemporal lobar degeneration: think progranulin. JAMA Neurol 71, 1562. doi:10.1001/jamaneurol.2014.1316</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamaneurol.2014.1316</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25317628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cash DM, Bocchetta M, Thomas DL, Dick KM, van Swieten JC, Borroni B, Galimberti D, Masellis M, Tartaglia MC, Rowe JB, Graff C, Tagliavini F, Frisoni GB, Laforce R, Finger E, de Mendon&#xe7;a A, Sorbi S, Rossor MN, Ourselin S, Rohrer JD, Andersson C, Archetti S, Arighi A, Benussi L, Black S, Cosseddu M, Fallstr&#xf6;m M, Ferreira C, Fenoglio C, Fox N, Freedman M, Fumagalli G, Gazzina S, Ghidoni R, Grisoli M, Jelic V, Jiskoot L, Keren R, Lombardi G, Maruta C, Mead S, Meeter L, van Minkelen R, Nacmias B, &#xd6;ijerstedt L, Padovani A, Panman J, Pievani M, Polito C, Premi E, Prioni S, Rademakers R, Redaelli V, Rogaeva E, Rossi G, Rossor M, Scarpini E, Tang-Wai D, Tartaglia C, Thonberg H, Tiraboschi P, Verdelho A, Warren J, 2018. Patterns of gray matter atrophy in genetic frontotemporal dementia: results from the GENFI study. Neurobiol Aging 62, 191&#x2013;196. doi:10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2017.10.008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2017.10.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5759893</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29172163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castelnovo V, Caminiti SP, Riva N, Magnani G, Silani V, Perani D, 2019. Heterogeneous brain FDG-PET metabolic patterns in patients with C9orf72 mutation. Neurol Sci 40, 515&#x2013;521. doi:10.1007/s10072-018-3685-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10072-018-3685-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30554355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cerami C, Dodich A, Greco L, Iannaccone S, Magnani G, Marcone A, Pelagallo E, Santangelo R, Cappa SF, Perani D, 2017. The role of single-subject brain metabolic patterns in the early differential diagnosis of primary progressive aphasias and in prediction of progression to dementia. J Alzheimers Dis 55, 183&#x2013;197. doi:10.3233/JAD-160682</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/JAD-160682</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5115609</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27662315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaussenot A, Le Ber I, Ait-El-Mkadem S, Camuzat A, de Septenville A, Bannwarth S, Genin EC, Serre V, Aug&#xe9; G, Brice A, Pouget J, Paquis-Flucklinger V, 2014. Screening of CHCHD10 in a French cohort confirms the involvement of this gene in frontotemporal dementia with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. Neurobiol Aging 35, 2884.e1&#x2013;2884.e4. doi:10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2014.07.022</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2014.07.022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25155093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Q, Boeve BF, Schwarz CG, Reid R, Tosakulwong N, Lesnick TG, Bove J, Brannelly P, Brushaber D, Coppola G, Dheel C, Dickerson BC, Dickinson S, Faber K, Fields J, Fong J, Foroud T, Forsberg L, Gavrilova RH, Gearhart D, Ghoshal N, Goldman J, Graff-Radford J, Graff-Radford NR, Grossman M, Haley D, Heuer HW, Hsiung G-YR, Huey E, Irwin DJ, Jack CR, Jones DT, Jones L, Karydas AM, Knopman DS, Kornak J, Kramer J, Kremers W, Kukull WA, Lapid M, Lucente D, Lungu C, Mackenzie IRA, Manoochehri M, McGinnis S, Miller BL, Pearlman R, Petrucelli L, Potter M, Rademakers R, Ramos EM, Rankin KP, Rascovsky K, Sengdy P, Shaw L, Syrjanen J, Tatton N, Taylor J, Toga AW, Trojanowski J, Weintraub S, Wong B, Boxer AL, Rosen H, Wszolek Z, Kantarci K, 2019a. Tracking white matter degeneration in asymptomatic and symptomatic MAPT mutation carriers. Neurobiol Aging 83, 54&#x2013;62. doi:10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2019.08.011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2019.08.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6858933</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31585367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Q, Boeve BF, Senjem M, Tosakulwong N, Lesnick T, Brushaber D, Dheel C, Fields J, Forsberg L, Gavrilova R, Gearhart D, Graff-Radford J, Graff-Radford N, Jack CR, Jones D, Knopman D, Kremers WK, Lapid M, Rademakers R, Ramos EM, Syrjanen J, Boxer AL, Rosen H, Wszolek ZK, Kantarci K, 2020. Trajectory of lobar atrophy in asymptomatic and symptomatic GRN mutation carriers: a longitudinal MRI study. Neurobiol Aging 88, 42&#x2013;50. doi:10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2019.12.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2019.12.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7767622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31918955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Q, Boeve BF, Senjem M, Tosakulwong N, Lesnick TG, Brushaber D, Dheel C, Fields J, Forsberg L, Gavrilova R, Gearhart D, Graff-Radford J, Graff-Radford NR, Jack CR, Jones DT, Knopman DS, Kremers WK, Lapid M, Rademakers R, Syrjanen J, Boxer AL, Rosen H, Wszolek ZK, Kantarci K, 2019b. Rates of lobar atrophy in asymptomatic MAPT mutation carriers. Alzheimers Dement (N Y) 5, 338&#x2013;346. doi:10.1016/j.trci.2019.05.010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.trci.2019.05.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6675939</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31388560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Q, Boeve BF, Tosakulwong N, Lesnick T, Brushaber D, Dheel C, Fields J, Forsberg L, Gavrilova R, Gearhart D, Haley D, Gunter JL, Graff-Radford J, Jones D, Knopman D, Graff-Radford N, Kraft R, Lapid M, Rademakers R, Syrjanen J, Wszolek ZK, Rosen H, Boxer AL, Kantarci K, 2019c. Frontal lobe 1H MR spectroscopy in asymptomatic and symptomatic MAPT mutation carriers. Neurology 93, e758&#x2013;e765. doi:10.1212/WNL.0000000000007961</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000007961</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6711662</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31315971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Q, Boeve BF, Tosakulwong N, Lesnick T, Brushaber D, Dheel C, Fields J, Forsberg L, Gavrilova R, Gearhart D, Haley D, Gunter JL, Graff-Radford J, Jones D, Knopman D, Graff-Radford N, Kraft R, Lapid M, Rademakers R, Wszolek ZK, Rosen H, Boxer AL, Kantarci K, 2019d. Brain MR spectroscopy changes precede frontotemporal lobar degeneration phenoconversion in Mapt mutation carriers. J Neuroimaging 29, 624&#x2013;629. doi:10.1111/jon.12642</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jon.12642</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6731148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31173437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Q, Kantarci K, 2020. Imaging Biomarkers for neurodegeneration in presymptomatic familial frontotemporal lobar degeneration. Front Neurol 11. doi:10.3389/fneur.2020.00080</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fneur.2020.00080</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7058699</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32184751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng YW, Lee MJ, Chen TF, Cheng TW, Lai YM, Hua MS, Chiu MJ, 2016. A single nucleotide TDP-43 mutation within a Taiwanese family: a multifaceted demon. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 17, 292&#x2013;294. doi:10.3109/21678421.2015.1111905</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/21678421.2015.1111905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26581115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen-Plotkin AS, Martinez-Lage M, Sleiman PMA, Hu W, Greene R, Wood EM, Bing S, Grossman M, Schellenberg GD, Hatanpaa KJ, Weiner MF, White CL, Brooks WS, Halliday GM, Kril JJ, Gearing M, Beach TG, Graff-Radford NR, Dickson DW, Rademakers R, Boeve BF, Pickering-Brown SM, Snowden J, van Swieten JC, Heutink P, Seelaar H, Murrell JR, Ghetti B, Spina S, Grafman J, Kaye JA, Woltjer RL, Mesulam M, Bigio E, Llad&#xf3; A, Miller BL, Alzualde A, Moreno F, Rohrer JD, Mackenzie IRA, Feldman HH, Hamilton RL, Cruts M, Engelborghs S, De Deyn PP, Van Broeckhoven C, Bird TD, Cairns NJ, Goate A, Frosch MP, Riederer PF, Bogdanovic N, Lee VMY, Trojanowski JQ, Van Deerlin VM, 2011. Genetic and clinical features of progranulin-associated frontotemporal lobar degeneration. Arch Neurol 68, 488. doi:10.1001/archneurol.2011.53</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archneurol.2011.53</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3160280</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21482928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheong I, Marja&#x144;ska M, Deelchand DK, Eberly LE, Walk D, &#xd6;z G, 2017. Ultra-high field proton MR spectroscopy in early-stage amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurochem Res 42, 1833&#x2013;1844. doi:10.1007/s11064-017-2248-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11064-017-2248-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5488866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28367604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi S, Jiang T, Tan L, Yu J-T, 2016. Distinct neurological disorders with C9orf72 mutations: genetics, pathogenesis, and therapy. Neurosci Biobehav Rev 66, 127&#x2013;142. doi:10.1016/j.neubiorev.2016.03.033</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neubiorev.2016.03.033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27139021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2; A, Calvo A, Moglia C, Restagno G, Ossola I, Brunetti M, Montuschi A, Cistaro A, Ticca A, Traynor BJ, Schymick JC, Mutani R, Marrosu MG, Murru MR, Borghero G, 2010. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis&#x2013;frontotemporal lobar dementia in 3 families with p.Ala382Thr TARDBP mutations. Arch Neurol 67, 1002&#x2013;1009. doi:10.1001/archneurol.2010.173</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archneurol.2010.173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3535689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20697052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2; A, Restagno G, Brunetti M, Ossola I, Calvo A, Mora G, Sabatelli M, Monsurr&#xf2; MR, Battistini S, Mandrioli J, Salvi F, Spataro R, Schymick J, Traynor BJ, La Bella V, 2009. Two Italian kindreds with familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis due to FUS mutation. Neurobiol Aging 30, 1272&#x2013;1275. doi:10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2009.05.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2009.05.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2771748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19450904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chipika RH, Finegan E, Li Hi Shing S, McKenna MC, Christidi F, Chang KM, Doherty MA, Hengeveld JC, Vajda A, Pender N, Hutchinson S, Donaghy C, McLaughlin RL, Hardiman O, Bede P, 2020. &#x201c;Switchboard&#x201d; malfunction in motor neuron diseases: Selective pathology of thalamic nuclei in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and primary lateral sclerosis. NeuroImage Clin 27, 102300. doi:10.1016/j.nicl.2020.102300</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nicl.2020.102300</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7303672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32554322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christidi F, Karavasilis E, Riederer F, Zalonis I, Ferentinos P, Velonakis G, Xirou S, Rentzos M, Argiropoulos G, Zouvelou V, Zambelis T, Athanasakos A, Toulas P, Vadikolias K, Efstathopoulos E, Kollias S, Karandreas N, Kelekis N, Evdokimidis I, 2018. Gray matter and white matter changes in non-demented amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients with or without cognitive impairment: A combined voxel-based morphometry and tract-based spatial statistics whole-brain analysis. Brain Imaging Behav 12, 547&#x2013;563. doi:10.1007/s11682-017-9722-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11682-017-9722-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28425061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cirulli ET, Lasseigne BN, Petrovski S, Sapp PC, Dion PA, Leblond CS, Couthouis J, Lu Y-F, Wang Q, Krueger BJ, Ren Z, Keebler J, Han Y, Levy SE, Boone BE, Wimbish JR, Waite LL, Jones AL, Carulli JP, Day-Williams AG, Staropoli JF, Xin WW, Chesi A, Raphael AR, McKenna-Yasek D, Cady J, Vianney de Jong JMB, Kenna KP, Smith BN, Topp S, Miller J, Gkazi A, FALS Sequencing Consortium, Al-Chalabi A, van den Berg LH, Veldink J, Silani V, Ticozzi N, Shaw CE, Baloh RH, Appel S, Simpson E, Lagier-Tourenne C, Pulst SM, Gibson S, Trojanowski JQ, Elman L, McCluskey L, Grossman M, Shneider NA, Chung WK, Ravits JM, Glass JD, Sims KB, Van Deerlin VM, Maniatis T, Hayes SD, Ordureau A, Swarup S, Landers J, Baas F, Allen AS, Bedlack RS, Harper JW, Gitler AD, Rouleau GA, Brown R, Harms MB, Cooper GM, Harris T, Myers RM, Goldstein DB, 2015. Exome sequencing in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis identifies risk genes and pathways. Science 347, 1436&#x2013;1441. doi:10.1126/science.aaa3650</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.aaa3650</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4437632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25700176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cistaro A, Pagani M, Montuschi A, Calvo A, Moglia C, Canosa A, Restagno G, Brunetti M, Traynor BJ, Nobili F, Carrara G, Fania P, Lopiano L, Valentini MC, Chi&#xf2; A, 2014. The metabolic signature of C9ORF72-related ALS: FDG PET comparison with nonmutated patients. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging 41, 844&#x2013;852. doi:10.1007/s00259-013-2667-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00259-013-2667-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24445987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cistaro A, Valentini MC, Chi&#xf2; A, Nobili F, Calvo A, Moglia C, Montuschi A, Morbelli S, Salmaso D, Fania P, Carrara G, Pagani M, 2012. Brain hypermetabolism in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a FDG PET study in ALS of spinal and bulbar onset. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging 39, 251&#x2013;259. doi:10.1007/s00259-011-1979-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00259-011-1979-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22089661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark LN, Poorkaj P, Wszolek Z, Geschwind DH, Nasreddine ZS, Miller B, Li D, Payami H, Awert F, Markopoulou K, Andreadis A, D&#x2019;Souza I, Lee VM, Reed L, Trojanowski JQ, Zhukareva V, Bird T, Schellenberg G, Wilhelmsen KC, 1998. Pathogenic implications of mutations in the tau gene in pallido-ponto-nigral degeneration and related neurodegenerative disorders linked to chromosome 17. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 95, 13103&#x2013;13107. doi:10.1073/pnas.95.22.13103</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.95.22.13103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC23724</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9789048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Consonni M, Cappa SF, Dalla Bella E, Contarino VE, Lauria G, 2019. Cortical correlates of behavioural change in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 90, 380&#x2013;386. doi:10.1136/jnnp-2018-318619</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp-2018-318619</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30322899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooper-Knock J, Hewitt C, Highley JR, Brockington A, Milano A, Man S, Martindale J, Hartley J, Walsh T, Gelsthorpe C, Baxter L, Forster G, Fox M, Bury J, Mok K, McDermott CJ, Traynor BJ, Kirby J, Wharton SB, Ince PG, Hardy J, Shaw PJ, 2012. Clinico-pathological features in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with expansions in C9ORF72. Brain 135, 751&#x2013;764. doi:10.1093/brain/awr365</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awr365</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3286332</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22366792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crockford C, Newton J, Lonergan K, Chiwera T, Booth T, Chandran S, Colville S, Heverin M, Mays I, Pal S, Pender N, Pinto-Grau M, Radakovic R, Shaw CE, Stephenson L, Swingler R, Vajda A, Al-Chalabi A, Hardiman O, Abrahams S, 2018. ALS-specific cognitive and behavior changes associated with advancing disease stage in ALS. Neurology 91, e1370&#x2013;e1380. doi:10.1212/WNL.0000000000006317</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000006317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6177274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30209236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cruchaga C, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Seara MA, Seijo-Mart&#xed;nez M, Samaranch L, Lorenzo E, Hinrichs A, Irigoyen J, Maestro C, Prieto E, Mart&#xed;-Climent JM, Arbizu J, Pastor MA, Pastor P, 2009. Cortical atrophy and language network reorganization associated with a novel progranulin mutation. Cereb Cortex 19, 1751&#x2013;1760. doi:10.1093/cercor/bhn202</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cercor/bhn202</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19020205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cruts M, Gijselinck I, van der Zee J, Engelborghs S, Wils H, Pirici D, Rademakers R, Vandenberghe R, Dermaut B, Martin J-J, van Duijn C, Peeters K, Sciot R, Santens P, De Pooter T, Mattheijssens M, Van den Broeck M, Cuijt I, Vennekens K, De Deyn PP, Kumar-Singh S, Van Broeckhoven C, 2006. Null mutations in progranulin cause ubiquitin-positive frontotemporal dementia linked to chromosome 17q21. Nature 442, 920&#x2013;924. doi:10.1038/nature05017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nature05017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16862115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cudkowicz ME, McKenna-Yasek D, Chen C, Hedley-Whyte ET, Brown RH, 1998. Limited corticospinal tract involvement in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis subjects with the A4V mutation in the copper/zinc superoxide dismutase gene. Ann Neurol 43, 703&#x2013;710. doi:10.1002/ana.410430604</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.410430604</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9629839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cudkowicz ME, McKenna-Yasek D, Sapp PE, Chin W, Geller B, Hayden DL, Schoenfeld DA, Hosler BA, Horvitz HR, Brown RH, 1997. Epidemiology of mutations in superoxide dismutase in amyotrophic lateal sclerosis. Ann Neurol 41, 210&#x2013;221. doi:10.1002/ana.410410212</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.410410212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9029070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dalakas MC, Hatazawa J, Brooks RA, Di Chiro G, 1987. Lowered cerebral glucose utilization in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol 22, 580&#x2013;586. doi:10.1002/ana.410220504</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.410220504</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3501273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daoud H, Suhail H, Szuto A, Camu W, Salachas F, Meininger V, Bouchard J-P, Dupr&#xe9; N, Dion PA, Rouleau GA, 2012. UBQLN2 mutations are rare in French and French&#x2013;Canadian amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurobiol Aging 33, 2230.e1&#x2013;2230.e5. doi:10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2012.03.015</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2012.03.015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22560112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Day GS, Farb NAS, Tang-Wai DF, Masellis M, Black SE, Freedman M, Pollock BG, Chow TW, 2013. Salience network resting-state activity: prediction of frontotemporal dementia progression. JAMA Neurol 70, 1249&#x2013;1253. doi:10.1001/jamaneurol.2013.3258</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamaneurol.2013.3258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23959214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Vocht J, Blommaert J, Devrome M, Radwan A, Van Weehaeghe D, De Schaepdryver M, Ceccarini J, Rezaei A, Schramm G, van Aalst J, Chi&#xf2; A, Pagani M, Stam D, Van Esch H, Lamaire N, Verhaegen M, Mertens N, Poesen K, van den Berg LH, van Es MA, Vandenberghe R, Vandenbulcke M, Van den Stock J, Koole M, Dupont P, Van Laere K, Van Damme P, 2020. Use of multimodal imaging and clinical biomarkers in presymptomatic carriers of C9orf72 repeat expansion. JAMA Neurol. doi:10.1001/jamaneurol.2020.1087</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamaneurol.2020.1087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7417970</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32421156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeJesus-Hernandez M, Mackenzie IR, Boeve BF, Boxer AL, Baker M, Rutherford NJ, Nicholson AM, Finch NA, Flynn H, Adamson J, Kouri N, Wojtas A, Sengdy P, Hsiung G-YR, Karydas A, Seeley WW, Josephs KA, Coppola G, Geschwind DH, Wszolek ZK, Feldman H, Knopman DS, Petersen RC, Miller BL, Dickson DW, Boylan KB, Graff-Radford NR, Rademakers R, 2011. Expanded GGGCC hexanucleotide repeat in noncoding region of C9ORF72 causes chromosome 9p-linked FTD and ALS. Neuron 72, 245&#x2013;256. doi:10.1016/j.neuron.2011.09.011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuron.2011.09.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3202986</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21944778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Del Bo R, Ghezzi S, Corti S, Pandolfo M, Ranieri M, Santoro D, Ghione I, Prelle A, Orsetti V, Mancuso M, Sorar&#xf9; G, Briani C, Angelini C, Siciliano G, Bresolin N, Comi GP, 2009. TARDBP (TDP-43) sequence analysis in patients with familial and sporadic ALS: identification of two novel mutations. Eur J Neurol 16, 727&#x2013;732. doi:10.1111/j.1468-1331.2009.02574.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1468-1331.2009.02574.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19236453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Del Bo R, Tiloca C, Pensato V, Corrado L, Ratti A, Ticozzi N, Corti S, Castellotti B, Mazzini L, Soraru G, Cereda C, D&#x2019;Alfonso S, Gellera C, Comi GP, Silani V, The SLAGEN Consortium, 2011. Novel optineurin mutations in patients with familial and sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 82, 1239&#x2013;1243. doi:10.1136/jnnp.2011.242313</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp.2011.242313</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21613650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deleon J, Miller BL, 2018. Frontotemporal dementia, in: Handbook of Clinical Neurology. Elsevier, pp. 409&#x2013;430. doi:10.1016/B978-0-444-64076-5.00027-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/B978-0-444-64076-5.00027-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29478591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delisle MB, Murrell JR, Richardson R, Trofatter JA, Rascol O, Soulages X, Mohr M, Calvas P, Ghetti B, 1999. A mutation at codon 279 (N279K) in exon 10 of the Tau gene causes a tauopathy with dementia and supranuclear palsy. Acta Neuropathol. 98, 62&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10412802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng H-X, Chen W, Hong S-T, Boycott KM, Gorrie GH, Siddique N, Yang Y, Fecto F, Shi Y, Zhai H, Jiang H, Hirano M, Rampersaud E, Jansen GH, Donkervoort S, Bigio EH, Brooks BR, Ajroud K, Sufit RL, Haines JL, Mugnaini E, Pericak-Vance MA, Siddique T, 2011. Mutations in UBQLN2 cause dominant X-linked juvenile and adult-onset ALS and ALS/dementia. Nature 477, 211&#x2013;215. doi:10.1038/nature10353</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nature10353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3169705</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21857683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deters KD, Risacher SL, Farlow MR, Unverzagt FW, Kareken DA, Hutchins GD, Yoder KK, Murrell JR, Spina S, Epperson F, Gao S, Saykin AJ, Ghetti B, 2014. Cerebral hypometabolism and grey matter density in MAPT intron 10 +3 mutation carriers. Am J Neurodegener Dis 3, 103&#x2013;114.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4299725</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25628962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devenney E, Foxe D, Dobson-Stone C, Kwok JB, Kiernan MC, Hodges JR, 2015. Clinical heterogeneity of the C9orf72 genetic mutation in frontotemporal dementia. Neurocase 21, 535&#x2013;541. doi:10.1080/13554794.2014.951058</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13554794.2014.951058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25138488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devenney E, Hornberger M, Irish M, Mioshi E, Burrell J, Tan R, Kiernan MC, Hodges JR, 2014. Frontotemporal dementia associated with the C9ORF72 mutation: a unique clinical profile. JAMA Neurol 71, 331. doi:10.1001/jamaneurol.2013.6002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamaneurol.2013.6002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24445580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dharmadasa T, Huynh W, Tsugawa J, Shimatani Y, Ma Y, Kiernan MC, 2018. Implications of structural and functional brain changes in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Expert Rev Neurother 18, 407&#x2013;419. doi:10.1080/14737175.2018.1464912</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14737175.2018.1464912</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29667443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diehl-Schmid J, Goldhardt O, F&#xf6;rstl H, Yakushew I, Otto M, Anderl-Straub S, Beer A, Ludolph AC, Landwehrmeyer GB, Levin J, Danek A, Fliessbach K, Spottke A, Fassbender K, Lyros E, Prudlo J, Krause BJ, Volk A, Edbauer D, Schroeter ML, Drzezga A, Kornhuber J, Lauer M, Grimmer T, Lauer M, Grimmer T, 2019. FDG-PET underscores the key role of the thalamus in frontotemporal lobar degeneration caused by C9ORF72 mutations. Transl Psychiatry 9. doi:10.1038/s41398-019-0381-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41398-019-0381-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6355852</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30705258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diehl-Schmid J, Grimmer T, Drzezga A, Bornschein S, Riemenschneider M, F&#xf6;rstl H, Schwaiger M, Kurz A, 2007. Decline of cerebral glucose metabolism in frontotemporal dementia: a longitudinal 18F-FDG-PET-study. Neurobiol Aging 28, 42&#x2013;50. doi:10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2005.11.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2005.11.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16448722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Djamshidian A, Schaefer J, Haubenberger D, Stogmann E, Zimprich F, Auff E, Zimprich A, 2009. A novel mutation in the VCP gene (G157R) in a german family with inclusion-body myopathy with paget disease of bone and frontotemporal dementia. Muscle Nerve 39, 389&#x2013;391. doi:10.1002/mus.21225</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.21225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19208399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dols-Icardo O, Nebot I, Gorostidi A, Ortega-Cubero S, Hern&#xe1;ndez I, Rojas-Garc&#xed;a R, Garc&#xed;a-Redondo A, Povedano M, Llad&#xf3; A, &#xc1;lvarez V, S&#xe1;nchez-Juan P, Pardo J, Jeric&#xf3; I, V&#xe1;zquez-Costa J, Sevilla T, Cardona F, Indakoechea B, Moreno F, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Torr&#xf3;n R, Mu&#xf1;oz-Llahuna L, Moreno-Grau S, Rosende-Roca M, Vela &#xc1;, Mu&#xf1;oz-Blanco JL, Combarros O, Coto E, Alcolea D, Fortea J, Lle&#xf3; A, S&#xe1;nchez-Valle R, Esteban-P&#xe9;rez J, Ruiz A, Pastor P, L&#xf3;pez De Munain A, P&#xe9;rez-Tur J, Clarim&#xf3;n J, on behalf of the Dementia Genetics Spanish Consortium (DEGESCO), 2015. Analysis of the CHCHD10 gene in patients with frontotemporal dementia and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis from Spain. Brain 138, e400&#x2013;e400. doi:10.1093/brain/awv175</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awv175</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26152333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dom&#xed;nguez-Vivero C, Wu L, Lee S, Manoochehri M, Cines S, Brickman AM, Rizvi B, Chesebro A, Gazes Y, Fallon E, Lynch T, Heidebrink JL, Paulson H, Goldman JS, Huey E, Cosentino S, 2020. Structural brain changes in pre-clinical FTD MAPT mutation carriers. J Alzheimers Dis 1&#x2013;12. doi:10.3233/JAD-190820</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/JAD-190820</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32310161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dopper EGP, Chalos V, Ghariq E, den Heijer T, Hafkemeijer A, Jiskoot LC, de Koning I, Seelaar H, van Minkelen R, van Osch MJP, Rombouts SARB, van Swieten JC, 2016. Cerebral blood flow in presymptomatic MAPT and GRN mutation carriers: A longitudinal arterial spin labeling study. NeuroImage Clin 12, 460&#x2013;465. doi:10.1016/j.nicl.2016.08.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nicl.2016.08.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5011170</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27625986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dopper EGP, Rombouts SARB, Jiskoot LC, den Heijer T, de Graaf JRA, de Koning I, Hammerschlag AR, Seelaar H, Seeley WW, Veer IM, van Buchem MA, Rizzu P, van Swieten JC, 2014. Structural and functional brain connectivity in presymptomatic familial frontotemporal dementia. Neurology 83, e19&#x2013;e26. doi:10.1212/WNL.0000000000000583</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000000583</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25002573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Douaud G, Filippini N, Knight S, Talbot K, Turner MR, 2011. Integration of structural and functional magnetic resonance imaging in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain 134, 3470&#x2013;3479. doi:10.1093/brain/awr279</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awr279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22075069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El Mendili M-M, Cohen-Adad J, Pelegrini-Issac M, Rossignol S, Morizot-Koutlidis R, Marchand-Pauvert V, Iglesias C, Sangari S, Katz R, Lehericy S, Benali H, Pradat P-F, 2014. Multi-parametric spinal cord MRI as potential progression marker in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. PLoS One 9, e95516. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0095516</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0095516</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3995720</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24755826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elahi FM, Marx G, Cobigo Y, Staffaroni AM, Kornak J, Tosun D, Boxer AL, Kramer JH, Miller BL, Rosen HJ, 2017. Longitudinal white matter change in frontotemporal dementia subtypes and sporadic late onset Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. NeuroImage Clin 16, 595&#x2013;603. doi:10.1016/j.nicl.2017.09.007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nicl.2017.09.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5614750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28975068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eskildsen SF, &#xd8;stergaard LR, Rodell AB, &#xd8;stergaard L, Nielsen JE, Isaacs AM, Johannsen P, 2009. Cortical volumes and atrophy rates in FTD-3 CHMP2B mutation carriers and related non-carriers. NeuroImage 45, 713&#x2013;721. doi:10.1016/j.neuroimage.2008.12.024</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuroimage.2008.12.024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19150504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fahed AC, McDonough B, Gouvion CM, Newell KL, Dure LS, Bebin M, Bick AG, Seidman JG, Harter DH, Seidman CE, 2014. UBQLN2 mutation causing heterogeneous X-linked dominant neurodegeneration. Ann Neurol 75, 793&#x2013;798. doi:10.1002/ana.24164</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.24164</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4106259</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24771548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fanganiello RD, Kimonis VE, C&#xf4;rte CC, Nitrini R, Passos-Bueno MR, 2011. A Brazilian family with hereditary inclusion body myopathy associated with Paget disease of bone and frontotemporal dementia. Braz J Med Biol Res 44, 374&#x2013;380. doi:10.1590/S0100-879X2011007500028</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/S0100-879X2011007500028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21412659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farb NAS, Grady CL, Strother S, Tang-Wai DF, Masellis M, Black S, Freedman M, Pollock BG, Campbell KL, Hasher L, Chow TW, 2013. Abnormal network connectivity in frontotemporal dementia: evidence for prefrontal isolation. Cortex 49, 1856&#x2013;1873. doi:10.1016/j.cortex.2012.09.008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cortex.2012.09.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23092697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fecto F, 2011. SQSTM1 mutations in familial and sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Arch Neurol 68, 1440. doi:10.1001/archneurol.2011.250</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archneurol.2011.250</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22084127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng Shu-Man, Che C, Feng Shu-Yan, Liu C, Li L, Li Y, Huang H, Zou Z, 2019. Novel mutation in optineurin causing aggressive ALS+/&#x2212;frontotemporal dementia. Ann Clin Transl Neurol 6, 2377&#x2013;2383. doi:10.1002/acn3.50928</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/acn3.50928</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6917321</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31838784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filippi M, Agosta F, Abrahams S, Fazekas F, Grosskreutz J, Kalra S, Kassubek J, Silani V, Turner MR, Masdeu JC, 2010. EFNS guidelines on the use of neuroimaging in the management of motor neuron diseases. Eur J Neurol 17, 526&#x2013;e20. doi:10.1111/j.1468-1331.2010.02951.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1468-1331.2010.02951.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3154636</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20136647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filippi M, Agosta F, Scola E, Canu E, Magnani G, Marcone A, Valsasina P, Caso F, Copetti M, Comi G, Cappa SF, Falini A, 2013. Functional network connectivity in the behavioral variant of frontotemporal dementia. Cortex 49, 2389&#x2013;2401. doi:10.1016/j.cortex.2012.09.017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cortex.2012.09.017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23164495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Floeter MK, Bageac D, Danielian LE, Braun LE, Traynor BJ, Kwan JY, 2016. Longitudinal imaging in C9orf72 mutation carriers: relationship to phenotype. NeuroImage Clin 12, 1035&#x2013;1043. doi:10.1016/j.nicl.2016.10.014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nicl.2016.10.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5153604</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27995069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Floeter MK, Danielian LE, Braun LE, Wu T, 2018. Longitudinal diffusion imaging across the C9orf72 clinical spectrum. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 89, 53&#x2013;60. doi:10.1136/jnnp-2017-316799</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp-2017-316799</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6454927</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29054917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Floris G, Borghero G, Cannas A, Di Stefano F, Murru MR, Corongiu D, Cuccu S, Tranquilli S, Cherchi MV, Serra A, Loi G, Marrosu MG, Chi&#xf2; A, Marrosu F, 2015. Clinical phenotypes and radiological findings in frontotemporal dementia related to TARDBP mutations. J Neurol 262, 375&#x2013;384. doi:10.1007/s00415-014-7575-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00415-014-7575-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25408367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freischmidt A, Wieland T, Richter B, Ruf W, Schaeffer V, M&#xfc;ller K, Marroquin N, Nordin F, H&#xfc;bers A, Weydt P, Pinto S, Press R, Millecamps S, Molko N, Bernard E, Desnuelle C, Soriani M-H, Dorst J, Graf E, Nordstr&#xf6;m U, Feiler MS, Putz S, Boeckers TM, Meyer T, Winkler AS, Winkelman J, de Carvalho M, Thal DR, Otto M, Br&#xe4;nnstr&#xf6;m T, Volk AE, Kursula P, Danzer KM, Lichtner P, Dikic I, Meitinger T, Ludolph AC, Strom TM, Andersen PM, Weishaupt JH, 2015. Haploinsufficiency of TBK1 causes familial ALS and frontotemporal dementia. Nat Neurosci 18, 631&#x2013;636. doi:10.1038/nn.4000</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nn.4000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25803835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu X, Zhu W, Guo Z, Shu G, Cui F, Yang F, Zhang Y, Ren Y, Zhang Xiaojun, Zhang Xiaolan, Chen Z, Ling L, Huang X, Zhang J, 2017. 18 F-fallypride PET-CT of dopamine D2/D3 receptors in patients with sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Sci 377, 79&#x2013;84. doi:10.1016/j.jns.2017.03.013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jns.2017.03.013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28477714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fumagalli GG, Basilico P, Arighi A, Bocchetta M, Dick KM, Cash DM, Harding S, Mercurio M, Fenoglio C, Pietroboni AM, Ghezzi L, van Swieten J, Borroni B, de Mendon&#xe7;a A, Masellis M, Tartaglia MC, Rowe JB, Graff C, Tagliavini F, Frisoni GB, Laforce R, Finger E, Sorbi S, Scarpini E, Rohrer JD, Galimberti D, Andersson C, Archetti S, Benussi L, Binetti G, Black S, Cosseddu M, Fallstr&#xf6;m M, Ferreira C, Fox NC, Freedman M, Gazzina S, Ghidoni R, Grisoli M, Jelic V, Jiskoot L, Keren R, Lombardi G, Maruta C, Mead S, Meeter L, van Minkelen R, Nacmias B, &#xd6;ijerstedt L, Ourselin S, Padovani A, Panman J, Pievani M, Polito C, Premi E, Prioni S, Rademakers R, Redaelli V, Rogaeva E, Rossi G, Rossor MN, Tang-Wai D, Thomas DL, Thonberg H, Tiraboschi P, Verdelho A, Warren JD, on behalf of the Genetic FTD Initiative (GENFI), 2018. Distinct patterns of brain atrophy in Genetic Frontotemporal Dementia Initiative (GENFI) cohort revealed by visual rating scales. Alzheimers Res Ther 10, 46. doi:10.1186/s13195-018-0376-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13195-018-0376-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5968621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29793546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gazzina S, Benussi A, Premi E, Paternic&#xf2; D, Cristillo V, Dell&#x2019;Era V, Cosseddu M, Archetti S, Alberici A, Gasparotti R, Padovani A, Borroni B, 2018. Neuroanatomical correlates of transcranial magnetic stimulation in presymptomatic granulin mutation carriers. Brain Topogr 31, 488&#x2013;497. doi:10.1007/s10548-017-0612-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10548-017-0612-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29256051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gellera C, Tiloca C, Del Bo R, Corrado L, Pensato V, Agostini J, Cereda C, Ratti A, Castellotti B, Corti S, Bagarotti A, Cagnin A, Milani P, Gabelli C, Riboldi G, Mazzini L, Sorar&#xf9; G, D&#x2019;Alfonso S, Taroni F, Comi GP, Ticozzi N, Silani V, Consortium TS, 2013. Ubiquilin 2 mutations in Italian patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal dementia. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 84, 183&#x2013;187. doi:10.1136/jnnp-2012-303433</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp-2012-303433</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23138764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gelpi E, van der Zee J, Turon Estrada A, Van Broeckhoven C, Sanchez-Valle R, 2014. TARDBP mutation p.Ile383Val associated with semantic dementia and complex proteinopathy. Neuropathol Appl Neurobiol 40, 225&#x2013;230. doi:10.1111/nan.12063</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/nan.12063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23692129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghetti B, Oblak AL, Boeve BF, Johnson KA, Dickerson BC, Goedert M, 2015. Invited review: Frontotemporal dementia caused by microtubule-associated protein tau gene ( MAPT ) mutations: a chameleon for neuropathology and neuroimaging: MAPT mutations and FTD. Neuropathol Appl Neurobiol 41, 24&#x2013;46. doi:10.1111/nan.12213</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/nan.12213</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4329416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25556536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghetti B, Wszolek ZK, Boeve BF, Spina S, Goedert M, 2011. Frontotemporal Dementia and Parkinsonism Linked to Chromosome 17, in: Dickson DW, Weller RO (Eds.), Neurodegeneration: The Molecular Pathology of Dementia and Movement Disorders. Wiley-Blackwell, Oxford, UK, pp. 110&#x2013;134. doi:10.1002/9781444341256.ch14</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/9781444341256.ch14</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gijselinck I, Van Mossevelde S, van der Zee J, Sieben A, Philtjens S, Heeman B, Engelborghs S, Vandenbulcke M, De Baets G, B&#xe4;umer V, Cuijt I, Van den Broeck M, Peeters K, Mattheijssens M, Rousseau F, Vandenberghe R, De Jonghe P, Cras P, De Deyn PP, Martin J-J, Cruts M, Van Broeckhoven C, 2015. Loss of TBK1 is a frequent cause of frontotemporal dementia in a Belgian cohort. Neurology 85, 2116&#x2013;2125. doi:10.1212/WNL.0000000000002220</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000002220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4691687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26581300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giraldo M, Lopera F, Siniard AL, Corneveaux JJ, Schrauwen I, Carvajal J, Mu&#xf1;oz C, Ramirez-Restrepo M, Gaiteri C, Myers AJ, Caselli RJ, Kosik KS, Reiman EM, Huentelman MJ, 2013. Variants in triggering receptor expressed on myeloid cells 2 are associated with both behavioral variant frontotemporal lobar degeneration and Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. Neurobiol Aging 34, 2077.e11&#x2013;2077.e18. doi:10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2013.02.016</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2013.02.016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3830921</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23582655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xf3;mez-Tortosa E, Serrano S, de Toledo M, P&#xe9;rez-P&#xe9;rez J, Sainz MJ, 2014. Familial benign frontotemporal deterioration with C9ORF72 hexanucleotide expansion. Alzheimers Dement 10, S284&#x2013;S289. doi:10.1016/j.jalz.2013.09.013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jalz.2013.09.013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24439166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez-S&#xe1;nchez M, Puertas-Mart&#xed;n V, Esteban-P&#xe9;rez J, Garc&#xed;a-Redondo A, Borrego-Hern&#xe1;ndez D, M&#xe9;ndez-Guerrero A, Llamas-Velasco S, Herrero-San Mart&#xed;n A, Cordero-V&#xe1;zquez P, Herrero-Manso MC, P&#xe9;rez-Mart&#xed;nez DA, Villarejo-Galende A, 2018. TARDBP mutation associated with semantic variant primary progressive aphasia, case report and review of the literature. Neurocase 24, 301&#x2013;305. doi:10.1080/13554794.2019.1581225</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13554794.2019.1581225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30773994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goode A, Layfield R, 2010. Recent advances in understanding the molecular basis of Paget disease of bone. J Clin Pathol 63, 199&#x2013;203. doi:10.1136/jcp.2009.064428</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jcp.2009.064428</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19858527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorno-Tempini ML, Dronkers NF, Rankin KP, Ogar JM, Phengrasamy L, Rosen HJ, Johnson JK, Weiner MW, Miller BL, 2004. Cognition and anatomy in three variants of primary progressive aphasia. Ann Neurol 55, 335&#x2013;346. doi:10.1002/ana.10825</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.10825</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2362399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14991811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorno-Tempini ML, Hillis AE, Weintraub S, Kertesz A, Mendez M, Cappa SF, Ogar JM, Rohrer JD, Black S, Boeve BF, Manes F, Dronkers NF, Vandenberghe R, Rascovsky K, Patterson K, Miller BL, Knopman DS, Hodges JR, Mesulam MM, Grossman M, 2011. Classification of primary progressive aphasia and its variants. Neurology 76, 1006&#x2013;1014. doi:10.1212/WNL.0b013e31821103e6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0b013e31821103e6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3059138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21325651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greaves CV, Rohrer JD, 2019. An update on genetic frontotemporal dementia. J Neurol 266, 2075&#x2013;2086. doi:10.1007/s00415-019-09363-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00415-019-09363-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6647117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31119452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greicius MD, Srivastava G, Reiss AL, Menon V, 2004. Default-mode network activity distinguishes Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease from healthy aging: Evidence from functional MRI. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 101, 4637&#x2013;4642. doi:10.1073/pnas.0308627101</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.0308627101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC384799</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15070770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grieve SM, Menon P, Korgaonkar MS, Gomes L, Foster S, Kiernan MC, Vucic S, 2016. Potential structural and functional biomarkers of upper motor neuron dysfunction in ALS. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 17, 85&#x2013;92. doi:10.3109/21678421.2015.1074707</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/21678421.2015.1074707</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26458122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grosskreutz J, Kaufmann J, Fr&#xe4;drich J, Dengler R, Heinze H-J, Peschel T, 2006. Widespread sensorimotor and frontal cortical atrophy in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. BMC Neurol 6, 17. doi:10.1186/1471-2377-6-17</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2377-6-17</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1459868</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16638121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grossman M, Mickanin J, Onishi K, Hughes E, D&#x2019;Esposito M, Ding X-S, Alavi A, Reivich M, 1996. Progressive nonfluent aphasia: language, cognitive, and PET measures contrasted with probable Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. J Cogn Neurosci 8, 135&#x2013;154. doi:10.1162/jocn.1996.8.2.135</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1162/jocn.1996.8.2.135</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23971420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guerreiro RJ, Lohmann E, Br&#xe1;s JM, Gibbs JR, Rohrer JD, Gurunlian N, Dursun B, Bilgic B, Hanagasi H, Gurvit H, Emre M, Singleton A, Hardy J, 2013. Using exome sequencing to reveal mutations in TREM2 presenting as a frontotemporal dementia-like syndrome without bone involvement. JAMA Neurol 70, 78&#x2013;84. doi:10.1001/jamaneurol.2013.579</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamaneurol.2013.579</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4001789</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23318515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo CC, Gorno-Tempini ML, Gesierich B, Henry M, Trujillo A, Shany-Ur T, Jovicich J, Robinson SD, Kramer JH, Rankin KP, Miller BL, Seeley WW, 2013. Anterior temporal lobe degeneration produces widespread network-driven dysfunction. Brain 136, 2979&#x2013;2991. doi:10.1093/brain/awt222</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awt222</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3857932</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24072486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gydesen S, Brown JM, Brun A, Chakrabarti L, Gade A, Johannsen P, Rossor M, Thusgaard T, Grove A, Yancopoulou D, Spillantini MG, Fisher EMC, Collinge J, Sorensen SA, 2002. Chromosome 3 linked frontotemporal dementia (FTD-3). Neurology 59, 1585&#x2013;1594. doi:10.1212/01.WNL.0000034763.54161.1F</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/01.WNL.0000034763.54161.1F</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12451202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hafkemeijer A, M&#xf6;ller C, Dopper EGP, Jiskoot LC, Schouten TM, van Swieten JC, van der Flier WM, Vrenken H, Pijnenburg YAL, Barkhof F, Scheltens P, van der Grond J, Rombouts SARB, 2015. Resting state functional connectivity differences between behavioral variant frontotemporal dementia and Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. Front Hum Neurosci 9, 474. doi:10.3389/fnhum.2015.00474</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnhum.2015.00474</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4561903</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26441584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanstock C, Sun K, Choi C, Eurich D, Camicioli R, Johnston W, Kalra S, 2020. Spectroscopic markers of neurodegeneration in the mesial prefrontal cortex predict survival in ALS. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 1&#x2013;6. doi:10.1080/21678421.2020.1727926</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/21678421.2020.1727926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32067510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hatazawa J, Brooks RA, Dalakas MC, Mansi L, Chiro GD, 1988. Cortical motor-sensory hypometabolism in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a PET study. J Comput Assist Tomogr 12, 630&#x2013;636. doi:10.1097/00004728-198807000-00019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00004728-198807000-00019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3260610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henry JD, Phillips LH, von Hippel C, 2014. A meta-analytic review of theory of mind difficulties in behavioural-variant frontotemporal dementia. Neuropsychologia 56, 53&#x2013;62. doi:10.1016/j.neuropsychologia.2013.12.024</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuropsychologia.2013.12.024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24412701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirano M, Nakamura Y, Saigoh K, Sakamoto H, Ueno S, Isono C, Mitsui Y, Kusunoki S, 2015. VCP gene analyses in Japanese patients with sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis identify a new mutation. Neurobiol Aging 36, 1604.e1&#x2013;1604.e6. doi:10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2014.10.012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2014.10.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25457024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirano M, Yamagishi Y, Yanagimoto S, Saigoh K, Nakamura Y, Kusunoki S, 2017. Time course of radiological imaging and variable interindividual symptoms in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal dementia associated with p.Arg487His mutation in the VCP gene. Eur Neurol 78, 78&#x2013;83. doi:10.1159/000478906</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000478906</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28738334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirsch-Reinshagen V, Alfaify OA, Hsiung G-YR, Pottier C, Baker M, Perkerson RB, Rademakers R, Briemberg H, Foti DJ, Mackenzie IR, 2019. Clinicopathologic correlations in a family with a TBK1 mutation presenting as primary progressive aphasia and primary lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 20, 568&#x2013;575. doi:10.1080/21678421.2019.1632347</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/21678421.2019.1632347</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6768716</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31244341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hjerpe R, Bett JS, Keuss MJ, Solovyova A, McWilliams TG, Johnson C, Sahu I, Varghese J, Wood N, Wightman M, Osborne G, Bates GP, Glickman MH, Trost M, Knebel A, Marchesi F, Kurz T, 2016. UBQLN2 mediates autophagy-independent protein aggregate clearance by the proteasome. Cell 166, 935&#x2013;949. doi:10.1016/j.cell.2016.07.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cell.2016.07.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5003816</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27477512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hodges JR, Patterson K, 1996. Nonfluent progressive aphasia and semantic dementia: a comparative neuropsychological study. J Int Neuropsychol Soc 2, 511&#x2013;524. doi:10.1017/S1355617700001685</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S1355617700001685</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9375155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huey ED, Ferrari R, Moreno JH, Jensen C, Morris CM, Potocnik F, Kalaria RN, Tierney M, Wassermann EM, Hardy J, Grafman J, Momeni P, 2012. FUS and TDP43 genetic variability in FTD and CBS. Neurobiol Aging 33, 1016.e9&#x2013;1016.e17. doi:10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2011.08.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2011.08.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4489700</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21943958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huey ED, Grafman J, Wassermann EM, Pietrini P, Tierney MC, Ghetti B, Spina S, Baker M, Hutton M, Elder JW, Berger SL, Heflin KA, Hardy J, Momeni P, 2006. Characteristics of frontotemporal dementia patients with a Progranulin mutation. Ann Neurol 60, 374&#x2013;380. doi:10.1002/ana.20969</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.20969</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2987739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16983677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hutton M, Lendon CL, Rizzu P, Baker M, Froelich S, Houlden H, Pickering-Brown S, Chakraverty S, Isaacs A, Grover A, Hackett J, Adamson J, Lincoln S, Dickson D, Davies P, Petersen RC, Stevens M, de Graaff E, Wauters E, van Baren J, Hillebrand M, Joosse M, Kwon JM, Nowotny P, Che LK, Norton J, Morris JC, Reed LA, Trojanowski J, Basun H, Lannfelt L, Neystat M, Fahn S, Dark F, Tannenberg T, Dodd PR, Hayward N, Kwok JB, Schofield PR, Andreadis A, Snowden J, Craufurd D, Neary D, Owen F, Oostra BA, Hardy J, Goate A, van Swieten J, Mann D, Lynch T, Heutink P, 1998. Association of missense and 5&#x2019;-splice-site mutations in tau with the inherited dementia FTDP-17. Nature 393, 702&#x2013;705. doi:10.1038/31508</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/31508</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9641683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iijima M, Tabira T, Poorkaj P, Schellenberg G, Trojanowski J, Lee V, Schmidt M, Takahashi K, Nabika T, Matsumoto T, Yamashita Y, Yoshioka S, Ishino H, 1999. A distinct familial presenile dementia with a novel missense mutation in the tau gene. Neuroreport 10, 497&#x2013;501.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10208578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ikawa M, Okazawa H, Tsujikawa T, Matsunaga A, Yamamura O, Mori T, Hamano T, Kiyono Y, Nakamoto Y, Yoneda M, 2015. Increased oxidative stress is related to disease severity in the ALS motor cortex: A PET study. Neurology 84, 2033&#x2013;2039. doi:10.1212/WNL.0000000000001588</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000001588</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25904686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ikeda K, Murata K, Kawase Y, Kawabe K, Kano O, Yoshii Y, Takazawa T, Hirayama T, Iwasaki Y, 2013. Relationship between cervical cord 1 H-magnetic resonance spectroscopy and clinoco-electromyographic profile in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve 47, 61&#x2013;67. doi:10.1002/mus.23467</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.23467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23042532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ince PG, Tomkins J, Slade JY, Thatcher NM, Shaw PJ, 1998. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis associated with genetic abnormalities in the gene encoding Cu/Zn superoxide dismutase: molecular pathology of five new cases, and comparison with previous reports and 73 sporadic cases of ALS. J Neuropath Exp Neur 57, 895&#x2013;904. doi:10.1097/00005072-199810000-00002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005072-199810000-00002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9786240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Irwin DJ, McMillan CT, Brettschneider J, Libon DJ, Powers J, Rascovsky K, Toledo JB, Boller A, Bekisz J, Chandrasekaran K, Wood EM, Shaw LM, Woo JH, Cook PA, Wolk DA, Arnold SE, Van Deerlin VM, McCluskey LF, Elman L, Lee VM-Y, Trojanowski JQ, Grossman M, 2013. Cognitive decline and reduced survival in C9orf72 expansion frontotemporal degeneration and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 84, 163&#x2013;169. doi:10.1136/jnnp-2012-303507</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp-2012-303507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3543474</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23117491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isaacs AM, Johannsen P, Holm I, Nielsen E, J., Consortium, Fr., 2011. Frontotemporal dementia caused by CHMP2B mutations. Curr Alzheimer Res 8, 246&#x2013;251. doi:10.2174/156720511795563764</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/156720511795563764</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3182073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21222599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ito H, Nakamura M, Komure O, Ayaki T, Wate R, Maruyama H, Nakamura Y, Fujita K, Kaneko S, Okamoto Y, Ihara M, Konishi T, Ogasawara K, Hirano A, Kusaka H, Kaji R, Takahashi R, Kawakami H, 2011. Clinicopathologic study on an ALS family with a heterozygous E478G optineurin mutation. Acta Neuropathol 122, 223&#x2013;229. doi:10.1007/s00401-011-0842-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00401-011-0842-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21644038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacova C, Hsiung G-YR, Tawankanjanachot I, Dinelle K, McCormick S, Gonzalez M, Lee H, Sengdy P, Bouchard-Kerr P, Baker M, Rademakers R, Sossi V, Stoessl AJ, Feldman HH, Mackenzie IR, 2013. Anterior brain glucose hypometabolism predates dementia in progranulin mutation carriers. Neurology 81, 1322&#x2013;1331. doi:10.1212/WNL.0b013e3182a8237e</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0b013e3182a8237e</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3806924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24005336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janssen JC, Warrington EK, Morris HR, Lantos P, Brown J, Revesz T, Wood N, Khan MN, Cipolotti L, Fox NC, Rossor MN, 2002. Clinical features of frontotemporal dementia due to the intronic tau 10 +16 mutation. Neurology 58, 1161&#x2013;1168. doi:10.1212/WNL.58.8.1161</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.58.8.1161</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11971081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiao B, Sun Q, Yuan Z, Wang J, Zhou L, Yan X, Tang B, Shen L, 2018. Rare TBK1 variants in patients with frontotemporal dementia and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in a Chinese cohort. Transl Neurodegener 7, 31. doi:10.1186/s40035-018-0136-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40035-018-0136-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6278101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30534373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiao B, Xiao T, Hou L, Gu X, Zhou Y, Zhou L, Tang B, Xu J, Shen L, 2016. High prevalence of CHCHD10 mutation in patients with frontotemporal dementia from China. Brain 139, e21&#x2013;e21. doi:10.1093/brain/awv367</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awv367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26719383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiskoot LC, Bocchetta M, Nicholas JM, Cash DM, Thomas D, Modat M, Ourselin S, Rombouts SARB, Dopper EGP, Meeter LH, Panman JL, van Minkelen R, van der Ende EL, Donker Kaat L, Pijnenburg YAL, Borroni B, Galimberti D, Masellis M, Tartaglia MC, Rowe J, Graff C, Tagliavini F, Frisoni GB, Laforce R, Finger E, de Mendon&#xe7;a A, Sorbi S, on behalf of the Genetic Frontotemporal dementia Initiative (GENFI), Papma JM, van Swieten JC, Rohrer JD, 2018. Presymptomatic white matter integrity loss in familial frontotemporal dementia in the GENFI cohort: a cross-sectional diffusion tensor imaging study. Ann Clin Transl Neurol 5, 1025&#x2013;1036. doi:10.1002/acn3.601</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/acn3.601</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6144447</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30250860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiskoot LC, Panman JL, Meeter LH, Dopper EGP, Donker Kaat L, Franzen S, van der Ende EL, van Minkelen R, Rombouts SARB, Papma JM, van Swieten JC, 2019. Longitudinal multimodal MRI as prognostic and diagnostic biomarker in presymptomatic familial frontotemporal dementia. Brain 142, 193&#x2013;208. doi:10.1093/brain/awy288</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awy288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6308313</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30508042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson JO, Mandrioli J, Benatar M, Abramzon Y, Van Deerlin VM, Trojanowski JQ, Gibbs JR, Brunetti M, Gronka S, Wuu J, Ding J, McCluskey L, Martinez-Lage M, Falcone D, Hernandez DG, Arepalli S, Chong S, Schymick JC, Rothstein J, Landi F, Wang Y-D, Calvo A, Mora G, Sabatelli M, Monsurr&#xf2; MR, Battistini S, Salvi F, Spataro R, Sola P, Borghero G, Galassi G, Scholz SW, Taylor JP, Restagno G, Chi&#xf2; A, Traynor BJ, 2010. Exome sequencing reveals VCP mutations as a cause of familial ALS. Neuron 68, 857&#x2013;864. doi:10.1016/j.neuron.2010.11.036</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuron.2010.11.036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3032425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21145000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones DT, Knopman DS, Graff-Radford J, Syrjanen JA, Senjem ML, Schwarz CG, Dheel C, Wszolek Z, Rademakers R, Kantarci K, Petersen RC, Jack CR, Lowe VJ, Boeve BF, 2018. In vivo 18 F-AV-1451 tau PET signal in MAPT mutation carriers varies by expected tau isoforms. Neurology 90, e947&#x2013;e954. doi:10.1212/WNL.0000000000005117</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000005117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5858948</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29440563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Josephs KA, Whitwell JL, Jack CR, 2008. Anatomic correlates of stereotypies in frontotemporal lobar degeneration. Neurobiol Aging 29, 1859&#x2013;1863. doi:10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2007.04.027</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2007.04.027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2745642</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17574708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaivorinne A-L, Bode MK, Paavola L, Tuominen H, Kallio M, Renton AE, Traynor BJ, Moilanen V, Remes AM, 2013. Clinical characteristics of C9ORF72-linked frontotemporal lobar degeneration. Dement Geriatr Cogn Disord Extra 3, 251&#x2013;262. doi:10.1159/000351859</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000351859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3776392</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24052799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamada M, Izumi Y, Ayaki T, Nakamura M, Kagawa S, Kudo E, Sako W, Maruyama H, Nishida Y, Kawakami H, Ito H, Kaji R, 2014. Clinicopathologic features of autosomal recessive amyotrophic lateral sclerosis associated with optineurin mutation: Autosomal recessive OPTN-ALS. Neuropathology 34, 64&#x2013;70. doi:10.1111/neup.12051</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/neup.12051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23889540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kantarci K, Boeve BF, Wszolek ZK, Rademakers R, Whitwell JL, Baker MC, Senjem ML, Samikoglu AR, Knopman DS, Petersen RC, Jack CR, 2010. MRS in presymptomatic MAPT mutation carriers: a potential biomarker for tau-mediated pathology. Neurology 75, 771&#x2013;778. doi:10.1212/WNL.0b013e3181f073c7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0b013e3181f073c7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2938968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20805522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kao AW, McKay A, Singh PP, Brunet A, Huang EJ, 2017. Progranulin, lysosomal regulation and neurodegenerative disease. Nat Rev Neurosci 18, 325&#x2013;333. doi:10.1038/nrn.2017.36</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrn.2017.36</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6040832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28435163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karch CM, Wen N, Fan CC, Yokoyama JS, Kouri N, Ross OA, H&#xf6;glinger G, M&#xfc;ller U, Ferrari R, Hardy J, Schellenberg GD, Sleiman PM, Momeni P, Hess CP, Miller BL, Sharma M, Van Deerlin V, Smeland OB, Andreassen OA, Dale AM, Desikan RS, for the International Frontotemporal Dementia (FTD)&#x2013;Genomics Consortium, International Collaboration for Frontotemporal Dementia, Progressive Supranuclear Palsy (PSP) Genetics Consortium, and International Parkinson&#x2019;s Disease Genomics Consortium, 2018. Selective genetic overlap between amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and diseases of the frontotemporal dementia spectrum. JAMA Neurol 75, 860&#x2013;875. doi:10.1001/jamaneurol.2018.0372</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamaneurol.2018.0372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6043387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29630712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kew JJM, Goldstein LH, Leigh PN, Abrahams S, Cosgrave N, Passingham RE, Frackowiak RSJ, Brooks DJ, 1993. The relationship between abnormalities of cognitive function and cerebral activation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A neuropsychological and positron emission tomography study. Brain 116, 1399&#x2013;1423. doi:10.1093/brain/116.6.1399</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/116.6.1399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8293278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan BK, Yokoyama JS, Takada LT, Sha SJ, Rutherford NJ, Fong JC, Karydas AM, Wu T, Ketelle RS, Baker MC, Hernandez M-D, Coppola G, Geschwind DH, Rademakers R, Lee SE, Rosen HJ, Rabinovici GD, Seeley WW, Rankin KP, Boxer AL, Miller BL, 2012. Atypical, slowly progressive behavioural variant frontotemporal dementia associated with C9ORF72 hexanucleotide expansion. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 83, 358&#x2013;364. doi:10.1136/jnnp-2011-301883</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp-2011-301883</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3388906</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22399793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim E-J, Park Y-E, Kim D-S, Ahn B-Y, Kim H-S, Chang YH, Kim S-J, Kim H-J, Lee H-W, Seeley WW, Kim S, 2011. Inclusion body myopathy with Paget disease of bone and frontotemporal dementia linked to VCP p.Arg155Cys in a Korean family. Arch Neurol 68, 787&#x2013;796. doi:10.1001/archneurol.2010.376</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archneurol.2010.376</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21320982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim E-J, Sidhu M, Gaus SE, Huang EJ, Hof PR, Miller BL, DeArmond SJ, Seeley WW, 2012. Selective frontoinsular von Economo neuron and fork cell loss in early behavioral variant frontotemporal dementia. Cereb Cortex 22, 251&#x2013;259. doi:10.1093/cercor/bhr004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cercor/bhr004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3256403</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21653702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kimonis VE, Watts GDJ, 2005. Autosomal dominant inclusion body myopathy, Paget disease of bone, and frontotemporal dementia. Alzheimer Dis Assoc Disord 19, S44&#x2013;S47. doi:10.1097/01.wad.0000183081.76820.5a</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/01.wad.0000183081.76820.5a</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16317258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kimonis Virginia.E., Mehta SG, Fulchiero EC, Thomasova D, Pasquali M, Boycott K, Neilan EG, Kartashov A, Forman MS, Tucker S, Kimonis K, Mumm S, Whyte MP, Smith CD, Watts GDJ, 2008. Clinical studies in familial VCP myopathy associated with Paget disease of bone and frontotemporal dementia. Am J Med Genet A 146A, 745&#x2013;757. doi:10.1002/ajmg.a.31862</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ajmg.a.31862</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2467391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18260132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kl&#xfc;nemann HH, Ridha BH, Magy L, Wherrett JR, Hemelsoet DM, Keen RW, De Bleecker JL, Rossor MN, Marienhagen J, Klein HE, Peltonen L, Paloneva J, 2005. The genetic causes of basal ganglia calcification, dementia, and bone cysts: DAP12 and TREM2. Neurology 64, 1502&#x2013;1507. doi:10.1212/01.WNL.0000160304.00003.CA</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/01.WNL.0000160304.00003.CA</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15883308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konrad C, Jansen A, Henningsen H, Sommer J, Turski PA, Brooks BR, Knecht S, 2006. Subcortical reorganization in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Exp Brain Res 172, 361&#x2013;369. doi:10.1007/s00221-006-0352-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00221-006-0352-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16463149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koppers M, van Blitterswijk MM, Vlam L, Rowicka PA, van Vught PWJ, Groen EJN, Spliet WGM, Engelen-Lee J, Schelhaas HJ, de Visser M, van der Kooi AJ, van der Pol W-L, Pasterkamp RJ, Veldink JH, van den Berg LH, 2012. VCP mutations in familial and sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurobiol Aging 33, 837.e7&#x2013;837.e13. doi:10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2011.10.006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2011.10.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22078486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koriath CAM, Bocchetta M, Brotherhood E, Woollacott IOC, Norsworthy P, Sim&#xf3;n-S&#xe1;nchez J, Blauwendraat C, Dick KM, Gordon E, Harding SR, Fox NC, Crutch S, Warren JD, Revesz T, Lashley T, Mead S, Rohrer JD, 2017. The clinical, neuroanatomical, and neuropathologic phenotype of TBK1-associated frontotemporal dementia: a longitudinal case report. Alzheimers Dement (Amst) 6, 75&#x2013;81. doi:10.1016/j.dadm.2016.10.003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.dadm.2016.10.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5312484</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28229125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kotan D, Iskender C, Ozoguz Erimis A, Basak AN, 2016. A Turkish Family with a Familial ALS-positive UBQLN2-S340I Mutation. Arch Neuropsychiatr 53, 283&#x2013;285. doi:10.5152/npa.2016.12371</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5152/npa.2016.12371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5378209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28373810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kovach MJ, Waggoner B, Leal SM, Gelber D, Khardori R, Levenstien MA, Shanks CA, Gregg G, Al-Lozi MT, Miller T, Rakowicz W, Lopate G, Florence J, Glosser G, Simmons Z, Morris JC, Whyte MP, Pestronk A, Kimonis VE, 2001. Clinical delineation and localization to chromosome 9p13.3-p12 of a unique dominant disorder in four families: hereditary inclusion body myopathy, Paget disease of bone, and frontotemporal dementia. Mol Genet Metab 74, 458&#x2013;475. doi:10.1006/mgme.2001.3256</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1006/mgme.2001.3256</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6277059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11749051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kovacs GG, Murrell JR, Horvath S, Haraszti L, Majtenyi K, Molnar MJ, Budka H, Ghetti B, Spina S, 2009. TARDBP variation associated with frontotemporal dementia, supranuclear gaze palsy, and chorea. Mov Disord 24, 1842&#x2013;1847. doi:10.1002/mds.22697</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mds.22697</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19609911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kovacs GG, van der Zee J, Hort J, Kristoferitsch W, Leitha T, H&#xf6;ftberger R, Str&#xf6;bel T, Van Broeckhoven C, Matej R, 2016. Clinicopathological description of two cases with SQSTM1 gene mutation associated with frontotemporal dementia: clinicopathology of SQSTM1 gene mutations. Neuropathology 36, 27&#x2013;38. doi:10.1111/neup.12233</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/neup.12233</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26234378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krause S, G&#xf6;hringer T, Walter MC, Schoser BGH, Reilich P, Linn J, P&#xf6;pperl GE, Fr&#xf6;lich L, Hentschel F, Lochm&#xfc;ller H, Danek A, 2007. Brain imaging and neuropsychology in late-onset dementia due to a novel mutation (R93C) of valosin-containing protein. Clin Neuropathol 26, 232&#x2013;240. doi:10.5414/NPP26232</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5414/NPP26232</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17907600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar V, Islam A, Hassan Md.I., Ahmad F, 2016. Delineating the relationship between amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal dementia: Sequence and structure-based predictions. Biochim Biophys Acta 1862, 1742&#x2013;1754. doi:10.1016/j.bbadis.2016.06.011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbadis.2016.06.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27318084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumfor F, Landin-Romero R, Devenney E, Hutchings R, Grasso R, Hodges JR, Piguet O, 2016. On the right side? A longitudinal study of left- versus right-lateralized semantic dementia. Brain 139, 986&#x2013;998. doi:10.1093/brain/awv387</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awv387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26811253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwiatkowski TJ, Bosco DA, LeClerc AL, Tamrazian E, Vanderburg CR, Russ C, Davis A, Gilchrist J, Kasarskis EJ, Munsat T, Valdmanis P, Rouleau GA, Hosler BA, Cortelli P, de Jong PJ, Yoshinaga Y, Haines JL, Pericak-Vance MA, Yan J, Ticozzi N, Siddique T, McKenna-Yasek D, Sapp PC, Horvitz HR, Landers JE, Brown RH, 2009. Mutations in the FUS/TLS gene on chromosome 16 cause familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Science 323, 1205&#x2013;1208. doi:10.1126/science.1166066</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.1166066</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19251627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lam BYK, Halliday GM, Irish M, Hodges JR, Piguet O, 2014. Longitudinal white matter changes in frontotemporal dementia subtypes. Hum Brain Mapp 35, 3547&#x2013;3557. doi:10.1002/hbm.22420</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hbm.22420</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6869363</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25050433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lamb R, Rohrer JD, Real R, Lubbe SJ, Waite AJ, Blake DJ, Walters RJ, Lashley T, Revesz T, Holton JL, Morris HR, 2019. A novel TBK1 mutation in a family with diverse frontotemporal dementia spectrum disorders. Cold Spring Harb Mol Case Stud 5, a003913. doi:10.1101/mcs.a003913</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/mcs.a003913</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6549548</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31160356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lant SB, Robinson AC, Thompson JC, Rollinson S, Pickering-Brown S, Snowden JS, Davidson YS, Gerhard A, Mann DMA, 2014. Patterns of microglial cell activation in frontotemporal lobar degeneration: Microglia and frontotemporal lobar degeneration. Neuropathol Appl Neurobiol 40, 686&#x2013;696. doi:10.1111/nan.12092</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/nan.12092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24117616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lattante S, Le Ber I, Camuzat A, Dayan S, Godard C, Van Bortel I, De Septenville A, Ciura S, Brice A, Kabashi E, 2013a. TREM2 mutations are rare in a French cohort of patients with frontotemporal dementia. Neurobiol Aging 34, 2443.e1&#x2013;2443.e2. doi:10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2013.04.030</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2013.04.030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23759145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lattante S, Rouleau GA, Kabashi E, 2013b. TARDBP and FUS mutations associated with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: summary and update. Hum Mutat 34, 812&#x2013;826. doi:10.1002/humu.22319</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/humu.22319</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23559573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le Ber I, 2013. SQSTM1 mutations in French patients with frontotemporal dementia or frontotemporal dementia with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. JAMA Neurol 70, 1403&#x2013;1410. doi:10.1001/jamaneurol.2013.3849</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamaneurol.2013.3849</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4199096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24042580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le Ber I, Camuzat A, Hannequin D, Pasquier F, Guedj E, Rovelet-Lecrux A, Hahn-Barma V, van der Zee J, Clot F, Bakchine S, Puel M, Ghanim M, Lacomblez L, Mikol J, Deramecourt V, Lejeune P, de la Sayette V, Belliard S, Vercelletto M, Meyrignac C, Van Broeckhoven C, Lambert J-C, Verpillat P, Campion D, Habert M-O, Dubois B, Brice A, 2008. Phenotype variability in progranulin mutation carriers: a clinical, neuropsychological, imaging and genetic study. Brain 131, 732&#x2013;746. doi:10.1093/brain/awn012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awn012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18245784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le Ber I, De Septenville A, Guerreiro R, Bras J, Camuzat A, Caroppo P, Lattante S, Couarch P, Kabashi E, Bouya-Ahmed K, Dubois B, Brice A, 2014. Homozygous TREM2 mutation in a family with atypical frontotemporal dementia. Neurobiol Aging 35, 2419.e23&#x2013;2419.e25. doi:10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2014.04.010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2014.04.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4208293</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24910390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le Blanc G, Jett&#xe9; Pomerleau V, McCarthy J, Borroni B, van Swieten J, Galimberti D, Sanchez-Valle R, LaForce R, Moreno F, Synofzik M, Graff C, Masellis M, Tartaglia MC, Rowe JB, Vandenberghe R, Finger E, Tagliavini F, de Mendon&#xe7;a A, Santana I, Butler C, Gerhard A, Danek A, Levin J, Otto M, Frisoni G, Sorbi S, Rohrer JD, Ducharme S, GENetic Frontotemporal dementia Initiative (GENFI), 2020. Faster cortical thinning and surface area loss in presymptomatic and symptomatic C9orf72 repeat expansion adult carriers. Ann Neurol. doi:10.1002/ana.25748</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.25748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32285980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee SE, Khazenzon AM, Trujillo AJ, Guo CC, Yokoyama JS, Sha SJ, Takada LT, Karydas AM, Block NR, Coppola G, Pribadi M, Geschwind DH, Rademakers R, Fong JC, Weiner MW, Boxer AL, Kramer JH, Rosen HJ, Miller BL, Seeley WW, 2014. Altered network connectivity in frontotemporal dementia with C9orf72 hexanucleotide repeat expansion. Brain 137, 3047&#x2013;3060. doi:10.1093/brain/awu248</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awu248</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4208465</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25273996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee SE, Sias AC, Kosik EL, Flagan TM, Deng J, Chu SA, Brown JA, Vidovszky AA, Ramos EM, Gorno-Tempini ML, Karydas AM, Coppola G, Geschwind DH, Rademakers R, Boeve BF, Boxer AL, Rosen HJ, Miller BL, Seeley WW, 2019. Thalamo-cortical network hyperconnectivity in preclinical progranulin mutation carriers. NeuroImage Clin 22, 101751. doi:10.1016/j.nicl.2019.101751</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nicl.2019.101751</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6438992</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30921613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee SE, Sias AC, Mandelli ML, Brown JA, Brown AB, Khazenzon AM, Vidovszky AA, Zanto TP, Karydas AM, Pribadi M, Dokuru D, Coppola G, Geschwind DH, Rademakers R, Gorno-Tempini ML, Rosen HJ, Miller BL, Seeley WW, 2017. Network degeneration and dysfunction in presymptomatic C9ORF72 expansion carriers. NeuroImage Clin 14, 286&#x2013;297. doi:10.1016/j.nicl.2016.12.006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nicl.2016.12.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5349617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28337409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leger GC, Banks SJ, Leverenz JB, Bekris LM, 2017. Behavioral variant FTD caused by UBQLN2 P525S mutation, without evidence of motor neuron disease. Alzheimers Dement 13, P1492. doi:10.1016/j.jalz.2017.07.579</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jalz.2017.07.579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lesage S, Le Ber I, Condroyer C, Broussolle E, Gabelle A, Thobois S, Pasquier F, Mondon K, Dion PA, Rochefort D, Rouleau GA, D&#xfc;rr A, Brice A, for the French Parkinson&#x2019;s Disease Genetics (PDG) Study Group, 2013. C9orf72 repeat expansions are a rare genetic cause of parkinsonism. Brain 136, 385&#x2013;391. doi:10.1093/brain/aws357</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/aws357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3984141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23413259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lillo P, Mioshi E, Burrell JR, Kiernan MC, Hodges JR, Hornberger M, 2012. Grey and white matter changes across the amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-frontotemporal dementia continuum. PLoS One 7, e43993. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0043993</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0043993</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3430626</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22952843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindquist S, Duno M, Batbayli M, Puschmann A, Braendgaard H, Mardosiene S, Svenstrup K, Pinborg L, Vestergaard K, Hjermind L, Stokholm J, Andersen B, Johannsen P, Nielsen J, 2013. Corticobasal and ataxia syndromes widen the spectrum of C9ORF72 hexanucleotide expansion disease. Clin Genet 83, 279&#x2013;283. doi:10.1111/j.1399-0004.2012.01903.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1399-0004.2012.01903.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22650353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindquist SG, Braendgaard H, Svenstrup K, Isaacs AM, Nielsen JE, on behalf of the FReJA Consortium, 2008. Frontotemporal dementia linked to chromosome 3 (FTD-3) - current concepts and the detection of a previously unknown branch of the Danish FTD-3 family: frontotemporal dementia linked to chromosome 3. Eur J Neurol 15, 667&#x2013;670. doi:10.1111/j.1468-1331.2008.02144.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1468-1331.2008.02144.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18484988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y, Yu J-T, Zong Y, Zhou J, Tan L, 2014. C9ORF72 mutations in neurodegenerative diseases. Mol Neurobiol 49, 386&#x2013;398. doi:10.1007/s12035-013-8528-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12035-013-8528-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23934648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Llamas-Velasco S, Garc&#xed;a-Redondo A, Herrero-San Mart&#xed;n A, Puertas Mart&#xed;n V, Gonz&#xe1;lez-S&#xe1;nchez M, P&#xe9;rez-Mart&#xed;nez DA, Villarejo-Galende A, 2018. Slowly progressive behavioral frontotemporal dementia with C9orf72 mutation. Case report and review of the literature. Neurocase 24, 68&#x2013;71. doi:10.1080/13554794.2018.1428353</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13554794.2018.1428353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29355451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lloyd CM, Richardson MP, Brooks DJ, Al-Chalabi A, Leigh PN, 2000. Extramotor involvement in ALS: PET studies with the GABAA ligand [11C]flumazenil. Brain 123, 2289&#x2013;2296. doi:10.1093/brain/123.11.2289</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/123.11.2289</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11050028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lomen-Hoerth C, Anderson T, Miller B, 2002. The overlap of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal dementia. Neurology 59, 1077&#x2013;1079. doi:10.1212/WNL.59.7.1077</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.59.7.1077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12370467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lui H, Zhang J, Makinson SR, Cahill MK, Kelley KW, Huang H-Y, Shang Y, Oldham MC, Martens LH, Gao F, Coppola G, Sloan SA, Hsieh CL, Kim CC, Bigio EH, Weintraub S, Mesulam M-M, Rademakers R, Mackenzie IR, Seeley WW, Karydas A, Miller BL, Borroni B, Ghidoni R, Farese RV, Paz JT, Barres BA, Huang EJ, 2016. Progranulin deficiency promotes circuit-specific synaptic pruning by microglia via complement activation. Cell 165, 921&#x2013;935. doi:10.1016/j.cell.2016.04.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cell.2016.04.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4860138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27114033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luis E, Ortiz A, Eudave L, Ortega-Cubero S, Borroni B, van der Zee J, Gazzina S, Caroppo P, Rubino E, D&#x2019;Agata F, Le Ber I, Santana I, Cunha G, Almeida MR, Boutoleau-Bretonni&#xe8;re C, Hannequin D, Wallon D, Rainero I, Galimberti D, Van Broeckhoven C, Pastor MA, Pastor P, 2016. Neuroimaging correlates of frontotemporal dementia associated with SQSTM1 mutations. J Alzheimers Dis 53, 303&#x2013;313. doi:10.3233/JAD-160006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/JAD-160006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27163810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lunau L, Mouridsen K, Rodell A, &#xd8;stergaard L, Nielsen JE, Isaacs A, Johannsen P, The FReJA Consortium, 2012. Presymptomatic cerebral blood flow changes in CHMP2B mutation carriers of familial frontotemporal dementia (FTD-3), measured with MRI. BMJ Open 2, e000368. doi:10.1136/bmjopen-2011-000368</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2011-000368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3307039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22422914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lynch T, Sano M, Marder KS, Bell KL, Foster NL, Defendini RF, Sima AA, Keohane C, Nygaard TG, Fahn S, 1994. Clinical characteristics of a family with chromosome 17-linked disinhibition-dementia-parkinsonism-amyotrophy complex. Neurology 44, 1878&#x2013;1884. doi:10.1212/wnl.44.10.1878</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/wnl.44.10.1878</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7936241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackenzie IR, Arzberger T, Kremmer E, Troost D, Lorenzl S, Mori K, Weng S-M, Haass C, Kretzschmar HA, Edbauer D, Neumann M, 2013. Dipeptide repeat protein pathology in C9ORF72 mutation cases: clinico-pathological correlations. Acta Neuropathol 126, 859&#x2013;879. doi:10.1007/s00401-013-1181-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00401-013-1181-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24096617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackenzie IRA, Baker M, Pickering-Brown S, Hsiung G-YR, Lindholm C, Dwosh E, Gass J, Cannon A, Rademakers R, Hutton M, Feldman HH, 2006. The neuropathology of frontotemporal lobar degeneration caused by mutations in the progranulin gene. Brain 129, 3081&#x2013;3090. doi:10.1093/brain/awl271</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awl271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17071926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackenzie IRA, Bigio EH, Ince PG, Geser F, Neumann M, Cairns NJ, Kwong LK, Forman MS, Ravits J, Stewart H, Eisen A, McClusky L, Kretzschmar HA, Monoranu CM, Highley JR, Kirby J, Siddique T, Shaw PJ, Lee VM-Y, Trojanowski JQ, 2007. Pathological TDP-43 distinguishes sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis from amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with SOD1 mutations. Ann Neurol 61, 427&#x2013;434. doi:10.1002/ana.21147</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.21147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17469116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahoney CJ, Beck J, Rohrer JD, Lashley T, Mok K, Shakespeare T, Yeatman T, Warrington EK, Schott JM, Fox NC, Rossor MN, Hardy J, Collinge J, Revesz T, Mead S, Warren JD, 2012a. Frontotemporal dementia with the C9ORF72 hexanucleotide repeat expansion: clinical, neuroanatomical and neuropathological features. Brain 135, 736&#x2013;750. doi:10.1093/brain/awr361</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awr361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3286330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22366791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahoney CJ, Downey LE, Ridgway GR, Beck J, Clegg S, Blair M, Finnegan S, Leung KK, Yeatman T, Golden H, Mead S, Rohrer JD, Fox NC, Warren JD, 2012b. Longitudinal neuroimaging and neuropsychological profiles of frontotemporal dementia with C9ORF72 expansions. Alzheimers Res Ther 4, 41. doi:10.1186/alzrt144</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/alzrt144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3580398</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23006986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahoney CJ, Malone IB, Ridgway GR, Buckley AH, Downey LE, Golden HL, Ryan NS, Ourselin S, Schott JM, Rossor MN, Fox NC, Warren JD, 2013. White matter tract signatures of the progressive aphasias. Neurobiol Aging 34, 1687&#x2013;1699. doi:10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2012.12.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2012.12.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3601331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23312804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahoney CJ, Ridgway GR, Malone IB, Downey LE, Beck J, Kinnunen KM, Schmitz N, Golden HL, Rohrer JD, Schott JM, Rossor MN, Ourselin S, Mead S, Fox NC, Warren JD, 2014. Profiles of white matter tract pathology in frontotemporal dementia. Hum Brain Mapp 35, 4163&#x2013;4179. doi:10.1002/hbm.22468</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hbm.22468</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4312919</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24510641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahoney CJ, Simpson IJA, Nicholas JM, Fletcher PD, Downey LE, Golden HL, Clark CN, Schmitz N, Rohrer JD, Schott JM, Zhang H, Ourselin S, Warren JD, Fox NC, 2015. Longitudinal diffusion tensor imaging in frontotemporal dementia. Ann Neurol 77, 33&#x2013;46. doi:10.1002/ana.24296</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.24296</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4305215</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25363208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandelli ML, Caverzasi E, Binney RJ, Henry ML, Lobach I, Block N, Amirbekian B, Dronkers N, Miller BL, Henry RG, Gorno-Tempini ML, 2014. Frontal white matter tracts sustaining speech production in primary progressive aphasia. J Neurosci 34, 9754&#x2013;9767. doi:10.1523/JNEUROSCI.3464-13.2014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1523/JNEUROSCI.3464-13.2014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4099550</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25031413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marini C, Cistaro A, Campi C, Calvo A, Caponnetto C, Nobili FM, Fania P, Beltrametti MC, Moglia C, Novi G, Buschiazzo A, Perasso A, Canosa A, Scial&#xf2; C, Pomposelli E, Massone AM, Bagnara MC, Cammarosano S, Bruzzi P, Morbelli S, Sambuceti G, Mancardi G, Piana M, Chi&#xf2; A, 2016. A PET/CT approach to spinal cord metabolism in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging 43, 2061&#x2013;2071. doi:10.1007/s00259-016-3440-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00259-016-3440-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5007279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27421971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marroquin N, Stranz S, M&#xfc;ller K, Wieland T, Ruf WP, Brockmann SJ, Danzer KM, Borck G, H&#xfc;bers A, Weydt P, Meitinger T, Strom T-M, Rosenbohm A, Ludolph AC, Weishaupt JH, 2016. Screening for CHCHD10 mutations in a large cohort of sporadic ALS patients: no evidence for pathogenicity of the p.P34S variant. Brain 139, e8&#x2013;e8. doi:10.1093/brain/awv218</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awv218</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5963426</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26362909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masuda M, Senda J, Watanabe H, Epifanio B, Tanaka Y, Imai K, Riku Y, Li Y, Nakamura R, Ito M, Ishigaki S, Atsuta N, Koike H, Katsuno M, Hattori N, Naganawa S, Sobue G, 2016. Involvement of the caudate nucleus head and its networks in sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-frontotemporal dementia continuum. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 17, 571&#x2013;579. doi:10.1080/21678421.2016.1211151</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/21678421.2016.1211151</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27684890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCombe PA, Ngo ST, Guo CC, Fazlollahi A, Bollmann S, Wang L, Hu X, Barth M, Salvado O, Davis M, Ceslis A, Robinson G, Henderson RD, Steyn FJ, 2018. Patient with ALS with a novel TBK1 mutation, widespread brain involvement, behaviour changes and metabolic dysfunction. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 90, 952&#x2013;954. doi:10.1136/jnnp-2018-318823</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp-2018-318823</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6691862</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30196251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMillan CT, Russ J, Wood EM, Irwin DJ, Grossman M, McCluskey L, Elman L, Van Deerlin V, Lee EB, 2015. C9orf72 promoter hypermethylation is neuroprotective: Neuroimaging and neuropathologic evidence. Neurology 84, 1622&#x2013;1630. doi:10.1212/WNL.0000000000001495</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000001495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4409587</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25795648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menke RAL, K&#xf6;rner S, Filippini N, Douaud G, Knight S, Talbot K, Turner MR, 2014. Widespread grey matter pathology dominates the longitudinal cerebral MRI and clinical landscape of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain 137, 2546&#x2013;2555. doi:10.1093/brain/awu162</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awu162</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4132644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24951638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menke RAL, Proudfoot M, Talbot K, Turner MR, 2018. The two-year progression of structural and functional cerebral MRI in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. NeuroImage Clin 17, 953&#x2013;961. doi:10.1016/j.nicl.2017.12.025</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nicl.2017.12.025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5752097</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29321969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menke RAL, Proudfoot M, Wuu J, Andersen PM, Talbot K, Benatar M, Turner MR, 2016. Increased functional connectivity common to symptomatic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and those at genetic risk. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 87, 580&#x2013;588. doi:10.1136/jnnp-2015-311945</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp-2015-311945</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4893149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26733601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mesulam M-M, 2003. Primary progressive aphasia &#x2014; a language-based dementia. N Engl J Med 349, 1535&#x2013;1542. doi:10.1056/NEJMra022435</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMra022435</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14561797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mezzapesa DM, D&#x2019;Errico E, Tortelli R, Distaso E, Cortese R, Tursi M, Federico F, Zoccolella S, Logroscino G, Dicuonzo F, Simone IL, 2013. Cortical thinning and clinical heterogeneity in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. PLoS One 8, e80748. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0080748</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0080748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3835750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24278317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Millecamps S, Boill&#xe9;e S, Le Ber I, Seilhean D, Teyssou E, Giraudeau M, Moigneu C, Vandenberghe N, Danel-Brunaud V, Corcia P, Pradat P-F, Le Forestier N, Lacomblez L, Bruneteau G, Camu W, Brice A, Cazeneuve C, LeGuern E, Meininger V, Salachas F, 2012. Phenotype difference between ALS patients with expanded repeats in C9ORF72 and patients with mutations in other ALS-related genes. J Med Genet 49, 258&#x2013;263. doi:10.1136/jmedgenet-2011-100699</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jmedgenet-2011-100699</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22499346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyoshi M, Shinotoh H, Wszolek ZK, Strongosky AJ, Shimada H, Arakawa R, Higuchi M, Ikoma Y, Yasuno F, Fukushi K, Irie T, Ito H, Suhara T, 2010. In vivo detection of neuropathologic changes in presymptomatic MAPT mutation carriers: a PET and MRI study. Parkinsonism Relat Disord 16, 404&#x2013;408. doi:10.1016/j.parkreldis.2010.04.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.parkreldis.2010.04.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20452812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammadi B, Kollewe K, Samii A, Krampfl K, Dengler R, M&#xfc;nte TF, 2009. Changes of resting state brain networks in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Exp Neurol 217, 147&#x2013;153. doi:10.1016/j.expneurol.2009.01.025</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.expneurol.2009.01.025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19416664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montalbetti L, Ratti MT, Greco B, Aprile C, Moglia A, Soragna D, 2005. Neuropsychological tests and functional nuclear neuroimaging provide evidence of subclinical impairment in Nasu-Hakola disease heterozygotes. Funct Neurol 20, 71&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15966270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morbelli S, Ferrara M, Fiz F, Dessi B, Arnaldi D, Picco A, Bossert I, Buschiazzo A, Accardo J, Picori L, Girtler N, Mandich P, Pagani M, Sambuceti G, Nobili F, 2016. Mapping brain morphological and functional conversion patterns in predementia late-onset bvFTD. Eur J Nucl Med Mol I 43, 1337&#x2013;1347. doi:10.1007/s00259-016-3335-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00259-016-3335-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26928581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreno F, Rabinovici GD, Karydas A, Miller Z, Hsu SC, Legati A, Fong J, Schonhaut D, Esselmann H, Watson C, Stephens ML, Kramer J, Wiltfang J, Seeley WW, Miller BL, Coppola G, Grinberg LT, 2015. A novel mutation P112H in the TARDBP gene associated with frontotemporal lobar degeneration without motor neuron disease and abundant neuritic amyloid plaques. Acta Neuropathol Commun 3, 19. doi:10.1186/s40478-015-0190-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40478-015-0190-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4382926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25853458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreno F, Sala-Llonch R, Barandiaran M, S&#xe1;nchez-Valle R, Estanga A, Bartr&#xe9;s-Faz D, Sistiaga A, Alzualde A, Fern&#xe1;ndez E, Mart&#xed; Mass&#xf3; JF, L&#xf3;pez de Munain A, Indakoetxea B, 2013. Distinctive age-related temporal cortical thinning in asymptomatic granulin gene mutation carriers. Neurobiol Aging 34, 1462&#x2013;1468. doi:10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2012.11.005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2012.11.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23218900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mori K, Weng S-M, Arzberger T, May S, Rentzsch K, Kremmer E, Schmid B, Kretzschmar HA, Cruts M, Van Broeckhoven C, Haass C, Edbauer D, 2013. The C9orf72 GGGGCC repeat is translated into aggregating dipeptide-repeat proteins in FTLD/ALS. Science 339, 1335&#x2013;1338. doi:10.1126/science.1232927</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.1232927</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23393093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller H-P, Agosta F, Riva N, Spinelli EG, Comi G, Ludolph AC, Filippi M, Kassubek J, 2018. Fast progressive lower motor neuron disease is an ALS variant: A two-centre tract of interest-based MRI data analysis. NeuroImage Clin 17, 145&#x2013;152. doi:10.1016/j.nicl.2017.10.008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nicl.2017.10.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5651542</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29071208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller H-P, Del Tredici K, Lul&#xe9; D, M&#xfc;ller K, Weishaupt JH, Ludolph AC, Kassubek J, 2020. In vivo histopathological staging in C9orf72-associated ALS: A tract of interest DTI study. NeuroImage Clin 27, 102298. doi:10.1016/j.nicl.2020.102298</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nicl.2020.102298</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7270604</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32505118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller H-P, Turner MR, Grosskreutz J, Abrahams S, Bede P, Govind V, Prudlo J, Ludolph AC, Filippi M, Kassubek J, 2016. A large-scale multicentre cerebral diffusion tensor imaging study in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 87, 570&#x2013;579. doi:10.1136/jnnp-2015-311952</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp-2015-311952</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26746186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller K, Andersen PM, H&#xfc;bers A, Marroquin N, Volk AE, Danzer KM, Meitinger T, Ludolph AC, Strom TM, Weishaupt JH, 2014. Two novel mutations in conserved codons indicate that CHCHD10 is a gene associated with motor neuron disease. Brain 137, e309&#x2013;e309. doi:10.1093/brain/awu227</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awu227</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25113787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munoz DG, Ros R, Fatas M, Bermejo F, de Yebenes JG, 2007. Progressive nonfluent aphasia associated with a new mutation V363I in tau gene. Am J Alzheimers Dis Other Demen 22, 294&#x2013;299. doi:10.1177/1533317507302320</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1533317507302320</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17712160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy NA, Arthur KC, Tienari PJ, Houlden H, Chi&#xf2; A, Traynor BJ, 2017. Age-related penetrance of the C9orf72 repeat expansion. Sci Rep 7, 2116. doi:10.1038/s41598-017-02364-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-017-02364-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5437033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28522837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murray ME, DeJesus-Hernandez M, Rutherford NJ, Baker M, Duara R, Graff-Radford NR, Wszolek ZK, Ferman TJ, Josephs KA, Boylan KB, Rademakers R, Dickson DW, 2011. Clinical and neuropathologic heterogeneity of c9FTD/ALS associated with hexanucleotide repeat expansion in C9ORF72. Acta Neuropathol 122, 673&#x2013;690. doi:10.1007/s00401-011-0907-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00401-011-0907-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3277860</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22083254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mutsaerts HJMM, Mirza SS, Petr J, Thomas DL, Cash DM, Bocchetta M, de Vita E, Metcalfe AWS, Shirzadi Z, Robertson AD, Tartaglia MC, Mitchell SB, Black SE, Freedman M, Tang-Wai D, Keren R, Rogaeva E, van Swieten J, Laforce R, Tagliavini F, Borroni B, Galimberti D, Rowe JB, Graff C, Frisoni GB, Finger E, Sorbi S, de Mendon&#xe7;a A, Rohrer JD, MacIntosh BJ, Masellis M, GENetic Frontotemporal dementia Initiative (GENFI), Andersson, C., Archetti S, Arighi A, Benussi L, Binetti G, Cosseddu M, Dick KM, Fallstr&#xf6;m M, Ferreira C, Fenoglio C, Fox NC, Fumagalli G, Gazzina S, Ghidoni R, Grisoli M, Jelic V, Jiskoot L, Lombardi G, Maruta C, Mead S, Meeter L, van Minkelen R, Nacmias B, &#xd6;ijerstedt L, Ourselin S, Padovani A, Panman J, Pievani M, Polito C, Premi E, Prioni S, Rademakers R, Redaelli V, Rossi G, Rossor MN, Scarpini E, Thonberg H, Tiraboschi P, Verdelho A, Warren JD, 2019. Cerebral perfusion changes in presymptomatic genetic frontotemporal dementia: a GENFI study. Brain 142, 1108&#x2013;1120. doi:10.1093/brain/awz039</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awz039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6439322</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30847466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neary D, Snowden JS, Gustafson L, Passant U, Stuss D, Black S, Freedman M, Kertesz A, Robert PH, Albert M, Boone K, Miller BL, Cummings J, Benson DF, 1998. Frontotemporal lobar degeneration: a consensus on clinical diagnostic criteria. Neurology 51, 1546&#x2013;1554. doi:10.1212/WNL.51.6.1546</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.51.6.1546</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9855500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neumann M, Mackenzie IRA, 2019. Review: neuropathology of non-tau frontotemporal lobar degeneration. Neuropathol Appl Neurobiol 45, 19&#x2013;40. doi:10.1111/nan.12526</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/nan.12526</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30357887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ng M-C, Ho JT, Ho S-L, Lee R, Li G, Cheng T-S, Song Y-Q, Ho PW-L, Fong GC-Y, Mak W, Chan K-H, Li LS-W, Luk KD-K, Hu Y, Ramsden DB, Leong LL-Y, 2008. Abnormal diffusion tensor in nonsymptomatic familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with a causative superoxide dismutase 1 mutation. J Magn Reson Imaging 27, 8&#x2013;13. doi:10.1002/jmri.21217</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmri.21217</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18022844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen HP, Van Broeckhoven C, van der Zee J, 2018. ALS genes in the genomic era and their implications for FTD. Trends Genet 34, 404&#x2013;423. doi:10.1016/j.tig.2018.03.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tig.2018.03.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29605155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olm CA, McMillan CT, Irwin DJ, Van Deerlin VM, Cook PA, Gee JC, Grossman M, 2018. Longitudinal structural gray matter and white matter MRI changes in presymptomatic progranulin mutation carriers. NeuroImage Clin 19, 497&#x2013;506. doi:10.1016/j.nicl.2018.05.017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nicl.2018.05.017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6029561</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29984158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olney NT, Ong E, Goh S-YM, Bajorek L, Dever R, Staffaroni AM, Cobigo Y, Bock M, Chiang K, Ljubenkov P, Kornak J, Heuer HW, Wang P, Rascovsky K, Wolf A, Appleby B, Bove J, Bordelon Y, Brannelly P, Brushaber D, Caso C, Coppola G, Dickerson BC, Dickinson S, Domoto-Reilly K, Faber K, Ferrall J, Fields J, Fishman A, Fong J, Foroud T, Forsberg LK, Gearhart DJ, Ghazanfari B, Ghoshal N, Goldman J, Graff-Radford J, Graff-Radford NR, Grant I, Grossman M, Haley D, Hsiung G, Huey ED, Irwin DJ, Jones DT, Kantarci K, Karydas AM, Kaufer D, Kerwin D, Knopman DS, Kramer JH, Kraft R, Kremers W, Kukull W, Lapid MI, Litvan I, Mackenzie IR, Maldonado M, Manoochehri M, McGinnis SM, McKinley EC, Mendez MF, Miller BL, Onyike C, Pantelyat A, Pearlman R, Petrucelli L, Potter M, Rademakers R, Ramos EM, Rankin KP, Roberson ED, Rogalski E, Sengdy P, Shaw LM, Syrjanen J, Tartaglia MC, Tatton N, Taylor J, Toga A, Trojanowski JQ, Weintraub S, Wong B, Wszolek Z, Boxer AL, Boeve BF, Rosen HJ, 2020. Clinical and volumetric changes with increasing functional impairment in familial frontotemporal lobar degeneration. Alzheimers Dement 16, 49&#x2013;59. doi:10.1016/j.jalz.2019.08.196</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jalz.2019.08.196</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6988137</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31784375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Omer T, Finegan E, Hutchinson S, Doherty M, Vajda A, McLaughlin RL, Pender N, Hardiman O, Bede P, 2017. Neuroimaging patterns along the ALS-FTD spectrum: a multiparametric imaging study. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 18, 611&#x2013;623. doi:10.1080/21678421.2017.1332077</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/21678421.2017.1332077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28562080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Origone P, Geroldi A, Lamp M, Sanguineri F, Caponnetto C, Cabona C, Gotta F, Trevisan L, Bellone E, Manganelli F, Devigili G, Mandich P, 2018. Role of MAPT in pure motor neuron disease: report of a recurrent mutation in Italian patients. Neurodegener Dis 18, 310&#x2013;314. doi:10.1159/000497820</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000497820</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30893702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pagani M, Chio A, Valentini MC, Oberg J, Nobili F, Calvo A, Moglia C, Bertuzzo D, Morbelli S, De Carli F, Fania P, Cistaro A, 2014. Functional pattern of brain FDG-PET in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology 83, 1067&#x2013;1074. doi:10.1212/WNL.0000000000000792</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000000792</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25122207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paloneva J, Manninen T, Christman G, Hovanes K, Mandelin J, Adolfsson R, Bianchin M, Bird T, Miranda R, Salmaggi A, Tranebj&#xe6;rg L, Konttinen Y, Peltonen L, 2002. Mutations in two genes encoding different subunits of a receptor signaling complex result in an identical disease phenotype. Am J Hum Genet 71, 656&#x2013;662. doi:10.1086/342259</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1086/342259</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC379202</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12080485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panman JL, Jiskoot LC, Bouts MJRJ, Meeter LHH, van der Ende EL, Poos JM, Feis RA, Kievit AJA, van Minkelen R, Dopper EGP, Rombouts SARB, van Swieten JC, Papma JM, 2019. Gray and white matter changes in presymptomatic genetic frontotemporal dementia: a longitudinal MRI study. Neurobiol Aging 76, 115&#x2013;124. doi:10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2018.12.017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2018.12.017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30711674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papma JM, Jiskoot LC, Panman JL, Dopper EG, den Heijer T, Donker Kaat L, Pijnenburg YAL, Meeter LH, van Minkelen R, Rombouts SARB, van Swieten JC, 2017. Cognition and gray and white matter characteristics of presymptomatic C9orf72 repeat expansion. Neurology 89, 1256&#x2013;1264. doi:10.1212/WNL.0000000000004393</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000004393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28855404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paternic&#xf2; D, Premi E, Gazzina S, Cosseddu M, Alberici A, Archetti S, Cotelli MS, Micheli A, Turla M, Gasparotti R, Padovani A, Borroni B, 2016. White matter hyperintensities characterize monogenic frontotemporal dementia with granulin mutations. Neurobiol Aging 38, 176&#x2013;180. doi:10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2015.11.011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2015.11.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26827655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Penttil&#xe4; S, Jokela M, Bouquin H, Saukkonen AM, Toivanen J, Udd B, 2015. Late onset spinal motor neuronopathy is caused by mutation in CHCHD10. Ann Neurol 77, 163&#x2013;172. doi:10.1002/ana.24319</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.24319</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25428574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perry DC, Lehmann M, Yokoyama JS, Karydas A, Lee JJ, Coppola G, Grinberg LT, Geschwind D, Seeley WW, Miller BL, Rosen H, Rabinovici G, 2013. Progranulin mutations as risk factors for Alzheimer disease. JAMA Neurol 70, 774&#x2013;778. doi:10.1001/2013.jamaneurol.393</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/2013.jamaneurol.393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3743672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23609919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perry DC, Whitwell JL, Boeve BF, Pankratz VS, Knopman DS, Petersen RC, Jack CR, Josephs KA, 2012. Voxel-based morphometry in patients with obsessivecompulsive behaviors in behavioral variant frontotemporal dementia: Compulsions in FTD. Eur J Neurol 19, 911&#x2013;917. doi:10.1111/j.1468-1331.2011.03656.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1468-1331.2011.03656.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3351534</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22284815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petkau TL, Leavitt BR, 2014. Progranulin in neurodegenerative disease. Trends Neurosci 37, 388&#x2013;398. doi:10.1016/j.tins.2014.04.003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tins.2014.04.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24800652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pievani M, Paternic&#xf2; D, Benussi L, Binetti G, Orlandini A, Cobelli M, Magnaldi S, Ghidoni R, Frisoni GB, 2014. Pattern of structural and functional brain abnormalities in asymptomatic granulin mutation carriers. Alzheimers Dement 10, S354&#x2013;S363.e1. doi:10.1016/j.jalz.2013.09.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jalz.2013.09.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24418059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piguet O, Peters&#xe9;n &#xc5;, Yin Ka Lam B, Gabery S, Murphy K, Hodges JR, Halliday GM, 2011. Eating and hypothalamus changes in behavioral-variant frontotemporal dementia. Ann Neurol 69, 312&#x2013;319. doi:10.1002/ana.22244</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.22244</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3084499</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21387376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poorkaj P, Bird TD, Wijsman E, Nemens E, Garruto RM, Anderson L, Andreadis A, Wiederholt WC, Raskind M, Schellenberg GD, 1998. Tau is a candidate gene for chromosome 17 frontotemporal dementia. Ann Neurol 43, 815&#x2013;825. doi:10.1002/ana.410430617</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.410430617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9629852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Popuri K, Dowds E, Beg MF, Balachandar R, Bhalla M, Jacova C, Buller A, Slack P, Sengdy P, Rademakers R, Wittenberg D, Feldman HH, Mackenzie IR, Hsiung G-YR, 2018. Gray matter changes in asymptomatic C9orf72 and GRN mutation carriers. NeuroImage Clin 18, 591&#x2013;598. doi:10.1016/j.nicl.2018.02.017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nicl.2018.02.017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5964622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29845007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pottier C, Bieniek KF, Finch N, van de Vorst M, Baker M, Perkersen R, Brown P, Ravenscroft T, van Blitterswijk M, Nicholson AM, DeTure M, Knopman DS, Josephs KA, Parisi JE, Petersen RC, Boylan KB, Boeve BF, Graff-Radford NR, Veltman JA, Gilissen C, Murray ME, Dickson DW, Rademakers R, 2015. Whole-genome sequencing reveals important role for TBK1 and OPTN mutations in frontotemporal lobar degeneration without motor neuron disease. Acta Neuropathol 130, 77&#x2013;92. doi:10.1007/s00401-015-1436-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00401-015-1436-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4470809</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25943890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poujois A, Schneider FC, Faillenot I, Camdessanch&#xe9; J-P, Vandenberghe N, Thomas-Ant&#xe9;rion C, Antoine JC, 2013. Brain plasticity in the motor network is correlated with disease progression in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: functional cerebral reorganization, disease progression, and ALS. Hum Brain Mapp 34, 2391&#x2013;2401. doi:10.1002/hbm.22070</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hbm.22070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6870334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22461315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Premi E, Cauda F, Costa T, Diano M, Gazzina S, Gualeni V, Alberici A, Archetti S, Magoni M, Gasparotti R, Padovani A, Borroni B, 2016. Looking for neuroimaging markers in frontotemporal lobar degeneration clinical trials: a multi-voxel pattern analysis study in granulin disease. J Alzheimers Dis 51, 249&#x2013;262. doi:10.3233/JAD-150340</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/JAD-150340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26836150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Premi E, Cauda F, Gasparotti R, Diano M, Silvana Archetti, Padovani A, Borroni B, 2014. Multimodal fMRI resting-state functional connectivity in granulin mutations: the case of fronto-parietal dementia. PLoS One 9, e106500. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0106500</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0106500</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4154688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25188321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pyra T, Hui B, Hanstock C, Concha L, Wong JCT, Beaulieu C, Johnston W, Kalra S, 2010. Combined structural and neurochemical evaluation of the corticospinal tract in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler 11, 157&#x2013;165. doi:10.3109/17482960902756473</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/17482960902756473</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19242831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiu T, Zhang Y, Tang X, Liu X, Wang Y, Zhou C, Luo C, Zhang J, 2019. Precentral degeneration and cerebellar compensation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a multimodal MRI analysis. Hum Brain Mapp 40, 3464&#x2013;3474. doi:10.1002/hbm.24609</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hbm.24609</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6865414</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31020731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Querin G, Bede P, El Mendili MM, Li M, P&#xe9;l&#xe9;grini-Issac M, Rinaldi D, Catala M, Saracino D, Salachas F, Camuzat A, Marchand-Pauvert V, Cohen-Adad J, Colliot O, Le Ber I, Pradat P, for The Predict to Prevent Frontotemporal Lobar Degeneration and Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis (PREV DEMALS) Study Group, 2019. Presymptomatic spinal cord pathology in c9orf72 mutation carriers: a longitudinal neuroimaging study. Ann Neurol. doi:10.1002/ana.25520</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.25520</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31177556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rademakers R, Stewart H, Dejesus-Hernandez M, Krieger C, Graff-Radford N, Fabros M, Briemberg H, Cashman N, Eisen A, Mackenzie IRA, 2010. Fus gene mutations in familial and sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve 42, 170&#x2013;176. doi:10.1002/mus.21665</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.21665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2969843</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20544928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rankin KP, Gorno-Tempini ML, Allison SC, Stanley CM, Glenn S, Weiner MW, Miller BL, 2006. Structural anatomy of empathy in neurodegenerative disease. Brain 129, 2945&#x2013;2956. doi:10.1093/brain/awl254</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awl254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2562652</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17008334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rascovsky K, Hodges JR, Knopman D, Mendez MF, Kramer JH, Neuhaus J, van Swieten JC, Seelaar H, Dopper EGP, Onyike CU, Hillis AE, Josephs KA, Boeve BF, Kertesz A, Seeley WW, Rankin KP, Johnson JK, Gorno-Tempini M-L, Rosen H, Prioleau-Latham CE, Lee A, Kipps CM, Lillo P, Piguet O, Rohrer JD, Rossor MN, Warren JD, Fox NC, Galasko D, Salmon DP, Black SE, Mesulam M, Weintraub S, Dickerson BC, Diehl-Schmid J, Pasquier F, Deramecourt V, Lebert F, Pijnenburg Y, Chow TW, Manes F, Grafman J, Cappa SF, Freedman M, Grossman M, Miller BL, 2011. Sensitivity of revised diagnostic criteria for the behavioural variant of frontotemporal dementia. Brain 134, 2456&#x2013;2477. doi:10.1093/brain/awr179</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awr179</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3170532</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21810890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rayaprolu S, Mullen B, Baker M, Lynch T, Finger E, Seeley WW, Hatanpaa KJ, Lomen-Hoerth C, Kertesz A, Bigio EH, Lippa C, Josephs KA, Knopman DS, White CL, Caselli R, Mackenzie IR, Miller BL, Boczarska-Jedynak M, Opala G, Krygowska-Wajs A, Barcikowska M, Younkin SG, Petersen RC, Ertekin-Taner N, Uitti RJ, Meschia JF, Boylan KB, Boeve BF, Graff-Radford NR, Wszolek ZK, Dickson DW, Rademakers R, Ross OA, 2013. TREM2 in neurodegeneration: evidence for association of the p.R47H variant with frontotemporal dementia and Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Mol Neurodegener 8, 19. doi:10.1186/1750-1326-8-19</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1750-1326-8-19</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3691612</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23800361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rea SL, Majcher V, Searle MS, Layfield R, 2014. SQSTM1 mutations &#x2013; bridging Paget disease of bone and ALS/FTLD. Exp Cell Res 325, 27&#x2013;37. doi:10.1016/j.yexcr.2014.01.020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.yexcr.2014.01.020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24486447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renton AE, Chi&#xf2; A, Traynor BJ, 2014. State of play in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis genetics. Nat Neurosci 17, 17&#x2013;23. doi:10.1038/nn.3584</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nn.3584</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4544832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24369373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renton AE, Majounie E, Waite A, Sim&#xf3;n-S&#xe1;nchez J, Rollinson S, Gibbs JR, Schymick JC, Laaksovirta H, van Swieten JC, Myllykangas L, Kalimo H, Paetau A, Abramzon Y, Remes AM, Kaganovich A, Scholz SW, Duckworth J, Ding J, Harmer DW, Hernandez DG, Johnson JO, Mok K, Ryten M, Trabzuni D, Guerreiro RJ, Orrell RW, Neal J, Murray A, Pearson J, Jansen IE, Sondervan D, Seelaar H, Blake D, Young K, Halliwell N, Callister JB, Toulson G, Richardson A, Gerhard A, Snowden J, Mann D, Neary D, Nalls MA, Peuralinna T, Jansson L, Isoviita V-M, Kaivorinne A-L, H&#xf6;ltt&#xe4;-Vuori M, Ikonen E, Sulkava R, Benatar M, Wuu J, Chi&#xf2; A, Restagno G, Borghero G, Sabatelli M, Heckerman D, Rogaeva E, Zinman L, Rothstein JD, Sendtner M, Drepper C, Eichler EE, Alkan C, Abdullaev Z, Pack SD, Dutra A, Pak E, Hardy J, Singleton A, Williams NM, Heutink P, Pickering-Brown S, Morris HR, Tienari PJ, Traynor BJ, 2011. A hexanucleotide repeat expansion in C9ORF72 is the cause of chromosome 9p21-linked ALS-FTD. Neuron 72, 257&#x2013;268. doi:10.1016/j.neuron.2011.09.010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuron.2011.09.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3200438</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21944779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rezaie T, 2002. Adult-onset primary open-angle glaucoma caused by mutations in optineurin. Science 295, 1077&#x2013;1079. doi:10.1126/science.1066901</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.1066901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11834836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ringholz GM, Appel SH, Bradshaw M, Cooke NA, Mosnik DM, Schulz PE, 2005. Prevalence and patterns of cognitive impairment in sporadic ALS. Neurology 65, 586&#x2013;590. doi:10.1212/01.wnl.0000172911.39167.b6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/01.wnl.0000172911.39167.b6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16116120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogalski E, Cobia D, Harrison TM, Wieneke C, Weintraub S, Mesulam M-M, 2011. Progression of language decline and cortical atrophy in subtypes of primary progressive aphasia. Neurology 76, 1804&#x2013;1810. doi:10.1212/WNL.0b013e31821ccd3c</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0b013e31821ccd3c</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3100122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21606451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rohrer JD, Ahsan RL, Isaacs AM, Nielsen JE, Ostergaard L, Scahill R, Warren JD, Rossor MN, Fox NC, Johannsen P, 2009a. Presymptomatic generalized brain atrophy in frontotemporal dementia caused by CHMP2B mutation. Dement Geriatr Cogn Disord 27, 182&#x2013;186. doi:10.1159/000200466</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000200466</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19202337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rohrer JD, Clarkson MJ, Kittus R, Rossor MN, Ourselin S, Warren JD, Fox NC, 2012. Rates of hemispheric and lobar atrophy in the language variants of frontotemporal lobar degeneration. J Alzheimers Dis 30, 407&#x2013;411. doi:10.3233/JAD-2012-111556</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/JAD-2012-111556</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4606976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22406442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rohrer JD, Guerreiro R, Vandrovcova J, Uphill J, Reiman D, Beck J, Isaacs AM, Authier A, Ferrari R, Fox NC, Mackenzie IRA, Warren JD, de Silva R, Holton J, Revesz T, Hardy J, Mead S, Rossor MN, 2009b. The heritability and genetics of frontotemporal lobar degeneration. Neurology 73, 1451&#x2013;1456. doi:10.1212/WNL.0b013e3181bf997a</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0b013e3181bf997a</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2779007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19884572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rohrer JD, Lashley T, Schott JM, Warren JE, Mead S, Isaacs AM, Beck J, Hardy J, de Silva R, Warrington E, Troakes C, Al-Sarraj S, King A, Borroni B, Clarkson MJ, Ourselin S, Holton JL, Fox NC, Revesz T, Rossor MN, Warren JD, 2011a. Clinical and neuroanatomical signatures of tissue pathology in frontotemporal lobar degeneration. Brain 134, 2565&#x2013;2581. doi:10.1093/brain/awr198</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awr198</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3170537</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21908872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rohrer JD, Nicholas JM, Cash DM, van Swieten J, Dopper E, Jiskoot L, van Minkelen R, Rombouts SA, Cardoso MJ, Clegg S, Espak M, Mead S, Thomas DL, De Vita E, Masellis M, Black SE, Freedman M, Keren R, MacIntosh BJ, Rogaeva E, Tang-Wai D, Tartaglia MC, Laforce R, Tagliavini F, Tiraboschi P, Redaelli V, Prioni S, Grisoli M, Borroni B, Padovani A, Galimberti D, Scarpini E, Arighi A, Fumagalli G, Rowe JB, Coyle-Gilchrist I, Graff C, Fallstr&#xf6;m M, Jelic V, St&#xe5;hlbom AK, Andersson C, Thonberg H, Lilius L, Frisoni GB, Binetti G, Pievani M, Bocchetta M, Benussi L, Ghidoni R, Finger E, Sorbi S, Nacmias B, Lombardi G, Polito C, Warren JD, Ourselin S, Fox NC, Rossor MN, 2015. Presymptomatic cognitive and neuroanatomical changes in genetic frontotemporal dementia in the Genetic Frontotemporal dementia Initiative (GENFI) study: a cross-sectional analysis. Lancet Neurol 14, 253&#x2013;262. doi:10.1016/S1474-4422(14)70324-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1474-4422(14)70324-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6742501</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25662776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rohrer JD, Ridgway GR, Modat M, Ourselin S, Mead S, Fox NC, Rossor MN, Warren JD, 2010. Distinct profiles of brain atrophy in frontotemporal lobar degeneration caused by progranulin and tau mutations. NeuroImage 53, 1070&#x2013;1076. doi:10.1016/j.neuroimage.2009.12.088</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuroimage.2009.12.088</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2941039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20045477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rohrer JD, Warren JD, 2011. Phenotypic signatures of genetic frontotemporal dementia. Curr Opin Neurol 24, 542&#x2013;549. doi:10.1097/WCO.0b013e32834cd442</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/WCO.0b013e32834cd442</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21986680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rohrer JD, Warren JD, Modat M, Ridgway GR, Douiri A, Rossor MN, Ourselin S, Fox NC, 2009c. Patterns of cortical thinning in the language variants of frontotemporal lobar degeneration. Neurology 72, 1562&#x2013;1569. doi:10.1212/WNL.0b013e3181a4124e</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0b013e3181a4124e</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2827264</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19414722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rohrer JD, Warren JD, Reiman D, Uphill J, Beck J, Collinge J, Rossor MN, Isaacs AM, Mead S, 2011b. A novel exon 2 I27V VCP variant is associated with dissimilar clinical syndromes. J Neurol 258, 1494&#x2013;1496. doi:10.1007/s00415-011-5966-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00415-011-5966-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4606971</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21387114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ronchi D, Riboldi G, Del Bo R, Ticozzi N, Scarlato M, Galimberti D, Corti S, Silani V, Bresolin N, Comi GP, 2015. CHCHD10 mutations in Italian patients with sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain 138, e372&#x2013;e372. doi:10.1093/brain/awu384</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awu384</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25576308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosen HJ, Allison SC, Schauer GF, Gorno-Tempini ML, Weiner MW, Miller BL, 2005. Neuroanatomical correlates of behavioural disorders in dementia. Brain 128, 2612&#x2013;2625. doi:10.1093/brain/awh628</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awh628</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1820861</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16195246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosen HJ, Gorno&#x2013;Tempini ML, Goldman WP, Perry RJ, Schuff N, Weiner M, Feiwell R, Kramer JH, Miller BL, 2002. Patterns of brain atrophy in frontotemporal dementia and semantic dementia. Neurology 58, 198&#x2013;208. doi:10.1212/WNL.58.2.198</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.58.2.198</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11805245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosso SM, Roks G, Stevens M, de Koning I, Tanghe HLJ, Kamphorst W, Ravid R, Niermeijer MF, van Swieten JC, 2001. Complex compulsive behaviour in the temporal variant of frontotemporal dementia. J Neurol 248, 965&#x2013;970. doi:10.1007/s004150170049</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s004150170049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11757960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rothstein JD, 2009. Current hypotheses for the underlying biology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol 65, S3&#x2013;S9. doi:10.1002/ana.21543</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.21543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19191304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rubino E, Rainero I, Chi&#xf2; A, Rogaeva E, Galimberti D, Fenoglio P, Grinberg Y, Isaia G, Calvo A, Gentile S, Bruni AC, St. George-Hyslop PH, Scarpini E, Gallone S, Pinessi L, For the TODEM Study Group, 2012. SQSTM1 mutations in frontotemporal lobar degeneration and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology 79, 1556&#x2013;1562. doi:10.1212/WNL.0b013e31826e25df</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0b013e31826e25df</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3655323</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22972638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rytty R, Nikkinen J, Paavola L, Abou Elseoud A, Moilanen V, Visuri A, Tervonen O, Renton AE, Traynor BJ, Kiviniemi V, Remes AM, 2013. GroupICA dual regression analysis of resting state networks in a behavioral variant of frontotemporal dementia. Front Hum Neurosci 7, 461. doi:10.3389/fnhum.2013.00461</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnhum.2013.00461</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3752460</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23986673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rytty R, Nikkinen J, Suhonen N, Moilanen V, Renton AE, Traynor BJ, Tervonen O, Kiviniemi V, Remes AM, 2014. Functional MRI in patients with the C9ORF72 expansion associate frontotemporal dementia. Mol Biol 03. doi:10.4172/2168-9547.1000117</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4172/2168-9547.1000117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saberi S, Stauffer JE, Schulte DJ, Ravits J, 2015. Neuropathology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and its variants. Neurol Clin 33, 855&#x2013;876. doi:10.1016/j.ncl.2015.07.012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ncl.2015.07.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4628785</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26515626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saracino D, Clot F, Camuzat A, Anquetil V, Hannequin D, Guyant-Mar&#xe9;chal L, Didic M, Guillot-No&#xeb;l L, Rinaldi D, Latouche M, Forlani S, Ghassab Y, Coppola C, Di Iorio G, David I, Le Guern E, Brice A, Le Ber I, 2018. Novel VCP mutations expand the mutational spectrum of frontotemporal dementia. Neurobiol Aging 72, 187.e11&#x2013;187.e14. doi:10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2018.06.037</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2018.06.037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30005904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld MA, Tempelmann C, Gaul C, K&#xfc;hnel GR, D&#xfc;zel E, Hopf J-M, Feistner H, Zierz S, Heinze H-J, Vielhaber S, 2005. Functional motor compensation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol 252, 944&#x2013;952. doi:10.1007/s00415-005-0787-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00415-005-0787-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15750701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sch&#xf6;necker S, Brendel M, van der Zee J, van Broeckhoven C, Rominger A, Danek A, Levin J, 2016. Ein Geschwisterpaar mit frontotemporaler Lob&#xe4;rdegeneration und amyotropher Lateralsklerose und einer neuen Mutation im TBK1-Gen (Thr462Lysfs). Fortschr Neurol Psychiatr 84, 494&#x2013;498. doi:10.1055/s-0042-110653</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0042-110653</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27570907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sch&#xf6;necker S, Neuhofer C, Otto M, Ludolph A, Kassubek J, Landwehrmeyer B, Anderl-Straub S, Semler E, Diehl-Schmid J, Prix C, Vollmar C, Fortea J, Deutsches FTLD-Konsortium, Huppertz H-J, Arzberger T, Edbauer D, Feddersen B, Dieterich M, Schroeter ML, Volk AE, Flie&#xdf;bach K, Schneider A, Kornhuber J, Maler M, Prudlo J, Jahn H, Boeckh-Behrens T, Danek A, Klopstock T, Levin J, 2018. Atrophy in the thalamus but not cerebellum is specific for C9orf72 FTD and ALS patients &#x2013; an atlas-based volumetric MRI study. Front Aging Neurosci 10, 45. doi:10.3389/fnagi.2018.00045</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnagi.2018.00045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5863593</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29599716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schroeter ML, Raczka K, Neumann J, Yves von Cramon D, 2007. Towards a nosology for frontotemporal lobar degenerations&#x2014;A meta-analysis involving 267 subjects. NeuroImage 36, 497&#x2013;510. doi:10.1016/j.neuroimage.2007.03.024</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuroimage.2007.03.024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17478101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwindt GC, Graham NL, Rochon E, Tang-Wai DF, Lobaugh NJ, Chow TW, Black SE, 2013. Whole-brain white matter disruption in semantic and nonfluent variants of primary progressive aphasia. Hum Brain Mapp 34, 973&#x2013;984. doi:10.1002/hbm.21484</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hbm.21484</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6870114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22109837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seelaar H, Papma JM, Garraux G, de Koning I, Reijs AE, Valkema R, Rozemuller AJM, Salmon E, van Swieten JC, 2011. Brain perfusion patterns in familial frontotemporal lobar degeneration. Neurology 77, 384&#x2013;392. doi:10.1212/WNL.0b013e3182270456</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0b013e3182270456</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21753175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seeley WW, Allman JM, Carlin DA, Crawford RK, Macedo MN, Greicius MD, DeArmond SJ, Miller BL, 2007a. Divergent social functioning in behavioral variant frontotemporal dementia and Alzheimer disease: reciprocal networks and neuronal evolution. Alzheimer Dis Assoc Disord 21, S50&#x2013;S57. doi:10.1097/WAD.0b013e31815c0f14</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/WAD.0b013e31815c0f14</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18090425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seeley WW, Crawford R, Rascovsky K, Kramer JH, Weiner M, Miller BL, Gorno-Tempini ML, 2008. Frontal paralimbic network atrophy in very mild behavioral variant frontotemporal dementia. Arch Neurol 65. doi:10.1001/archneurol.2007.38</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archneurol.2007.38</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2544627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18268196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seeley WW, Crawford RK, Zhou J, Miller BL, Greicius MD, 2009. Neurodegenerative diseases target large-scale human brain networks. Neuron 62, 42&#x2013;52. doi:10.1016/j.neuron.2009.03.024</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuron.2009.03.024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2691647</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19376066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seeley WW, Menon V, Schatzberg AF, Keller J, Glover GH, Kenna H, Reiss AL, Greicius MD, 2007b. Dissociable intrinsic connectivity networks for salience processing and executive control. J Neurosci 27, 2349&#x2013;2356. doi:10.1523/JNEUROSCI.5587-06.2007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1523/JNEUROSCI.5587-06.2007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2680293</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17329432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sha SJ, Takada LT, Rankin KP, Yokoyama JS, Rutherford NJ, Fong JC, Khan B, Karydas A, Baker MC, DeJesus-Hernandez M, Pribadi M, Coppola G, Geschwind DH, Rademakers R, Lee SE, Seeley W, Miller BL, Boxer AL, 2012. Frontotemporal dementia due to C9ORF72 mutations: clinical and imaging features. Neurology 79, 1002&#x2013;1011. doi:10.1212/WNL.0b013e318268452e</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0b013e318268452e</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3430713</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22875087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen D, Cui L, Fang J, Cui B, Li D, Tai H, 2016. Voxel-wise meta-analysis of gray matter changes in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Front Aging Neurosci 8, 64. doi:10.3389/fnagi.2016.00064</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnagi.2016.00064</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4811926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27065078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skibinski G, Parkinson NJ, Brown JM, Chakrabarti L, Lloyd SL, Hummerich H, Nielsen JE, Hodges JR, Spillantini MG, Thusgaard T, Brandner S, Brun A, Rossor MN, Gade A, Johannsen P, S&#xf8;rensen SA, Gydesen S, Fisher EM, Collinge J, 2005. Mutations in the endosomal ESCRTIII-complex subunit CHMP2B in frontotemporal dementia. Nat Genet 37, 806&#x2013;808. doi:10.1038/ng1609</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ng1609</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16041373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skoglund L, Viitanen M, Kalimo H, Lannfelt L, Jonhagen ME, Ingelsson M, Glaser A, Herva R, 2008. The tau S305S mutation causes frontotemporal dementia with parkinsonism. Eur J Neurol 15, 156&#x2013;161. doi:10.1111/j.1468-1331.2007.02017.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1468-1331.2007.02017.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18093153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith BN, Newhouse S, Shatunov A, Vance C, Topp S, Johnson L, Miller J, Lee Y, Troakes C, Scott KM, Jones A, Gray I, Wright J, Hortob&#xe1;gyi T, Al-Sarraj S, Rogelj B, Powell J, Lupton M, Lovestone S, Sapp PC, Weber M, Nestor PJ, Schelhaas HJ, Asbroek A.A. ten, Silani V, Gellera C, Taroni F, Ticozzi N, Van den Berg L, Veldink J, Van Damme P, Robberecht W, Shaw PJ, Kirby J, Pall H, Morrison KE, Morris A, de Belleroche J, Vianney de Jong JMB, Baas F, Andersen PM, Landers J, Brown RH, Weale ME, Al-Chalabi A, Shaw CE, 2013. The C9ORF72 expansion mutation is a common cause of ALS+/&#x2212;FTD in Europe and has a single founder. Eur J Hum Genet 21, 102&#x2013;108. doi:10.1038/ejhg.2012.98</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ejhg.2012.98</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3522204</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22692064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith R, Puschmann A, Sch&#xf6;ll M, Ohlsson T, van Swieten J, Honer M, Englund E, Hansson O, 2016. 18 F-AV-1451 tau PET imaging correlates strongly with tau neuropathology in MAPT mutation carriers. Brain 139, 2372&#x2013;2379. doi:10.1093/brain/aww163</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/aww163</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4995360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27357347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Snowden JS, Goulding PJ, Neary D, 1989. Semantic dementia: a form of circumscribed cerebral atrophy. Behav Neurol 2, 167&#x2013;182.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Snowden JS, Rollinson S, Thompson JC, Harris JM, Stopford CL, Richardson AMT, Jones M, Gerhard A, Davidson YS, Robinson A, Gibbons L, Hu Q, DuPlessis D, Neary D, Mann DMA, Pickering-Brown SM, 2012. Distinct clinical and pathological characteristics of frontotemporal dementia associated with C9ORF72 mutations. Brain 135, 693&#x2013;708. doi:10.1093/brain/awr355</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awr355</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3286329</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22300873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solje E, Aaltokallio H, Koivumaa-Honkanen H, Suhonen NM, Moilanen V, Kiviharju A, Traynor B, Tienari PJ, Hartikainen P, Remes AM, 2015. The phenotype of the C9ORF72 expansion carriers according to revised criteria for bvFTD. PLoS One 10, e0131817. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0131817</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0131817</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4493025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26146826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spillantini MG, Murrell JR, Goedert M, Farlow MR, Klug A, Ghetti B, 1998. Mutation in the tau gene in familial multiple system tauopathy with presenile dementia. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 95, 7737&#x2013;7741. doi:10.1073/pnas.95.13.7737</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.95.13.7737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC22742</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9636220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spinelli EG, Agosta F, Ferraro PM, Riva N, Lunetta C, Falzone YM, Comi G, Falini A, Filippi M, 2016. Brain MR imaging in patients with lower motor neuronpredominant disease. Radiology 280, 545&#x2013;556. doi:10.1148/radiol.2016151846</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1148/radiol.2016151846</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26963576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sreedharan J, Blair IP, Tripathi VB, Hu X, Vance C, Rogelj B, Ackerley S, Durnall JC, Williams KL, Buratti E, Baralle F, de Belleroche J, Mitchell JD, Leigh PN, Al-Chalabi A, Miller CC, Nicholson G, Shaw CE, 2008. TDP-43 mutations in familial and sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Science 319, 1668&#x2013;1672. doi:10.1126/science.1154584</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.1154584</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7116650</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18309045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stanton BR, Shinhmar D, Turner MR, Williams VC, Williams SCR, Blain CRV, Giampietro VP, Catani M, Leigh PN, Andersen PM, Simmons A, 2009. Diffusion tensor imaging in sporadic and familial (D90A SOD1) forms of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Arch Neurol 66. doi:10.1001/archneurol.2008.527</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archneurol.2008.527</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19139308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stanton BR, Williams VC, Leigh PN, Williams SCR, Blain CRV, Jarosz JM, Simmons A, 2007. Altered cortical activation during a motor task in ALS: evidence for involvement of central pathways. J Neurol 254, 1260&#x2013;1267. doi:10.1007/s00415-006-0513-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00415-006-0513-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17385077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strong MJ, Abrahams S, Goldstein LH, Woolley S, Mclaughlin P, Snowden J, Mioshi E, Roberts-South A, Benatar M, Hortob&#xe1;Gyi T, Rosenfeld J, Silani V, Ince PG, Turner MR, 2017. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis - frontotemporal spectrum disorder (ALS-FTSD): revised diagnostic criteria. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 18, 153&#x2013;174. doi:10.1080/21678421.2016.1267768</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/21678421.2016.1267768</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7409990</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28054827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudre CH, Bocchetta M, Cash D, Thomas DL, Woollacott I, Dick KM, van Swieten J, Borroni B, Galimberti D, Masellis M, Tartaglia MC, Rowe JB, Graff C, Tagliavini F, Frisoni G, Laforce R, Finger E, de Mendon&#xe7;a A, Sorbi S, Ourselin S, Cardoso MJ, Rohrer JD, Andersson C, Archetti S, Arighi A, Benussi L, Binetti G, Black S, Cosseddu M, Fallstr&#xf6;m M, Ferreira C, Fenoglio C, Fox NC, Freedman M, Fumagalli G, Gazzina S, Ghidoni R, Grisoli M, Jelic V, Jiskoot L, Keren R, Lombardi G, Maruta C, Mead S, Meeter L, van Minkelen R, Nacmias B, &#xd6;ijerstedt L, Padovani A, Panman J, Pievani M, Polito C, Premi E, Prioni S, Rademakers R, Redaelli V, Rogaeva E, Rossi G, Rossor MN, Scarpini E, Tang-Wai D, Thonberg H, Tiraboschi P, Verdelho A, Warren JD, 2017. White matter hyperintensities are seen only in GRN mutation carriers in the GENFI cohort. NeuroImage Clin 15, 171&#x2013;180. doi:10.1016/j.nicl.2017.04.015</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nicl.2017.04.015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5429247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28529873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudre CH, Bocchetta M, Heller C, Convery R, Neason M, Moore KM, Cash DM, Thomas DL, Woollacott IOC, Foiani M, Heslegrave A, Shafei R, Greaves C, van Swieten J, Moreno F, Sanchez-Valle R, Borroni B, Laforce R, Masellis M, Tartaglia MC, Graff C, Galimberti D, Rowe JB, Finger E, Synofzik M, Vandenberghe R, de Mendon&#xe7;a A, Tagliavini F, Santana I, Ducharme S, Butler C, Gerhard A, Levin J, Danek A, Frisoni GB, Sorbi S, Otto M, Zetterberg H, Ourselin S, Cardoso MJ, Rohrer JD, 2019. White matter hyperintensities in progranulin-associated frontotemporal dementia: A longitudinal GENFI study. NeuroImage Clin 24, 102077. doi:10.1016/j.nicl.2019.102077</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nicl.2019.102077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6911860</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31835286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun L, Rong Z, Li W, Zheng H, Xiao S, Li X, 2018. Identification of a novel hemizygous SQSTM1 nonsense mutation in atypical behavioral variant frontotemporal dementia. Front Aging Neurosci 10, 26. doi:10.3389/fnagi.2018.00026</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnagi.2018.00026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5808128</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29467647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Synofzik M, Born C, Rominger A, Lummel N, Sch&#xf6;ls L, Biskup S, Sch&#xfc;le C, Grasshoff U, Klopstock T, Adamczyk C, 2014. Targeted high-throughput sequencing identifies a TARDBP mutation as a cause of early-onset FTD without motor neuron disease. Neurobiol Aging 35, 1212.e1&#x2013;1212.e5. doi:10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2013.10.092</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2013.10.092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24300238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Synofzik M, Maetzler W, Grehl T, Prudlo J, vom Hagen JM, Haack T, Rebassoo P, Munz M, Sch&#xf6;ls L, Biskup S, 2012. Screening in ALS and FTD patients reveals 3 novel UBQLN2 mutations outside the PXX domain and a pure FTD phenotype. Neurobiol Aging 33, 2949.e13&#x2013;2949.e17. doi:10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2012.07.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2012.07.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22892309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan RH, Kril JJ, Yang Y, Tom N, Hodges JR, Villemagne VL, Rowe CC, Leyton CE, Kwok JBJ, Ittner LM, Halliday GM, 2017. Assessment of amyloid &#x3b2; in pathologically confirmed frontotemporal dementia syndromes. Alzheimers Dement (Amst) 9, 10&#x2013;20. doi:10.1016/j.dadm.2017.05.005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.dadm.2017.05.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5473545</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28653036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tateishi T, Hokonohara T, Yamasaki R, Miura S, Kikuchi H, Iwaki A, Tashiro H, Furuya H, Nagara Y, Ohyagi Y, Nukina N, Iwaki T, Fukumaki Y, Kira J, 2010. Multiple system degeneration with basophilic inclusions in Japanese ALS patients with FUS mutation. Acta Neuropathol 119, 355&#x2013;364. doi:10.1007/s00401-009-0621-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00401-009-0621-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19967541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor JP, 2015. Multisystem proteinopathy: intersecting genetics in muscle, bone, and brain degeneration. Neurology 85, 658&#x2013;660. doi:10.1212/WNL.0000000000001862</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000001862</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26208960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tedeschi G, Trojsi F, Tessitore A, Corbo D, Sagnelli A, Paccone A, D&#x2019;Ambrosio A, Piccirillo G, Cirillo M, Cirillo S, Monsurr&#xf2; MR, Esposito F, 2012. Interaction between aging and neurodegeneration in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurobiol Aging 33, 886&#x2013;898. doi:10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2010.07.011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2010.07.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20739098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teyssou E, Chartier L, Albert M, Bouscary A, Antoine J-C, Camdessanch&#xe9; J-P, Rotolo F, Couratier P, Salachas F, Seilhean D, Millecamps S, 2016. Genetic analysis of CHCHD10 in French familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. Neurobiol Aging 42, 218.e1&#x2013;218.e3. doi:10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2016.03.022</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2016.03.022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27095681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tohnai G, Nakamura R, Sone J, Nakatochi M, Yokoi D, Katsuno M, Watanabe Hazuki, Watanabe Hirohisa, Ito M, Li Y, Izumi Y, Morita M, Taniguchi A, Kano O, Oda M, Kuwabara S, Abe K, Aiba I, Okamoto K, Mizoguchi K, Hasegawa K, Aoki M, Hattori N, Onodera O, Naruse H, Mitsui J, Takahashi Y, Goto J, Ishiura H, Morishita S, Yoshimura J, Doi K, Tsuji S, Nakashima K, Kaji R, Atsuta N, Sobue G, 2018. Frequency and characteristics of the TBK1 gene variants in Japanese patients with sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurobiol Aging 64, 158.e15&#x2013;158.e19. doi:10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2017.12.005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2017.12.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29398122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tosun D, Schuff N, Rabinovici GD, Ayakta N, Miller BL, Jagust W, Kramer J, Weiner MM, Rosen HJ, 2016. Diagnostic utility of ASL-MRI and FDG-PET in the behavioral variant of FTD and AD. Ann Clin Transl Neurol 3, 740&#x2013;751. doi:10.1002/acn3.330</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/acn3.330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5048385</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27752510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trojsi F, Corbo D, Caiazzo G, Piccirillo G, Monsurr&#xf2; MR, Cirillo S, Esposito F, Tedeschi G, 2013. Motor and extramotor neurodegeneration in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A 3T high angular resolution diffusion imaging (HARDI) study. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 14, 553&#x2013;561. doi:10.3109/21678421.2013.785569</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/21678421.2013.785569</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23586325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trojsi F, Esposito F, de Stefano M, Buonanno D, Conforti FL, Corbo D, Piccirillo G, Cirillo M, Monsurr&#xf2; MR, Montella P, Tedeschi G, 2015. Functional overlap and divergence between ALS and bvFTD. Neurobiol Aging 36, 413&#x2013;423. doi:10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2014.06.025</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2014.06.025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25063233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsai RM, Bejanin A, Lesman-Segev O, LaJoie R, Visani A, Bourakova V, O&#x2019;Neil JP, Janabi M, Baker S, Lee SE, Perry DC, Bajorek L, Karydas A, Spina S, Grinberg LT, Seeley WW, Ramos EM, Coppola G, Gorno-Tempini ML, Miller BL, Rosen HJ, Jagust W, Boxer AL, Rabinovici GD, 2019. 18F-flortaucipir (AV-1451) tau PET in frontotemporal dementia syndromes. Alzheimers Res Ther 11, 13. doi:10.1186/s13195-019-0470-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13195-019-0470-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6357510</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30704514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsujimoto M, Senda J, Ishihara T, Niimi Y, Kawai Y, Atsuta N, Watanabe H, Tanaka F, Naganawa S, Sobue G, 2011. Behavioral changes in early ALS correlate with voxel-based morphometry and diffusion tensor imaging. J Neurol Sci 307, 34&#x2013;40. doi:10.1016/j.jns.2011.05.025</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jns.2011.05.025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21641004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tu S, Leyton CE, Hodges JR, Piguet O, Hornberger M, 2015. Divergent longitudinal propagation of white matter degradation in logopenic and semantic variants of primary progressive aphasia. J Alzheimers Dis 49, 853&#x2013;861. doi:10.3233/JAD-150626</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/JAD-150626</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26484929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner MR, 2005. [11C]-WAY100635 PET demonstrates marked 5-HT1A receptor changes in sporadic ALS. Brain 128, 896&#x2013;905. doi:10.1093/brain/awh428</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awh428</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15689356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner MR, Hammers A, Al-Chalabi A, Shaw CE, Andersen PM, Brooks DJ, Leigh PN, 2005. Distinct cerebral lesions in sporadic and &#x201c;D90A&#x201d; SOD1 ALS: studies with [11C]flumazenil PET. Brain 128, 1323&#x2013;1329. doi:10.1093/brain/awh509</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awh509</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15843422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner MR, Hammers A, Allsop J, Al-Chalabi A, Shaw CE, Brooks DJ, Nigel Leigh P, Andersen PM, 2007a. Volumetric cortical loss in sporadic and familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler 8, 343&#x2013;347. doi:10.1080/17482960701538734</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17482960701538734</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18033592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner MR, Rabiner EA, Al-Chalabi A, Shaw CE, Brooks DJ, Leigh PN, Andersen PM, 2007b. Cortical 5-HT1A receptor binding in patients with homozygous D90A SOD1 vs sporadic ALS. Neurology 68, 1233&#x2013;1235. doi:10.1212/01.wnl.0000259083.31837.64</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/01.wnl.0000259083.31837.64</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17420412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ueno H, Kobatake K, Matsumoto M, Morino H, Maruyama H, Kawakami H, 2011. Severe brain atrophy after long-term survival seen in siblings with familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and a mutation in the optineurin gene: a case series. J Med Case Rep 5, 573. doi:10.1186/1752-1947-5-573</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1752-1947-5-573</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3251630</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22152722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valsasina P, Agosta F, Benedetti B, Caputo D, Perini M, Salvi F, Prelle A, Filippi M, 2006. Diffusion anisotropy of the cervical cord is strictly associated with disability in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 78, 480&#x2013;484. doi:10.1136/jnnp.2006.100032</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp.2006.100032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2117814</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17030586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Burgh HK, Westeneng H-J, Meier JM, van Es MA, Veldink JH, Hendrikse J, van den Heuvel MP, van den Berg LH, 2019. Cross-sectional and longitudinal assessment of the upper cervical spinal cord in motor neuron disease. NeuroImage: Clinical 24, 101984. doi:10.1016/j.nicl.2019.101984</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nicl.2019.101984</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6734179</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31499409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Burgh HK, Westeneng H-J, Walhout R, van Veenhuijzen K, Tan HHG, Meier JM, Bakker LA, Hendrikse J, van Es MA, Veldink JH, van den Heuvel MP, van den Berg LH, 2020. Multimodal longitudinal study of structural brain involvement in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology 94, e2592&#x2013;e2604. doi:10.1212/WNL.0000000000009498</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000009498</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7455328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32414878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Graaff MM, Sage CA, Caan MWA, Akkerman EM, Lavini C, Majoie CB, Nederveen AJ, Zwinderman AH, Vos F, Brugman F, van den Berg LH, de Rijk MC, van Doorn PA, Van Hecke W, Peeters RR, Robberecht W, Sunaert S, de Visser M, 2011. Upper and extra-motoneuron involvement in early motoneuron disease: a diffusion tensor imaging study. Brain 134, 1211&#x2013;1228. doi:10.1093/brain/awr016</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awr016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21362631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Zee J, Pirici D, Van Langenhove T, Engelborghs S, Vandenberghe R, Hoffmann M, Pusswald G, Van den Broeck M, Peeters K, Mattheijssens M, Martin J-J, De Deyn PP, Cruts M, Haubenberger D, Kumar-Singh S, Zimprich A, Van Broeckhoven C, 2009. Clinical heterogeneity in 3 unrelated families linked to VCP p.Arg159His. Neurology 73, 626&#x2013;632. doi:10.1212/WNL.0b013e3181b389d9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0b013e3181b389d9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19704082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Zee J, Urwin H, Engelborghs S, Bruyland M, Vandenberghe R, Dermaut B, De Pooter T, Peeters K, Santens P, De Deyn PP, Fisher EM, Collinge J, Isaacs AM, Van Broeckhoven C, 2008. CHMP2B C-truncating mutations in frontotemporal lobar degeneration are associated with an aberrant endosomal phenotype in vitro. Hum Mol Genet 17, 313&#x2013;322. doi:10.1093/hmg/ddm309</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/hmg/ddm309</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17956895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Zee J, Van Langenhove T, Kovacs GG, Dillen L, Deschamps W, Engelborghs S, Mat&#x11b;j R, Vandenbulcke M, Sieben A, Dermaut B, Smets K, Van Damme P, Merlin C, Laureys A, Van Den Broeck M, Mattheijssens M, Peeters K, Benussi L, Binetti G, Ghidoni R, Borroni B, Padovani A, Archetti S, Pastor P, Razquin C, Ortega-Cubero S, Hern&#xe1;ndez I, Boada M, Ruiz A, de Mendon&#xe7;a A, Miltenberger-Milt&#xe9;nyi G, do Couto FS, Sorbi S, Nacmias B, Bagnoli S, Graff C, Chiang H-H, Thonberg H, Perneczky R, Diehl-Schmid J, Alexopoulos P, Frisoni GB, Bonvicini C, Synofzik M, Maetzler W, vom Hagen JM, Sch&#xf6;ls L, Haack TB, Strom TM, Prokisch H, Dols-Icardo O, Clarim&#xf3;n J, Lle&#xf3; A, Santana I, Almeida MR, Santiago B, Heneka MT, Jessen F, Ramirez A, Sanchez-Valle R, Llado A, Gelpi E, Sarafov S, Tournev I, Jordanova A, Parobkova E, Fabrizi GM, Testi S, Salmon E, Str&#xf6;bel T, Santens P, Robberecht W, De Jonghe P, Martin J-J, Cras P, Vandenberghe R, De Deyn PP, Cruts M, Sleegers K, Van Broeckhoven C, 2014. Rare mutations in SQSTM1 modify susceptibility to frontotemporal lobar degeneration. Acta Neuropathol 128, 397&#x2013;410. doi:10.1007/s00401-014-1298-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00401-014-1298-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4131163</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24899140</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Herpen E, Rosso SM, Serverijnen L-A, Yoshida H, Breedveld G, Van De Graaf R, Kamphorst W, Ravid R, Willemsen R, Dooijes D, Majoor-Krakauer D, Kros JM, Crowther RA, Goedert M, Heutink P, Van Swieten JC, 2003. Variable phenotypic expression and extensive tau pathology in two families with the noveltau mutation L315R. Ann Neurol 54, 573&#x2013;581. doi:10.1002/ana.10721</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.10721</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14595646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Laere K, Vanhee A, Verschueren J, De Coster L, Driesen A, Dupont P, Robberecht W, Van Damme P, 2014. Value of 18fluorodeoxyglucose&#x2013;positron-emission tomography in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a prospective study. JAMA Neurol 71, 553. doi:10.1001/jamaneurol.2014.62</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamaneurol.2014.62</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24615479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Mossevelde S, van der Zee J, Gijselinck I, Engelborghs S, Sieben A, Van Langenhove T, De Bleecker J, Baets J, Vandenbulcke M, Van Laere K, Ceyssens S, Van den Broeck M, Peeters K, Mattheijssens M, Cras P, Vandenberghe R, De Jonghe P, Martin J-J, De Deyn PP, Cruts M, Van Broeckhoven C, 2016. Clinical features of TBK1 carriers compared with C9orf72, GRN and non-mutation carriers in a Belgian cohort. Brain 139, 452&#x2013;467. doi:10.1093/brain/awv358</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awv358</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4805085</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26674655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Swieten JC, Stevens M, Rosso SM, Rizzu P, Joosse M, De Koning I, Kamphorst W, Ravid R, Spillantini MG, Niermeijer MF, Heutink P, 1999. Phenotypic variation in hereditary frontotemporal dementia with tau mutations. Ann Neurol 46, 617&#x2013;626. doi:10.1002/1531-8249(199910)46:4&lt;617::AID-ANA10&gt;3.0.CO;2-I</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/1531-8249(199910)46:4&lt;617::AID-ANA10&gt;3.0.CO;2-I</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10514099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varma AR, Adams W, Lloyd JJ, Carson KJ, Snowden JS, Testa HJ, Jackson A, Neary D, 2002. Diagnostic patterns of regional atrophy on MRI and regional cerebral blood flow change on SPECT in young onset patients with Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease, frontotemporal dementia and vascular dementia. Acta Neurol Scand 105, 261&#x2013;269. doi:10.1034/j.1600-0404.2002.1o148.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1034/j.1600-0404.2002.1o148.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11939938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vengoechea J, David MP, Yaghi SR, Carpenter L, Rudnicki SA, 2013. Clinical variability and female penetrance in X-linked familial FTD/ALS caused by a P506S mutation in UBQLN2. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 14, 615&#x2013;619. doi:10.3109/21678421.2013.824001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/21678421.2013.824001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23944734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verfaillie SCJ, Adriaanse SM, Binnewijzend MAA, Benedictus MR, Ossenkoppele R, Wattjes MP, Pijnenburg YAL, van der Flier WM, Lammertsma AA, Kuijer JPA, Boellaard R, Scheltens P, van Berckel BNM, Barkhof F, 2015. Cerebral perfusion and glucose metabolism in Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease and frontotemporal dementia: two sides of the same coin? Eur Radiol 25, 3050&#x2013;3059. doi:10.1007/s00330-015-3696-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00330-015-3696-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4562004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25899416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verschueren J, Vanhee A, De Coster L, Van Damme P, Van Laere K, 2013. Impact of the C9Orf72 expansion on brain glucose metabolism in ALS patients. J Nucl Med 54, 155&#x2013;155.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viassolo V, Previtali S, Schiatti E, Magnani G, Minetti C, Zara F, Grasso M, Dagn&#xe0;-Bricarelli F, Di Maria E, 2008. Inclusion body myopathy, Paget&#x2019;s disease of the bone and frontotemporal dementia: recurrence of the VCP R155H mutation in an Italian family and implications for genetic counselling. Clin Genet 74, 54&#x2013;60. doi:10.1111/j.1399-0004.2008.00984.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1399-0004.2008.00984.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18341608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vijverberg EGB, Wattjes MP, Dols A, Krudop WA, M&#xf6;ller C, Peters A, Kerssens CJ, Gossink F, Prins ND, Stek ML, Scheltens P, van Berckel BNM, Barkhof F, Pijnenburg YAL, 2016. Diagnostic accuracy of MRI and additional [18F]FDG-PET for behavioral variant frontotemporal dementia in patients with late onset behavioral changes. J Alzheimers Dis 53, 1287&#x2013;1297. doi:10.3233/JAD-160285</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/JAD-160285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27372646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S, Winhammar JMC, Rowe DB, Kiernan MC, 2010. Corticomotoneuronal function in asymptomatic SOD-1 mutation carriers. Clin Neurophysiol 121, 1781&#x2013;1785. doi:10.1016/j.clinph.2010.02.164</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clinph.2010.02.164</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20362497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walhout R, Schmidt R, Westeneng H-J, Verstraete E, Seelen M, van Rheenen W, de Reus MA, van Es MA, Hendrikse J, Veldink JH, van den Heuvel MP, van den Berg LH, 2015a. Brain morphologic changes in asymptomatic C9orf72 repeat expansion carriers. Neurology 85, 1780&#x2013;1788. doi:10.1212/WNL.0000000000002135</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000002135</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26497991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walhout R, Westeneng H-J, Verstraete E, Hendrikse J, Veldink JH, van den Heuvel MP, van den Berg LH, 2015b. Cortical thickness in ALS: towards a marker for upper motor neuron involvement. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 86, 288&#x2013;294. doi:10.1136/jnnp-2013-306839</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp-2013-306839</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25121571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang YT, Edison P, 2019. Tau imaging in neurodegenerative diseases using positron emission tomography. Curr Neurol Neurosci Rep 19, 45. doi:10.1007/s11910-019-0962-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11910-019-0962-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6554240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31172290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watts GDJ, Wymer J, Kovach MJ, Mehta SG, Mumm S, Darvish D, Pestronk A, Whyte MP, Kimonis VE, 2004. Inclusion body myopathy associated with Paget disease of bone and frontotemporal dementia is caused by mutant valosin-containing protein. Nat Genet 36, 377&#x2013;381. doi:10.1038/ng1332</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ng1332</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15034582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weber M, Eisen A, Stewart HG, Andersen PM, 2000. Preserved slow conducting corticomotoneuronal projections in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with autosomal recessive D90A CuZn-superoxide dismutase mutation. Brain 123 ( Pt 7), 1505&#x2013;1515. doi:10.1093/brain/123.7.1505</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/123.7.1505</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10869061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weidberg H, Elazar Z, 2011. TBK1 mediates crosstalk between the innate immune response and autophagy. Sci Signal 4, p e39. doi:10.1126/scisignal.2002355</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/scisignal.2002355</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21868362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wen J, Zhang H, Alexander DC, Durrleman S, Routier A, Rinaldi D, Houot M, Couratier P, Hannequin D, Pasquier F, Zhang J, Colliot O, Le Ber I, Bertrand A, 2018. Neurite density is reduced in the presymptomatic phase of C9orf72 disease. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 90, 387&#x2013;394. doi:10.1136/jnnp-2018-318994</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp-2018-318994</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30355607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westeneng HJ, Verstraete E, Walhout R, Schmidt R, Hendrikse J, Veldink JH, van den Heuvel MP, van den Berg LH, 2015. Subcortical structures in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurobiol Aging 36, 1075&#x2013;1082. doi:10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2014.09.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2014.09.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25281019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westeneng HJ, Walhout R, Straathof M, Schmidt R, Hendrikse J, Veldink JH, van den Heuvel MP, van den Berg LH, 2016. Widespread structural brain involvement in ALS is not limited to the C9orf72 repeat expansion. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 87, 1354&#x2013;1360. doi:10.1136/jnnp-2016-313959</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp-2016-313959</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5136726</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27756805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westeneng HJ, Wismans C, Nitert A, Walhout R, Lujiten P, Wijnen J, van den Berg LH, 2017. Metabolic differences between asymptomatic C9orf72 carriers and non-carriers assessed by brain 7T MRSI. Proceedings of the 25th Annual Meeting of ISMRM, Honolulu, USA Abstract 0028.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitwell JL, Avula R, Senjem ML, Kantarci K, Weigand SD, Samikoglu A, Edmonson HA, Vemuri P, Knopman DS, Boeve BF, Petersen RC, Josephs KA, Jack CR, 2010. Gray and white matter water diffusion in the syndromic variants of frontotemporal dementia. Neurology 74, 1279&#x2013;1287. doi:10.1212/WNL.0b013e3181d9edde</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0b013e3181d9edde</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2860485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20404309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitwell JL, Boeve BF, Weigand SD, Senjem ML, Gunter JL, Baker MC, DeJesus-Hernandez M, Knopman DS, Wszolek ZK, Petersen RC, Rademakers R, Jack CR, Josephs KA, 2015. Brain atrophy over time in genetic and sporadic frontotemporal dementia: a study of 198 serial magnetic resonance images. Eur J Neurol 22, 745&#x2013;752. doi:10.1111/ene.12675</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ene.12675</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4390434</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25683866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitwell JL, Jack CR, Baker M, Rademakers R, Adamson J, Boeve BF, Knopman DS, Parisi JF, Petersen RC, Dickson DW, Hutton ML, Josephs KA, 2007a. Voxel-based morphometry in frontotemporal lobar degeneration with ubiquitin-positive inclusions with and without progranulin mutations. Arch Neurol 64, 371. doi:10.1001/archneur.64.3.371</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archneur.64.3.371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2752412</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17353379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitwell JL, Jack CR, Boeve BF, Senjem ML, Baker M, Ivnik RJ, Knopman DS, Wszolek ZK, Petersen RC, Rademakers R, Josephs KA, 2009a. Atrophy patterns in IVS10+16, IVS10+3, N279K, S305N, P301L, and V337M MAPT mutations. Neurology 73, 1058&#x2013;1065. doi:10.1212/WNL.0b013e3181b9c8b9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0b013e3181b9c8b9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2754325</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19786698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitwell JL, Jack CR, Boeve BF, Senjem ML, Baker M, Rademakers R, Ivnik RJ, Knopman DS, Wszolek ZK, Petersen RC, Josephs KA, 2009b. Voxel-based morphometry patterns of atrophy in FTLD with mutations in MAPT or PGRN. Neurology 72, 813&#x2013;820. doi:10.1212/01.wnl.0000343851.46573.67</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/01.wnl.0000343851.46573.67</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2677544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19255408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitwell JL, Josephs KA, Avula R, Tosakulwong N, Weigand SD, Senjem ML, Vemuri P, Jones DT, Gunter JL, Baker M, Wszolek ZK, Knopman DS, Rademakers R, Petersen RC, Boeve BF, Jack CR, 2011. Altered functional connectivity in asymptomatic MAPT subjects: a comparison to bvFTD. Neurology 77, 866&#x2013;874. doi:10.1212/WNL.0b013e31822c61f2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0b013e31822c61f2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3162637</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21849646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitwell JL, Sampson EL, Loy CT, Warren JE, Rossor MN, Fox NC, Warren JD, 2007b. VBM signatures of abnormal eating behaviours in frontotemporal lobar degeneration. NeuroImage 35, 207&#x2013;213. doi:10.1016/j.neuroimage.2006.12.006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuroimage.2006.12.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17240166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitwell JL, Weigand SD, Boeve BF, Senjem ML, Gunter JL, DeJesus-Hernandez M, Rutherford NJ, Baker M, Knopman DS, Wszolek ZK, Parisi JE, Dickson DW, Petersen RC, Rademakers R, Jack CR, Josephs KA, 2012. Neuroimaging signatures of frontotemporal dementia genetics: C9ORF72, tau, progranulin and sporadics. Brain 135, 794&#x2013;806. doi:10.1093/brain/aws001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/aws001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3286334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22366795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilke C, Baets J, De Bleecker JL, Deconinck T, Biskup S, Hayer SN, Z&#xfc;chner S, Sch&#xfc;le R, De Jonghe P, Synofzik M, 2018. Beyond ALS and FTD: the phenotypic spectrum of TBK1 mutations includes PSP-like and cerebellar phenotypes. Neurobiol Aging 62, 244.e9&#x2013;244.e13. doi:10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2017.10.010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2017.10.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29137817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong CH, Topp S, Gkazi AS, Troakes C, Miller JW, de Majo M, Kirby J, Shaw PJ, Morrison KE, de Belleroche J, Vance CA, Al-Chalabi A, Al-Sarraj S, Shaw CE, Smith BN, 2015. The CHCHD10 P34S variant is not associated with ALS in a UK cohort of familial and sporadic patients. Neurobiol Aging 36, 2908.e17&#x2013;2908.e18. doi:10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2015.07.014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2015.07.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26344877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wongworawat YC, Liu YA, Raghavan R, White CL, Dietz R, Zuppan C, Rosenfeld J, 2020. Aggressive FUS-mutant motor neuron disease without profound spinal cord pathology. J Neuropath Exp Neur 79, 365&#x2013;369. doi:10.1093/jnen/nlaa011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jnen/nlaa011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32142142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woollacott IOC, Bocchetta M, Sudre CH, Ridha BH, Strand C, Courtney R, Ourselin S, Cardoso MJ, Warren JD, Rossor MN, Revesz T, Fox NC, Holton JL, Lashley T, Rohrer JD, 2018. Pathological correlates of white matter hyperintensities in a case of progranulin mutation associated frontotemporal dementia. Neurocase 24, 166&#x2013;174. doi:10.1080/13554794.2018.1506039</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13554794.2018.1506039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6168954</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30112957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woolley JD, Gorno-Tempini M-L, Seeley WW, Rankin K, Lee SS, Matthews BR, Miller BL, 2007. Binge eating is associated with right orbitofrontal-insular-striatal atrophy in frontotemporal dementia. Neurology 69, 1424&#x2013;1433. doi:10.1212/01.wnl.0000277461.06713.23</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/01.wnl.0000277461.06713.23</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17909155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu L, Liu J, Feng X, Dong J, Qin W, Liu Y, Wang J, Lu J, Chen K, Wang Y, Jia J, 2018. 11C-CFT-PET in presymptomatic FTDP-17: a potential biomarker predicting onset. J Alzheimers Dis 61, 613&#x2013;618. doi:10.3233/JAD-170561</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/JAD-170561</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29226866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia Q, Wang G, Wang H, Hu Q, Ying Z, 2016. Folliculin, a tumor suppressor associated with Birt&#x2013;Hogg&#x2013;Dub&#xe9; (BHD) syndrome, is a novel modifier of TDP-43 cytoplasmic translocation and aggregation. Hum Mol Genet 25, 83&#x2013;96. doi:10.1093/hmg/ddv450</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/hmg/ddv450</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26516189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamashita T, Hatakeyama T, Sato K, Fukui Y, Hishikawa N, Ohta Y, Nishiyama Y, Kawai N, Tamiya T, Abe K, 2017. Flow-metabolism uncoupling in the cervical spinal cord of ALS patients. Neurol Sci 38, 659&#x2013;665. doi:10.1007/s10072-017-2823-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10072-017-2823-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28120243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan J, Deng H-X, Siddique N, Fecto F, Chen W, Yang Y, Liu E, Donkervoort S, Zheng JG, Shi Y, Ahmeti KB, Brooks B, Engel WK, Siddique T, 2010. Frameshift and novel mutations in FUS in familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and ALS/dementia. Neurology 75, 807&#x2013;814. doi:10.1212/WNL.0b013e3181f07e0c</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0b013e3181f07e0c</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2938970</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20668259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ygland E, van Westen D, Englund E, Rademakers R, Wszolek ZK, Nilsson K, Nilsson C, Landqvist Wald&#xf6; M, Alafuzoff I, Hansson O, Gustafson L, Puschmann A, 2018. Slowly progressive dementia caused by MAPT R406W mutations: longitudinal report on a new kindred and systematic review. Alzheimers Res Ther 10, 2. doi:10.1186/s13195-017-0330-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13195-017-0330-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6389050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29370822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yilmaz R, M&#xfc;ller K, Brenner D, Volk AE, Borck G, Hermann A, Meitinger T, Strom TM, Danzer KM, Ludolph AC, Andersen PM, Weishaupt JH, Weyen U, Hermann A, Regensburger M, Winkler J, Linker R, Winner B, Hagenacker T, Koch JC, Lingor P, G&#xf6;ricke B, Zierz S, Jordan B, Baum P, Wolf J, Winkler A, Young P, Bogdahn U, Prudlo J, Kassubek J, 2020. SQSTM1/p62 variants in 486 patients with familial ALS from Germany and Sweden. Neurobiol Aging 87, 139.e9&#x2013;139.e15. doi:10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2019.10.018</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2019.10.018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31859009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young AL, Marinescu RV, Oxtoby NP, Bocchetta M, Yong K, Firth NC, Cash DM, Thomas DL, Dick KM, Cardoso J, van Swieten J, Borroni B, Galimberti D, Masellis M, Tartaglia MC, Rowe JB, Graff C, Tagliavini F, Frisoni GB, Laforce R, Finger E, de Mendon&#xe7;a A, Sorbi S, Warren JD, Crutch S, Fox NC, Ourselin S, Schott JM, Rohrer JD, Alexander DC, Andersson C, Archetti S, Arighi A, Benussi L, Binetti G, Black S, Cosseddu M, Fallstr&#xf6;m M, Ferreira C, Fenoglio C, Freedman M, Fumagalli GG, Gazzina S, Ghidoni R, Grisoli M, Jelic V, Jiskoot L, Keren R, Lombardi G, Maruta C, Meeter L, Mead S, van Minkelen R, Nacmias B, &#xd6;ijerstedt L, Padovani A, Panman J, Pievani M, Polito C, Premi E, Prioni S, Rademakers R, Redaelli V, Rogaeva E, Rossi G, Rossor M, Scarpini E, Tang-Wai D, Thonberg H, Tiraboschi P, Verdelho A, Weiner MW, Aisen P, Petersen R, Jack CR, Jagust W, Trojanowki JQ, Toga AW, Beckett L, Green RC, Saykin AJ, Morris J, Shaw LM, Khachaturian Z, Sorensen G, Kuller L, Raichle M, Paul S, Davies P, Fillit H, Hefti F, Holtzman D, Mesulam MM, Potter W, Snyder P, Schwartz A, Montine T, Thomas RG, Donohue M, Walter S, Gessert D, Sather T, Jiminez G, Harvey D, Bernstein M, Thompson P, Schuff N, Borowski B, Gunter J, Senjem M, Vemuri P, Jones D, Kantarci K, Ward C, Koeppe RA, Foster N, Reiman EM, Chen K, Mathis C, Landau S, Cairns NJ, Householder E, Taylor-Reinwald L, Lee V, Korecka M, Figurski M, Crawford K, Neu S, Foroud TM, Potkin S, Shen L, Faber K, Kim S, Nho K, Thal L, Buckholtz N, Albert Marylyn, Frank R, Hsiao J, Kaye J, Quinn J, Lind B, Carter R, Dolen S, Schneider LS, Pawluczyk S, Beccera M, Teodoro L, Spann BM, Brewer J, Vanderswag H, Fleisher A, Heidebrink JL, Lord JL, Mason SS, Albers CS, Knopman D, Johnson Kris, Doody RS, Villanueva-Meyer J, Chowdhury M, Rountree S, Dang M, Stern Y, Honig LS, Bell KL, Ances B, Carroll M, Leon S, Mintun MA, Schneider S, Oliver A, Marson D, Griffith R, Clark D, Geldmacher D, Brockington J, Roberson E, Grossman H, Mitsis E, de Toledo-Morrell L, Shah RC, Duara R, Varon D, Greig MT, Roberts P, Albert Marilyn, Onyike C, D&#x2019;Agostino D, Kielb S, Galvin JE, Cerbone B, Michel CA, Rusinek H, de Leon MJ, Glodzik L, De Santi S, Doraiswamy PM, Petrella JR, Wong TZ, Arnold SE, Karlawish JH, Wolk D, Smith CD, Jicha G, Hardy P, Sinha P, Oates E, Conrad G, Lopez OL, Oakley M, Simpson DM, Porsteinsson AP, Goldstein BS, Martin K, Makino KM, Ismail MS, Brand C, Mulnard RA, Thai G, Mc-Adams-Ortiz C, Womack K, Mathews D, Quiceno M, Diaz-Arrastia R, King R, Weiner M, Martin-Cook K, DeVous M, Levey AI, Lah JJ, Cellar JS, Burns JM, Anderson HS, Swerdlow RH, Apostolova L, Tingus K, Woo E, Silverman DH, Lu PH, Bartzokis G, Graff-Radford NR, Parfitt F, Kendall T, Johnson H, Farlow MR, Hake AM, Matthews BR, Herring S, Hunt C, van Dyck CH, Carson RE, MacAvoy MG, Chertkow H, Bergman H, Hosein C, Stefanovic B, Caldwell C, Hsiung G-YR, Feldman H, Mudge B, Assaly M, Kertesz A, Rogers J, Bernick C, Munic D, Kerwin D, Mesulam M-M, Lipowski K, Wu C-K, Johnson N, Sadowsky C, Martinez W, Villena T, Turner RS, Johnson Kathleen, Reynolds B, Sperling RA, Johnson KA, Marshall G, Frey M, Lane B, Rosen A, Tinklenberg J, Sabbagh MN, Belden CM, Jacobson SA, Sirrel SA, Kowall N, Killiany R, Budson AE, Norbash A, Johnson PL, Allard J, Lerner A, Ogrocki P, Hudson L, Fletcher E, The Genetic FTD Initiative (GENFI), The Alzheimer&#x2019;s Disease Neuroimaging Initiative (ADNI), 2018. Uncovering the heterogeneity and temporal complexity of neurodegenerative diseases with Subtype and Stage Inference. Nat Commun 9, 1&#x2013;16. doi:10.1038/s41467-018-05892-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-018-05892-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6189176</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30323170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu C-E, Bird TD, Bekris LM, Montine TJ, Leverenz JB, Steinbart E, Galloway NM, Feldman H, Woltjer R, Miller CA, Wood EM, Grossman M, McCluskey L, Clark CM, Neumann M, Danek A, Galasko DR, Arnold SE, Chen-Plotkin A, Karydas A, Miller BL, Trojanowski JQ, Lee VM-Y, Schellenberg GD, Van Deerlin VM, 2010. The spectrum of mutations in progranulin: a collaborative study screening 545 cases of neurodegeneration. Arch Neurol 67, 161&#x2013;170. doi:10.1001/archneurol.2009.328</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archneurol.2009.328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2901991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20142524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu H, Yu W, Luo S, Yang Y, Liu F, Zhang Y, Chen Y, Sun Y, Wu J, 2019. Association of the TBK1 mutation p.Ile334Thr with frontotemporal dementia and literature review. Mol Genet Genom Med 7, e547. doi:10.1002/mgg3.547</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mgg3.547</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6418353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30672142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang M, Xi Z, Zinman L, Bruni AC, Maletta RG, Curcio SAM, Rainero I, Rubino E, Pinessi L, Nacmias B, Sorbi S, Galimberti D, Lang AE, Fox S, Surace EI, Ghani M, Guo J, Sato C, Moreno D, Liang Y, Keith J, Traynor BJ, St George-Hyslop P, Rogaeva E, 2015. Mutation analysis of CHCHD10 in different neurodegenerative diseases. Brain 138, e380&#x2013;e380. doi:10.1093/brain/awv082</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awv082</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4547051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25833818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Tartaglia MC, Schuff N, Chiang GC, Ching C, Rosen HJ, Gorno-Tempini ML, Miller BL, Weiner MW, 2013. MRI signatures of brain macrostructural atrophy and microstructural degradation in frontotemporal lobar degeneration subtypes. J Alzheimers Dis 33, 431&#x2013;444. doi:10.3233/JAD-2012-121156</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/JAD-2012-121156</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3738303</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22976075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou B, Wang H, Cai Y, Wen H, Wang L, Zhu M, Chen Y, Yu Y, Lu X, Zhou M, Fang P, Li X, Hong D, 2020. FUS P525L mutation causing amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and movement disorders. Brain Behav 10, e01625. doi:10.1002/brb3.1625</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/brb3.1625</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7303404</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32307925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou J, Greicius MD, Gennatas ED, Growdon ME, Jang JY, Rabinovici GD, Kramer JH, Weiner M, Miller BL, Seeley WW, 2010. Divergent network connectivity changes in behavioural variant frontotemporal dementia and Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. Brain 133, 1352&#x2013;1367. doi:10.1093/brain/awq075</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awq075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2912696</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20410145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>