<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">32914883</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>01</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1941-2444</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>45</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>JPEN. Journal of parenteral and enteral nutrition</Title><ISOAbbreviation>JPEN J Parenter Enteral Nutr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Safety of Gastrostomy Tube Placement in Patients with Advanced Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis With Noninvasive Ventilation.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1338</StartPage><EndPage>1346</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1338-1346</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jpen.2018</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">In patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS), bulbar muscle dysfunction can occur, which eventually requires the initiation of enteral tube feeding. However, there is no consensus on the optimal timing for the gastrostomy or the proper ventilator support method during the procedure. We aimed to investigate the safe range of gastrostomy according to respiratory support status and forced vital capacity (FVC)&#xa0;% of predicted values classification and to compare the safety of noninvasive and invasive mechanical ventilation during the procedure in ALS patients with FVC &lt; 30% of predicted.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">A total of 477 patients diagnosed with ALS at our institution from January 1, 2009, to December 31, 2018, were evaluated, and 105 patients were enrolled in this study. All medical records covering ventilation status and complications within 6 months to 1 year after the initial gastrostomy were gathered and reviewed.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">The gastrostomy procedure was considered safe regardless of FVC status or modality of respiratory support. There were complications related to the gastrostomy procedure in 6 of 105 patients and all were managed through conservative care. The incidence of complications, including respiratory ones, for noninvasive and invasive positive pressure ventilation was 5.5% and 9.6%, respectively, which were not statistically significantly different (P = .294).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">The procedure and tube placement of a gastrostomy can be safely performed in ALS patients with minimal FVC regardless of ventilation invasiveness. We suggest that there should be a new standard for FVC&#xa0;% of predicted to facilitate performing gastrostomy in ALS patients.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020 American Society for Parenteral and Enteral Nutrition.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Eun Young</ForeName><Initials>EY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Medicine and Rehabilitation Institute of Neuromuscular Disease, Gangnam Severance Hospital, Yonsei University College of Medicine, Seoul, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pulmonary Rehabilitation Center, Gangnam Severance Hospital, Yonsei University College of Medicine, Seoul, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kang</LastName><ForeName>Seong Woong</ForeName><Initials>SW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Medicine and Rehabilitation Institute of Neuromuscular Disease, Gangnam Severance Hospital, Yonsei University College of Medicine, Seoul, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pulmonary Rehabilitation Center, Gangnam Severance Hospital, Yonsei University College of Medicine, Seoul, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Suh</LastName><ForeName>Mi Ri</ForeName><Initials>MR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Medicine, CHA Bundang Medical Center, CHA University School of Medicine, Seongnam, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jung</LastName><ForeName>Jiho</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Medicine and Rehabilitation Institute of Neuromuscular Disease, Gangnam Severance Hospital, Yonsei University College of Medicine, Seoul, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pulmonary Rehabilitation Center, Gangnam Severance Hospital, Yonsei University College of Medicine, Seoul, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Park</LastName><ForeName>Jihyun</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Medicine and Rehabilitation Institute of Neuromuscular Disease, Gangnam Severance Hospital, Yonsei University College of Medicine, Seoul, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pulmonary Rehabilitation Center, Gangnam Severance Hospital, Yonsei University College of Medicine, Seoul, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Choi</LastName><ForeName>Won Ah</ForeName><Initials>WA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0403-8869</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Medicine and Rehabilitation Institute of Neuromuscular Disease, Gangnam Severance Hospital, Yonsei University College of Medicine, Seoul, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pulmonary Rehabilitation Center, Gangnam Severance Hospital, Yonsei University College of Medicine, Seoul, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>JPEN J Parenter Enteral Nutr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7804134</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0148-6071</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004750" MajorTopicYN="N">Enteral Nutrition</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005774" MajorTopicYN="N">Gastrostomy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D063087" MajorTopicYN="Y">Noninvasive Ventilation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014797" MajorTopicYN="N">Vital Capacity</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">gastrostomy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">noninvasive ventilation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pulmonary rehabilitation</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32914883</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jpen.2018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Brown RH, Al-Chalabi A. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. N Engl J Med. 2017;377(2):162-172.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Es MA, Hardiman O, Chio A, etal. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet. 2017;390(10107):2084-2098.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beghi E, Millul A, Logroscino G, Vitelli E, Micheli A. Outcome measures and prognostic indicators in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord. 2008;9(3):163-167.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kak M, Issa NP, Roos RP, et&#xa0;al. Gastrostomy tube placement is safe in advanced amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurol Res. 2017;39(1):16-22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen PM, Abrahams S, Borasio GD, et&#xa0;al. EFNS guidelines on the clinical management of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (MALS)-revised report of an EFNS task force. Eur J Neurol. 2012;19(3):360-375.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loser C, Aschl G, Hebuterne X, et&#xa0;al. ESPEN guidelines on artificial enteral nutrition-percutaneous endoscopic gastrostomy (PEG). Clin Nutr. 2005;24(5):848-861.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller RG, Jackson CE, Kasarskis EJ, et&#xa0;al. Practice parameter update: the care of the patient with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: drug, nutritional, and respiratory therapies (an evidence-based review): report of the Quality Standards Subcommittee of the American Academy of Neurology. Neurology. 2009;73(15):1218-1226.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bokuda K, Shimizu T, Imamura K, et&#xa0;al. Predictive factors for prognosis following unsedated percutaneous endoscopic gastrostomy in ALS patients. Muscle Nerve. 2016;54(2):277-283.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niedermeyer S, Murn M, Choi PJ. Respiratory Failure in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. Chest. 2019;155(2):401-408.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chio A, Galletti R, Finocchiaro C, et&#xa0;al. Percutaneous radiological gastrostomy: a safe and effective method of nutritional tube placement in advanced ALS. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2004;75(4):645-647.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boitano LJ, Jordan T, Benditt JO. Noninvasive ventilation allows gastrostomy tube placement in patients with advanced ALS. Neurology. 2001;56(3):413-414.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park JH, Kang SW. Percutaneous radiologic gastrostomy in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis on noninvasive ventilation. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2009;90(6):1026-1029.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, Miller RG, Swash M, Munsat TL. El Escorial revisited: revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord. 2000;1(5):293-299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR. El Escorial World Federation of Neurology criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Subcommittee on Motor Neuron Diseases/Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis of the World Federation of Neurology Research Group on Neuromuscular Diseases and the El Escorial &#x201c;Clinical limits of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis&#x201d; workshop contributors. J Neurol Sci. 1994;124(suppl):96-107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson SH, Cooke NT, Edwards RH, Spiro SG. Predicted normal values for maximal respiratory pressures in caucasian adults and children. Thorax. 1984;39(7):535-538.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang SW. Pulmonary rehabilitation in patients with neuromuscular disease. Yonsei Med J. 2006;47(3):307-314.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ward S, Chatwin M, Heather S, Simonds AK. Randomised controlled trial of non-invasive ventilation (NIV) for nocturnal hypoventilation in neuromuscular and chest wall disease patients with daytime normocapnia. Thorax. 2005;60(12):1019-1024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berry RB, Budhiraja R, Gottlieb DJ, et&#xa0;al. Rules for scoring respiratory events in sleep: update of the 2007 AASM Manual for the Scoring of Sleep and Associated Events. Deliberations of the Sleep Apnea Definitions Task Force of the American Academy of Sleep Medicine. J Clin Sleep Med. 2012;8(5):597-619.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Won YH, Choi WA, Lee JW, Bach JR, Park J, Kang SW. Sleep transcutaneous vs. end-tidal CO2 monitoring for patients with neuromuscular disease. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2016;95(2):91-95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McClellan F, Washington M, Ruff R, Selkirk SM. Early and innovative symptomatic care to improve quality of life of ALS patients at Cleveland VA ALS Center. J Rehabil Res Dev. 2013;50(4):vii-xvi.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zamietra K, Lehman EB, Felgoise SH, Walsh SM, Stephens HE, Simmons Z. Non-invasive ventilation and gastrostomy may not impact overall quality of life in patients with ALS. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2012;13(1):55-58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desport JC, Preux PM, Truong CT, Courat L, Vallat JM, Couratier P. Nutritional assessment and survival in ALS patients. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord. 2000;1(2):91-96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazzini L, Corra T, Zaccala M, Mora G, Del Piano M, Galante M. Percutaneous endoscopic gastrostomy and enteral nutrition in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol. 1995;242(10):695-698.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller RG, Rosenberg JA, Gelinas DF, et&#xa0;al. Practice parameter: The care of the patient with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (an evidence-based review). Muscle Nerve. 1999;22(8):1104-1118.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Czell D, Bauer M, Binek J, Schoch OD, Weber M. Outcomes of percutaneous endoscopic gastrostomy tube insertion in respiratory impaired amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients under noninvasive ventilation. Respir Care. 2013;58(5):838-844.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarmento A, de Andrade AF, Lima IN, Aliverti A, de Freitas Fregonezi GA, Resqueti VR. Air stacking: a detailed look into physiological acute effects on cough peak flow and chest wall volumes of healthy subjects. Respir Care. 2017;62(4):432-443.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dorst J, Dupuis L, Petri S, et&#xa0;al. Percutaneous endoscopic gastrostomy in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a prospective observational study. J Neurol. 2015;262(4):849-858.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoang PT, Menias CO, Niemeyer MM. Percutaneous gastrostomy tube placement: recognizing when things go wrong. Semin Intervent Radiol. 2019;36(3):264-274.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strijbos D, Hofstede J, Keszthelyi D, Masclee AAM, Gilissen LPL. Percutaneous endoscopic gastrostomy under conscious sedation in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis is safe: an observational study. Eur J Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2017;29(11):1303-1308.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desport JC, Mabrouk T, Bouillet P, Perna A, Preux PM, Couratier P. Complications and survival following radiologically and endoscopically-guided gastrostomy in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord. 2005;6(2):88-93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russ KB, Phillips MC, Wilcox CM, Peter S. Percutaneous endoscopic gastrostomy in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Am J Med Sci. 2015;350(2):95-97.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>