<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">32946280</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>18</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2325-6621</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Annals of the American Thoracic Society</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Ann Am Thorac Soc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Noninvasive Ventilation Use Is Associated with Better Survival in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>486</StartPage><EndPage>494</EndPage><MedlinePgn>486-494</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1513/AnnalsATS.202002-169OC</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText><b>Rationale:</b> Noninvasive ventilation (NIV) is standard of care in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS), yet few data exist regarding its benefits.<b>Objectives:</b> We sought to identify whether the use of NIV was associated with survival in ALS.<b>Methods:</b> This was a single-center retrospective cohort study of 452 patients with ALS seen between 2006 and 2015. We matched one or more NIV subjects (prescribed NIV) to non-NIV subjects (never prescribed NIV) without replacement. The outcome was time from NIV prescription date (NIV subjects) or matched date (non-NIV subjects) until death. We performed a multivariable Cox proportional hazards model with NIV hourly usage as a time-varying covariate and stratified by matched groups.<b>Results:</b> After creating 180 matched groups and adjusting for age, body mass index, ALS Functional Rating Scale Revised dyspnea score, and hourly NIV use, NIV was associated with a 26% reduction in the rate of death compared with non-NIV subjects (hazard ratio [HR], 0.74; 95% confidence interval [CI], 0.57-0.98; <i>P</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.04). Among those with limb-onset ALS, NIV subjects had a 37% lower rate of death compared with non-NIV subjects (HR, 0.63; 95% CI, 0.45-0.87; <i>P</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.006). Among NIV subjects, we found that NIV use for an average of &#x2265;4 h/d was associated with improved survival.<b>Conclusions:</b> NIV use was associated with significantly better survival in ALS after matching and adjusting for confounders. Increasing duration of daily NIV use was associated with longer survival. Randomized clinical trials should be performed to identify ideal thresholds for improving survival and optimizing adherence in ALS.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ackrivo</LastName><ForeName>Jason</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4379-1255</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hsu</LastName><ForeName>Jesse Y</ForeName><Initials>JY</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1522-6534</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biostatistics, Epidemiology and Informatics.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Clinical Epidemiology and Biostatistics, and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hansen-Flaschen</LastName><ForeName>John</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1989-7244</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Elman</LastName><ForeName>Lauren</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4706-950X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Perelman School of Medicine at the University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kawut</LastName><ForeName>Steven M</ForeName><Initials>SM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7896-0608</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Clinical Epidemiology and Biostatistics, and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>F32 HL144145</GrantID><Acronym>HL</Acronym><Agency>NHLBI NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>K23 HL151879</GrantID><Acronym>HL</Acronym><Agency>NHLBI NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>K24 HL103844</GrantID><Acronym>HL</Acronym><Agency>NHLBI NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>T32 HL007891</GrantID><Acronym>HL</Acronym><Agency>NHLBI NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Ann Am Thorac Soc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101600811</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2325-6621</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="CommentIn"><RefSource>Ann Am Thorac Soc. 2021 Mar;18(3):419-420</RefSource><PMID Version="1">33646079</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D063087" MajorTopicYN="Y">Noninvasive Ventilation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012131" MajorTopicYN="Y">Respiratory Insufficiency</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013997" MajorTopicYN="N">Time Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">matching</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">noninvasive ventilation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">respiratory failure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">survival analysis</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32946280</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7919153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1513/AnnalsATS.202002-169OC</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Brown RH, Al-Chalabi A. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. N Engl J Med. 2017;377:162&#x2013;172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28700839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsai C-P, Chang B-H, Lee CT-C. Underlying cause and place of death among patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in Taiwan: a population-based study, 2003-2008. J Epidemiol. 2013;23:424&#x2013;428.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3834279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23933623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bourke SC, Tomlinson M, Williams TL, Bullock RE, Shaw PJ, Gibson GJ. Effects of non-invasive ventilation on survival and quality of life in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a randomised controlled trial. Lancet Neurol. 2006;5:140&#x2013;147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16426990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sancho J, Servera E, Morelot-Panzini C, Salachas F, Similowski T, Gonzalez-Bermejo J. Non-invasive ventilation effectiveness and the effect of ventilatory mode on survival in ALS patients. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2014;15:55&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24266679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paipa AJ, Povedano M, Barcelo A, Dom&#xed;nguez R, Saez M, Turon J, et al. Survival benefit of multidisciplinary care in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in Spain: association with noninvasive mechanical ventilation. J Multidiscip Healthc. 2019;12:465&#x2013;470.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6590410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31354285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bach JR. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: prolongation of life by noninvasive respiratory AIDS. Chest. 2002;122:92&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12114343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berlowitz DJ, Howard ME, Fiore JF, Jr, Vander Hoorn S, O&#x2019;Donoghue FJ, Westlake J, et al. Identifying who will benefit from non-invasive ventilation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis/motor neurone disease in a clinical cohort. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2016;87:280&#x2013;286.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25857659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peysson S, Vandenberghe N, Philit F, Vial C, Petitjean T, Bouhour F, et al. Factors predicting survival following noninvasive ventilation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Eur Neurol. 2008;59:164&#x2013;171.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18230874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller RG, Jackson CE, Kasarskis EJ, England JD, Forshew D, Johnston W, et al. Quality Standards Subcommittee of the American Academy of Neurology. Practice parameter update: the care of the patient with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: drug, nutritional, and respiratory therapies (an evidence-based review): report of the Quality Standards Subcommittee of the American Academy of Neurology. Neurology. 2009;73:1218&#x2013;1226.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2764727</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19822872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen PM, Abrahams S, Borasio GD, de Carvalho M, Chio A, Van Damme P, et al. EFNS Task Force on Diagnosis and Management of Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. EFNS guidelines on the clinical management of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (MALS): revised report of an EFNS task force. Eur J Neurol. 2012;19:360&#x2013;375.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21914052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kleopa KA, Sherman M, Neal B, Romano GJ, Heiman-Patterson T. Bipap improves survival and rate of pulmonary function decline in patients with ALS. J Neurol Sci. 1999;164:82&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10385053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sancho J, Mart&#xed;nez D, Bures E, D&#xed;az JL, Ponz A, Servera E. Bulbar impairment score and survival of stable amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients after noninvasive ventilation initiation. ERJ Open Res. 2018;4:1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5900060</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29670892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kent DM, van Klaveren D, Paulus JK, D&#x2019;Agostino R, Goodman S, Hayward R, et al. The Predictive Approaches to Treatment effect Heterogeneity (PATH) statement: explanation and elaboration. Ann Intern Med. 2020;172:W1&#x2013;W25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7750907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31711094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, Miller RG, Swash M, Munsat TL World Federation of Neurology Research Group on Motor Neuron Diseases. El Escorial revisited: revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord. 2000;1:293&#x2013;299.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11464847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stuart EA. Matching methods for causal inference: a review and a look forward. Stat Sci. 2010;25:1&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2943670</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20871802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rubin DB. Bias reduction using Mahalanobis metric matching. Ets Res Bulletin Ser. 1978;1978:1&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lederer DJ, Bell SC, Branson RD, Chalmers JD, Marshall R, Maslove DM, et al. Control of confounding and reporting of results in causal inference studies: guidance for authors from editors of Respiratory, Sleep, and Critical Care journals. Ann Am Thorac Soc. 2019;16:22&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30230362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Czaplinski A, Yen AA, Simpson EP, Appel SH. Predictability of disease progression in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 2006;34:702&#x2013;708.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16967489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Czaplinski A, Yen AA, Appel SH. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: early predictors of prolonged survival. J Neurol. 2006;253:1428&#x2013;1436.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16773270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Czaplinski A, Yen AA, Appel SH. Forced vital capacity (FVC) as an indicator of survival and disease progression in an ALS clinic population. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2006;77:390&#x2013;392.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2077717</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16484652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paganoni S, Deng J, Jaffa M, Cudkowicz ME, Wills AM. Body mass index, not dyslipidemia, is an independent predictor of survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 2011;44:20&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4441750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21607987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calvo A, Moglia C, Lunetta C, Marinou K, Ticozzi N, Ferrante GD, et al. Factors predicting survival in ALS: a multicenter Italian study. J Neurol. 2017;264:54&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27778156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westeneng H-J, Debray TPA, Visser AE, van Eijk RPA, Rooney JPK, Calvo A, et al. Prognosis for patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: development and validation of a personalised prediction model. Lancet Neurol. 2018;17:423&#x2013;433.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29598923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magnus T, Beck M, Giess R, Puls I, Naumann M, Toyka KV. Disease progression in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: predictors of survival. Muscle Nerve. 2002;25:709&#x2013;714.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11994965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bourke SC, Bullock RE, Williams TL, Shaw PJ, Gibson GJ. Noninvasive ventilation in ALS: indications and effect on quality of life. Neurology. 2003;61:171&#x2013;177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12874394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ackrivo J, Hansen-Flaschen J, Wileyto EP, Schwab RJ, Elman L, Kawut SM. Development of a prognostic model of respiratory insufficiency or death in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Eur Respir J. 2019;53:1802237.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6684229</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30728207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ackrivo J, Hansen-Flaschen J, Jones BL, Wileyto EP, Schwab RJ, Elman L, et al. Classifying patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis by changes in FVC: a group-based trajectory analysis. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2019;200:1513&#x2013;1521.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6909832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31322417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boher J-M, Filleron T, Giorgi R, Kramar A, Cook RJ. Goodness-of-fit test for monotone proportional subdistribution hazards assumptions based on weighted residuals. Stat Med. 2017;36:362&#x2013;377.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27790725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld D. Chi-squared goodness-of-fit tests for the proportional hazards regression model. Biometrika. 1980;67:145&#x2013;153.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lo Coco D, Marchese S, Pesco MC, La Bella V, Piccoli F, Lo Coco A. Noninvasive positive-pressure ventilation in ALS: predictors of tolerance and survival. Neurology. 2006;67:761&#x2013;765.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16899545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lechtzin N, Scott Y, Busse AM, Clawson LL, Kimball R, Wiener CM. Early use of non-invasive ventilation prolongs survival in subjects with ALS. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2007;8:185&#x2013;188.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17538782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vitacca M, Montini A, Lunetta C, Banfi P, Bertella E, De Mattia E, et al. ALS RESPILOM Study Group. Impact of an early respiratory care programme with non-invasive ventilation adaptation in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Eur J Neurol. 2018;25:556&#x2013;e33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29266547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boentert M, Brenscheidt I, Glatz C, Young P. Effects of non-invasive ventilation on objective sleep and nocturnal respiration in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol. 2015;262:2073&#x2013;2082.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26076745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vrijsen B, Buyse B, Belge C, Robberecht W, Van Damme P, Decramer M, et al. Noninvasive ventilation improves sleep in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a prospective polysomnographic study. J Clin Sleep Med. 2015;11:559&#x2013;566.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4410930</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25766713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>