<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">32978838</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>12</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1468-1331</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>28</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Cardiovascular disease, psychiatric diagnosis and sex differences in the multistep hypothesis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>421</StartPage><EndPage>429</EndPage><MedlinePgn>421-429</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/ene.14554</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND PURPOSE">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) risk increases with age, and a linear log-incidence and log-age relationship is interpreted to suggest that five to six factors are involved in disease onset. The factors remain unidentified, except that fewer steps are predicted for those carrying a known ALS-causing mutation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Men with a psychiatric disorder or cardiovascular disease (CVD) diagnosis have an increased relative risk of ALS. Using the Danish population registries and ALS diagnosis years 1980 to 2017, we tested whether these factors would decrease the predicted steps to disease.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Consistent with previous reports, we find a linear log-incidence and log-age ALS-onset relationship (n&#xa0;=&#xa0;4385, regression coefficient b&#xa0;=&#xa0;4.6, 95% confidence interval [CI]: 4.3-4.9, R<sup>2</sup> &#xa0;=&#xa0;0.99). This did not differ when considering ALS cases with a prior psychiatric diagnosis (n&#xa0;=&#xa0;391, b&#xa0;=&#xa0;4.6, 95% CI: 4.0-5.1) Surprisingly, it was higher (+1.5 steps, P&#xa0;=&#xa0;2.3&#xa0;&#xd7;&#xa0;10<sup>-5</sup> ) for those with a prior CVD diagnosis (n&#xa0;=&#xa0;901, b&#xa0;=&#xa0;6.1, 95% CI: 5.4-6.8). To control for competing risk of death, a test to investigate if this effect was maintained in those with CVD in the population demonstrated an increased baseline risk and fewer steps to disease (b&#xa0;=&#xa0;1.8, 95% CI: 1.2-2.3, P&#xa0;=&#xa0;4.6&#xa0;&#xd7;&#xa0;10<sup>-21</sup> ), which consistent with a positive association of CVD and ALS. Assessing sex differences, our data and meta-analyses (n&#xa0;=&#xa0;22&#xa0;495) support half a step fewer for men (-0.4, 95% CI: &#xb1;0.24, P&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.00031) without support for contributing differences explained by menopause.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Any factor associated with ALS disease onset may be relevant for understanding disease pathogenesis and/or counselling. Modelling disease incidence with age demonstrates some insight into relevant risk factors; however, the outcome can differ if competing risks are considered.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020 European Academy of Neurology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Garton</LastName><ForeName>F C</ForeName><Initials>FC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1490-5930</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Molecular Bioscience, University of Queensland, Brisbane, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Trabjerg</LastName><ForeName>B B</ForeName><Initials>BB</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6282-2614</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Centre for Register-Based Research NCRR, Aarhus University, Aarhus, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Integrated Register-Based Research CIRRAU, Aarhus University, Aarhus, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Lundbeck Foundation Initiative for Integrative Psychiatric Research, iPSYCH, Aarhus, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wray</LastName><ForeName>N R</ForeName><Initials>NR</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7421-3357</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Molecular Bioscience, University of Queensland, Brisbane, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Queensland Brain Institute, University of Queensland, Brisbane, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Agerbo</LastName><ForeName>E</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2849-524X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Centre for Register-Based Research NCRR, Aarhus University, Aarhus, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Integrated Register-Based Research CIRRAU, Aarhus University, Aarhus, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Lundbeck Foundation Initiative for Integrative Psychiatric Research, iPSYCH, Aarhus, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9506311</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1351-5101</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002318" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cardiovascular Diseases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015994" MajorTopicYN="N">Incidence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001523" MajorTopicYN="Y">Mental Disorders</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012727" MajorTopicYN="N">Sex Characteristics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Denmark</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cardiovascular disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">incidence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">male</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32978838</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ene.14554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Armitage P, Doll R. The age distribution of cancer and a multi-stage theory of carcinogenesis. Br J Cancer 1954; 8: 1-12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Chalabi A, Calvo A, Chio A, et al. Analysis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis as a multistep process: a population-based modelling study. Lancet Neurol 2014; 13: 1108-1113.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S, Westeneng HJ, Al-Chalabi A, Van Den Berg LH, Talman P, Kiernan MC. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis as a multi-step process: an Australia population study. Amyotrophic Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2019; 20: 532-537.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S, Higashihara M, Sobue G, et al. ALS is a multistep process in South Korean, Japanese, and Australian patients. Neurology 2020; 94: e1657-e1663.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chio A, Mazzini L, D'Alfonso S, et al. The multistep hypothesis of ALS revisited: the role of genetic mutations. Neurology 2018; 91: e635-e642.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zou ZY, Zhou ZR, Che CH, Liu CY, He RL, Huang HP. Genetic epidemiology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2017; 88: 540-549.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veldink JH. ALS genetic epidemiology; How simplex is the genetic epidemiology of ALS? J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2017; 88: 537.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin S, Al Khleifat A, Al-Chalabi A. What causes amyotrophic lateral sclerosis? F1000Res 2017; 6: 371.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trabjerg BB, Garton FC, van Rheenen W, et al. ALS in Danish Registries. Neurology. Genetics 2020; 6: e398.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee SH, Yang J, Goddard ME, Visscher PM, Wray NR. Estimation of pleiotropy between complex diseases using single-nucleotide polymorphism-derived genomic relationships and restricted maximum likelihood. Bioinformatics 2012; 28: 2540-2542.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bulik-Sullivan B, Finucane HK, Anttila V, et al. An atlas of genetic correlations across human diseases and traits. Nat Genet 2015; 47: 1236-1241.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLaughlin RL, Schijven D, van Rheenen W, et al. Genetic correlation between amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and schizophrenia. Nat Commun 2017; 8: 14774.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kioumourtzoglou M-A, Seals RM, Gredal O, Mittleman MA, Hansen J, Weisskopf MG. Cardiovascular disease and diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a population based study. Amyotrophic Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2016; 17: 548-554.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seals RM, Kioumourtzoglou M-A, Hansen J, Gredal O, Weisskopf MG. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and the military: a population-based study in the Danish Registries. Epidemiology 2016; 27: 188-193.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mors O, Perto GP, Mortensen PB. The Danish Psychiatric Central Research Register. Scand J Public Health 2011; 39: 54-57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laursen TM, Munk-Olsen T, Agerbo E, Gasse C, Mortensen PB. Somatic hospital contacts, invasive cardiac procedures, and mortality from heart disease in patients with severe mental disorder. Arch Gen Psychiatry 2009; 66: 713-720.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R: A language and environment for statistical computing. [computer program]: Vienna, Austria: R Foundation for Statistical Computing; 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kioumourtzoglou MA, Seals RM, Himmerslev L, Gredal O, Hansen J, Weisskopf MG. Comparison of diagnoses of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis by use of death certificates and hospital discharge data in the Danish population. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2015; 16: 224-229.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seals RM, Hansen J, Gredal O, Weisskopf MG. Age-period-cohort analysis of trends in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in Denmark, 1970-2009. Am J Epidemiol 2013; 178: 1265-1271.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manjaly ZR, Scott KM, Abhinav K, et al. The sex ratio in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A population based study. Amyotrophic Lateral Scler 2010; 11: 439-442.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schierbeck LL, Rejnmark L, Tofteng CL, et al. Effect of hormone replacement therapy on cardiovascular events in recently postmenopausal women: randomised trial. Br Med J 2012; 345: e6409.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beltr&#xe1;n-S&#xe1;nchez H, Finch CE, Crimmins EM. Twentieth century surge of excess adult male mortality. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 2015; 112: 8993-8998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trabjerg B, Garton F, van Rheenen W, et al. ALS in Danish Registries. Neurol Genet 2020; 6: e398.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laursen TM. Life expectancy among persons with schizophrenia or bipolar affective disorder. Schizophr Res 2011; 131: 101-104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, Miller RG, Swash M, Munsat TL. El Escorial revisited: revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotrophic Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord 2000; 1: 293-299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bandres-Ciga S, Noyce AJ, Hemani G, et al. Shared polygenic risk and causal inferences in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol 2019; 85: 470-481.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans MC, Couch Y, Sibson N, Turner MR. Inflammation and neurovascular changes in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Mol Cell Neurosci 2013; 53: 34-41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore KJ. Targeting inflammation in CVD: advances and challenges. Nat Rev Cardiol 2019; 16: 74-75.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>