<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">32991398</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>28</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2048-7940</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>46</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><MedlineDate>2021 Sep-Oct 01</MedlineDate></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Rehabilitation nursing : the official journal of the Association of Rehabilitation Nurses</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Rehabil Nurs</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Quality of Life Structural Equation Model for Patients With Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>253</StartPage><EndPage>261</EndPage><MedlinePgn>253-261</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/RNJ.0000000000000292</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The aim of the study was to propose and test a quality of life model among Korean patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) using structural equation modeling.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DESIGN" NlmCategory="METHODS">A cross-sectional study was performed.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Data from 184 patients with ALS were collected from two university hospitals in Seoul and Busan, South Korea, between June and December 2018.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="FINDINGS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The modified model indices indicated adequate data fit. Quality of life predictors were social support, physical functional status, depression, and general health perception.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This study improved the understanding of quality of life for Korean patients with ALS, including complex direct and indirect relationships among quality of life factors.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CLINICAL RELEVANCE" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Depression was identified as the most influential factor in this population; hence, early assessment and timely intervention for depression are essential for better quality of life in patients with ALS.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2020 Association of Rehabilitation Nurses.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oh</LastName><ForeName>Juyeon</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Nursing, Dankook University, Cheonan, South Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Jung A</ForeName><Initials>JA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Nursing, Hanyang University, Seoul, South Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Rehabil Nurs</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8104825</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0278-4807</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003430" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Sectional Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="Y">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D056910" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Republic of Korea</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012944" MajorTopicYN="N">Social Support</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32991398</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/RNJ.0000000000000292</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00006939-202109000-00003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abe K. (2004). Fatigue and depression are associated with poor quality of life in ALS. Neurology, 62(10), 1914.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Averill A. J., Kasarskis E. J., Segerstrom S. C. (2013). Expressive disclosure to improve well-being in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A randomised, controlled trial. Psychology &amp; Health, 28(6), 701&#x2013;713. 10.1080/08870446.2012.754891.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/08870446.2012.754891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakas T., McLennon S. M., Carpenter J. S., Buelow J. M., Otte J. L., Hanna K. M., Ellett M. L., Hadler K. A., Welch J. L. (2012). Systematic review of health-related quality of life models. Health and Quality of Life Outcomes, 10, 134. 10.1186/1477-7525-10-134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1477-7525-10-134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beeldman E., Raaphorst J., Klein Twennaar M., de Visser M., Schmand B. A., de Haan R. J. (2016). The cognitive profile of ALS: A systematic review and meta-analysis update. Journal of Neurology, Neurosurgery, and Psychiatry, 87(6), 611&#x2013;619. 10.1136/jnnp-2015-310734.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp-2015-310734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beran T. N., Violato C. (2010). Structural equation modeling in medical research: A primer. BMC Research Notes, 3, 267. 10.1186/1756-0500-3-267.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1756-0500-3-267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bremer B. A., Simone A. L., Walsh S., Simmons Z., Felgoise S. H. (2004). Factors supporting quality of life over time for individuals with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: The role of positive self-perception and religiosity. Annals of Behavioral Medicine, 28(2), 119&#x2013;125. 10.1207/s15324796abm2802_7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1207/s15324796abm2802_7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks B. R., Miller R. G., Swash M., Munsat T. L.; World Federation of Neurology Research Group on Motor Neuron Diseases (2000). El Escorial revisited: Revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis &amp; Frontotemporal Degeneration, 1(5), 293&#x2013;299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burns T. M., Graham C. D., Rose M. R., Simmons Z. (2012). Quality of life and measures of quality of life in patients with neuromuscular disorders. Muscle &amp; Nerve, 46(1), 9&#x2013;25. 10.1002/mus.23245.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.23245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carmack C. L., Basen-Engquist K., Yuan Y., Greisinger A., Rodriguez-Bigas M., Wolff R. A., Barker T., Baum G., Pennebaker J. W. (2011). Feasibility of an expressive-disclosure group intervention for post-treatment colorectal cancer patients. Cancer, 117(21), 4993&#x2013;5002. 10.1002/cncr.26110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cncr.26110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum J. M., Stambler N., Malta E., Fuller C., Hilt D., Thurmond B., Nakanishi A. (1999). The ALSFRS-R: A revised ALS Functional Rating Scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. BDNF ALS Study Group (Phase III). Journal of the Neurological Sciences, 169(1&#x2013;2), 13&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chio A., Gauthier A., Montuschi A., Calvo A., Di Vito N., Ghiglione P., Mutani R. (2004). A cross-sectional study on determinants of quality of life in ALS. Journal of Neurology, Neurosurgery, and Psychiatry, 75(11), 1597&#x2013;1601. 10.1136/jnnp.2003.033100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp.2003.033100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chu H. S., Oh J. (2020). Information needs and preferences of family caregivers of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Journal of Neuroscience Nursing. 52(5), 207&#x2013;213. 10.1097/JNN.0000000000000534.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/JNN.0000000000000534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Felgoise S. H., Feinberg R., Stephens H. E., Barkhaus P., Boylan K., Caress J., Clawson L. L., Elman L., Goutman S. A., Mccluskey L., Russell J., Tiryaki E., Weiss M., Simmons Z. (2018). Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis-Specific Quality of Life&#x2013;Short Form (ALSSQOL-SF): A brief, reliable, and valid version of the ALSSQOL-R. Muscle &amp; Nerve, 58(5), 646&#x2013;654. 10.1002/mus.26203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.26203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrans C. E., Zerwic J. J., Wilbur J. E., Larson J. L. (2005). Conceptual model of health-related quality of life. Journal of Nursing Scholarship, 37(4), 336&#x2013;342.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fornell C., Larcker D. F. (1981). Evaluating structural equation models with unobservable variables and measurement error. Journal of Marketing Research, 18(1), 39&#x2013;50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fox-Wasylyshyn S. M., El-Masri M. M. (2005). Handling missing data in self-report measures. Research in Nursing &amp; Health, 28(6), 488&#x2013;495. 10.1002/nur.20100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/nur.20100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibbons C., Thornton E., Ealing J., Shaw P., Talbot K., Tennant A., Young C. (2013). The impact of fatigue and psychosocial variables on quality of life for patients with motor neuron disease. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis &amp; Frontotemporal Degeneration, 14(7&#x2013;8), 537&#x2013;545. 10.3109/21678421.2013.799700.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/21678421.2013.799700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hong S. H. (2000). The criteria for selecting appropriate fit indices in structural equation modeling and their rationales. Korean Journal of Clinical Psychology, 19(1), 161&#x2013;177.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jakobsson Larsson B., Ozanne A. G., Nordin K., Nygren I. (2017). A prospective study of quality of life in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. Acta Neurologica Scandinavica, 136(6), 631&#x2013;638. 10.1111/ane.12774.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ane.12774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jun K. Y., Park J., Oh K. W., Kim E. M., Bae J. S., Kim I., Kim S. H. (2019). Epidemiology of ALS in Korea using nationwide big data. Journal of Neurology, Neurosurgery, and Psychiatry, 90(4), 395&#x2013;403. 10.1136/jnnp-2018-318974.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp-2018-318974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim J. H., Shin S., Park J. H. (2015). A methodological quality assessment of South Korean nursing research using structural equation modeling in South Korea. Journal of Korean Academy of Nursing, 45(2), 159&#x2013;168. 10.4040/jkan.2015.45.2.159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4040/jkan.2015.45.2.159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korner S., Kollewe K., Abdulla S., Zapf A., Dengler R., Petri S. (2015). Interaction of physical function, quality of life and depression in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Characterization of a large patient cohort. BMC Neurology, 15, 84. 10.1186/s12883-015-0340-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12883-015-0340-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee Y.-K., Lim N.-Y., Kim S.-H. (2008). The adjustment process of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Journal of Muscle and Joint Health, 15(2), 140&#x2013;154.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Little R. J. (1988). A test of missing completely at random for multivariate data with missing values. Journal of the American Statistical Association, 83(404), 1198&#x2013;1202.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lou J. S., Moore D., Gordon P. H., Miller R. (2010). Correlates of quality of life in ALS: Lessons from the minocycline study. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis, 11(1&#x2013;2), 116&#x2013;121. 10.3109/17482960902918719.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/17482960902918719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNair D. M. (1971). Manual Profile of Mood States. Educational &amp; Industrial Testing Service.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miglioretti M., Mazzini L., Oggioni G. D., Testa L., Monaco F. (2008). Illness perceptions, mood and health-related quality of life in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Journal of Psychosomatic Research, 65(6), 603&#x2013;609. 10.1016/j.jpsychores.2008.05.012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpsychores.2008.05.012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moon Y. S., Kim D. H. (2013). Association between religiosity/spirituality and quality of life or depression among living-alone elderly in a South Korean city. Asia-Pacific Psychiatry, 5(4), 293&#x2013;300. 10.1111/appy.12025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/appy.12025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nevitt J., Hancock G. R. (2001). Performance of bootstrapping approaches to model test statistics and parameter standard error estimation in structural equation modeling. Structural Equation Modeling, 8(3), 353&#x2013;377.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh H., Sin M. K., Schepp K. G., Choi-Kwon S. (2012). Depressive symptoms and functional impairment among amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients in South Korea. Rehabilitation Nursing, 37(3), 136&#x2013;144. 10.1002/rnj.00045.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/rnj.00045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh J., Hong G. R. S., Kim S. H., Kim J. A. (2017). Translation and psychometric evaluation of a Korean version of the Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis-Specific Quality of Life&#x2013;Revised. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis &amp; Frontotemporal Degeneration, 18(1&#x2013;2), 92&#x2013;98. 10.1080/21678421.2016.1249885.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/21678421.2016.1249885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh J., Kim S. H., Kim J. A. (2019). Unmet supportive care needs mediate the relationship between functional status and quality of life in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Palliative &amp; Supportive Care, 17(6), 650&#x2013;654. 10.1017/s1478951519000221.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/s1478951519000221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pagnini F. (2013). Psychological wellbeing and quality of life in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A review. International Journal of Psychology, 48(3), 194&#x2013;205. 10.1080/00207594.2012.691977.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00207594.2012.691977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park H., Nguyen T., Park H. (2012). Validation of Multidimensional Scale of Perceived Social Support in middle-aged Korean women with diabetes. Asia Pacific Journal of Social Work and Development, 22(3), 202&#x2013;213. 10.1080/02185385.2012.691719.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02185385.2012.691719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peric S., Rakocevic-Stojanovic V., Stevic Z., Basta I., Pavlovic S., Vujanac V., Marjanovic L., Lavrnic D. (2010). Health-related quality of life in patients with myotonic dystrophy Type 1 and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neurologica Belgica, 110(1), 71&#x2013;77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roos E., Mariosa D., Ingre C., Lundholm C., Wirdefeldt K., Roos P. M., Fang F. (2016). Depression in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology, 86(24), 2271&#x2013;2277. 10.1212/wnl.0000000000002671.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/wnl.0000000000002671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rowland L. P., Shneider N. A. (2001). Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. The New England Journal of Medicine, 344(22), 1688&#x2013;1700. 10.1056/NEJM200105313442207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJM200105313442207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandstedt P., Johansson S., Ytterberg C., Ingre C., Holmqvist L. W., Kierkegaard M. (2016). Predictors of health-related quality of life in people with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Journal of the Neurological Sciences, 370, 269&#x2013;273. 10.1016/j.jns.2016.09.034.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jns.2016.09.034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seo H. J., Ryu E. J., Ham M. Y. (2018). Relationships among mood status, social support, symptom experience and quality of life in colorectal cancer patients-based on the theory of unpleasant symptoms. Asian Oncology Nursing, 18(2), 104&#x2013;113.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shamshiri H., Fatehi F., Abolfazli R., Harirchian M. H., Sedighi B., Zamani B., Roudbari A., Razazian N., Khamseh F., Nafissi S. (2016). Trends of quality of life changes in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. Journal of the Neurological Sciences, 368, 35&#x2013;40. 10.1016/j.jns.2016.06.056.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jns.2016.06.056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simmons Z. (2015). Patient-perceived outcomes and quality of life in ALS. Neurotherapeutics, 12(2), 394&#x2013;402. 10.1007/s13311-014-0322-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13311-014-0322-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weldring T., Smith S. M. S. (2013). Patient-reported outcomes (PROs) and patient-reported outcome measures (PROMs). Health Services Insights, 6, 61&#x2013;68. 10.4137/hsi.s11093.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4137/hsi.s11093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>West S. G., Finch J. F., Curran P. J. (1995). Structural equation models with nonnormal variables: Problems and remedies. Sage.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHOQoL Group (1995). The World Health Organization Quality of Life Assessment (WHOQoL): Position paper from the World Health Organization. Social Science &amp; Medicine, 41(10), 1403&#x2013;1409.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeun E. J., Shin-Park K. K. (2006). Verification of the Profile of Mood States&#x2013;Brief: Cross-cultural analysis. Journal of Clinical Psychology, 62(9), 1173&#x2013;1180. 10.1002/jclp.20269.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jclp.20269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoo S. Y. (2013). Analysis of research trends about spiritual care in Korea. Korean Journal of Adult Nursing, 25(3), 332&#x2013;343.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young C. A., Ealing J., McDermott C., Williams T., Al-Chalabi A., Majeed T., Burke G., Pinto A., Dick D., Talbot K., Harrower T., Walsh J., Chandran S., Hanemann C. O., Mills R., Tennant A. (2019). The relationships between symptoms, disability, perceived health and quality of life in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis/motor neuron disease. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerlosis Frontotemporal Degeneration, 20(5&#x2013;6), 317&#x2013;327. 10.1080/21678421.2019.1615951.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/21678421.2019.1615951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu J. (2014). The misunderstanding and prejudice of structural equation models. Hannare.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zach N., Ennist D. L., Taylor A. A., Alon H., Sherman A., Kueffner R., Walker J., Sinani E., Katsovskiy I., Cudkowicz M., Leitner M. L. (2015). Being PRO-ACTive: What can a clinical trial database reveal about ALS?Neurotherapeutics, 12(2), 417&#x2013;423. 10.1007/s13311-015-0336-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13311-015-0336-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zimet G. D., Dahlem N. W., Zimet S. G., Farley G. K. (1988). The Multidimensional Scale of Perceived Social Support. Journal of Personality Assessment, 52(1), 30&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>