<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">33064315</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>17</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-4159</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>157</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>May</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of neurochemistry</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Neurochem</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Mislocalisation of TDP-43 to the cytoplasm causes cortical hyperexcitability and reduced excitatory neurotransmission in the motor cortex.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1300</StartPage><EndPage>1315</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1300-1315</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/jnc.15214</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) is a chronic neurodegenerative disease pathologically characterised by mislocalisation of the RNA-binding protein TAR-DNA-binding protein 43 (TDP-43) from the nucleus to the cytoplasm. Changes to neuronal excitability and synapse dysfunction in the motor cortex are early pathological changes occurring in people with ALS and mouse models of disease. To investigate the effect of mislocalised TDP-43 on the function of motor cortex neurons we utilised mouse models that express either human wild-type (TDP-43<sup>WT</sup> ) or nuclear localisation sequence-deficient TDP-43 (TDP-43<sup>&#x394;NLS</sup> ) on an inducible promoter that enriches expression to forebrain neurons. Pathophysiology was investigated through immunohistochemistry and whole-cell patch-clamp electrophysiology. Thirty days expression of TDP-43<sup>&#x394;NLS</sup> in adult mice did not cause any changes in the number of CTIP2-positive neurons in the motor cortex. However, at this time-point, the expression of TDP-43<sup>&#x394;NLS</sup> drives intrinsic hyperexcitability in layer V excitatory neurons of the motor cortex. This hyperexcitability occurs concomitantly with a decrease in excitatory synaptic input to these cells and fluctuations in both directions of ionotropic glutamate receptors. This pathophysiology is not present with TDP-43<sup>WT</sup> expression, demonstrating that the localisation of TDP-43 to the cytoplasm is crucial for the altered excitability phenotype. This study has important implications for the mechanisms of toxicity of one of the most notorious proteins linked to ALS, TDP-43. We provide the first evidence that TDP-43 mislocalisation causes aberrant synaptic function and a hyperexcitability phenotype in the motor cortex, linking some of the earliest dysfunctions to arise in people with ALS to mislocalisation of TDP-43.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020 International Society for Neurochemistry.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dyer</LastName><ForeName>Marcus S</ForeName><Initials>MS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Menzies Institute for Medical Research, College of Health and Medicine, University of Tasmania, Hobart, Tas, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Reale</LastName><ForeName>Laura A</ForeName><Initials>LA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Menzies Institute for Medical Research, College of Health and Medicine, University of Tasmania, Hobart, Tas, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lewis</LastName><ForeName>Katherine E</ForeName><Initials>KE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Menzies Institute for Medical Research, College of Health and Medicine, University of Tasmania, Hobart, Tas, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Walker</LastName><ForeName>Adam K</ForeName><Initials>AK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurodegeneration Pathobiology Laboratory, Queensland Brain Institute, University of Queensland, Brisbane, Qld, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dickson</LastName><ForeName>Tracey C</ForeName><Initials>TC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9196-1661</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Menzies Institute for Medical Research, College of Health and Medicine, University of Tasmania, Hobart, Tas, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Woodhouse</LastName><ForeName>Adele</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wicking Dementia Research and Education Centre, College of Health and Medicine, University of Tasmania, Hobart, Tas, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Blizzard</LastName><ForeName>Catherine A</ForeName><Initials>CA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8683-2937</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Menzies Institute for Medical Research, College of Health and Medicine, University of Tasmania, Hobart, Tas, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Neurochem</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>2985190R</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0022-3042</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D004268">DNA-Binding Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C000598624">TARDBP protein, human</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="ErratumIn"><RefSource>J Neurochem. 2021 Nov;159(4):789-790</RefSource><PMID Version="1">34762745</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002540" MajorTopicYN="N">Cerebral Cortex</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003593" MajorTopicYN="N">Cytoplasm</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004268" MajorTopicYN="N">DNA-Binding Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051379" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009044" MajorTopicYN="N">Motor Cortex</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009046" MajorTopicYN="N">Motor Neurons</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D021381" MajorTopicYN="N">Protein Transport</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009435" MajorTopicYN="N">Synaptic Transmission</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ALS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">TDP-43</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cortex</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">excitability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">glutamate</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hyperexcitability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mislocalisation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mouse model</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33064315</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jnc.15214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Al-Chalabi, A., &amp; Hardiman, O. (2013). The epidemiology of ALS: A conspiracy of genes, environment and time. Nature Reviews. Neurology, 9, 617-628. https://doi.org/10.1038/nrneurol.2013.203</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alfieri, J. A., Pino, N. S., &amp; Igaz, L. M. (2014). Reversible behavioral phenotypes in a conditional mouse model of TDP-43 proteinopathies. Journal of Neuroscience, 34, 15244-15259. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.1918-14.2014</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amlie-Wolf, A., Ryvkin, P., Tong, R., Dragomir, I., Suh, E. R., Xu, Y., Van Deerlin, V. M., Gregory, B. D., Kwong, L. K., Trojanowski, J. Q., Lee, V.-Y., Wang, L.-S., &amp; Lee, E. B. (2015). Transcriptomic changes due to cytoplasmic TDP-43 expression reveal dysregulation of histone transcripts and nuclear chromatin. PLoS One, 10, e0141836. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0141836</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson, C. T., Sheets, P. L., Kiritani, T., &amp; Shepherd, G. M. (2010). Sublayer-specific microcircuits of corticospinal and corticostriatal neurons in motor cortex. Nature Neuroscience, 13, 739-744. https://doi.org/10.1038/nn.2538</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arlotta, P., Molyneaux, B. J., Chen, J., Inoue, J., Kominami, R., &amp; Macklis, J. D. (2005). Neuronal subtype-specific genes that control corticospinal motor neuron development in vivo. Neuron, 45, 207-221. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2004.12.036</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayala, Y. M., De Conti, L., Avenda&#xf1;o-V&#xe1;zquez, S. E., Dhir, A., Romano, M., D'Ambrogio, A., Tollervey, J., Ule, J., Baralle, M., Buratti, E., &amp; Baralle, F. E. (2011). TDP-43 regulates its mRNA levels through a negative feedback loop. EMBO Journal, 30, 277-288. https://doi.org/10.1038/emboj.2010.310</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buskila, Y., K&#xe9;kesi, O., Bellot-Saez, A., Seah, W., Berg, T., Trpceski, M., Yerbury, J. J., &amp; Ooi, L. (2019). Dynamic interplay between H-current and M-current controls motoneuron hyperexcitability in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Cell Health and Disease, 10, 310-314. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41419-019-1538-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desai, N. S., Rutherford, N. J., &amp; Turrigiano, G. G. (1999). Plasticity in the intrinsic excitability of cortical pyramidal neurons. Nature Neuroscience, 2, 515-520. https://doi.org/10.1038/9165</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faber, E. S., &amp; Sah, P. (2007). Functions of SK channels in central neurons. Clinical and Experimental Pharmacology and Physiology, 34, 1077-1083. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1440-1681.2007.04725.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fogarty, M. J., Mu, E. W. H., Lavidis, N. A., Noakes, P. G., &amp; Bellingham, M. C. (2017). Motor areas show altered dendritic structure in an amyotrophic lateral sclerosis mouse model. Frontiers in Neuroscience, 11, 609. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnins.2017.00609</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fogarty, M. J., Noakes, P. G., &amp; Bellingham, M. C. (2015). Motor cortex layer V pyramidal neurons exhibit dendritic regression, spine loss, and increased synaptic excitation in the presymptomatic hSOD1(G93A) mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Journal of Neuroscience, 35, 643-647.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geevasinga, N., Menon, P., Ng, K., Van Den Bos, M., Byth, K., Kiernan, M. C., &amp; Vucic, S. (2016). Riluzole exerts transient modulating effects on cortical and axonal hyperexcitability in ALS. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener, 17, 580-588. https://doi.org/10.1080/21678421.2016.1188961</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geevasinga, N., Menon, P., Yiannikas, C., Kiernan, M. C., &amp; Vucic, S. (2014). Diagnostic utility of cortical excitability studies in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. European Journal of Neurology, 21, 1451-1457. https://doi.org/10.1111/ene.12422</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greger, I. H., Watson, J. F., &amp; Cull-Candy, S. G. (2017). Structural and functional architecture of AMPA-Type glutamate receptors and their auxiliary proteins. Neuron, 94, 713-730. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2017.04.009</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gregory, J. M., Livesey, M. R., McDade, K., Selvaraj, B. T., Barton, S. K., Chandran, S., &amp; Smith, C. (2020). Dysregulation of AMPA receptor subunit expression in sporadic ALS post-mortem brain. The Journal of Pathology, 250, 67-78. https://doi.org/10.1002/path.5351</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grieve, S. M., Menon, P., Korgaonkar, M. S., Gomes, L., Foster, S., Kiernan, M. C., &amp; Vucic, S. (2015). Potential structural and functional biomarkers of upper motor neuron dysfunction in ALS. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener, 17, 85-92. https://doi.org/10.3109/21678421.2015.1074707</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han, H. J., Allen, C. C., Buchovecky, C. M., Yetman, M. J., Born, H. A., Marin, M. A., Rodgers, S. P., Song, B. J., Lu, H.-C., Justice, M. J., Probst, F. J., &amp; Jankowsky, J. L. (2012). Strain background influences neurotoxicity and behavioral abnormalities in mice expressing the tetracycline transactivator. Journal of Neuroscience, 32, 10574-10586. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.0893-12.2012</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Handley, E. E., Pitman, K. A., Dawkins, E., Young, K. M., Clark, R. M., Jiang, T. C., Turner, B. J., Dickson, T. C., &amp; Blizzard, C. A. (2017). Synapse dysfunction of layer V pyramidal neurons precedes neurodegeneration in a mouse model of TDP-43 proteinopathies. Cerebral Cortex, 27, 3630-3647.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harb, K., Magrinelli, E., Nicolas, C. S., Lukianets, N., Frangeul, L., Pietri, M., Sun, T., Sandoz, G., Grammont, F., Jabaudon, D., Studer, M., &amp; Alfano, C. (2016). Area-specific development of distinct projection neuron subclasses is regulated by postnatal epigenetic modifications. Elife, 5, e09531. https://doi.org/10.7554/eLife.09531</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henley, J., &amp; Wilkinson, K. (2013). AMPA receptor trafficking and the mechanisms underlying synaptic plasticity and cognitive aging. Dialogues in Clinical Neuroscience, 15, 11-27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horoupian, D. S., Thal, L., Katzman, R., Terry, R. D., Davies, P., Hirano, A., DeTeresa, R., Fuld, P. A., Petito, C., Blass, J., &amp; Ellis, J. M. (1984). Dementia and motor neuron disease: Morphometric, biochemical, and Golgi studies. Annals of Neurology, 4, 305-316. https://doi.org/10.1002/ana.410160306</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Igaz, L. M., Kwong, L. K., Lee, E. B., Chen-Plotkin, A., Swanson, E., Unger, T., Malunda, J., Xu, Y., Winton, M. J., Trojanowski, J. Q., &amp; Lee, V.-Y. (2011). Dysregulation of the ALS-associated gene TDP-43 leads to neuronal death and degeneration in mice. Journal of Clinical Investigation, 121, 726-738. https://doi.org/10.1172/JCI44867</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang, T., Handley, E., Brizuela, M., Dawkins, E., Lewis, K. E. A., Clark, R. M., Dickson, T. C., &amp; Blizzard, C. A. (2019). Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis mutant TDP-43 may cause synaptic dysfunction through altered dendritic spine function. Disease Models &amp; Mechanisms, 12. https://doi.org/10.1242/dmm.038109</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, J., Hughes, E. G., Shetty, A. S., Arlotta, P., Goff, L. A., Bergles, D. E., &amp; Brown, S. P. (2017). Changes in the excitability of neocortical neurons in a mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis are not specific to corticospinal neurons and are modulated by advancing disease. Journal of Neuroscience, 37, 9037-9053. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.0811-17.2017</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu-Yesucevitz, L., Bassell, G. J., Gitler, A. D., Hart, A. C., Klann, E., Richter, J. D., Warren, S. T., &amp; Wolozin, B. (2011). Local RNA translation at the synapse and in disease. Journal of Neuroscience, 31, 16086-16093. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.4105-11.2011</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lomeli, H., Mosbacher, J., Melcher, T., Hoger, T., Geiger, J. R., Kuner, T., Monyer, H., Higuchi, M., Bach, A., &amp; Seeburg, P. (1994). Control of kinetic properties of AMPA receptor channels by nuclear RNA editing. Science, 266, 1709-1713. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.7992055</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu, W., Shi, Y., Jackson, A. C., Bjorgan, K., During, M. J., Sprengel, R., Seeburg, P. H., &amp; Nicoll, R. A. (2009). Subunit composition of synaptic AMPA receptors revealed by a single-cell genetic approach. Neuron, 62, 254-268. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2009.02.027</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menon, P., Kiernan, M. C., &amp; Vucic, S. (2015). Cortical hyperexcitability precedes lower motor neuron dysfunction in ALS. Clinical Neurophysiology, 126, 803-809. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.clinph.2014.04.023</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mills, K. R., &amp; Nithi, K. A. (1997). Corticomotor threshold is reduced in early sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle and Nerve, 20, 1137-1141. https://doi.org/10.1002/(SICI)1097-4598(199709)20:9&lt;1137:AID-MUS7&gt;3.0.CO;2-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Narayanan, R. K., Mangelsdorf, M., Panwar, A., Butler, T. J., Noakes, P. G., &amp; Wallace, R. H. (2013). Identification of RNA bound to the TDP-43 ribonucleoprotein complex in the adult mouse brain. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener, 14, 252-260. https://doi.org/10.3109/21678421.2012.734520</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neumann, M. (2009). Molecular neuropathology of TDP-43 proteinopathies. International Journal of Molecular Sciences, 10, 232-246. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms10010232</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neumann, M. S., Kwong, D. M., Truax, L. K., Micsenyi, A. C., Chou, M. C., Bruce, T. T., Schuck, J., Grossman, T., Clark, M., McCluskey, C. M., Miller, L. F., Masliah, B. L., Mackenzie, E., Feldman, I. R., Feiden, H., Kretzschmar, W., Trojanowski, H. A., Lee, V. M. -Y.,(2006). Ubiquitinated TDP-43 in frontotemporal lobar degeneration and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Science, 314, 130-133. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.1134108</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orr, B. O., Hauswirth, A. G., Celona, B., Fetter, R. D., Zunino, G., Kvon, E. Z., Zhu, Y., Pennacchio, L. A., Black, B. L., &amp; Davis, G. W. (2020). Presynaptic homeostasis opposes disease progression in mouse models of ALS-like degeneration: Evidence for homeostatic neuroprotection. Neuron, 107(1), 95-111.e6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paoletti, P., Bellone, C., &amp; Zhou, Q. (2013). NMDA receptor subunit diversity: Impact on receptor properties, synaptic plasticity and disease. Nature Reviews Neuroscience, 14, 383-400. https://doi.org/10.1038/nrn3504</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paxinos, G., &amp; Franklin, K. (2007). The mouse brain in stereotaxic coordinates. Academic Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polymenidou, M., Lagier-Tourenne, C., Hutt, K. R., Huelga, S. C., Moran, J., Liang, T. Y., Ling, S.-C., Sun, E., Wancewicz, E., Mazur, C., Kordasiewicz, H., Sedaghat, Y., Donohue, J. P., Shiue, L., Bennett, C. F., Yeo, G. W., &amp; Cleveland, D. W. (2011). Long pre-mRNA depletion and RNA missplicing contribute to neuronal vulnerability from loss of TDP-43. Nature Neuroscience, 14, 459-468. https://doi.org/10.1038/nn.2779</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ravits, J. P., &amp; Jorg, P. C.(2007). Focality of upper and lower motor neuron degeneration at the clinical onset of ALS. Neurology, 68, 1571-1575. https://doi.org/10.1212/01.wnl.0000260965.20021.47</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ravits, J., &amp; LaSpada, A. (2009). ALS motor phenotype heterogeneity, focality, and spread. Neurology, 73, 805-811.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosler, K. T., Hess, A., Magistris, C. W., &amp; Magistris M. R.(2000). Quantification of upper motor neuron loss in amytrophic lateral sclerosis. Clinical Neurophysiology, 111, 2208-2218.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rothstein, J. T., Kuncl, G., Clawson, R. W., Cornblath, L., Drachman, D. R., Pestronk, D. B., Stauch, A., &amp; Coyle, B. L. J.(1990). Abnormal excitatory amino acid metabolism in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Annals of Neurology, 28, 18-25. https://doi.org/10.1002/ana.410280106</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saba, L., Viscomi, M. T., Caioli, S., Pignataro, A., Bisicchia, E., Pieri, M., Molinari, M., Ammassari-Teule, M., &amp; Zona, C. (2016). Altered functionality, morphology, and vesicular glutamate transporter expression of cortical motor neurons from a presymptomatic mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Cerebral Cortex, 26, 1512-1528. https://doi.org/10.1093/cercor/bhu317</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saba, L., Viscomi, M. T., Martini, A., Caioli, S., Mercuri, N. B., Guatteo, E., &amp; Zona, C. (2019). Modified age-dependent expression of NaV1.6 in an ALS model correlates with motor cortex excitability alterations. Neurobiology of Diseases, 130, 104532. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nbd.2019.104532</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sephton, C. F., Cenik, C., Kucukural, A., Dammer, E. B., Cenik, B., Han, Y. H., Dewey, C. M., Roth, F. P., Herz, J., Peng, J., Moore, M. J., &amp; Yu, G. (2011). Identification of neuronal RNA targets of TDP-43-containing ribonucleoprotein complexes. Journal of Biological Chemistry, 286, 1204-1215. https://doi.org/10.1074/jbc.M110.190884</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi, S., Hayashi, Y., Esteben, J., &amp; Manilow, R. (2001). Subunit-specific rules governing AMPA receptor trafficking to synapses in hippocampal pyramidal neurons. Cell, 105, 331-343. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0092-8674(01)00321-X</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stallings, N. R., Puttaparthi, K., Luther, C. M., Burns, D. K., &amp; Elliott, J. L. (2010). Progressive motor weakness in transgenic mice expressing human TDP-43. Neurobiology of Diseases, 40, 404-414. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nbd.2010.06.017</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swarup, V., Phaneuf, D., Bareil, C., Robertson, J., Rouleau, G. A., Kriz, J., &amp; Julien, J. P. (2011). Pathological hallmarks of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis/frontotemporal lobar degeneration in transgenic mice produced with TDP-43 genomic fragments. Brain, 134, 2610-2626. https://doi.org/10.1093/brain/awr159</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ting, J. T., Daigle, T. L., Chen, Q., &amp; Feng, G. (2014). Acute brain slice methods for adult and aging animals: Application of targeted patch clamp analysis and optogenetics. Methods in Molecular Biology, 1183, 221-242.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsuzuki, K., Lambolez, B., Rossier, J., &amp; Ozawa, S. (2001). Absolute quantification of AMPA receptor subunit mRNAs in single hippocampal neurons. Journal of Neurochemistry, 77, 1650-1659. https://doi.org/10.1046/j.1471-4159.2001.00388.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turrigiano, G. (2012). Homeostatic synaptic plasticity: Local and global mechanisms for stabilizing neuronal function. Cold Spring Harb Perspect Biol, 4, a005736. https://doi.org/10.1101/cshperspect.a005736</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Urbani, A., &amp; Belluzzi, O. (2000). Riluzole inhibits the persistent sodium current in mammalian CNS neurons. European Journal of Neuroscience, 12, 3567-3574. https://doi.org/10.1046/j.1460-9568.2000.00242.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van den Bos, M. A. J., Higashihara, M., Geevasinga, N., Menon, P., Kiernan, M. C., &amp; Vucic, S. (2018). Imbalance of cortical facilitatory and inhibitory circuits underlies hyperexcitability in ALS. Neurology, 91, e1669-e1676. https://doi.org/10.1212/WNL.0000000000006438</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic, S., Cheah, B. C., Yiannikas, C., &amp; Kiernan, M. C. (2011). Cortical excitability distinguishes ALS from mimic disorders. Clinical Neurophysiology, 122, 1860-1866. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.clinph.2010.12.062</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic, S., &amp; Kiernan, M. C. (2008). Cortical excitability testing distinguishes Kennedy's disease from amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clinical Neurophysiology, 119, 1088-1096. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.clinph.2008.01.011</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic, S., Nicholson, G. A., &amp; Kiernan, M. C. (2008). Cortical hyperexcitability may precede the onset of familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain, 131, 1540-1550. https://doi.org/10.1093/brain/awn071</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weskamp, K., Tank, E. M., Miguez, R., McBride, J. P., G&#xf3;mez, N. B., White, M., Lin, Z., Gonzalez, C. M., Serio, A., Sreedharan, J., &amp; Barmada, S. J. (2020). Shortened TDP43 isoforms upregulated by neuronal hyperactivity drive TDP43 pathology in ALS. Journal of Clinical Investigation, 130, 1139-1155. https://doi.org/10.1172/JCI130988</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wright, A. L., Della Gatta, P. A., Le, S. et al (2020) Riluzole does not ameliorate disease caused by cytoplasmic TDP43 in a mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis BiorXiv.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, Y.-F., Gendron, T. F., Zhang, Y.-J., Lin, W.-L., D'Alton, S., Sheng, H., Casey, M. C., Tong, J., Knight, J., Yu, X., Rademakers, R., Boylan, K., Hutton, M., McGowan, E., Dickson, D. W., Lewis, J., &amp; Petrucelli, L. (2010). Wild-type human TDP-43 expression causes TDP-43 phosphorylation, mitochondrial aggregation, motor deficits, and early mortality in transgenic mice. Journal of Neuroscience, 30, 10851-10859. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.1630-10.2010</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamashita, T., &amp; Kwak, S. (2014). The molecular link between inefficient GluA2 Q/R site-RNA editing and TDP-43 pathology in motor neurons of sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. Brain Research, 1584, 28-38. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.brainres.2013.12.011</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, W., Zhang, L., Liang, B., Schroeder, D., Zhang, Z. W., Cox, G. A., Li, Y., &amp; Lin, D. T. (2016). Hyperactive somatostatin interneurons contribute to excitotoxicity in neurodegenerative disorders. Nature Neuroscience, 19, 557-559. https://doi.org/10.1038/nn.4257</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zona, C., Pieri, M., &amp; Carunchio, I. (2006). Voltage-dependent sodium channels in spinal cord motor neurons display rapid recovery from fast inactivation in a mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Journal of Neurophysiology, 96, 3314-3322. https://doi.org/10.1152/jn.00566.2006</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>