<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">33094490</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>19</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-4598</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>63</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Muscle &amp; nerve</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Muscle Nerve</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Endocannabinoids and related lipids in serum from patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>120</StartPage><EndPage>126</EndPage><MedlinePgn>120-126</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/mus.27096</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">The goals of this study were to determine whether serum concentrations of endocannabinoids (eCB) and related lipids predict disease status in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) relative to healthy controls, and whether concentrations correlate with disease duration and severity.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Serum concentrations of the eCBs 2-arachidonoylglycerol (2-AG) and N-arachidonoylethanolamine (AEA), and related lipids palmitoylethanolamine (PEA), oleoylethanolamine (OEA), and 2-oleoylglycerol (2-OG), were measured in samples from 47 patients with ALS and 19 healthy adults. Hierarchical binary logistic and linear regression analyses assessed whether lipid concentrations predicted disease status (ALS or healthy control), duration, or severity.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Binary logistic regression revealed that, after controlling for age and gender, 2-AG, 2-OG and AEA concentrations were unique predictors of the presence of ALS, demonstrating odds ratios of 0.86 (P = .039), 1.03 (P = .023), and 42.17 (P = .026), respectively. When all five lipids and covariates (age, sex, race, ethnicity, body mass index, presence of a feeding tube) were included, the resulting model had an overall classification accuracy of 92.9%. Hierarchical linear regression analyses indicated that in patients with ALS, AEA and OEA inversely correlated with disease duration (P = .030 and .031 respectively), while PEA demonstrated a positive relationship with disease duration (P = .013). None of the lipids examined predicted disease severity.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">These findings support previous studies indicating significant alterations in concentrations of circulating lipids in patients with ALS. They suggest that arachidonic and oleic acid containing small lipids may serve as biomarkers for identifying the presence and duration of this disease.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Carter</LastName><ForeName>Gregory T</ForeName><Initials>GT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>St. Luke's Rehabilitation Institute, Spokane, Washington, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McLaughlin</LastName><ForeName>Ryan J</ForeName><Initials>RJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Integrative Physiology &amp; Neuroscience, College of Veterinary Medicine, Washington State University, Pullman, Washington, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cuttler</LastName><ForeName>Carrie</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, Washington State University, Pullman, Washington, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sauber</LastName><ForeName>Garrett J</ForeName><Initials>GJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacology and Toxicology, Neuroscience Research Center, Medical College of Wisconsin, Milwaukee, Wisconsin, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Weeks</LastName><ForeName>Douglas L</ForeName><Initials>DL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>St. Luke's Rehabilitation Institute, Spokane, Washington, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hillard</LastName><ForeName>Cecilia J</ForeName><Initials>CJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacology and Toxicology, Neuroscience Research Center, Medical College of Wisconsin, Milwaukee, Wisconsin, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Weiss</LastName><ForeName>Michael D</ForeName><Initials>MD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of Washington School of Medicine, Seattle, Washington, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Muscle Nerve</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7803146</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0148-639X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D001095">Arachidonic Acids</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D015415">Biomarkers</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D063388">Endocannabinoids</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D005989">Glycerides</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D008055">Lipids</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D053284">Polyunsaturated Alkamides</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>9A2389K694</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C505247">2-oleoylglycerol</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>UR5G69TJKH</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C078814">anandamide</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="Y">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001095" MajorTopicYN="N">Arachidonic Acids</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015415" MajorTopicYN="N">Biomarkers</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D063388" MajorTopicYN="N">Endocannabinoids</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="Y">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005989" MajorTopicYN="N">Glycerides</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008055" MajorTopicYN="N">Lipids</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="Y">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053284" MajorTopicYN="N">Polyunsaturated Alkamides</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012720" MajorTopicYN="N">Severity of Illness Index</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ALSFRS-R</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">biomarker</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic criteria</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">motor neuron disease</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33094490</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.27096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Aydemir D, Ulusu NN. Importance of the serum biochemical parameters as potential biomarkers for rapid diagnosis and evaluating preclinical stage of ALS. Med Hypotheses. 2020;141:109736.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Aguilar JLG. Lipid biomarkers for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Front Neurol. 2019;10:284.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dupuis L, Pradat PF, Ludolph AC, Loeffler JP. Energy metabolism in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet Neurol. 2011;10:75-82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hillard CJ. The endocannabinoid signaling system in the CNS: A primer. Int Rev Neurobiol. 2015;125:1-47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maccarrone M, Bab I, B&#xed;r&#xf3; T, et al. Endocannabinoid signaling at the periphery: 50&#x2009;years after THC. Trends Pharmacol Sci. 2015;36(5):277-296.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cristino L, Bisogno T, Di Marzo V. Cannabinoids and the expanded endocannabinoid system in neurological disorders. Nat Rev Neurol. 2020;16(1):9-29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao P, Ignacio S, Beattie EC, Abood ME. Altered presymptomatic AMPA and cannabinoid receptor trafficking in motor neurons of ALS model mice: Implications for excitotoxicity. Eur J Neurosci. 2008;27(3):572-579.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Witting A, Weydt P, Hong S, Kliot M, Moller T, Stella N. Endocannabinoids accumulate in spinal cord of SOD1 G93A transgenic mice. J Neurochem. 2004;89(6):1555-1557.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bilsland LG, Dick JR, Pryce G, et al. Increasing cannabinoid levels by pharmacological and genetic manipulation delay disease progression in SOD1 mice. FASEB J. 2006;20(7):1003-1005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pasquarelli N, Engelskirchen M, Hanselmann J, et al. Evaluation of monoacylglycerol lipase as a therapeutic target in a transgenic mouse model of ALS. Neuropharmacology. 2017;124:157-169.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Urbi B, Owusu MA, Hughes I, Katz M, Broadley S, Sabet A. Effects of cannabinoids in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) murine models: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Neurochem. 2019;149(2):284-297.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amtmann D, Weydt P, Johnson KL, Jensen MP, Carter GT. Survey of cannabis use in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Am J Hosp Palliat Care. 2004;21(2):95-104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer T, Funke A, M&#xfc;nch C, et al. Real world experience of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) in the treatment of spasticity using tetrahydrocannabinol:cannabidiol (THC:CBD). BMC Neurol. 2019;19(1):222.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weber M, Goldman B, Truniger S. Tetrahydrocannabinol (THC) for cramps in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A randomised, double-blind crossover trial. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2010;81(10):1135-1140.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giacoppo S, Mazzon E. Can cannabinoids be a potential therapeutic tool in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis? Neural Regen Res. 2016;11(12):1896-1899.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hillard CJ. Circulating Endocannabinoids: From whence do they come and where are they going? Neuropsychopharmacology. 2018;43(1):155-172.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crombie KM, Brellenthin AG, Hillard CJ, Koltyn KF. Psychobiological responses to aerobic exercise in individuals with posttraumatic stress disorder. J Trauma Stress. 2018;31(1):134-145.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum JM, Stambler N, Malta E, et al. The ALSFRS-R: A revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. BDNF ALS study group (phase III). J Neurol Sci. 1999;169(1-2):13-21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tabachnick BG, Fidell LS. Using Multivariate Statistics. 6th ed. Boston, MA: Pearson; 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouteloup C, Desport JC, Clavelou P, et al. Hypermetabolism in ALS patients: An early and persistent phenomenon. J Neurol. 2009;256(8):1236-1242.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J&#xe9;sus P, Fayemendy P, Nicol M, et al. Hypermetabolism is a deleterious prognostic factor in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Eur J Neurol. 2018;25(1):97-104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huisman MH, Seelen M, van Doormaal PT, et al. Effect of presymptomatic body mass index and consumption of fat and alcohol on amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. JAMA Neurol. 2015;72(10):1155-1162.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vercruysse P, Sinniger J, El Oussini H, et al. Alterations in the hypothalamic melanocortin pathway in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain. 2016;139(Pt 4):1106-1122.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorges M, Vercruysse P, M&#xfc;ller HP, et al. Hypothalamic atrophy is related to body mass index and age at onset in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2017;88(12):1033-1041.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang R, Guo X, Chen X, et al. The serum lipid profiles of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients: A study from south-West China and a meta-analysis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2015;16(5-6):359-365.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mariosa D, Hammar N, Malmstrom H, et al. Blood biomarkers of carbohydrate, lipid, and apolipoprotein metabolisms and risk of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A more than 20-year follow-up of the Swedish AMORIS cohort. Ann Neurol. 2017;81:718-728.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ingre C, Chen L, Zhan Y, Termorshuizen J, Yin L, Fang F. Lipids, apolipoproteins, and prognosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology. 2020;94(17):e1835-e1844.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kleberg K, Hassing HA, Hansen HS. Classical endocannabinoid-like compounds and their regulation by nutrients. Biofactors. 2014;40(4):363-372.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mand&#xf8;e MJ, Hansen KB, Windel&#xf8;v JA, et al. Comparing olive oil and C4-dietary oil, a prodrug for the GPR119 agonist, 2-oleoyl glycerol, less energy intake of the latter is needed to stimulate incretin hormone secretion in overweight subjects with type 2 diabetes. Nutr Diabetes. 2018;8(1):2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hansen KB, Rosenkilde MM, Knop FK, et al. 2-Oleoyl glycerol is a GPR119 agonist and signals GLP-1 release in humans. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2011;96(9):E1409-E1417.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dunning BE, Foley JE, Ahr&#xe9;n B. Alpha cell function in health and disease: Influence of glucagon-like peptide-1. Diabetologia. 2005;48(9):1700-1713.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holst JJ. The physiology of glucagon-like peptide 1. Physiol Rev. 2007;87(4):1409-1439.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ngo ST, Steyn FJ, Huang L, et al. Altered expression of metabolic proteins and adipokines in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Sci. 2015;357(1-2):22-27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhutani S, Howard JD, Reynolds R, Zee PC, Gottfried J, Kahnt T. Olfactory connectivity mediates sleep-dependent food choices in humans. Elife. 2019;8:e49053.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dupuis L, Corcia P, Fergani A, et al. Dyslipidemia is a protective factor in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology. 2008;70:1004-1009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Reilly &#xc9;J, Wang H, Weisskopf MG, et al. Premorbid body mass index and risk of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2013;14(3):205-211.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nelson LM, Matkin C, Longstreth WT Jr, McGuire V. Population-based case-control study of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in western Washington state. II. Diet. Am J Epidemiol. 2000;151(2):164-173.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tutunchi H, Saghafi-Asl M, Ostadrahimi A. A systematic review of the effects of oleoylethanolamide, a high-affinity endogenous ligand of PPAR-&#x3b1;, on the management and prevention of obesity. Clin Exp Pharmacol Physiol. 2020;47(4):543-552.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown AJ. Novel cannabinoid receptors. Br J Pharmacol. 2007;152:567-575.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu J, Gaetani S, Oveisi F, et al. Oleylethanolamide regulates feeding and body weight through activation of the nuclear receptor PPAR-alpha. Nature. 2003;425(6953):90-93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Syed SK, Bui HH, Beavers LS, et al. Regulation of GPR119 receptor activity with endocannabinoid-like lipids. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2012;303(12):E1469-E1478.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venkatesan T, Zadvornova Y, Raff H, Hillard CJ. Endocannabinoid-related lipids are increased during an episode of cyclic vomiting syndrome. Neurogastroenterol Motil. 2016;28(9):1409-1418.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrosino S, Di Marzo V. The pharmacology of palmitoylethanolamide and first data on the therapeutic efficacy of some of its new formulations. Br J Pharmacol. 2017;174(11):1349-1365.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clemente S. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis treatment with ultramicronized palmitoylethanolamide: A case report. CNS Neurol Disord Drug Targets. 2012;11(7):933-936.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palma E, Reyes-Ruiz JM, Lopergolo D, et al. Acetylcholine receptors from human muscle as pharmacological targets for ALS therapy. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2016;113(11):3060-3065.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>