<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">33099869</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>30</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1932-8494</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>304</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Anatomical record (Hoboken, N.J. : 2007)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Anat Rec (Hoboken)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Size-dependent dendritic maladaptations of hypoglossal motor neurons in SOD1<sup>G93A</sup> mice.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1562</StartPage><EndPage>1581</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1562-1581</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/ar.24542</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The total motor neuron (MN) somato-dendritic surface area is correlated with motor unit type. MNs with smaller surface areas innervate slow (S) and fast fatigue-resistant (FR) motor units, while MNs with larger surface areas innervate fast fatigue-intermediate (FInt) and fast fatigable (FF) motor units. Differences in MN surface area (equivalent to membrane capacitance) underpin the intrinsic excitability of MNs and are consistent with the orderly recruitment of motor units (S&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;FR&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;FInt&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;FF) via the Size Principle. In amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS), large MNs controlling FInt and FF motor units exhibit earlier denervation and death, compared to smaller and more resilient MNs of type S and FR motor units that are spared until late in ALS. Abnormal dendritic morphologies in MNs precede neuronal death in human ALS and in rodent models. We employed Golgi-Cox methods to investigate somal size-dependent changes in the dendritic morphology of hypoglossal MNs in wildtype and SOD1<sup>G93A</sup> mice (a model of ALS), at postnatal (P) day ~30 (pre-symptomatic), ~P60 (onset), and ~P120 (mid-disease) stages. In wildtype hypoglossal MNs, increased MN somal size correlated with increased dendritic length and spines in a linear fashion. By contrast, in SOD1<sup>G93A</sup> mice, significant deviations from this linear correlation were restricted to the larger vulnerable MNs at pre-symptomatic (maladaptive) and mid-disease (degenerative) stages. These findings are consistent with excitability changes observed in ALS patients and in rodent models. Our results suggest that intrinsic or synaptic increases in MN excitability are likely to contribute to ALS pathogenesis, not compensate for it.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020 American Association for Anatomy.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fogarty</LastName><ForeName>Matthew J</ForeName><Initials>MJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0128-7042</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Biomedical Sciences, The University of Queensland, St Lucia, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology and Biomedical Engineering, Mayo Clinic, Rochester, Minnesota, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mu</LastName><ForeName>Erica W H</ForeName><Initials>EWH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Biomedical Sciences, The University of Queensland, St Lucia, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lavidis</LastName><ForeName>Nickolas A</ForeName><Initials>NA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Biomedical Sciences, The University of Queensland, St Lucia, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Noakes</LastName><ForeName>Peter G</ForeName><Initials>PG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Biomedical Sciences, The University of Queensland, St Lucia, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Queensland Brain Institute, The University of Queensland, St Lucia, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bellingham</LastName><ForeName>Mark C</ForeName><Initials>MC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Biomedical Sciences, The University of Queensland, St Lucia, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Anat Rec (Hoboken)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101292775</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1932-8486</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 1.15.1.1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000072105">Superoxide Dismutase-1</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="Y">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003712" MajorTopicYN="N">Dendrites</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="Y">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004195" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Models, Animal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007002" MajorTopicYN="N">Hypoglossal Nerve</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="Y">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051379" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008822" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice, Transgenic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009046" MajorTopicYN="N">Motor Neurons</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="Y">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000072105" MajorTopicYN="N">Superoxide Dismutase-1</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SOD1G93A mouse</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dendrite</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dendritic spine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hypoglossal</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">motor neuron disease</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33099869</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ar.24542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Abe, S., Maejima, M., Watanabe, H., Shibahara, T., Agematsu, H., Doi, T., &#x2026; Ide, Y. (2002). Muscle-fiber characteristics in adult mouse-tongue muscles. Anatomical Science International, 77, 145-148. https://doi.org/10.1046/j.0022-7722.2002.00019.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agbulut, O., Noirez, P., Beaumont, F., &amp; Butler-Browne, G. (2003). Myosin heavy chain isoforms in postnatal muscle development of mice. Biology of the Cell, 95, 399-406. https://doi.org/10.1016/s0248-4900(03)00087-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amendola, J., &amp; Durand, J. (2008). Morphological differences between wild-type and transgenic superoxide dismutase 1 lumbar motoneurons in postnatal mice. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 511, 329-341. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.21818</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bae, J. S., Simon, N. G., Menon, P., Vucic, S., &amp; Kiernan, M. C. (2013). The puzzling case of hyperexcitability in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Journal of Clinical Neurology, 9, 65-74. https://doi.org/10.3988/jcn.2013.9.2.65</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bandaru, S. P., Liu, S., Waxman, S. G., &amp; Tan, A. M. (2015). Dendritic spine dysgenesis contributes to hyperreflexia after spinal cord injury. Journal of Neurophysiology, 113, 1598-1615. https://doi.org/10.1152/jn.00566.2014</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellingham, M. C. (2011). A review of the neural mechanisms of action and clinical efficiency of riluzole in treating amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: What have we learned in the last decade? CNS Neuroscience and Therapeutics, 17, 4-31. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1755-5949.2009.00116.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Binder, M. D., Powers, R. K., &amp; Heckman, C. J. (2020). Nonlinear input-output functions of motoneurons. Physiology (Bethesda), 35, 31-39. https://doi.org/10.1152/physiol.00026.2019</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brandenburg, J. E., Fogarty, M. J., Brown, A. D., &amp; Sieck, G. C. (2020). Phrenic motor neuron loss in an animal model of early onset hypertonia. Journal of Neurophysiology, 123, 1682-1690. https://doi.org/10.1152/jn.00026.2020</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brandenburg, J. E., Gransee, H. M., Fogarty, M. J., &amp; Sieck, G. C. (2018). Differences in lumbar motor neuron pruning in an animal model of early onset spasticity. Journal of Neurophysiology, 120, 601-609. https://doi.org/10.1152/jn.00186.2018</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brannstrom, T. (1993). Quantitative synaptology of functionally different types of cat medial gastrocnemius alpha-motoneurons. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 330, 439-454. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.903300311</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charcot, J.-M., &amp; Joffroy, A. (1869). Deux cas d'atrophie musculaire progressive avec lesions de la substance grise et des faisceaux antero-lateraux de la moelle epiniere. Archives in Physiology, Neurology, and Pathology, 2, 744-754.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conradi, S., Kellerth, J. O., Berthold, C. H., &amp; Hammarberg, C. (1979). Electron microscopic studies of serially sectioned cat spinal alpha-motoneurons. IV. Motoneurons innervating slow-twitch (type S) units of the soleus muscle. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 184, 769-782. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.901840409</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cullheim, S., Fleshman, J. W., Glenn, L. L., &amp; Burke, R. E. (1987). Membrane area and dendritic structure in type-identified triceps surae alpha motoneurons. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 255, 68-81. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.902550106</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cullheim, S., &amp; Ulfhake, B. (1979). Relations between cell body size, axon diameter and axon conduction velocity of triceps surae alpha montoneurons during the postnatal development in the cat. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 188, 679-686. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.901880410</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cullins, M. J., &amp; Connor, N. P. (2017). Alterations of intrinsic tongue muscle properties with aging. Muscle &amp; Nerve, 56, E119-E125. https://doi.org/10.1002/mus.25605</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DePaul, R., Abbs, J. H., Caligiuri, M., Gracco, V. L., &amp; Brooks, B. R. (1988). Hypoglossal, trigeminal, and facial motoneuron involvement in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology, 38, 281-283. https://doi.org/10.1212/wnl.38.2.281</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dukkipati, S. S., Garrett, T. L., &amp; Elbasiouny, S. M. (2018). The vulnerability of spinal motoneurons and soma size plasticity in a mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. The Journal of Physiology, 596, 1723-1745. https://doi.org/10.1113/JP275498</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eisen, A., Nakajima, M., &amp; Weber, M. (1998). Corticomotorneuronal hyper-excitability in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Journal of the Neurological Sciences, 160(Suppl 1), S64-S68.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrucci, M., Spalloni, A., Bartalucci, A., Cantafora, E., Fulceri, F., Nutini, M., &#x2026; Fornai, F. (2010). A systematic study of brainstem motor nuclei in a mouse model of ALS, the effects of lithium. Neurobiology of Disease, 37, 370-383. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nbd.2009.10.017</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filipchuk, A. A., &amp; Durand, J. (2012). Postnatal dendritic development in lumbar motoneurons in mutant superoxide dismutase 1 mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuroscience, 209, 144-154. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuroscience.2012.01.046</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foerster, B. R., Pomper, M. G., Callaghan, B. C., Petrou, M., Edden, R. A., Mohamed, M. A., &#x2026; Feldman, E. L. (2013). An imbalance between excitatory and inhibitory neurotransmitters in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis revealed by use of 3-T proton magnetic resonance spectroscopy. JAMA Neurology, 70, 1009-1016. https://doi.org/10.1001/jamaneurol.2013.234</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fogarty, M. J. (2018a). The bigger they are the harder they fall: Size-dependent vulnerability of motor neurons in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. The Journal of Physiology, 596, 2471-2472. https://doi.org/10.1113/JP276312</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fogarty, M. J. (2018b). Driven to decay: Excitability and synaptic abnormalities in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain Research Bulletin, 140, 318-333. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.brainresbull.2018.05.023</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fogarty, M. J. (2019). Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis as a synaptopathy. Neural Regeneration Research, 14, 189-192. https://doi.org/10.4103/1673-5374.244782</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fogarty, M. J., Hammond, L. A., Kanjhan, R., Bellingham, M. C., &amp; Noakes, P. G. (2013a). A method for the three-dimensional reconstruction of Neurobiotin-filled neurons and the location of their synaptic inputs. Frontiers in Neural Circuits, 7, 153. https://doi.org/10.3389/fncir.2013.00153</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fogarty, M. J., Kanjhan, R., Bellingham, M. C., &amp; Noakes, P. G. (2016a). Glycinergic neurotransmission: A potent regulator of embryonic motor neuron dendritic morphology and synaptic plasticity. The Journal of Neuroscience, 36, 80-87. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.1576-15.2016</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fogarty, M. J., Kanjhan, R., Yanagawa, Y., Noakes, P. G., &amp; Bellingham, M. C. (2017a). Alterations in hypoglossal motor neurons due to GAD67 and VGAT deficiency in mice. Experimental Neurology, 289, 117-127. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.expneurol.2016.12.004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fogarty, M. J., Klenowski, P. M., Lee, J. D., Drieberg-Thompson, J. R., Bartlett, S. E., Ngo, S. T., &#x2026; Noakes, P. G. (2016b). Cortical synaptic and dendritic spine abnormalities in a presymptomatic TDP-43 model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Scientific Reports, 6, 37968. https://doi.org/10.1038/srep37968</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fogarty, M. J., Mu, E. W., Noakes, P. G., Lavidis, N. A., &amp; Bellingham, M. C. (2016c). Marked changes in dendritic structure and spine density precede significant neuronal death in vulnerable cortical pyramidal neuron populations in the SOD1(G93A) mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathologica Communications, 4, 77. https://doi.org/10.1186/s40478-016-0347-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fogarty, M. J., Mu, E. W. H., Lavidis, N. A., Noakes, P. G., &amp; Bellingham, M. C. (2017b). Motor areas show altered dendritic structure in an amyotrophic lateral sclerosis mouse model. Frontiers in Neuroscience, 11, 609. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnins.2017.00609</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fogarty, M. J., Mu, E. W. H., Lavidis, N. A., Noakes, P. G., &amp; Bellingham, M. C. (2019). Size-dependent vulnerability of lumbar motor neuron dendritic degeneration in SOD1(G93A) mice. Anatomical Record (Hoboken), 303, 1455-1471. https://doi.org/10.1002/ar.24255</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fogarty, M. J., Noakes, P. G., &amp; Bellingham, M. C. (2015a). Motor cortex layer V pyramidal neurons exhibit dendritic regression, spine loss, and increased synaptic excitation in the presymptomatic hSOD1(G93A) mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. The Journal of Neuroscience, 35, 643-647. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.3483-14.2015</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fogarty, M. J., Omar, T. S., Zhan, W. Z., Mantilla, C. B., &amp; Sieck, G. C. (2018). Phrenic motor neuron loss in aged rats. Journal of Neurophysiology, 119, 1852-1862. https://doi.org/10.1152/jn.00868.2017</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fogarty, M. J., &amp; Sieck, G. C. (2019). Evolution and functional differentiation of the diaphragm muscle of mammals. Comprehensive Physiology, 9, 715-766.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fogarty, M. J., Smallcombe, K. L., Yanagawa, Y., Obata, K., Bellingham, M. C., &amp; Noakes, P. G. (2013b). Genetic deficiency of GABA differentially regulates respiratory and non-respiratory motor neuron development. PLoS One, 8, e56257. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0056257</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fogarty, M. J., Yanagawa, Y., Obata, K., Bellingham, M. C., &amp; Noakes, P. G. (2015b). Genetic absence of the vesicular inhibitory amino acid transporter differentially regulates respiratory and locomotor motor neuron development. Brain Structure &amp; Function, 220, 525-540. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00429-013-0673-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fournier, M., &amp; Sieck, G. C. (1988). Mechanical properties of muscle units in the cat diaphragm. Journal of Neurophysiology, 59, 1055-1066. https://doi.org/10.1152/jn.1988.59.3.1055</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franklin, K. B. J., &amp; Paxinos, G. (2008). The mouse brain in stereotaxic coordinates (3rd ed.) San Diego: Academic Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frey, D., Schneider, C., Xu, L., Borg, J., Spooren, W., &amp; Caroni, P. (2000). Early and selective loss of neuromuscular synapse subtypes with low sprouting competence in motoneuron diseases. The Journal of Neuroscience, 20, 2534-2542.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geevasinga, N., Menon, P., Ozdinler, P. H., Kiernan, M. C., &amp; Vucic, S. (2016). Pathophysiological and diagnostic implications of cortical dysfunction in ALS. Nature Reviews Neurology, 12, 651-661. https://doi.org/10.1038/nrneurol.2016.140</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Genc, B., Jara, J. H., Lagrimas, A. K., Pytel, P., Roos, R. P., Mesulam, M. M., &#x2026; Ozdinler, P. H. (2017). Apical dendrite degeneration, a novel cellular pathology for Betz cells in ALS. Scientific Reports, 7, 41765. https://doi.org/10.1038/srep41765</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gil, J., Funalot, B., Verschueren, A., Danel-Brunaud, V., Camu, W., Vandenberghe, N., &#x2026; Couratier, P. (2008). Causes of death amongst French patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A prospective study. European Journal of Neurology, 15, 1245-1251. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1468-1331.2008.02307.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gurney, M. E., Pu, H., Chiu, A. Y., Dal Canto, M. C., Polchow, C. Y., Alexander, D. D., et al. (1994). Motor neuron degeneration in mice that express a human Cu,Zn superoxide dismutase mutation. Science, 264, 1772-1775.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haenggeli, C., &amp; Kato, A. C. (2002). Differential vulnerability of cranial motoneurons in mouse models with motor neuron degeneration. Neuroscience Letters, 335, 39-43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hammer, R. P., Jr., Tomiyasu, U., &amp; Scheibel, A. B. (1979). Degeneration of the human Betz cell due to amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Experimental Neurology, 63, 336-346.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Handley, E. E., Pitman, K. A., Dawkins, E., Young, K. M., Clark, R. M., Jiang, T. C., &#x2026; Blizzard, C. A. (2017). Synapse dysfunction of layer V pyramidal neurons precedes neurodegeneration in a mouse model of TDP-43 proteinopathies. Cerebral Cortex, 27, 3630-3647. https://doi.org/10.1093/cercor/bhw185</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardiman, O., van den Berg, L. H., &amp; Kiernan, M. C. (2011). Clinical diagnosis and management of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nature Reviews. Neurology, 7, 639-649. https://doi.org/10.1038/nrneurol.2011.153</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris, K. M. (1999). Structure, development, and plasticity of dendritic spines. Current Opinion in Neurobiology, 9, 343-348.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hegedus, J., Putman, C. T., &amp; Gordon, T. (2007). Time course of preferential motor unit loss in the SOD1 G93A mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurobiology of Disease, 28, 154-164. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nbd.2007.07.003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hegedus, J., Putman, C. T., Tyreman, N., &amp; Gordon, T. (2008). Preferential motor unit loss in the SOD1 G93A transgenic mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. The Journal of Physiology, 586, 3337-3351. https://doi.org/10.1113/jphysiol.2007.149286</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henneman, E. (1957). Relation between size of neurons and their susceptibility to discharge. Science, 126, 1345-1347.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henneman, E., Somjen, G., &amp; Carpenter, D. O. (1965). Functional significance of cell size in spinal motoneurons. Journal of Neurophysiology, 28, 560-580. https://doi.org/10.1152/jn.1965.28.3.560</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inglis, F. M., Crockett, R., Korada, S., Abraham, W. C., Hollmann, M., &amp; Kalb, R. G. (2002). The AMPA receptor subunit GluR1 regulates dendritic architecture of motor neurons. The Journal of Neuroscience, 22, 8042-8051.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jara, J. H., Genc, B., Cox, G. A., Bohn, M. C., Roos, R. P., Macklis, J. D., &#x2026; Ozdinler, P. H. (2015). Corticospinal motor neurons are susceptible to increased ER stress and display profound degeneration in the absence of UCHL1 function. Cerebral Cortex, 25, 4259-4272. https://doi.org/10.1093/cercor/bhu318</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jara, J. H., Villa, S. R., Khan, N. A., Bohn, M. C., &amp; Ozdinler, P. H. (2012). AAV2 mediated retrograde transduction of corticospinal motor neurons reveals initial and selective apical dendrite degeneration in ALS. Neurobiology of Disease, 47, 174-183. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nbd.2012.03.036</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalb, R. G. (1994). Regulation of motor neuron dendrite growth by NMDA receptor activation. Development, 120, 3063-3071.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanjhan, R., Fogarty, M. J., Noakes, P. G., &amp; Bellingham, M. C. (2015). Developmental changes in the morphology of mouse hypoglossal motor neurons. Brain Structure &amp; Function, 221, 3755-3786. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00429-015-1130-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaplan, A., Spiller, K. J., Towne, C., Kanning, K. C., Choe, G. T., Geber, A., &#x2026; Henderson, C. E. (2014). Neuronal matrix metalloproteinase-9 is a determinant of selective neurodegeneration. Neuron, 81, 333-348. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2013.12.009</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kato, T., Hirano, A., &amp; Donnenfeld, H. (1987). A Golgi study of the large anterior horn cells of the lumbar cords in normal spinal cords and in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathologica, 75, 34-40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kellerth, J. O., Berthold, C. H., &amp; Conradi, S. (1979). Electron microscopic studies of serially sectioned cat spinal alpha-motoneurons. III. Motoneurons innervating fast-twitch (type FR) units of the gastrocnemius muscle. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 184, 755-767. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.901840408</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiernan, J.A., Hudson, A.J., 1991. Changes in sizes of cortical and lower motor neurons in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain 114 ( Pt 2), 843-853.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiernan, M. C., &amp; Petri, S. (2012). Hyperexcitability and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology, 78, 1544-1545. https://doi.org/10.1212/WNL.0b013e3182563c0a</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiernan, M. C., Vucic, S., Cheah, B. C., Turner, M. R., Eisen, A., Hardiman, O., &#x2026; Zoing, M. C. (2011). Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet, 377, 942-955. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0140-6736(10)61156-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klenowski, P. M., Fogarty, M. J., Shariff, M., Belmer, A., Bellingham, M. C., &amp; Bartlett, S. E. (2016a). Increased synaptic excitation and abnormal dendritic structure of prefrontal cortex layer V pyramidal neurons following prolonged binge-like consumption of ethanol. eNeuro, 3, ENEURO.0248-ENEU16.2016. https://doi.org/10.1523/ENEURO.0248-16.2016</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klenowski, P. M., Shariff, M. R., Belmer, A., Fogarty, M. J., Mu, E. W., Bellingham, M. C., &amp; Bartlett, S. E. (2016b). Prolonged consumption of sucrose in a binge-like manner, alters the morphology of medium spiny neurons in the nucleus Accumbens Shell. Frontiers in Behavioral Neuroscience, 10, 54. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnbeh.2016.00054</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klenowski, P. M., Wright, S. E., Mu, E. W. H., Noakes, P. G., Lavidis, N. A., Bartlett, S. E., &#x2026; Fogarty, M. J. (2017). Investigating methodological differences in the assessment of dendritic morphology of Basolateral amygdala principal neurons-a comparison of Golgi-Cox and Neurobiotin electroporation techniques. Brain Sciences, 7(12), 165. https://doi.org/10.3390/brainsci7120165</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kletzien, H., Russell, J. A., Leverson, G., &amp; Connor, N. P. (2018). Effect of neuromuscular electrical stimulation frequency on muscles of the tongue. Muscle &amp; Nerve, 58, 441-448. https://doi.org/10.1002/mus.26173</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuhnlein, P., Gdynia, H. J., Sperfeld, A. D., Lindner-Pfleghar, B., Ludolph, A. C., Prosiegel, M., &amp; Riecker, A. (2008). Diagnosis and treatment of bulbar symptoms in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nature Clinical Practice. Neurology, 4, 366-374. https://doi.org/10.1038/ncpneuro0853</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuo, J. J., Siddique, T., Fu, R., &amp; Heckman, C. J. (2005). Increased persistent Na(+) current and its effect on excitability in motoneurones cultured from mutant SOD1 mice. The Journal of Physiology, 563, 843-854. https://doi.org/10.1113/jphysiol.2004.074138</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuo, S. W., Binder, M. D., &amp; Heckman, C. J. (2020). Excessive homeostatic gain in spinal Motoneurons in a mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Scientific Reports, 10, 9049. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-020-65685-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, J. D., Kamaruzaman, N. A., Fung, J. N., Taylor, S. M., Turner, B. J., Atkin, J. D., &#x2026; Noakes, P. G. (2013). Dysregulation of the complement cascade in the hSOD1G93A transgenic mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Journal of Neuroinflammation, 10, 119. https://doi.org/10.1186/1742-2094-10-119</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leroy, F., Lamotte d'Incamps, B., Imhoff-Manuel, R. D., &amp; Zytnicki, D. (2014). Early intrinsic hyperexcitability does not contribute to motoneuron degeneration in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. eLife, 3. https://doi.org/10.7554/eLife.04046</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leroy, F., &amp; Zytnicki, D. (2015). Is hyperexcitability really guilty in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis? Neural Regeneration Research, 10, 1413-1415. https://doi.org/10.4103/1673-5374.165308</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lever, T. E., Gorsek, A., Cox, K. T., O'Brien, K. F., Capra, N. F., Hough, M. S., &amp; Murashov, A. K. (2009). An animal model of oral dysphagia in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Dysphagia, 24, 180-195. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00455-008-9190-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma, W. Y., &amp; Vacca-Galloway, L. L. (1991). Reduced branching and length of dendrites detected in cervical spinal cord motoneurons of wobbler mouse, a model for inherited motoneuron disease. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 311, 210-222. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.903110204</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maejima, M., Abe, S., Sakiyama, K., Agematsu, H., Hashimoto, M., Tamatsu, Y., &amp; Ide, Y. (2005). Changes in the properties of mouse tongue muscle fibres before and after weaning. Archives of Oral Biology, 50, 988-993. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.archoralbio.2005.03.007</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ngo, S. T., Baumann, F., Ridall, P. G., Pettitt, A. N., Henderson, R. D., Bellingham, M. C., &amp; McCombe, P. A. (2012). The relationship between Bayesian motor unit number estimation and histological measurements of motor neurons in wild-type and SOD1(G93A) mice. Clinical Neurophysiology, 123, 2080-2091. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.clinph.2012.01.028</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nieto-Gonzalez, J. L., Moser, J., Lauritzen, M., Schmitt-John, T., &amp; Jensen, K. (2011). Reduced GABAergic inhibition explains cortical hyperexcitability in the wobbler mouse model of ALS. Cerebral Cortex, 21, 625-635. https://doi.org/10.1093/cercor/bhq134</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nijssen, J., Comley, L. H., &amp; Hedlund, E. (2017). Motor neuron vulnerability and resistance in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathologica, 133, 863-885. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00401-017-1708-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nunez-Abades, P. A., &amp; Cameron, W. E. (1995). Morphology of developing rat genioglossal motoneurons studied in vitro: Relative changes in diameter and surface area of somata and dendrites. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 353, 129-142. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.903530112</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nunez-Abades, P. A., He, F., Barrionuevo, G., &amp; Cameron, W. E. (1994). Morphology of developing rat genioglossal motoneurons studied in vitro: Changes in length, branching pattern, and spatial distribution of dendrites. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 339, 401-420. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.903390308</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olney, J. W. (1969). Brain lesions, obesity, and other disturbances in mice treated with monosodium glutamate. Science, 164, 719-721.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olney, J. W., &amp; Sharpe, L. G. (1969). Brain lesions in an infant rhesus monkey treated with monsodium glutamate. Science, 166, 386-388.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osman, K. L., Kohlberg, S., Mok, A., Brooks, R., Lind, L. A., McCormack, K., &#x2026; Lever, T. E. (2020). Optimizing the translational value of mouse models of ALS for dysphagia therapeutic discovery. Dysphagia, 35, 343-359. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00455-019-10034-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozdinler, P. H., Benn, S., Yamamoto, T. H., Guzel, M., Brown, R. H., Jr., &amp; Macklis, J. D. (2011). Corticospinal motor neurons and related subcerebral projection neurons undergo early and specific neurodegeneration in hSOD1G(9)(3)a transgenic ALS mice. The Journal of Neuroscience, 31, 4166-4177. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.4184-10.2011</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plaitakis, A., &amp; Caroscio, J. T. (1987). Abnormal glutamate metabolism in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Annals of Neurology, 22, 575-579. https://doi.org/10.1002/ana.410220503</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Powell, G. L., Gaddy, J., Xu, F., Fregosi, R. F., &amp; Levine, R. B. (2016). Developmental nicotine exposure disrupts dendritic arborization patterns of hypoglossal motoneurons in the neonatal rat. Developmental Neurobiology, 76, 1125-1137. https://doi.org/10.1002/dneu.22379</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rafuse, V.F., Pattullo, M.C., Gordon, T., 1997. Innervation ratio and motor unit force in large muscles: A study of chronically stimulated cat medial gastrocnemius. The Journal of Physiology 499 (Pt 3), 809-823.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosen, D. R., Siddique, T., Patterson, D., Figlewicz, D. A., Sapp, P., Hentati, A., et al. (1993). Mutations in cu/Zn superoxide dismutase gene are associated with familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nature, 362, 59-62. https://doi.org/10.1038/362059a0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rutledge, L. T., Duncan, J., &amp; Beatty, N. (1969). A study of pyramidal cell axon collaterals in intact and partially isolated adult cerebral cortex. Brain Research, 16, 15-22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saba, L., Viscomi, M. T., Caioli, S., Pignataro, A., Bisicchia, E., Pieri, M., &#x2026; Zona, C. (2015). Altered functionality, morphology, and vesicular glutamate transporter expression of cortical motor neurons from a Presymptomatic mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Cerebral Cortex, 26, 1512-1528. https://doi.org/10.1093/cercor/bhu317</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schiaffino, S., &amp; Reggiani, C. (2011). Fiber types in mammalian skeletal muscles. Physiological Reviews, 91, 1447-1531. https://doi.org/10.1152/physrev.00031.2010</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaw, P. J., Chinnery, R. M., Thagesen, H., Borthwick, G. M., &amp; Ince, P. G. (1997). Immunocytochemical study of the distribution of the free radical scavenging enzymes Cu/Zn superoxide dismutase (SOD1); MN superoxide dismutase (MN SOD) and catalase in the normal human spinal cord and in motor neuron disease. Journal of the Neurological Sciences, 147, 115-125.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sokoloff, A. J. (2000). Localization and contractile properties of intrinsic longitudinal motor units of the rat tongue. Journal of Neurophysiology, 84, 827-835. https://doi.org/10.1152/jn.2000.84.2.827</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steyn, F. J., Lee, K., Fogarty, M. J., Veldhuis, J. D., McCombe, P. A., Bellingham, M. C., &#x2026; Chen, C. (2013). Growth hormone secretion is correlated with neuromuscular innervation rather than motor neuron number in early-symptomatic male amyotrophic lateral sclerosis mice. Endocrinology, 154, 4695-4706. https://doi.org/10.1210/en.2013-1570</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner, M. R., Hardiman, O., Benatar, M., Brooks, B. R., Chio, A., de Carvalho, M., &#x2026; Kiernan, M. C. (2013). Controversies and priorities in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet Neurology, 12, 310-322. https://doi.org/10.1016/S1474-4422(13)70036-X</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Udaka, F., Kameyama, M., &amp; Tomonaga, M. (1986). Degeneration of Betz cells in motor neuron disease. A Golgi study. Acta Neuropathologica, 70, 289-295.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ulfhake, B., &amp; Cullheim, S. (1988). Postnatal development of cat hind limb motoneurons. III: Changes in size of motoneurons supplying the triceps surae muscle. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 278, 103-120. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.902780107</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Zundert, B., Peuscher, M. H., Hynynen, M., Chen, A., Neve, R. L., Brown, R. H., Jr., &#x2026; Bellingham, M. C. (2008). Neonatal neuronal circuitry shows hyperexcitable disturbance in a mouse model of the adult-onset neurodegenerative disease amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. The Journal of Neuroscience, 28, 10864-10874. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.1340-08.2008</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic, S., Rothstein, J. D., &amp; Kiernan, M. C. (2014). Advances in treating amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Insights from pathophysiological studies. Trends in Neurosciences, 37, 433-442. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tins.2014.05.006</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wegorzewska, I., Bell, S., Cairns, N. J., Miller, T. M., &amp; Baloh, R. H. (2009). TDP-43 mutant transgenic mice develop features of ALS and frontotemporal lobar degeneration. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 106, 18809-18814. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.0908767106</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams, P. A., Bellinger, D. L., &amp; Wilson, C. G. (2018). Changes in the morphology of hypoglossal motor neurons in the brainstem of developing rats. Anatomical Record (Hoboken), 302, 869-892. https://doi.org/10.1002/ar.23971</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wils, H., Kleinberger, G., Janssens, J., Pereson, S., Joris, G., Cuijt, I., &#x2026; Kumar-Singh, S. (2010). TDP-43 transgenic mice develop spastic paralysis and neuronal inclusions characteristic of ALS and frontotemporal lobar degeneration. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 107, 3858-3863. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.0912417107</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>