<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">33118185</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>21</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-0258</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>40</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>10</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Statistics in medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Stat Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Serial correlation structures in latent linear mixed models for analysis of multivariate longitudinal ordinal responses.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>578</StartPage><EndPage>592</EndPage><MedlinePgn>578-592</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/sim.8790</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>We propose a latent linear mixed model to analyze multivariate longitudinal data of multiple ordinal variables, which are manifestations of fewer continuous latent variables. We focus on the latent level where the effects of observed covariates on the latent variables are of interest. We incorporate serial correlation into the variance component rather than assuming independent residuals. We show that misleading inference may be drawn when misspecifying the variance component. Furthermore, we provide a graphical tool depicting latent empirical semi-variograms to detect serial correlation for latent stationary linear mixed models. We apply our proposed model to examine the treatment effect on patients having the amyotrophic lateral sclerosis disease. The result shows that the treatment can slow down progression of latent cervical and lumbar functions.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020 John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tran</LastName><ForeName>Trung Dung</ForeName><Initials>TD</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9967-1012</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>I-BioStat, KU Leuven, Leuven, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>I-BioStat, Universiteit Hasselt, Hasselt, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lesaffre</LastName><ForeName>Emmanuel</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>I-BioStat, KU Leuven, Leuven, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>I-BioStat, Universiteit Hasselt, Hasselt, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Verbeke</LastName><ForeName>Geert</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>I-BioStat, KU Leuven, Leuven, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>I-BioStat, Universiteit Hasselt, Hasselt, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Molenberghs</LastName><ForeName>Geert</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6453-5448</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>I-BioStat, KU Leuven, Leuven, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>I-BioStat, Universiteit Hasselt, Hasselt, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Stat Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8215016</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0277-6715</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016014" MajorTopicYN="N">Linear Models</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008137" MajorTopicYN="N">Longitudinal Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015999" MajorTopicYN="N">Multivariate Analysis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ALS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ornstein-Uhlenbeck</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">latent linear mixed model</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">serial correlation</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>56</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33118185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/sim.8790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Wijesekera LC, Nigel Leigh P. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Orphanet J Rare Dis. 2009;4(1):3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo S, Lawson AB, He B, Elm JJ, Tilley BC. Bayesian multiple imputation for missing multivariate longitudinal data from a Parkinson's disease clinical trial. Stat Methods Med Res. 2016;25(2):821-837.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azevedo CLN, Fox JP, Andrade DF. Bayesian longitudinal item response modeling with restricted covariance pattern structures. Stat Comput. 2016;26(1):443-460.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proust-Lima C, Amieva H, Jacqmin-Gadda H. Analysis of multivariate mixed longitudinal data: a flexible latent process approach. Br J Math Stat Psychol. 2013;66(3):470-487.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Luo S. Multidimensional latent trait linear mixed model: an application in clinical studies with multivariate longitudinal outcomes. Stat Med. 2017a;36(20):3244-3256.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui K, Dunson DB. Generalized dynamic factor models for mixed-measurement time series. J Comput Graph Stat. 2014;23(1):169-191.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tran TD, Lesaffre E, Verbeke G, Duyck J. Modeling local dependence in latent vector autoregressive models. Biostatistics. 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tran TD, Lesaffre E, Verbeke G, Duyck J. Latent Ornstein-Uhlenbeck models for Bayesian analysis of multivariate longitudinal categorical responses. Biometrics. 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diggle P, Liang K, Zeger S. Analysis of Longitudinal Data. Oxford, UK: Clarendon Press; 1994.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heitjan DF, Sharma D. Modelling repeated-series longitudinal data. Stat Med. 1997;16(4):347-355.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sy JP, Taylor JMG, Cumberland WG. A stochastic model for the analysis of bivariate longitudinal AIDS data. Biometrics. 1997;53(2):542-555.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldstein H, Healy MJR, Rasbash J. Multilevel time series models with applications to repeated measures data. Stat Med. 1994;13(16):1643-1655.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verbeke G, Molenberghs G. Linear Mixed Models for Longitudinal Data. New York, NY: Springer; 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang WL, Lin TI. Multivariate t nonlinear mixed-effects models for multi-outcome longitudinal data with missing values. Stat Med. 2014;33(17):3029-3046.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oravecz Z, Tuerlinckx F, Vandekerckhove J. A hierarchical Ornstein-Uhlenbeck model for continuous repeated measurement data. Psychometrika. 2009;74(3):395-418.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Ayala RJ. The Theory and Practice of Item Response Theory. New York, NY: Guildord Press; 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reckase M. Multidimensional Item Response Theory. New York, NY: Springer; 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laird NM, Ware JH. Random-effects models for longitudinal data. Biometrics. 1982;38(4):963-974.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reinsel G. Estimation and prediction in a multivariate random effects generalized linear model. J Am Stat Assoc. 1984;79(386):406-414.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>vM E, Hardiman O, Chio A, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet. 2017;390(10107):2084-2098.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell J, Borasio G. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet. 2007;369(9578):2031-2041.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The ALS CNTF treatment study (ACTS) phase I-II Study Group. The amyotrophic lateral sclerosis functional rating scale: assessment of activities of daily living in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Arch Neurol. 1996;53(2):141-147.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum JM, Stambler N, Malta E, et al. The ALSFRS-R: a revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. J Neurol Sci. 1999;169(1):13-21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atassi N, Berry J, Shui A, et al. The PRO-ACT database. Neurology. 2014;83(19):1719-1725.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Chalabi A, Hardiman O, Kiernan MC, Chi&#xf2; A, Berg v dLH. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: moving towards a new classification system. Lancet Neurol. 2016;15:1182-1194.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ostini R, Nering ML. Polytomous Item Response Theory Models. Thousand Oaks, CA: Sage Publications; 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fitzmaurice G, Davidian M, Verbeke G, Molenberghs G. Longitudinal Data Analysis. Handbooks of Modern Statistical Methods. Boca Raton, FL: Chapman &amp; Hall/CRC Press; 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minasny B, McBratney AB. The Mat&#xe9;rn function as a general model for soil variograms. Geoderma. 2005;128(3):192-207.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stein M. Interpolation of Spatial Data: Some Theory for Kriging. Springer Series in Statistics. New York, NY: Springer; 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oort F. Three-mode models for multivariate longitudinal data. Br J Math Stat Psychol. 2001;54:49-78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J&#xf6;reskog KG. A general approach to confirmatory maximum likelihood factor analysis. Psychometrika. 1969;34(2):183-202.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verbeke G, Lesaffre E, Brant LJ. The detection of residual serial correlation in linear mixed models. Stat Med. 1998;17(12):1391-1402.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gelman A. Prior distributions for variance parameters in hierarchical models. Bayesian Anal. 2006;1(3):515-534.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewandowski D, Kurowicka D, Joe H. Generating random correlation matrices based on vines and extended onion method. J Multivar Anal. 2009;100(9):1989-2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carpenter B, Gelman A, Hoffman M, et al. Stan: a probabilistic programming language. J Stat Softw. 2017;76(1):1-32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lesaffre E, Lawson AB. Bayesian Biostatistics. West Sussex: Wiley; 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gelman A, Carlin J, Stern H, Dunson D, Vehtari A, Rubin D. Bayesian Data Analysis. Texts in Statistical Science Taylor &amp; Francis. 3rd ed. Boca Raton, FL: Chapman &amp; Hall/CRC Press; 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watanabe S. Asymptotic equivalence of Bayes cross validation and widely applicable information criterion in singular learning theory. J Mach Learn Res. 2010;11:3571-3594.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pindyck RS. The long-run evolution of energy prices. Energy J. 1999;20(2):1-27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oravecz Z, Tuerlinckx F, Vandekerckhove J. Bayesian data analysis with the bivariate hierarchical ornstein-uhlenbeck process model. Multivar Behav Res. 2016;51:106-119.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>