<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">33130950</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>04</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1432-1459</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>268</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The presymptomatic phase of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: are we merely scratching the surface?</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>4607</StartPage><EndPage>4629</EndPage><MedlinePgn>4607-4629</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s00415-020-10289-5</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Presymptomatic studies in ALS have consistently captured considerable disease burden long before symptom manifestation and contributed important academic insights. With the emergence of genotype-specific therapies, however, there is a pressing need to address practical objectives such as the estimation of age of symptom onset, phenotypic prediction, informing the optimal timing of pharmacological intervention, and identifying a core panel of biomarkers which may detect response to therapy. Existing presymptomatic studies in ALS have adopted striking different study designs, relied on a variety of control groups, used divergent imaging and electrophysiology methods, and focused on different genotypes and demographic groups. We have performed a systematic review of existing presymptomatic studies in ALS to identify common themes, stereotyped shortcomings, and key learning points for future studies. Existing presymptomatic studies in ALS often suffer from sample size limitations, lack of disease controls and rarely follow their cohort until symptom manifestation. As the characterisation of presymptomatic processes in ALS serves a multitude of academic and clinical purposes, the careful review of existing studies offers important lessons for future initiatives.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020. Springer-Verlag GmbH Germany, part of Springer Nature.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chipika</LastName><ForeName>Rangariroyashe H</ForeName><Initials>RH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Computational Neuroimaging Group (CNG), Biomedical Sciences Institute, Trinity College Dublin, Pearse Street, Dublin, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Siah</LastName><ForeName>We Fong</ForeName><Initials>WF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Computational Neuroimaging Group (CNG), Biomedical Sciences Institute, Trinity College Dublin, Pearse Street, Dublin, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McKenna</LastName><ForeName>Mary Clare</ForeName><Initials>MC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Computational Neuroimaging Group (CNG), Biomedical Sciences Institute, Trinity College Dublin, Pearse Street, Dublin, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li Hi Shing</LastName><ForeName>Stacey</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Computational Neuroimaging Group (CNG), Biomedical Sciences Institute, Trinity College Dublin, Pearse Street, Dublin, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hardiman</LastName><ForeName>Orla</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Computational Neuroimaging Group (CNG), Biomedical Sciences Institute, Trinity College Dublin, Pearse Street, Dublin, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bede</LastName><ForeName>Peter</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0492-4772</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Computational Neuroimaging Group (CNG), Biomedical Sciences Institute, Trinity College Dublin, Pearse Street, Dublin, Ireland. bedep@tcd.ie.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>HRB EIA-2017-019</GrantID><Agency>Health Research Board Ireland</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>SPF-2020</GrantID><Agency>Spastic Paraplegia Foundation, Inc.</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>J Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0423161</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0340-5354</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018401" MajorTopicYN="N">Sample Size</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Frontotemporal degeneration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neuroimaging</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Presymptomatic</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33130950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00415-020-10289-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s00415-020-10289-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Miller T, Cudkowicz M, Shaw PJ, Andersen PM, Atassi N, Bucelli RC, Genge A, Glass J, Ladha S, Ludolph AL, Maragakis NJ, McDermott CJ, Pestronk A, Ravits J, Salachas F, Trudell R, Van Damme P, Zinman L, Bennett CF, Lane R, Sandrock A, Runz H, Graham D, Houshyar H, McCampbell A, Nestorov I, Chang I, McNeill M, Fanning L, Fradette S, Ferguson TA (2020) Phase 1&#x2013;2 trial of antisense oligonucleotide tofersen for SOD1 ALS. The N Engl J Med 383:109&#x2013;119</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32640130</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2003715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mueller C, Berry JD, McKenna-Yasek DM, Gernoux G, Owegi MA, Pothier LM, Douthwright CL, Gelevski D, Luppino SD, Blackwood M, Wightman NS, Oakley DH, Frosch MP, Flotte TR, Cudkowicz ME, Brown RH Jr (2020) SOD1 Suppression with adeno-associated virus and microrna in familial ALS. The N Engl J Med 383:151&#x2013;158</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32640133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2005056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Omer T, Finegan E, Hutchinson S, Doherty M, Vajda A, McLaughlin RL, Pender N, Hardiman O, Bede P (2017) Neuroimaging patterns along the ALS-FTD spectrum: a multiparametric imaging study. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Front Degener 18:611&#x2013;623</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/21678421.2017.1332077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke T, Pinto-Grau M, Lonergan K, Bede P, O&#x2019;Sullivan M, Heverin M, Vajda A, McLaughlin RL, Pender N, Hardiman O (2017) A Cross-sectional population-based investigation into behavioral change in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: subphenotypes, staging, cognitive predictors, and survival. Ann Clini Transl Neurol 4:305&#x2013;317</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/acn3.407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finegan E, Chipika RH, Shing SLH, Hardiman O, Bede P (2019) Primary lateral sclerosis: a distinct entity or part of the ALS spectrum? Amyotroph Lateral Scler Front Degener 20:133&#x2013;145</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/21678421.2018.1550518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiernan MC, Ziemann U, Eisen A (2019) Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: origins traced to impaired balance between neural excitation and inhibition in the neonatal period. Muscle Nerve 60:232&#x2013;235</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31233613</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.26617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bertrand A, Wen J, Rinaldi D, Houot M, Sayah S, Camuzat A, Fournier C, Fontanella S, Routier A, Couratier P, Pasquier F, Habert MO, Hannequin D, Martinaud O, Caroppo P, Levy R, Dubois B, Brice A, Durrleman S, Colliot O, Le Ber I (2018) Early cognitive, structural, and microstructural changes in presymptomatic C9orf72 carriers younger than 40 years. JAMA Neurol 75:236&#x2013;245</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29197216</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamaneurol.2017.4266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Querin G, Bede P, El Mendili MM, Li M, Pelegrini-Issac M, Rinaldi D, Catala M, Saracino D, Salachas F, Camuzat A, Marchand-Pauvert V, Cohen-Adad J, Colliot O, Le Ber I, Pradat PF (2019) Presymptomatic spinal cord pathology in c9orf72 mutation carriers: a longitudinal neuroimaging study. Ann Neurol 86:158&#x2013;167</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31177556</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.25520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benatar M, Turner MR, Wuu J (2019) Defining pre-symptomatic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Front Degener 20:303&#x2013;309</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/21678421.2019.1587634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carew JD, Nair G, Andersen PM, Wuu J, Gronka S, Hu X, Benatar M (2011) Presymptomatic spinal cord neurometabolic findings in SOD1-positive people at risk for familial ALS. Neurology 77:1370&#x2013;1375</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21940617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3182757</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0b013e318231526a</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cirak S, Arechavala-Gomeza V, Guglieri M, Feng L, Torelli S, Anthony K, Abbs S, Garralda ME, Bourke J, Wells DJ, Dickson G, Wood MJ, Wilton SD, Straub V, Kole R, Shrewsbury SB, Sewry C, Morgan JE, Bushby K, Muntoni F (2011) Exon skipping and dystrophin restoration in patients with Duchenne muscular dystrophy after systemic phosphorodiamidate morpholino oligomer treatment: an open-label, phase 2, dose-escalation study. Lancet (London, England) 378:595&#x2013;605</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(11)60756-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendell JR, Rodino-Klapac LR, Sahenk Z, Roush K, Bird L, Lowes LP, Alfano L, Gomez AM, Lewis S, Kota J, Malik V, Shontz K, Walker CM, Flanigan KM, Corridore M, Kean JR, Allen HD, Shilling C, Melia KR, Sazani P, Saoud JB, Kaye EM (2013) Eteplirsen for the treatment of Duchenne muscular dystrophy. Ann Neurol 74:637&#x2013;647</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23907995</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.23982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendell JR, Goemans N, Lowes LP, Alfano LN, Berry K, Shao J, Kaye EM, Mercuri E (2016) Longitudinal effect of eteplirsen versus historical control on ambulation in Duchenne muscular dystrophy. Ann Neurol 79:257&#x2013;271</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26573217</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5064753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.24555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanouchi T, Ohkubo T, Yokota T (2012) Can regional spreading of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis motor symptoms be explained by prion-like propagation? J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 83:739&#x2013;745</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22544947</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp-2011-301826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bede P, Iyer PM, Schuster C, Elamin M, McLaughlin RL, Kenna K, Hardiman O (2016) The selective anatomical vulnerability of ALS: &#x201c;disease-defining&#x201d; and &#x201c;disease-defying&#x201d; brain regions. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Front Degener 17:561&#x2013;570</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/21678421.2016.1173702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bede P, Querin G, Pradat PF (2018) The changing landscape of motor neuron disease imaging: the transition from descriptive studies to precision clinical tools. Curr Opin Neurol 31:431&#x2013;438</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29750730</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/WCO.0000000000000569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eisen A (2011) The real onset of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 82:593</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21551172</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp.2011.245761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benatar M, Wuu J (2012) Presymptomatic studies in ALS: rationale, challenges, and approach. Neurology 79:1732&#x2013;1739</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23071166</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3468777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0b013e31826e9b1d</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swash M, Ingram D (1988) Preclinical and subclinical events in motor neuron disease. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 51:165&#x2013;168</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3346681</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">1031524</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp.51.2.165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eisen A, Kiernan M, Mitsumoto H, Swash M (2014) Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a long preclinical period? J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 85:1232&#x2013;1238</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24648037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp-2013-307135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aggarwal A, Nicholson G (2002) Detection of preclinical motor neurone loss in SOD1 mutation carriers using motor unit number estimation. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 73:199&#x2013;201</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12122184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">1737965</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp.73.2.199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aggarwal A, Nicholson G (2001) Normal complement of motor units in asymptomatic familial (SOD1 mutation) amyotrophic lateral sclerosis carriers. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 71:478&#x2013;481</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11561030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">1763514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp.71.4.478</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walhout R, Schmidt R, Westeneng HJ, Verstraete E, Seelen M, van Rheenen W, de Reus MA, van Es MA, Hendrikse J, Veldink JH, van den Heuvel MP, van den Berg LH (2015) Brain morphologic changes in asymptomatic C9orf72 repeat expansion carriers. Neurology 85:1780&#x2013;1788</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26497991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000002135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Floeter MK, Bageac D, Danielian LE, Braun LE, Traynor BJ, Kwan JY (2016) Longitudinal imaging in C9orf72 mutation carriers: relationship to phenotype. NeuroImage Clin 12:1035&#x2013;1043</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27995069</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5153604</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nicl.2016.10.014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee SE, Sias AC, Mandelli ML, Brown JA, Brown AB, Khazenzon AM, Vidovszky AA, Zanto TP, Karydas AM, Pribadi M, Dokuru D, Coppola G, Geschwind DH, Rademakers R, Gorno-Tempini ML, Rosen HJ, Miller BL, Seeley WW (2017) Network degeneration and dysfunction in presymptomatic C9ORF72 expansion carriers. NeuroImage Clin 14:286&#x2013;297</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28337409</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nicl.2016.12.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papma JM, Jiskoot LC, Panman JL, Dopper EG, den Heijer T, Donker Kaat L, Pijnenburg YAL, Meeter LH, van Minkelen R, Rombouts S, van Swieten JC (2017) Cognition and gray and white matter characteristics of presymptomatic C9orf72 repeat expansion. Neurology 89:1256&#x2013;1264</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28855404</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000004393</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wen J, Zhang H, Alexander DC, Durrleman S, Routier A, Rinaldi D, Houot M, Couratier P, Hannequin D, Pasquier F, Zhang J, Colliot O, Le Ber I, Bertrand A (2019) Neurite density is reduced in the presymptomatic phase of C9orf72 disease. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 90:387&#x2013;394</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30355607</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp-2018-318994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le Blanc G, Jett&#xe9; Pomerleau V, McCarthy J, Borroni B, van Swieten J, Galimberti D, Sanchez-Valle R, LaForce R Jr, Moreno F, Synofzik M, Graff C, Masellis M, Tartaglia MC, Rowe JB, Vandenberghe R, Finger E, Tagliavini F, de Mendon&#xe7;a A, Santana I, Butler C, Gerhard A, Danek A, Levin J, Otto M, Frisoni G, Sorbi S, Rohrer JD, Ducharme S (2020) Faster Cortical thinning and surface area loss in presymptomatic and symptomatic C9orf72 repeat expansion adult carriers. Ann Neurol 88:113</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32285980</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.25748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Vocht J et al (2020) Use of Multimodal imaging and clinical biomarkers in presymptomatic carriers of C9orf72 repeat expansion. JAMA Neurol 77(8):1008&#x2013;1017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32421156</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamaneurol.2020.1087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lul&#xe9; DE et al (2020) Deficits in verbal fluency in presymptomatic C9orf72 mutation gene carriers-a developmental disorder. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 91(11):1195&#x2013;1200</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32855285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp-2020-323671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorges M, Vercruysse P, M&#xfc;ller HP, Huppertz HJ, Rosenbohm A, Nagel G, Weydt P, Peters&#xe9;n &#xc5;, Ludolph AC, Kassubek J, Dupuis L (2017) Hypothalamic atrophy is related to body mass index and age at onset in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 88:1033&#x2013;1041</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28596251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp-2017-315795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menke RA, Proudfoot M, Wuu J, Andersen PM, Talbot K, Benatar M, Turner MR (2016) Increased functional connectivity common to symptomatic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and those at genetic risk. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 87:580&#x2013;588</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26733601</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp-2015-311945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S, Winhammar JM, Rowe DB, Kiernan MC (2010) Corticomotoneuronal function in asymptomatic SOD-1 mutation carriers. Clin Neurophysiol 121:1781&#x2013;1785</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20362497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clinph.2010.02.164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ng MC, Ho JT, Ho SL, Lee R, Li G, Cheng TS, Song YQ, Ho PW, Fong GC, Mak W, Chan KH, Li LS, Luk KD, Hu Y, Ramsden DB, Leong LL (2008) Abnormal diffusion tensor in nonsymptomatic familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with a causative superoxide dismutase 1 mutation. J Magn Reson Imaging 27:8&#x2013;13</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18022844</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmri.21217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner MR, Hammers A, Al-Chalabi A, Shaw CE, Andersen PM, Brooks DJ, Leigh PN (2005) Distinct cerebral lesions in sporadic and &#x201c;D90A&#x201d; SOD1 ALS: studies with [11C]flumazenil PET. Brain J Neurol 128:1323&#x2013;1329</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awh509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Premi E, Calhoun VD, Diano M, Gazzina S, Cosseddu M, Alberici A, Archetti S, Paternic&#xf2; D, Gasparotti R, van Swieten J, Galimberti D, Sanchez-Valle R, Laforce R Jr, Moreno F, Synofzik M, Graff C, Masellis M, Tartaglia MC, Rowe J, Vandenberghe R, Finger E, Tagliavini F, de Mendon&#xe7;a A, Santana I, Butler C, Ducharme S, Gerhard A, Danek A, Levin J, Otto M, Frisoni G, Cappa S, Sorbi S, Padovani A, Rohrer JD, Borroni B (2019) The inner fluctuations of the brain in presymptomatic frontotemporal dementia: the chronnectome fingerprint. Neuroimage 189:645&#x2013;654</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30716457</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuroimage.2019.01.080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Staffaroni AM, Cobigo Y, Goh SM, Kornak J, Bajorek L, Chiang K, Appleby B, Bove J, Bordelon Y, Brannelly P, Brushaber D, Caso C, Coppola G, Dever R, Dheel C, Dickerson BC, Dickinson S, Dominguez S, Domoto-Reilly K, Faber K, Ferrall J, Fields JA, Fishman A, Fong J, Foroud T, Forsberg LK, Gavrilova R, Gearhart D, Ghazanfari B, Ghoshal N, Goldman J, Graff-Radford J, Graff-Radford N, Grant I, Grossman M, Haley D, Heuer HW, Hsiung GY, Huey ED, Irwin DJ, Jones DT, Jones L, Kantarci K, Karydas A, Kaufer DI, Kerwin DR, Knopman DS, Kraft R, Kramer JH, Kremers WK, Kukull WA, Litvan I, Ljubenkov PA, Lucente D, Lungu C, Mackenzie IR, Maldonado M, Manoochehri M, McGinnis SM, McKinley E, Mendez MF, Miller BL, Multani N, Onyike C, Padmanabhan J, Pantelyat A, Pearlman R, Petrucelli L, Potter M, Rademakers R, Ramos EM, Rankin KP, Rascovsky K, Roberson ED, Rogalski E, Sengdy P, Shaw LM, Syrjanen J, Tartaglia MC, Tatton N, Taylor J, Toga A, Trojanowski JQ, Weintraub S, Wang P, Wong B, Wszolek Z, Boxer AL, Boeve BF, Rosen HJ (2020) Individualized atrophy scores predict dementia onset in familial frontotemporal lobar degeneration. Alzheimer&#x2019;s Dement J Alzheimer&#x2019;s Assoc 16:37&#x2013;48</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jalz.2019.04.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gazzina S, Grassi M, Premi E, Cosseddu M, Alberici A, Archetti S, Gasparotti R, Van Swieten J, Galimberti D, Sanchez-Valle R, Laforce RJ, Moreno F, Synofzik M, Graff C, Masellis M, Tartaglia MC, Rowe JB, Vandenberghe R, Finger E, Tagliavini F, de Mendon&#xe7;a A, Santana I, Butler CR, Ducharme S, Gerhard A, Danek A, Levin J, Otto M, Frisoni G, Sorbi S, Padovani A, Rohrer JD, Borroni B (2019) Education modulates brain maintenance in presymptomatic frontotemporal dementia. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 90:1124&#x2013;1130</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31182509</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp-2019-320439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mutsaerts H, Mirza SS, Petr J, Thomas DL, Cash DM, Bocchetta M, de Vita E, Metcalfe AWS, Shirzadi Z, Robertson AD, Tartaglia MC, Mitchell SB, Black SE, Freedman M, Tang-Wai D, Keren R, Rogaeva E, van Swieten J, Laforce R, Tagliavini F, Borroni B, Galimberti D, Rowe JB, Graff C, Frisoni GB, Finger E, Sorbi S, de Mendon&#xe7;a A, Rohrer JD, MacIntosh BJ, Masellis M (2019) Cerebral perfusion changes in presymptomatic genetic frontotemporal dementia: a GENFI study. Brain 142:1108&#x2013;1120</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30847466</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6439322</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awz039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fumagalli GG, Basilico P, Arighi A, Bocchetta M, Dick KM, Cash DM, Harding S, Mercurio M, Fenoglio C, Pietroboni AM, Ghezzi L, van Swieten J, Borroni B, de Mendon&#xe7;a A, Masellis M, Tartaglia MC, Rowe JB, Graff C, Tagliavini F, Frisoni GB, Laforce R Jr, Finger E, Sorbi S, Scarpini E, Rohrer JD, Galimberti D (2018) Distinct patterns of brain atrophy in Genetic frontotemporal dementia initiative (GENFI) cohort revealed by visual rating scales. Alzheimer&#x2019;s Res Ther 10:46</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13195-018-0376-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cash DM, Bocchetta M, Thomas DL, Dick KM, van Swieten JC, Borroni B, Galimberti D, Masellis M, Tartaglia MC, Rowe JB, Graff C, Tagliavini F, Frisoni GB, Laforce R Jr, Finger E, de Mendonca A, Sorbi S, Rossor MN, Ourselin S, Rohrer JD (2018) Patterns of gray matter atrophy in genetic frontotemporal dementia: results from the GENFI study. Neurobiol Aging 62:191&#x2013;196</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29172163</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5759893</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2017.10.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Premi E, Grassi M, van Swieten J, Galimberti D, Graff C, Masellis M, Tartaglia C, Tagliavini F, Rowe JB, Laforce R Jr, Finger E, Frisoni GB, de Mendon&#xe7;a A, Sorbi S, Gazzina S, Cosseddu M, Archetti S, Gasparotti R, Manes M, Alberici A, Cardoso MJ, Bocchetta M, Cash DM, Ourselin S, Padovani A, Rohrer JD, Borroni B (2017) Cognitive reserve and TMEM106B genotype modulate brain damage in presymptomatic frontotemporal dementia: a GENFI study. Brain 140:1784&#x2013;1791</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28460069</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5445253</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awx103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tavares TP, Mitchell DGV, Coleman K, Shoesmith C, Bartha R, Cash DM, Moore KM, van Swieten J, Borroni B, Galimberti D, Tartaglia MC, Rowe J, Graff C, Tagliavini F, Frisoni G, Cappa S, Laforce R Jr, de Mendon&#xe7;a A, Sorbi S, Wallstrom G, Masellis M, Rohrer JD, Finger EC (2019) Ventricular volume expansion in presymptomatic genetic frontotemporal dementia. Neurology 93:e1699&#x2013;e1706</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31578297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6946476</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000008386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rittman T, Borchert R, Jones S, van Swieten J, Borroni B, Galimberti D, Masellis M, Tartaglia MC, Graff C, Tagliavini F, Frisoni GB, Laforce R Jr, Finger E, Mendon&#xe7;a A, Sorbi S, Rohrer JD, Rowe JB (2019) Functional network resilience to pathology in presymptomatic genetic frontotemporal dementia. Neurobiol Aging 77:169&#x2013;177</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30831384</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6491498</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2018.12.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cury C, Durrleman S, Cash DM, Lorenzi M, Nicholas JM, Bocchetta M, van Swieten JC, Borroni B, Galimberti D, Masellis M, Tartaglia MC, Rowe JB, Graff C, Tagliavini F, Frisoni GB, Laforce R Jr, Finger E, de Mendon&#xe7;a A, Sorbi S, Ourselin S, Rohrer JD, Modat M (2019) Spatiotemporal analysis for detection of pre-symptomatic shape changes in neurodegenerative diseases: Initial application to the GENFI cohort. Neuroimage 188:282&#x2013;290</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30529631</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuroimage.2018.11.063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudre CH, Bocchetta M, Cash D, Thomas DL, Woollacott I, Dick KM, van Swieten J, Borroni B, Galimberti D, Masellis M, Tartaglia MC, Rowe JB, Graff C, Tagliavini F, Frisoni G, Laforce R Jr, Finger E, de Mendon&#xe7;a A, Sorbi S, Ourselin S, Cardoso MJ, Rohrer JD (2017) White matter hyperintensities are seen only in GRN mutation carriers in the GENFI cohort. Neuroimage Clin 15:171&#x2013;180</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28529873</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5429247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nicl.2017.04.015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Staffaroni AM, Bajorek L, Casaletto KB, Cobigo Y, Goh SM, Wolf A, Heuer HW, Elahi FM, Ljubenkov PA, Dever R, Kornak J, Appleby B, Bove J, Bordelon Y, Brannelly P, Brushaber D, Caso C, Coppola G, Dheel C, Dickerson BC, Dickinson S, Dominguez S, Domoto-Reilly K, Faber K, Ferrall J, Fields JA, Fishman A, Fong J, Foroud T, Forsberg LK, Gavrilova R, Gearhart D, Ghazanfari B, Ghoshal N, Goldman J, Graff-Radford J, Graff-Radford N, Grant I, Grossman M, Haley D, Hsiung GY, Huey ED, Irwin DJ, Jones DT, Jones L, Kantarci K, Karydas A, Kaufer DI, Kerwin DR, Knopman DS, Kraft R, Kremers WK, Kukull WA, Litvan I, Lucente D, Lungu C, Mackenzie IR, Maldonado M, Manoochehri M, McGinnis SM, McKinley E, Mendez MF, Miller BL, Multani N, Onyike C, Padmanabhan J, Pantelyat A, Pearlman R, Petrucelli L, Potter M, Rademakers R, Ramos EM, Rankin KP, Rascovsky K, Roberson ED, Rogalski E, Sengdy P, Shaw LM, Syrjanen J, Tartaglia MC, Tatton N, Taylor J, Toga A, Trojanowski JQ, Weintraub S, Wang P, Wong B, Wszolek Z, Boxer AL, Boeve BF, Kramer JH, Rosen HJ (2020) Assessment of executive function declines in presymptomatic and mildly symptomatic familial frontotemporal dementia: NIH-EXAMINER as a potential clinical trial endpoint. Alzheimer&#x2019;s Dement J Alzheimer&#x2019;s Assoc 16:11&#x2013;21</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jalz.2019.01.012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Popuri K, Dowds E, Beg MF, Balachandar R, Bhalla M, Jacova C, Buller A, Slack P, Sengdy P, Rademakers R, Wittenberg D, Feldman HH, Mackenzie IR, Hsiung GR (2018) Gray matter changes in asymptomatic C9orf72 and GRN mutation carriers. NeuroImage Clin 18:591&#x2013;598</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29845007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5964622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nicl.2018.02.017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feis RA, Bouts M, Panman JL, Jiskoot LC, Dopper EGP, Schouten TM, de Vos F, van der Grond J, van Swieten JC, Rombouts S (2019) Single-subject classification of presymptomatic frontotemporal dementia mutation carriers using multimodal MRI. Neuroimage Clin 22:101718</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30827922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6543025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nicl.2019.101718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panman JL, Jiskoot LC, Bouts M, Meeter LHH, van der Ende EL, Poos JM, Feis RA, Kievit AJA, van Minkelen R, Dopper EGP, Rombouts S, van Swieten JC, Papma JM (2019) Gray and white matter changes in presymptomatic genetic frontotemporal dementia: a longitudinal MRI study. Neurobiol Aging 76:115&#x2013;124</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30711674</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2018.12.017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feis RA, Bouts M, de Vos F, Schouten TM, Panman JL, Jiskoot LC, Dopper EGP, van der Grond J, van Swieten JC, Rombouts S (2019) A multimodal MRI-based classification signature emerges just prior to symptom onset in frontotemporal dementia mutation carriers. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 90:1207&#x2013;1214</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31203211</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp-2019-320774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rohrer JD, Nicholas JM, Cash DM, van Swieten J, Dopper E, Jiskoot L, van Minkelen R, Rombouts SA, Cardoso MJ, Clegg S, Espak M, Mead S, Thomas DL, De Vita E, Masellis M, Black SE, Freedman M, Keren R, MacIntosh BJ, Rogaeva E, Tang-Wai D, Tartaglia MC, Laforce R Jr, Tagliavini F, Tiraboschi P, Redaelli V, Prioni S, Grisoli M, Borroni B, Padovani A, Galimberti D, Scarpini E, Arighi A, Fumagalli G, Rowe JB, Coyle-Gilchrist I, Graff C, Fallstrom M, Jelic V, Stahlbom AK, Andersson C, Thonberg H, Lilius L, Frisoni GB, Pievani M, Bocchetta M, Benussi L, Ghidoni R, Finger E, Sorbi S, Nacmias B, Lombardi G, Polito C, Warren JD, Ourselin S, Fox NC, Rossor MN, Binetti G (2015) Presymptomatic cognitive and neuroanatomical changes in genetic frontotemporal dementia in the Genetic Frontotemporal dementia Initiative (GENFI) study: a cross-sectional analysis. Lancet Neurol 14:253&#x2013;262</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25662776</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6742501</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1474-4422(14)70324-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke T, Elamin M, Bede P, Pinto-Grau M, Lonergan K, Hardiman O, Pender N (2016) Discordant performance on the &#x201c;Reading the Mind in the Eyes&#x201d; Test, based on disease onset in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Front Degener 17:1&#x2013;6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke T, Pinto-Grau M, Lonergan K, Elamin M, Bede P, Costello E, Hardiman O, Pender N (2016) Measurement of social cognition in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a population based study. PLoS ONE 11:e0160850</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27556398</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4996502</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0160850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christidi F, Karavasilis E, Rentzos M, Kelekis N, Evdokimidis I, Bede P (2018) Clinical and radiological markers of extra-motor deficits in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Front Neurol 9:1005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30524366</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6262087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fneur.2018.01005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elamin M, Pinto-Grau M, Burke T, Bede P, Rooney J, O&#x2019;Sullivan M, Lonergan K, Kirby E, Quinlan E, Breen N, Vajda A, Heverin M, Pender N, Hardiman O (2017) Identifying behavioural changes in ALS: validation of the Beaumont behavioural inventory (BBI). Amyotroph Lateral Scler Front Degener 18:68&#x2013;73</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/21678421.2016.1248976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tremolizzo L, Lizio A, Santangelo G, Diamanti S, Lunetta C, Gerardi F, Messina S, La Foresta S, Riva N, Falzone Y, Filippi M, Woolley SC, Sansone VA, Siciliano M, Ferrarese C, Appollonio I (2020) ALS Cognitive behavioral screen (ALS-CBS): normative values for the Italian population and clinical usability. Neurol Sci 41:835&#x2013;841</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31807998</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10072-019-04154-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aggarwal A (2012) Handgrip maximal voluntary isometric contraction does not correlate with thenar motor unit number estimation. Neurol Res Int 2012:187947</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22649725</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3357599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2012/187947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proudfoot M, Rohenkohl G, Quinn A, Colclough GL, Wuu J, Talbot K, Woolrich MW, Benatar M, Nobre AC, Turner MR (2017) Altered cortical beta-band oscillations reflect motor system degeneration in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Hum Brain Mapp 38:237&#x2013;254</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27623516</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hbm.23357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geevasinga N, Menon P, Nicholson GA, Ng K, Howells J, Kril JJ, Yiannikas C, Kiernan MC, Vucic S (2015) Cortical function in asymptomatic carriers and patients with C9orf72 amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. JAMA neurology 72:1268&#x2013;1274</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26348842</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4707047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamaneurol.2015.1872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S, Nicholson GA, Kiernan MC (2008) Cortical hyperexcitability may precede the onset of familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain J Neurol 131:1540&#x2013;1550</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awn071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benussi A, Gazzina S, Premi E, Cosseddu M, Archetti S, Dell&#x2019;Era V, Cantoni V, Cotelli MS, Alberici A, Micheli A, Benussi L, Ghidoni R, Padovani A, Borroni B (2019) Clinical and biomarker changes in presymptomatic genetic frontotemporal dementia. Neurobiol Aging 76:133&#x2013;140</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30711676</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2018.12.018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benatar M, Wuu J, Andersen PM, Lombardi V, Malaspina A (2018) Neurofilament light: a candidate biomarker of presymptomatic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and phenoconversion. Ann Neurol 84:130&#x2013;139</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30014505</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.25276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benatar M, Wuu J, Lombardi V, Jeromin A, Bowser R, Andersen PM, Malaspina A (2019) Neurofilaments in pre-symptomatic ALS and the impact of genotype. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Front Degener 20:538&#x2013;548</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/21678421.2019.1646769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weydt P, Oeckl P, Huss A, M&#xfc;ller K, Volk AE, Kuhle J, Knehr A, Andersen PM, Prudlo J, Steinacker P, Weishaupt JH, Ludolph AC, Otto M (2016) Neurofilament levels as biomarkers in asymptomatic and symptomatic familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol 79:152&#x2013;158</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26528863</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.24552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oeckl P, Weydt P, Thal DR, Weishaupt JH, Ludolph AC, Otto M (2020) Proteomics in cerebrospinal fluid and spinal cord suggests UCHL1, MAP2 and GPNMB as biomarkers and underpins importance of transcriptional pathways in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathol 139:119&#x2013;134</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31701227</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00401-019-02093-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson AG, Gray E, Bampton A, Raciborska D, Talbot K, Turner MR (2019) CSF chitinase proteins in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 90:1215&#x2013;1220</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31123140</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp-2019-320442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gendron TF, Chew J, Stankowski JN, Hayes LR, Zhang YJ, Prudencio M, Carlomagno Y, Daughrity LM, Jansen-West K, Perkerson EA, O&#x2019;Raw A, Cook C, Pregent L, Belzil V, van Blitterswijk M, Tabassian LJ, Lee CW, Yue M, Tong J, Song Y, Castanedes-Casey M, Rousseau L, Phillips V, Dickson DW, Rademakers R, Fryer JD, Rush BK, Pedraza O, Caputo AM, Desaro P, Palmucci C, Robertson A, Heckman MG, Diehl NN, Wiggs E, Tierney M, Braun L, Farren J, Lacomis D, Ladha S, Fournier CN, McCluskey LF, Elman LB, Toledo JB, McBride JD, Tiloca C, Morelli C, Poletti B, Solca F, Prelle A, Wuu J, Jockel-Balsarotti J, Rigo F, Ambrose C, Datta A, Yang W, Raitcheva D, Antognetti G, McCampbell A, Van Swieten JC, Miller BL, Boxer AL, Brown RH, Bowser R, Miller TM, Trojanowski JQ, Grossman M, Berry JD, Hu WT, Ratti A, Traynor BJ, Disney MD, Benatar M, Silani V, Glass JD, Floeter MK, Rothstein JD, Boylan KB, Petrucelli L (2017) Poly(GP) proteins are a useful pharmacodynamic marker for C9ORF72-associated amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Sci Transl Med 9:eaai866</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/scitranslmed.aai7866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lehmer C, Oeckl P, Weishaupt JH, Volk AE, Diehl-Schmid J, Schroeter ML, Lauer M, Kornhuber J, Levin J, Fassbender K, Landwehrmeyer B, Schludi MH, Arzberger T, Kremmer E, Flatley A, Feederle R, Steinacker P, Weydt P, Ludolph AC, Edbauer D, Otto M (2017) Poly-GP in cerebrospinal fluid links C9orf72-associated dipeptide repeat expression to the asymptomatic phase of ALS/FTD. EMBO Mol Med 9:859&#x2013;868</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28408402</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5494528</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15252/emmm.201607486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barschke P, Oeckl P, Steinacker P, Al Shweiki MR, Weishaupt JH, Landwehrmeyer GB, Anderl-Straub S, Weydt P, Diehl-Schmid J, Danek A, Kornhuber J, Schroeter ML, Prudlo J, Jahn H, Fassbender K, Lauer M, van der Ende EL, van Swieten JC, Volk AE, Ludolph AC, Otto M (2020) Different CSF protein profiles in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal dementia with C9orf72 hexanucleotide repeat expansion. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 91:503&#x2013;511</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32132225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp-2019-322476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stoccoro A, Mosca L, Carnicelli V, Cavallari U, Lunetta C, Marocchi A, Migliore L, Copped&#xe8; F (2018) Mitochondrial DNA copy number and D-loop region methylation in carriers of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis gene mutations. Epigenomics 10:1431&#x2013;1443</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30088417</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2217/epi-2018-0072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Q, Boeve BF, Senjem M, Tosakulwong N, Lesnick T, Brushaber D, Dheel C, Fields J, Forsberg L, Gavrilova R, Gearhart D, Graff-Radford J, Graff-Radford N, Jack CR Jr, Jones D, Knopman D, Kremers WK, Lapid M, Rademakers R, Ramos EM, Syrjanen J, Boxer AL, Rosen H, Wszolek ZK, Kantarci K (2020) Trajectory of lobar atrophy in asymptomatic and symptomatic GRN mutation carriers: a longitudinal MRI study. Neurobiol Aging 88:42&#x2013;50</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31918955</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2019.12.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee SE, Sias AC, Kosik EL, Flagan TM, Deng J, Chu SA, Brown JA, Vidovszky AA, Ramos EM, Gorno-Tempini ML, Karydas AM, Coppola G, Geschwind DH, Rademakers R, Boeve BF, Boxer AL, Rosen HJ, Miller BL, Seeley WW (2019) Thalamo-cortical network hyperconnectivity in preclinical progranulin mutation carriers. Neuroimage Clin 22:101751</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30921613</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6438992</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nicl.2019.101751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olm CA, McMillan CT, Irwin DJ, Van Deerlin VM, Cook PA, Gee JC, Grossman M (2018) Longitudinal structural gray matter and white matter MRI changes in presymptomatic progranulin mutation carriers. Neuroimage Clin 19:497&#x2013;506</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29984158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6029561</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nicl.2018.05.017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dopper EG, Rombouts SA, Jiskoot LC, den Heijer T, de Graaf JR, de Koning I, Hammerschlag AR, Seelaar H, Seeley WW, Veer IM, van Buchem MA, Rizzu P, van Swieten JC (2014) Structural and functional brain connectivity in presymptomatic familial frontotemporal dementia. Neurology 83:e19-26</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25002573</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000000583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caroppo P, Habert MO, Durrleman S, Funkiewiez A, Perlbarg V, Hahn V, Bertin H, Gaubert M, Routier A, Hannequin D, Deramecourt V, Pasquier F, Rivaud-Pechoux S, Vercelletto M, Edouart G, Valabregue R, Lejeune P, Didic M, Corvol JC, Benali H, Lehericy S, Dubois B, Colliot O, Brice A, Le Ber I (2015) Lateral temporal lobe: an early imaging marker of the presymptomatic GRN disease? J Alzheimer&#x2019;s Dis JAD 47:751&#x2013;759</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/JAD-150270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Premi E, Cauda F, Costa T, Diano M, Gazzina S, Gualeni V, Alberici A, Archetti S, Magoni M, Gasparotti R, Padovani A, Borroni B (2016) Looking for neuroimaging markers in frontotemporal lobar degeneration clinical trials: a multi-voxel pattern analysis study in granulin disease. J Alzheimer&#x2019;s Dis JAD 51:249&#x2013;262</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/JAD-150340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacova C, Hsiung GY, Tawankanjanachot I, Dinelle K, McCormick S, Gonzalez M, Lee H, Sengdy P, Bouchard-Kerr P, Baker M, Rademakers R, Sossi V, Stoessl AJ, Feldman HH, Mackenzie IR (2013) Anterior brain glucose hypometabolism predates dementia in progranulin mutation carriers. Neurology 81:1322&#x2013;1331</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24005336</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3806924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0b013e3182a8237e</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Premi E, Gazzina S, Bozzali M, Archetti S, Alberici A, Cercignani M, Bianchetti A, Gasparotti R, Turla M, Caltagirone C, Padovani A, Borroni B (2013) Cognitive reserve in granulin-related frontotemporal dementia: from preclinical to clinical stages. PLoS ONE 8:e74762</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24040338</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3767639</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0074762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milanesi E, Bonvicini C, Alberici A, Pilotto A, Cattane N, Premi E, Gazzina S, Archetti S, Gasparotti R, Cancelli V, Gennarelli M, Padovani A, Borroni B (2013) Molecular signature of disease onset in granulin mutation carriers: a gene expression analysis study. Neurobiol Aging 34:1837&#x2013;1845</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23419701</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2012.11.016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Premi E, Cauda F, Gasparotti R, Diano M, Archetti S, Padovani A, Borroni B (2014) Multimodal FMRI resting-state functional connectivity in granulin mutations: the case of fronto-parietal dementia. PLoS ONE 9:e106500</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25188321</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4154688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0106500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borroni B, Alberici A, Cercignani M, Premi E, Serra L, Cerini C, Cosseddu M, Pettenati C, Turla M, Archetti S, Gasparotti R, Caltagirone C, Padovani A, Bozzali M (2012) Granulin mutation drives brain damage and reorganization from preclinical to symptomatic FTLD. Neurobiol Aging 33:2506&#x2013;2520</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22130207</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2011.10.031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pietroboni AM, Fumagalli GG, Ghezzi L, Fenoglio C, Cortini F, Serpente M, Cantoni C, Rotondo E, Corti P, Carecchio M, Bassi M, Bresolin N, Galbiati D, Galimberti D, Scarpini E (2011) Phenotypic heterogeneity of the GRN Asp22fs mutation in a large Italian kindred. J Alzheimer&#x2019;s Dis JAD 24:253&#x2013;259</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/JAD-2011-101704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borroni B, Alberici A, Premi E, Archetti S, Garibotto V, Agosti C, Gasparotti R, Di Luca M, Perani D, Padovani A (2008) Brain magnetic resonance imaging structural changes in a pedigree of asymptomatic progranulin mutation carriers. Rejuvenation Res 11:585&#x2013;595</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18593276</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/rej.2007.0623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu L, Liu J, Feng X, Dong J, Qin W, Liu Y, Wang J, Lu J, Chen K, Wang Y, Jia J (2018) 11C-CFT-PET in presymptomatic FTDP-17: a potential biomarker predicting onset. J Alzheimer&#x2019;s Dis JAD 61:613&#x2013;618</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/JAD-170561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dom&#xed;nguez-Vivero C, Wu L, Lee S, Manoochehri M, Cines S, Brickman AM, Rizvi B, Chesebro A, Gazes Y, Fallon E, Lynch T, Heidebrink JL, Paulson H, Goldman JS, Huey E, Cosentino S (2020) Structural brain changes in pre-clinical FTD MAPT mutation carriers. J Alzheimer&#x2019;s Dis JAD 75:595&#x2013;606</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/JAD-190820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dopper EG, Chalos V, Ghariq E, den Heijer T, Hafkemeijer A, Jiskoot LC, de Koning I, Seelaar H, van Minkelen R, van Osch MJ, Rombouts SA, van Swieten JC (2016) Cerebral blood flow in presymptomatic MAPT and GRN mutation carriers: a longitudinal arterial spin labeling study. Neuroimage Clin 12:460&#x2013;465</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27625986</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5011170</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nicl.2016.08.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Q, Boeve BF, Senjem M, Tosakulwong N, Lesnick TG, Brushaber D, Dheel C, Fields J, Forsberg L, Gavrilova R, Gearhart D, Graff-Radford J, Graff-Radford NR, Jack CR Jr, Jones DT, Knopman DS, Kremers WK, Lapid M, Rademakers R, Syrjanen J, Boxer AL, Rosen H, Wszolek ZK, Kantarci K (2019) Rates of lobar atrophy in asymptomatic MAPT mutation carriers. Alzheimer&#x2019;s Dement (New York, N Y) 5:338&#x2013;346</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.trci.2019.05.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eskildsen SF, &#xd8;stergaard LR, Rodell AB, &#xd8;stergaard L, Nielsen JE, Isaacs AM, Johannsen P (2009) Cortical volumes and atrophy rates in FTD-3 CHMP2B mutation carriers and related non-carriers. Neuroimage 45:713&#x2013;721</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19150504</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuroimage.2008.12.024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rohrer JD, Ahsan RL, Isaacs AM, Nielsen JE, Ostergaard L, Scahill R, Warren JD, Rossor MN, Fox NC, Johannsen P (2009) Presymptomatic generalized brain atrophy in frontotemporal dementia caused by CHMP2B mutation. Dement Geriatr Cogn Disord 27:182&#x2013;186</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19202337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000200466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lunau L, Mouridsen K, Rodell A, Ostergaard L, Nielsen JE, Isaacs A, Johannsen P (2012) Presymptomatic cerebral blood flow changes in CHMP2B mutation carriers of familial frontotemporal dementia (FTD-3), measured with MRI. BMJ Open 2:e000368</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22422914</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3307039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2011-000368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wijeratne PA, Johnson EB, Eshaghi A, Aksman L, Gregory S, Johnson HJ, Poudel GR, Mohan A, Sampaio C, Georgiou-Karistianis N, Paulsen JS, Tabrizi SJ, Scahill RI, Alexander DC (2020) Robust markers and sample sizes for multicenter trials of huntington disease. Ann Neurol 87:751&#x2013;762</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32105364</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7187160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.25709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilkes FA, Abaryan Z, Ching CRK, Gutman BA, Madsen SK, Walterfang M, Velakoulis D, Stout JC, Chua P, Egan GF, Thompson PM, Looi JCL, Georgiou-Karistianis N (2019) Striatal morphology and neurocognitive dysfunction in Huntington disease: The IMAGE-HD study. Psychiatry Res Neuroimaging 291:1&#x2013;8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31330407</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pscychresns.2019.07.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang X, Ross CA, Johnson H, Paulsen JS, Younes L, Albin RL, Ratnanather JT, Miller MI (2019) Regional subcortical shape analysis in premanifest Huntington&#x2019;s disease. Hum Brain Mapp 40:1419&#x2013;1433</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30376191</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hbm.24456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McColgan P, Gregory S, Seunarine KK, Razi A, Papoutsi M, Johnson E, Durr A, Roos RAC, Leavitt BR, Holmans P, Scahill RI, Clark CA, Rees G, Tabrizi SJ (2018) Brain regions showing white matter loss in huntington&#x2019;s disease are enriched for synaptic and metabolic genes. Biol Psychiatry 83:456&#x2013;465</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29174593</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5803509</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biopsych.2017.10.019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castro E, Polosecki P, Rish I, Pustina D, Warner JH, Wood A, Sampaio C, Cecchi GA (2018) Baseline multimodal information predicts future motor impairment in premanifest Huntington&#x2019;s disease. Neuroimage Clin 19:443&#x2013;453</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29984153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6029560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nicl.2018.05.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McColgan P, Gregory S, Razi A, Seunarine KK, Gargouri F, Durr A, Roos RA, Leavitt BR, Scahill RI, Clark CA, Tabrizi SJ, Rees G, Track On HDI, Coleman A, Decolongon J, Fan M, Petkau T, Jauffret C, Justo D, Lehericy S, Nigaud K, Valabregue R, Choonderbeek A, Hart EP, Hensman Moss DJ, Crawford H, Johnson E, Papoutsi M, Berna C, Reilmann R, Weber N, Stout J, Labuschagne I, Landwehrmeyer B, Orth M, Johnson H (2017) White matter predicts functional connectivity in premanifest Huntington&#x2019;s disease. Ann Clin Transl Neurol 4:106&#x2013;118</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28168210</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5288460</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/acn3.384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahveninen LM, Stout JC, Georgiou-Karistianis N, Lorenzetti V, Glikmann-Johnston Y (2018) Reduced amygdala volumes are related to motor and cognitive signs in Huntington&#x2019;s disease: The IMAGE-HD study. Neuroimage Clin 18:881&#x2013;887</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29876272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5988225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nicl.2018.03.027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosas HD, Wilkens P, Salat DH, Mercaldo ND, Vangel M, Yendiki AY, Hersch SM (2018) Complex spatial and temporally defined myelin and axonal degeneration in Huntington disease. Neuroimage Clin 20:236&#x2013;242</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30090698</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6078048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nicl.2018.01.029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lahr J, Minkova L, Tabrizi SJ, Stout JC, Kloppel S, Scheller E (2018) Working memory-related effective connectivity in Huntington&#x2019;s disease patients. Front Neurol 9:370</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29915555</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5994408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fneur.2018.00370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon BA, Blazey TM, Christensen J, Dincer A, Flores S, Keefe S, Chen C, Su Y, McDade EM, Wang G, Li Y, Hassenstab J, Aschenbrenner A, Hornbeck R, Jack CR, Ances BM, Berman SB, Brosch JR, Galasko D, Gauthier S, Lah JJ, Masellis M, van Dyck CH, Mintun MA, Klein G, Ristic S, Cairns NJ, Marcus DS, Xiong C, Holtzman DM, Raichle ME, Morris JC, Bateman RJ, Benzinger TLS (2019) Tau PET in autosomal dominant Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease: relationship with cognition, dementia and other biomarkers. Brain 142:1063&#x2013;1076</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30753379</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6439328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awz019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Preische O, Schultz SA, Apel A, Kuhle J, Kaeser SA, Barro C, Gr&#xe4;ber S, Kuder-Buletta E, LaFougere C, Laske C, V&#xf6;glein J, Levin J, Masters CL, Martins R, Schofield PR, Rossor MN, Graff-Radford NR, Salloway S, Ghetti B, Ringman JM, Noble JM, Chhatwal J, Goate AM, Benzinger TLS, Morris JC, Bateman RJ, Wang G, Fagan AM, McDade EM, Gordon BA, Jucker M (2019) Serum neurofilament dynamics predicts neurodegeneration and clinical progression in presymptomatic Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. Nat Med 25:277&#x2013;283</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30664784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6367005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-018-0304-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon BA, Blazey TM, Su Y, Hari-Raj A, Dincer A, Flores S, Christensen J, McDade E, Wang G, Xiong C, Cairns NJ, Hassenstab J, Marcus DS, Fagan AM, Jack CR Jr, Hornbeck RC, Paumier KL, Ances BM, Berman SB, Brickman AM, Cash DM, Chhatwal JP, Correia S, F&#xf6;rster S, Fox NC, Graff-Radford NR, la Foug&#xe8;re C, Levin J, Masters CL, Rossor MN, Salloway S, Saykin AJ, Schofield PR, Thompson PM, Weiner MM, Holtzman DM, Raichle ME, Morris JC, Bateman RJ, Benzinger TLS (2018) Spatial patterns of neuroimaging biomarker change in individuals from families with autosomal dominant Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease: a longitudinal study. Lancet Neurol 17:241&#x2013;250</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29397305</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5816717</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1474-4422(18)30028-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kinnunen KM, Cash DM, Poole T, Frost C, Benzinger TLS, Ahsan RL, Leung KK, Cardoso MJ, Modat M, Malone IB, Morris JC, Bateman RJ, Marcus DS, Goate A, Salloway SP, Correia S, Sperling RA, Chhatwal JP, Mayeux RP, Brickman AM, Martins RN, Farlow MR, Ghetti B, Saykin AJ, Jack CR Jr, Schofield PR, McDade E, Weiner MW, Ringman JM, Thompson PM, Masters CL, Rowe CC, Rossor MN, Ourselin S, Fox NC (2018) Presymptomatic atrophy in autosomal dominant Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease: a serial magnetic resonance imaging study. Alzheimer&#x2019;s Dement J Alzheimer&#x2019;s Assoc 14:43&#x2013;53</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jalz.2017.06.2268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee S, Zimmerman ME, Narkhede A, Nasrabady SE, Tosto G, Meier IB, Benzinger TLS, Marcus DS, Fagan AM, Fox NC, Cairns NJ, Holtzman DM, Buckles V, Ghetti B, McDade E, Martins RN, Saykin AJ, Masters CL, Ringman JM, F&#x4e7;rster S, Schofield PR, Sperling RA, Johnson KA, Chhatwal JP, Salloway S, Correia S, Jack CR Jr, Weiner M, Bateman RJ, Morris JC, Mayeux R, Brickman AM (2018) White matter hyperintensities and the mediating role of cerebral amyloid angiopathy in dominantly-inherited Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. PLoS ONE 13:e0195838</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29742105</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5942789</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0195838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sala-Llonch R, Falg&#xe0;s N, Bosch B, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Villullas G, Balasa M, Antonell A, Perissinotti A, Pav&#xed;a J, Campos F, Llad&#xf3; A, Lome&#xf1;a F, S&#xe1;nchez-Valle R (2019) Regional patterns of 18F-florbetaben uptake in presenilin 1 mutation carriers. Neurobiol Aging 81:1&#x2013;8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31207465</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2019.04.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan NS, Keihaninejad S, Shakespeare TJ, Lehmann M, Crutch SJ, Malone IB, Thornton JS, Mancini L, Hyare H, Yousry T, Ridgway GR, Zhang H, Modat M, Alexander DC, Rossor MN, Ourselin S, Fox NC (2013) Magnetic resonance imaging evidence for presymptomatic change in thalamus and caudate in familial Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. Brain 136:1399&#x2013;1414</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23539189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3634199</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awt065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dean DC 3rd, Hurley SA, Kecskemeti SR, O&#x2019;Grady JP, Canda C, Davenport-Sis NJ, Carlsson CM, Zetterberg H, Blennow K, Asthana S, Sager MA, Johnson SC, Alexander AL, Bendlin BB (2017) Association of amyloid pathology with myelin alteration in preclinical Alzheimer disease. JAMA Neurol 74:41&#x2013;49</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27842175</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5195903</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamaneurol.2016.3232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donix M, Burggren AC, Suthana NA, Siddarth P, Ekstrom AD, Krupa AK, Jones M, Martin-Harris L, Ercoli LM, Miller KJ, Small GW, Bookheimer SY (2010) Family history of Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease and hippocampal structure in healthy people. Am J Psychiatry 167:1399&#x2013;1406</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20686185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3086166</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1176/appi.ajp.2010.09111575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verfaillie SCJ, Pichet Binette A, Vachon-Presseau E, Tabrizi S, Savard M, Bellec P, Ossenkoppele R, Scheltens P, van der Flier WM, Breitner JCS, Villeneuve S (2018) Subjective cognitive decline is associated with altered default mode network connectivity in individuals with a family history of Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. Biol Psychiatry Cogn Neurosci Neuroimaging 3:463&#x2013;472</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29735156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu SY, Wile DJ, Fu JF, Valerio J, Shahinfard E, McCormick S, Mabrouk R, Vafai N, McKenzie J, Neilson N, Perez-Soriano A, Arena JE, Cherkasova M, Chan P, Zhang J, Zabetian CP, Aasly JO, Wszolek ZK, McKeown MJ, Adam MJ, Ruth TJ, Schulzer M, Sossi V, Stoessl AJ (2018) The effect of LRRK2 mutations on the cholinergic system in manifest and premanifest stages of Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: a cross-sectional PET study. Lancet Neurol 17:309&#x2013;316</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29456161</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5942215</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1474-4422(18)30032-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vilas D, Segura B, Baggio HC, Pont-Sunyer C, Compta Y, Valldeoriola F, Jos&#xe9; Mart&#xed; M, Quintana M, Bay&#xe9;s A, Hern&#xe1;ndez-Vara J, Calopa M, Aguilar M, Junqu&#xe9; C, Tolosa E (2016) Nigral and striatal connectivity alterations in asymptomatic LRRK2 mutation carriers: a magnetic resonance imaging study. Mov Disord 31:1820&#x2013;1828</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27653520</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mds.26799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helmich RC, Thaler A, van Nuenen BF, Gurevich T, Mirelman A, Marder KS, Bressman S, Orr-Urtreger A, Giladi N, Bloem BR, Toni I (2015) Reorganization of corticostriatal circuits in healthy G2019S LRRK2 carriers. Neurology 84:399&#x2013;406</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25540317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4336002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000001189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pyatigorskaya N, Sharman M, Corvol JC, Valabregue R, Yahia-Cherif L, Poupon F, Cormier-Dequaire F, Siebner H, Klebe S, Vidailhet M, Brice A, Leh&#xe9;ricy S (2015) High nigral iron deposition in LRRK2 and Parkin mutation carriers using R2* relaxometry. Mov Disord 30:1077&#x2013;1084</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26011561</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mds.26218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thaler A, Artzi M, Mirelman A, Jacob Y, Helmich RC, van Nuenen BF, Gurevich T, Orr-Urtreger A, Marder K, Bressman S, Bloem BR, Hendler T, Giladi N, Ben Bashat D (2014) A voxel-based morphometry and diffusion tensor imaging analysis of asymptomatic Parkinson&#x2019;s disease-related G2019S LRRK2 mutation carriers. Mov Disord 29:823&#x2013;827</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24482120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mds.25827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thaler A, Mirelman A, Helmich RC, van Nuenen BF, Rosenberg-Katz K, Gurevich T, Orr-Urtreger A, Marder K, Bressman S, Bloem BR, Giladi N, Hendler T (2013) Neural correlates of executive functions in healthy G2019S LRRK2 mutation carriers. Cortex 49:2501&#x2013;2511</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23357204</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cortex.2012.12.017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brockmann K, Gr&#xf6;ger A, Di Santo A, Liepelt I, Schulte C, Klose U, Maetzler W, Hauser AK, Hilker R, Gomez-Mancilla B, Berg D, Gasser T (2011) Clinical and brain imaging characteristics in leucine-rich repeat kinase 2-associated PD and asymptomatic mutation carriers. Mov Disord 26:2335&#x2013;2342</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21989859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mds.23991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reetz K, Tadic V, Kasten M, Br&#xfc;ggemann N, Schmidt A, Hagenah J, Pramstaller PP, Ramirez A, Behrens MI, Siebner HR, Klein C, Binkofski F (2010) Structural imaging in the presymptomatic stage of genetically determined parkinsonism. Neurobiol Dis 39:402&#x2013;408</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20483373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nbd.2010.05.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anders S, Sack B, Pohl A, M&#xfc;nte T, Pramstaller P, Klein C, Binkofski F (2012) Compensatory premotor activity during affective face processing in subclinical carriers of a single mutant Parkin allele. Brain 135:1128&#x2013;1140</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22434215</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3326258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/aws040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buhmann C, Binkofski F, Klein C, B&#xfc;chel C, van Eimeren T, Erdmann C, Hedrich K, Kasten M, Hagenah J, Deuschl G, Pramstaller PP, Siebner HR (2005) Motor reorganization in asymptomatic carriers of a single mutant Parkin allele: a human model for presymptomatic parkinsonism. Brain 128:2281&#x2013;2290</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15947065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awh572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szamosi A, Nagy H, K&#xe9;ri S (2013) Delay discounting of reward and caudate nucleus volume in individuals with &#x3b1;-synuclein gene duplication before and after the development of Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Neurodegener Dis 11:72&#x2013;78</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23038403</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000341997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bede P, Siah WF, McKenna MC, Li Hi Shing S (2020) Consideration of C9orf72-associated ALS-FTD as a neurodevelopmental disorder: insights from neuroimaging. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 91(11):1138</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32855286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp-2020-324416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finegan E, Chipika RH, Li Hi Shing S, Doherty MA, Hengeveld JC, Vajda A, Donaghy C, McLaughlin RL, Pender N, Hardiman O, Bede P (2019) The clinical and radiological profile of primary lateral sclerosis: a population-based study. J Neurol 266:2718&#x2013;2733</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31325016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00415-019-09473-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finegan E, Li Hi Shing S, Siah WF, Chipika RH, Chang KM, McKenna MC, Doherty MA, Hengeveld JC, Vajda A, Donaghy C, Hutchinson S, McLaughlin RL, Hardiman O, Bede P (2020) Evolving diagnostic criteria in primary lateral sclerosis: the clinical and radiological basis of &#x201c;probable PLS.&#x201d; J Neurol Sci 417:117052</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32731060</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jns.2020.117052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Querin G, El Mendili MM, Lenglet T, Behin A, Stojkovic T, Salachas F, Devos D, Le Forestier N, Del Mar AM, Debs R, Lacomblez L, Meninger V, Bruneteau G, Cohen-Adad J, Lehericy S, Laforet P, Blancho S, Benali H, Catala M, Li M, Marchand-Pauvert V, Hogrel JY, Bede P, Pradat PF (2019) The spinal and cerebral profile of adult spinal-muscular atrophy: a multimodal imaging study. NeuroImage Clinical 21:101618</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30522974</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nicl.2018.101618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark MG, Smallwood Shoukry R, Huang CJ, Danielian LE, Bageac D, Floeter MK (2018) Loss of functional connectivity is an early imaging marker in primary lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Front Degener 19:562&#x2013;569</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/21678421.2018.1517180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuster C, Elamin M, Hardiman O, Bede P (2015) Presymptomatic and longitudinal neuroimaging in neurodegeneration&#x2013;from snapshots to motion picture: a systematic review. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 86:1089&#x2013;1096</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25632156</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp-2014-309888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuster C, Hardiman O, Bede P (2017) Survival prediction in Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis based on MRI measures and clinical characteristics. BMC Neurol 17:73</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28412941</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5393027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12883-017-0854-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westeneng HJ, Debray TPA, Visser AE, van Eijk RPA, Rooney JPK, Calvo A, Martin S, McDermott CJ, Thompson AG, Pinto S, Kobeleva X, Rosenbohm A, Stubendorff B, Sommer H, Middelkoop BM, Dekker AM, van Vugt J, van Rheenen W, Vajda A, Heverin M, Kazoka M, Hollinger H, Gromicho M, Korner S, Ringer TM, Rodiger A, Gunkel A, Shaw CE, Bredenoord AL, van Es MA, Corcia P, Couratier P, Weber M, Grosskreutz J, Ludolph AC, Petri S, de Carvalho M, Van Damme P, Talbot K, Turner MR, Shaw PJ, Al-Chalabi A, Chio A, Hardiman O, Moons KGM, Veldink JH, van den Berg LH (2018) Prognosis for patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: development and validation of a personalised prediction model. Lancet Neurol 17:423</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29598923</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1474-4422(18)30089-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grollemund V, Chat GL, Secchi-Buhour MS, Delbot F, Pradat-Peyre JF, Bede P, Pradat PF (2020) Development and validation of a 1-year survival prognosis estimation model for Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis using manifold learning algorithm UMAP. Sci Rep 10:13378</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32770027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7414917</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-020-70125-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grollemund V, Pradat PF, Querin G, Delbot F, Le Chat G, Pradat-Peyre JF, Bede P (2019) Machine learning in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: achievements, pitfalls, and future directions. Front Neurosci 13:135</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30872992</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6403867</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnins.2019.00135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El Mendili MM, Querin G, Bede P, Pradat PF (2019) Spinal cord imaging in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: historical concepts-novel techniques. Front Neurol 10:350</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31031688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6474186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fneur.2019.00350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Querin G, El Mendili MM, Bede P, Delphine S, Lenglet T, Marchand-Pauvert V, Pradat PF (2018) Multimodal spinal cord MRI offers accurate diagnostic classification in ALS. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 89:1220&#x2013;1221</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29353238</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp-2017-317214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuster C, Hardiman O, Bede P (2016) Development of an automated mri-based diagnostic protocol for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis using disease-specific pathognomonic features: a quantitative disease-state classification study. PLoS ONE 11:e0167331</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27907080</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5132189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0167331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bede P, Iyer PM, Finegan E, Omer T, Hardiman O (2017) Virtual brain biopsies in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: diagnostic classification based on in vivo pathological patterns. NeuroImage Clin 15:653&#x2013;658</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28664036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5479963</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nicl.2017.06.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chipika RH, Finegan E, Li Hi Shing S, Hardiman O, Bede P (2019) Tracking a fast-moving disease: longitudinal markers, monitoring, and clinical trial endpoints in ALS. Front Neurol 10:229</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30941088</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6433752</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fneur.2019.00229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>