<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">33141927</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>31</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1600-0404</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>143</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>May</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Acta neurologica Scandinavica</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Acta Neurol Scand</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>End-of-life care in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A comparative registry study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>481</StartPage><EndPage>488</EndPage><MedlinePgn>481-488</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/ane.13370</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) is a fatal disease requiring palliative care. End-of-life care has been well studied in patients with incurable cancer, but less is known about the quality of such care for patients with ALS.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="AIM" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To study whether the quality of end-of-life care the last week in life for patients dying from ALS differed compared to patients with cancer in terms of registered symptoms, symptom management, and communication.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DESIGN" NlmCategory="METHODS">This retrospective comparative registry study used data from the Swedish Registry of Palliative Care for 2012-2016. Each patient with ALS (n&#xa0;=&#xa0;825) was matched to 4 patients with cancer (n&#xa0;=&#xa0;3,300).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Between-group differences in assessments for pain and other symptoms were significant (p&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;0.01), and patients with ALS had fewer as-needed injection drugs prescribed than patients with cancer. Patients with ALS also had dyspnea and anxiety significantly more often than patients with cancer. There was no significant difference in communication about transition to end-of-life care between the two groups. Patients dying from ALS received artificial nutrition on their last day of life significantly more often than patients with cancer.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The results indicate that patients with ALS receive poorer end-of-life care than patients dying from cancer in terms of validated symptom assessments, prescription of as-needed drugs, and timely cessation of artificial nutrition. Educational efforts seem needed to facilitate equal care of dying patients, regardless of diagnosis.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020 John Wiley &amp; Sons A/S. Published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Eljas Ahlberg</LastName><ForeName>Eva</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0388-5521</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgery, &#xd6;stersund Hospital, &#xd6;stersund, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Axelsson</LastName><ForeName>Bertil</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4951-980X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Unit of Clinical Research Centre &#xd6;stersund, Ume&#xe5; University, Ume&#xe5;, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D003160">Comparative Study</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Denmark</Country><MedlineTA>Acta Neurol Scand</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0370336</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0001-6314</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009369" MajorTopicYN="N">Neoplasms</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010166" MajorTopicYN="N">Palliative Care</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012042" MajorTopicYN="N">Registries</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013548" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Sweden</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013727" MajorTopicYN="N">Terminal Care</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">palliative care</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">quality indicators</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">terminal care</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33141927</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ane.13370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Foster LA, Salajeghej MK. Motor neuron disease: pathophysiology, diagnosis, and management. Am J Med. 2019;132(1):32-37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen PM, Abrahams S, Borasio GD, de Carvalho M, Chio A, Van Damme P. EFNS guidelines on the clinical management of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (MALS)-revised report of an EFNS task force. Eur J Neurol. 2012;19(3):360-375.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliver DJ. Palliative care for patients with motor neuron disease: current challenges. Degener Neurolo Neuromuscul Dis. 2016;6:65-72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hogden A, Foley G, Henderson RD, James N, Aoun SM. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: improving care with a multidisciplinary approach. J Multidiscip Healthc. 2017;10:205-215.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng HWB, Chan KY, Chung YKJ, et al. Supportive &amp; palliative interventions in motor neuron disease: what we know from current literature? Ann Palliat Med. 2018;7(3):320-331.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ng L, Khan F, Young CA, Galea M. Symptomatic treatments for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis/motor neuron disease. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2017;1:CD011776.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ng L, Khan F. Multidisciplinary care for adults with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis or motor neuron disease. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2009;4:CD007425.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin S, Trevor-Jones E, Khan S, et al. The benefit of evolving multidisciplinary care in ALS: a diagnostic cohort survival comparison. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2017;18:569-575.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van den Berg JP, Kalmijn S, Lindeman E, et al. Multidisciplinary ALS care improves quality of life in patients with ALS. Neurology. 2005;65:1264-1267.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borasio GD. The role of palliative care in patients with neurological disease. Nat Rev Neurol. 2013;9:292-295.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borasio GD, Volts R. Palliative care in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurology. 1997;244(Suppl 4):S11-S17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliver DJ. The quality and care of symptom control-the effects on the terminal phase of ALS/MND. J Neurol Sci. 1996;139(suppl):134-136.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliver DJ, Borasio GD, Caraceni A, et al. A concensus review on the development of palliative care for patients with chronic and progressive neurological disease. Eur J Neurol. 2016;23:30-38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozanne A, Sawatsky R, H&#xe5;kansson C, et al. Symptom relief during last week of life in neurological diseases. Brain Behav. 2019;9:e01348.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Connolly S, Galvin M, Hardiman O. End-of-life management in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet Neurol. 2015;14:435-442.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neudert C, Oliver D, Wasner M, Borasio GD. The course of the terminal phase in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol. 2001;248:612-616.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng HWB, Chan OMI, Chan CHR, Chan WH, Fung KS, Wong KY. End-of-life characteristics and palliative care provision for patients with motor neuron disease. Am J Hosp Palliat Care. 2018;35(6):847-851.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bentley B, O&#x2019;Connor M. The end-of life experiences of people with motor neuron disease: family carers&#x2019; perspectives. J Palliat Med. 2016;19(8):857-862.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chochinov HM, Johnston W, McClement SE, et al. Dignity and distress towards the end of life across four non-cancer populations. PLoS One. 2016;25:1-13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rudnicki S, McVey AL, Jackson CE, Dimachkie MM, Barohn RJ. Symptom management and end of life care. Neurol Clin. 2015;33:889-908.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karam CHY, Paganoni S, Joyce N, Carter GT, Bedlack R. Palliative care issues in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: an evidenced-based review. Am J Hosp Palliat Med. 2016;33:84-92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burkhardt C, Neuwirth C, Sommacal A, Andersen PM, Weber M. Is survival improved by the use of NIV and PEG in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS)? A post-mortem study of 80 patients. PLoS One. 2017;12:e0177555.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tiirola A, Korhonen T, Suurakka T, Lehto JT. End-of-life care of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and other nonmalignant disease. Am J Hosp Palliat Med. 2017;34:154-159.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Br&#xe4;nnstr&#xf6;m M, H&#xe4;gglund L, Furst CJ, Boman K. Unequal care for dying patients in Sweden. A comparative registry study of deaths from heart disease and cancer. Eur J Cardiovasc Nurs. 2012;11:454-459.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eriksson H, Milberg A, Hjelm K, Friedrichsen M. End of life care for patients dying from stroke. A comparative registry study of stroke and cancer. PLoS One. 2016;11:e0147694.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martinsson L, Lundstr&#xf6;m S, Sundel&#xf6;f J. Quality of end-of-life care in patients with dementia compared to patients with cancer: a population-based registry study. PLoS One. 2018;13(7):e0201051. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0201051</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lundstr&#xf6;m S, Axelsson B, Heedman P-A, Fransson G, F&#xfc;rst C-J. Developing a national quality register in end-of-life care: the Swedish experience. Palliat Med. 2012;26:313-321.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martinsson L, Heedman P-A, Lundstr&#xf6;m S, Fransson G, Axelsson B. Validation study of an end-of-life questionnaire from the Swedish Register of Palliative Care. Acta Oncol. 2011;50:642-647.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martinsson L, Heedman P-A, Lundstr&#xf6;m S, Axelsson B. Improved data validity in the Swedish Register of Palliative Care. PLoS One. 2017;12(10):e0186804.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Socialstyrelsen [National Board of Health and Welfare]. Nationella riktlinjer-Palliativ v&#xe5;rd i livets slutskede-M&#xe5;lniv&#xe5;er f&#xf6;r indikatorer [National guidelines-palliative end-of-life care-goal levels for indicators]. Stockholm: Socialstyrelsen; 2017. Swedish.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National institute for Health and Care Excellence. NICE Guidance on Motor Neurone disease; 2016. NICE. www.nice.org.nk/NG42. Accessed February 24, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Regionala cancercentrum i samverkan [Regional Cancer Centre in Collaboration]. Nationellt v&#xe5;rdprogram palliativ v&#xe5;rd i livets slutskede [National guidelines palliative end-of-life care]. Regionala cancercentrum i samverkan; 2016. Swedish.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fritzon A, Tavelin B, Axelsson B. Association between parenteral fluids and symptoms in hospital end-of-life care: an observational study of 280 patients. BMJ Support Palliat Care. 2013;5(2):160-168.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ganzini L, Johnston WS, Silviera MJ. The final month of life in patients with ALS. Neurology. 2002;59:428-431.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishida N, Hongo S, Kumano A, et al. Relationship between pain and functional status in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a multicenter cross-sectional study. J Palliat Med. 2018;21(5):588-591.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopes LCG, Galhardoni R, Silva V, et al. Beyond weakness: characterization of pain, sensory profile and conditioned pain modulation in patients with motor neuron disease: a controlled study. Eur J Pain. 2018;22:72-83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pizzimenti A, Aragona M, Onesti E, Inghilleri M. Depression, pain and quality of life in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a cross-sectional study. Funct Neurol. 2013;28:115-119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanisch F, Skudlarek A, Berndt J, Kornhuber ME. Characteristics of pain in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain Behav. 2015;5:e00296.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stephens HE, Lehman E, Raheja D, et al. Pain in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: patient and physician perspectives and practices. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2016;17:21-29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rivera I, Ajroud-Driss S, Casey P, et al. Prevalence and characteristics of pain in early and late stages of ALS. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2013;14:369-372.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsai C-P, Chang B-H, Lee CT-C. Underlying cause and place of death among patients with amytrophic lateral sclerosis in Taiwan: a population-based study, 2003-2008. J Epidemiol. 2013;23(6):424-428.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spataro R, Lo Re M, Piccoli F, La Bella V. Causes and places of death in Italian patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurologica. 2010;122:217-223.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang R, Huang R, Chen D, et al. Causes and places of death of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in Southwest China. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2011;12(3):206-209.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dom&#xed;nguez-berj&#xf3;n MF, Esteban-Vasallo MD, Zoni AC, G&#xe8;nova-Maleras R, Astray-Mochales J. Place of death and associated factors among patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in Madrid (Spain). Amyotrophic Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2016;17:62-68.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>