<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">33151660</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1537-1603</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>37</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of clinical neurophysiology : official publication of the American Electroencephalographic Society</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Clin Neurophysiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Electrodiagnosis of Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis: A Review of Existing Guidelines.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>294</StartPage><EndPage>298</EndPage><MedlinePgn>294-298</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/WNP.0000000000000682</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) is characterized by degeneration of upper motor neurons in the motor cortex and lower motor neurons (LMN) in the brainstem and spinal cord, resulting in a progressive functional impairment. Neurophysiology is a diagnostic tool to detect dysfunction of upper motor neurons and LMN, even when the changes are subclinical. Electromyography is the standard neurophysiological investigation to detect LMN changes, which is essential to exclude mimicking disorders and attain early diagnosis. Recently, Awaji criteria was proposed to support ALS diagnosis, in these criteria fasciculation potentials associated with neurogenic motor unit potentials represents a sufficient marker of LMN involvement, in each muscle. Many studies have confirmed that Awaji criteria are more sensitive, permitting earlier diagnosis without loss of specificity when compared with the revised El Escorial criteria. Fasciculations are easily detected by ultrasound; increasingly, this technique has been used to diagnose ALS, combined with electromyography. This combination can increase diagnostic accuracy. Many techniques for estimating the number of motor units have been proposed, they are useful to quantify LMN loss. Electrical impedance myography is an emerging technique with great potential to monitor ALS progression. Neurophysiological investigation of upper motor neuron dysfunction is difficult in ALS, detecting decreased cortical inhibition by threshold tracking cortical magnetic stimulation is a promising method, which needs to be validated in different centers.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>de Carvalho</LastName><ForeName>Mamede</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Instituto de Fisiologia, Instituto de Medicina Molecular, Faculdade de Medicina, Universidade de Lisboa, Lisbon, Portugal; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosciences and Mental Health, Hospital de Santa Maria, Centro Hospitalar Universit&#xe1;rio de Lisboa Norte, Lisbon, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Clin Neurophysiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8506708</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0736-0258</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="Y">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004568" MajorTopicYN="N">Electrodiagnosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009482" MajorTopicYN="N">Neurophysiology</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017410" MajorTopicYN="Y">Practice Guidelines as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33151660</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/WNP.0000000000000682</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00004691-202007000-00004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR. El Escorial World Federation of Neurology criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Sci 1994;124:96&#x2013;107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, Miller RG, Swash M, Munsat TL. El Escorial revisited: revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Mot Neuron Disord 2000;1:293&#x2013;299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Dengler R, Eisen A, et al. Electrodiagnostic criteria for diagnosis of ALS. Clin Neurophysiol 2008;119:497&#x2013;503.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swash M. Why are upper motor neuron signs difficult to elicit in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis? J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2012;83:659&#x2013;662.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ince PG, Evans J, Knopp M, et al. Corticospinal tract degeneration in the progressive muscular atrophy variant of ALS. Neurology 2003;60:1252&#x2013;1258.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lambert EH, Mulder DW. Electromyographic studies in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Mayo Clinic 1957;32:441&#x2013;446.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Asseldonk JT, Franssen H, Van den Berg-Vos RM, Wokke JH, Van den Berg LH. Multifocal motor neuropathy. Lancet Neurol 2005;4:309&#x2013;319.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bentes C, Santos-Bento M, de S&#xe1; J, de Lurdes Sales Lu&#xed;s M, de Carvalho M. Allgrove syndrome in adulthood. Muscle Nerve 2001;24:292&#x2013;296.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carvalho MD, Scotto M, Lopes A, Swash M. F-waves and the corticospinal lesion in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Mot Neuron Disord 2002;3:131&#x2013;136.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pugdahl K, Fuglsang-Frederiksen A, de Carvalho M, et al. Generalised sensory system abnormalities in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a European multicentre study. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2007;78:746&#x2013;749.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pugdahl K, Fuglsang-Frederiksen A, Johnsen B, et al. A prospective multicentre study on sural nerve action potentials in ALS. Clin Neurophysiol 2008;119:1106&#x2013;1110.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cappellari A, Brioschi A, Barbieri S, Braga M, Scarlato G, Silani V. A tentative interpretation of electromyographic regional differences in bulbar- and limb-onset ALS. Neurology 1999;52:644&#x2013;646.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J, Petajan J, Smith G, Bromberg M. Electromyography of sternocleidomastoid muscle in ALS: a prospective study. Muscle Nerve 2002;25:725&#x2013;728.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Bentes C, Evangelista T, ML Sales Luis M. Fibrillation and sharp-waves: do we need them to diagnose ALS? Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Mot Neuron Disord 2000;1:29&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trojaborg W, Buchthal F. Malignant and benign fasciculations. Acta Neurol Scand Suppl 1965;13 pt 1:251&#x2013;254.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Swash M. Conventional clinical neurophysiology in ALS. In: Brown R, Pasinelli P, Swash M, Martin D, eds. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and related disorders. Hampsshire: Taylor &amp; Francis, 2006; 105&#x2013;124.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa J, Swash M, de Carvalho M. Awaji criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a systematic review. Arch Neurol 2012;69:1410&#x2013;1416.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jang JS, Bae JS. AWAJI criteria are not always superior to the previous criteria: a meta-analysis. Muscle Nerve 2015;51:822&#x2013;829.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geevasinga N, Loy CT, Menon P, et al. Awaji criteria improves the diagnostic sensitivity in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a systematic review using individual patient data. Clin Neurophysiol 2016;127:2684&#x2013;2691.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geevasinga N, Howells J, Menon P, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis diagnostic index: toward a personalized diagnosis of ALS. Neurology 2019;92:536&#x2013;547.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnsen B, Pugdahl K, Fuglsang-Frederiksen A, et al. Diagnostic criteria for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a multicentre study of inter-rater variation and sensitivity. Clin Neurophysiol 2019;130:307&#x2013;314.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walker FO, Donofrio PD, Harpold GJ, Ferrell WG. Sonographic imaging of muscle contraction and fasciculations: a correlation with electromyography. Muscle Nerve 1990;13:33&#x2013;39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reimers CD, Ziemann U, Scheel A, Rieckmann P, Kinkel M, Kurth C. Fasciculations: clinical, electromyographic, and ultrasonographic assessment. J Neurol 1996;243:579&#x2013;584.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Misawa S, Noto Y, Shibuya K, et al. Ultrasonographic detection of fasciculations markedly increases diagnostic sensitivity of ALS. Neurology 2011;77:1532&#x2013;1537.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arts IMP, Overeem S, Pillen S, et al. Muscle ultrasonography: a diagnostic tool for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Neurophysiol 2012;123:1662&#x2013;1667.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johansson MT, Ellegaard HR, Tankisi H, Fuglsang-Frederiksen A, Qerama E. Fasciculations in nerve and muscle disorders&#x2014;a prospective study of muscle ultrasound compared to electromyography. Clin Neurophysiol 2017;128:2250&#x2013;2257.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grimm A, Prell T, Decard B, Schumacher U, Witte OW, Axer H. Muscle ultrasonography as an additional diagnostic tool for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Neurophysiol 2015;126:820&#x2013;827.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Swash M. Fasciculation potentials and earliest changes in motor unit physiology in ALS. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2013;84:963&#x2013;968.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Barkhaus PE, Nandedkar SD, Swash M. Motor unit number estimation (MUNE): where are we now? Clin Neurophysiol 2018;129:1507&#x2013;1516.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neuwirth C, Burkhardt C, Alix J, et al. Quality control of Motor Unit Number Index (MUNIX) measurements in 6 muscles in a single-subject &#x201c;round-robin&#x201d; setup. PloS one 2016;11:e0153948.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobsen AB, Bostock H, Fuglsang-Frederiksen A, et al. Reproducibility, and sensitivity to motor unit loss in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, of a novel MUNE method: MScanFit MUNE. Clin Neurophysiol 2017;128:1380&#x2013;1388.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swash M, de Carvalho M. The neurophysiological index in ALS. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Mot Neuron Disord 2004;5(suppl 1):108&#x2013;110.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Pinto S, Costa J, Evangelista T, Ohana B, Pinto A. A randomized, placebo-controlled trial of memantine for functional disability in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler 2010;11:456&#x2013;460.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao B, Wei Q, Ou R, et al. Neurophysiological index is associated with the survival of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Neurophysiol 2019;130:1730&#x2013;1733.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rutkove SB. Electrical impedance myography: background, current state, and future directions. Muscle Nerve 2009;40:936&#x2013;946.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rutkove SB, Caress JB, Cartwright MS, et al. Electrical impedance myography correlates with standard measures of ALS severity. Muscle Nerve 2014;49:441&#x2013;443.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eisen AA, Shtybel W. AAEM minimonograph# 35: clinical experience with transcranial magnetic stimulation. Muscle Nerve 1990;13:995&#x2013;1011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Triggs WJ, Menkes D, Onorato J, et al. Transcranial magnetic stimulation identifies upper motor neuron involvement in motor neuron disease. Neurology 1999;53:605&#x2013;611.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Turkman A, Swash M. Motor responses evoked by transcranial magnetic stimulation and peripheral nerve stimulation in the ulnar innervation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: the effect of upper and lower motor neuron lesion. J Neuro Sci 2003;210:83&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhai P, Pagan F, Statland J, Butman JA, Floeter MK. Primary lateral sclerosis: a heterogeneous disorder composed of different subtypes? Neurology 2003;60:1258&#x2013;1265.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prout AJ, Eisen AA. The cortical silent period and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve 1994;7:217&#x2013;223.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Swash M. Sensitivity of electrophysiological tests for upper and lower motor neuron dysfunction in ALS: a six-month longitudinal study. Muscle Nerve 2010;41:208&#x2013;211.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magistris MR, R&#xf6;sler KM, Truffert A, Landis T, Hess CW. A clinical study of motor evoked potentials using a triple stimulation technique. Brain 1999;122(pt 2):265&#x2013;279.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S, van den Bos M, Menon P, Howells J, Dharmadasa T, Kiernan MC. Utility of threshold tracking transcranial magnetic stimulation in ALS. Clin Neurophysiol Pract 2018;3:164&#x2013;172.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S, Howells J, Trevillion L, Kiernan MC. Assessment of cortical excitability using threshold tracking techniques. Muscle Nerve 2006;33:477&#x2013;486.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menon P, Geevasinga N, Yiannikas C, Howells J, Kiernan M, Vucic S. The sensitivity and specificity of threshold-tracking transcranial magnetic stimulation for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a prospective study. Lancet Neurol 2015;14:478&#x2013;484.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S, Lin CS, Cheah BC, et al. Riluzole exerts central and peripheral modulating effects in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain 2013;136:1361&#x2013;1370.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samusyte G, Bostock H, Rothwell J, Koltzenburg M. Short-interval intracortical inhibition: comparison between conventional and threshold-tracking techniques. Brain Stim 2018;11:806&#x2013;817.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>