<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">33167079</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1552-6569</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>30</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of neuroimaging : official journal of the American Society of Neuroimaging</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Neuroimaging</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Ultrasound Detection of Vagus Nerve Atrophy in Bulbar Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>762</StartPage><EndPage>765</EndPage><MedlinePgn>762-765</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/jon.12761</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND PURPOSE">Neuromuscular ultrasound in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) is of increasing interest. As bulbar symptoms are commonly developed by most ALS patients during disease, the aim of our study was to find possible sonographic changes of vagus nerve size in bulbar affected ALS patients.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">We investigated 24 ALS patients and 19 controls without neuromuscular disorders. In ALS patients, bulbar affection was documented clinically (eg, dysarthria, dysphagia, and fasciculations) or subclinically using ultrasound and electromyography of bulbar muscles. Vagus nerve ultrasound was performed in all participants bilaterally at the level of the thyroid gland.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">The cross-sectional area (CSA) of the vagus nerve in bulbar affected ALS patients (mean CSA right/left 1.9 &#xb1; .7 mm&#xb2;/1.8 &#xb1; .6 mm&#xb2;) was significantly reduced on both sides compared to controls (mean CSA right/left 2.2 &#xb1; .6 mm&#xb2;/2.0 &#xb1; .3 mm&#xb2;) - right: P = .0387, left: P = .0386. Receiver operating characteristic curve analysis of the vagus nerve CSA yielded a sensitivity of 66.7% and a specificity of 63.2% (cutoff value 1.85 mm&#xb2;). Vagus nerve CSA did not correlate significantly with age in controls (right: P = .45, left: P = .66). In controls and ALS patients, there was no significant difference of vagus nerve CSA between the right and left sides (controls: P = .43; patients: P = .86).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">Our study demonstrates vagus nerve atrophy in bulbar affected ALS patients. Further studies are warranted investigating the relevance of our finding for monitoring disease progression in ALS.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020 The Authors. Journal of Neuroimaging published by Wiley Periodicals LLC on behalf of American Society of Neuroimaging.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Holzapfel</LastName><ForeName>Korbinian</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6293-7032</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology and Clinical Neurophysiology, University of Augsburg, Augsburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Naumann</LastName><ForeName>Markus</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology and Clinical Neurophysiology, University of Augsburg, Augsburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Neuroimaging</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9102705</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1051-2284</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="Y">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001284" MajorTopicYN="N">Atrophy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="Y">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018450" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Progression</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014463" MajorTopicYN="N">Ultrasonography</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014630" MajorTopicYN="N">Vagus Nerve</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="Y">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neuromuscular ultrasound</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">vagus nerve</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33167079</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jon.12761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Pan H, Jian F, Lin J, et&#xa0;al. Needle electromyography of the frontalis muscle in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve 2016;54:1093-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johansson MT, Ellegaard HR, Tankisi H, et&#xa0;al. Fasciculations in nerve and muscle disorders - a prospective study of muscle ultrasound compared to electromyography. Clin Neurophysiol 2017;128:2250-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Gorman CM, Weikamp JG, Baria M, et&#xa0;al. Detecting fasciculations in cranial nerve innervated muscles with ultrasound in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve 2017;56:1072-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grimm A, Decard BF, Athanasopoulou I, et&#xa0;al. Nerve ultrasound for differentiation between amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and multifocal motor neuropathy. J Neurol 2015;262:870-80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schreiber S, Dannhardt-Stieger V, Henkel D, et&#xa0;al. Quantifying disease progression in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis using peripheral nerve sonography. Muscle Nerve 2016;54:391-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tawfik EA. Vagus nerve ultrasound in a patient with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve 2016;54:978-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Dengler R, Eisen A, et&#xa0;al. Electrodiagnostic criteria for diagnosis of ALS. Clin Neurophysiol 2008;119:497-503.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pelz JO, Belau E, Henn P, et&#xa0;al. Sonographic evaluation of the vagus nerves: protocol, reference values, and side-to-side differences. Muscle Nerve 2018;57:766-71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum JM, Stambler N, Malta E, et&#xa0;al. The ALSFRS-R: a revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. BDNF ALS Study Group (Phase III). J Neurol Sci 1999;169:13-21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith RA, Macklin EA, Myers KJ, et&#xa0;al. Assessment of bulbar function in amyo-trophic lateral sclerosis: validation of a self-report scale (Center for Neurologic Study Bulbar Function Scale). Eur J Neurol 2018;25:907-e66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kido M, Fujisaki N, Miyagi T, et&#xa0;al. Complimentary use of needle electromyography and ultrasonography of tongue is effective for early detection of abnormality in 20 patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Rinsho Shinkeigaku 2017;57:681-4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noto YI, Shibuya K, Shahrizaila N, et&#xa0;al. Detection of fasciculations in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: the optimal ultrasound scan time. Muscle Nerve 2017;56:1068-71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cartwright MS, Passmore LV, Yoon J, et&#xa0;al. Cross-sectional area reference values for nerve ultrasonography. Muscle Nerve 2008;37:566-71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walter U, Tsiberidou P, Kersten M, et&#xa0;al. Atrophy of the vagus nerve in Parkinson's disease revealed by high-resolution ultrasonography. Front Neurol 2018;9:805.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bede P, Chipika RH, Finegan E, et&#xa0;al. Progressive brainstem pathology in motor neuron diseases: imaging data from amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and primary lateral sclerosis. Data Brief 2020;29:105229.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oey PL, Vos PE, Wieneke GH, et&#xa0;al. Subtle involvement of the sympathetic nervous system in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve 2002;25:402-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tawfik EA, Walker FO, Cartwright MS, et&#xa0;al. Diagnostic ultrasound of the vagus nerve in patients with diabetes. J Neuroimaging 2017;27:589-93.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>