<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">33210770</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>12</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1468-1331</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>28</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Non-invasive and tracheostomy invasive ventilation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Utilization and survival rates in a cohort study over 12 years in Germany.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1160</StartPage><EndPage>1171</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1160-1171</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/ene.14647</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND PURPOSE">The aim of this study was to investigate utilization rates, treatment pathways and survival prognosis in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) undergoing non-invasive (NIV) and tracheostomy invasive ventilation (TIV) in a real-world setting.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">A prospective cohort study using a single-centre register of 2702 ALS patients (2007 to 2019) was conducted. Utilization of NIV/TIV and survival data were analysed in three cohorts: (i) non-NIV; (ii) NIV (NIV without subsequent TIV); and (iii) TIV (including TIV preceded by NIV).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">A total of 1720 patients with available data were identified, 72.0% of whom (n&#xa0;=&#xa0;1238) did not receive ventilation therapy. NIV was performed in 20.8% of patients (n&#xa0;=&#xa0;358). TIV was performed in 9.5% of patients (n&#xa0;=&#xa0;164), encompassing both primary TIV (7.2%, n&#xa0;=&#xa0;124) and TIV with preceding NIV (2.3%, n&#xa0;=&#xa0;40). TIV was more often utilized without previous NIV (25.7% vs. 8.3% of all ventilated patients), demonstrating that primary TIV was the prevailing pathway for invasive ventilation. The median (range) survival was significantly longer in the NIV cohort (40.8&#xa0;[37.2-44.3] months) and the TIV cohort (82.1&#xa0;[68.7-95.6] months) as compared to the non-NIV cohort (33.6&#xa0;[31.6-35.7] months).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Although NIV represents the standard of care, its utilization rate was low. TIV was mainly started without preceding NIV, suggesting that TIV may not be confined to NIV treatment escalation. However, TIV was pursued in a minority of patients who had previously undergone NIV. The survival benefit observed in the patients with NIV was equal to that reported in a controlled pivotal trial, but the prognosis with TIV is highly variable. The determinants of utilization of NIV/TIV and of survival (bulbar syndrome, availability of ventilation-related home nursing, cultural factors) warrant further investigation.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020 The Authors. European Journal of Neurology published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of European Academy of Neurology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Spittel</LastName><ForeName>Susanne</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9471-7798</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Center for ALS and other Motor Neuron Disorders, Charit&#xe9; - Universit&#xe4;tsmedizin Berlin, Berlin, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ambulanzpartner Soziotechnologie APST GmbH, Berlin, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maier</LastName><ForeName>Andr&#xe9;</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Center for ALS and other Motor Neuron Disorders, Charit&#xe9; - Universit&#xe4;tsmedizin Berlin, Berlin, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kettemann</LastName><ForeName>Dagmar</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Center for ALS and other Motor Neuron Disorders, Charit&#xe9; - Universit&#xe4;tsmedizin Berlin, Berlin, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Walter</LastName><ForeName>Bertram</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Center for ALS and other Motor Neuron Disorders, Charit&#xe9; - Universit&#xe4;tsmedizin Berlin, Berlin, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Koch</LastName><ForeName>Birgit</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Center for ALS and other Motor Neuron Disorders, Charit&#xe9; - Universit&#xe4;tsmedizin Berlin, Berlin, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Krause</LastName><ForeName>Kerstin</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Center for ALS and other Motor Neuron Disorders, Charit&#xe9; - Universit&#xe4;tsmedizin Berlin, Berlin, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Norden</LastName><ForeName>Jenny</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Center for ALS and other Motor Neuron Disorders, Charit&#xe9; - Universit&#xe4;tsmedizin Berlin, Berlin, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>M&#xfc;nch</LastName><ForeName>Christoph</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Center for ALS and other Motor Neuron Disorders, Charit&#xe9; - Universit&#xe4;tsmedizin Berlin, Berlin, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ambulanzpartner Soziotechnologie APST GmbH, Berlin, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Meyer</LastName><ForeName>Thomas</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Center for ALS and other Motor Neuron Disorders, Charit&#xe9; - Universit&#xe4;tsmedizin Berlin, Berlin, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ambulanzpartner Soziotechnologie APST GmbH, Berlin, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9506311</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1351-5101</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015331" MajorTopicYN="N">Cohort Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005858" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Germany</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D063087" MajorTopicYN="Y">Noninvasive Ventilation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011446" MajorTopicYN="N">Prospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012131" MajorTopicYN="Y">Respiratory Insufficiency</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015996" MajorTopicYN="N">Survival Rate</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014139" MajorTopicYN="N">Tracheostomy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">invasive ventilation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">non-invasive ventilation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">survival</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">utilization rates</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33210770</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ene.14647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Andersen PM, Abrahams S, Borasio GD, et al. EFNS guidelines on the clinical management of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (MALS)-revised report of an EFNS task force. Eur J Neurol. 2012;19:360-375.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen PM, Borasio GD, Dengler R, et al. Good practice in the management of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: clinical guidelines. An evidence-based review with good practice points. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2007;8:195-213.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bourke SC, Tomlinson M, Williams TL, Bullock RE, Shaw PJ, Gibson GJ. Effects of non-invasive ventilation on survival and quality of life in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a randomised controlled trial. Lancet Neurol. 2006;5:140-147.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ludolph AC. Amyotrophe Lateralsklerose (Motoneuronerkrankungen). In: Diener HC, ed. Leitlinien f&#xfc;r Diagnostik und Therapie in der Neurologie Stuttgart. New York, NY: Thieme; 2012:254-263.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner MR, Faull C, McDermott CJ, Nickol AH, Palmer J, Talbot K. Tracheostomy in motor neurone disease. Pract Neurol. 2019;19:467-475.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kimura F. Tracheostomy and invasive mechanical ventilation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: decision-making factors and survival analysis. Rinsho Shinkeigaku [Clin Neurol]. 2016;56:241-247.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chio A, Calvo A, Ghiglione P, Mazzini L, Mutani R, Mora G. Tracheostomy in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a 10-year population-based study in Italy. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2010;81:1141-1143.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tagami M, Kimura F, Nakajima H, et al. Tracheostomy and invasive ventilation in Japanese ALS patients: decision-making and survival analysis: 1990-2010. J Neurol Sci. 2014;344(1-2):158-164.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dreyer PS, Felding M, Klitnaes CS, Lorenzen CK. Withdrawal of invasive home mechanical ventilation in patients with advanced amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: ten years of Danish experience. J Palliat Med. 2012;15:205-209.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Georgoulopoulou E, Fini N, Vinceti M, et al. The impact of clinical factors, riluzole and therapeutic interventions on ALS survival: a population based study in Modena, Italy. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2013;14:338-345.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fini N, Georgoulopoulou E, Vinceti M, et al. Noninvasive and invasive ventilation and enteral nutrition for ALS in Italy. Muscle Nerve. 2014;50:508-516.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chadwick R, Nadig V, Oscroft NS, Shneerson JM, Smith IE. Weaning from prolonged invasive ventilation in motor neuron disease: analysis of outcomes and survival. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2011;82:643-645.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vianello A, Arcaro G, Palmieri A, et al. Survival and quality of life after tracheostomy for acute respiratory failure in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Crit Care. 2011;26(329):e7-14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winterholler MG, Erbguth FJ, Hecht MJ, Heuss D, Neundorfer B. Survival with artificial respiration at home. An open, prospective study on home ventilation for neuromuscular diseases, in particular, the situation of ALS patients. Nervenarzt. 2001;72:293-301.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borasio GD, Gelinas DF, Yanagisawa N. Mechanical ventilation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a cross-cultural perspective. J Neurol. 1998;245:S7-12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borasio GD, Voltz R. Discontinuation of mechanical ventilation in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol. 1998;245:717-722.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vandenbroucke JP, von Elm E, Altman DG, et al. Strengthening the Reporting of Observational Studies in Epidemiology (STROBE): explanation and elaboration. PLoS Med. 2007;4:e297.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, Miller RG, Swash M, Munsat TL. El Escorial revisited: revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord. 2000;1:293-299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ackermann H, Arendt G, Baron R, et al. Amyotrophe Lateralsklerose (Motoneuronerkrankungen). In: Diener HC, Putzki N, eds. Leitlinien f&#xfc;r Diagnostik und Therapie in der Neurologie, vol. 4. Stuttgart, Germany: Thieme; 2012:205-212.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaplan EL, Meier P. Nonparametric estimation from incomplete observations. J Am Stat Assoc. 1958;53:457-481.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasarskis EJ, Berryman S, Vanderleest JG, Schneider AR, McClain CJ. Nutritional status of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: relation to the proximity of death. Am J Clin Nutr. 1996;63:130-137.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desport JC, Preux PM, Truong TC, Vallat JM, Sautereau D, Couratier P. Nutritional status is a prognostic factor for survival in ALS patients. Neurology. 1999;53:1059-1063.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chio A, Ilardi A, Cammarosano S, Moglia C, Montuschi A, Calvo A. Neurobehavioral dysfunction in ALS has a negative effect on outcome and use of PEG and NIV. Neurology. 2012;78:1085-1089.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenbohm A, Peter RS, Erhardt S, et al. Epidemiology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in Southern Germany. J Neurol. 2017;264:749-757.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Funke A, Spittel S, Grehl T, et al. Provision of assistive technology devices among people with ALS in Germany: a platform-case management approach. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2018;19:342-350.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer R, Spittel S, Steinfurth L, et al. Patient-reported outcome of physical therapy in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: observational online study. JMIR Rehabil Assist Technol. 2018;5:e10099.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer T, Funke A, Munch C, et al. Real world experience of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) in the treatment of spasticity using tetrahydrocannabinol:cannabidiol (THC:CBD). BMC Neurol. 2019;19:222.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F&#xfc;rstenau D, Auschra C, Klein S. A Configuration Approach to Multi-Sided Platforms in Healthcare: An ALS Platform Case. Completed Research Paper. Forty-First International Conference on Information Systems, India. 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer T, Kettemann D, Maier A, et al. Symptomatic pharmacotherapy in ALS: data analysis from a platform-based medication management programme. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2020;91(7):783-785.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller RG, Jackson CE, Kasarskis EJ, et al. Practice parameter update: the care of the patient with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: drug, nutritional, and respiratory therapies (an evidence-based review): report of the Quality Standards Subcommittee of the American Academy of Neurology. Neurology. 2009;73:1218-1226.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chio A, Calvo A, Moglia C, et al. Non-invasive ventilation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a 10 year population based study. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2012;83:377-381.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berlowitz DJ, Howard ME, Fiore JF Jr, et al. Identifying who will benefit from non-invasive ventilation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis/motor neurone disease in a clinical cohort. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2016;87:280-286.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thakore NJ, Lapin BR, Pioro EP, Aboussouan LS. Variation in noninvasive ventilation use in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology. 2019;93:e306-e316.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee CT, Chiu YW, Wang KC, et al. Riluzole and prognostic factors in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis long-term and short-term survival: a population-based study of 1149 cases in Taiwan. J Epidemiol. 2013;23:35-40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gruis KL, Brown DL, Schoennemann A, Zebarah VA, Feldman EL. Predictors of noninvasive ventilation tolerance in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 2005;32:808-811.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lo Coco D, Marchese S, Pesco MC, La Bella V, Piccoli F, Lo CA. Noninvasive positive-pressure ventilation in ALS: predictors of tolerance and survival. Neurology. 2006;67:761-765.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kettemann D, Funke A, Maier A, et al. Clinical characteristics and course of dying in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis withdrawing from long-term ventilation. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2017;18:53-59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayashi N, Atsuta N, Yokoi D, et al. Prognosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients undergoing tracheostomy invasive ventilation therapy in Japan. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2020;91:285-290.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zoccolella S, Beghi E, Palagano G, et al. Analysis of survival and prognostic factors in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a population based study. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2008;79:33-37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuzma-Kozakiewicz M, Andersen PM, Ciecwierska K, et al. An observational study on quality of life and preferences to sustain life in locked-in state. Neurology. 2019;93:e938-e945.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rabkin J, Ogino M, Goetz R, et al. Tracheostomy with invasive ventilation for ALS patients: neurologists&#x2019; roles in the US and Japan. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2013;14:116-123.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sancho J, Servera E, Diaz JL, Banuls P, Marin J. Home tracheotomy mechanical ventilation in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: causes, complications and 1-year survival. Thorax. 2011;66:948-952.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spataro R, Bono V, Marchese S, La Bella V. Tracheostomy mechanical ventilation in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: clinical features and survival analysis. J Neurol Sci. 2012;323:66-70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vitacca M, Montini A, Lunetta C, et al. Impact of an early respiratory care programme with non-invasive ventilation adaptation in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Eur J Neurol. 2018;25:556-e33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leonardis L, Dolenc Groselj L, Vidmar G. Factors related to respiration influencing survival and respiratory function in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a retrospective study. Eur J Neurol. 2012;19:1518-1524.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanjuan-Lopez P, Valino-Lopez P, Ricoy-Gabaldon J, Verea-Hernando H. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: impact of pulmonary follow-up and mechanical ventilation on survival. A study of 114 cases. Arch Bronconeumol. 2014;50:509-513.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan GP, Soon LHY, Ni B, et al. The pattern of use and survival outcomes of a dedicated adult Home Ventilation and Respiratory Support Service in Singapore: a 7-year retrospective observational cohort study. J Thorac Dis. 2019;11:795-804.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dreyer P, Lorenzen CK, Schou L, Felding M. Survival in ALS with home mechanical ventilation non-invasively and invasively: a 15-year cohort study in west Denmark. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2014;15:62-67.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>