<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">33220162</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>12</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1468-1331</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>28</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Pathophysiological associations of transcallosal dysfunction in ALS.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1172</StartPage><EndPage>1180</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1172-1180</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/ene.14653</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="AIM">Involvement of the corpus callosum has been identified as a feature of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS), particularly through neuropathological studies. The aim of the present study was to determine whether alteration in transcallosal function contributed to the development of ALS, disease progression and thereby functional disability.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Transcallosal function and motor cortex excitability were assessed in 17 ALS patients with results compared to healthy controls. Transcallosal inhibition (interstimulus intervals (ISI) of 8-40&#xa0;ms), short interval intracortical facilitation (SICF) and inhibition (SICI) were assessed in both cerebral hemispheres. Patients were staged utilising clinical and neurophysiological staging assessments.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">In ALS, there was prominent reduction of transcallosal inhibition (TI) when recorded from the primary and secondary motor cortices compared to controls (F&#xa0;=&#xa0;23.255, p&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;0.001). This reduction of TI was accompanied by features indicative of cortical hyperexcitability, including reduction of SICI and increase in SICF. There was a significant correlation between the reduction in TI and the rate of disease progression (R&#xa0;=&#xa0;-0.825, p&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;0.001) and reduction in muscle strength (R&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.54, p&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.031).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">The present study has established that dysfunction of transcallosal circuits was an important pathophysiological mechanism in ALS, correlating with greater disability and a faster rate of disease progression. Therapies aimed at restoring the function of transcallosal circuits may be considered for therapeutic approaches in ALS.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020 European Academy of Neurology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>van den Bos</LastName><ForeName>Mehdi A J</ForeName><Initials>MAJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0381-917X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Westmead Clinical School, University of Sydney, Sydney, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Higashihara</LastName><ForeName>Mana</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8015-2028</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Westmead Clinical School, University of Sydney, Sydney, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Tokyo Metropolitan Geriatric Hospital, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Geevasinga</LastName><ForeName>Nimeshan</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9338-0318</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Westmead Clinical School, University of Sydney, Sydney, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Menon</LastName><ForeName>Parvathi</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6935-5852</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Westmead Clinical School, University of Sydney, Sydney, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kiernan</LastName><ForeName>Matthew C</ForeName><Initials>MC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9054-026X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Brain and Mind Centre, Royal Prince Alfred Hospital, University of Sydney, Sydney, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vucic</LastName><ForeName>Steve</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8323-873X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Westmead Clinical School, University of Sydney, Sydney, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9506311</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1351-5101</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003337" MajorTopicYN="N">Corpus Callosum</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019054" MajorTopicYN="N">Evoked Potentials, Motor</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009044" MajorTopicYN="Y">Motor Cortex</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009433" MajorTopicYN="N">Neural Inhibition</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D050781" MajorTopicYN="N">Transcranial Magnetic Stimulation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ALS pathophysiology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">TMS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cortical neurophysiology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">transcallosal inhibition</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33220162</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ene.14653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Ravits JM, La Spada AR. ALS motor phenotype heterogeneity, focality, and spread: deconstructing motor neuron degeneration. Neurology. 2009;73:805-811.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner MR, Menke RAL. The tough body at the epicentre of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2017;88:369-370.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner MR, Wicks P, Brownstein CA, et al. Concordance between site of onset and limb dominance in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2011;82:853-854.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devine MS, Kiernan MC, Heggie S, McCombe PA, Henderson RD. Study of motor asymmetry in ALS indicates an effect of limb dominance on onset and spread of weakness, and an important role for upper motor neurons. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2014;15:481-487.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S, Kiernan MC. Novel threshold tracking techniques suggest that cortical hyperexcitability is an early feature of motor neuron disease. Brain. 2006;129:2436-2446.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filippini N, Douaud G, Mackay CE, Knight S, Talbot K, Turner MR. Corpus callosum involvement is a consistent feature of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology. 2010;75:1645-1652.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menon P, Geevasinga N, van den Bos M, Yiannikas C, Kiernan MC, Vucic S. Cortical hyperexcitability and disease spread in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Eur J Neurol. 2017;24:816-824.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van den Bos MAJ, Higashihara M, Geevasinga N, Menon P, Kiernan MC, Vucic S. Imbalance of cortical facilitatory and inhibitory circuits underlies hyperexcitability in ALS. Neurology. 2018;91:e1669-e1676.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menon P, Yiannikas C, Kiernan MC, Vucic S. Regional motor cortex dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Clin Transl Neurol. 2019;6:1373-1382.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shefner JM, Al-Chalabi A, Baker MR, et al. A proposal for new diagnostic criteria for ALS. Clin Neurophysiol. 2020;131:1975-1978.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luders E, Thompson PM, Toga AW. The development of the corpus callosum in the healthy human brain. J Neurosci. 2010;30:10985-10990.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sugiyama M, Takao M, Hatsuta H, et al. Increased number of astrocytes and macrophages/microglial cells in the corpus callosum in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuropathology. 2013;33:591-599.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chapman MC, Jelsone-Swain L, Johnson TD, Gruis KL, Welsh RC. Diffusion tensor MRI of the corpus callosum in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Magn Reson Imaging. 2014;39:641-647.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chio A, Pagani M, Agosta F, Calvo A, Cistaro A, Filippi M. Neuroimaging in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: insights into structural and functional changes. Lancet Neurol. 2014;13:1228-1240.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J, Ji B, Hu J, et al. Aberrant interhemispheric homotopic functional and structural connectivity in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2017;88:369-370.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eisen A. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-Evolutionary and other perspectives. Muscle Nerve. 2009;40:297-304.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tu S, Wang C, Menke RAL, et al. Regional callosal integrity and bilaterality of limb weakness in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2020;21:1-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karandreas N, Papadopoulou M, Kokotis P, Papapostolou A, Tsivgoulis G, Zambelis T. Impaired interhemispheric inhibition in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2007;8:112-118.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wittstock M, Wolters A, Benecke R. Transcallosal inhibition in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Neurophysiol. 2007;118:301-307.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wittstock M, Meister S, Walter U, Benecke R, Wolters A. Mirror movements in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2011;12:393-397.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khedr EM, Ahmed MA, Hamdy A, Shawky OA. Cortical excitability of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: transcranial magnetic stimulation study. Neurophysiol Clin. 2011;41:73-79.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferbert A, Priori A, Rothwell JC, Day BL, Colebatch JG, Marsden CD. Interhemispheric inhibition of the human motor cortex. J Physiol. 1992;453:525-546.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer BU, Roricht S, Grafin von Einsiedel H, Kruggel F, Weindl A. Inhibitory and excitatory interhemispheric transfers between motor cortical areas in normal humans and patients with abnormalities of the corpus callosum. Brain. 1995;118(Pt 2):429-440.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Lazzaro V, Oliviero A, Profice P, et al. Direct demonstration of interhemispheric inhibition of the human motor cortex produced by transcranial magnetic stimulation. Exp Brain Res. 1999;124:520-524.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiers L, Cros D, Chiappa KH, Fang J. Variability of motor potentials evoked by transcranial magnetic stimulation. Electroencephalogr Clin Neurophysiol. 1993;89:415-423.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S, Howells J, Trevillion L, Kiernan MC. Assessment of cortical excitability using threshold tracking techniques. Muscle Nerve. 2006;33:477-486.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samusyte G, Bostock H, Rothwell J, Koltzenburg M. Short-interval intracortical inhibition: comparison between conventional and threshold-tracking techniques. Brain stimulation. 2018;11:806-817.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Dengler R, Eisen A, et al. Electrodiagnostic criteria for diagnosis of ALS. Clin Neurophysiol. 2008;119:497-503.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oldfield RC. The assessment and analysis of handedness: the Edinburgh inventory. Neuropsychologia. 1971;9:97-113.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum JM, Stambler N, Malta E, et al. The ALSFRS-R: a revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. BDNF ALS Study Group (Phase III). J Neurol Sci. 1999;169:13-21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Labra J, Menon P, Byth K, Morrison S, Vucic S. Rate of disease progression: a prognostic biomarker in ALS. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2016;87:628-632.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matamala JM, Howells J, Dharmadasa T, et al. Inter-session reliability of short-interval intracortical inhibition measured by threshold tracking TMS. Neurosci Lett. 2018;674:18-23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van den Bos MAJ, Menon P, Howells J, Geevasinga N, Kiernan MC, Vucic S. Physiological processes underlying short interval intracortical facilitation in the human motor cortex. Front Neurosci. 2018;12:240.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swash M, de Carvalho M. The neurophysiological index in ALS. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord. 2004;5(Suppl 1):108-110.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daskalakis ZJ, Christensen BK, Fitzgerald PB, Roshan L, Chen R. The mechanisms of interhemispheric inhibition in the human motor cortex. J Physiol. 2002;543:317-326.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chovsepian A, Empl L, Correa D, Bareyre FM. Heterotopic transcallosal projections are present throughout the mouse cortex. Front Cell Neurosci. 2017;11:36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wahl M, Lauterbach-Soon B, Hattingen E, et al. Human motor corpus callosum: topography, somatotopy, and link between microstructure and function. J Neurosci. 2007;27:12132-12138.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xfc;bers A, B&#xf6;ckler B, Abaei A, et al. Functional and structural impairment of transcallosal motor fibres in ALS: a study using transcranial magnetic stimulation, diffusion tensor imaging, and diffusion weighted spectroscopy. Brain Imaging Behav. 2020. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11682-020-00282.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wittstock M, Wilde N, Grossmann A, Kasper E, Teipel S. Mirror movements in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a combined study using diffusion tensor imaging and transcranial magnetic stimulation. Front Neurol. 2020;11:164.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamauchi H, Fukuyama H, Ouchi Y, et al. Corpus callosum atrophy in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Sci. 1995;134:189-196.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ziemann U, Reis J, Schwenkreis P, et al. TMS and drugs revisited 2014. Clin Neurophysiol. 2015;126:1847-1868.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menon P, Kiernan MC, Vucic S. Cortical dysfunction underlies the development of the split-hand in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. PLoS ONE. 2014;9:e87124.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S, Kiernan MC. Abnormalities in cortical and peripheral excitability in flail arm variant amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2007;78:849-852.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nihei K, McKee AC, Kowall NW. Patterns of neuronal degeneration in the motor cortex of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. Acta Neuropathol. 1993;86:55-64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark RM, Blizzard CA, Young KM, King AE, Dickson TC. Calretinin and Neuropeptide Y interneurons are differentially altered in the motor cortex of the SOD1G93A mouse model of ALS. Sci Rep. 2017;7:44461.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang W, Zhang L, Liang B, et al. Hyperactive somatostatin interneurons contribute to excitotoxicity in neurodegenerative disorders. Nat Neurosci. 2016;19:557-559.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petri S, Krampfl K, Hashemi F, et al. Distribution of GABAA receptor mRNA in the motor cortex of ALS patients. J Neuropathol Exp Neurol. 2003;62:1041-1051.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lloyd C, Richardson M, Brooks D, Al Chalabi A, Leigh P. Extramotor involvement in ALS: PET studies with the GABA(A) ligand [(11)C]flumazenil. Brain. 2000;123:2289-2296.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee H, Gunraj C, Chen R. The effects of inhibitory and facilitatory intracortical circuits on interhemispheric inhibition in the human motor cortex. J Physiol. 2007;580:1021-1032.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neumann M, Sampathu DM, Kwong LK, et al. Ubiquitinated TDP-43 in frontotemporal lobar degeneration and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Science. 2006;314:130-133.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rusu CV, Murakami M, Ziemann U, Triesch J. A model of TMS-induced I-waves in motor cortex. Brain Stimul. 2014;7:401-414.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S, van den Bos M, Menon P, Howells J, Dharmadasa T, Kiernan MC. Utility of threshold tracking transcranial magnetic stimulation in ALS. Clin Neurophysiol Pract. 2018;3:164-172.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mills KR, Nithi KA. Corticomotor threshold is reduced in early sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 1997;20:1137-1141.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eisen A, Weber M. The motor cortex and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 2001;24:564-573.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eisen A, Braak H, Del Tredici K, Lemon R, Ludolph AC, Kiernan MC. Cortical influences drive amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2017;88:917-924.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shibuya K, Park SB, Geevasinga N, et al. Motor cortical function determines prognosis in sporadic ALS. Neurology. 2016;87:513-520.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eisen A, Kim S, Pant B. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS): a phylogenetic disease of the corticomotoneuron? Muscle Nerve. 1992;15:219-224.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>