<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">33305472</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1440-1789</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>40</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Neuropathology : official journal of the Japanese Society of Neuropathology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Neuropathology</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Astrocytes release glutamate via cystine/glutamate antiporter upregulated in response to increased oxidative stress related to sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>587</StartPage><EndPage>598</EndPage><MedlinePgn>587-598</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/neup.12716</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>A vast body of evidence implicates increased oxidative stress and extracellular glutamate accumulation in the pathomechanism of sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). Cystine/glutamate antiporter (xCT) carries extracellular cystine uptake and intracellular glutamate release (cystine/glutamate exchange) in the presence of oxidative stress. The aim of the present study was to determine the involvement of xCT in ALS. Immunohistochemical observations in the spinal cord sections demonstrated that xCT was mainly expressed in astrocytes, with staining more intense in 12 sporadic ALS patients as compared to 12 age-matched control individuals. Western blot and densitometric analyses of the spinal cord samples revealed that the relative value of xCT/&#x3b2;-actin optical density ratio was significantly higher in the ALS group as compared to the control group. Next, we conducted cell culture experiments using a human astrocytoma-derived cell line (1321N1) and a mouse motor neuron/neuroblastoma hybrid cell line (NSC34). In 1321N1 cells, the normalized xCT expression levels in cell lysates were significantly increased by H<sub>2</sub> O<sub>2</sub> treatment. Glutamate concentrations in 1321&#x2009;N1 cell culture-conditioned media were significantly elevated by H<sub>2</sub> O<sub>2</sub> treatment, and the H<sub>2</sub> O<sub>2</sub> -driven elevations were completely canceled by the xCT inhibitor erastin pretreatment. In motor neuron-differentiated NSC34 cells (NSC34d cells), both the normalized xCT expression levels in the cell lysates and glutamate concentrations in the cell-conditioned media were constant with or without H<sub>2</sub> O<sub>2</sub> treatment. The present results provide in vivo and in vitro evidence that astrocytes upregulate xCT expression to release glutamate in response to increased oxidative stress associated with ALS, contributing to extracellular glutamate accumulation.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020 Japanese Society of Neuropathology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kazama</LastName><ForeName>Miku</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, Tokyo Women's Medical University, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kato</LastName><ForeName>Yoichiro</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0777-5020</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Pathological Neuroscience, Department of Pathology, Tokyo Women's Medical University, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kakita</LastName><ForeName>Akiyoshi</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathology, Brain Research Institute, Niigata University, Niigata, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Noguchi</LastName><ForeName>Noriko</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Life Systems, Faculty of Life and Medical Sciences, Doshisha University, Kyotanabe, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Urano</LastName><ForeName>Yasuomi</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Life Systems, Faculty of Life and Medical Sciences, Doshisha University, Kyotanabe, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Masui</LastName><ForeName>Kenta</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Pathological Neuroscience, Department of Pathology, Tokyo Women's Medical University, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Niida-Kawaguchi</LastName><ForeName>Motoko</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Pathological Neuroscience, Department of Pathology, Tokyo Women's Medical University, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yamamoto</LastName><ForeName>Tomoko</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Pathological Neuroscience, Department of Pathology, Tokyo Women's Medical University, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Watabe</LastName><ForeName>Kazuhiko</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Technology, Kyorin University, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kitagawa</LastName><ForeName>Kazuo</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Tokyo Women's Medical University, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shibata</LastName><ForeName>Noriyuki</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, Tokyo Women's Medical University, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Australia</Country><MedlineTA>Neuropathology</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9606526</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0919-6544</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D027182">Amino Acid Transport System y+</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C118895">SLC7A11 protein, human</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>3KX376GY7L</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D018698">Glutamic Acid</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D027182" MajorTopicYN="N">Amino Acid Transport System y+</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001253" MajorTopicYN="N">Astrocytes</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018698" MajorTopicYN="N">Glutamic Acid</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051379" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018384" MajorTopicYN="N">Oxidative Stress</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013116" MajorTopicYN="N">Spinal Cord</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015854" MajorTopicYN="N">Up-Regulation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">astrocyte</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">glutamate</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">oxidative stress</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">xCT</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33305472</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/neup.12716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Filipi T, Hermanova Z, Tureckova J, Vanatko O, Anderova M. Glial cells - The strategic targets in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis treatment. J Clin Med 2020; 9: 261.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Derek A, Drechsel DA, Alvaro G, Estevez AG, Luis Barbeito L, Beckman JS. Nitric oxide-mediated oxidative damage and the progressive demise of motor neurons in ALS. Neurotox Res 2012; 22: 251-264.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim BW, Jeong YE, Wong M, Martin LJ. DNA damage accumulates and responses are engaged in human ALS brain and spinal motor neurons and DNA repair is activatable in iPSC-derived motor neurons with SOD1 mutations. Acta Neuropathol Commun 2020; 8: 7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shibata T, Iio K, Kawai Y et al. Identification of a lipid peroxidation product as a potential trigger of the p53 pathway. J Biol Chem 2006; 281: 1196-1204.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shibata N, Nagai R, Uchida K et al. Morphological evidence for lipid peroxidation and protein glycoxidation in spinal cords from sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. Brain Res 2001; 917: 97-104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shibata N, Yamada S, Uchida K et al. Accumulation of protein-bound 4-hydroxy-2-hexenal in spinal cords from patients with sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain Res 2004; 1019: 170-177.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niida-Kawaguchi M, Kakita A et al. Soluble iron accumulation induces microglial glutamate release in the spinal cord of sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuropathology 2020; 40: 152-166.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L, Wang X, Cueto R et al. Biochemical basis and metabolic interplay of redox regulation. Redox Biol 2019; 26: 101284.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rothstein JD, Tsai G, Kuncl RW et al. Abnormal excitatory amino acid metabolism in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol 1990; 28: 18-25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rothstein JD, Van Kammen M, Levey AI, Martin LJ. Selective loss of glial glutamate transporter GLT-1 in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol 1995; 38: 73-84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blanc EM, Keller JN, Fernandez S, Mattson MP. 4- Hydroxynonenal, a lipid eroxidation product, impairs glutamate transport in cortical astrocytes. Glia 1998; 22: 149-160.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedersen WA, Fu W, Keller JN et al. Protein modification by the lipid peroxidation product 4-hydroxynonenal in the spinal cords of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. Ann Neurol 1998; 44: 819-824.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawaguchi M, Shibata N, Horiuchi S, Kobayashi M. Glyoxal inactivates glutamate transporter-1 in cultured rat astrocytes. Neuropathology 2005; 25: 27-36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewerenz J, Hewett SJ, Huang Y et al. The cystine/glutamate antiporter system Xc&#x2212; in health and disease: From molecular mechanisms to novel therapeutic opportunities. Antioxid Redox Signal 2013; 18: 522-555.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harvey CJ, Thimmulappa RK, Singh A et al. Nrf2-regulated glutathione recycling independent of biosynthesis is critical for cell survival during oxidative stress. Free Radic Biol Med 2009; 46: 443-453.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zmijewski CS, Song L, Harkins L, Cobbs CS, Jpe RS. Oxidative stress and heat shock stimulate RGS2 expression in 1321N1 astrocytoma cells. Arch Biochem Biophys 2001; 392: 192-196.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim W, Kwon HJ, Jung HY et al. Tat-HSP70 protects neurons from oxidative damage in the NSC34 cells and ischemic damage in the ventral horn of rabbit spinal cord. Neurochem Int 2019; 129: 104477.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mesci P, Za&#xef;di S, Lobsiger CS et al. System xc&#x2212; is a mediator of microglial function and its deletion slows symptoms in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis mice. Brain 2015; 138: 53-68.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wijesekera LC, Leigh PN. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Orphanet J Rare Dis 2009; 4: 3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackman NA, Uliasz TF, Hewett JA, Hewett SJ. Regulation of system xc&#x2212; activity and expression in astrocytes by interleukin-1beta: Implications for hypoxic neuronal injury. Glia 2010; 58: 1806-1815.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee M, Cho T, Jantaratnotai N, Wang YT, McGeer E, McGeer PL. Depletion of GSH in glial cells induces neurotoxicity: Relevance to aging and degenerative neurological diseases. FASEB J 2010; 24: 2533-2545.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sato H, Tamba M, Okuno S et al. Distribution of cystine/glutamate exchange transporter, system xc&#x2212;, in the mouse brain. J Neurosci 2002; 22: 8028-8033.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Massie A, Boillee S, Hewett S, Knackstedt L, Lewerenz J. Main path and byways: Non-vesicular glutamate release by system xc&#x2212; as an important modifier of glutamatergic neurotransmission. J Neurochem 2015; 135: 1062-1079.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewerenz J, Albrecht P, Tien ML et al. Induction of Nrf2 and xCT are involved in the action of the neuroprotective antibiotic ceftriaxone in vitro. J Neurochem 2009; 111: 332-343.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewerenz J, Maher P. Basal levels of sIF2&#x3b1; phosphorylation determine cellular antioxidant status by regulating ATF4 and xCT expression. J Biol Chem 2009; 284: 1106-1115.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sato H, Fujiwara K, Sagara J, Bannai S. Induction of cystine transport activity in mouse peritoneal macrophages by bacterial lipopolysaccharide. Biochem J 1995; 310: 547-551.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X, Resch J, Rush T, Lobner D. Functional upregulation of system xc&#x2212; by fibroblast growth factor-2. Neuropharmacology 2012; 62: 901-906.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sims B, Clarke M, Njah W, Hopkins ES, Sontheimer H. Erythropoietin-induced neuroprotection requires cystine glutamate exchanger activity. Brain Res 2010; 1321: 88-95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu XX, Li XJ, Zhang B et al. MicroRNA-26b is underexpressed in human breast cancer and induces cell apoptosis by targeting SLC7A11. FEBS Lett 2011; 585: 1363-1367.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fogal B, Li J, Lobner D, McCullough LD, Hewett SJ. System xc&#x2212; activity and astrocytes are necessary for interleukin-1&#x3b2;-mediated hypoxic neuronal injury. J Neurosci 2007; 27: 10094-10105.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackman NA, Melchior SE, Hewett JA, Hewett SJ. Non-cell autonomous influence of the astrocyte system xc&#x2212; on hypoglycemic neuronal cell death. ASN Neuro 2012; 4: 23-32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soria FN, P&#xe9;r&#xe9;z-Samartin A, Martin A et al. Extrasynaptic glutamate release through cystine/glutamate antiporter contributes to ischemic damage. J Clin Invest 2014; 124: 3645-3655.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krzy&#x17c;anowska W, Pomierny B, Flip M, Pera J. Glutamate transporters in brain ischemia: To modulate or not? Acta Pharmacol Sin 2014; 35: 444-462.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Albano R, Liu X, Lobner D. Regulation of system xc&#x2212; in the SOD1-G93A mouse model of ALS. Exp Neurol 2013; 250: 69-73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warita BA, Manabe Y, Murakami T et al. Tardive decrease of astrocytic glutamate transporter protein in transgenic mice with ALS-linked mutant SOD1. Neurol Res 2002; 24: 577-581.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alexianu ME, Ho BK, Mohamed AH, La Bella V, Smith RG, Appel SH. The role of calcium-binding proteins in selective motor neuron vulnerability in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol 1994; 36: 846-858.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armada-Moreira A, Gomes JI, Pina CC et al. Going the extra (synaptic) mile: Excitotoxicity as the road toward neurodegenerative diseases. Front Cell Neurosci 2020; 14: 90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayala V, Granado-Serrano AB, Cacabelos D et al. Cell stress induces TDP-43 pathological changes associated with ERK1/2dysfunction: Implications in ALS. Acta Neuropathol 2011; 122: 259-270.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warren BA, Patel SA, Nunn PB, Bridges RJ. The Lathyrus excitotoxin &#x3b2;-N-oxalyl-L-&#x3b1;,&#x3b2;-diaminopropionic acid is a substrate of the L-cystine/L-glutamate exchanger system xc&#x2212;. Toxicol Appl Pharmacol 2004; 200: 83-92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X, Rush T, Zapata J, Lobner D. &#x3b2;-N-methylamino-L-alanine induces oxidative stress and glutamate release through action on system xc&#x2212;. Exp Neurol 2009; 217: 429-433.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirano A, Kurland LT, Krooth RS, Lessell S. Parkinsonism-dementia complex, an endemic disease on the island of Guam. I. Clinical features. Brain 1961; 84: 642-661.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirano A, Malamud N, Kurland LT. Parkinsonism-dementia complex, an endemic disease on the island of Guam. II. Pathological features. Brain 1961; 84: 662-679.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>