<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">33301428</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>20</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1643-3750</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>10</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medical science monitor : international medical journal of experimental and clinical research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Med Sci Monit</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Repeat Administration of Bone Marrow-Derived Mesenchymal Stem Cells for Treatment of Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e927484</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e927484</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.12659/MSM.927484</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>BACKGROUND The aim of this study was to investigate repeated intrathecal injection of autologous bone marrow-derived mesenchymal stem cells (BM-D MSCs) to patients for treatment of sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). MATERIAL AND METHODS Autologous MSCs were isolated from the patients' bone marrow, plated, expanded, harvested, and passaged. Stem cells from a single bone marrow collection were used for 3 injections per patient, given over a 3-month period. Outcomes were measured with the Revised Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Functional Rating Scale (ALSFRS-R). Participants were observed for a minimum of 6 months before transplantation to assess the natural course of ALS and for the same amount of time after transplantation to compare the rate of disease progression, estimated based on average monthly changes in ALSFRS-R scores. Data from 8 of the 15 participants eligible for the study were analyzed. RESULTS The safety of the MSC injections was confirmed and various effects of the therapy were documented. In patients who had ALS with an inherently slow course, there were no significant changes in the rate of disease progression. In patients who had ALS with an inherently rapid course, slowing of the disease was noted following treatment with MSCs. However, because that subgroup was so small, it was not possible to assess whether the changes were statistically significant. CONCLUSIONS Identifying groups of patients who are not responding or potentially responding negatively to injection of MSCs may help prevent it from being offered to individuals who may not benefit from the therapy. One of the limitations of this treatment method is the amount of time required for long-lasting preparation of bone marrow-derived MSCs for a disease that is rapidly progressive. Therefore, it is worth looking for other allogeneic sources of stromal cells for these types of injections.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Siwek</LastName><ForeName>Tomasz</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, School of Medicine, University of Warmia and Mazury, Olsztyn, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University Hospital in Olsztyn, Olsztyn, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jezierska-Wo&#x17a;niak</LastName><ForeName>Katarzyna</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory for Regenerative Medicine, School of Medicine, University of Warmia and Mazury, Olsztyn, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maksymowicz</LastName><ForeName>Stanis&#x142;aw</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology and Sociology of Health and Public Health, School of Public Health, Collegium Medicum, University of Warmia and Mazury, Olsztyn, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Barczewska</LastName><ForeName>Monika</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, School of Medicine, University of Warmia and Mazury, Olsztyn, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departament of Neurosurgery, University Hospital in Olsztyn, Olsztyn, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sowa</LastName><ForeName>Mariusz</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, School of Medicine, University of Warmia and Mazury, Olsztyn, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, University Hospital in Olsztyn, Olsztyn, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Badowska</LastName><ForeName>Wanda</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Paediatrics, School of Medicine, University of Warmia and Mazury, Olsztyn, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maksymowicz</LastName><ForeName>Wojciech</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, School of Medicine, University of Warmia and Mazury, Olsztyn, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, University Hospital in Olsztyn, Olsztyn, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016430">Clinical Trial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Med Sci Monit</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9609063</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1234-1010</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018450" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Progression</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D045164" MajorTopicYN="Y">Mesenchymal Stem Cell Transplantation</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D059630" MajorTopicYN="N">Mesenchymal Stem Cells</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000166" MajorTopicYN="Y">cytology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement><b>Conflicts of interest</b>. None.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33301428</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7737405</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12659/MSM.927484</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">927484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Dash RP, Babu RJ, Srinivas NR. Two-decade-long journey from riluzole to edaravone: Revisiting the clinical pharmacokinetics of the only two amyotrophic lateral sclerosis therapeutics. Clin Pharmacokinet. 2018;57(11):1385&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29682695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazzini L, Fagioli F, Boccaletti R, et al. Stem cell therapy in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A methodological approach in humans. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disorder. 2003;4(3):158&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13129802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Staff NP, Madigan NN, Morris J, et al. Safety of intrathecal autologous adipose-derived mesenchymal stromal cells in patients with ALS. Neurology. 2016;87(21):2230&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5123559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27784774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karussis D, Karageorgiou C, Vaknin-Dembinsky A, et al. Safety and immunological effects of mesenchymal stem cell transplantation in patients with multiple sclerosis and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Arch Neurol. 2010;67(10):1187&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3036569</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20937945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomsen GM, Gowing G, Svendsen S, et al. The past, present and future of stem cell clinical trials for ALS. Exp Neurol. 2014;262(Pt B):127&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24613827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sykov&#xe1; E, Rychmach P, Drahor&#xe1;dov&#xe1; I, et al. Transplantation of mesenchymal stromal cells in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Results of phase I/IIa clinical trial. Cell Transplant. 2017;26(4):647&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5661219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27938483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrou P, Gothelf Y, Argov Z, et al. Safety and clinical effects of mesenchymal stem cells secreting neurotrophic factor transplantation in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Results of phase 1/2 and 2a clinical trials. JAMA Neurol. 2016;73(3):337&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26751635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nabavi SM, Arab L, Jarooghi N, et al. Safety, feasibility of intravenous and intrathecal injection of autologous bone marrow derived mesenchymal stromal cells in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: An open label phase I clinical trial. Cell J. 2019;20(4):592&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6099146</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30124008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barczewska M, Grudniak M, Maksymowicz S, et al. Safety of intrathecal injection of Wharton&#x2019;s jelly-derived mesenchymal stem cells in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis therapy. Neural Regen Res. 2019;14(2):313&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6301165</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30531015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siwek T, Maksymowicz W, Barczewska M, et al. Mesenchymal stem cell (MSC) transplantation in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS): Is there a &#x201c;responder population&#x201d;? J Neurol Neurosci. 2018;9(3):260.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grisendi G, Anner&#xe9;n C, Cafarelli L, et al. GMP-manufactured density gradient media for optimized mesenchymal stromal/stem cell isolation and expansion. Cytotherapy. 2010;12(4):466&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20353309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dominici M, Le Blanc K, Mueller I, et al. Minimum criteria for defining multipotent mesenchymal stromal cells. The International Society for Cellular Therapy position statement. Cytotherapy. 2006;8(4):315&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16923606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum JM, Stambler N, Malta E, et al. The ALSFRS-R: A revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. BDNF ALS Study Group (Phase III) J Neurol Sci. 1999;169(1&#x2013;2):13&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10540002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kollewe K, Mauss U, Krampfl K, et al. ALSFRS-R score and its ratio: A useful predictor for ALS progression. J Neurol Sci. 2008;275(12):69&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18721928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maksymowicz S, Kuko&#x142;owicz P, Siwek T, et al. Validation of the revised Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Functional Rating Scale in Poland and its reliability in conditions of the medical experiment. Neurol Sci. 2020 [Online ahead of print]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32676760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gugliandolo A, Bramanti P, Mazzon E. Mesenchymal stem cells: A potential therapeutical approach for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis? Stem Cells Int. 2019;2019 3675627.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6431432</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30956667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Czarzasta J, Habich A, Siwek T, et al. Stem cells for ALS: An overview of possible therapeutic approaches. Int J Dev Neurosci. 2017;57:46&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28088365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barczewska M, Maksymowicz S, Zdoli&#x144;ska-Malinowska I, et al. Umbilical cord mesenchymal stem cells in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: An original study. Stem Cell Rev Rep. 2020;16:922&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7456414</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32725316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim HY, Kim H, Oh KW, et al. Biological markers of mesenchymal stromal cells as predictors of response to autologous stem cell transplantation in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: An investigator-initiated trial and in vivo study. Stem Cells. 2014;32(10):2724&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24966156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh KW, Moon C, Kim HY, et al. Phase I trial of repeated intrathecal autologous bone marrow-derived mesenchymal stromal cells in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Stem Cells Transl Med. 2015;4(6):590&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4449093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25934946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh KW, Noh MY, Kwon MS, et al. Repeated intrathecal mesenchymal stem cells for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol. 2018;84(3):361&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6175096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30048006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>