<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">33323321</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>04</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1096-3634</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>112</Volume><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Seminars in cell &amp; developmental biology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Semin Cell Dev Biol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Importance of lipids for upper motor neuron health and disease.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>92</StartPage><EndPage>104</EndPage><MedlinePgn>92-104</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.semcdb.2020.11.004</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S1084-9521(20)30004-5</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Building evidence reveals the importance of maintaining lipid homeostasis for the health and function of neurons, and upper motor neurons (UMNs) are no exception. UMNs are critically important for the initiation and modulation of voluntary movement as they are responsible for conveying cerebral cortex' input to spinal cord targets. To maintain their unique cytoarchitecture with a prominent apical dendrite and a very long axon, UMNs require a stable cell membrane, a lipid bilayer. Lipids can act as building blocks for many biomolecules, and they also contribute to the production of energy. Therefore, UMNs require sustained control over the production, utilization and homeostasis of lipids. Perturbations of lipid homeostasis lead to UMN vulnerability and progressive degeneration in diseases such as hereditary spastic paraplegia (HSP) and primary lateral sclerosis (PLS). Here, we discuss the importance of lipids, especially for UMNs.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2020 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gunay</LastName><ForeName>Aksu</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Northwestern University, Feinberg School of Medicine, Chicago, IL, USA, 60611.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shin</LastName><ForeName>Heather H</ForeName><Initials>HH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Northwestern University, Feinberg School of Medicine, Chicago, IL, USA, 60611.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gozutok</LastName><ForeName>Oge</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Northwestern University, Feinberg School of Medicine, Chicago, IL, USA, 60611.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gautam</LastName><ForeName>Mukesh</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Northwestern University, Feinberg School of Medicine, Chicago, IL, USA, 60611.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ozdinler</LastName><ForeName>P Hande</ForeName><Initials>PH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Northwestern University, Feinberg School of Medicine, Chicago, IL, USA, 60611. Electronic address: ozdinler@northwestern.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R01 AG061708</GrantID><Acronym>AG</Acronym><Agency>NIA NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Semin Cell Dev Biol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9607332</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1084-9521</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D008055">Lipids</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001369" MajorTopicYN="N">Axons</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002540" MajorTopicYN="N">Cerebral Cortex</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003712" MajorTopicYN="N">Dendrites</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D050356" MajorTopicYN="N">Lipid Metabolism</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="Y">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008055" MajorTopicYN="N">Lipids</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016472" MajorTopicYN="N">Motor Neuron Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009046" MajorTopicYN="N">Motor Neurons</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013116" MajorTopicYN="N">Spinal Cord</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ALS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Betz cells</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Corticospinal motor neurons</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ER, lipid homeostasis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">HSP</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PLS, mitochondria</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement><b>Conflicts of Interest:</b> The authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33323321</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS1654305</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8026509</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.semcdb.2020.11.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S1084-9521(20)30004-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Jara JH, Sheets PL, Nigro MJ, Peri&#x107; M, Brooks C, Heller DB, Martina M, Andjus PR, Ozdinler PH, The Electrophysiological Determinants of Corticospinal Motor Neuron Vulnerability in ALS, Frontiers in Molecular Neuroscience 13(73) (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7248374</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32508590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shepherd GM, Corticostriatal connectivity and its role in disease, Nat Rev Neurosci 14(4) (2013) 278&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4096337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23511908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peters OM, Ghasemi M, Brown RH Jr., Emerging mechanisms of molecular pathology in ALS, J Clin Invest 125(5) (2015) 1767&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4463186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25932674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boylan K, Familial Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis, Neurol Clin 33(4) (2015) 807&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4670044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26515623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rickman OJ, Baple EL, Crosby AH, Lipid metabolic pathways converge in motor neuron degenerative diseases, Brain (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7174042</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31848577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dervishi I, Gozutok O, Murnan K, Gautam M, Heller D, Bigio E, Ozdinler PH, Protein-protein interactions reveal key canonical pathways, upstream regulators, interactome domains, and novel targets in ALS, Sci Rep 8(1) (2018) 14732.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6170493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30283000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Branchu J, Boutry M, Sourd L, Depp M, Leone C, Corriger A, Vallucci M, Esteves T, Matusiak R, Dumont M, Muriel MP, Santorelli FM, Brice A, El Hachimi KH, Stevanin G, Darios F, Loss of spatacsin function alters lysosomal lipid clearance leading to upper and lower motor neuron degeneration, Neurobiol Dis 102 (2017) 21&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5391847</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28237315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirst J, Borner GH, Edgar J, Hein MY, Mann M, Buchholz F, Antrobus R, Robinson MS, Interaction between AP-5 and the hereditary spastic paraplegia proteins SPG11 and SPG15, Mol Biol Cell 24(16) (2013) 2558&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3744948</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23825025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanein S, Martin E, Boukhris A, Byrne P, Goizet C, Hamri A, Benomar A, Lossos A, Denora P, Fernandez J, Elleuch N, Forlani S, Durr A, Feki I, Hutchinson M, Santorelli FM, Mhiri C, Brice A, Stevanin G, Identification of the SPG15 gene, encoding spastizin, as a frequent cause of complicated autosomal-recessive spastic paraplegia, including Kjellin syndrome, Am J Hum Genet 82(4) (2008) 992&#x2013;1002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2427184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18394578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barber CN, Raben DM, Lipid Metabolism Crosstalk in the Brain: Glia and Neurons, Front Cell Neurosci 13 (2019) 212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6536584</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31164804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koutsis G, Lynch DS, Tucci A, Houlden H, Karadima G, Panas M, A novel ABCD1 mutation detected by next generation sequencing in presumed hereditary spastic paraplegia: A 30-year diagnostic delay caused by misleading biochemical findings, J Neurol Sci 355(1&#x2013;2) (2015) 199&#x2013;201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26049658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crow YJ, Zaki MS, Abdel-Hamid MS, Abdel-Salam G, Boespflug-Tanguy O, Cordeiro NJ, Gleeson JG, Gowrinathan NR, Laugel V, Renaldo F, Rodriguez D, Livingston JH, Rice GI, Mutations in ADAR1, IHH1, and RNASEH2B presenting as spastic paraplegia, Neuropediatrics 45(6) (2014) 386&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25243380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coutelier M, Goizet C, Durr A, Habarou F, Morais S, Dionne-Laporte A, Tao F, Konop J, Stoll M, Charles P, Jacoupy M, Matusiak R, Alonso I, Tallaksen C, Mairey M, Kennerson M, Gaussen M, Schule R, Janin M, Morice-Picard F, Durand CM, Depienne C, Calvas P, Coutinho P, Saudubray JM, Rouleau G, Brice A, Nicholson G, Darios F, Loureiro JL, Zuchner S, Ottolenghi C, Mochel F, Stevanin G, Alteration of ornithine metabolism leads to dominant and recessive hereditary spastic paraplegia, Brain 138(Pt 8) (2015) 2191&#x2013;205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4553756</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26026163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panza E, Escamilla-Honrubia JM, Marco-Marin C, Gougeard N, De Michele G, Morra VB, Liguori R, Salviati L, Donati MA, Cusano R, Pippucci T, Ravazzolo R, Nemeth AH, Smithson S, Davies S, Hurst JA, Bordo D, Rubio V, Seri M, ALDH18A1 gene mutations cause dominant spastic paraplegia SPG9: loss of function effect and plausibility of a dominant negative mechanism, Brain 139(Pt 1) (2016) e3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26297558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rizzo WB, Carney G, Lin Z, The molecular basis of Sjogren-Larsson syndrome: mutation analysis of the fatty aldehyde dehydrogenase gene, Am J Hum Genet 65(6) (1999) 1547&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1288365</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10577908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon N, Sjogren-Larsson syndrome, Dev Med Child Neurol 49(2) (2007) 152&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17254005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Novarino G, Fenstermaker AG, Zaki MS, Hofree M, Silhavy JL, Heiberg AD, Abdellateef M, Rosti B, Scott E, Mansour L, Masri A, Kayserili H, Al-Aama JY, Abdel-Salam GMH, Karminejad A, Kara M, Kara B, Bozorgmehri B, Ben-Omran T, Mojahedi F, El Din Mahmoud IG, Bouslam N, Bouhouche A, Benomar A, Hanein S, Raymond L, Forlani S, Mascaro M, Selim L, Shehata N, Al-Allawi N, Bindu PS, Azam M, Gunel M, Caglayan A, Bilguvar K, Tolun A, Issa MY, Schroth J, Spencer EG, Rosti RO, Akizu N, Vaux KK, Johansen A, Koh AA, Megahed H, Durr A, Brice A, Stevanin G, Gabriel SB, Ideker T, Gleeson JG, Exome sequencing links corticospinal motor neuron disease to common neurodegenerative disorders, Science 343(6170) (2014) 506&#x2013;511.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4157572</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24482476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blumkin L, Lerman-Sagie T, Lev D, Yosovich K, Leshinsky-Silver E, A new locus (SPG47) maps to 1p13.2-1p12 in an Arabic family with complicated autosomal recessive hereditary spastic paraplegia and thin corpus callosum, J Neurol Sci 305(1&#x2013;2) (2011) 67&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21440262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreno-De-Luca A, Helmers SL, Mao H, Burns TG, Melton AM, Schmidt KR, Fernhoff PM, Ledbetter DH, Martin CL, Adaptor protein complex-4 (AP-4) deficiency causes a novel autosomal recessive cerebral palsy syndrome with microcephaly and intellectual disability, J Med Genet 48(2) (2011) 141&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3150730</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20972249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verkerk AJ, Schot R, Dumee B, Schellekens K, Swagemakers S, Bertoli-Avella AM, Lequin MH, Dudink J, Govaert P, van Zwol AL, Hirst J, Wessels MW, Catsman-Berrevoets C, Verheijen FW, de Graaff E, de Coo IF, Kros JM, Willemsen R, Willems PJ, van der Spek PJ, Mancini GM, Mutation in the AP4M1 gene provides a model for neuroaxonal injury in cerebral palsy, Am J Hum Genet 85(1) (2009) 40&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2706965</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19559397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Najmabadi H, Hu H, Garshasbi M, Zemojtel T, Abedini SS, Chen W, Hosseini M, Behjati F, Haas S, Jamali P, Zecha A, Mohseni M, Puttmann L, Vahid LN, Jensen C, Moheb LA, Bienek M, Larti F, Mueller I, Weissmann R, Darvish H, Wrogemann K, Hadavi V, Lipkowitz B, Esmaeeli-Nieh S, Wieczorek D, Kariminejad R, Firouzabadi SG, Cohen M, Fattahi Z, Rost I, Mojahedi F, Hertzberg C, Dehghan A, Rajab A, Banavandi MJ, Hoffer J, Falah M, Musante L, Kalscheuer V, Ullmann R, Kuss AW, Tzschach A, Kahrizi K, Ropers HH, Deep sequencing reveals 50 novel genes for recessive cognitive disorders, Nature 478(7367) (2011) 57&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21937992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abou Jamra R, Philippe O, Raas-Rothschild A, Eck SH, Graf E, Buchert R, Borck G, Ekici A, Brockschmidt FF, Nothen MM, Munnich A, Strom TM, Reis A, Colleaux L, Adaptor protein complex 4 deficiency causes severe autosomal-recessive intellectual disability, progressive spastic paraplegia, shy character, and short stature, Am J Hum Genet 88(6) (2011) 788&#x2013;795.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3113253</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21620353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slabicki M, Theis M, Krastev DB, Samsonov S, Mundwiller E, Junqueira M, Paszkowski-Rogacz M, Teyra J, Heninger AK, Poser I, Prieur F, Truchetto J, Confavreux C, Marelli C, Durr A, Camdessanche JP, Brice A, Shevchenko A, Pisabarro MT, Stevanin G, Buchholz F, A genome-scale DNA repair RNAi screen identifies SPG48 as a novel gene associated with hereditary spastic paraplegia, PLoS Biol 8(6) (2010) e1000408.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2893954</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20613862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darios F, Mochel F, Stevanin G, Lipids in the Physiopathology of Hereditary Spastic Paraplegias, Front Neurosci 14 (2020) 74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7059351</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32180696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lo Giudice T, Lombardi F, Santorelli FM, Kawarai T, Orlacchio A, Hereditary spastic paraplegia: clinical-genetic characteristics and evolving molecular mechanisms, Exp Neurol 261 (2014) 518&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24954637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooper HM, Yang Y, Ylikallio E, Khairullin R, Woldegebriel R, Lin KL, Euro L, Palin E, Wolf A, Trokovic R, Isohanni P, Kaakkola S, Auranen M, Lonnqvist T, Wanrooij S, Tyynismaa H, ATPase-deficient mitochondrial inner membrane protein ATAD3A disturbs mitochondrial dynamics in dominant hereditary spastic paraplegia, Hum Mol Genet 26(8) (2017) 1432&#x2013;1443.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5393146</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28158749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao X, Alvarado D, Rainier S, Lemons R, Hedera P, Weber CH, Tukel T, Apak M, Heiman-Patterson T, Ming L, Bui M, Fink JK, Mutations in a newly identified GTPase gene cause autosomal dominant hereditary spastic paraplegia, Nat Genet 29(3) (2001) 326&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11685207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Estrada-Cuzcano A, Martin S, Chamova T, Synofzik M, Timmann D, Holemans T, Andreeva A, Reichbauer J, De Rycke R, Chang DI, van Veen S, Samuel J, Schols L, Poppel T, Mollerup Sorensen D, Asselbergh B, Klein C, Zuchner S, Jordanova A, Vangheluwe P, Tournev I, Schule R, Loss-of-function mutations in the ATP13A2/PARK9 gene cause complicated hereditary spastic paraplegia (SPG78), Brain 140(2) (2017) 287&#x2013;305.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5278306</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28137957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boukhris A, Schule R, Loureiro JL, Lourenco CM, Mundwiller E, Gonzalez MA, Charles P, Gauthier J, Rekik I, Acosta Lebrigio RF, Gaussen M, Speziani F, Ferbert A, Feki I, Caballero-Oteyza A, Dionne-Laporte A, Amri M, Noreau A, Forlani S, Cruz VT, Mochel F, Coutinho P, Dion P, Mhiri C, Schols L, Pouget J, Darios F, Rouleau GA, Marques W Jr., Brice A, Durr A, Zuchner S, Stevanin G, Alteration of ganglioside biosynthesis responsible for complex hereditary spastic paraplegia, Am J Hum Genet 93(1) (2013) 118&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3710753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23746551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Redwine WB, DeSantis ME, Hollyer I, Htet ZM, Tran PT, Swanson SK, Florens L, Washburn MP, Reck-Peterson SL, The human cytoplasmic dynein interactome reveals novel activators of motility, Elife 6 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5533585</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28718761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oates EC, Rossor AM, Hafezparast M, Gonzalez M, Speziani F, MacArthur DG, Lek M, Cottenie E, Scoto M, Foley AR, Hurles M, Houlden H, Greensmith L, Auer-Grumbach M, Pieber TR, Strom TM, Schule R, Herrmann DN, Sowden JE, Acsadi G, Menezes MP, Clarke NF, Zuchner S, Uk10K, Muntoni F, North KN, Reilly MM, Mutations in BICD2 cause dominant congenital spinal muscular atrophy and hereditary spastic paraplegia, Am J Hum Genet 92(6) (2013) 965&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3675232</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23664120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Windpassinger C, Auer-Grumbach M, Irobi J, Patel H, Petek E, Horl G, Malli R, Reed JA, Dierick I, Verpoorten N, Warner TT, Proukakis C, Van den Bergh P, Verellen C, Van Maldergem L, Merlini L, De Jonghe P, Timmerman V, Crosby AH, Wagner K, Heterozygous missense mutations in BSCL2 are associated with distal hereditary motor neuropathy and Silver syndrome, Nat Genet 36(3) (2004) 271&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14981520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimazaki H, Takiyama Y, Ishiura H, Sakai C, Matsushima Y, Hatakeyama H, Honda J, Sakoe K, Naoi T, Namekawa M, Fukuda Y, Takahashi Y, Goto J, Tsuji S, Goto Y, Nakano I, Japan C Spastic Paraplegia Research, A homozygous mutation of C12orf65 causes spastic paraplegia with optic atrophy and neuropathy (SPG55), J Med Genet 49(12) (2012) 777&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23188110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Landoure G, Zhu PP, Lourenco CM, Johnson JO, Toro C, Bricceno KV, Rinaldi C, Meilleur KG, Sangare M, Diallo O, Pierson TM, Ishiura H, Tsuji S, Hein N, Fink JK, Stoll M, Nicholson G, Gonzalez MA, Speziani F, Durr A, Stevanin G, Biesecker LG, Center NIHIS, Accardi J, Landis DM, Gahl WA, Traynor BJ, Marques W Jr., Zuchner S, Blackstone C, Fischbeck KH, Burnett BG, Hereditary spastic paraplegia type 43 (SPG43) is caused by mutation in C19orf12, Hum Mutat 34(10) (2013) 1357&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3819934</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23857908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gan-Or Z, Bouslam N, Birouk N, Lissouba A, Chambers DB, Veriepe J, Androschuk A, Laurent SB, Rochefort D, Spiegelman D, Dionne-Laporte A, Szuto A, Liao M, Figlewicz DA, Bouhouche A, Benomar A, Yahyaoui M, Ouazzani R, Yoon G, Dupre N, Suchowersky O, Bolduc FV, Parker JA, Dion PA, Drapeau P, Rouleau GA, Ouled Amar Bencheikh B, Mutations in CAPN1 Cause Autosomal-Recessive Hereditary Spastic Paraplegia, Am J Hum Genet 98(5) (2016) 1038&#x2013;1046.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4863665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27153400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouhouche A, Benomar A, Bouslam N, Chkili T, Yahyaoui M, Mutation in the epsilon subunit of the cytosolic chaperonin-containing t-complex peptide-1 (Cct5) gene causes autosomal recessive mutilating sensory neuropathy with spastic paraplegia, J Med Genet 43(5) (2006) 441&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2564519</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16399879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rinaldi C, Schmidt T, Situ AJ, Johnson JO, Lee PR, Chen KL, Bott LC, Fado R, Harmison GH, Parodi S, Grunseich C, Renvoise B, Biesecker LG, De Michele G, Santorelli FM, Filla A, Stevanin G, Durr A, Brice A, Casals N, Traynor BJ, Blackstone C, Ulmer TS, Fischbeck KH, Mutation in CPT1C Associated With Pure Autosomal Dominant Spastic Paraplegia, JAMA Neurol 72(5) (2015) 561&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5612424</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25751282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tesson C, Nawara M, Salih MA, Rossignol R, Zaki MS, Al Balwi M, Schule R, Mignot C, Obre E, Bouhouche A, Santorelli FM, Durand CM, Oteyza AC, El-Hachimi KH, Al Drees A, Bouslam N, Lamari F, Elmalik SA, Kabiraj MM, Seidahmed MZ, Esteves T, Gaussen M, Monin ML, Gyapay G, Lechner D, Gonzalez M, Depienne C, Mochel F, Lavie J, Schols L, Lacombe D, Yahyaoui M, Al Abdulkareem I, Zuchner S, Yamashita A, Benomar A, Goizet C, Durr A, Gleeson JG, Darios F, Brice A, Stevanin G, Alteration of fatty-acid-metabolizing enzymes affects mitochondrial form and function in hereditary spastic paraplegia, Am J Hum Genet 91(6) (2012) 1051&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3516610</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23176821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salen G, Steiner RD, Epidemiology, diagnosis, and treatment of cerebrotendinous xanthomatosis (CTX), J Inherit Metab Dis 40(6) (2017) 771&#x2013;781.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28980151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilkinson PA, Crosby AH, Turner C, Patel H, Wood NW, Schapira AH, Warner TT, A clinical and genetic study of SPG5A linked autosomal recessive hereditary spastic paraplegia, Neurology 61(2) (2003) 235&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12874406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouslam N, Benomar A, Azzedine H, Bouhouche A, Namekawa M, Klebe S, Charon C, Durr A, Ruberg M, Brice A, Yahyaoui M, Stevanin G, Mapping of a new form of pure autosomal recessive spastic paraplegia (SPG28), Ann Neurol 57(4) (2005) 567&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15786464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuurs-Hoeijmakers JH, Geraghty MT, Kamsteeg EJ, Ben-Salem S, de Bot ST, Nijhof B, van de V II, van der Graaf M, Nobau AC, Otte-Holler I, Vermeer S, Smith AC, Humphreys P, Schwartzentruber J, Consortium FC, Ali BR, Al-Yahyaee SA, Tariq S, Pramathan T, Bayoumi R, Kremer HP, van de Warrenburg BP, van den Akker WM, Gilissen C, Veltman JA, Janssen IM, Vulto-van Silfhout AT, van der Velde-Visser S, Lefeber DJ, Diekstra A, Erasmus CE, Willemsen MA, Vissers LE, Lammens M, van Bokhoven H, Brunner HG, Wevers RA, Schenck A, Al-Gazali L, de Vries BB, de Brouwer AP, Mutations in DDHD2, encoding an intracellular phospholipase A(1), cause a recessive form of complex hereditary spastic paraplegia, Am J Hum Genet 91(6) (2012) 1073&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3516595</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23176823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mueller N, Sassa T, Morales-Gonzalez S, Schneider J, Salchow DJ, Seelow D, Knierim E, Stenzel W, Kihara A, Schuelke M, De novo mutation in ELOVL1 causes ichthyosis, acanthosis nigricans, hypomyelination, spastic paraplegia, high frequency deafness and optic atrophy, J Med Genet 56(3) (2019) 164&#x2013;175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30487246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mamelona J, Crapoulet N, Marrero A, A new case of spastic paraplegia type 64 due to a missense mutation in the ENTPD1 gene, Hum Genome Var 6 (2019) 5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6329766</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30652007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed MY, Al-Khayat A, Al-Murshedi F, Al-Futaisi A, Chioza BA, Pedro Fernandez-Murray J, Self JE, Salter CG, Harlalka GV, Rawlins LE, Al-Zuhaibi S, Al-Azri F, Al-Rashdi F, Cazenave-Gassiot A, Wenk MR, Al-Salmi F, Patton MA, Silver DL, Baple EL, McMaster CR, Crosby AH, A mutation of EPT1 (SELENOI) underlies a new disorder of Kennedy pathway phospholipid biosynthesis, Brain 140(3) (2017) 547&#x2013;554.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5382949</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28052917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horibata Y, Elpeleg O, Eran A, Hirabayashi Y, Savitzki D, Tal G, Mandel H, Sugimoto H, EPT1 (selenoprotein I) is critical for the neural development and maintenance of plasmalogen in humans, J Lipid Res 59(6) (2018) 1015&#x2013;1026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5983406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29500230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alazami AM, Adly N, Al Dhalaan H, Alkuraya FS, A nullimorphic ERLIN2 mutation defines a complicated hereditary spastic paraplegia locus (SPG18), Neurogenetics 12(4) (2011) 333&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3215864</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21796390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dick KJ, Eckhardt M, Paisan-Ruiz C, Alshehhi AA, Proukakis C, Sibtain NA, Maier H, Sharifi R, Patton MA, Bashir W, Koul R, Raeburn S, Gieselmann V, Houlden H, Crosby AH, Mutation of FA2H underlies a complicated form of hereditary spastic paraplegia (SPG35), Hum Mutat 31(4) (2010) E1251&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20104589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y, Liu W, Fang Z, Shi J, Che F, He C, Yao L, Wang E, Wu Y, A Newly Identified Missense Mutation in FARS2 Causes Autosomal-Recessive Spastic Paraplegia, Hum Mutat 37(2) (2016) 165&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26553276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lynex CN, Carr IM, Leek JP, Achuthan R, Mitchell S, Maher ER, Woods CG, Bonthon DT, Markham AF, Homozygosity for a missense mutation in the 67 kDa isoform of glutamate decarboxylase in a family with autosomal recessive spastic cerebral palsy: parallels with Stiff-Person Syndrome and other movement disorders, BMC Neurol 4(1) (2004) 20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC544830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15571623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin E, Schule R, Smets K, Rastetter A, Boukhris A, Loureiro JL, Gonzalez MA, Mundwiller E, Deconinck T, Wessner M, Jornea L, Oteyza AC, Durr A, Martin JJ, Schols L, Mhiri C, Lamari F, Zuchner S, De Jonghe P, Kabashi E, Brice A, Stevanin G, Loss of function of glucocerebrosidase GBA2 is responsible for motor neuron defects in hereditary spastic paraplegia, Am J Hum Genet 92(2) (2013) 238&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3567271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23332916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wassenberg T, Schouten MI, Helmich RC, Willemsen M, Kamsteeg EJ, van de Warrenburg BPC, Autosomal dominant GCH1 mutations causing spastic paraplegia at disease onset, Parkinsonism Relat Disord 74 (2020) 12&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32278297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orthmann-Murphy JL, Salsano E, Abrams CK, Bizzi A, Uziel G, Freidin MM, Lamantea E, Zeviani M, Scherer SS, Pareyson D, Hereditary spastic paraplegia is a novel phenotype for GJA12/GJC2 mutations, Brain 132(Pt 2) (2009) 426&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2640216</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19056803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faber I, Prota JR, Martinez AR, Lopes-Cendes I, Franca MCJ, A new phenotype associated with homozygous GRN mutations: complicated spastic paraplegia, Eur J Neurol 24(1) (2017) e3&#x2013;e4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28000352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bross P, Naundrup S, Hansen J, Nielsen MN, Christensen JH, Kruhoffer M, Palmfeldt J, Corydon TJ, Gregersen N, Ang D, Georgopoulos C, Nielsen KL, The Hsp60-(p.V98I) mutation associated with hereditary spastic paraplegia SPG13 compromises chaperonin function both in vitro and in vivo, J Biol Chem 283(23) (2008) 15694&#x2013;700.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3259655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18400758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lossos A, Stumpfig C, Stevanin G, Gaussen M, Zimmerman BE, Mundwiller E, Asulin M, Chamma L, Sheffer R, Misk A, Dotan S, Gomori JM, Ponger P, Brice A, Lerer I, Meiner V, Lill R, Fe/S protein assembly gene IBA57 mutation causes hereditary spastic paraplegia, Neurology 84(7) (2015) 659&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25609768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu N, Chen J, Xu C, Shi T, Li J, Hereditary spastic paraplegia associated with a rare IFIH1 mutation: a case report and literature review, Hereditas 156 (2019) 28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6693153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31427910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helbig KL, Hedrich UB, Shinde DN, Krey I, Teichmann AC, Hentschel J, Schubert J, Chamberlin AC, Huether R, Lu HM, Alcaraz WA, Tang S, Jungbluth C, Dugan SL, Vainionpaa L, Karle KN, Synofzik M, Schols L, Schule R, Lehesjoki AE, Helbig I, Lerche H, Lemke JR, A recurrent mutation in KCNA2 as a novel cause of hereditary spastic paraplegia and ataxia, Ann Neurol 80(4) (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5129488</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27543892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valdmanis PN, Meijer IA, Reynolds A, Lei A, MacLeod P, Schlesinger D, Zatz M, Reid E, Dion PA, Drapeau P, Rouleau GA, Mutations in the KIAA0196 gene at the SPG8 locus cause hereditary spastic paraplegia, Am J Hum Genet 80(1) (2007) 152&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1785307</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17160902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erlich Y, Edvardson S, Hodges E, Zenvirt S, Thekkat P, Shaag A, Dor T, Hannon GJ, Elpeleg O, Exome sequencing and disease-network analysis of a single family implicate a mutation in KIF1A in hereditary spastic paraparesis, Genome Res 21(5) (2011) 658&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3083082</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21487076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dor T, Cinnamon Y, Raymond L, Shaag A, Bouslam N, Bouhouche A, Gaussen M, Meyer V, Durr A, Brice A, Benomar A, Stevanin G, Schuelke M, Edvardson S, KIF1C mutations in two families with hereditary spastic paraparesis and cerebellar dysfunction, J Med Genet 51(2) (2014) 137&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24319291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fichera M, Lo Giudice M, Falco M, Sturnio M, Amata S, Calabrese O, Bigoni S, Calzolari E, Neri M, Evidence of kinesin heavy chain (KIF5A) involvement in pure hereditary spastic paraplegia, Neurology 63(6) (2004) 1108&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15452312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macedo-Souza LI, Kok F, Santos S, Amorim SC, Starling A, Nishimura A, Lezirovitz K, Lino AM, Zatz M, Spastic paraplegia, optic atrophy, and neuropathy is linked to chromosome 11q13, Ann Neurol 57(5) (2005) 730&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15852396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blanco G, Coulton GR, Biggin A, Grainge C, Moss J, Barrett M, Berquin A, Marechal G, Skynner M, van Mier P, Nikitopoulou A, Kraus M, Ponting CP, Mason RM, Brown SD, The kyphoscoliosis (ky) mouse is deficient in hypertrophic responses and is caused by a mutation in a novel muscle-specific protein, Hum Mol Genet 10(1) (2001) 9&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11136708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jouet M, Rosenthal A, Armstrong G, MacFarlane J, Stevenson R, Paterson J, Metzenberg A, Ionasescu V, Temple K, Kenwrick S, X-linked spastic paraplegia (SPG1), MASA syndrome and X-linked hydrocephalus result from mutations in the L1 gene, Nat Genet 7(3) (1994) 402&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7920659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimazaki H, Honda J, Naoi T, Namekawa M, Nakano I, Yazaki M, Nakamura K, Yoshida K, Ikeda S, Ishiura H, Fukuda Y, Takahashi Y, Goto J, Tsuji S, Takiyama Y, Autosomal-recessive complicated spastic paraplegia with a novel lysosomal trafficking regulator gene mutation, J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 85(9) (2014) 1024&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24521565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mou Y, Li XJ, Rescue axonal defects by targeting mitochondrial dynamics in hereditary spastic paraplegias, Neural Regen Res 14(4) (2019) 574&#x2013;577.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6352593</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30632492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verny C, Guegen N, Desquiret V, Chevrollier A, Prundean A, Dubas F, Cassereau J, Ferre M, Amati-Bonneau P, Bonneau D, Reynier P, Procaccio V, Hereditary spastic paraplegia-like disorder due to a mitochondrial ATP6 gene point mutation, Mitochondrion 11(1) (2011) 70&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20656066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Svenstrup K, Moller RS, Christensen J, Budtz-Jorgensen E, Gilling M, Nielsen JE, NIPA1 mutation in complex hereditary spastic paraplegia with epilepsy, Eur J Neurol 18(9) (2011) 1197&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21599812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martinez-Lage M, Molina-Porcel L, Falcone D, McCluskey L, Lee VM, Van Deerlin VM, Trojanowski JQ, TDP-43 pathology in a case of hereditary spastic paraplegia with a NIPA1/SPG6 mutation, Acta Neuropathol 124(2) (2012) 285&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3361549</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22302102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu-Wai-Man P, Griffiths PG, Gorman GS, Lourenco CM, Wright AF, Auer-Grumbach M, Toscano A, Musumeci O, Valentino ML, Caporali L, Lamperti C, Tallaksen CM, Duffey P, Miller J, Whittaker RG, Baker MR, Jackson MJ, Clarke MP, Dhillon B, Czermin B, Stewart JD, Hudson G, Reynier P, Bonneau D, Marques W Jr., Lenaers G, McFarland R, Taylor RW, Turnbull DM, Votruba M, Zeviani M, Carelli V, Bindoff LA, Horvath R, Amati-Bonneau P, Chinnery PF, Multi-system neurological disease is common in patients with OPA1 mutations, Brain 133(Pt 3) (2010) 771&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2842512</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20157015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yahalom G, Anikster Y, Huna-Baron R, Hoffmann C, Blumkin L, Lev D, Tsabari R, Nitsan Z, Lerman SF, Ben-Zeev B, Pode-Shakked B, Sofer S, Schweiger A, Lerman-Sagie T, Hassin-Baer S, Costeff syndrome: clinical features and natural history, J Neurol 261(12) (2014) 2275&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25201222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozes B, Karagoz N, Schule R, Rebelo A, Sobrido MJ, Harmuth F, Synofzik M, Pascual SIP, Colak M, Ciftci-Kavaklioglu B, Kara B, Ordonez-Ugalde A, Quintans B, Gonzalez MA, Soysal A, Zuchner S, Battaloglu E, PLA2G6 mutations associated with a continuous clinical spectrum from neuroaxonal dystrophy to hereditary spastic paraplegia, Clin Genet 92(5) (2017) 534&#x2013;539.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5597457</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28295203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cambi F, Tang XM, Cordray P, Fain PR, Keppen LD, Barker DF, Refined genetic mapping and proteolipid protein mutation analysis in X-linked pure hereditary spastic paraplegia, Neurology 46(4) (1996) 1112&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8780101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rainier S, Bui M, Mark E, Thomas D, Tokarz D, Ming L, Delaney C, Richardson RJ, Albers JW, Matsunami N, Stevens J, Coon H, Leppert M, Fink JK, Neuropathy target esterase gene mutations cause motor neuron disease, Am J Hum Genet 82(3) (2008) 780&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2427280</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18313024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gauquelin L, Tetreault M, Thiffault I, Farrow E, Miller N, Yoo B, Bareke E, Yoon G, Suchowersky O, Dupre N, Tarnopolsky M, Brais B, Wolf NI, Majewski J, Rouleau GA, Gan-Or Z, Bernard G, POLR3A variants in hereditary spastic paraplegia and ataxia, Brain 141(1) (2018) e1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5837469</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29228109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tinti M, Johnson C, Toth R, Ferrier DE, Mackintosh C, Evolution of signal multiplexing by 14-3-3-binding 2R-ohnologue protein families in the vertebrates, Open Biol 2(7) (2012) 120103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3411107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22870394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beetz C, Schule R, Deconinck T, Tran-Viet KN, Zhu H, Kremer BP, Frints SG, van Zelst-Stams WA, Byrne P, Otto S, Nygren AO, Baets J, Smets K, Ceulemans B, Dan B, Nagan N, Kassubek J, Klimpe S, Klopstock T, Stolze H, Smeets HJ, Schrander-Stumpel CT, Hutchinson M, van de Warrenburg BP, Braastad C, Deufel T, Pericak-Vance M, Schols L, de Jonghe P, Zuchner S, REEP1 mutation spectrum and genotype/phenotype correlation in hereditary spastic paraplegia type 31, Brain 131(Pt 4) (2008) 1078&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2841798</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18321925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esteves T, Durr A, Mundwiller E, Loureiro JL, Boutry M, Gonzalez MA, Gauthier J, El-Hachimi KH, Depienne C, Muriel MP, Acosta Lebrigio RF, Gaussen M, Noreau A, Speziani F, Dionne-Laporte A, Deleuze JF, Dion P, Coutinho P, Rouleau GA, Zuchner S, Brice A, Stevanin G, Darios F, Loss of association of REEP2 with membranes leads to hereditary spastic paraplegia, Am J Hum Genet 94(2) (2014) 268&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3928657</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24388663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee JYW, Hsu CK, Michael M, Nanda A, Liu L, McMillan JR, Pourreyron C, Takeichi T, Tolar J, Reid E, Hayday T, Blumen SC, Abu-Mouch S, Straussberg R, Basel-Vanagaite L, Barhum Y, Zouabi Y, Al-Ajmi H, Huang HY, Lin TC, Akiyama M, Lee JYY, McLean WHI, Simpson MA, Parsons M, McGrath JA, Large Intragenic Deletion in DSTYK Underlies Autosomal-Recessive Complicated Spastic Paraparesis, SPG23, Am J Hum Genet 100(2) (2017) 364&#x2013;370.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5294675</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28157540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montenegro G, Rebelo AP, Connell J, Allison R, Babalini C, D&#x2019;Aloia M, Montieri P, Schule R, Ishiura H, Price J, Strickland A, Gonzalez MA, Baumbach-Reardon L, Deconinck T, Huang J, Bernardi G, Vance JM, Rogers MT, Tsuji S, De Jonghe P, Pericak-Vance MA, Schols L, Orlacchio A, Reid E, Zuchner S, Mutations in the ER-shaping protein reticulon 2 cause the axon-degenerative disorder hereditary spastic paraplegia type 12, J Clin Invest 122(2) (2012) 538&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3266795</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22232211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roeben B, Schule R, Ruf S, Bender B, Alhaddad B, Benkert T, Meitinger T, Reich S, Bohringer J, Langhans CD, Vaz FM, Wortmann SB, Marquardt T, Haack TB, Krageloh-Mann I, Schols L, Synofzik M, SERAC1 deficiency causes complicated HSP: evidence from a novel splice mutation in a large family, J Med Genet 55(1) (2018) 39&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28916646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elert-Dobkowska E, Stepniak I, Krysa W, Ziora-Jakutowicz K, Rakowicz M, Sobanska A, Pilch J, Antczak-Marach D, Zaremba J, Sulek A, Next-generation sequencing study reveals the broader variant spectrum of hereditary spastic paraplegia and related phenotypes, Neurogenetics 20(1) (2019) 27&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6411833</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30778698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Capri Y, Friesema EC, Kersseboom S, Touraine R, Monnier A, Eymard-Pierre E, Des Portes V, De Michele G, Brady AF, Boespflug-Tanguy O, Visser TJ, Vaurs-Barriere C, Relevance of different cellular models in determining the effects of mutations on SLC16A2/MCT8 thyroid hormone transporter function and genotype-phenotype correlation, Hum Mutat 34(7) (2013) 1018&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23568789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bialer MG, Lawrence L, Stevenson RE, Silverberg G, Williams MK, Arena JF, Lubs HA, Schwartz CE, Allan-Herndon-Dudley syndrome: clinical and linkage studies on a second family, Am J Med Genet 43(1&#x2013;2) (1992) 491&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1605231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin P, Li J, Liu Q, Mao F, Li J, Qiu R, Hu H, Song Y, Yang Y, Gao G, Yan C, Yang W, Shao C, Gong Y, A missense mutation in SLC33A1, which encodes the acetyl-CoA transporter, causes autosomal-dominant spastic paraplegia (SPG42), Am J Hum Genet 83(6) (2008) 752&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2668077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19061983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel H, Cross H, Proukakis C, Hershberger R, Bork P, Ciccarelli FD, Patton MA, McKusick VA, Crosby AH, SPG20 is mutated in Troyer syndrome, an hereditary spastic paraplegia, Nat Genet 31(4) (2002) 347&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12134148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charvin D, Cifuentes-Diaz C, Fonknechten N, Joshi V, Hazan J, Melki J, Betuing S, Mutations of SPG4 are responsible for a loss of function of spastin, an abundant neuronal protein localized in the nucleus, Hum Mol Genet 12(1) (2003) 71&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12490534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simpson MA, Cross H, Proukakis C, Pryde A, Hershberger R, Chatonnet A, Patton MA, Crosby AH, Maspardin is mutated in mast syndrome, a complicated form of hereditary spastic paraplegia associated with dementia, Am J Hum Genet 73(5) (2003) 1147&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1180493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14564668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warnecke T, Duning T, Schwan A, Lohmann H, Epplen JT, Young P, A novel form of autosomal recessive hereditary spastic paraplegia caused by a new SPG7 mutation, Neurology 69(4) (2007) 368&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17646629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wijemanne S, Shulman JM, Jimenez-Shahed J, Curry D, Jankovic J, SPG11 Mutations Associated With a Complex Phenotype Resembling Dopa-Responsive Dystonia, Mov Disord Clin Pract 2(2) (2015) 149&#x2013;154.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6183009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30363882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oz-Levi D, Ben-Zeev B, Ruzzo EK, Hitomi Y, Gelman A, Pelak K, Anikster Y, Reznik-Wolf H, Bar-Joseph I, Olender T, Alkelai A, Weiss M, Ben-Asher E, Ge D, Shianna KV, Elazar Z, Goldstein DB, Pras E, Lancet D, Mutation in TECPR2 reveals a role for autophagy in hereditary spastic paraparesis, Am J Hum Genet 91(6) (2012) 1065&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3516605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23176824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beetz C, Johnson A, Schuh AL, Thakur S, Varga RE, Fothergill T, Hertel N, Bomba-Warczak E, Thiele H, Nurnberg G, Altmuller J, Saxena R, Chapman ER, Dent EW, Nurnberg P, Audhya A, Inhibition of TFG function causes hereditary axon degeneration by impairing endoplasmic reticulum structure, Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 110(13) (2013) 5091&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3612678</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23479643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evangelista T, Bansagi B, Pyle A, Griffin H, Douroudis K, Polvikoski T, Antoniadi T, Bushby K, Straub V, Chinnery PF, Lochmuller H, Horvath R, Phenotypic variability of TRPV4 related neuropathies, Neuromuscul Disord 25(6) (2015) 516&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4454778</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25900305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vulinovic F, Krajka V, Hausrat TJ, Seibler P, Alvarez-Fischer D, Madoev H, Park JS, Kumar KR, Sue CM, Lohmann K, Kneussel M, Klein C, Rakovic A, Motor protein binding and mitochondrial transport are altered by pathogenic TUBB4A variants, Hum Mutat 39(12) (2018) 1901&#x2013;1915.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30079973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bilguvar K, Tyagi NK, Ozkara C, Tuysuz B, Bakircioglu M, Choi M, Delil S, Caglayan AO, Baranoski JF, Erturk O, Yalcinkaya C, Karacorlu M, Dincer A, Johnson MH, Mane S, Chandra SS, Louvi A, Boggon TJ, Lifton RP, Horwich AL, Gunel M, Recessive loss of function of the neuronal ubiquitin hydrolase UCHL1 leads to early-onset progressive neurodegeneration, Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 110(9) (2013) 3489&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3587195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23359680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shih YT, Hsueh YP, The involvement of endoplasmic reticulum formation and protein synthesis efficiency in VCP- and ATL1-related neurological disorders, J Biomed Sci 25(1) (2018) 2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5757295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29310658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zivony-Elboum Y, Westbroek W, Kfir N, Savitzki D, Shoval Y, Bloom A, Rod R, Khayat M, Gross B, Samri W, Cohen H, Sonkin V, Freidman T, Geiger D, Fattal-Valevski A, Anikster Y, Waters AM, Kleta R, Falik-Zaccai TC, A founder mutation in Vps37A causes autosomal recessive complex hereditary spastic paraparesis, J Med Genet 49(7) (2012) 462&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22717650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes CA, Byrne PC, Webb S, McMonagle P, Patterson V, Hutchinson M, Parfrey NA, SPG15, a new locus for autosomal recessive complicated HSP on chromosome 14q, Neurology 56(9) (2001) 1230&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11342696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mannan AU, Krawen P, Sauter SM, Boehm J, Chronowska A, Paulus W, Neesen J, Engel W, ZFYVE27 (SPG33), a novel spastin-binding protein, is mutated in hereditary spastic paraplegia, Am J Hum Genet 79(2) (2006) 351&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1559503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16826525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mintchev N, Zamba-Papanicolaou E, Kleopa KA, Christodoulou K, A novel ALS2 splice-site mutation in a Cypriot juvenile-onset primary lateral sclerosis family, Neurology 72(1) (2009) 28&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19122027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Saif A, Bohlega S, Al-Mohanna F, Loss of ERLIN2 function leads to juvenile primary lateral sclerosis, Ann Neurol 72(4) (2012) 510&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23109145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dupre N, Valdmanis PN, Bouchard JP, Rouleau GA, Autosomal dominant primary lateral sclerosis, Neurology 68(14) (2007) 1156&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17404201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y, Zhang L, Lynch DR, Lukas T, Ahmeti K, Sleiman PM, Ryan E, Schadt KA, Newman JH, Deng HX, Siddique N, Siddique T, Compound heterozygote mutations in SPG7 in a family with adult-onset primary lateral sclerosis, Neurol Genet 2(2) (2016) e60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4830188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27123479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goizet C, Depienne C, Benard G, Boukhris A, Mundwiller E, Sole G, Coupry I, Pilliod J, Martin-Negrier ML, Fedirko E, Forlani S, Cazeneuve C, Hannequin D, Charles P, Feki I, Pinel JF, Ouvrard-Hernandez AM, Lyonnet S, Ollagnon-Roman E, Yaouanq J, Toutain A, Dussert C, Fontaine B, Leguern E, Lacombe D, Durr A, Rossignol R, Brice A, Stevanin G, REEP1 mutations in SPG31: frequency, mutational spectrum, and potential association with mitochondrial morpho-functional dysfunction, Hum Mutat 32(10) (2011) 1118&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21618648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar KR, Blair NF, Sue CM, An Update on the Hereditary Spastic Paraplegias: New Genes and New Disease Models, Mov Disord Clin Pract 2(3) (2015) 213&#x2013;223.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6353461</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30838228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Urwin H, Ghazi-Noori S, Collinge J, Isaacs A, The role of CHMP2B in frontotemporal dementia, Biochem Soc Trans 37(Pt 1) (2009) 208&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19143633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waegaert R, Dirrig-Grosch S, Parisot F, Keime C, Henriques A, Loeffler JP, Rene F, Longitudinal transcriptomic analysis of altered pathways in a CHMP2B(intron5)-based model of ALS-FTD, Neurobiol Dis 136 (2020) 104710.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31837425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inloes JM, Kiosses WB, Wang H, Walther TC, Farese RV Jr., Cravatt BF, Functional Contribution of the Spastic Paraplegia-Related Triglyceride Hydrolase DDHD2 to the Formation and Content of Lipid Droplets, Biochemistry 57(5) (2018) 827&#x2013;838.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5854151</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29278326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez M, Nampoothiri S, Kornblum C, Oteyza AC, Walter J, Konidari I, Hulme W, Speziani F, Schols L, Zuchner S, Schule R, Mutations in phospholipase DDHD2 cause autosomal recessive hereditary spastic paraplegia (SPG54), Eur J Hum Genet 21(11) (2013) 1214&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3798837</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23486545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J, Liu Q, Cholesterol metabolism and homeostasis in the brain, Protein Cell 6(4) (2015) 254&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4383754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25682154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wigger D, Gulbins E, Kleuser B, Schumacher F, Monitoring the Sphingolipid de novo Synthesis by Stable-Isotope Labeling and Liquid Chromatography-Mass Spectrometry, Front Cell Dev Biol 7 (2019) 210.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6779703</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31632963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berg JM, Tymoczko JL, Stryer L, The complex regulation of cholesterol biosynthesis takes place at several levels, Biochemistry, W H Freeman, New York, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huff T, Jialal I, Physiology, Cholesterol, StatPearls, Treasure Island (FL), 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bjorkhem I, Meaney S, Brain cholesterol: long secret life behind a barrier, Arterioscler Thromb Vasc Biol 24(5) (2004) 806&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14764421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olsen BN, Schlesinger PH, Ory DS, Baker NA, Side-chain oxysterols: from cells to membranes to molecules, Biochim Biophys Acta 1818(2) (2012) 330&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3197895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21745458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gosselet F, Saint-Pol J, Fenart L, Effects of oxysterols on the blood-brain barrier: implications for Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease, Biochem Biophys Res Commun 446(3) (2014) 687&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24275140</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goizet C, Boukhris A, Durr A, Beetz C, Truchetto J, Tesson C, Tsaousidou M, Forlani S, Guyant-Marechal L, Fontaine B, Guimaraes J, Isidor B, Chazouilleres O, Wendum D, Grid D, Chevy F, Chinnery PF, Coutinho P, Azulay JP, Feki I, Mochel F, Wolf C, Mhiri C, Crosby A, Brice A, Stevanin G, CYP7B1 mutations in pure and complex forms of hereditary spastic paraplegia type 5, Brain 132(Pt 6) (2009) 1589&#x2013;600.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19439420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schule R, Siddique T, Deng HX, Yang Y, Donkervoort S, Hansson M, Madrid RE, Siddique N, Schols L, Bjorkhem I, Marked accumulation of 27-hydroxycholesterol in SPG5 patients with hereditary spastic paresis, J Lipid Res 51(4) (2010) 819&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2842155</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19812052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartke N, Hannun YA, Bioactive sphingolipids: metabolism and function, J Lipid Res 50 Suppl (2009) S91&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2674734</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19017611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schneider N, Hauser J, Oliveira M, Cazaubon E, Mottaz SC, O&#x2019;Neill BV, Steiner P, Deoni SCL, Sphingomyelin in Brain and Cognitive Development: Preliminary Data, eNeuro 6(4) (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6709232</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31324675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zoller I, Meixner M, Hartmann D, Bussow H, Meyer R, Gieselmann V, Eckhardt M, Absence of 2-hydroxylated sphingolipids is compatible with normal neural development but causes late-onset axon and myelin sheath degeneration, J Neurosci 28(39) (2008) 9741&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6671223</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18815260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Potter KA, Kern MJ, Fullbright G, Bielawski J, Scherer SS, Yum SW, Li JJ, Cheng H, Han X, Venkata JK, Khan PA, Rohrer B, Hama H, Central nervous system dysfunction in a mouse model of FA2H deficiency, Glia 59(7) (2011) 1009&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3094470</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21491498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dan P, Edvardson S, Bielawski J, Hama H, Saada A, 2-Hydroxylated sphingomyelin profiles in cells from patients with mutated fatty acid 2-hydroxylase, Lipids Health Dis 10 (2011) 84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3107802</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21599921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips MJ, Voeltz GK, Structure and function of ER membrane contact sites with other organelles, Nat Rev Mol Cell Biol 17(2) (2016) 69&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5117888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26627931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jara JH, Genc B, Cox GA, Bohn MC, Roos RP, Macklis JD, Ulupinar E, Ozdinler PH, Corticospinal Motor Neurons Are Susceptible to Increased ER Stress and Display Profound Degeneration in the Absence of UCHL1 Function, Cereb Cortex 25(11) (2015) 4259&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4626833</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25596590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gautam M, Jara JH, Kocak N, Rylaarsdam LE, Kim KD, Bigio EH, Hande Ozdinler P, Mitochondria, ER, and nuclear membrane defects reveal early mechanisms for upper motor neuron vulnerability with respect to TDP-43 pathology, Acta Neuropathol 137(1) (2019) 47&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6339587</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30450515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pollard W.C.E. Thomas D., Lippincott-Schwartz Jennifer, Johnson Graham T., Endoplasmic Reticulum, Cell Biology, Elsevier; 2017, pp. 331&#x2013;350.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blom T, Somerharju P, Ikonen E, Synthesis and biosynthetic trafficking of membrane lipids, Cold Spring Harb Perspect Biol 3(8) (2011) a004713.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3140686</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21482741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson CL, Walch L, Verbavatz JM, Lipids and Their Trafficking: An Integral Part of Cellular Organization, Dev Cell 39(2) (2016) 139&#x2013;153.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27780039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lev S, Nonvesicular lipid transfer from the endoplasmic reticulum, Cold Spring Harb Perspect Biol 4(10) (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3475164</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23028121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balla T, Sengupta N, Kim YJ, Lipid synthesis and transport are coupled to regulate membrane lipid dynamics in the endoplasmic reticulum, Biochim Biophys Acta Mol Cell Biol Lipids 1865(1) (2020) 158461.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6858525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31108203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krahmer N, Guo Y, Wilfling F, Hilger M, Lingrell S, Heger K, Newman HW, Schmidt-Supprian M, Vance DE, Mann M, Farese RV Jr., Walther TC, Phosphatidylcholine synthesis for lipid droplet expansion is mediated by localized activation of CTP:phosphocholine cytidylyltransferase, Cell Metab 14(4) (2011) 504&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3735358</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21982710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Welte MA, Expanding roles for lipid droplets, Curr Biol 25(11) (2015) R470&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4452895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26035793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kociucka B, Flisikowska T, Mroz D, Szczerbal I, Expression of genes involved in lipid droplet formation (BSCL2, SNAP23 and COPA) during porcine in vitro adipogenesis, J Appl Genet 57(4) (2016) 505&#x2013;510.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5061828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27108337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurahashi T, Hamashima S, Shirato T, Lee J, Homma T, Kang ES, Fujii J, An SOD1 deficiency enhances lipid droplet accumulation in the fasted mouse liver by aborting lipophagy, Biochem Biophys Res Commun 467(4) (2015) 866&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26474701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pennetta G, Welte MA, Emerging Links between Lipid Droplets and Motor Neuron Diseases, Dev Cell 45(4) (2018) 427&#x2013;432.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5988256</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29787708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilfling F, Wang H, Haas JT, Krahmer N, Gould TJ, Uchida A, Cheng JX, Graham M, Christiano R, Frohlich F, Liu X, Buhman KK, Coleman RA, Bewersdorf J, Farese RV Jr., Walther TC, Triacylglycerol synthesis enzymes mediate lipid droplet growth by relocalizing from the ER to lipid droplets, Dev Cell 24(4) (2013) 384&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3727400</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23415954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu J, Loh K, Song ZY, Yang HQ, Zhang Y, Lin S, Update on glycerol-3-phosphate acyltransferases: the roles in the development of insulin resistance, Nutr Diabetes 8(1) (2018) 34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5968029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29799006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pagac M, Cooper DE, Qi Y, Lukmantara IE, Mak HY, Wu Z, Tian Y, Liu Z, Lei M, Du X, Ferguson C, Kotevski D, Sadowski P, Chen W, Boroda S, Harris TE, Liu G, Parton RG, Huang X, Coleman RA, Yang H, SEIPIN Regulates Lipid Droplet Expansion and Adipocyte Development by Modulating the Activity of Glycerol-3-phosphate Acyltransferase, Cell Rep 17(6) (2016) 1546&#x2013;1559.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5647143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27806294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel H, Hart PE, Warner TT, Houlston RS, Patton MA, Jeffery S, Crosby AH, The Silver syndrome variant of hereditary spastic paraplegia maps to chromosome 11q12-q14, with evidence for genetic heterogeneity within this subtype, Am J Hum Genet 69(1) (2001) 209&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1226036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11389484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silver JR, Familial spastic paraplegia with amyotrophy of the hands, Ann Hum Genet 30(1) (1966) 69&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5964029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neumann M, Sampathu DM, Kwong LK, Truax AC, Micsenyi MC, Chou TT, Bruce J, Schuck T, Grossman M, Clark CM, McCluskey LF, Miller BL, Masliah E, Mackenzie IR, Feldman H, Feiden W, Kretzschmar HA, Trojanowski JQ, Lee VM, Ubiquitinated TDP-43 in frontotemporal lobar degeneration and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, Science 314(5796) (2006) 130&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17023659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winton MJ, Igaz LM, Wong MM, Kwong LK, Trojanowski JQ, Lee VM, Disturbance of nuclear and cytoplasmic TAR DNA-binding protein (TDP-43) induces disease-like redistribution, sequestration, and aggregate formation, J Biol Chem 283(19) (2008) 13302&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2442318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18305110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu YJ, Ju TC, Chen HM, Jang YS, Lee LM, Lai HL, Tai HC, Fang JM, Lin YL, Tu PH, Chern Y, Activation of AMP-activated protein kinase alpha1 mediates mislocalization of TDP-43 in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, Hum Mol Genet 24(3) (2015) 787&#x2013;801.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25256353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herms A, Bosch M, Reddy BJ, Schieber NL, Fajardo A, Ruperez C, Fernandez-Vidal A, Ferguson C, Rentero C, Tebar F, Enrich C, Parton RG, Gross SP, Pol A, AMPK activation promotes lipid droplet dispersion on detyrosinated microtubules to increase mitochondrial fatty acid oxidation, Nat Commun 6 (2015) 7176.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4446796</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26013497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Genc B, Gozutok O, Ozdinler PH, Complexity of Generating Mouse Models to Study the Upper Motor Neurons: Let Us Shift Focus from Mice to Neurons, Int J Mol Sci 20(16) (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6720674</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31394733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raichle ME, Gusnard DA, Appraising the brain&#x2019;s energy budget, Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 99(16) (2002) 10237&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC124895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12149485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferri A, Coccurello R, What is &#x201c;Hyper&#x201d; in the ALS Hypermetabolism?, Mediators Inflamm 2017 (2017) 7821672.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5610793</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29081604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Funalot B, Desport JC, Sturtz F, Camu W, Couratier P, High metabolic level in patients with familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, Amyotroph Lateral Scler 10(2) (2009) 113&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18792852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dupuis L, Corcia P, Fergani A, Gonzalez De Aguilar JL, Bonnefont-Rousselot D, Bittar R, Seilhean D, Hauw JJ, Lacomblez L, Loeffler JP, Meininger V, Dyslipidemia is a protective factor in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, Neurology 70(13) (2008) 1004&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18199832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dalakas MC, Hatazawa J, Brooks RA, Di Chiro G, Lowered cerebral glucose utilization in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, Ann Neurol 22(5) (1987) 580&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3501273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim SM, Kim H, Kim JE, Park KS, Sung JJ, Kim SH, Lee KW, Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis is associated with hypolipidemia at the presymptomatic stage in mice, PLoS One 6(3) (2011) e17985.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3064597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21464953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hatazawa J, Brooks RA, Dalakas MC, Mansi L, Di Chiro G, Cortical motor-sensory hypometabolism in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a PET study, J Comput Assist Tomogr 12(4) (1988) 630&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3260610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renard D, Collombier L, Castelnovo G, Fourcade G, Kotzki PO, LaBauge P, Brain FDG-PET changes in ALS and ALS-FTD, Acta Neurol Belg 111(4) (2011) 306&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22368970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blasco H, Veyrat-Durebex C, Bocca C, Patin F, Vourc&#x2019;h P, Kouassi Nzoughet J, Lenaers G, Andres CR, Simard G, Corcia P, Reynier P, Lipidomics Reveals Cerebrospinal-Fluid Signatures of ALS, Sci Rep 7(1) (2017) 17652.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5732162</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29247199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pradat PF, Bruneteau G, Gordon PH, Dupuis L, Bonnefont-Rousselot D, Simon D, Salachas F, Corcia P, Frochot V, Lacorte JM, Jardel C, Coussieu C, Le Forestier N, Lacomblez L, Loeffler JP, Meininger V, Impaired glucose tolerance in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, Amyotroph Lateral Scler 11(1-2) (2010) 166&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20184518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reyes ET, Perurena OH, Festoff BW, Jorgensen R, Moore WV, Insulin resistance in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, J Neurol Sci 63(3) (1984) 317&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6374040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skowronska-Krawczyk D, Budin I, Aging membranes: Unexplored functions for lipids in the lifespan of the central nervous system, Exp Gerontol 131 (2020) 110817.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7877915</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31862420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Kroon AI, Dolis D, Mayer A, Lill R, de Kruijff B, Phospholipid composition of highly purified mitochondrial outer membranes of rat liver and Neurospora crassa. Is cardiolipin present in the mitochondrial outer membrane?, Biochim Biophys Acta 1325(1) (1997) 108&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9106488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lau DHW, Hartopp N, Welsh NJ, Mueller S, Glennon EB, Morotz GM, Annibali A, Gomez-Suaga P, Stoica R, Paillusson S, Miller CCJ, Disruption of ER-mitochondria signalling in fronto-temporal dementia and related amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, Cell Death Dis 9(3) (2018) 327.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5832427</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29491392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rowland AA, Voeltz GK, Endoplasmic reticulum-mitochondria contacts: function of the junction, Nat Rev Mol Cell Biol 13(10) (2012) 607&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5111635</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22992592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horvath SE, Daum G, Lipids of mitochondria, Prog Lipid Res 52(4) (2013) 590&#x2013;614.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24007978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basu P, Alibhai FJ, Tsimakouridze EV, Singh RK, Paglialunga S, Holloway GP, Martino TA, Bakovic M, Male-Specific Cardiac Dysfunction in CTP:Phosphoethanolamine Cytidylyltransferase (Pcyt2)-Deficient Mice, Mol Cell Biol 35(15) (2015) 2641&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4524120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25986609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manzo E, O&#x2019;Conner AG, Barrows JM, Shreiner DD, Birchak GJ, Zarnescu DC, Medium-Chain Fatty Acids, Beta-Hydroxybutyric Acid and Genetic Modulation of the Carnitine Shuttle Are Protective in a Drosophila Model of ALS Based on TDP-43, Front Mol Neurosci 11 (2018) 182.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5990617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29904341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCoin CS, Knotts TA, Adams SH, Acylcarnitines--old actors auditioning for new roles in metabolic physiology, Nat Rev Endocrinol 11(10) (2015) 617&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4966159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26303601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones LL, McDonald DA, Borum PR, Acylcarnitines: role in brain, Prog Lipid Res 49(1) (2010) 61&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19720082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen TB, Louie SM, Daniele JR, Tran Q, Dillin A, Zoncu R, Nomura DK, Olzmann JA, DGAT1-Dependent Lipid Droplet Biogenesis Protects Mitochondrial Function during Starvation-Induced Autophagy, Dev Cell 42(1) (2017) 9&#x2013;21 e5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5553613</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28697336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirkinezos IG, Bacman SR, Hernandez D, Oca-Cossio J, Arias LJ, Perez-Pinzon MA, Bradley WG, Moraes CT, Cytochrome c association with the inner mitochondrial membrane is impaired in the CNS of G93A-SOD1 mice, J Neurosci 25(1) (2005) 164&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6725219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15634778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaves-Filho AB, Pinto IFD, Dantas LS, Xavier AM, Inague A, Faria RL, Medeiros MHG, Glezer I, Yoshinaga MY, Miyamoto S, Alterations in lipid metabolism of spinal cord linked to amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, Sci Rep 9(1) (2019) 11642.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6691112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31406145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pfeiffer K, Gohil V, Stuart RA, Hunte C, Brandt U, Greenberg ML, Schagger H, Cardiolipin stabilizes respiratory chain supercomplexes, J Biol Chem 278(52) (2003) 52873&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14561769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wenz T, Hielscher R, Hellwig P, Schagger H, Richers S, Hunte C, Role of phospholipids in respiratory cytochrome bc(1) complex catalysis and supercomplex formation, Biochim Biophys Acta 1787(6) (2009) 609&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19254687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bazan S, Mileykovskaya E, Mallampalli VK, Heacock P, Sparagna GC, Dowhan W, Cardiolipin-dependent reconstitution of respiratory supercomplexes from purified Saccharomyces cerevisiae complexes III and IV, J Biol Chem 288(1) (2013) 401&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3537037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23172229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maruyama T, Baba T, Maemoto Y, Hara-Miyauchi C, Hasegawa-Ogawa M, Okano HJ, Enda Y, Matsumoto K, Arimitsu N, Nakao K, Hamamoto H, Sekimizu K, Ohto-Nakanishi T, Nakanishi H, Tokuyama T, Yanagi S, Tagaya M, Tani K, Loss of DDHD2, whose mutation causes spastic paraplegia, promotes reactive oxygen species generation and apoptosis, Cell Death Dis 9(8) (2018) 797.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6056544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30038238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chao H, Lin C, Zuo Q, Liu Y, Xiao M, Xu X, Li Z, Bao Z, Chen H, You Y, Kochanek PM, Yin H, Liu N, Kagan VE, Bayir H, Ji J, Cardiolipin-Dependent Mitophagy Guides Outcome after Traumatic Brain Injury, J Neurosci 39(10) (2019) 1930&#x2013;1943.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6407296</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30626699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gautam M, Xie EF, Kocak N, Ozdinler PH, Mitoautophagy: A Unique Self-Destructive Path Mitochondria of Upper Motor Neurons With TDP-43 Pathology Take, Very Early in ALS, Front Cell Neurosci 13 (2019) 489.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6854036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31787882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDermott CJ, Taylor RW, Hayes C, Johnson M, Bushby KM, Turnbull DM, Shaw PJ, Investigation of mitochondrial function in hereditary spastic paraparesis, Neuroreport 14(3) (2003) 485&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12634509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Attwell D, Laughlin SB, An energy budget for signaling in the grey matter of the brain, J Cereb Blood Flow Metab 21(10) (2001) 1133&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11598490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris JJ, Attwell D, The energetics of CNS white matter, J Neurosci 32(1) (2012) 356&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3272449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22219296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palamiuc L, Schlagowski A, Ngo ST, Vernay A, Dirrig-Grosch S, Henriques A, Boutillier AL, Zoll J, Echaniz-Laguna A, Loeffler JP, Rene F, A metabolic switch toward lipid use in glycolytic muscle is an early pathologic event in a mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, EMBO Mol Med 7(5) (2015) 526&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4492815</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25820275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitfield J, Paglialunga S, Smith BK, Miotto PM, Simnett G, Robson HL, Jain SS, Herbst EAF, Desjardins EM, Dyck DJ, Spriet LL, Steinberg GR, Holloway GP, Ablating the protein TBC1D1 impairs contraction-induced sarcolemmal glucose transporter 4 redistribution but not insulin-mediated responses in rats, J Biol Chem 292(40) (2017) 16653&#x2013;16664.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5633127</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28808062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aalling NN, Nedergaard M, DiNuzzo M, Cerebral Metabolic Changes During Sleep, Curr Neurol Neurosci Rep 18(9) (2018) 57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6688614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30014344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weightman Potter PG, Vlachaki Walker JM, Robb JL, Chilton JK, Williamson R, Randall AD, Ellacott KLJ, Beall C, Basal fatty acid oxidation increases after recurrent low glucose in human primary astrocytes, Diabetologia 62(1) (2019) 187&#x2013;198.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6290858</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30293112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhillon KK, Gupta S, Biochemistry, Ketogenesis, StatPearls, Treasure Island (FL), 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prins ML, Giza CC, Induction of monocarboxylate transporter 2 expression and ketone transport following traumatic brain injury in juvenile and adult rats, Dev Neurosci 28(4-5) (2006) 447&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16943667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prins ML, Fujima LS, Hovda DA, Age-dependent reduction of cortical contusion volume by ketones after traumatic brain injury, J Neurosci Res 82(3) (2005) 413&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16180224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guzman M, Blazquez C, Ketone body synthesis in the brain: possible neuroprotective effects, Prostaglandins Leukot Essent Fatty Acids 70(3) (2004) 287&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14769487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thevenet J, De Marchi U, Domingo JS, Christinat N, Bultot L, Lefebvre G, Sakamoto K, Descombes P, Masoodi M, Wiederkehr A, Medium-chain fatty acids inhibit mitochondrial metabolism in astrocytes promoting astrocyte-neuron lactate and ketone body shuttle systems, FASEB J 30(5) (2016) 1913&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26839375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Auestad N, Korsak RA, Morrow JW, Edmond J, Fatty acid oxidation and ketogenesis by astrocytes in primary culture, J Neurochem 56(4) (1991) 1376&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2002348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le Foll C, Levin BE, Fatty acid-induced astrocyte ketone production and the control of food intake, Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol 310(11) (2016) R1186&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4935491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27122369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Unger RH, Clark GO, Scherer PE, Orci L, Lipid homeostasis, lipotoxicity and the metabolic syndrome, Biochim Biophys Acta 1801(3) (2010) 209&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19948243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schonfeld P, Reiser G, Why does brain metabolism not favor burning of fatty acids to provide energy? Reflections on disadvantages of the use of free fatty acids as fuel for brain, J Cereb Blood Flow Metab 33(10) (2013) 1493&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3790936</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23921897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Speijer D, Manjeri GR, Szklarczyk R, How to deal with oxygen radicals stemming from mitochondrial fatty acid oxidation, Philos Trans R Soc Lond B Biol Sci 369(1646) (2014) 20130446.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4032520</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24864314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kausar S, Wang F, Cui H, The Role of Mitochondria in Reactive Oxygen Species Generation and Its Implications for Neurodegenerative Diseases, Cells 7(12) (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6316843</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30563029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bogdanov M, Brown RH, Matson W, Smart R, Hayden D, O&#x2019;Donnell H, Flint Beal M, Cudkowicz M, Increased oxidative damage to DNA in ALS patients, Free Radic Biol Med 29(7) (2000) 652&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11033417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#x2019;Amico E, Factor-Litvak P, Santella RM, Mitsumoto H, Clinical perspective on oxidative stress in sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, Free Radic Biol Med 65 (2013) 509&#x2013;527.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3859834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23797033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simpson EP, Henry YK, Henkel JS, Smith RG, Appel SH, Increased lipid peroxidation in sera of ALS patients: a potential biomarker of disease burden, Neurology 62(10) (2004) 1758&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15159474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitsumoto H, Santella RM, Liu X, Bogdanov M, Zipprich J, Wu HC, Mahata J, Kilty M, Bednarz K, Bell D, Gordon PH, Hornig M, Mehrazin M, Naini A, Flint Beal M, Factor-Litvak P, Oxidative stress biomarkers in sporadic ALS, Amyotroph Lateral Scler 9(3) (2008) 177&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4332387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18574762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veyrat-Durebex C, Reynier P, Procaccio V, Hergesheimer R, Corcia P, Andres CR, Blasco H, How Can a Ketogenic Diet Improve Motor Function?, Front Mol Neurosci 11 (2018) 15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5790787</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29434537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gasior M, Rogawski MA, Hartman AL, Neuroprotective and disease-modifying effects of the ketogenic diet, Behav Pharmacol 17(5-6) (2006) 431&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2367001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16940764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elia M, Klepper J, Leiendecker B, Hartmann H, Ketogenic Diets in the Treatment of Epilepsy, Curr Pharm Des 23(37) (2017) 5691&#x2013;5701.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28799513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dabek A, Wojtala M, Pirola L, Balcerczyk A, Modulation of Cellular Biochemistry, Epigenetics and Metabolomics by Ketone Bodies. Implications of the Ketogenic Diet in the Physiology of the Organism and Pathological States, Nutrients 12(3) (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7146425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32192146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee RWY, Corley MJ, Pang A, Arakaki G, Abbott L, Nishimoto M, Miyamoto R, Lee E, Yamamoto S, Maunakea AK, Lum-Jones A, Wong M, A modified ketogenic gluten-free diet with MCT improves behavior in children with autism spectrum disorder, Physiol Behav 188 (2018) 205&#x2013;211.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5863039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29421589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pasca L, De Giorgis V, Macasaet JA, Trentani C, Tagliabue A, Veggiotti P, The changing face of dietary therapy for epilepsy, Eur J Pediatr 175(10) (2016) 1267&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27586246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lefevre F, Aronson N, Ketogenic diet for the treatment of refractory epilepsy in children: A systematic review of efficacy, Pediatrics 105(4) (2000) E46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10742367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baranano KW, Hartman AL, The ketogenic diet: uses in epilepsy and other neurologic illnesses, Curr Treat Options Neurol 10(6) (2008) 410&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2898565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18990309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergqvist AG, Schall JI, Gallagher PR, Cnaan A, Stallings VA, Fasting versus gradual initiation of the ketogenic diet: a prospective, randomized clinical trial of efficacy, Epilepsia 46(11) (2005) 1810&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16302862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahn Y, Sabouny R, Villa BR, Yee NC, Mychasiuk R, Uddin GM, Rho JM, Shutt TE, Aberrant Mitochondrial Morphology and Function in the BTBR Mouse Model of Autism Is Improved by Two Weeks of Ketogenic Diet, Int J Mol Sci 21(9) (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7246481</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32380723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guan YF, Huang GB, Xu MD, Gao F, Lin S, Huang J, Wang J, Li YQ, Wu CH, Yao S, Wang Y, Zhang YL, Teoh JP, Xuan A, Sun XD, Anti-depression effects of ketogenic diet are mediated via the restoration of microglial activation and neuronal excitability in the lateral habenula, Brain Behav Immun (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32413556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vanitallie TB, Nonas C, Di Rocco A, Boyar K, Hyams K, Heymsfield SB, Treatment of Parkinson disease with diet-induced hyperketonemia: a feasibility study, Neurology 64(4) (2005) 728&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15728303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lilamand M, Porte B, Cognat E, Hugon J, Mouton-Liger F, Paquet C, Are ketogenic diets promising for Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease? A translational review, Alzheimers Res Ther 12(1) (2020) 42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7158135</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32290868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demirel A, Li J, Morrow C, Barnes S, Jansen J, Gower B, Kirksey K, Redden D, Yarar-Fisher C, Evaluation of a ketogenic diet for improvement of neurological recovery in individuals with acute spinal cord injury: study protocol for a randomized controlled trial, Trials 21(1) (2020) 372.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7197123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32366293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dupuis L, Oudart H, Rene F, Gonzalez de Aguilar JL, Loeffler JP, Evidence for defective energy homeostasis in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: benefit of a high-energy diet in a transgenic mouse model, Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 101(30) (2004) 11159&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC503756</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15263088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Z, Lange DJ, Voustianiouk A, MacGrogan D, Ho L, Suh J, Humala N, Thiyagarajan M, Wang J, Pasinetti GM, A ketogenic diet as a potential novel therapeutic intervention in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, BMC Neurosci 7 (2006) 29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1488864</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16584562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed RM, Highton-Williamson E, Caga J, Thornton N, Ramsey E, Zoing M, Kim WS, Halliday GM, Piguet O, Hodges JR, Farooqi IS, Kiernan MC, Lipid Metabolism and Survival Across the Frontotemporal Dementia-Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Spectrum: Relationships to Eating Behavior and Cognition, J Alzheimers Dis 61(2) (2018) 773&#x2013;783.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29254092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed RM, Caga J, Devenney E, Hsieh S, Bartley L, Highton-Williamson E, Ramsey E, Zoing M, Halliday GM, Piguet O, Hodges JR, Kiernan MC, Cognition and eating behavior in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: effect on survival, J Neurol 263(8) (2016) 1593&#x2013;603.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27260291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ludolph AC, Dorst J, Dreyhaupt J, Weishaupt JH, Kassubek J, Weiland U, Meyer T, Petri S, Hermann A, Emmer A, Grosskreutz J, Grehl T, Zeller D, Boentert M, Schrank B, Prudlo J, Winkler AS, Gorbulev S, Roselli F, Schuster J, Dupuis L, Group L-AS, Effect of High-Caloric Nutrition on Survival in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis, Ann Neurol 87(2) (2020) 206&#x2013;216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31849093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Branco AF, Ferreira A, Simoes RF, Magalhaes-Novais S, Zehowski C, Cope E, Silva AM, Pereira D, Sardao VA, Cunha-Oliveira T, Ketogenic diets: from cancer to mitochondrial diseases and beyond, Eur J Clin Invest 46(3) (2016) 285&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26782788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kovacs Z, D&#x2019;Agostino DP, Diamond D, Kindy MS, Rogers C, Ari C, Therapeutic Potential of Exogenous Ketone Supplement Induced Ketosis in the Treatment of Psychiatric Disorders: Review of Current Literature, Front Psychiatry 10 (2019) 363.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6543248</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31178772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao W, Varghese M, Vempati P, Dzhun A, Cheng A, Wang J, Lange D, Bilski A, Faravelli I, Pasinetti GM, Caprylic triglyceride as a novel therapeutic approach to effectively improve the performance and attenuate the symptoms due to the motor neuron loss in ALS disease, PLoS One 7(11) (2012) e49191.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3492315</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23145119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ari C, Poff AM, Held HE, Landon CS, Goldhagen CR, Mavromates N, D&#x2019;Agostino DP, Metabolic therapy with Deanna Protocol supplementation delays disease progression and extends survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) mouse model, PLoS One 9(7) (2014) e103526.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4111621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25061944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newport MT, VanItallie TB, Kashiwaya Y, King MT, Veech RL, A new way to produce hyperketonemia: use of ketone ester in a case of Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease, Alzheimers Dement 11(1) (2015) 99&#x2013;103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4300286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25301680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schonfeld P, Wojtczak L, Short- and medium-chain fatty acids in energy metabolism: the cellular perspective, J Lipid Res 57(6) (2016) 943&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4878196</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27080715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaplin A, Carpene C, Mercader J, Resveratrol, Metabolic Syndrome, and Gut Microbiota, Nutrients 10(11) (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6266067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30400297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang Z, Chen K, Cheng L, Yan B, Qian W, Cao J, Li J, Wu E, Ma Q, Yang W, Resveratrol and cancer treatment: updates, Ann N Y Acad Sci 1403(1) (2017) 59&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28945938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarubbo F, Moranta D, Asensio VJ, Miralles A, Esteban S, Effects of Resveratrol and Other Polyphenols on the Most Common Brain Age-Related Diseases, Curr Med Chem 24(38) (2017) 4245&#x2013;4266.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28738770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schutz B, Reimann J, Dumitrescu-Ozimek L, Kappes-Horn K, Landreth GE, Schurmann B, Zimmer A, Heneka MT, The oral antidiabetic pioglitazone protects from neurodegeneration and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-like symptoms in superoxide dismutase-G93A transgenic mice, J Neurosci 25(34) (2005) 7805&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6725264</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16120782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dupuis L, Dengler R, Heneka MT, Meyer T, Zierz S, Kassubek J, Fischer W, Steiner F, Lindauer E, Otto M, Dreyhaupt J, Grehl T, Hermann A, Winkler AS, Bogdahn U, Benecke R, Schrank B, Wessig C, Grosskreutz J, Ludolph AC, Group GAS, A randomized, double blind, placebo-controlled trial of pioglitazone in combination with riluzole in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, PLoS One 7(6) (2012) e37885.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3371007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22715372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maldonado C, Vazquez M, Fagiolino P, Potential Therapeutic Role of Carnitine and Acetylcarnitine in Neurological Disorders, Curr Pharm Des 26(12) (2020) 1277&#x2013;1285.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32048954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rolim LC, da Silva EM, Flumignan RL, Abreu MM, Dib SA, Acetyl-L-carnitine for the treatment of diabetic peripheral neuropathy, Cochrane Database Syst Rev 6 (2019) CD011265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6953387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31201734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bigini P, Larini S, Pasquali C, Muzio V, Mennini T, Acetyl-L-carnitine shows neuroprotective and neurotrophic activity in primary culture of rat embryo motoneurons, Neurosci Lett 329(3) (2002) 334&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12183043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kazak F, Yarim GF, Neuroprotective effects of acetyl-l-carnitine on lipopolysaccharide-induced neuroinflammation in mice: Involvement of brain-derived neurotrophic factor, Neurosci Lett 658 (2017) 32&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28822835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beghi E, Pupillo E, Bonito V, Buzzi P, Caponnetto C, Chio A, Corbo M, Giannini F, Inghilleri M, Bella VL, Logroscino G, Lorusso L, Lunetta C, Mazzini L, Messina P, Mora G, Perini M, Quadrelli ML, Silani V, Simone IL, Tremolizzo L, Italian ALSSG, Randomized double-blind placebo-controlled trial of acetyl-L-carnitine for ALS, Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 14(5-6) (2013) 397&#x2013;405.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23421600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Federici T, Boulis NM, Gene-based treatment of motor neuron diseases, Muscle Nerve 33(3) (2006) 302&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16228969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veldink JH, Van den Berg LH, Wokke JH, The future of motor neuron disease: the challenge is in the genes, J Neurol 251(4) (2004) 491&#x2013;500.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15083302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ingusci S, Verlengia G, Soukupova M, Zucchini S, Simonato M, Gene Therapy Tools for Brain Diseases, Front Pharmacol 10 (2019) 724.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6613496</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31312139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jara JH, Stanford MJ, Zhu Y, Tu M, Hauswirth WW, Bohn MC, DeVries SH, Ozdinler PH, Healthy and diseased corticospinal motor neurons are selectively transduced upon direct AAV2-2 injection into the motor cortex, Gene Ther 23(3) (2016) 272&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4777664</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26704722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouteloup C, Desport JC, Clavelou P, Guy N, Derumeaux-Burel H, Ferrier A, Couratier P, Hypermetabolism in ALS patients: an early and persistent phenomenon, J Neurol 256(8) (2009) 1236&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19306035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang R, Guo X, Chen X, Zheng Z, Wei Q, Cao B, Zeng Y, Shang H, The serum lipid profiles of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients: A study from south-west China and a meta-analysis, Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 16(5-6) (2015) 359&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26121273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez De Aguilar JL, Lipid Biomarkers for Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis, Front Neurol 10 (2019) 284.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6458258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31019485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dorst J, Kuhnlein P, Hendrich C, Kassubek J, Sperfeld AD, Ludolph AC, Patients with elevated triglyceride and cholesterol serum levels have a prolonged survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, J Neurol 258(4) (2011) 613&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21128082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Germeys C, Vandoorne T, Bercier V, Van Den Bosch L, Existing and Emerging Metabolomic Tools for ALS Research, Genes (Basel) 10(12) (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6947647</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31817338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ala-Korpela M, Critical evaluation of 1H NMR metabonomics of serum as a methodology for disease risk assessment and diagnostics, Clin Chem Lab Med 46(1) (2008) 27&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18020967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ala-Korpela M, Potential role of body fluid 1H NMR metabonomics as a prognostic and diagnostic tool, Expert Rev Mol Diagn 7(6) (2007) 761&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18020906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blasco H, Corcia P, Moreau C, Veau S, Fournier C, Vourc&#x2019;h P, Emond P, Gordon P, Pradat PF, Praline J, Devos D, Nadal-Desbarats L, Andres CR, 1H-NMR-based metabolomic profiling of CSF in early amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, PLoS One 5(10) (2010) e13223.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2951909</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20949041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Z, Shon JC, Liu KH, Mass Spectrometry-based Lipidomics and Its Application to Biomedical Research, J Lifestyle Med 4(1) (2014) 17&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4390758</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26064851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dawson G, Measuring brain lipids, Biochim Biophys Acta 1851(8) (2015) 1026&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4457555</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25701718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bjornevik K, O&#x2019;Reilly EJ, Cortese M, Furtado JD, Kolonel LN, Le Marchand L, McCullough ML, Paganoni S, Schwarzschild MA, Shadyab AH, Manson JE, Ascherio A, Pre-diagnostic plasma lipid levels and the risk of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener (2020) 1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8004541</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32985910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>