<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">33382092</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>21</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-4159</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>157</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>May</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of neurochemistry</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Neurochem</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Neuromuscular junction-on-a-chip: ALS disease modeling and read-out development in microfluidic devices.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>393</StartPage><EndPage>412</EndPage><MedlinePgn>393-412</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/jnc.15289</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) is a fatal and progressive neurodegenerative disease affecting upper and lower motor neurons with no cure available. Clinical and animal studies reveal that the neuromuscular junction (NMJ), a synaptic connection between motor neurons and skeletal muscle fibers, is highly vulnerable in ALS and suggest that NMJ defects may occur at the early stages of the disease. However, mechanistic insight into how NMJ dysfunction relates to the onset and progression of ALS is incomplete, which hampers therapy development. This is, in part, caused by a lack of robust in vitro models. The ability to combine microfluidic and induced pluripotent stem cell (iPSC) technologies has opened up new avenues for studying molecular and cellular ALS phenotypes in vitro. Microfluidic devices offer several advantages over traditional culture approaches when modeling the NMJ, such as the spatial separation of different cell types and increased control over the cellular microenvironment. Moreover, they are compatible with 3D cell culture, which enhances NMJ functionality and maturity. Here, we review how microfluidic technology is currently being employed to develop more reliable in vitro NMJ models. To validate and phenotype such models, various morphological and functional read-outs have been developed. We describe and discuss the relevance of these read-outs and specifically illustrate how these read-outs have enhanced our understanding of NMJ pathology in ALS. Finally, we share our view on potential future directions and challenges.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 The Authors. Journal of Neurochemistry published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of International Society for Neurochemistry.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>de Jongh</LastName><ForeName>Rianne</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Translational Neuroscience, University Medical Center Utrecht Brain Center, Utrecht University, Utrecht, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Spijkers</LastName><ForeName>Xandor M</ForeName><Initials>XM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Translational Neuroscience, University Medical Center Utrecht Brain Center, Utrecht University, Utrecht, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mimetas B.V., Organ-on-a-chip Company, Leiden, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pasteuning-Vuhman</LastName><ForeName>Svetlana</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Translational Neuroscience, University Medical Center Utrecht Brain Center, Utrecht University, Utrecht, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vulto</LastName><ForeName>Paul</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mimetas B.V., Organ-on-a-chip Company, Leiden, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pasterkamp</LastName><ForeName>R Jeroen</ForeName><Initials>RJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1631-6440</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Translational Neuroscience, University Medical Center Utrecht Brain Center, Utrecht University, Utrecht, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Neurochem</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>2985190R</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0022-3042</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003198" MajorTopicYN="Y">Computer Simulation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D056656" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lab-On-A-Chip Devices</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D044085" MajorTopicYN="N">Microfluidics</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009046" MajorTopicYN="N">Motor Neurons</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009469" MajorTopicYN="N">Neuromuscular Junction</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ALS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">iPSC</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">microfluidics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">motor neurons</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neuromuscular junction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">organ-on-a-chip</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33382092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jnc.15289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Afshar Bakooshli, M., Lippmann, E. S., Mulcahy, B., Iyer, N., Nguyen, C. T., Tung, K., Stewart, B. A., van den Dorpel, H., Fuehrmann, T., Shoichet, M., Bigot, A., Pegoraro, E., Ahn, H., Ginsberg, H., Zhen, M., Ashton, R. S., &amp; Gilbert, P. M. (2019). A 3D culture model of innervated human skeletal muscle enables studies of the adult neuromuscular junction. Elife, 8, e44530. https://doi.org/10.7554/eLife.44530</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Chalabi, A., Hardiman, O., Kiernan, M. C., Chi&#xf2;, A., Rix-Brooks, B., van den Berg, L. H.(2016). Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Moving towards a new classification system. The Lancet Neurology, 15, 1182-1194. https://doi.org/10.1016/S1474-4422(16)30199-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altman, T., Geller, D., Kleeblatt, E., Gradus-Perry, T., &amp; Perlson, E. (2019). An in vitro compartmental system underlines the contribution of mitochondrial immobility to the ATP supply in the NMJ. Journal of Cell Science, 132, jcs234492.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altman, T., Maimon, R., Ionescu, A., Pery, T. G., &amp; Perlson, E. (2020). Axonal transport of organelles in motor neuron cultures using microfluidic chambers system. Journal of Visualized Experiments: Jove, 159, 60993.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arbour, D., Tremblay, E., Martineau, E., Julien, J.-P., &amp; Robitaille, R. (2015). Early and persistent abnormal decoding by glial cells at the neuromuscular junction in an ALS model. Journal of Neuroscience, 35, 688-706. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.1379-14.2015</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arbour, D., Velde, C., &amp; Vande, R. R. (2017). New perspectives on amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: The role of glial cells at the neuromuscular junction. Journal of Physiology, 595, 647-661. https://doi.org/10.1113/JP270213</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baleriola, J., &amp; Hengst, U. (2015). Targeting axonal protein synthesis in neuroregeneration and degeneration. Neurother. J. Am. Soc. Exp. Neurother., 12, 57-65. https://doi.org/10.1007/s13311-014-0308-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barberi, T., Bradbury, M., Dincer, Z., Panagiotakos, G., Socci, N. D., &amp; Studer, L. (2007). Derivation of engraftable skeletal myoblasts from human embryonic stem cells. Nature Medicine, 13, 642-648.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barros, C. S., Franco, S. J., &amp; M&#xfc;ller, U. (2011). Extracellular matrix: Functions in the nervous system. Cold Spring Harbor Perspectives in Biology, 3, a005108. https://doi.org/10.1101/cshperspect.a005108</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartanusz, V., Jezova, D., Alajajian, B., &amp; Digicaylioglu, M. (2011). The blood-spinal cord barrier: Morphology and clinical implications. Annals of Neurology, 70, 194-206. https://doi.org/10.1002/ana.22421</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berthier, E., Young, E. W. K., &amp; Beebe, D. (2012). Engineers are from PDMS-land, biologists are from polystyrenia. Lab on a Chip, 12, 1224-1237. https://doi.org/10.1039/c2lc20982a</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bishop, D. L., Misgeld, T., Walsh, M. K., Gan, W.-B., &amp; Lichtman, J. W. (2004). Axon branch removal at developing synapses by axosome shedding. Neuron, 44, 651-661. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2004.10.026</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bjornskov, E. K., Norris, F. H., &amp; Mower-Kuby, J. (1984). Quantitative axon terminal and end-plate morphology in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Archives of Neurology, 41, 527-530.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blijham, P. J., Schelhaas, H. J., Laak, H. J. ter, van Engelen, B. G. M., Zwarts, M. J.(2007). Early diagnosis of ALS: The search for signs of denervation in clinically normal muscles. Journal of the Neurological Sciences, 263, 154-157.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boehm, I., Alhindi, A., Leite, A. S., Logie, C., Gibbs, A., Murray, O., Farrukh, R., Pirie, R., Proudfoot, C., Clutton, R., Wishart, T. M., Jones, R. A., &amp; Gillingwater, T. H. (2020). Comparative anatomy of the mammalian neuromuscular junction. Journal of Anatomy, 237, 827-836. https://doi.org/10.1111/joa.13260</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boillee, S., Yamanaka, K., Lobsiger, C. S., Copeland, N. G., Jenkins, N. A., Kassiotis, G., Kollias, G., &amp; Cleveland, D. W. (2006). Onset and progression in inherited ALS determined by motor neurons and microglia. Science, 312, 1389-1392. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.1123511</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bornstein, M., &amp; Breitbart, L. (1964). Anatomical studies of mouse embryo spinal cord-skeletal muscle in long-term tissue culture. Anatomical Record, 148, 362.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borthwick, G. M., Johnson, M. A., Ince, P. G., Shaw, P. J., &amp; Turnbull, D. M. (1999). Mitochondrial enzyme activity in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Implications for the role of mitochondria in neuronal cell death. Annals of Neurology, 46, 787-790. https://doi.org/10.1002/1531-8249(199911)46:5&lt;787:AID-ANA17&gt;3.0.CO;2-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boyden, E. S., Zhang, F., Bamberg, E., Nagel, G., &amp; Deisseroth, K. (2005). Millisecond-timescale, genetically targeted optical control of neural activity. Nature Neuroscience, 8, 1263-1268.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Br&#xe4;nnvall, K., Bergman, K., Wallenquist, U., Svahn, S., Bowden, T., Hilborn, J., &amp; Forsberg-Nilsson, K. (2007). Enhanced neuronal differentiation in a three-dimensional collagen-hyaluronan matrix. Journal of Neuroscience Research, 85, 2138-2146.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breslin, S., &amp; O&#x2019;Driscoll, L. (2013). Three-dimensional cell culture: The missing link in drug discovery. Drug Discov Today, 18, 240-249. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.drudis.2012.10.003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Briese, M., Saal, L., Appenzeller, S., Moradi, M., Baluapuri, A., &amp; Sendtner, M. (2015). Whole transcriptome profiling reveals the RNA content of motor axons. Nucleic Acids Research, 44, e33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burk, K., &amp; Pasterkamp, R. J. (2019). Disrupted neuronal trafficking in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathologica, 137, 859-877. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00401-019-01964-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campanari, M.-L., Garcia-Ayllon, M.-S., Ciura, S., Saez-Valero, J., &amp; Kabashi, E. (2016). Neuromuscular junction impairment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Reassessing the role of acetylcholinesterase. Frontiers in Molecular Neuroscience, 9, 160.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campenot, R. B. (1977). Local control of neurite development by nerve growth factor. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 74, 4516-4519.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cappello, V., &amp; Francolini, M. (2017). Neuromuscular junction dismantling in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. International Journal of Molecular Sciences, 18, 2092.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carcamo-Orive, I., Hoffman, G. E., Cundiff, P., Beckmann, N. D., D&#x2019;Souza, S. L., Knowles, J. W., Patel, A., Papatsenko, D., Abbasi, F., Reaven, G. M., Whalen, S., Lee, P., Shahbazi, M., Henrion, M. Y. R., Zhu, K., Wang, S., Roussos, P., Schadt, E. E., Pandey, G., &#x2026; Lemischka, I. (2017). Analysis of transcriptional variability in a large human iPSC library reveals genetic and non-genetic determinants of heterogeneity. Cell Stem Cell, 20, 518-532. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.stem.2016.11.005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casas, C., Manzano, R., Vaz, R., Osta, R., &amp; Brites, D. (2016) Synaptic failure: Focus in an integrative view of ALS. Brain Plast. (Amsterdam, Netherlands) 1, 159-175.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chand, K. K., Lee, K. M., Lee, J. D., Qiu, H., Willis, E. F., Lavidis, N. A., Hilliard, M. A., &amp; Noakes, P. G. (2018). Defects in synaptic transmission at the neuromuscular junction precede motor deficits in a TDP-43(Q331K) transgenic mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. The FASEB Journal: The Journal of the Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology, 32, 2676-2689.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark, J. A., Southam, K. A., Blizzard, C. A., King, A. E., &amp; Dickson, T. C. (2016). Axonal degeneration, distal collateral branching and neuromuscular junction architecture alterations occur prior to symptom onset in the SOD1(G93A) mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Journal of Chemical Neuroanatomy, 76, 35-47. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jchemneu.2016.03.003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conforti, L., Adalbert, R., &amp; Coleman, M. P. (2007). Neuronal death: Where does the end begin? Trends in Neurosciences, 30, 159-166.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Court, F. A., Gillingwater, T. H., Melrose, S., Sherman, D. L., Greenshields, K. N., Morton, A. J., Harris, J. B., Willison, H. J., &amp; Ribchester, R. R. (2008). Identity, developmental restriction and reactivity of extralaminar cells capping mammalian neuromuscular junctions. Journal of Cell Science, 121, 3901-3911. https://doi.org/10.1242/jcs.031047</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crain, S. M., &amp; Peterson, E. R. (1964). Complex bioelectric activity in organized tissue cultures of spinal cord (human, rat and chick). The Journal of Cellular Physiology, 64, 1-13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darabi, R., Gehlbach, K., Bachoo, R. M., Kamath, S., Osawa, M., Kamm, K. E., Kyba, M., &amp; Perlingeiro, R. C. R. (2008). Functional skeletal muscle regeneration from differentiating embryonic stem cells. Nature Medicine, 14, 134-143.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darabid, H., Arbour, D., &amp; Robitaille, R. (2013). Glial cells decipher synaptic competition at the mammalian neuromuscular junction. Journal of Neuroscience, 33, 1297-1313. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.2935-12.2013</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Das, M., Rumsey, J. W., Bhargava, N., Stancescu, M., &amp; Hickman, J. J. (2010). A defined long-term in vitro tissue engineered model of neuromuscular junctions. Biomaterials, 31, 4880-4888. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biomaterials.2010.02.055</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De, V. K. J., &amp; Hafezparast, M. (2017). Neurobiology of axonal transport defects in motor neuron diseases: Opportunities for translational research? Neurobiology of Diseases, 105, 283-299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeJesus-Hernandez, M., Mackenzie, I. R., Boeve, B. F., Boxer, A. L., Baker, M., Rutherford, N. J., Nicholson, A. M., Finch, N. C. A., Flynn, H., Adamson, J., Kouri, N., Wojtas, A., Sengdy, P., Hsiung, G.-Y., Karydas, A., Seeley, W. W., Josephs, K. A., Coppola, G., Geschwind, D. H., &#x2026; Rademakers, R. (2011). Expanded GGGGCC hexanucleotide repeat in noncoding region of C9ORF72 causes chromosome 9p-linked FTD and ALS. Neuron, 72, 245-256. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2011.09.011</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demestre, M., Orth, M., F&#xf6;hr, K. J., Achberger, K., Ludolph, A. C., Liebau, S., &amp; Boeckers, T. M. (2015). Formation and characterisation of neuromuscular junctions between hiPSC derived motoneurons and myotubes. Stem Cell Research, 15, 328-336. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scr.2015.07.005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ditsworth, D., Maldonado, M., McAlonis-Downes, M., Sun, S., Seelman, A., Drenner, K., Arnold, E., Ling, S.-C., Pizzo, D., Ravits, J., Cleveland, D. W., &amp; Da Cruz, S. (2017). Mutant TDP-43 within motor neurons drives disease onset but not progression in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathologica, 133, 907-922. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00401-017-1698-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duffy, D. C., McDonald, J. C., Schueller, O. J., &amp; Whitesides, G. M. (1998). Rapid prototyping of microfluidic systems in poly(dimethylsiloxane). Analytical Chemistry, 70, 4974-4984.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edmondson, R., Broglie, J. J., Adcock, A. F., &amp; Yang, L. (2014). Three-dimensional cell culture systems and their applications in drug discovery and cell-based biosensors. Assay Drug Development Technologies, 12, 207-218.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fallini, C., Donlin-Asp, P. G., Rouanet, J. P., Bassell, G. J., &amp; Rossoll, W. (2016). Deficiency of the survival of motor neuron protein impairs mRNA localization and local translation in the growth cone of motor neurons. Journal of Neuroscience, 36, 3811-3820. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.2396-15.2016</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faustino Martins, J.-M., Fischer, C., Urzi, A., Vidal, R., Kunz, S., Ruffault, P.-L., Kabuss, L., Hube, I., Gazzerro, E., Birchmeier, C., Spuler, S., Sauer, S., &amp; Gouti, M. (2020). Self-organizing 3D human trunk neuromuscular organoids. Cell Stem Cell, 26, 172-186. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.stem.2019.12.007</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng, Z., &amp; Ko, C.-P. (2008). The role of glial cells in the formation and maintenance of the neuromuscular junction. Annals of the New York Academy of Sciences, 1132, 19-28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferraiuolo, L., Meyer, K., Sherwood, T. W., Vick, J., Likhite, S., Frakes, A., Miranda, C. J., Braun, L., Heath, P. R., Pineda, R., Beattie, C. E., Shaw, P. J., Askwith, C. C., McTigue, D., &amp; Kaspar, B. K. (2016). Oligodendrocytes contribute to motor neuron death in ALS via SOD1-dependent mechanism. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, 113, E6496-E6505. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1607496113</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fischer, L. R., Culver, D. G., Tennant, P., Davis, A. A., Wang, M., Castellano-Sanchez, A., Khan, J., Polak, M. A., &amp; Glass, J. D. (2004). Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis is a distal axonopathy: Evidence in mice and man. Experimental Neurology, 185, 232-240. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.expneurol.2003.10.004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fischer-Hayes, L. R., Brotherton, T., &amp; Glass, J. D. (2013). Axonal degeneration in the peripheral nervous system: Implications for the pathogenesis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Experimental Neurology, 246, 6-13. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.expneurol.2013.05.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fox, M. A., Sanes, J. R., Borza, D.-B., Eswarakumar, V. P., F&#xe4;ssler, R., Hudson, B. G., John, S. W. M., Ninomiya, Y., Pedchenko, V., Pfaff, S. L., Rheault, M. N., Sado, Y., Segal, Y., Werle, M. J., &amp; Umemori, H. (2007). Distinct target-derived signals organize formation, maturation, and maintenance of motor nerve terminals. Cell, 129, 179-193. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2007.02.035</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grainger, F., James, D. W., &amp; Tresman, R. L. (1968). An electron-microscopic study of the early outgrowth from chick spinal cord in vitro. Z. Zellforsch. Mikrosk. Anat., 90, 53-67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grebenyuk, S., &amp; Ranga, A. (2019). Engineering organoid vascularization. Frontiers in Bioengineering and Biotechnology, 7, 1-12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gross, G. W. (1979). Simultaneous single unit recording in vitro with a photoetched laser deinsulated gold multimicroelectrode surface. IEEE Transactions on Biomedical Engineering, BME-26, 273-279. https://doi.org/10.1109/TBME.1979.326402</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grosskreutz, J., Bosch, L., Den, V., &amp; Keller, B. U. (2010). Calcium dysregulation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Cell Calcium, 42, 165-174. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceca.2009.12.002</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo, X., Gonzalez, M., Stancescu, M., Vandenburgh, H. H., &amp; Hickman, J. J. (2011). Neuromuscular junction formation between human stem cell-derived motoneurons and human skeletal muscle in a defined system. Biomaterials, 32, 9602-9611. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biomaterials.2011.09.014</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hafner, A. S., Donlin-Asp, P. G., Leitch, B., Herzog, E., &amp; Schuman, E. M. (2019). Local protein synthesis is a ubiquitous feature of neuronal pre- And postsynaptic compartments. Science, 364. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.aau3644</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanyu, N., Oguchi, K., Yanagisawa, N., &amp; Tsukagoshi, H. (1982). Degeneration and regeneration of ventral root motor fibers in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Morphometric studies of cervical ventral roots. Journal of the Neurological Sciences, 55, 99-115.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harrison, D. J., Fluri, K., Seiler, K., Fan, Z., Effenhauser, C. S., &amp; Manz, A. (1993). Micromachining a miniaturized capillary electrophoresis-based chemical analysis system on a chip. Science, 261, 895-897. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.261.5123.895</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heida, T., Vulto, P., Rutten, W. L., &amp; Marani, E. (2001). Viability of dielectrophoretically trapped neural cortical cells in culture. Journal of Neuroscience Methods, 110, 37-44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirsch, N. P. (2007). Neuromuscular junction in health and disease. British Journal of Anaesthesia, 99, 132-138. https://doi.org/10.1093/bja/aem144</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holt, C. E., Martin, K. C., &amp; Schuman, E. M. (2019). Local translation in neurons: Visualization and function. Nature Structural &amp; Molecular Biology, 26, 557-566.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holt, C. E., &amp; Schuman, E. M. (2013). The central dogma decentralized: New perspectives on RNA function and local translation in neurons. Neuron, 80, 648-657. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2013.10.036</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hung, P. J., Lee, P. J., Sabounchi, P., Lin, R., &amp; Lee, L. P. (2005). Continuous perfusion microfluidic cell culture array for high-throughput cell-based assays. Biotechnology and Bioengineering, 89, 1-8. https://doi.org/10.1002/bit.20289</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ilieva, H., Polymenidou, M., &amp; Cleveland, D. W. (2009). Non-cell autonomous toxicity in neurodegenerative disorders: ALS and beyond. Journal of Cell Biology, 187, 761-772. https://doi.org/10.1083/jcb.200908164</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ingber, D. E. (2018). Developmentally inspired human &#x201c;organs on chips&#x201d;. Development, 145, dev156125. https://doi.org/10.1242/dev.156125</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ionescu, A., Gradus, T., Altman, T., Maimon, R., Saraf, A. N., Geva, M., Hayden, M., &amp; Perlson, E. (2019). Targeting the sigma-1 receptor via pridopidine ameliorates central features of ALS pathology in a SOD1(G93A) model. Cell Death &amp; Disease, 10, 210. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41419-019-1451-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ionescu, A., Zahavi, E. E., Gradus, T., Ben-Yaakov, K., &amp; Perlson, E. (2016). Compartmental microfluidic system for studying muscle-neuron communication and neuromuscular junction maintenance. European Journal of Cell Biology, 95, 69-88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaiswal, M. K. (2019). Riluzole and edaravone: A tale of two amyotrophic lateral sclerosis drugs. Medicinal Research Reviews, 39, 733-748. https://doi.org/10.1002/med.21528</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jimbo, Y., &amp; Kawana, A. (1992). Electrical stimulation and recording from cultured neurons using a planar electrode array. Bioelectrochemistry and Bioenergetics, 29, 193-204. https://doi.org/10.1016/0302-4598(92)80067-Q</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Junaid, A., Mashaghi, A., Hankemeier, T., &amp; Vulto, P. (2017). An end-user perspective on organ-on-a-chip: Assays and usability aspects. Current Opinion in Biomedical Engineering, 1, 15-22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jung, H., Yoon, B. C., &amp; Holt, C. E. (2012). Axonal mRNA localization and local protein synthesis in nervous system assembly, maintenance and repair. Nature Reviews Neuroscience, 13, 308-324.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang, S. H., Li, Y., Fukaya, M., Lorenzini, I., Cleveland, D. W., Ostrow, L. W., Rothstein, J. D., &amp; Bergles, D. E. (2013). Degeneration and impaired regeneration of gray matter oligodendrocytes in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nature Neuroscience, 16, 571-579.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanning, K. C., Kaplan, A., &amp; Henderson, C. E. (2010). Motor neuron diversity in development and disease. Annual Review of Neuroscience, 33, 409-440.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Killian, J. M., Wilfong, A. A., Burnett, L., Appel, S. H., &amp; Boland, D. (1994). Decremental motor responses to repetitive nerve stimulation in ALS. Muscle and Nerve, 17, 747-754. https://doi.org/10.1002/mus.880170708</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kimura, H., Sakai, Y., &amp; Fujii, T. (2018). Organ/body-on-a-chip based on microfluidic technology for drug discovery. Drug Metabolism and Pharmacokinetics, 33, 43-48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ko, C.-P., &amp; Robitaille, R. (2015). Perisynaptic schwann cells at the neuromuscular synapse: Adaptable, multitasking glial cells. Cold Spring Harbor Perspectives in Biology, 7(10), a020503</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koppers, M., Cagnetta, R., Shigeoka, T., Wunderlich, L. C. S., Vallejo-Ramirez, P., Qiaojin Lin, J., Zhao, S., Jakobs, M. A. H., Dwivedy, A., Minett, M. S., Bellon, A., Kaminski, C. F., Harris, W. A., Flanagan, J. G., &amp; Holt, C. E. (2019). Receptor-specific interactome as a hub for rapid cue-induced selective translation in axons. Elife, 8, 48718. https://doi.org/10.7554/eLife.48718</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krakora, D., Macrander, C., &amp; Suzuki, M. (2012). Neuromuscular junction protection for the potential treatment of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology Research International, 2012, 379657.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwiatkowski, T. J., Bosco, D. A., LeClerc, A. L., Tamrazian, E., Vanderburg, C. R., Russ, C., Davis, A., Gilchrist, J., Kasarskis, E. J., Munsat, T., Valdmanis, P., Rouleau, G. A., Hosler, B. A., Cortelli, P., de Jong, P. J., Yoshinaga, Y., Haines, J. L., Pericak-Vance, M. A., Yan, J., &#x2026; Brown, R. H. (2009). Mutations in the FUS/TLS gene on chromosome 16 cause familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Science, 323, 1205-1208. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.1166066</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le, N. T. T., Chang, L., Kovlyagina, I., Georgiou, P., Safren, N., Braunstein, K. E., Kvarta, M. D. et al (2016). Motor neuron disease, TDP-43 pathology, and memory deficits in mice expressing ALS-FTD-linked UBQLN2 mutations. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 113, E7580-E7589.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leclerc, E., Sakai, Y., &amp; Fujii, T. (2003). Cell culture in 3-dimensional microfluidic structure of PDMS (polydimethylsiloxane). Biomedical Microdevices, 5, 109-114.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, H., Shamy, G., Al, E. Y., Schofield, C. M., Harrsion, N. L., Panagiotakos, G., Socci, N. D., Tabar, V., &amp; Studer, L. (2007). Directed differentiation and transplantation of human embryonic stem cell-derived motoneurons. Stem Cells, 25, 1931-1939. https://doi.org/10.1634/stemcells.2007-0097</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, J. H., Daugharthy, E. R., Scheiman, J., Kalhor, R., Ferrante, T. C., Terry, R., Turczyk, B. M., Yang, J. L., Lee, H. S., Aach, J., Zhang, K., &amp; Church, G. M. (2015). Fluorescent in situ sequencing (FISSEQ) of RNA for gene expression profiling in intact cells and tissues. Nature Protocols, 10, 442-458. https://doi.org/10.1038/nprot.2014.191</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leung, K.-M., Horck, F. P. G., van Lin, A. C., Allison, R., Standart, N., &amp; Holt, C. E.(2006). Asymmetrical beta-actin mRNA translation in growth cones mediates attractive turning to netrin-1. Nature Neuroscience, 9, 1247-1256.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, X.-J., Du, Z.-W., Zarnowska, E. D., Pankratz, M., Hansen, L. O., Pearce, R. A., &amp; Zhang, S.-C. (2005). Specification of motoneurons from human embryonic stem cells. Nature Biotechnology, 23, 215-221. https://doi.org/10.1038/nbt1063</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, C.-Y., Yoshida, M., Li, L.-T., Ikenaka, A., Oshima, S., Nakagawa, K., Sakurai, H., Matsui, E., Nakahata, T., &amp; Saito, M. K. (2019). iPSC-derived functional human neuromuscular junctions model the pathophysiology of neuromuscular diseases. JCI Insight, 4, e124299. https://doi.org/10.1172/jci.insight.124299</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loeffler, J.-P., Picchiarelli, G., Dupuis, L., &amp; Gonzalez De Aguilar, J.-L. (2016). The role of skeletal muscle in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain Pathology, 26, 227-236. https://doi.org/10.1111/bpa.12350</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf3;pez-Erauskin, J., Tadokoro, T., Baughn, M. W., Myers, B., McAlonis-Downes, M., Chillon-Marinas, C., Asiaban, J. N., Artates, J., Bui, A. T., Vetto, A. P., Lee, S. K., Le, A. V., Sun, Y., Jambeau, M., Boubaker, J., Swing, D., Qiu, J., Hicks, G. G., Ouyang, Z., &#x2026; Da Cruz, S. (2018). ALS/FTD-linked mutation in FUS suppresses intra-axonal protein synthesis and drives disease without nuclear loss-of-function of FUS. Neuron, 100, 816-830. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2018.09.044</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu, X., Kim-Han, J. S., O&#x2019;Malley, K. L., &amp; Sakiyama-Elbert, S. E. (2012). A microdevice platform for visualizing mitochondrial transport in aligned dopaminergic axons. Journal of Neuroscience Methods, 209, 35-39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ly, C. V., &amp; Verstreken, P. (2006). Mitochondria at the synapse. Neuroscientist, 12, 291-299. https://doi.org/10.1177/1073858406287661</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Machado, C. B., Pluchon, P., Harley, P., Rigby, M., Gonzalez, S. V., Stevenson, D. C., Hynes, S. et al (2019). In vitro modelling of nerve-muscle connectivity in a compartmentalised tissue culture device. Advanced Biosystems, 3, 1800307.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Machamer, J. B., Collins, S. E., &amp; Lloyd, T. E. (2014). The ALS gene FUS regulates synaptic transmission at the Drosophila neuromuscular junction. Human Molecular Genetics, 23, 3810-3822.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Machamer, J. B., Woolums, B. M., Fuller, G. G., &amp; Lloyd, T. E. (2018). FUS causes synaptic hyperexcitability in Drosophila dendritic arborization neurons. Brain Research, 1693, 55-66. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.brainres.2018.03.037</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maffioletti, S. M., Sarcar, S., Henderson, A. B. H., Mannhardt, I., Pinton, L., Moyle, L. A., Steele-Stallard, H., Cappellari, O., Wells, K. E., Ferrari, G., Mitchell, J. S., Tyzack, G. E., Kotiadis, V. N., Khedr, M., Ragazzi, M., Wang, W., Duchen, M. R., Patani, R., Zammit, P. S., &#x2026; Tedesco, F. S. (2018). Three-dimensional human iPSC-Derived artificial skeletal muscles model muscular dystrophies and enable multilineage tissue engineering. Cell Reports, 23, 899-908. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.celrep.2018.03.091</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maimon, R., Ionescu, A., Bonnie, A., Sweetat, S., Wald-Altman, S., Inbar, S., Gradus, T., Trotti, D., Weil, M., Behar, O., &amp; Perlson, E. (2018). Mir126-5p downregulation facilitates axon degeneration and nmj disruption via a non-cell-autonomous mechanism in ALS. Journal of Neuroscience, 38, 5478-5494. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.3037-17.2018</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manz, A., Fettinger, J. C., Verpoorte, E., L&#xfc;di, H., Widmer, H. M., &amp; Harrison, D. J. (1991). Micromachining of monocrystalline silicon and glass for chemical analysis systems A look into next century&#x2019;s technology or just a fashionable craze? TrAC Trends Anal. Chem., 10, 144-149.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manz, A., Graber, N., &amp; Widmer, H. M. (1990). Miniaturized total chemical analysis systems: A novel concept for chemical sensing. Sensors Actuators B Chem., 1, 244-248. https://doi.org/10.1016/0925-4005(90)80209-I</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marteyn, A., Maury, Y., Gauthier, M. M., Lecuyer, C., Vernet, R., Denis, J. A., Pietu, G., Peschanski, M., &amp; Martinat, C. (2011). Mutant human embryonic stem cells reveal neurite and synapse formation defects in type 1 myotonic dystrophy. Cell Stem Cell, 8, 434-444. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.stem.2011.02.004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martineau, &#xc9;., Polo, A., Di, V. C., &amp; Vande, R. R. (2018). Dynamic neuromuscular remodeling precedes motor-unit loss in a mouse model of ALS. Elife, 7, e41973. https://doi.org/10.7554/eLife.41973</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marx, U., Andersson, T. B., Bahinski, A., Beilmann, M., Beken, S., Cassee, F. R., Cirit, M. et al (2016). Biology-inspired microphysiological system approaches to solve the prediction dilemma of substance testing. Altex, 33, 272-321. https://doi.org/10.14573/altex.1603161</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mertens, J., Paquola, A. C. M., Ku, M., Hatch, E., B&#xf6;hnke, L., Ladjevardi, S., McGrath, S., Campbell, B., Lee, H., Herdy, J. R., Gon&#xe7;alves, J. T., Toda, T., Kim, Y., Winkler, J., Yao, J., Hetzer, M. W., &amp; Gage, F. H. (2015). Directly reprogrammed human neurons retain aging-associated transcriptomic signatures and reveal age-related nucleocytoplasmic defects. Cell Stem Cell, 17, 705-718. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.stem.2015.09.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Millecamps, S., &amp; Julien, J. P. (2013). Axonal transport deficits and neurodegenerative diseases. Nature Reviews Neuroscience, 14, 161-176.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller, P. G., Chen, C.-Y., Wang, Y. I., Gao, E., &amp; Shuler, M. L. (2020). Multiorgan microfluidic platform with breathable lung chamber for inhalation or intravenous drug screening and development. Biotechnology and Bioengineering, 117, 486-497. https://doi.org/10.1002/bit.27188</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ming, G., Wong, S. T., Henley, J., Yuan, X., Song, H., Spitzer, N. C., &amp; Poo, M. (2002). Adaptation in the chemotactic guidance of nerve growth cones. Nature, 417, 411-418. https://doi.org/10.1038/nature745</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minis, A., Dahary, D., Manor, O., Leshkowitz, D., Pilpel, Y., &amp; Yaron, A. (2014). Subcellular transcriptomics-dissection of the mRNA composition in the axonal compartment of sensory neurons. Developmental Neurobiology Developmental Neurobiology, 74, 365-381.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moloney, E. B., de Winter, F., &amp; Verhaagen, J.(2014). ALS as a distal axonopathy: Molecular mechanisms affecting neuromuscular junction stability in the presymptomatic stages of the disease. Frontiers in Neuroscience, 8, 252.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morimoto, Y., Kato-Negishi, M., Onoe, H., &amp; Takeuchi, S. (2013). Three-dimensional neuron-muscle constructs with neuromuscular junctions. Biomaterials, 34, 9413-9419. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biomaterials.2013.08.062</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murray, L. M., Talbot, K., &amp; Gillingwater, T. H. (2010). Review: Neuromuscular synaptic vulnerability in motor neurone disease: Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and spinal muscular atrophy. Neuropathology and Applied Neurobiology, 36, 133-156. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2990.2010.01061.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakata, M., Kuwabara, S., Kanai, K., Misawa, S., Tamura, N., Sawai, S., Hattori, T., &amp; Bostock, H. (2006). Distal excitability changes in motor axons in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clinical Neurophysiology, 117, 1444-1448. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.clinph.2006.04.005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Natarajan, A., Sethumadhavan, A., &amp; Krishnan, U. M. (2019). Toward building the neuromuscular junction: In vitro models to study synaptogenesis and neurodegeneration. ACS Omega, 4, 12969-12977. https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.9b00973</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neumann, M., Sampathu, D. M., Kwong, L. K., Truax, A. C., Micsenyi, M. C., Chou, T. T., Bruce, J., Schuck, T., Grossman, M., Clark, C. M., McCluskey, L. F., Miller, B. L., Masliah, E., Mackenzie, I. R., Feldman, H., Feiden, W., Kretzschmar, H. A., Trojanowski, J. Q., &amp; Lee, V.- M.-Y. (2006). Ubiquitinated TDP-43 in frontotemporal lobar degeneration and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Science, 314, 130-133. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.1134108</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nijssen, J., Aguila, J., Hoogstraaten, R., Kee, N., &amp; Hedlund, E. (2018). Axon-seq decodes the motor axon transcriptome and its modulation in response to ALS. Stem Cell Reports, 11, 1565-1578. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.stemcr.2018.11.005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osaki, T., Uzel, S. G. M., &amp; Kamm, R. D. (2018). Microphysiological 3D model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) from human iPS-derived muscle cells and optogenetic motor neurons. Science Advances, 4, eaat5847. https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.aat5847</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osaki, T., Uzel, S. G. M., &amp; Kamm, R. D. (2020). On-chip 3D neuromuscular model for drug screening and precision medicine in neuromuscular disease. Nature Protocols, 15, 421-449. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41596-019-0248-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osking, Z., Ayers, J. I., Hildebrandt, R., Skruber, K., Brown, H., Ryu, D., Eukovich, A. R., Golde, T. E., Borchelt, D. R., Read, T.-A., &amp; Vitriol, E. A. (2019). ALS-linked SOD1 mutants enhance neurite outgrowth and branching in adult motor neurons. Iscience, 11, 294-304. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.isci.2018.12.026</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Painter, M. W. (2017). Aging schwann cells: Mechanisms, implications, future directions. Current Opinion in Neurobiology, 47, 203-208.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palma, E., Inghilleri, M., Conti, L., Deflorio, C., Frasca, V., Manteca, A., Pichiorri, F. et al (2011). Physiological characterization of human muscle acetylcholine receptors from ALS patients. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 108, 20184-20188.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pandya, V. A., &amp; Patani, R. (2020). Decoding the relationship between ageing and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A cellular perspective. Brain, 143, 1057-1072. https://doi.org/10.1093/brain/awz360</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pansarasa, O., Rossi, D., Berardinelli, A., &amp; Cereda, C. (2014). Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and skeletal muscle: An update. Molecular Neurobiology, 49, 984-990. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12035-013-8578-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paranjape, S. R., Nagendran, T., Poole, V., Harris, J., &amp; Taylor, A. M. (2019). Compartmentalization of human stem cell-derived neurons within pre-assembled plastic microfluidic chips. Journal of Visualized Experiments, 147, e59250.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pasteuning-Vuhman, S., Jongh, R., De, T. A., &amp; Jeroen, P. R. (2020). Towards advanced iPSC-based drug development for neurodegenerative disease. Trends in Molecular Medicine.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng, H. B., Yang, J.-F., Dai, Z., Lee, C. W., Hung, H. W., Feng, Z. H., &amp; Ko, C.-P. (2003). Differential effects of neurotrophins and schwann cell-derived signals on neuronal survival/growth and synaptogenesis. Journal of Neuroscience, 23, 5050-5060. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.23-12-05050.2003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perry, R.- B.-T., Doron-Mandel, E., Iavnilovitch, E., Rishal, I., Dagan, S. Y., Tsoory, M., Coppola, G. et al (2012). Subcellular knockout of importin beta1 perturbs axonal retrograde signaling. Neuron, 75, 294-305.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Philips, T., Bento-Abreu, A., Nonneman, A., Haeck, W., Staats, K., Geelen, V., Hersmus, N., K&#xfc;sters, B., Van Den Bosch, L., Van Damme, P., Richardson, W. D., &amp; Robberecht, W. (2013). Oligodendrocyte dysfunction in the pathogenesis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain, 136, 471-482. https://doi.org/10.1093/brain/aws339</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Picchiarelli, G., Demestre, M., Zuko, A., Been, M., Higelin, J., Dieterle, S., Goy, M.-A. et al (2019). FUS-mediated regulation of acetylcholine receptor transcription at neuromuscular junctions is compromised in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nature Neuroscience, 22, 1793-1805.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piper, M., Anderson, R., Dwivedy, A., Weinl, C., van Horck, F., Leung, K. M., Cogill, E., &amp; Holt, C. (2006). Signaling mechanisms underlying Slit2-induced collapse of Xenopus retinal growth cones. Neuron, 49, 215-228. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2005.12.008</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pollari, E., Goldsteins, G., Bart, G., Koistinaho, J., &amp; Giniatullin, R. (2014). The role of oxidative stress in degeneration of the neuromuscular junction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Frontiers in Cellular Neuroscience, 8, 131.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Powers, M. J., Domansky, K., Kaazempur-Mofrad, M. R., Kalezi, A., Capitano, A., Upadhyaya, A., Kurzawski, P., Wack, K. E., Stolz, D. B., Kamm, R., &amp; Griffith, L. G. (2002). A microfabricated array bioreactor for perfused 3D liver culture. Biotechnology and Bioengineering, 78, 257-269. https://doi.org/10.1002/bit.10143</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prpar, M. S., Pavlin, M., Darovic, S., &#x17d;ivin, M., Podbregar, M., Rogelj, B., &amp; Mars, T. (2017). Modelling FUS mislocalisation in an in vitro model of innervated human muscle. Journal of Molecular Neuroscience, 62, 318-328.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pun, S., Santos, A. F., Saxena, S., Xu, L., &amp; Caroni, P. (2006). Selective vulnerability and pruning of phasic motoneuron axons in motoneuron disease alleviated by CNTF. Nature Neuroscience, 9, 408-419.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puttonen, K. A., Ruponen, M., Naumenko, N., Hovatta, O. H., Tavi, P., &amp; Koistinaho, J. (2015). Generation of functional neuromuscular junctions from human pluripotent stem cell lines. Frontiers in Cellular Neuroscience, 9, 473.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rabieh, N., Ojovan, S. M., Shmoel, N., Erez, H., Maydan, E., &amp; Spira, M. E. (2016). On-chip, multisite extracellular and intracellular recordings from primary cultured skeletal myotubes. Scientific Reports, 6, 36498.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renton, A. E., Chio, A., &amp; Traynor, B. J. (2014). State of play in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis genetics. Nature Neuroscience, 17, 17-23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renton, A. E., Majounie, E., Waite, A., Sim&#xf3;n-S&#xe1;nchez, J., Rollinson, S., Gibbs, J. R., Schymick, J. C., Laaksovirta, H., van&#xa0;Swieten, J. C., Myllykangas, L., Kalimo, H., Paetau, A., Abramzon, Y., Remes, A. M., Kaganovich, A., Scholz, S. W., Duckworth, J., Ding, J., Harmer, D. W., &#x2026; Traynor, B. J. (2011). A hexanucleotide repeat expansion in C9ORF72 is the cause of chromosome 9p21-linked ALS-FTD. Neuron, 72, 257-268. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2011.09.010</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robitaille, R. (1998). Modulation of synaptic efficacy and synaptic depression by glial cells at the frog neuromuscular junction. Neuron, 21, 847-855. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0896-6273(00)80600-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosen, D. R., Siddique, T., Patterson, D., Figlewicz, D. A., Sapp, P., Hentati, A., Donaldson, D., Goto, J., O'Regan, J. P., Deng, H.-X., Rahmani, Z., Krizus, A., McKenna-Yasek, D., Cayabyab, A., Gaston, S. M., Berger, R., Tanzi, R. E., Halperin, J. J., Herzfeldt, B., &#x2026; Brown, R. H. (1993). Mutations in Cu/Zn superoxide dismutase gene are associated with familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nature, 362, 59-62. https://doi.org/10.1038/362059a0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rotem, N., Magen, I., Ionescu, A., Gershoni-Emek, N., Altman, T., Costa, C. J., Gradus, T. et al (2017). ALS along the Axons - Expression of coding and noncoding RNA differs in axons of ALS models. Scientific Reports, 7, 44500.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rudolf, R., Khan, M. M., &amp; Witzemann, V. (2019). Motor Endplate-Anatomical, Functional, and Molecular Concepts in the Historical Perspective. Cells, 8, 387. https://doi.org/10.3390/cells8050387</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saberi, S., Stauffer, J. E., Schulte, D. J., &amp; Ravits, J. (2015). Neuropathology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and its variants. Neurologic Clinics, 33, 855-876.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sahoo, P. K., Smith, D. S., Perrone-Bizzozero, N., &amp; Twiss, J. L. (2018). Axonal mRNA transport and translation at a glance. Journal of Cell Science, 131. https://doi.org/10.1242/jcs.196808</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sances, S., Bruijn, L. I., Chandran, S., Eggan, K., Ho, R., Klim, J. R., Livesey, M. R. et al (2016). Modeling ALS with motor neurons derived from human induced pluripotent stem cells. Nature Neuroscience, 19, 542-553.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santhanam, N., Kumanchik, L., Guo, X., Sommerhage, F., Cai, Y., Jackson, M., Martin, C., Saad, G., McAleer, C. W., Wang, Y., Lavado, A., Long, C. J., &amp; Hickman, J. J. (2018). Stem cell derived phenotypic human neuromuscular junction model for dose response evaluation of therapeutics. Biomaterials, 166, 64-78. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biomaterials.2018.02.047</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santoso, J. W., &amp; McCain, M. L. (2020). Neuromuscular disease modeling on a chip. Disease Models &amp; Mechanisms, 13(7),</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sasaki, S., &amp; Maruyama, S. (1994). Synapse loss in anterior horn neurons in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathologica, 88, 222-227. https://doi.org/10.1007/BF00293397</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scekic-Zahirovic, J., Oussini, H. E., Mersmann, S., Drenner, K., Wagner, M., Sun, Y., Allmeroth, K., Dieterl&#xe9;, S., Sinniger, J., Dirrig-Grosch, S., Ren&#xe9;, F., Dormann, D., Haass, C., Ludolph, A. C., Lagier-Tourenne, C., Storkebaum, E., &amp; Dupuis, L. (2017). Motor neuron intrinsic and extrinsic mechanisms contribute to the pathogenesis of FUS-associated amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathologica, 133, 887-906. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00401-017-1687-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scheib, J. L., &amp; H&#xf6;ke, A. (2016). An attenuated immune response by Schwann cells and macrophages inhibits nerve regeneration in aged rats. Neurobiology of Aging, 45, 1-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seecof, R. L., Teplitz, R. L., Gerson, I., Ikeda, K., &amp; Donady, J. (1972). Differentiation of neuromuscular junctions in cultures of embryonic Drosophila cells. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 69, 566-570.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma, A., Lyashchenko, A. K., Lu, L., Nasrabady, S. E., Elmaleh, M., Mendelsohn, M., Nemes, A., Tapia, J. C., Mentis, G. Z., &amp; Shneider, N. A. (2016). ALS-associated mutant FUS induces selective motor neuron degeneration through toxic gain of function. Nature Communications, 7, 10465.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shima, A., Morimoto, Y., Sweeney, H. L., &amp; Takeuchi, S. (2018). Three-dimensional contractile muscle tissue consisting of human skeletal myocyte cell line. Experimental Cell Research, 370, 168-173. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.yexcr.2018.06.015</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimada, Y., Fischman, D. A., &amp; Moscona, A. A. (1969). Formation of neuromuscular junctions in embryonic cell cultures. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 62, 715-721.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siklos, L., Engelhardt, J., Harati, Y., Smith, R. G., Joo, F., &amp; Appel, S. H. (1996). Ultrastructural evidence for altered calcium in motor nerve terminals in amyotropic lateral sclerosis. Annals of Neurology, 39, 203-216.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slater, C. R. (2017). The structure of human neuromuscular junctions: Some unanswered molecular questions. International Journal of Molecular Sciences, 18, 2183.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith, A. S. T., Passey, S., Greensmith, L., Mudera, V., &amp; Lewis, M. P. (2012). Characterization and optimization of a simple, repeatable system for the long term in vitro culture of aligned myotubes in 3D. Journal of Cellular Biochemistry, 113, 1044-1053. https://doi.org/10.1002/jcb.23437</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith, I. W., Mikesh, M., Lee, Y. I, &amp; Thompson, W. J,(2013). Terminal Schwann cells participate in the competition underlying neuromuscular synapse elimination. Journal of Neuroscience, 33, 17724-17736. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.3339-13.2013</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>So, E., Mitchell, J. C., Memmi, C., Chennell, G., Vizcay-Barrena, G., Allison, L., Shaw, C. E., &amp; Vance, C. (2018). Mitochondrial abnormalities and disruption of the neuromuscular junction precede the clinical phenotype and motor neuron loss in hFUSWT transgenic mice. Human Molecular Genetics, 27, 463-474.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Southam, K. A., King, A. E., Blizzard, C. A., McCormack, G. H., &amp; Dickson, T. C. (2013). Microfluidic primary culture model of the lower motor neuron-neuromuscular junction circuit. Journal of Neuroscience Methods, 218, 164-169.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steinbeck, J. A., Jaiswal, M. K., Calder, E. L., Kishinevsky, S., Weishaupt, A., Toyka, K. V., Goldstein, P. A., &amp; Studer, L. (2016). Functional connectivity under optogenetic control allows modeling of human neuromuscular disease. Cell Stem Cell, 18, 134-143. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.stem.2015.10.002</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swinnen, B., Robberecht, W., Bosch, L., &amp; Den, V. (2020). RNA toxicity in non-coding repeat expansion disorders. EMBO Journal, 39, e101112. https://doi.org/10.15252/embj.2018101112</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szepsenwol, J. (1946). A comparison of growth, differentiation, activity and action currents of heart and skeletal muscle in tissue culture. Anatomical Record, 95, 125-146.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takahashi, K., &amp; Yamanaka, S. (2006). Induction of pluripotent stem cells from mouse embryonic and adult fibroblast cultures by defined factors. Cell, 126, 663-676. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2006.07.024</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takeuchi, A., Nakafutami, S., Tani, H., Mori, M., Takayama, Y., Moriguchi, H., Kotani, K., Miwa, K., Lee, J.-K., Noshiro, M., &amp; Jimbo, Y. (2011). Device for co-culture of sympathetic neurons and cardiomyocytes using microfabrication. Lab on a Chip, 11, 2268-2275. https://doi.org/10.1039/c0lc00327a</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tallon, C., Russell, K. A., Sakhalkar, S., Andrapallayal, N., &amp; Farah, M. H. (2016). Length-dependent axo-terminal degeneration at the neuromuscular synapses of type II muscle in SOD1 mice. Neuroscience, 312, 179-189. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuroscience.2015.11.018</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tapia, J. C., Wylie, J. D., Kasthuri, N., Hayworth, K. J., Schalek, R., Berger, D. R., Guatimosim, C., Seung, H. S., &amp; Lichtman, J. W. (2012). Pervasive synaptic branch removal in the mammalian neuromuscular system at birth. Neuron, 74, 816-829. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2012.04.017</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor, A. M., Blurton-Jones, M., Rhee, S. W., Cribbs, D. H., Cotman, C. W., &amp; Jeon, N. L. (2005). A microfluidic culture platform for CNS axonal injury, regeneration and transport. Nature Methods, 2, 599-605.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thi&#xe9;baud, P., Rooij, N. F., De, K.-H., &amp; Stoppini, L. (1997). Microelectrode arrays for electrophysiological monitoring of hippocampal organotypic slice cultures. IEEE Transactions on Biomedical Engineering, 44, 1159-1163.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Todd, K. J., Darabid, H., &amp; Robitaille, R. (2010). Perisynaptic glia discriminate patterns of motor nerve activity and influence plasticity at the neuromuscular junction. Journal of Neuroscience, 30, 11870-11882. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.3165-10.2010</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trietsch, S. J., Isra&#xeb;ls, G. D., Joore, J., Hankemeier, T., &amp; Vulto, P. (2013). Microfluidic titer plate for stratified 3D cell culture. Lab on a Chip, 13, 3548-3554. https://doi.org/10.1039/c3lc50210d</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Umbach, J. A., Adams, K. L., Gundersen, C. B., &amp; Novitch, B. G. (2012). Functional neuromuscular junctions formed by embryonic stem cell-derived motor neurons. PLoS One, 7, e36049. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0036049</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uzel, S. G. M., Platt, R. J., Subramanian, V., Pearl, T. M., Rowlands, C. J., Chan, V., Boyer, L. A., So, P. T. C., &amp; Kamm, R. D. (2016). Microfluidic device for the formation of optically excitable, three-dimensional, compartmentalized motor units. Science Advances, 2(8), e1501429</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Dyke, D. J. M., Smit-Oistad, I. M., Macrander, C., Krakora, D., Meyer, M. G., &amp; Suzuki, M. (2016). Macrophage-mediated inflammation and glial response in the skeletal muscle of a rat model of familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). Experimental Neurology, 277, 275-282.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Duinen, V., Zhu, D., Ramakers, C., van Zonneveld, A. J., Vulto, P., &amp; Hankemeier, T. (2019). Perfused 3D angiogenic sprouting in a high-throughput in vitro platform. Angiogenesis, 22, 157-165. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10456-018-9647-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Es, M. A., Hardiman, O., Chio, A., Al-Chalabi, A., Pasterkamp, R. J., Veldink, J. H., &amp; van den Berg, L. H. (2017). Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet, 390, 2084-2098. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0140-6736(17)31287-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vance, C., Rogelj, B., Hortobagyi, T., De Vos, K. J., Nishimura, A. L., Sreedharan, J., Hu, X., Smith, B., Ruddy, D., Wright, P., Ganesalingam, J., Williams, K. L., Tripathi, V., Al-Saraj, S., Al-Chalabi, A., Leigh, P. N., Blair, I. P., Nicholson, G., de Belleroche, J., &#x2026; Shaw, C. E. (2009). Mutations in FUS, an RNA processing protein, cause familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis type 6. Science, 323, 1208-1211. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.1165942</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vandoorne, T., Bock, K., De, B. L., &amp; Den, V. (2018). Energy metabolism in ALS: An underappreciated opportunity? Acta Neuropathologica, 135, 489-509.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verma, P., Chierzi, S., Codd, A. M., Campbell, D. S., Meyer, R. L., Holt, C. E., &amp; Fawcett, J. W. (2005). Axonal protein synthesis and degradation are necessary for efficient growth cone regeneration. Journal of Neuroscience, 25, 331-342. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.3073-04.2005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vilmont, V., Cadot, B., Ouanounou, G., &amp; Gomes, E. R. (2016). A system for studying mechanisms of neuromuscular junction development and maintenance. Development, 143, 2464-2477. https://doi.org/10.1242/dev.130278</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viravaidya, K., Sin, A., &amp; Shuler, M. L. (2004). Development of a microscale cell culture analog to probe naphthalene toxicity. Biotechnology Progress, 20, 316-323.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vulto, P., Podszun, S., Meyer, P., Hermann, C., Manz, A., &amp; Urban, G. A. (2011). Phaseguides: A paradigm shift in microfluidic priming and emptying. Lab on a Chip, 11, 1596-1602. https://doi.org/10.1039/c0lc00643b</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wevers, N. R., Kasi, D. G., Gray, T., Wilschut, K. J., Smith, B., van Vught, R., Shimizu, F., Sano, Y., Kanda, T., Marsh, G., Trietsch, S. J., Vulto, P., Lanz, H. L., &amp; Obermeier, B. (2018). A perfused human blood-brain barrier on-a-chip for high-throughput assessment of barrier function and antibody transport. Fluids Barriers CNS, 15, 1-12. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12987-018-0108-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wevers, N. R., &amp; de Vries, H. E. (2016). Morphogens and blood-brain barrier function in health and disease. Tissue Barriers, 4, e1090524. https://doi.org/10.1080/21688370.2015.1090524</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wichterle, H., Lieberam, I., Porter, J. A., &amp; Jessell, T. M. (2002). Directed differentiation of embryonic stem cells into motor neurons. Cell, 110, 385-397. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0092-8674(02)00835-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiedemann, F. R., Manfredi, G., Mawrin, C., Beal, M. F., &amp; Schon, E. A. (2002). Mitochondrial DNA and respiratory chain function in spinal cords of ALS patients. Journal of Neurochemistry, 80, 616-625. https://doi.org/10.1046/j.0022-3042.2001.00731.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wishart, T. M., Parson, S. H., &amp; Gillingwater, T. H. (2006). Synaptic vulnerability in neurodegenerative disease. Journal of Neuropathology and Experimental Neurology, 65, 733-739.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, H., Xiong, W. C., &amp; Mei, L. (2010). To build a synapse: Signaling pathways in neuromuscular junction assembly. Development, 137, 1017-1033. https://doi.org/10.1242/dev.038711</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamanaka, K., Chun, S. J., Boillee, S., Fujimori-Tonou, N., Yamashita, H., Gutmann, D. H., Takahashi, R., Misawa, H., &amp; Cleveland, D. W. (2008). Astrocytes as determinants of disease progression in inherited amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nature Neuroscience, 11, 251-253.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao, J., Sasaki, Y., Wen, Z., Bassell, G. J., &amp; Zheng, J. Q. (2006). An essential role for beta-actin mRNA localization and translation in Ca2+-dependent growth cone guidance. Nature Neuroscience, 9, 1265-1273.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoon, B. C., Jung, H., Dwivedy, A., O&#x2019;Hare, C. M., Zivraj, K. H., &amp; Holt, C. E. (2012). Local translation of extranuclear lamin B promotes axon maintenance. Cell, 148, 752-764. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2011.11.064</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshida, M., Kitaoka, S., Egawa, N., Yamane, M., Ikeda, R., Tsukita, K., Amano, N., Watanabe, A., Morimoto, M., Takahashi, J., Hosoi, H., Nakahata, T., Inoue, H., &amp; Saito, M. K. (2015). Modeling the early phenotype at the neuromuscular junction of spinal muscular atrophy using patient-derived iPSCs. Stem Cell Reports, 4, 561-568. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.stemcr.2015.02.010</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zahavi, E. E., Ionescu, A., Gluska, S., Gradus, T., Ben-Yaakov, K., &amp; Perlson, E. (2015). A compartmentalized microfluidic neuromuscular co-culture system reveals spatial aspects of GDNF functions. Journal of Cell Science, 128, 1241-1252. https://doi.org/10.1242/jcs.167544</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng, J. Q., Kelly, T. K., Chang, B., Ryazantsev, S., Rajasekaran, A. K., Martin, K. C., &amp; Twiss, J. L. (2001). A functional role for intra-axonal protein synthesis during axonal regeneration from adult sensory neurons. Journal of Neuroscience, 21, 9291-9303. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.21-23-09291.2001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ziff, O. J., &amp; Patani, R. (2019). Harnessing cellular aging in human stem cell models of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Aging Cell, 18, e12862. https://doi.org/10.1111/acel.12862</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>