<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">33396003</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>25</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2213-1582</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>28</Volume><PubDate><Year>2020</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>NeuroImage. Clinical</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Neuroimage Clin</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Fiber-specific white matter reductions in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>102516</StartPage><MedlinePgn>102516</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">102516</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.nicl.2020.102516</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S2213-1582(20)30353-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) is a progressive neurodegenerative disorder characterized by the loss of both upper and lower motor neurons. Studies using metrics derived from the diffusion tensor model have documented decreased fractional anisotropy (FA) and increased mean diffusivity in the corticospinal tract (CST) and the corpus callosum (CC) in ALS. These studies, however, only focused on microstructural white matter (WM) changes, while the macrostructural alterations of WM tracts in ALS remain unknown. Moreover, studies conducted based on the diffusion tensor model cannot provide information related to specific fiber bundles and fail to clarify which biological characteristics are changing. Using a novel fixel-based analytical method that can characterize the fiber density (FD) and the fiber-bundle cross-section (FC), this study investigated both microstructural and macrostructural changes in the WM in a large cohort of patients with ALS (N&#xa0;=&#xa0;60) compared with demographically matched healthy controls (N&#xa0;=&#xa0;60). Compared with healthy controls, we found decreased FD, FC and fiber density and cross-section (FDC, a combined measure of the FD and FC) values in the bilateral CST and the middle posterior body of the CC in patients with ALS, suggesting not only microstructural but also macrostructural abnormalities in these fiber bundles. Additionally, we found that the mean FD and FDC values in the bilateral CST were positively correlated with the revised ALS Functional Rating Scale, indicating that these two indices may serve as potential markers for assessing the clinical severity of ALS. Thus, these findings provide initial evidence for the existence of microstructural and macrostructural abnormalities of the fiber bundles in ALS.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2020 The Author(s). Published by Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cheng</LastName><ForeName>Luqi</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory for NeuroInformation of Ministry of Education, School of Life Science and Technology, University of Electronic Science and Technology of China, Chengdu 610054, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tang</LastName><ForeName>Xie</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory for NeuroInformation of Ministry of Education, School of Life Science and Technology, University of Electronic Science and Technology of China, Chengdu 610054, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Luo</LastName><ForeName>Chunxia</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, The First Affiliated Hospital, Third Military Medical University, Chongqing 400308, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Daihong</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, Chongqing University Cancer Hospital, School of Medicine, Chongqing University, Chongqing 400030, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Yuanchao</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory for NeuroInformation of Ministry of Education, School of Life Science and Technology, University of Electronic Science and Technology of China, Chengdu 610054, PR China. Electronic address: yuanchao.zhang8@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Jiuquan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, Chongqing University Cancer Hospital, School of Medicine, Chongqing University, Chongqing 400030, PR China. Electronic address: zhangjq_radiol@foxmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Neuroimage Clin</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101597070</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2213-1582</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016880" MajorTopicYN="N">Anisotropy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D056324" MajorTopicYN="N">Diffusion Tensor Imaging</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011712" MajorTopicYN="N">Pyramidal Tracts</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D066127" MajorTopicYN="Y">White Matter</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Corticospinal tract</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fiber density</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fiber-bundle cross-section</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fixel-based analysis</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33396003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7724379</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nicl.2020.102516</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2213-1582(20)30353-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Andersson J.L., Sotiropoulos S.N. An integrated approach to correction for off-resonance effects and subject movement in diffusion MR imaging. NeuroImage. 2016;125:1063&#x2013;1078.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4692656</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26481672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beaulieu C. The basis of anisotropic water diffusion in the nervous system&#x2013;a technical review. NMR Biomedicine. 2002;15:435&#x2013;455.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12489094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks B.R., Miller R.G., Swash M., Munsat T.L. El Escorial revisited: revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis and Other Motor Neuron Disorders. 2000;1:293&#x2013;299.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11464847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brownell B., Oppenheimer D., Hughes J.T. The central nervous system in motor neurone disease. J. Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatry. 1970;33:338&#x2013;357.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC493478</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5431724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum J.M., Stambler N., Malta E., Fuller C., Hilt D., Thurmond B., Nakanishi A. The ALSFRS-R: a revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. J. Neurol. Sci. 1999;169:13&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10540002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhollander, T., Connelly, A., 2016. A novel iterative approach to reap the benefits of multi-tissue CSD from just single-shell (+ b= 0) diffusion MRI data. Proc ISMRM, p. 3010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhollander T., Raffelt D., Connelly A. Towards interpretation of 3-tissue constrained spherical deconvolution results in pathology. Intl. Soc. Mag. Reson. Med. Proc. 2017:1815.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dimond D., Schuetze M., Smith R.E., Dhollander T., Cho I., Vinette S., Ten Eycke K., Lebel C., McCrimmon A., Dewey D. Reduced white matter fiber density in autism spectrum disorder. Cereb. Cortex. 2019;29:1778&#x2013;1788.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6418389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30668849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foerster B.R., Welsh R.C., Feldman E.L. 25 years of neuroimaging in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nature Reviews Neurology. 2013;9:513&#x2013;524.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4182931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23917850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gajamange S., Raffelt D., Dhollander T., Lui E., van der Walt A., Kilpatrick T., Fielding J., Connelly A., Kolbe S. Fibre-specific white matter changes in multiple sclerosis patients with optic neuritis. NeuroImage: Clinical. 2018;17:60&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5842545</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29527473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon P.H. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: an update for 2013 clinical features, pathophysiology, management and therapeutic trials. Aging and disease. 2013;4:295.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3794725</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24124634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes J. Pathology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Adv. Neurol. 1982;36:61&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7180695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishaque A., Mah D., Seres P., Luk C., Johnston W., Chenji S., Beaulieu C., Yang Y.H., Kalra S. Corticospinal tract degeneration in ALS unmasked in T1-weighted images using texture analysis. Hum. Brain Mapp. 2019;40:1174&#x2013;1183.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6865626</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30367724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeurissen B., Leemans A., Tournier J.D., Jones D.K., Sijbers J. Investigating the prevalence of complex fiber configurations in white matter tissue with diffusion magnetic resonance imaging. Hum. Brain Mapp. 2013;34:2747&#x2013;2766.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6870534</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22611035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalra S., M&#xfc;ller H.-P., Ishaque A., Zinman L., Korngut L., Genge A., Beaulieu C., Frayne R., Graham S.J., Kassubek J. A prospective harmonized multicenter DTI study of cerebral white matter degeneration in ALS. Neurology. 2020;95:e943&#x2013;e952.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7668555</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32646955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kassubek J., M&#xfc;ller H.-P., Del Tredici K., Lul&#xe9; D., Gorges M., Braak H., Ludolph A.C. Imaging the pathoanatomy of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in vivo: targeting a propagation-based biological marker. J. Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatry. 2018;89:374&#x2013;381.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5869447</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29101254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mito R., Raffelt D., Dhollander T., Vaughan D.N., Tournier J.-D., Salvado O., Brodtmann A., Rowe C.C., Villemagne V.L., Connelly A. Fibre-specific white matter reductions in Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease and mild cognitive impairment. Brain. 2018;141:888&#x2013;902.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29309541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mori S., Wakana S., Van Zijl P.C., Nagae-Poetscher L. Elsevier; 2005. MRI atlas of human white matter.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller H.-P., Del Tredici K., Lul&#xe9; D., M&#xfc;ller K., Weishaupt J.H., Ludolph A.C., Kassubek J. In vivo histopathological staging in C9orf72-associated ALS: A tract of interest DTI study. NeuroImage: Clinical. 2020;102298</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7270604</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32505118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller H.-P., Turner M.R., Grosskreutz J., Abrahams S., Bede P., Govind V., Prudlo J., Ludolph A.C., Filippi M., Kassubek J. A large-scale multicentre cerebral diffusion tensor imaging study in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J. Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatry. 2016;87:570&#x2013;579.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26746186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nasreddine Z.S., Phillips N.A., B&#xe9;dirian V., Charbonneau S., Whitehead V., Collin I., Cummings J.L., Chertkow H. The Montreal Cognitive Assessment, MoCA: a brief screening tool for mild cognitive impairment. J. Am. Geriatr. Soc. 2005;53:695&#x2013;699.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15817019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiu T., Zhang Y., Tang X., Liu X., Wang Y., Zhou C., Luo C., Zhang J. Precentral degeneration and cerebellar compensation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A multimodal MRI analysis. Hum. Brain Mapp. 2019;40:3464&#x2013;3474.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6865414</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31020731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raffelt D., Tournier J.-D., Fripp J., Crozier S., Connelly A., Salvado O. Symmetric diffeomorphic registration of fibre orientation distributions. NeuroImage. 2011;56:1171&#x2013;1180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21316463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raffelt D., Tournier J.-D., Rose S., Ridgway G.R., Henderson R., Crozier S., Salvado O., Connelly A. Apparent fibre density: a novel measure for the analysis of diffusion-weighted magnetic resonance images. NeuroImage. 2012;59:3976&#x2013;3994.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22036682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raffelt D., Tournier J.D., Crozier S., Connelly A., Salvado O. Reorientation of fiber orientation distributions using apodized point spread functions. Magn. Reson. Med. 2012;67:844&#x2013;855.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22183751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raffelt D.A., Smith R.E., Ridgway G.R., Tournier J.-D., Vaughan D.N., Rose S., Henderson R., Connelly A. Connectivity-based fixel enhancement: Whole-brain statistical analysis of diffusion MRI measures in the presence of crossing fibres. NeuroImage. 2015;117:40&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4528070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26004503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raffelt D.A., Tournier J.-D., Smith R.E., Vaughan D.N., Jackson G., Ridgway G.R., Connelly A. Investigating white matter fibre density and morphology using fixel-based analysis. NeuroImage. 2017;144:58&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5182031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27639350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seo J., Jang S. Different characteristics of the corticospinal tract according to the cerebral origin: DTI study. Am. J. Neuroradiol. 2013;34:1359&#x2013;1363.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23370470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith M.C. Nerve fibre degeneration in the brain in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J. Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatry. 1960;23:269.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC497425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21610893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith R.E., Tournier J.-D., Calamante F., Connelly A. SIFT: Spherical-deconvolution informed filtering of tractograms. NeuroImage. 2013;67:298&#x2013;312.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23238430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tournier J.-D., Smith R., Raffelt D., Tabbara R., Dhollander T., Pietsch M., Christiaens D., Jeurissen B., Yeh C.-H., Connelly A. MRtrix3: A fast, flexible and open software framework for medical image processing and visualisation. NeuroImage. 2019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31473352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trojsi F., Caiazzo G., Di Nardo F., Fratello M., Santangelo G., Siciliano M., Femiano C., Russo A., Monsurr&#xf2; M.R., Cirillo M. High angular resolution diffusion imaging abnormalities in the early stages of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J. Neurol. Sci. 2017;380:215&#x2013;222.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28870572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trojsi F., Corbo D., Caiazzo G., Piccirillo G., Monsurr&#xf2; M.R., Cirillo S., Esposito F., Tedeschi G. Motor and extramotor neurodegeneration in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a 3T high angular resolution diffusion imaging (HARDI) study. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis and Frontotemporal Degeneration. 2013;14:553&#x2013;561.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23586325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner M.R., Agosta F., Bede P., Govind V., Lul&#xe9; D., Verstraete E. Neuroimaging in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Biomarkers Med. 2012;6:319&#x2013;337.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22731907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner M.R., Verstraete E. What does imaging reveal about the pathology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis? Current Neurol. Neurosci. Rep. 2015;15:45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4443002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26008817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tustison N.J., Avants B.B., Cook P.A., Zheng Y., Egan A., Yushkevich P.A., Gee J.C. N4ITK: improved N3 bias correction. IEEE Trans. Med. Imaging. 2010;29:1310&#x2013;1320.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3071855</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20378467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Knaap L.J., van der Ham I.J. How does the corpus callosum mediate interhemispheric transfer? A review. Behav. Brain Res. 2011;223:211&#x2013;221.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21530590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veraart J., Fieremans E., Novikov D.S. Diffusion MRI noise mapping using random matrix theory. Magn. Reson. Med. 2016;76:1582&#x2013;1593.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4879661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26599599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wahl M., Lauterbach-Soon B., Hattingen E., Jung P., Singer O., Volz S., Klein J.C., Steinmetz H., Ziemann U. Human motor corpus callosum: topography, somatotopy, and link between microstructure and function. J. Neurosci. 2007;27:12132&#x2013;12138.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6673264</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17989279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wakana S., Caprihan A., Panzenboeck M.M., Fallon J.H., Perry M., Gollub R.L., Hua K., Zhang J., Jiang H., Dubey P. Reproducibility of quantitative tractography methods applied to cerebral white matter. NeuroImage. 2007;36:630&#x2013;644.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2350213</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17481925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Welniarz Q., Dusart I., Roze E. The corticospinal tract: Evolution, development, and human disorders. Dev. Neurobiol. 2017;77:810&#x2013;829.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27706924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wittstock M., Meister S., Walter U., Benecke R., Wolters A. Mirror movements in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. 2011;12:393&#x2013;397.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21554031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J., Ji B., Hu J., Zhou C., Li L., Li Z., Huang X., Hu X. Aberrant interhemispheric homotopic functional and structural connectivity in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J. Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatry. 2017;88:369&#x2013;370.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27913627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>