<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">33404153</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>12</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1468-1331</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>28</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>May</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Structural and functional underpinnings of precentral abnormalities in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1528</StartPage><EndPage>1536</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1528-1536</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/ene.14717</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND PURPOSE">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) is a progressive neurodegenerative disorder characterized by the loss of both upper and lower motor neurons. Studies using various magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) analytical approaches have consistently identified significant precentral abnormalities in ALS, whereas their structural and functional underpinnings remain poorly understood.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Using cortical thickness, fractional anisotropy (FA), and effective connectivity, we performed a multimodal MRI study to examine the structural and functional alterations associated with precentral abnormalities in patients with ALS (n&#xa0;=&#xa0;60) compared with healthy controls (n&#xa0;=&#xa0;60).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Cortical thickness analysis revealed significant cortical thinning in the right precentral gyrus (PCG), superior frontal gyrus, and superior temporal gyrus in patients with ALS. Tractwise white matter microstructure analyses revealed decreased FA in the tracts connected to the PCG cluster in patients with ALS involving the right corticospinal tract and the middle posterior body of the corpus callosum. Additionally, the cortical thickness of the PCG cluster was found to be positively correlated with FA of the tracts connected to the PCG cluster, suggesting that these two structural features are tightly coupled. Using spectral dynamic causal modelling, effective connectivity analysis among the three regions with cortical thinning revealed decreased self-inhibitory influence in the PCG cluster in patients with ALS, which might be an endophenotypic manifestation of an imbalance in inhibitory and excitatory neurotransmitters in this region.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">The present data shed new light on the structural and functional underpinnings of precentral abnormalities in ALS.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 European Academy of Neurology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cheng</LastName><ForeName>Luqi</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory for Neuroinformation of the Ministry of Education, School of Life Science and Technology, University of Electronic Science and Technology of China, Chengdu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yuan</LastName><ForeName>Yumin</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Intelligent Technology and Engineering, Chongqing University of Science and Technology, Chongqing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tang</LastName><ForeName>Xie</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory for Neuroinformation of the Ministry of Education, School of Life Science and Technology, University of Electronic Science and Technology of China, Chengdu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Yuan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>CAS Key Laboratory of Behavioral Science, Institute of Psychology, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, University of Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Luo</LastName><ForeName>Chunxia</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, First Affiliated Hospital, Third Military Medical University, Chongqing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Daihong</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, Chongqing University Cancer Hospital, Chongqing Cancer Institute, and Chongqing Cancer Hospital, Chongqing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Yuanchao</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8191-4899</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory for Neuroinformation of the Ministry of Education, School of Life Science and Technology, University of Electronic Science and Technology of China, Chengdu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Jiuquan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, Chongqing University Cancer Hospital, Chongqing Cancer Institute, and Chongqing Cancer Hospital, Chongqing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9506311</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1351-5101</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003337" MajorTopicYN="N">Corpus Callosum</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007091" MajorTopicYN="N">Image Processing, Computer-Assisted</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008279" MajorTopicYN="N">Magnetic Resonance Imaging</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011712" MajorTopicYN="N">Pyramidal Tracts</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cortical thickness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">effective connectivity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">precentral gyrus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">spectral dynamic causal modelling</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>51</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33404153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ene.14717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Turner MR, Agosta F, Bede P, Govind V, Lul&#xe9; D, Verstraete E. Neuroimaging in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Biomark Med. 2012;6:319-337.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agosta F, Pagani E, Rocca M, et al. Voxel-based morphometry study of brain volumetry and diffusivity in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients with mild disability. Hum Brain Mapp. 2007;28:1430-1438.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devine MS, Pannek K, Coulthard A, McCombe PA, Rose SE, Henderson RD. Exposing asymmetric gray matter vulnerability in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuroimage Clin. 2015;7:782-787.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mezzapesa DM, D'Errico E, Tortelli R, et al. Cortical thinning and clinical heterogeneity in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. PLoS ONE. 2013;8:e80748.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walhout R, Westeneng H-J, Verstraete E, et al. Cortical thickness in ALS: towards a marker for upper motor neuron involvement. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2015;86:288-294.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld MA, Tempelmann C, Gaul C, et al. Functional motor compensation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol. 2005;252:944-952.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stoppel CM, Vielhaber S, Eckart C, et al. Structural and functional hallmarks of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis progression in motor-and memory-related brain regions. Neuroimage Clin. 2014;5:277-290.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou F, Xu R, Dowd E, Zang Y, Gong H, Wang Z. Alterations in regional functional coherence within the sensory-motor network in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurosci Lett. 2014;558:192-196.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou C, Hu X, Hu J, et al. Altered brain network in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a resting graph theory-based network study at voxel-wise level. Front Neurosci. 2016;10:204.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filippini N, Douaud G, Mackay C, Knight S, Talbot K, Turner M. Corpus callosum involvement is a consistent feature of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology. 2010;75:1645-1652.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Douaud G, Filippini N, Knight S, Talbot K, Turner MR. Integration of structural and functional magnetic resonance imaging in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain. 2011;134:3470-3479.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jelsone-Swain LM, Fling BW, Seidler RD, Hovatter R, Gruis K, Welsh RC. Reduced interhemispheric functional connectivity in the motor cortex during rest in limb-onset amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Front Syst Neurosci. 2010;4:158.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tedeschi G, Trojsi F, Tessitore A, et al. Interaction between aging and neurodegeneration in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurobiol Aging. 2012;33:886-898.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friston KJ, Harrison L, Penny W. Dynamic causal modelling. NeuroImage. 2003;19:1273-1302.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friston KJ, Litvak V, Oswal A, et al. Bayesian model reduction and empirical Bayes for group (DCM) studies. NeuroImage. 2016;128:413-431.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Qiu T, Yuan X, et al. Abnormal topological organization of structural covariance networks in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuroimage Clin. 2019;21:101619.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiu T, Zhang Y, Tang X, et al. Precentral degeneration and cerebellar compensation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a multimodal MRI analysis. Hum Brain Mapp. 2019;40:3464-3474.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum JM, Stambler N, Malta E, et al. The ALSFRS-R: a revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. J Neurol Sci. 1999;169:13-21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith SM. Fast robust automated brain extraction. Hum Brain Mapp. 2002;17:143-155.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Contarino VE, Conte G, Morelli C, et al. Toward a marker of upper motor neuron impairment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a fully automatic investigation of the magnetic susceptibility in the precentral cortex. Eur J Radiol. 2020;124:108815.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johns SL, Ishaque A, Khan M, Yang Y-H, Wilman AH, Kalra S. Quantifying changes on susceptibility weighted images in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis using MRI texture analysis. Amyotroph Lat Scl Fr. 2019;20:1-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saberi S, Stauffer JE, Schulte DJ, Ravits J. Neuropathology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and its variants. Neurol Clin. 2015;33:855-876.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riku Y, Atsuta N, Yoshida M, et al. Differential motor neuron involvement in progressive muscular atrophy: a comparative study with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. BMJ open. 2014;4.e005213</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gen&#xe7; B, Jara JH, Lagrimas AK, et al. Apical dendrite degeneration, a novel cellular pathology for Betz cells in ALS. Sci Rep. 2017;7:41765.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang J, Lomen-Hoerth C, Murphy J, et al. A voxel-based morphometry study of patterns of brain atrophy in ALS and ALS/FTLD. Neurology. 2005;65:75-80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agosta F, Valsasina P, Riva N, et al. The cortical signature of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. PLoS ONE. 2012;7:e42816.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Owen AM, Stern CE, Look RB, Tracey I, Rosen BR, Petrides M. Functional organization of spatial and nonspatial working memory processing within the human lateral frontal cortex. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 1998;95:7721-7726.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corbetta M, Patel G, Shulman GL. The reorienting system of the human brain: from environment to theory of mind. Neuron. 2008;58:306-324.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J&#xe4;ncke L, W&#xfc;stenberg T, Scheich H, Heinze H-J. Phonetic perception and the temporal cortex. NeuroImage. 2002;15:733-746.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoekert M, Bais L, Kahn RS, Aleman A. Time course of the involvement of the right anterior superior temporal gyrus and the right fronto-parietal operculum in emotional prosody perception. PLoS ONE. 2008;3:e2244.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abrahams S, Goldstein L, Simmons A, et al. Word retrieval in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a functional magnetic resonance imaging study. Brain. 2004;127:1507-1517.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phukan J, Pender NP, Hardiman O. Cognitive impairment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet Neurol. 2007;6:994-1003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benbrika S, Desgranges B, Eustache F, Viader F. Cognitive, emotional and psychological manifestations in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis at baseline and overtime: a review. Front Neurosci. 2019;13:951.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martins AP, Prado LdGR, Lillo P, Mioshi E, Teixeira AL, De Souza LC. Deficits in emotion recognition as markers of frontal behavioral dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neuropsychiatry Clin Neurosci. 2019;31:165-169.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seo J, Jang S. Different characteristics of the corticospinal tract according to the cerebral origin: DTI study. AJNR Am J Neuroradiol. 2013;34:1359-1363.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Standring S. Gray's anatomy: the anatomical basis of clinical practice, Elsevier Health Sciences; 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Welniarz Q, Dusart I, Roze E. The corticospinal tract: evolution, development, and human disorders. Dev Neurobiol. 2017;77:810-829.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wahl M, Lauterbach-Soon B, Hattingen E, et al. Human motor corpus callosum: topography, somatotopy, and link between microstructure and function. J Neurosci. 2007;27:12132-12138.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J, Ji B, Hu J, et al. Aberrant interhemispheric homotopic functional and structural connectivity in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2017;88:369-370.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon PH. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: an update for 2013 clinical features, pathophysiology, management and therapeutic trials. Aging Dis. 2013;4:295.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basser PJ. Focal magnetic stimulation of an axon. IEEE Trans Biomed Eng. 1994;41:601-606.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beaulieu C. The basis of anisotropic water diffusion in the nervous system-a technical review. NMR Biomed. 2002;15:435-455.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang SH, Li Y, Fukaya M, et al. Degeneration and impaired regeneration of gray matter oligodendrocytes in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat Neurosci. 2013;16:571-579.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferraiuolo L, Meyer K, Sherwood TW, et al. Oligodendrocytes contribute to motor neuron death in ALS via SOD1-dependent mechanism. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2016;113:E6496-E6505.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nihei K, McKee AC, Kowall NW. Patterns of neuronal degeneration in the motor cortex of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. Acta Neuropathol. 1993;86:55-64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lloyd C, Richardson M, Brooks D, Al-Chalabi A, Leigh P. Extramotor involvement in ALS: PET studies with the GABAA ligand [11C] flumazenil. Brain. 2000;123:2289-2296.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petri S, Krampfl K, Hashemi F, et al. Distribution of GABAA receptor mRNA in the motor cortex of ALS patients. J Neuropathol Exp Neurol. 2003;62:1041-1051.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S, Cheah BC, Kiernan MC. Defining the mechanisms that underlie cortical hyperexcitability in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Exp Neurol. 2009;220:177-182.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kew J, Leigh P, Playford E, et al. Cortical function in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a positron emission tomography study. Brain. 1993;116:655-680.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kollewe K, M&#xfc;nte TF, Samii A, Dengler R, Petri S, Mohammadi B. Patterns of cortical activity differ in ALS patients with limb and/or bulbar involvement depending on motor tasks. J Neurol. 2011;258:804-810.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams KL, Fifita JA, Vucic S, et al. Pathophysiological insights into ALS with C9ORF72 expansions. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2013;84:931-935.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bastos AM, Usrey WM, Adams RA, Mangun GR, Fries P, Friston KJ. Canonical microcircuits for predictive coding. Neuron. 2012;76:695-711.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petroff OA. Book review: GABA and glutamate in the human brain. Neuroscientist. 2002;8:562-573.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duncan NW, Wiebking C, Northoff G. Associations of regional GABA and glutamate with intrinsic and extrinsic neural activity in humans-a review of multimodal imaging studies. Neurosci Biobehav Rev. 2014;47:36-52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Limongi R, Jeon P, Mackinley M, et al. Glutamate and Dysconnection in the salience network: Neurochemical, effective-connectivity, and computational evidence in schizophrenia. Biol Psychiatry. 2020;88:273-281.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foerster B, Callaghan B, Petrou M, Edden RAE, Chenevert T, Feldman E. Decreased motor cortex &#x3b3;-aminobutyric acid in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology. 2012;78:1596-1600.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foerster BR, Pomper MG, Callaghan BC, et al. An imbalance between excitatory and inhibitory neurotransmitters in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis revealed by use of 3-T proton magnetic resonance spectroscopy. JAMA Neurol. 2013;70:1009-1016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bertel O, Malessa S, Sluga E, Hornykiewicz O. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: changes of noradrenergic and serotonergic transmitter systems in the spinal cord. Brain Res. 1991;566:54-60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner M, Rabiner E, Al-Chalabi A, et al. Cortical 5-HT1A receptor binding in patients with homozygous D90A SOD1 vs sporadic ALS. Neurology. 2007;68:1233-1235.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu X, Zhu W, Guo Z, et al. 18F-fallypride PET-CT of dopamine D2/D3 receptors in patients with sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Sci. 2017;377:79-84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vermeiren Y, Janssens J, Van Dam D, De Deyn PP. Serotonergic dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and Parkinson's disease: similar mechanisms, dissimilar outcomes. Front Neurosci. 2018;12:185.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kunisato Y, Okamoto Y, Okada G, et al. Modulation of default-mode network activity by acute tryptophan depletion is associated with mood change: a resting state functional magnetic resonance imaging study. Neurosci Res. 2011;69:129-134.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alavash M, Lim S-J, Thiel C, Sehm B, Deserno L, Obleser J. Dopaminergic modulation of hemodynamic signal variability and the functional connectome during cognitive performance. NeuroImage. 2018;172:341-356.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conio B, Martino M, Magioncalda P, et al. Opposite effects of dopamine and serotonin on resting-state networks: review and implications for psychiatric disorders. Mol Psychiatry. 2020;25:82-93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang LE, Fink GR, Diekhoff S, Rehme AK, Eickhoff SB, Grefkes C. Noradrenergic enhancement improves motor network connectivity in stroke patients. Ann Neurol. 2011;69:375-388.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rubenstein J, Merzenich MM. Model of autism: increased ratio of excitation/inhibition in key neural systems. Genes Brain Behav. 2003;2:255-267.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>