<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">33427296</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>01</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1460-2156</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>143</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Brain : a journal of neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Brain</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The microglial component of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>3526</StartPage><EndPage>3539</EndPage><MedlinePgn>3526-3539</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1093/brain/awaa309</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Microglia are the primary immune cells of the CNS, carrying out key homeostatic roles and undergoing context-dependent and temporally regulated changes in response to injury and neurodegenerative diseases. Microglia have been implicated in playing a role in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS), a neurodegenerative disease characterized by extensive motor neuron loss leading to paralysis and premature death. However, as the pathomechansims of ALS are increasingly recognized to involve a multitude of different cell types, it has been difficult to delineate the specific contribution of microglia to disease. Here, we review the literature of microglial involvement in ALS and discuss the evidence for the neurotoxic and neuroprotective pathways that have been attributed to microglia in this disease. We also discuss accumulating evidence for spatiotemporal regulation of microglial activation in this context. A deeper understanding of the role of microglia in the 'cellular phase' of ALS is crucial in the development of mechanistically rationalized therapies.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) (2020). Published by Oxford University Press on behalf of the Guarantors of Brain.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Clarke</LastName><ForeName>Benjamin E</ForeName><Initials>BE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuromuscular disease, Institute of Neurology, University College London, Queen Square, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Francis Crick Institute, 1 Midland Road, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Patani</LastName><ForeName>Rickie</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuromuscular disease, Institute of Neurology, University College London, Queen Square, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Francis Crick Institute, 1 Midland Road, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>FC0101 10</GrantID><Acronym>CRUK_</Acronym><Agency>Cancer Research UK</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>FC010110</GrantID><Acronym>WT_</Acronym><Agency>Wellcome Trust</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>FC010110</GrantID><Acronym>MRC_</Acronym><Agency>Medical Research Council</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>MR/S006591/1</GrantID><Acronym>MRC_</Acronym><Agency>Medical Research Council</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Brain</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0372537</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0006-8950</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="Y">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017628" MajorTopicYN="N">Microglia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="Y">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ALS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ageing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">astrocyte</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">microglia</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33427296</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7805793</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awaa309</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">6016135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ajami B, Samusik N, Wieghofer P, Ho PP, Crotti A, Bjornson Z, et al.Single-cell mass cytometry reveals distinct populations of brain myeloid cells in mouse neuroinflammation and neurodegeneration models. Nat Neurosci 2018; 21: 541&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29507414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ajmone-Cat MA, Onori A, Toselli C, Stronati E, Morlando M, Bozzoni I, et al.Increased FUS levels in astrocytes leads to astrocyte and microglia activation and neuronal death. Sci Rep 2019; 9: 4572.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6418113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30872738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Chalabi A, van den Berg LH, Veldink J.. Gene discovery in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: implications for clinical management. Nat Rev Neurol 2017; 13: 96&#x2013;104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27982040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alexianu ME, Kozovska M, Appel SH.. Immune reactivity in a mouse model of familial ALS correlates with disease progression. Neurology 2001; 57: 1282&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11591849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almer G, Vukosavic S, Romero N, Przedborski S.. Inducible nitric oxide synthase up-regulation in a transgenic mouse model of familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurochem 1999; 72: 2415&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10349851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alshikho MJ, Z&#xfc;rcher NR, Loggia ML, Cernasov P, Reynolds B, Pijanowski O, et al.Integrated magnetic resonance imaging. Ann Neurol 2018; 83: 1186&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6105567</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29740862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Apolloni S, Amadio S, Montilli C, Volont&#xe9; C, D'Ambrosi N.. Ablation of P2X7 receptor exacerbates gliosis and motoneuron death in the SOD1-G93A mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Hum Mol Genet 2013; 22: 4102&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23736299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Apolloni S, Amadio S, Parisi C, Matteucci A, Potenza RL, Armida M, et al.Spinal cord pathology is ameliorated by P2X7 antagonism in a SOD1-mutant mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Dis Model Mech 2014; 7: 1101&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4142730</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25038061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balendra R, Isaacs AM.. C9orf72-mediated ALS and FTD: multiple pathways to disease. Nat Rev Neurol 2018; 14: 544&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6417666</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30120348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beers DR, Appel SH.. Immune dysregulation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: mechanisms and emerging therapies. Lancet Neurol 2019; 18: 211&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30663610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beers DR, Henkel JS, Xiao Q, Zhao W, Wang J, Yen AA, et al.Wild-type microglia extend survival in PU.1 knockout mice with familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA 2006; 103: 16021&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1613228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17043238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beers DR, Henkel JS, Zhao W, Wang J, Appel SH.. CD4+ T cells support glial neuroprotection, slow disease progression, and modify glial morphology in an animal model of inherited ALS. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA 2008; 105: 15558&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2547419</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18809917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beers DR, Henkel JS, Zhao W, Wang J, Huang A, Wen S, et al.Endogenous regulatory T lymphocytes ameliorate amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in mice and correlate with disease progression in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain 2011. a; 134: 1293&#x2013;314.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3097891</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21596768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beers DR, Zhao W, Liao B, Kano O, Wang J, Huang A, et al.Neuroinflammation modulates distinct regional and temporal clinical responses in ALS mice. Brain Behav Immun 2011. b; 25: 1025&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3096756</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21176785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bennett FC, Bennett ML, Yaqoob F, Mulinyawe SB, Grant GA, Hayden Gephart M, et al.A Combination of ontogeny and CNS environment establishes microglial identity. Neuron 2018; 98: 1170&#x2013;83.e8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6023731</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29861285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boillee S, Yamanaka K, Lobsiger CS, Copeland NG, Jenkins NA, Kassiotis G, et al.Onset and progression in inherited ALS determined by motor neurons and microglia. Science 2006; 312: 1389&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16741123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brettschneider J, Toledo JB, Van Deerlin VM, Elman L, McCluskey L, Lee VM, et al.Microglial activation correlates with disease progression and upper motor neuron clinical symptoms in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. PLoS One 2012; 7: e39216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3375234</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22720079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bussian TJ, Aziz A, Meyer CF, Swenson BL, van Deursen JM, Baker DJ.. Clearance of senescent glial cells prevents tau-dependent pathology and cognitive decline. Nature 2018; 562: 578&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6206507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30232451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xf6;ttcher C, Schlickeiser S, Sneeboer MAM, Kunkel D, Knop A, Paza E, et al.Human microglia regional heterogeneity and phenotypes determined by multiplexed single-cell mass cytometry. Nat Neurosci 2019; 22: 78&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30559476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cady J, Koval ED, Benitez BA, Zaidman C, Jockel-Balsarotti J, Allred P, et al.TREM2 variant p.R47H as a risk factor for sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. JAMA Neurol 2014; 71: 449&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4087113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24535663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calabrese V, Mancuso C, Calvani M, Rizzarelli E, Butterfield DA, Stella AM.. Nitric oxide in the central nervous system: neuroprotection versus neurotoxicity. Nat Rev Neurosci 2007; 8: 766&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17882254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardona AE, Pioro EP, Sasse ME, Kostenko V, Cardona SM, Dijkstra IM, et al.Control of microglial neurotoxicity by the fractalkine receptor. Nat Neurosci 2006; 9: 917&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16732273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casula M, Iyer AM, Spliet WG, Anink JJ, Steentjes K, Sta M, et al.Toll-like receptor signaling in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis spinal cord tissue. Neuroscience 2011; 179: 233&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21303685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chabas D, Baranzini SE, Mitchell D, Bernard CC, Rittling SR, Denhardt DT, et al.The influence of the proinflammatory cytokine, osteopontin, on autoimmune demyelinating disease. Science 2001; 294: 1731&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11721059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen K, Northington FJ, Martin LJ.. Inducible nitric oxide synthase is present in motor neuron mitochondria and Schwann cells and contributes to disease mechanisms in ALS mice. Brain Struct Funct 2010; 214: 219&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3010349</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19888600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiu IM, Chen A, Zheng Y, Kosaras B, Tsiftsoglou SA, Vartanian TK, et al.T lymphocytes potentiate endogenous neuroprotective inflammation in a mouse model of ALS. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA 2008; 105: 17913&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2581614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18997009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiu IM, Morimoto ET, Goodarzi H, Liao JT, O'Keeffe S, Phatnani HP, et al.A neurodegeneration-specific gene-expression signature of acutely isolated microglia from an amyotrophic lateral sclerosis mouse model. Cell Rep 2013; 4: 385&#x2013;401.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4272581</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23850290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cie&#x15b;lak M, Roszek K, Wujak M.. Purinergic implication in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-from pathological mechanisms to therapeutic perspectives. Purinergic Signal 2019; 15: 1&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6439052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30430356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clarke BE, Gil RS, Yip J, Kalmar B, Greensmith L.. Regional differences in the inflammatory and heat shock response in glia: implications for ALS. Cell Stress Chaperones 2019; 24: 857&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6717175</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31168740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clarke LE, Liddelow SA, Chakraborty C, M&#xfc;nch AE, Heiman M, Barres BA.. Normal aging induces A1-like astrocyte reactivity. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA 2018; 115: E1896&#x2013;E905.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5828643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29437957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clement AM, Nguyen MD, Roberts EA, Garcia ML, Boill&#xe9;e S, Rule M, et al.Wild-type nonneuronal cells extend survival of SOD1 mutant motor neurons in ALS mice. Science 2003; 302: 113&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14526083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coque E, Salsac C, Espinosa-Carrasco G, Varga B, Degauque N, Cadoux M, et al.Cytotoxic CD8 T lymphocytes expressing ALS-causing mutant SOD1 selectively. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA 2019; 116: 2312&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6369778</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30674678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corcia P, Tauber C, Vercoullie J, Arlicot N, Prunier C, Praline J, et al.Molecular imaging of microglial activation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. PLoS One 2012; 7: e52941.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3534121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23300829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crisafulli SG, Brajkovic S, Cipolat Mis MS, Parente V, Corti S.. Therapeutic strategies under development targeting inflammatory mechanisms in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Mol Neurobiol 2018; 55: 2789&#x2013;813.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28455693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D'Ambrosi N, Finocchi P, Apolloni S, Cozzolino M, Ferri A, Padovano V, et al.The proinflammatory action of microglial P2 receptors is enhanced in SOD1 models for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Immunol 2009; 183: 4648&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19734218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D'Erchia AM, Gallo A, Manzari C, Raho S, Horner DS, Chiara M, et al.Massive transcriptome sequencing of human spinal cord tissues provides new insights into motor neuron degeneration in ALS. Sci Rep 2017; 7: 10046.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5577269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28855684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davalos D, Grutzendler J, Yang G, Kim JV, Zuo Y, Jung S, et al.ATP mediates rapid microglial response to local brain injury in vivo. Nat Neurosci 2005; 8: 752&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15895084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeJesus-Hernandez M, Mackenzie IR, Boeve BF, Boxer AL, Baker M, Rutherford NJ, et al.Expanded GGGGCC hexanucleotide repeat in noncoding region of C9ORF72 causes chromosome 9p-linked FTD and ALS. Neuron 2011; 72: 245&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3202986</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21944778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dodge JC, Haidet AM, Yang W, Passini MA, Hester M, Clarke J, et al.Delivery of AAV-IGF-1 to the CNS extends survival in ALS mice through modification of aberrant glial cell activity. Mol Ther 2008; 16: 1056&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2737251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18388910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dols-Icardo O, Montal V, Sirisi S, L&#xf3;pez-Pernas G, Cervera-Carles L, Querol-Vilaseca M, et al.Motor cortex transcriptome reveals microglial key events in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurol Neuroimmunol Neuroinflamm 2020; 7: e829.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7371375</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32669313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Endo F, Komine O, Fujimori-Tonou N, Katsuno M, Jin S, Watanabe S, et al.Astrocyte-derived TGF-&#x3b2;1 accelerates disease progression in ALS mice by interfering with the neuroprotective functions of microglia and T cells. Cell Rep 2015; 11: 592&#x2013;604.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25892237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Engelhardt JI, Tajti J, Appel SH.. Lymphocytic infiltrates in the spinal cord in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Arch Neurol 1993; 50: 30&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8093428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frakes AE, Ferraiuolo L, Haidet-Phillips AM, Schmelzer L, Braun L, Miranda CJ, et al.Microglia induce motor neuron death via the classical NF-&#x3ba;B pathway in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuron 2014; 81: 1009&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3978641</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24607225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Funikov SY, Rezvykh AP, Mazin PV, Morozov AV, Maltsev AV, Chicheva MM, et al.FUS(1-359) transgenic mice as a model of ALS: pathophysiological and molecular aspects of the proteinopathy. Neurogenetics 2018; 19: 189&#x2013;204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29982879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galatro TF, Holtman IR, Lerario AM, Vainchtein ID, Brouwer N, Sola PR, et al.Transcriptomic analysis of purified human cortical microglia reveals age-associated changes. Nat Neurosci 2017; 20: 1162&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28671693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garofalo S, Cocozza G, Porzia A, Inghilleri M, Raspa M, Scavizzi F, et al.Natural killer cells modulate motor neuron-immune cell cross talk in models of Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. Nat Commun 2020; 11: 1773.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7156729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32286313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerber YN, Sabourin JC, Rabano M, Vivanco M, Perrin FE.. Early functional deficit and microglial disturbances in a mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. PLoS One 2012; 7: e36000.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3338492</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22558300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ginhoux F, Greter M, Leboeuf M, Nandi S, See P, Gokhan S, et al.Fate mapping analysis reveals that adult microglia derive from primitive macrophages. Science 2010; 330: 841&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3719181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20966214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gowing G, Dequen F, Soucy G, Julien JP.. Absence of tumor necrosis factor-alpha does not affect motor neuron disease caused by superoxide dismutase 1 mutations. J Neurosci 2006; 26: 11397&#x2013;402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6674545</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17079668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gowing G, Lalancette-H&#xe9;bert M, Audet JN, Dequen F, Julien JP.. Macrophage colony stimulating factor (M-CSF) exacerbates ALS disease in a mouse model through altered responses of microglia expressing mutant superoxide dismutase. Exp Neurol 2009; 220: 267&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19733170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gowing G, Philips T, Van Wijmeersch B, Audet JN, Dewil M, Van Den Bosch L, et al.Ablation of proliferating microglia does not affect motor neuron degeneration in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis caused by mutant superoxide dismutase. J Neurosci 2008; 28: 10234&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6671032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18842883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grabert K, Michoel T, Karavolos MH, Clohisey S, Baillie JK, Stevens MP, et al.Microglial brain region-dependent diversity and selective regional sensitivities to aging. Nat Neurosci 2016; 19: 504&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4768346</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26780511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grassivaro F, Menon R, Acquaviva M, Ottoboni L, Ruffini F, Bergamaschi A, et al.Convergence between microglia and peripheral macrophages phenotype during development and neuroinflammation. J Neurosci 2020; 40: 784&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6975289</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31818979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gravel M, B&#xe9;land LC, Soucy G, Abdelhamid E, Rahimian R, Gravel C, et al.IL-10 controls early microglial phenotypes and disease onset in ALS caused by misfolded superoxide dismutase 1. J Neurosci 2016; 36: 1031&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6601999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26791230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta PK, Prabhakar S, Abburi C, Sharma NK, Anand A.. Vascular endothelial growth factor-A and chemokine ligand (CCL2) genes are upregulated in peripheral blood mononuclear cells in Indian amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. J Neuroinflammation 2011; 8: 114.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3177897</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21906274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gurney ME, Pu H, Chiu AY, Dal Canto MC, Polchow CY, Alexander DD, et al.Motor neuron degeneration in mice that express a human Cu, Zn superoxide dismutase mutation. Science 1994; 264: 1772&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8209258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hall BM, Balan V, Gleiberman AS, Strom E, Krasnov P, Virtuoso LP, et al.p16(Ink4a) and senescence-associated &#x3b2;-galactosidase can be induced in macrophages as part of a reversible response to physiological stimuli. Aging (Albany NY) 2017; 9: 1867&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5611982</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28768895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hammond TR, Dufort C, Dissing-Olesen L, Giera S, Young A, Wysoker A, et al.Single-cell RNA sequencing of microglia throughout the mouse lifespan and in the injured brain reveals complex cell-state changes. Immunity 2019; 50: 253&#x2013;71.e6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6655561</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30471926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harraz MM, Marden JJ, Zhou W, Zhang Y, Williams A, Sharov VS, et al.SOD1 mutations disrupt redox-sensitive RAC regulation of NADPH oxidase in a familial ALS model. J Clin Invest 2008; 118: 659&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2213375</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18219391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haruwaka K, Ikegami A, Tachibana Y, Ohno N, Konishi H, Hashimoto A, et al.Dual microglia effects on blood brain barrier permeability induced by systemic inflammation. Nat Commun 2019; 10: 5816.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6925219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31862977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hashimoto M, Sun D, Rittling SR, Denhardt DT, Young W.. Osteopontin-deficient mice exhibit less inflammation, greater tissue damage, and impaired locomotor recovery from spinal cord injury compared with wild-type controls. J Neurosci 2007; 27: 3603&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6672107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17392476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henkel JS, Engelhardt JI, Sikl&#xf3;s L, Simpson EP, Kim SH, Pan T, et al.Presence of dendritic cells, MCP-1, and activated microglia/macrophages in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis spinal cord tissue. Ann Neurol 2004; 55: 221&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14755726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hensley K, Fedynyshyn J, Ferrell S, Floyd RA, Gordon B, Grammas P, et al.Message and protein-level elevation of tumor necrosis factor alpha (TNF alpha) and TNF alpha-modulating cytokines in spinal cords of the G93A-SOD1 mouse model for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurobiol Dis 2003; 14: 74&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13678668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeyachandran A, Mertens B, McKissick EA, Mitchell CS.. Type I Vs. type II cytokine levels as a function of SOD1 G93A mouse amyotrophic lateral sclerosis disease progression. Front Cell Neurosci 2015; 9: 462.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4664727</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26648846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jha MK, Jo M, Kim JH, Suk K.. Microglia-astrocyte crosstalk: an intimate molecular conversation. Neuroscientist 2019; 25: 227&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29931997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang SH, Li Y, Fukaya M, Lorenzini I, Cleveland DW, Ostrow LW, et al.Degeneration and impaired regeneration of gray matter oligodendrocytes in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat Neurosci 2013; 16: 571&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3637847</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23542689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaspar BK, Llad&#xf3; J, Sherkat N, Rothstein JD, Gage FH.. Retrograde viral delivery of IGF-1 prolongs survival in a mouse ALS model. Science 2003; 301: 839&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12907804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawamata T, Akiyama H, Yamada T, McGeer PL.. Immunologic reactions in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis brain and spinal cord tissue. Am J Pathol 1992; 140: 691&#x2013;707.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1886170</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1347673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwiatkowski TJ, Bosco DA, Leclerc AL, Tamrazian E, Vanderburg CR, Russ C, et al.Mutations in the FUS/TLS gene on chromosome 16 cause familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Science 2009; 323: 1205&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19251627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee JY, Lee JD, Phipps S, Noakes PG, Woodruff TM.. Absence of toll-like receptor 4 (TLR4) extends survival in the hSOD1 G93A mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neuroinflammation 2015; 12: 90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4431460</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25962427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lepore AC, Rauck B, Dejea C, Pardo AC, Rao MS, Rothstein JD, et al.Focal transplantation-based astrocyte replacement is neuroprotective in a model of motor neuron disease. Nat Neurosci 2008; 11: 1294&#x2013;301.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2656686</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18931666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lerman BJ, Hoffman EP, Sutherland ML, Bouri K, Hsu DK, Liu FT, et al.Deletion of galectin-3 exacerbates microglial activation and accelerates disease progression and demise in a SOD1(G93A) mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain Behav 2012; 2: 563&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3489809</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23139902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Q, Barres BA.. Microglia and macrophages in brain homeostasis and disease. Nat Rev Immunol 2018; 18: 225&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29151590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Q, Cheng Z, Zhou L, Darmanis S, Neff NF, Okamoto J, et al.Developmental heterogeneity of microglia and brain myeloid cells revealed by deep single-cell RNA sequencing. Neuron 2019; 101: 207&#x2013;23.e10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6336504</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30606613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao B, Zhao W, Beers DR, Henkel JS, Appel SH.. Transformation from a neuroprotective to a neurotoxic microglial phenotype in a mouse model of ALS. Exp Neurol 2012; 237: 147&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4126417</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22735487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liddelow SA, Guttenplan KA, Clarke LE, Bennett FC, Bohlen CJ, Schirmer L, et al.Neurotoxic reactive astrocytes are induced by activated microglia. Nature 2017; 541: 481&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5404890</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28099414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J, Allender E, Wang J, Simpson EH, Loeb JA, Song F.. Slowing disease progression in the SOD1 mouse model of ALS by blocking neuregulin-induced microglial activation. Neurobiol Dis 2018; 111: 118&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29278738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y, Hao W, Dawson A, Liu S, Fassbender K.. Expression of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-linked SOD1 mutant increases the neurotoxic potential of microglia via TLR2. J Biol Chem 2009; 284: 3691&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19091752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lombardi M, Parolisi R, Scaroni F, Bonfanti E, Gualerzi A, Gabrielli M, et al.Detrimental and protective action of microglial extracellular vesicles on myelin lesions: astrocyte involvement in remyelination failure. Acta Neuropathol 2019; 138: 987&#x2013;1012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6851224</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31363836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu CH, Allen K, Oei F, Leoni E, Kuhle J, Tree T, et al.Systemic inflammatory response and neuromuscular involvement in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurol Neuroimmunol Neuroinflamm 2016; 3: e244.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4897985</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27308305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maniatis S, &#xc4;ij&#xf6; T, Vickovic S, Braine C, Kang K, Mollbrink A, et al.Spatiotemporal dynamics of molecular pathology in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Science 2019; 364: 89&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30948552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marden JJ, Harraz MM, Williams AJ, Nelson K, Luo M, Paulson H, et al.Redox modifier genes in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in mice. J Clin Invest 2007; 117: 2913&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1974865</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17853944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marrali G, Casale F, Salamone P, Fuda G, Caorsi C, Amoroso A, et al.NADPH oxidase (NOX2) activity is a modifier of survival in ALS. J Neurol 2014; 261: 2178&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25178511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin LJ, Liu Z, Chen K, Price AC, Pan Y, Swaby JA, et al.Motor neuron degeneration in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis mutant superoxide dismutase-1 transgenic mice: mechanisms of mitochondriopathy and cell death. J Comp Neurol 2007; 500: 20&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17099894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;nez-Muriana A, Mancuso R, Francos-Quijorna I, Olmos-Alonso A, Osta R, Perry VH, et al.CSF1R blockade slows the progression of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis by reducing microgliosis and invasion of macrophages into peripheral nerves. Sci Rep 2016; 6: 25663.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4865981</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27174644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathys H, Adaikkan C, Gao F, Young JZ, Manet E, Hemberg M, et al.Temporal tracking of microglia activation in neurodegeneration at single-cell resolution. Cell Rep 2017; 21: 366&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5642107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29020624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meissner F, Molawi K, Zychlinsky A.. Mutant superoxide dismutase 1-induced IL-1beta accelerates ALS pathogenesis. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA 2010; 107: 13046&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2919927</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20616033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mesci P, Za&#xef;di S, Lobsiger CS, Millecamps S, Escartin C, Seilhean D, et al.System xC- is a mediator of microglial function and its deletion slows symptoms in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis mice. Brain 2015; 138: 53&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4441079</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25384799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miron VE, Boyd A, Zhao JW, Yuen TJ, Ruckh JM, Shadrach JL, et al.M2 microglia and macrophages drive oligodendrocyte differentiation during CNS remyelination. Nat Neurosci 2013; 16: 1211&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3977045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23872599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell JC, McGoldrick P, Vance C, Hortobagyi T, Sreedharan J, Rogelj B, et al.Overexpression of human wild-type FUS causes progressive motor neuron degeneration in an age- and dose-dependent fashion. Acta Neuropathol 2013; 125: 273&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3549237</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22961620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreno-Martinez L, Calvo AC, Mu&#xf1;oz MJ, Osta R.. Are circulating cytokines reliable biomarkers for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis? Int J Mol Sci 2019. a; 20: 2759.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6600567</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31195629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreno-Martinez L, de la Torre M, Toivonen JM, Zaragoza P, Garc&#xed;a-Redondo A, Calvo AC, et al.Circulating cytokines could not be good prognostic biomarkers in a mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Front Immunol 2019. b 10: 801.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6473074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31031774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mu&#xf1;oz-Esp&#xed;n D, Serrano M.. Cellular senescence: from physiology to pathology. Nat Rev Mol Cell Biol 2014; 15: 482&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24954210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagai M, Re DB, Nagata T, Chalazonitis A, Jessell TM, Wichterle H, et al.Astrocytes expressing ALS-linked mutated SOD1 release factors selectively toxic to motor neurons. Nat Neurosci 2007; 10: 615&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3799799</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17435755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neumann M, Sampathu DM, Kwong LK, Truax AC, Micsenyi MC, Chou TT, et al.Ubiquitinated TDP-43 in frontotemporal lobar degeneration and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Science 2006; 314: 130&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17023659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen MD, Julien JP, Rivest S.. Induction of proinflammatory molecules in mice with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: no requirement for proapoptotic interleukin-1beta in neurodegeneration. Ann Neurol 2001; 50: 630&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11706969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niedermeyer S, Murn M, Choi PJ.. Respiratory failure in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Chest 2019; 155: 401&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29990478</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nikodemova M, Small AL, Smith SM, Mitchell GS, Watters JJ.. Spinal but not cortical microglia acquire an atypical phenotype with high VEGF, galectin-3 and osteopontin, and blunted inflammatory responses in ALS rats. Neurobiol Dis 2014; 69: 43&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4079765</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24269728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nimmerjahn A, Kirchhoff F, Helmchen F.. Resting microglial cells are highly dynamic surveillants of brain parenchyma in vivo. Science 2005; 308: 1314&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15831717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Rourke JG, Bogdanik L, Y&#xe1;&#xf1;ez A, Lall D, Wolf AJ, Muhammad AK, et al.C9orf72 is required for proper macrophage and microglial function in mice. Science 2016; 351: 1324&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5120541</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26989253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan J, Ma N, Yu B, Zhang W, Wan J.. Transcriptomic profiling of microglia and astrocytes throughout aging. J Neuroinflammation 2020; 17: 97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7115095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32238175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pandya VA, Patani R.. Decoding the relationship between ageing and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a cellular perspective. Brain 2019; 143: 1057&#x2013;1072.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7174045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31851317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paolicelli RC, Jawaid A, Henstridge CM, Valeri A, Merlini M, Robinson JL, et al.TDP-43 Depletion in microglia promotes amyloid clearance but also induces synapse loss. Neuron 2017; 95: 297&#x2013;308.e6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5519492</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28669544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papadeas ST, Kraig SE, O'Banion C, Lepore AC, Maragakis NJ.. Astrocytes carrying the superoxide dismutase 1 (SOD1G93A) mutation induce wild-type motor neuron degeneration in vivo. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA 2011; 108: 17803&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3203804</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21969586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parisi C, Napoli G, Amadio S, Spalloni A, Apolloni S, Longone P, et al.MicroRNA-125b regulates microglia activation and motor neuron death in ALS. Cell Death Differ 2016; 23: 531&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5072447</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26794445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Philips T, Rothstein JD.. Glial cells in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Exp Neurol 2014; 262: 111&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4241182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24859452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pollari E, Savchenko E, Jaronen M, Kanninen K, Malm T, Wojciechowski S, et al.Granulocyte colony stimulating factor attenuates inflammation in a mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neuroinflammation 2011; 8: 74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3146845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21711557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poloni M, Facchetti D, Mai R, Micheli A, Agnoletti L, Francolini G, et al.Circulating levels of tumour necrosis factor-alpha and its soluble receptors are increased in the blood of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurosci Lett 2000; 287: 211&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10863032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pramatarova A, Lagani&#xe8;re J, Roussel J, Brisebois K, Rouleau GA.. Neuron-specific expression of mutant superoxide dismutase 1 in transgenic mice does not lead to motor impairment. J Neurosci 2001; 21: 3369&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6762496</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11331366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ransohoff RM. A polarizing question: do M1 and M2 microglia exist? Nat Neurosci 2016; 19: 987&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27459405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renton AE, Majounie E, Waite A, Sim&#xf3;n-S&#xe1;nchez J, Rollinson S, Gibbs JR, et al.A hexanucleotide repeat expansion in C9ORF72 is the cause of chromosome 9p21-linked ALS-FTD. Neuron 2011; 72: 257&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3200438</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21944779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts K, Zeineddine R, Corcoran L, Li W, Campbell IL, Yerbury JJ.. Extracellular aggregated Cu/Zn superoxide dismutase activates microglia to give a cytotoxic phenotype. Glia 2013; 61: 409&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23281114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosen DR. Mutations in Cu/Zn superoxide dismutase gene are associated with familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nature 1993; 364: 362.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8332197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossi C, Cusimano M, Zambito M, Finardi A, Capotondo A, Garcia-Manteiga JM, et al.Interleukin 4 modulates microglia homeostasis and attenuates the early slowly progressive phase of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Cell Death Dis 2018; 9: 250.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5833860</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29445154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schafer DP, Lehrman EK, Stevens B.. The &#x201c;quad-partite&#x201d; synapse: microglia-synapse interactions in the developing and mature CNS. Glia 2013; 61: 24&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4082974</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22829357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwartz N, Stock AD, Putterman C.. Neuropsychiatric lupus: new mechanistic insights and future treatment directions. Nat Rev Rheumatol 2019; 15: 137&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30659245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seredenina T, Nayernia Z, Sorce S, Maghzal GJ, Filippova A, Ling SC, et al.Evaluation of NADPH oxidases as drug targets in a mouse model of familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Free Radic Biol Med 2016; 97: 95&#x2013;108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27212019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serio A, Patani R.. Concise review: the cellular conspiracy of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Stem Cells 2018; 36: 293&#x2013;303.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29235200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soreq L, Rose J, Soreq E, Hardy J, Trabzuni D, Cookson MR, et al.Major shifts in glial regional identity are a transcriptional hallmark of human brain aging. Cell Rep 2017; 18: 557&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5263238</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28076797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spiller KJ, Restrepo CR, Khan T, Dominique MA, Fang TC, Canter RG, et al.Microglia-mediated recovery from ALS-relevant motor neuron degeneration in a mouse model of TDP-43 proteinopathy. Nat Neurosci 2018; 21: 329&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5857237</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29463850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun S, Sun Y, Ling SC, Ferraiuolo L, McAlonis-Downes M, Zou Y, et al.Translational profiling identifies a cascade of damage initiated in motor neurons and spreading to glia in mutant SOD1-mediated ALS. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA 2015; 112: E6993&#x2013;7002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4687558</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26621731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swarup V, Phaneuf D, Bareil C, Robertson J, Rouleau GA, Kriz J, et al.Pathological hallmarks of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis/frontotemporal lobar degeneration in transgenic mice produced with TDP-43 genomic fragments. Brain 2011. a; 134: 2610&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21752789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swarup V, Phaneuf D, Dupr&#xe9; N, Petri S, Strong M, Kriz J, et al.Deregulation of TDP-43 in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis triggers nuclear factor &#x3ba;B-mediated pathogenic pathways. J Exp Med 2011. b; 208: 2429&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3256969</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22084410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szalay G, Martinecz B, L&#xe9;n&#xe1;rt N, K&#xf6;rnyei Z, Orsolits B, Jud&#xe1;k L, et al.Microglia protect against brain injury and their selective elimination dysregulates neuronal network activity after stroke. Nat Commun 2016; 7: 11499.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4857403</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27139776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tada S, Okuno T, Yasui T, Nakatsuji Y, Sugimoto T, Kikutani H, et al.Deleterious effects of lymphocytes at the early stage of neurodegeneration in an animal model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neuroinflammation 2011; 8: 19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3048550</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21345177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tam OH, Rozhkov NV, Shaw R, Kim D, Hubbard I, Fennessey S, et al.Postmortem cortex samples identify distinct molecular subtypes of ALS: retrotransposon activation, oxidative stress, and activated glia. Cell Rep 2019; 29: 1164&#x2013;77.e5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6866666</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31665631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tateishi T, Yamasaki R, Tanaka M, Matsushita T, Kikuchi H, Isobe N, et al.CSF chemokine alterations related to the clinical course of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neuroimmunol 2010; 222: 76&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20381883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thonhoff JR, Simpson EP, Appel SH.. Neuroinflammatory mechanisms in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis pathogenesis. Curr Opin Neurol 2018; 31: 635&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30048339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trias E, Beilby PR, Kovacs M, Ibarburu S, Varela V, Barreto-N&#xfa;&#xf1;ez R, et al.Emergence of microglia bearing senescence markers during paralysis progression in a rat model of inherited ALS. Front Aging Neurosci 2019; 11:42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6403180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30873018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trias E, D&#xed;az-Amarilla P, Olivera-Bravo S, Isasi E, Drechsel DA, Lopez N, et al.Phenotypic transition of microglia into astrocyte-like cells associated with disease onset in a model of inherited ALS. Front Cell Neurosci 2013; 7: 274.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3871969</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24399933</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner MR, Cagnin A, Turkheimer FE, Miller CC, Shaw CE, Brooks DJ, et al.Evidence of widespread cerebral microglial activation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: an [11C](R)-PK11195 positron emission tomography study. Neurobiol Dis 2004; 15: 601&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15056468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tyzack GE, Luisier R, Taha DM, Neeves J, Modic M, Mitchell JS, et al.Widespread FUS mislocalization is a molecular hallmark of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain 2019; 142: 2572&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6735815</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31368485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vance C, Rogelj B, Hortob&#xe1;gyi T, De Vos KJ, Nishimura AL, Sreedharan J, et al.Mutations in FUS, an RNA processing protein, cause familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis type 6. Science 2009; 323: 1208&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4516382</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19251628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vasile F, Dossi E, Rouach N.. Human astrocytes: structure and functions in the healthy brain. Brain Struct Funct 2017; 222: 2017&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5504258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28280934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Duan W, Wang W, Di Wen Liu Y, Li Z, et al.scAAV9-VEGF prolongs the survival of transgenic ALS mice by promoting activation of M2 microglia and the PI3K/Akt pathway. Brain Res 2016; 1648: 1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27392886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu DC, R&#xe9; DB, Nagai M, Ischiropoulos H, Przedborski S.. The inflammatory NADPH oxidase enzyme modulates motor neuron degeneration in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis mice. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA 2006; 103: 12132&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1562547</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16877542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao Q, Zhao W, Beers DR, Yen AA, Xie W, Henkel JS, et al.Mutant SOD1(G93A) microglia are more neurotoxic relative to wild-type microglia. J Neurochem 2007; 102: 2008&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17555556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamanaka K, Chun SJ, Boillee S, Fujimori-Tonou N, Yamashita H, Gutmann DH, et al.Astrocytes as determinants of disease progression in inherited amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat Neurosci 2008; 11: 251&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3137510</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18246065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao W, Beers DR, Bell S, Wang J, Wen S, Baloh RH, et al.TDP-43 activates microglia through NF-&#x3ba;B and NLRP3 inflammasome. Exp Neurol 2015; 273: 24&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26222336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao W, Beers DR, Henkel JS, Zhang W, Urushitani M, Julien JP, et al.Extracellular mutant SOD1 induces microglial-mediated motoneuron injury. Glia 2010; 58: 231&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2784168</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19672969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao W, Xie W, Le W, Beers DR, He Y, Henkel JS, et al.Activated microglia initiate motor neuron injury by a nitric oxide and glutamate-mediated mechanism. J Neuropathol Exp Neurol 2004; 63: 964&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15453095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Q, Mareljic N, Michaelsen M, Parhizkar S, Heindl S, Nuscher B, et al.Active poly-GA vaccination prevents microglia activation and motor deficits in a C9orf72 mouse model. EMBO Mol Med 2020; 12: e10919.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7005532</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31858749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu Q, Jiang J, Gendron TF, McAlonis-Downes M, Jiang L, Taylor A, et al.Reduced C9ORF72 function exacerbates gain of toxicity from ALS/FTD-causing repeat expansion in C9orf72. Nat Neurosci 2020: 23; 615&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7384305</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32284607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>