<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">33433755</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>17</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1590-3478</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>42</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Neurological sciences : official journal of the Italian Neurological Society and of the Italian Society of Clinical Neurophysiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Neurol Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Preclinical studies of mesenchymal stem cells transplantation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a systemic review and metaanalysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>3637</StartPage><EndPage>3646</EndPage><MedlinePgn>3637-3646</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s10072-020-05036-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To assess the quality of preclinical evidence for mesenchymal stromal cell (MSCs) therapy of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS), decide the effect size of MSCs treatment, and identify clinical parameters that associate with differences in MSCs effects.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A literature search identified studies of MSCs in animal models of ALS. Four main indicators (age of onset, disease progression deceleration, survival time, hazard ratio reduction) obtained through specific neurobehavioral assessment, and 14 relative clinical parameters were extracted for metaanalysis and systematic review. Subgroup analysis and metaregression were performed to explore sources of heterogeneity.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 25 studies and 41 independent treated arms were used for systematic review and metaanalysis. After adjusted by sensitivity analysis, the mean effect sizes were significantly improved by 0.28 for the age of onset, 0.25 for the disease progression deceleration, 0.54 for the survival time, and 0.48 for hazard ratio reduction. With further analysis, we demonstrated that both the clinical parameter of animal gender and immunosuppressive drug of cyclosporin A (CSA) had a close correlation with disease progression deceleration effect size.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">These results showed that MSCs transplantation was beneficial for neurobehavioral improvement in the treatment of ALS animal model and recommended that all potential reparative roles of MSCs postdelivery, should be carefully considered and fused to maximize the effectiveness of MSCs therapy in ALS.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021. Fondazione Societ&#xe0; Italiana di Neurologia.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Qi</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Jiangxi Provincial People's Hospital, Affiliated People's Hospital of Nanchang University, No. 152, Aiguo Road, Nanchang, 330006, Jiangxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Yuan</LastName><ForeName>Min</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1190-5337</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Jiangxi Provincial People's Hospital, Affiliated People's Hospital of Nanchang University, No. 152, Aiguo Road, Nanchang, 330006, Jiangxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Qiu</LastName><ForeName>Weiwen</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Jiangxi Provincial People's Hospital, Affiliated People's Hospital of Nanchang University, No. 152, Aiguo Road, Nanchang, 330006, Jiangxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cao</LastName><ForeName>Wenfeng</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Jiangxi Provincial People's Hospital, Affiliated People's Hospital of Nanchang University, No. 152, Aiguo Road, Nanchang, 330006, Jiangxi, China. caowf-2004@126.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Renshi</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Jiangxi Provincial People's Hospital, Affiliated People's Hospital of Nanchang University, No. 152, Aiguo Road, Nanchang, 330006, Jiangxi, China. 13767015770@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Italy</Country><MedlineTA>Neurol Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100959175</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1590-1874</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004195" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Models, Animal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018450" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Progression</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D045164" MajorTopicYN="Y">Mesenchymal Stem Cell Transplantation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D059630" MajorTopicYN="Y">Mesenchymal Stem Cells</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mesenchymal stem cells</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Metaanalysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neurodegenerative disorder</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33433755</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10072-020-05036-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s10072-020-05036-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Brown RJ, Al-Chalabi A (2017) Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. N Engl J Med 377:1602</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMra1603471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sartucci F, Pelagatti A, Santin M, Bocci T, Dolciotti C, Bongioanni P (2019) Diaphragm ultrasonography in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a diagnostic tool to assess ventilatory dysfunction and disease severity. Neurol Sci 40:2065&#x2013;2071</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10072-019-03938-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardiman O, Al-Chalabi A, Chio A, Corr EM, Logroscino G, Robberecht W, Shaw PJ, Simmons Z, van den Berg LH (2017) Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat Rev Dis Primers 3:17071</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrdp.2017.71</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Chalabi A, Andersen PM, Chandran S, Chio A, Corcia P, Couratier P, Danielsson O, de Carvalho M, Desnuelle C, Grehl T, Grosskreutz J, Holmoy T, Ingre C, Karlsborg M, Kleveland G, Koch JC, Koritnik B, KuzmaKozakiewicz M, Laaksovirta H, Ludolph A, McDermott C, Meyer T, Mitre RB, Mora PJ, Nygren I, Petri S, Povedano PM, Salachas F, Shaw P, Silani V, Staaf G, Svenstrup K, Talbot K, Tysnes OB, Van Damme P, van der Kooi A, Weber M, Weydt P, Wolf J, Hardiman O, van den Berg LH (2017) July 2017 ENCALS statement on edaravone. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 18:471&#x2013;474</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/21678421.2017.1369125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller RG, Mitchell JD, Moore DH (2012) Riluzole for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS)/motor neuron disease (MND). Cochrane Database Syst Rev D1447</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bucchia M, Ramirez A, Parente V, Simone C, Nizzardo M, Magri F, Dametti S, Corti S (2015) Therapeutic development in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Ther 37:668&#x2013;680</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clinthera.2014.12.020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takei K, Watanabe K, Yuki S, Akimoto M, Sakata T, Palumbo J (2017) Edaravone and its clinical development for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 18:5&#x2013;10</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/21678421.2017.1353101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sawada H (2017) Clinical efficacy of edaravone for the treatment of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Expert Opin Pharmacother 18:735&#x2013;738</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14656566.2017.1319937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shiota M, Heike T, Haruyama M, Baba S, Tsuchiya A, Fujino H, Kobayashi H, Kato T, Umeda K, Yoshimoto M, Nakahata T (2007) Isolation and characterization of bone marrow-derived mesenchymal progenitor cells with myogenic and neuronal properties. Exp Cell Res 313:1008&#x2013;1023</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.yexcr.2006.12.017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dodson MV, Wei S, Duarte M, Du M, Jiang Z, Hausman GJ, Bergen WG (2013) Cell supermarket: adipose tissue as a source of stem cells. J Genom 1:39&#x2013;44</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7150/jgen.3949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X, Hirai M, Cantero S, Ciubotariu R, Dobrila L, Hirsh A, Igura K, Satoh H, Yokomi I, Nishimura T, Yamaguchi S, Yoshimura K, Rubinstein P, Takahashi TA (2011) Isolation and characterization of mesenchymal stem cells from human umbilical cord blood: reevaluation of critical factors for successful isolation and high ability to proliferate and differentiate to chondrocytes as compared to mesenchymal stem cells from bone marrow and adipose tissue. J Cell Biochem 112:1206&#x2013;1218</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jcb.23042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Da CEAL, Ribeiro-Paes JT, Longo BM, Ferrazoli EG, de Andrade TG (2013) Effect of the bone marrow cell transplantation on elevated plus-maze performance in hippocampal-injured mice. Behav Brain Res 248:32&#x2013;40</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbr.2013.03.042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li M, Ikehara S (2013)Bone-marrow-derived mesenchymal stem cells for organ repair. Stem Cells Int 2013:132642</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2013/132642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Y, Yamamoto Y, Xiao Z, Ochiya T (2019) The Immunomodulatory functions of mesenchymal stromal/stem cells mediated via paracrine activity. J Clin Med 8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schinkothe T, Bloch W, Schmidt A (2008) In vitro secreting profile of human mesenchymal stem cells. Stem Cells Dev 17:199&#x2013;206</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/scd.2007.0175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao LR, Duan WM, Reyes M, Keene CD, Verfaillie CM, Low WC (2002) Human bone marrow stem cells exhibit neural phenotypes and ameliorate neurological deficits after grafting into the ischemic brain of rats. Exp Neurol 174:11&#x2013;20</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1006/exnr.2001.7853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knippenberg S, Thau N, Schwabe K, Dengler R, Schambach A, Hass R, Petri S (2012) Intraspinal injection of human umbilical cord blood-derived cells is neuroprotective in a transgenic mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurodegener Dis 9:107&#x2013;120</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000331327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gubert F, Decotelli AB, Bonacossa-Pereira I, Figueiredo FR, Zaverucha-do-Valle C, Tovar-Moll F, Hoffmann L, Urmenyi TP, Santiago MF, Mendez-Otero R (2016) Intraspinal bone-marrow cell therapy at pre- and symptomatic phases in a mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Stem Cell Res Ther 7:41</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13287-016-0293-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang BL (2017) The use of mesenchymal stem cells (MSCs) for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) therapy - a perspective on cell biological mechanisms. Rev Neurosci 28:725&#x2013;738</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/revneuro-2017-0018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim SH, Oh KW, Jin HK, Bae JS (2018) Immune inflammatory modulation as a potential therapeutic strategy of stem cell therapy for ALS and neurodegenerative diseases. BMB Rep 51:545&#x2013;546</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5483/BMBRep.2018.51.11.255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewis CM, Suzuki M (2014) Therapeutic applications of mesenchymal stem cells for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Stem Cell Res Ther 5:32</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/scrt421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vercelli A, Mereuta OM, Garbossa D, Muraca G, Mareschi K, Rustichelli D, Ferrero I, Mazzini L, Madon E, Fagioli F (2008) Human mesenchymal stem cell transplantation extends survival, improves motor performance and decreases neuroinflammation in mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurobiol Dis 31:395&#x2013;405</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nbd.2008.05.016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macleod MR, O'Collins T, Howells DW, Donnan GA (2004) Pooling of animal experimental data reveals influence of study design and publication bias. STROKE 35:1203&#x2013;1208</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/01.STR.0000125719.25853.20</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gardner MJ, Altman DG (1986) Confidence intervals rather than P values: estimation rather than hypothesis testing. Br Med J (Clin Res Ed) 292:746&#x2013;750</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.292.6522.746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boucherie C, Schafer S, Lavand'Homme P, Maloteaux JM, Hermans E (2009) Chimerization of astroglial population in the lumbar spinal cord after mesenchymal stem cell transplantation prolongs survival in a rat model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurosci Res 87:2034&#x2013;2046</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jnr.22038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forostyak S, Homola A, Turnovcova K, Svitil P, Jendelova P, Sykova E (2014) Intrathecal delivery of mesenchymal stromal cells protects the structure of altered perineuronal nets in SOD1 rats and amends the course of ALS. Stem Cells 32:3163&#x2013;3172</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/stem.1812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rehorova M, Vargova I, Forostyak S, Vackova I, Turnovcova K, Kupcova SH, Vodicka P, Kubinova S, Sykova E, Jendelova P (2019) A combination of intrathecal and intramuscular application of human mesenchymal stem cells partly reduces the activation of necroptosis in the spinal cord of SOD1(G93A) rats. Stem Cells Transl Med 8:535&#x2013;547</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/sctm.18-0223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou C, Zhang C, Zhao R, Chi S, Ge P, Zhang C (2013) Human marrow stromal cells reduce microglial activation to protect motor neurons in a transgenic mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neuroinflammation 10:52</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1742-2094-10-52</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen X, Wang S, Cao W (2018) Mesenchymal stem cell-mediated immunomodulation in cell therapy of neurodegenerative diseases. Cell Immunol 326:8&#x2013;14</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cellimm.2017.06.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volkman R, Offen D (2017) Concise review: mesenchymal stem cells in neurodegenerative diseases. Stem Cells 35:1867&#x2013;1880</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/stem.2651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu X, Liu G, Halim A, Ju Y, Luo Q, Song AG (2019) Mesenchymal stem cell migration and tissue repair. CELLS-BASEL 8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naderi-Meshkin H, Bahrami AR, Bidkhori HR, Mirahmadi M, Ahmadiankia N (2015) Strategies to improve homing of mesenchymal stem cells for greater efficacy in stem cell therapy. Cell Biol Int 39:23&#x2013;34</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cbin.10378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sohni A, Verfaillie CM (2013) Mesenchymal stem cells migration homing and tracking. Stem Cells Int 2013:130763</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2013/130763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanna T, Sachan V (2014) Mesenchymal stem cells: potential in treatment of neurodegenerative diseases. Curr Stem Cell Res Ther 9:513&#x2013;521</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/1574888X09666140923101110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lo FD, Mannino G, Giuffrida R (2018) Functional role of mesenchymal stem cells in the treatment of chronic neurodegenerative diseases. J Cell Physiol 233:3982&#x2013;3999</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jcp.26192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marconi S, Bonaconsa M, Scambi I, Squintani GM, Rui W, Turano E, Ungaro D, D'Agostino S, Barbieri F, Angiari S, Farinazzo A, Constantin G, Del CU, Bonetti B, Mariotti R (2013) Systemic treatment with adipose-derived mesenchymal stem cells ameliorates clinical and pathological features in the amyotrophic lateral sclerosis murine model. NEUROSCIENCE 248:333&#x2013;343</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuroscience.2013.05.034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwon MS, Noh MY, Oh KW, Cho KA, Kang BY, Kim KS, Kim YS, Kim SH (2014) The immunomodulatory effects of human mesenchymal stem cells on peripheral blood mononuclear cells in ALS patients. J Neurochem 131:206&#x2013;218</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jnc.12814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCombe PA, Henderson RD (2010) Effects of gender in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Gend Med 7:557&#x2013;570</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.genm.2010.11.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tajiri N, Borlongan CV, Kaneko Y (2016) Cyclosporine a treatment abrogates ischemia-induced neuronal cell death by preserving mitochondrial integrity through upregulation of the Parkinson&#x2019;s disease-associated protein DJ-1. CNS Neurosci Ther 22:602&#x2013;610</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cns.12546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen ZR, Ma Y, Guo HH, Lu ZD, Jin QH (2018) Therapeutic efficacy of cyclosporin A against spinal cord injury in rats with hyperglycemia. Mol Med Rep 17:4369&#x2013;4375</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29328412</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5802210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsumoto S, Murozono M, Kanazawa M, Nara T, Ozawa T, Watanabe Y (2018) Edaravone and cyclosporine A as neuroprotective agents for acute ischemic stroke. Acute Med Surg 5:213&#x2013;221</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ams2.343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forsse A, Nielsen TH, Nygaard KH, Nordstrom CH, Gramsbergen JB, Poulsen FR (2019) Cyclosporin A ameliorates cerebral oxidative metabolism and infarct size in the endothelin-1 rat model of transient cerebral ischaemia. Sci Rep 9:3702</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-019-40245-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Straathof K, Anoop P, Allwood Z, Silva J, Nikolajeva O, Chiesa R, Veys P, Amrolia PJ, Rao K (2017)Long-term outcome following cyclosporine-related neurotoxicity in paediatric allogeneic haematopoietic stem cell transplantation. Bone Marrow Transplant 52:159&#x2013;162</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/bmt.2016.232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baky NA, Fadda L, Al-Rasheed NM, Al-Rasheed NM, Mohamed A, Yacoub H (2016) Neuroprotective effect of carnosine and cyclosporine-A against inflammation, apoptosis, and oxidative brain damage after closed head injury in immature rats. Toxicol Mech Methods 26:1&#x2013;10</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo XD, Liu QF, Ning J, Fan ZP, Xu D, Wei YQ (2008) [A clinical analysis of severe cyclosporine A-related neurotoxicity after allogenic hematopoietic stem cell transplantation]. Zhonghua Nei Ke Za Zhi 47:40&#x2013;43</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teksam M, Casey SO, Michel E, Truwit CL (2001) Subarachnoid hemorrhage associated with cyclosporine A neurotoxicity in a bone-marrow transplant recipient. Neuroradiology 43:242&#x2013;245</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Collins VE, Macleod MR, Donnan GA, Horky LL, van der Worp BH, Howells DW (2006) 1,026 experimental treatments in acute stroke. Ann Neurol 59:467&#x2013;477</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schulz KF, Chalmers I, Hayes RJ, Altman DG (1995) Empirical evidence of bias. Dimensions of methodological quality associated with estimates of treatment effects in controlled trials. JAMA 273:408&#x2013;412</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>