<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">33443392</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>07</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1537-1603</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>39</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of clinical neurophysiology : official publication of the American Electroencephalographic Society</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Clin Neurophysiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Reduced Occipital Cortex Excitability in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>486</StartPage><EndPage>491</EndPage><MedlinePgn>486-491</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/WNP.0000000000000805</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE">In addition to motor cortex involvement, sensory abnormalities have been demonstrated in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS), including structural and metabolic alterations in the occipital cortex. The aim of this study was to examine occipital excitability changes in ALS.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Twenty-one patients with ALS and 16 healthy subjects were enrolled into the study. Phosphene experience and phosphene threshold were studied to assess occipital excitability. Cognitive function was evaluated in both groups by means of Montreal Cognitive Assessment and Addenbrooke's Cognitive Examination-Revised visuospatial score tests.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Phosphene was experienced in 13 (81.3%) healthy subjects and 9 (42.9%) patients with ALS ( P = 0.04). The mean phosphene threshold was not significantly different between the two groups. No correlation existed between phosphene threshold and motor cortical excitability parameters, ALS Functional Rating Scale Revised, Montreal Cognitive Assessment, and Addenbrooke's Cognitive Examination-Revised scores.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Visual cortex is affected, and the occipital excitability is reduced in ALS, without any relation to motor cortical excitability changes, providing another clue suggestive of sensory involvement in ALS.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2021 by the American Clinical Neurophysiology Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cengiz</LastName><ForeName>B&#xfc;lent</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Gazi University Faculty of Medicine, Ankara, Turkey; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Clinical Neurophysiology, Gazi University Faculty of Medicine, Ankara, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fidanc&#x131;</LastName><ForeName>Halit</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Gazi University Faculty of Medicine, Ankara, Turkey; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Clinical Neurophysiology, Gazi University Faculty of Medicine, Ankara, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Baltac&#x131;</LastName><ForeName>Hande</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Gazi University Faculty of Medicine, Ankara, Turkey; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>T&#xfc;rksoy</LastName><ForeName>Ece</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Gazi University Faculty of Medicine, Ankara, Turkey; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kuruo&#x11f;lu</LastName><ForeName>Reha</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Gazi University Faculty of Medicine, Ankara, Turkey; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Clinical Neurophysiology, Gazi University Faculty of Medicine, Ankara, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Clin Neurophysiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8506708</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0736-0258</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000071080" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cortical Excitability</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009044" MajorTopicYN="Y">Motor Cortex</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009483" MajorTopicYN="N">Neuropsychological Tests</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009778" MajorTopicYN="N">Occipital Lobe</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors have no funding or conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33443392</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/WNP.0000000000000805</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00004691-202209000-00009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Dyck PJ, Stevens JC, Mulder DW, Espinosa RE. Frequency of nerve fiber degeneration of peripheral motor and sensory neurons in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Morphometry of deep and superficial peroneal nerves. Neurology 1975;25:781&#x2013;785.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hammad M, Silva A, Glass J, Sladky JT, Benatar M. Clinical, electrophysiologic, and pathologic evidence for sensory abnormalities in ALS. Neurology 2007;69:2236&#x2013;2242.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li TM, Alberman E, Swash M. Comparison of sporadic and familial disease amongst 580 cases of motor neuron disease. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 1988;51:778&#x2013;784.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jamal GA, Weir AI, Hansen S, Ballantyne JP. Sensory involvement in motor neuron disease: further evidence from automated thermal threshold determination. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 1985;48:906&#x2013;910.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isak B, Tankisi H, Johnsen B, et al. Involvement of distal sensory nerves in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve 2016;54:1086&#x2013;1092.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pugdahl K, Fuglsang-Frederiksen A, de Carvalho M, et al. Generalised sensory system abnormalities in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a European multicentre study. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2007;78:746&#x2013;749.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pugdahl K, Fuglsang-Frederiksen A, Johnsen B, et al. A prospective multicentre study on sural nerve action potentials in ALS. Clin Neurophysiol 2008;119:1106&#x2013;1110.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bosch EP, Yamada T, Kimura J. Somatosensory evoked potentials in motor neuron disease. Muscle Nerve 1985;8:556&#x2013;562.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matheson JK, Harrington HJ, Hallett M. Abnormalities of multimodality evoked potentials in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Arch Neurol 1986;43:338&#x2013;340.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radtke RA, Erwin A, Erwin CW. Abnormal sensory evoked potentials in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology 1986;36:796&#x2013;801.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zanette G, Polo A, Gasperini M, Bertolasi L, De Grandis D. Far-field and cortical somatosensory evoked potentials in motor neuron disease. Muscle Nerve 1990;13:47&#x2013;55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimizu T, Bokuda K, Kimura H, et al. Sensory cortex hyperexcitability predicts short survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology 2018;90:e1578&#x2013;e1587.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agosta F, Valsasina P, Riva N, et al. The cortical signature of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. PLoS One 2012;7:e42816.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang NX, Zou ZY, Xue YJ, Chen HJ. Abnormal cerebral microstructures revealed by diffusion kurtosis imaging in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Magn Reson Imaging 2020;51:554&#x2013;562.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mezzapesa DM, D'Errico E, Tortelli R, et al. Cortical thinning and clinical heterogeneity in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. PLoS One 2013;8:e80748.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thorns J, Jansma H, Peschel T, et al. Extent of cortical involvement in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-an analysis based on cortical thickness. BMC Neurol 2013;13:148.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cistaro A, Pagani M, Montuschi A, et al. The metabolic signature of C9ORF72-related ALS: FDG PET comparison with nonmutated patients. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging 2014;41:844&#x2013;852.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sala A, Iaccarino L, Fania P, et al. Testing the diagnostic accuracy of [18F]FDG-PET in discriminating spinal- and bulbar-onset amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging 2019;46:1117&#x2013;1131.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Laere K, Vanhee A, Verschueren J, et al. Value of 18fluorodeoxyglucose-positron-emission tomography in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a prospective study. JAMA Neurol 2014;71:553&#x2013;561.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pagani M, Chio A, Valentini MC, et al. Functional pattern of brain FDG-PET in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology 2014;83:1067&#x2013;1074.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dukic S, McMackin R, Buxo T, et al. Patterned functional network disruption in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Hum Brain Mapp 2019;40:4827&#x2013;4842.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geevasinga N, Korgaonkar MS, Menon P, et al. Brain functional connectome abnormalities in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis are associated with disability and cortical hyperexcitability. Eur J Neurol 2017;24:1507&#x2013;1517.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li W, Zhang J, Zhou C, et al. Abnormal functional connectivity density in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Front Aging Neurosci 2018;10:215.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loewe K, Machts J, Kaufmann J, et al. Widespread temporo-occipital lobe dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Sci Rep 2017;7:40252.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serra A, Galdi P, Pesce E, et al. Strong-weak pruning for brain network identification in connectome-wide neuroimaging: application to amyotrophic lateral sclerosis disease stage characterization. Int J Neural Syst 2019;29:1950007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou C, Hu X, Hu J, et al. Altered brain network in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a resting graph theory-based network study at voxel-wise level. Front Neurosci 2016;10:204.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beeldman E, Raaphorst J, Klein Twennaar M, de Visser M, Schmand BA, de Haan RJ. The cognitive profile of ALS: a systematic review and meta-analysis update. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2016;87:611&#x2013;619.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silvanto J. Transcranial magnetic stimulation and vision. Handb Clin Neurol 2013;116:655&#x2013;669.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Dengler R, Eisen A, et al. Electrodiagnostic criteria for diagnosis of ALS. Clin Neurophysiol 2008;119:497&#x2013;503.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum JM, Stambler N, Malta E, et al. The ALSFRS-R: a revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. BDNF ALS Study Group (Phase III). J Neurol Sci 1999;169:13&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee HW, Hong SB, Seo DW, Tae WS, Hong SC. Mapping of functional organization in human visual cortex: electrical cortical stimulation. Neurology 2000;54:849&#x2013;854.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher RJ, Nakamura Y, Bestmann S, Rothwell JC, Bostock H. Two phases of intracortical inhibition revealed by transcranial magnetic threshold tracking. Exp Brain Res 2002;143:240&#x2013;248.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bede P, Bokde A, Elamin M, et al. Grey matter correlates of clinical variables in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS): a neuroimaging study of ALS motor phenotype heterogeneity and cortical focality. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2013;84:766&#x2013;773.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terhune DB, Murray E, Near J, Stagg CJ, Cowey A, Cohen Kadosh R. Phosphene perception relates to visual cortex glutamate levels and covaries with atypical visuospatial awareness. Cereb Cortex 2015;25:4341&#x2013;4350.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S, Kiernan MC. Transcranial magnetic stimulation for the assessment of neurodegenerative disease. Neurotherapeutics 2017;14:91&#x2013;106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han J, Ma L. Study of the features of proton MR spectroscopy ((1)H-MRS) on amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Magn Reson Imaging 2010;31:305&#x2013;308.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weerasekera A, Peeters R, Sima D, et al. Motor cortex metabolite alterations in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis assessed in vivo using edited and non-edited magnetic resonance spectroscopy. Brain Res 2019;1718:22&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinto L, Goard MJ, Estandian D, et al. Fast modulation of visual perception by basal forebrain cholinergic neurons. Nat Neurosci 2013;16:1857&#x2013;1863.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chamoun M, Groleau M, Bhat M, Vaucher E. Dose-dependent effect of donepezil administration on long-term enhancement of visually evoked potentials and cholinergic receptor overexpression in rat visual cortex. J Physiol Paris 2016;110:65&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crochemore C, Pena-Altamira E, Virgili M, Monti B, Contestabile A. Disease-related regressive alterations of forebrain cholinergic system in SOD1 mutant transgenic mice. Neurochem Int 2005;46:357&#x2013;368.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berger ML, Veitl M, Malessa S, Sluga E, Hornykiewicz O. Cholinergic markers in ALS spinal cord. J Neurol Sci 1992;108:114&#x2013;117.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagao M, Misawa H, Kato S, Hirai S. Loss of cholinergic synapses on the spinal motor neurons of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neuropathol Exp Neurol 1998;57:329&#x2013;333.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cengiz B, Fidanci H, Kiyak Keceli Y, Baltaci H, Kuruo&#x11f;lu R. Impaired short- and long-latency afferent inhibition in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve 2019;59:699&#x2013;704.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Afra J, Mascia A, Gerard P, Maertens de Noordhout A, Schoenen J. Interictal cortical excitability in migraine: a study using transcranial magnetic stimulation of motor and visual cortices. Ann Neurol 1998;44:209&#x2013;215.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gothe J, Brandt SA, Irlbacher K, Roricht S, Sabel BA, Meyer BU. Changes in visual cortex excitability in blind subjects as demonstrated by transcranial magnetic stimulation. Brain 2002;125:479&#x2013;490.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazzi C, Savazzi S, Abrahamyan A, Ruzzoli M. Reliability of TMS phosphene threshold estimation: toward a standardized protocol. Brain Stimul 2017;10:609&#x2013;617.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hallett M. Transcranial magnetic stimulation and the human brain. Nature 2000;406:147&#x2013;150.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boroojerdi B, Meister IG, Foltys H, Sparing R, Cohen LG, Topper R. Visual and motor cortex excitability: a transcranial magnetic stimulation study. Clin Neurophysiol 2002;113:1501&#x2013;1504.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brigo F, Storti M, Tezzon F, Manganotti P, Nardone R. Primary visual cortex excitability in migraine: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Neurol Sci 2013;34:819&#x2013;830.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>