<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">33533539</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>30</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-4598</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>63</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Muscle &amp; nerve</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Muscle Nerve</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Assessment of feasibility and utility of universal referral to specialty palliative care in a multidisciplinary amyotrophic lateral sclerosis clinic: A cohort study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>818</StartPage><EndPage>823</EndPage><MedlinePgn>818-823</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/mus.27194</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION">Although the value of palliative care integration in multidisciplinary amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) clinics has been increasingly recognized, limited data are available demonstrating the feasibility and utility of a palliative care specialist embedded in an ALS clinic. The purpose of this study is to describe the feasibility and utility of a universal outpatient referral model for specialty palliative care for patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">This is a retrospective cohort study of initial patient visits with a palliative care physician in a multidisciplinary ALS clinic at an academic institution. All patients were referred to an embedded palliative care physician from January to December 2019.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Within the study period, 52 of 69 (75%) patients with a confirmed diagnosis of ALS were seen by the palliative care physician. The most common reason patients were not seen by palliative care was a lack of insurance authorization (n&#xa0;=&#xa0;5). At the visit, 94% of patients discussed at least one advance care planning or goals of care topic. The most common advance care planning topic discussed was code status (40%). The most common goals of care topic discussed was meaning and values (57%). Symptom management was discussed with 40 patients (77%). The most common symptom addressed was pain and/or muscle spasms (33%).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION">These data support the feasibility and utility of universal, outpatient palliative care referral for patients with ALS. Further research is necessary to determine the long-term effect on outcomes for this population.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hafer</LastName><ForeName>Julia</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>David Geffen School of Medicine, University of California, Los Angeles, Los Angeles, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jensen</LastName><ForeName>Sarah</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>David Geffen School of Medicine, University of California, Los Angeles, Los Angeles, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wiedau-Pazos</LastName><ForeName>Martina</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of California, Los Angeles, Los Angeles, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mehta</LastName><ForeName>Ambereen K</ForeName><Initials>AK</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7834-2279</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Palliative Care Program, Department of Medicine, University of California, Los Angeles, Los Angeles, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Palliative Care Program, Division of General Internal Medicine, Johns Hopkins Bayview Medical Center, Baltimore, Maryland, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Muscle Nerve</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7803146</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0148-639X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="CommentIn"><RefSource>Muscle Nerve. 2021 Jun;63(6):790-792</RefSource><PMID Version="1">33759457</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D032722" MajorTopicYN="Y">Advance Care Planning</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015331" MajorTopicYN="N">Cohort Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005240" MajorTopicYN="N">Feasibility Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010166" MajorTopicYN="Y">Palliative Care</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010348" MajorTopicYN="Y">Patient Care Team</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">advance care planning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">outpatients</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">palliative care</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">referral and consultation</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33533539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.27194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Mitsumoto H, Rabkin JG. Palliative care for patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. JAMA 2007; 298:207.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Albert SM, Murphy PL, Del Bene ML, Rowland LP. Prospective study of palliative care in ALS: choice, timing, outcomes. J Neurol Sci 1999; 169:108-113.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hogden A, Foley G, Henderson RD, James N, Aoun SM. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: improving care with a multidisciplinary approach. J Multidiscip Healthc 2017; 10:205-215.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bede P, Oliver D, Stodart J, Van Den Berg L, Simmons Z, Brannag&#xe1;in D&#xd3;, et al. Palliative care in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a review of current international guidelines and initiatives. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2011; 82:413-418.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boersma I, Miyasaki J, Kutner J, Kluger B. Palliative care and neurology: time for a paradigm shift. Neurology 2014; 83:561-567.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehta AK, Najjar S, May N, Shah B, Blackhall L. A Needs assessment of palliative care education among the United States adult neurology residency programs. J Palliat Med 2018; 21:1448-1457.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veronese S, Gallo G, Valle A, Cugno C, Chi&#xf2; A, Calvo A, et al. Specialist palliative care improves the quality of life in advanced neurodegenerative disorders: NE-PAL, a pilot randomised controlled study. BMJ Support Palliat Care 2017; 7:164-172.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brizzi K, Paganoni S, Zehm A, De Marchi F, Berry JD. Integration of a palliative care specialist in an amyotrophic lateral sclerosis clinic: observations from one center. Muscle Nerve 2019; 60:137-140.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng HWB, Chan OMI, Chan CHR, Chan WH, Fung KS, Wong KY. End-of-life characteristics and palliative care provision for patients with motor neuron disease. Am J Hosp Palliat Care 2018; 35:847-851.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hepgul N, Gao W, Evans CJ, Jackson D, Van Vliet LM, Byrne A, et al. Integrating palliative care into neurology services: what do the professionals say? BMJ Support Palliat Care 2018; 8:41-44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips JN, Besbris J, Foster LA, Kramer NM, Maiser S, Mehta AK. Models of outpatient neuropalliative care for patients with amyotrophic lateral. Neurology 2020; 95:e623-e636.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seeber AA, Pols AJ, Hijdra A, Grupstra HF, Willems DL, De Visser M. Advance care planning in progressive neurological diseases: lessons from ALS. BMC Palliat Care 2019; 18:10-13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudore RL, Lum HD, You JJ, Hanson LC, Meier DE, Pantilat SZ, et al. Defining advance care planning for adults: a consensus definition from a multidisciplinary Delphi panel. J Pain Symptom Manage 2017; 53:821-832.e1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y, Kline D, Aerts S, Youngwerth JM, Kutner JS, Sillau S, et al. Inpatient palliative care for neurological disorders: lessons from a large retrospective series. J Palliat Med 2017; 20:59-64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernacki RE, Block SD, Force for the AC of PHVCT. Communication about serious illness care goals: a review and synthesis of best practices. JAMA Intern Med 2014; 174:1994-2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang RS-K, Poon WS. &#x201c;Triggers&#x201d; for referral to neurology palliative care service. Ann Palliat Med 2018; 7:289-295.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walbert T. Integration of palliative care into the neuro-oncology practice: patterns in the United States. Neurooncol Pract 2014; 1:3-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murray L, Butow PN. Advance care planning in motor neuron disease: a systematic review. Palliat Support Care 2016; 14:411-432.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicholson K, Murphy A, McDonnell E, Shapiro J, Simpson E, Glass J, et al. Improving symptom management for people with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve 2018; 57:20-24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walsh S, Lehman E, Yang C, Raheja D, Stephens HE, Simmons Z. Patient-reported problematic symptoms in an ALS treatment trial. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2016; 17:198-205.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stephens HE, Young J, Felgoise SH, Simmons Z. A qualitative study of multidisciplinary ALS clinic use in the United States. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2016; 17:55-61.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>