<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">33548103</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2443</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Genes to cells : devoted to molecular &amp; cellular mechanisms</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Genes Cells</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-associated Vap33 is required for maintaining neuronal dendrite morphology and organelle distribution in Drosophila.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>230</StartPage><EndPage>239</EndPage><MedlinePgn>230-239</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/gtc.12835</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>VAMP-associated protein (VAP) is an endoplasmic reticulum (ER) membrane protein that functions as a tethering protein at the membrane contact sites between the ER and various intracellular organelles. Mutations such as P56S in human VAPB cause neurodegenerative diseases such as amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). However, VAP functions in neurons are poorly understood. Here, we utilized Drosophila olfactory projection neurons with a mosaic analysis with a repressible cell marker (MARCM) to analyze the neuronal function of Vap33, a Drosophila ortholog of human VAPB. In vap33 null mutant clones, the dendrites of projection neurons exhibited defects in the maintenance of their morphology. The subcellular localization of the Golgi apparatus and mitochondria were also abnormal. These results indicate that Vap33 is required for neuronal morphology and organelle distribution. Additionally, to examine the impact of ALS-associated mutations in neurons, we overexpressed human VAPB-P56S in vap33 null mutant clones (mosaic rescue experiments) and found that, in aged flies, human VAPB-P56S expression caused mislocalization of Bruchpilot, a presynaptic protein. These results implied that synaptic protein localization and ER quality control may be affected by disease mutations. We provide insights into the physiological and pathological functions of VAP in neurons.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 Molecular Biology Society of Japan and John Wiley &amp; Sons Australia, Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kamemura</LastName><ForeName>Kosuke</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Program of Biomedical Science and Basic Biology, Graduate School of Integrated Sciences for Life, Hiroshima University, Hiroshima, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Chun-An</ForeName><Initials>CA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Genetics, Graduate School of Pharmaceutical Sciences, The University of Tokyo, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Okumura</LastName><ForeName>Misako</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3162-0416</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Program of Biomedical Science and Basic Biology, Graduate School of Integrated Sciences for Life, Hiroshima University, Hiroshima, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Miura</LastName><ForeName>Masayuki</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7444-5705</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Genetics, Graduate School of Pharmaceutical Sciences, The University of Tokyo, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chihara</LastName><ForeName>Takahiro</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9989-3619</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Program of Biomedical Science and Basic Biology, Graduate School of Integrated Sciences for Life, Hiroshima University, Hiroshima, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>Frontier Development Program for Genome Editing</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><Agency>Toray Science Foundation</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>JPMXS05S2900002</GrantID><Agency>Program for Advancing Strategic International Networks to Accelerate the Circulation of Talented Researchers</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>18H05369</GrantID><Agency>Japan Society for the Promotion of Science</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>18K14716</GrantID><Agency>Japan Society for the Promotion of Science</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>20K15903</GrantID><Agency>Japan Society for the Promotion of Science</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Genes Cells</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9607379</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1356-9597</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C510146">BRP protein, Drosophila</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D002352">Carrier Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D029721">Drosophila Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D008565">Membrane Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D066329">Protein Aggregates</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C496748">VAPB protein, human</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C491921">Vap33 protein, Drosophila</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D033921">Vesicular Transport Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002352" MajorTopicYN="N">Carrier Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003712" MajorTopicYN="N">Dendrites</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D029721" MajorTopicYN="N">Drosophila Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004331" MajorTopicYN="N">Drosophila melanogaster</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008565" MajorTopicYN="N">Membrane Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009154" MajorTopicYN="N">Mutation</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015388" MajorTopicYN="N">Organelles</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D066329" MajorTopicYN="N">Protein Aggregates</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013347" MajorTopicYN="N">Subcellular Fractions</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D033921" MajorTopicYN="N">Vesicular Transport Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33548103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/gtc.12835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Aliaga, L., Lai, C., Yu, J., Chub, N., Shim, H., Sun, L., Xie, C., Yang, W. J., Lin, X., O&#x2019;Donovan, M. J., &amp; Cai, H. (2013). Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-related VAPB P56S mutation differentially affects the function and survival of corticospinal and spinal motor neurons. Human Molecular Genetics, 22, 4293-4305. https://doi.org/10.1093/hmg/ddt279</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Araki, K., &amp; Nagata, K. (2012). Protein folding and quality control in the ER. Cold Spring Harbor Perspectives in Biology, 4, 1-26. https://doi.org/10.1101/cshperspect.a015438</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chai, A., Withers, J., Koh, Y. H., Parry, K., Bao, H., Zhang, B., Budnik, V., &amp; Pennetta, G. (2008). hVAPB, the causative gene of a heterogeneous group of motor neuron diseases in humans, is functionally interchangeable with its Drosophila homologue DVAP-33A at the neuromuscular junction. Human Molecular Genetics, 17, 266-280. https://doi.org/10.1093/hmg/ddm303</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, H., Anagnostou, G., Chai, A., Withers, J., Morris, A., Adhikaree, J., Pennetta, G., &amp; Belleroche, J. S. D. (2010). Characterization of the properties of a novel mutation in VAPB in familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis*. Journal of Biological Chemistry, 285, 40266-40281. https://doi.org/10.1074/jbc.M110.161398</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chihara, T., Luginbuhl, D., &amp; Luo, L. (2007). Cytoplasmic and mitochondrial protein translation in axonal and dendritic terminal arborization. Nature Neuroscience, 10, 828-837. https://doi.org/10.1038/nn1910</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conforti, F. L., Sprovieri, T., Mazzei, R., Ungaro, C., Tessitore, A., Tedeschi, G., Patitucci, A., Magariello, A., Gabriele, A. L., Labella, V., Simone, I. L., Majorana, G., Monsurr&#xf2;, M. R., Valentino, P., Muglia, M., &amp; Quattrone, A. (2006). Sporadic ALS is not associated with VAPB gene mutations in Southern Italy. Journal of Negative Results in BioMedicine, 5, 4-6. https://doi.org/10.1186/1477-5751-5-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diego, P., Nili, D., Eyal, S., Koret, H., &amp; Sima, L. (2008). Coordinated lipid transfer between the endoplasmic reticulum and the golgi complex requires the VAP proteins and is essential for golgi-mediated transport. Molecular Biology of the Cell, 19, 3871-3884. https://doi.org/10.1091/mbc.e08-05-0498</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forrest, S., Chai, A., Sanhueza, M., Marescotti, M., Parry, K., Georgiev, A., Sahota, V., Mendez-Castro, R., &amp; Pennetta, G. (2013). Increased levels of phosphoinositides cause neurodegeneration in a Drosophila model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Human Molecular Genetics, 22, 2689-2704. https://doi.org/10.1093/hmg/ddt118</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedlander, R., Jarosch, E., Urban, J., Volkwein, C., &amp; Sommer, T. (2000). A regulatory link between ER-associated protein degradation and the unfolded-protein response. Nature Cell Biology, 2, 379-384. https://doi.org/10.1038/35017001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han, S. M., Tsuda, H., Yang, Y., Vibbert, J., Cottee, P., Lee, S. J., Winek, J., Haueter, C., Bellen, H. J., &amp; Miller, M. A. (2012). Secreted VAPB/ALS8 major sperm protein domains modulate mitochondrial localization and morphology via growth cone guidance receptors. Developmental Cell, 22, 348-362. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.devcel.2011.12.009</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>James, C., M&#xfc;ller, M., Goldberg, M. W., Lenz, C., Urlaub, H., &amp; Kehlenbach, R. H. (2019). Proteomic mapping by rapamycin-dependent targeting of APEX2 identifies binding partners of VAPB at the inner nuclear membrane. Journal of Biological Chemistry, 294, 16241-16254. https://doi.org/10.1074/jbc.RA118.007283</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jefferis, G. S. X. E., Marin, E. C., Stocker, R. F., &amp; Luo, L. (2001). Target neuron prespecification in the olfactory map of Drosophila. Nature, 414, 204-208. https://doi.org/10.1038/35102574</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jefferis, G. S. X. E., Vyas, R. M., Berdnik, D., Ramaekers, A., Stocker, R. F., Tanaka, N. K., Ito, K., &amp; Luo, L. (2004). Developmental origin of writing specificity in the olfactory system of Drosophila. Development, 131, 117-130.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kabashi, E., El Oussini, H., Bercier, V., Gros-Louis, F., Valdmanis, P. N., McDearmid, J., Mejier, I. A., Dion, P. A., Dupre, N., Hollinger, D., Sinniger, J., Dirrig-Grosch, S., Camu, W., Meininger, V., Loeffler, J.-P., Ren&#xe9;, F., Drapeau, P., Rouleau, G. A., &amp; Dupuis, L. (2013). Investigating the contribution of VAPB/ALS8 loss of function in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Human Molecular Genetics, 22, 2350-2360. https://doi.org/10.1093/hmg/ddt080</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamemura, K., &amp; Chihara, T. (2019). Multiple functions of the ER-resident VAP and its extracellular role in neural development and disease. Journal of Biochemistry, 165, 391-400. https://doi.org/10.1093/jb/mvz011</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuijpers, M., Yu, K. L., Teuling, E., Akhmanova, A., Jaarsma, D., &amp; Hoogenraad, C. (2013). The ALS8 protein VAPB interacts with the ER - Golgi recycling protein YIF1A and regulates membrane delivery into dendrites. EMBO Journal, 32, 2056-2072. https://doi.org/10.1038/emboj.2013.131</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Landers, J. E., Leclerc, A. L., Shi, L., Virkud, A., Cho, T., Maxwell, M. M., Henry, A. F., Polak, M., Glass, J. D., Kwiatkowski, T. J., Al-Chalabi, A., Shaw, C. E., Leigh, P. N., Rodriguez-Leyza, I., McKenna-Yasek, D., Sapp, P. C., &amp; Brown, R. H. (2008). New VAPB deletion variant and exclusion of VAPB mutations in familial ALS. Neurology, 70(14), 1179-1185. https://doi.org/10.1212/01.wnl.0000289760.85237.4e</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larroquette, F., Seto, L., Gaub, P. L., Kamal, B., Wallis, D., Larivi&#xe8;re, R., Vall&#xe9;e, J., Robitaille, R., &amp; Tsuda, H. (2015). Vapb/Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis 8 knock-in mice display slowly progressive motor behavior defects accompanying ER stress and autophagic response. Human Molecular Genetics, 24, 6515-6529.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, T., &amp; Luo, L. (2001). Mosaic analysis with a repressible cell marker (MARCM) for Drosophila neural development. Trends in Neurosciences, 24, 251-254. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0166-2236(00)01791-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Z., Okamoto, K. I., Hayashi, Y., &amp; Sheng, M. (2004). The importance of dendritic mitochondria in the morphogenesis and plasticity of spines and synapses. Cell, 119, 873-887. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2004.11.003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo, L., &amp; Wu, J. S. (2007). A protocol for mosaic analysis with a repressible cell marker (Marcm) in Drosophila. Nature Protocols, 1, 2583-2589.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mikitova, V., &amp; Levine, T. P. (2012). Analysis of the key elements of FFAT-like motifs identifies new proteins that potentially bind VAP on the ER, including two AKAPs and FAPP2. PLoS One, 7, e30455.-https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0030455</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moustaqim-barrette, A., Lin, Y. Q., Pradhan, S., Neely, G. G., Bellen, H. J., &amp; Tsuda, H. (2014). The amyotrophic lateral sclerosis 8 protein, VAP, is required for ER protein quality control. Human Molecular Genetics, 23, 1975-1989. https://doi.org/10.1093/hmg/ddt594</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishimura, A. L., Mitne-Neto, M., Silva, H. C. A., Richieri-Costa, A., Middleton, S., Cascio, D., Kok, F., Oliveira, J. R. M., Gillingwater, T., Webb, J., Skehel, P., &amp; Zatz, M. (2004). A Mutation in the vesicle-trafficking protein VAPB causes late-onset spinal muscular atrophy and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. American Journal of Human Genetics, 75, 822-831. https://doi.org/10.1086/425287</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ori-McKenney, K. M., Jan, L. Y., &amp; Jan, Y. N. (2012). Golgi outposts shape dendrite morphology by functioning as sites of acentrosomal microtubule nucleation in neurons. Neuron, 76, 921-930. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2012.10.008</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pennetta, G., Hiesinger, P. R., Fabian-Fine, R., Meinertzhagen, I. A., &amp; Bellen, H. J. (2002). Drosophila VAP-33A directs bouton formation at neuromuscular junctions in a dosage-dependent manner. Neuron, 35, 291-306. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0896-6273(02)00769-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratnaparkhi, A., Lawless, G. M., Schweizer, F. E., Golshani, P., &amp; George, R. (2008). A Drosophila model of ALS: Human ALS-associated mutation in VAP33A suggests a dominant negative mechanism. PLoS One, 3, e2334.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakuma, C., Anzo, M., Miura, M., &amp; Chihara, T. (2014). Development of olfactory projection neuron dendrites that contribute to wiring specificity of the Drosophila olfactory circuit. Genes &amp; Genetic Systems, 89, 17-26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stowers, R. S., Megeath, L. J., G&#xf3;rska-Andrzejak, J., Meinertzhagen, I. A., &amp; Schwarz, T. L. (2002). Axonal transport of mitochondria to synapses depends on Milton, a novel Drosophila protein. Neuron, 36, 1063-1077. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0896-6273(02)01094-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tran, D., Chalhoub, A., Schooley, A., Zhang, W., &amp; Ngsee, J. K. (2012). A mutation in VAPB that causes amyotrophic lateral sclerosis also causes a nuclear envelope defect. Journal of Cell Science, 125, 2831-2836. https://doi.org/10.1242/jcs.102111</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsuda, H., Han, S. M., Yang, Y., Tong, C., Lin, Y. Q., Mohan, K., Haueter, C., Zoghbi, A., Harati, Y., Kwan, J., Miller, M. A., &amp; Bellen, H. J. (2008). The amyotrophic lateral sclerosis 8 Protein VAPB is cleaved, secreted, and acts as a ligand for Eph receptors. Cell, 133, 963-977. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2008.04.039</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Blitterswijk, M., van Es, M. A., Koppers, M., van Rheenen, W., Medic, J., Schelhaas, H. J., van der Kooi, A. J., de Visser, M., Veldink, J. H., &amp; van den Berg, L. H. (2012). VAPB and C9orf72 mutations in 1 familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patient. Neurobiology of Aging, 33, 2950.e1-2950.e4. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2012.07.004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viguera, C., Wang, J., Mosmiller, E., Cerezo, A., &amp; Maragakis, N. J. (2018). Olfactory dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Annals of Clinical and Translational Neurology, 5, 976-981. https://doi.org/10.1002/acn3.594</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye, B., Zhang, Y., Song, W., Younger, S. H., Jan, L. Y., &amp; Jan, Y. N. (2007). Growing dendrites and axons differ in their reliance on the secretory pathway. Cell, 130, 717-729. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2007.06.032</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>