<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">33548116</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>26</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1742-4658</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>288</Volume><Issue>15</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The FEBS journal</Title><ISOAbbreviation>FEBS J</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A glaucoma- and ALS-associated mutant of OPTN induces neuronal cell death dependent on Tbk1 activity, autophagy and ER stress.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>4576</StartPage><EndPage>4595</EndPage><MedlinePgn>4576-4595</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/febs.15752</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Mutations in OPTN are associated with glaucoma, an eye disease, and also with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS), a motor neuron disease. A 2-bp insertion in OPTN (691_692insAG or 2bpIns-OPTN) is associated with both glaucoma and ALS. This mutation results in frame shift after 127 amino acids, giving rise to a protein with C-terminal aberrant sequence. We have explored the mechanism of induction of cell death by this mutant in a motor neuron cell line, NSC-34, and also in a retinal cell line, 661W. Compared to wild-type OPTN, this mutant induced more cell death in NSC-34 and 661W cells. This mutant localizes predominantly in the nucleus whereas normal OPTN localizes in the cytoplasm. Deletion analysis of 2bpIns-OPTN showed that the aberrant sequence was not essential for cell death induction. This mutant interacts with TANK-binding kinase 1 (Tbk1) but not with OPTN and activates Tbk1. This mutant induced ER stress in NSC-34 cells as seen by induction of C/EBP homologous protein (CHOP) and some other genes. Induction of CHOP, autophagosomal protein LC3-II and cell death by this mutant were abrogated by Tbk1 knockdown and also by 4-phenylbutyric acid, that inhibits ER stress. Induction of CHOP and cell death by 2bpIns-OPTN was autophagy dependent as shown by the effect of Atg5 knockdown. This mutant caused increased formation of LC3-positive aggregates. Treatment of cells with autophagy inducer rapamycin reduced LC3-positive aggregates, CHOP and cell death induced by 2bpIns-OPTN. These results suggest that constitutive activation of Tbk1 by 2bpIns-OPTN leads to impaired autophagy that results in ER stress and cell death.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 Federation of European Biochemical Societies.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Medchalmi</LastName><ForeName>Swetha</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>CSIR-Centre for Cellular and Molecular Biology, Hyderabad, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tare</LastName><ForeName>Priyanka</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>CSIR-Centre for Cellular and Molecular Biology, Hyderabad, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sayyad</LastName><ForeName>Zuberwasim</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>CSIR-Centre for Cellular and Molecular Biology, Hyderabad, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Swarup</LastName><ForeName>Ghanshyam</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8098-0509</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>CSIR-Centre for Cellular and Molecular Biology, Hyderabad, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>FEBS J</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101229646</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1742-464X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C502778">ATG5 protein, human</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000071187">Autophagy-Related Protein 5</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D018797">Cell Cycle Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C497249">DDIT3 protein, human</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C502070">MAP1LC3B protein, human</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D026901">Membrane Transport Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D008869">Microtubule-Associated Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C409460">OPTN protein, human</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>147336-12-7</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D051742">Transcription Factor CHOP</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 2.7.11.1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D017346">Protein Serine-Threonine Kinases</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 2.7.11.1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C403191">TBK1 protein, human</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="Y">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017209" MajorTopicYN="Y">Apoptosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001343" MajorTopicYN="N">Autophagy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000071187" MajorTopicYN="N">Autophagy-Related Protein 5</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018797" MajorTopicYN="N">Cell Cycle Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="Y">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D059865" MajorTopicYN="N">Endoplasmic Reticulum Stress</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005901" MajorTopicYN="N">Glaucoma</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="Y">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057809" MajorTopicYN="N">HEK293 Cells</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D026901" MajorTopicYN="N">Membrane Transport Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="Y">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008869" MajorTopicYN="N">Microtubule-Associated Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009154" MajorTopicYN="Y">Mutation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009474" MajorTopicYN="N">Neurons</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011485" MajorTopicYN="N">Protein Binding</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017346" MajorTopicYN="N">Protein Serine-Threonine Kinases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051742" MajorTopicYN="N">Transcription Factor CHOP</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ER stress</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Tbk1</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">glaucoma</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">optineurin</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33548116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/febs.15752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Kachaner D, Genin P, Laplantine E &amp; Weil R (2012) Toward an integrative view of Optineurin functions. Cell Cycle 11, 2808-2818.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ying H &amp; Yue BY (2012) Cellular and molecular biology of optineurin. Int Rev Cell Mol Biol 294, 223-258.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minegishi Y, Nakayama M, Iejima D, Kawase K &amp; Iwata T (2016) Significance of optineurin mutations in glaucoma and other diseases. Prog Retinal Eye Res 55, 149-181.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Markovinovic A, Cimbro R, Ljutic T, Kriz J, Rogelj B &amp; Munitic I (2017) Optineurin in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: multifunctional adaptor protein at the crossroads of different neuroprotective mechanisms. Prog Neurogibol 154, 1-20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toth RP &amp; Atkin JD (2018) Dysfunction of optineurin in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and glaucoma. Front Immunol 9, 1017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swarup G &amp; Sayyad Z (2018) Altered functions and interactions of glaucoma-associated mutants of optineurin. Front Immunol 9, 1287.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Kang J &amp; Horwitz MS (1998) Interaction of an adenovirus E3 14.7-kilodalton protein with a novel tumor necrosis factor alpha-inducible cellular protein containing leucine zipper domains. Mol Cell Biol 18, 1601-1610.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rezaie T, Waitzman DM, Seeman JL, Kaufman PL &amp; Sarfarazi M (2005) Molecular cloning and expression profiling of optineurin in the rhesus monkey. Invest Ophthalmol Vis Sci 46, 2404-2410.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Marco N, Buono M, Troise F &amp; Diez-Roux G (2006) Optineurin increases cell survival and translocates to the nucleus in a Rab8-dependent manner upon an apoptotic stimulus. J Biol Chem 281, 16147-16156.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wild P, Farhan H, McEwan DG, Wagner S, Rogov VV, Brady NR, Richter B, Korac J, Waidmann O, Choudhary C et al. (2011) Phosphorylation of the autophagy receptor optineurin restricts Salmonella growth. Science 333, 228-233.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korac J, Schaeffer V, Kovacevic I, Clement AM, Jungblut B, Behl C, Terzic J &amp; Dikic I (2013) Ubiquitin-independent function of optineurin in autophagic clearance of protein aggregates. J Cell Sci 126, 580-592.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong YC &amp; Holzbaur EL (2014) Optineurin is an autophagy receptor for damaged mitochondria in parkin-mediated mitophagy that is disrupted by an ALS-linked mutation. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA 111, E4439-E4448.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bansal M, Moharir SC, Sailasree SP, Sirohi K, Sudhakar C, Sarathi DP, Lakshmi BJ, Buono M, Kumar S &amp; Swarup G (2018) Optineurin promotes autophagosome formation by recruiting the autophagy-related Atg12-5-16L1 complex to phagophores containing the Wipi2 protein. J Biol Chem 293, 132-147.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sirohi K, Kumari A, Radha V &amp; Swarup G (2015) A glaucoma-associated variant of optineurin, M98K, activates Tbk1 to enhance autophagosome formation and retinal cell death dependent on Ser177 phosphorylation of optineurin. PLoS One 10, e0138289.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rezaie T, Child A, Hitchings R, Brice G, Miller L, Coca-Prados M, Heon E, Krupin T, Ritch R, Kreutzer D et al. (2002) Adult-onset primary open-angle glaucoma caused by mutations in optineurin. Science 295, 1077-1079.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maruyama H, Morino H, Ito H, Izumi Y, Kato H, Watanabe Y, Kinoshita Y, Kamada M, Nodera H, Suzuki H et al. (2010) Mutations of optineurin in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nature 465, 223-226.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quigley HA &amp; Broman AT (2006) The number of people with glaucoma worldwide in 2010 and 2020. Br J Ophthalmol 90, 262-267.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agudo-Barriuso M, Villegas-Perez MP, de Imperial JM &amp; Vidal-Sanz M (2013) Anatomical and functional damage in experimental glaucoma. Curr Opin Pharmacol 13, 5-11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi SS, Zawadzki RJ, Lim MC, Brandt JD, Keltner JL, Doble N &amp; Werner JS (2011) Evidence of outer retinal changes in glaucoma patients as revealed by ultrahigh-resolution in vivo retinal imaging. Br J Ophthalmol 95, 131-141.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Millecamps S, Boillee S, Chabrol E, Camu W, Cazeneuve C, Salachas F, Pradat PF, Danel-Brunaud V, Vandenberghe N, Corcia P et al. (2011) Screening of OPTN in French familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurobiol Aging 32, e11-e13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldstein O, Nayshool O, Nefussy B, Traynor BJ, Renton AE, Gana-Weisz M, Drory VE &amp; Orr-Urtreger A (2016) OPTN 691_692insAG is a founder mutation causing recessive ALS and increased risk in heterozygotes. Neurology 86, 446-453.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weishaupt JH, Waibel S, Birve A, Volk AE, Mayer B, Meyer T, Ludolph AC &amp; Andersen PM (2013) A novel optineurin truncating mutation and three glaucoma-associated missense variants in patients with familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in Germany. Neurobiol Aging 34, 1516.e9-1516.e15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turturro S, Shen X, Shyam R, Yue BY &amp; Ying H (2014) Effects of mutations and deletions in the human optineurin gene. Springerplus 3, 99.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atkin JD, Farg MA, Walker AK, McLean C, Tomas D &amp; Horne MK (2008) Endoplasmic reticulum stress and induction of the unfolded protein response in human sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurobiol Dis 30, 400-407.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen S, Zhang X, Song L &amp; Le W (2012) Autophagy dysregulation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain Pathol 22, 110-116.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sundaramoorthy V, Walker AK, Yerbury J, Soo KY, Farg MA, Hoang V, Zeineddine R, Spencer D &amp; Atkin JD (2013) Extracellular wildtype and mutant SOD1 induces ER-Golgi pathology characteristic of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in neuronal cells. Cell Mol Life Sci 70, 4181-4195.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atkin JD, Farg MA, Soo KY, Walker AK, Halloran M, Turner BJ, Nagley P &amp; Horne MK (2014) Mutant SOD1 inhibits ER-Golgi transport in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurochem 129, 190-204.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai Y, Arikkath J, Yang L, Guo ML, Periyasamy P &amp; Buch S (2016) Interplay of endoplasmic reticulum stress and autophagy in neurodegenerative disorders. Autophagy 12, 225-244.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almanza A, Carlesso A, Chintha C, Creedican S, Doultsinos D, Leuzzi B, Lu&#xed;s A, McCarthy N, Montibeller L, More S et al. (2019) Endoplasmic reticulum stress signalling - from basic mechanisms to clinical applications. FEBS J 286, 241-278.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sundaramoorthy V, Walker AK, Tan V, Fifita JA, McCann EP, Williams KL, Blair IP, Guillemin GJ, Farg MA &amp; Atkin JD (2015) Defects in optineurin- and myosin VI-mediated cellular trafficking in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Hum Mol Genet 24, 3830-3846.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inagaki S, Kawase K, Funato M, Seki J, Kawase C, Ohuchi K, Kameyama T, Ando S, Sato A, Morozumi W et al. (2018) Effect of timolol on optineurin aggregation in transformed induced pluripotent stem cells derived from patient with familial glaucoma. Invest Ophthalmol Vis Sci 59, 2293-2304.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cashman NR, Durham HD, Blusztajn JK, Oda K, Tabira T, Shaw IT, Dahrouge S &amp; Antel JP (1992) Neuroblastoma x spinal cord (NSC) hybrid cell lines resemble developing motor neurons. Dev Dyn 194, 209-221.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sayyad Z, Sirohi K, Radha V &amp; Swarup G (2017) 661W is a retinal ganglion precursor-like cell line in which glaucoma-associated optineurin mutants induce cell death selectively. Sci Rep 7, 16855.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lange A, Mills RE, Lange CJ, Stewart M, Devine SE &amp; Corbett AH (2007) Classical nuclear localization signals: definition, function, and interaction with importin alpha. J Biol Chem 282, 5101-5105.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morton S, Hesson L, Peggie M &amp; Cohen P (2008) Enhanced binding of TBK1 by an optineurin mutant that causes a familial form of primary open angle glaucoma. FEBS Lett 582, 997-1002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis LK, Meyer KJ, Schindler EI, Beck JS, Rudd DS, Grundstad AJ, Scheetz TE, Braun TA, Fingert JH, Alward WL et al. (2011) Copy number variations and primary open-angle glaucoma. Invest Ophthalmol Vis Sci 52, 7122-7133.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cirulli ET, Lasseigne BN, Petrovski S, Sapp PC, Dion PA, Leblond CS, Couthouis J, Lu YF, Wang Q, Krueger BJ et al. (2015) Exome sequencing in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis identifies risk genes and pathways. Science 347, 1436-1441.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freischmidt A, Wieland T, Richter B, Ruf W, Schaeffer V, Muller K, Marroquin N, Nordin F, Hubers A, Weydt P et al. (2015) Haploinsufficiency of TBK1 causes familial ALS and fronto-temporal dementia. Nat Neurosci 18, 631-636.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fingert JH, Miller K, Hedberg-Buenz A, Roos BR, Lewis CJ, Mullins RF &amp; Anderson MG (2017) Transgenic TBK1 mice have features of normal tension glaucoma. Hum Mol Genet 26, 124-132.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye J, Cheung J, Gerbino V, Ahls&#xe9;n G, Zimanyi C, Hirsh D &amp; Maniatis T (2019) Effects of ALS-associated TANK binding kinase 1 mutations on protein-protein interactions and kinase activity. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA 116, 24517-24526.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pozzi L, Valenza F, Mosca L, Dal Mas A, Domi T, Romano A, Tarlarini C, Falzone YM, Tremolizzo L, Sorar&#xf9; G et al. (2017) TBK1 mutations in Italian patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: genetic and functional characterisation. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 88, 869-875.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao P, Wong KI, Sun X, Reilly SM, Uhm M, Liao Z, Skorobogatko Y &amp; Saltiel AR (2018) TBK1 at the crossroads of inflammation and energy homeostasis in adipose tissue. Cell 172, 731-743.e12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russell RC, Tian Y, Yuan H, Park HW, Chang YY, Kim J, Kim H, Neufeld TP, Dillin A &amp; Guan KL (2013) ULK1 induces autophagy by phosphorylating Beclin-1 and activating VPS34 lipid kinase. Nat Cell Biol 15, 741-750.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghislat G, Patron M, Rizzuto R &amp; Knecht E (2012) Withdrawal of essential amino acids increases autophagy by a pathway involving Ca2+/calmodulin-dependent kinase kinase-beta (CaMKK-beta). J Biol Chem 287, 38625-38636.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pourcelot M, Zemirli N, Silva Da Costa L, Loyant R, Garcin D, Vitour D, Munitic I, Vazquez A &amp; Arnoult D (2016) The Golgi apparatus acts as a platform for TBK1 activation after viral RNA sensing. BMC Biol 14, 69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iurlaro R &amp; Munoz-Pinedo C (2016) Cell death induced by endoplasmic reticulum stress. FEBS J 283, 2640-2652.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sirohi K, Chalasani ML, Sudhakar C, Kumari A, Radha V &amp; Swarup G (2013) M98K-OPTN induces transferrin receptor degradation and RAB12-mediated autophagic death in retinal ganglion cells. Autophagy 9, 510-527.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chalasani ML, Kumari A, Radha V &amp; Swarup G (2014) E50K-OPTN-induced retinal cell death involves the Rab GTPase-activating protein, TBC1D17 mediated block in autophagy. PLoS One 9, e95758.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lamb CA, Yoshimori T &amp; Tooze SA (2013) The autophagosome: origins unknown, biogenesis complex. Nat Rev Mol Cell Biol 14, 759-774.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weil R, Laplantine E &amp; Genin P (2016) Regulation of TBK1 activity by Optineurin contributes to cell cycle-dependent expression of the interferon pathway. Cytokine Growth Factor Rev 29, 23-33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vargas JNS, Wang C, Bunker E, Hao L, Maric D, Schiavo G, Randow F &amp; Youle RJ (2019) Spatiotemporal control of ULK1 activation by NDP52 and TBK1 during selective autophagy. Mol Cell 74, 347-362.e6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sippl C, Bosserhoff AK, Fischer D &amp; Tamm ER (2011) Depletion of optineurin in RGC-5 cells derived from retinal neurons causes apoptosis and reduces the secretion of neurotrophins. Exp Eye Res 93, 669-680.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akizuki M, Yamashita H, Uemura K, Maruyama H, Kawakami H, Ito H &amp; Takahashi R (2013) Optineurin suppression causes neuronal cell death via NF-kappaB pathway. J Neurochem 126, 699-704.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen WC, Li HY, Chen GC, Chern Y &amp; Tu PH (2015) Mutations in the ubiquitin-binding domain of OPTN/optineurin interfere with autophagy-mediated degradation of misfolded proteins by a dominant-negative mechanism. Autophagy 11, 685-700.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moharir SC, Bansal M, Ramachandran G, Ramaswamy R, Rawat S, Raychaudhuri S &amp; Swarup G (2018) Identification of a splice variant of optineurin which is defective in autophagy and phosphorylation. Biochim Biophys Acta Mol Cell Res 1865, 1526-1538.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raghawan AK, Sripada A, Gopinath G, Pushpanjali P, Kumar Y, Radha V &amp; Swarup G (2017) A disease-associated mutant of NLRC4 shows enhanced interaction with SUG1 leading to constitutive FADD-dependent caspase-8 activation and cell death. J Biol Chem 292, 1218-1230.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radha V, Nambirajan S &amp; Swarup G (1994) Subcellular localization of a protein-tyrosine phosphatase: evidence for association with chromatin. Biochem J 299 (Pt 1), 41-47.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>