<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">33545308</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>08</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1873-2747</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>170</Volume><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>May</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Brain research bulletin</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Brain Res Bull</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Detection of endothelial cell-associated human DNA reveals transplanted human bone marrow stem cell engraftment into CNS capillaries of ALS mice.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>22</StartPage><EndPage>28</EndPage><MedlinePgn>22-28</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.brainresbull.2021.01.020</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0361-9230(21)00033-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Repairing the altered blood-CNS-barrier in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) is imperative to prevent entry of detrimental blood-borne substances into the CNS. Cell transplantation with the goal of replacing damaged endothelial cells (ECs) may be a new therapeutic approach for barrier restoration. We showed positive effects of human bone marrow-derived CD34+ cells (hBM34+) and endothelial progenitor cells (hBM-EPCs) intravenous transplantation into symptomatic G93A SOD1 mutant mice on barrier reparative processes. These benefits mainly occurred by administered cells engraftment into vascular walls in ALS mice; however, additional studies are needed to confirm cell engraftment within capillaries. The aim of this investigation was to determine the presence of human DNA within microvascular ECs isolated from the CNS tissues of G93A SOD1 mutant mice treated with human bone marrow-derived stem cells. The CNS tissues were obtained from previously cell-treated and media-treated G93A mice at 17 weeks of age. Real-time PCR (RT-PCR) assay for detection of human DNA was performed in ECs isolated from mouse CNS tissue. Viability of these ECs was determined using the LIVE/DEAD viability/cytotoxicity assay. Results showed appropriate EC isolation as verified by immunoexpression of endothelial cell marker. Human DNA was detected in isolated ECs from cell-treated mice with greater concentrations in mice receiving hBM-EPCs vs. hBM34<sup>+</sup> cells. Also, higher numbers of live ECs were determined in mice treated with hBM-EPCs vs. hBM34<sup>+</sup> cells or media-injection. Results revealed that transplanted human cells engrafted into mouse capillary walls and efficaciously maintained endothelium function. These study results support our previous findings showing that intravenous administration of hBM-EPCs into symptomatic ALS mice was more beneficial than hBM34<sup>+</sup> cell treatment in repair of barrier integrity, likely due to replacement of damaged ECs in mouse CNS vessels. Based on this evidence, hBM-EPCs may be advanced as a cell-specific approach for ALS therapy through restored CNS barrier integrity.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2021 Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Garbuzova-Davis</LastName><ForeName>Svitlana</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center of Excellence for Aging and Brain Repair, University of South Florida, Morsani College of Medicine, Tampa, FL, United States; Department of Neurosurgery and Brain Repair, University of South Florida, Morsani College of Medicine, Tampa, FL, United States; Department of Molecular Pharmacology and Physiology, University of South Florida, Morsani College of Medicine, Tampa, FL, United States; Department of Pathology and Cell Biology, University of South Florida, Morsani College of Medicine, Tampa, FL, United States. Electronic address: sgarbuzo@usf.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Boccio</LastName><ForeName>Kayla J</ForeName><Initials>KJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center of Excellence for Aging and Brain Repair, University of South Florida, Morsani College of Medicine, Tampa, FL, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ehrhart</LastName><ForeName>Jared</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center of Excellence for Aging and Brain Repair, University of South Florida, Morsani College of Medicine, Tampa, FL, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sanberg</LastName><ForeName>Paul R</ForeName><Initials>PR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center of Excellence for Aging and Brain Repair, University of South Florida, Morsani College of Medicine, Tampa, FL, United States; Department of Neurosurgery and Brain Repair, University of South Florida, Morsani College of Medicine, Tampa, FL, United States; Department of Pathology and Cell Biology, University of South Florida, Morsani College of Medicine, Tampa, FL, United States; Department of Psychiatry, University of South Florida, Morsani College of Medicine, Tampa, FL, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Appel</LastName><ForeName>Stanley H</ForeName><Initials>SH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Stanley H. Appel Department of Neurology, Houston Methodist Neurological Institute, Houston, TX, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Borlongan</LastName><ForeName>Cesario V</ForeName><Initials>CV</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center of Excellence for Aging and Brain Repair, University of South Florida, Morsani College of Medicine, Tampa, FL, United States; Department of Neurosurgery and Brain Repair, University of South Florida, Morsani College of Medicine, Tampa, FL, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R01 NS090962</GrantID><Acronym>NS</Acronym><Agency>NINDS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Brain Res Bull</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7605818</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0361-9230</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 1.15.1.1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D013482">Superoxide Dismutase</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004195" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Models, Animal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D042783" MajorTopicYN="N">Endothelial Cells</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D059630" MajorTopicYN="N">Mesenchymal Stem Cells</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051379" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008822" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice, Transgenic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009046" MajorTopicYN="N">Motor Neurons</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013116" MajorTopicYN="N">Spinal Cord</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013482" MajorTopicYN="N">Superoxide Dismutase</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ALS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Blood-CNS-barrier</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Endothelial cells</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">G93A SOD1 mice</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Human bone marrow-derived stem cells</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">LIVE/DEAD viability/cytotoxicity assay</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Real-time PCR</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Repair</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations of Interest: none</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33545308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS1672392</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7990719</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.brainresbull.2021.01.020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0361-9230(21)00033-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Cleveland DW, Rothstein JD, 2001. From Charcot to Lou Gehrig: deciphering selective motor neuron death in ALS. Nat. Rev. Neurosci 2, 806&#x2013;819. 10.1038/35097565</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/35097565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11715057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ehrhart J, Sanberg PR, Garbuzova-Davis S, 2018. Plasma derived from human umbilical cord blood: Potential cell-additive or cell-substitute therapeutic for neurodegenerative diseases. J. Cell. Mol. Med 22, 6157&#x2013;6166. 10.1111/jcmm.13898</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jcmm.13898</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6237605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30334335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ehrhart J, Smith AJ, Kuzmin-Nichols N, Zesiewicz TA, Jahan L, Shytle RD, Kim S-H, Sanberg CD, Vu TH, Gooch CL, Sanberg PR, Garbuzova-Davis S, 2015. Humoral factors in ALS patients during disease progression. J. Neuroinflammation 12, 127. 10.1186/s12974-015-0350-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12974-015-0350-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4487852</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26126965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eve DJ, Steiner G, Mahendrasah A, Sanberg PR, Kurien C, Thomson A, Borlongan CV, Garbuzova-Davis S, 2018. Reduction of microhemorrhages in the spinal cord of symptomatic ALS mice after intravenous human bone marrow stem cell transplantation accompanies repair of the blood-spinal cord barrier. Oncotarget 9, 10621&#x2013;10634. 10.18632/oncotarget.24360</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18632/oncotarget.24360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5828209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29535831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garbuzova-Davis S, Ehrhart J, Mustafa H, Llauget A, Boccio KJ, Sanberg PR, Appel SH, Borlongan CV, 2019a. Phenotypic characteristics of human bone marrow-derived endothelial progenitor cells in vitro support cell effectiveness for repair of the blood-spinal cord barrier in ALS. Brain Res. 1724, 146428. 10.1016/j.brainres.2019.146428</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.brainres.2019.146428</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6779528</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31493389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garbuzova-Davis S, Ehrhart J, Sanberg PR, Borlongan CV, 2018a. Potential role of humoral IL-6 cytokine in mediating pro-inflammatory endothelial cell response in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. Int. J. Mol. Sci 19. 10.3390/ijms19020423</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms19020423</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5855645</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29385088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garbuzova-Davis S, Haller E, Navarro S, Besong TE, Boccio KJ, Hailu S, Khatib M, Sanberg PR, Appel SH, Borlongan CV, 2018b. Transplantation of human bone marrow stem cells into symptomatic ALS mice enhances structural and functional blood-spinal cord barrier repair. Exp. Neurol 310, 33&#x2013;47. 10.1016/j.expneurol.2018.08.012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.expneurol.2018.08.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6203661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30172620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garbuzova-Davis S, Haller E, Saporta S, Kolomey I, Nicosia SV, Sanberg PR, 2007a. Ultrastructure of blood-brain barrier and blood-spinal cord barrier in SOD1 mice modeling ALS. Brain Res. 1157, 126&#x2013;137. 10.1016/j.brainres.2007.04.044</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.brainres.2007.04.044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17512910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garbuzova-Davis S, Hernandez-Ontiveros DG, Rodrigues MCO, Haller E, Frisina-Deyo A, Mirtyl S, Sallot S, Saporta S, Borlongan CV, Sanberg PR, 2012. Impaired blood-brain/spinal cord barrier in ALS patients. Brain Res. 1469, 114&#x2013;128. 10.1016/j.brainres.2012.05.056</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.brainres.2012.05.056</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22750125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garbuzova-Davis S, Kurien C, Haller E, Eve DJ, Navarro S, Steiner G, Mahendrasah A, Hailu S, Khatib M, Boccio KJ, Borlongan CV, Van Loveren HR, Appel SH, Sanberg PR, 2019b. Human bone marrow endothelial progenitor cell transplantation into symptomatic ALS mice delays disease progression and increases motor neuron survival by repairing blood-spinal cord barrier. Sci. Rep 9, 5280. 10.1038/s41598-019-41747-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-019-41747-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6437219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30918315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garbuzova-Davis S, Kurien C, Thomson A, Falco D, Ahmad S, Staffetti J, Steiner G, Abraham S, James G, Mahendrasah A, Sanberg PR, Borlongan CV, 2017. Endothelial and astrocytic support by human bone marrow stem cell grafts into symptomatic ALS mice towards blood-spinal cord barrier repair. Sci. Rep 7, 884. 10.1038/s41598-017-00993-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-017-00993-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5429840</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28408761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garbuzova-Davis S, Rodrigues MCO, Hernandez-Ontiveros DG, Louis MK, Willing AE, Borlongan CV, Sanberg PR, 2011. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a neurovascular disease. Brain Res. 1398, 113&#x2013;125. 10.1016/j.brainres.2011.04.049</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.brainres.2011.04.049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21632035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garbuzova-Davis S, Sanberg PR, 2014. Blood-CNS barrier impairment in ALS patients versus an animal model. Front. Cell. Neurosci 8, 21. 10.3389/fincel.2014.00021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fincel.2014.00021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3910123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24550780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garbuzova-Davis S, Saporta S, Haller E, Kolomey I, Bennett SP, Potter H, Sanberg PR, 2007b. Evidence of compromised blood-spinal cord barrier in early and late symptomatic SOD1 mice modeling ALS. PLoS ONE 2, e1205. 10.1371/journal.pone.0001205</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0001205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2075163</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18030339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garbuzova-Davis S, Thomson A, Kurien C, Shytle RD, Sanberg PR, 2016. Potential new complication in drug therapy development for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Expert Rev Neurother 16, 1397&#x2013;1405. 10.1080/14737175.2016.1207530</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14737175.2016.1207530</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5164916</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27362330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ge S, Pachter JS, 2006. Isolation and culture of microvascular endothelial cells from murine spinal cord. J. Neuroimmunol. 177, 209&#x2013;214. 10.1016/j.jneuroim.2006.05.012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jneuroim.2006.05.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16806499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henkel JS, Beers DR, Wen S, Bowser R, Appel SH, 2009. Decreased mRNA expression of tight junction proteins in lumbar spinal cords of patients with ALS. Neurology 72, 1614&#x2013;1616. 10.1212/WNL.0b013e3181a41228</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0b013e3181a41228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19414730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu Y, Cao C, Qin X-Y, Yu Y, Yuan J, Zhao Y, Cheng Y, 2017. Increased peripheral blood inflammatory cytokine levels in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a meta-analysis study. Sci. Rep. 7, 9094. 10.1038/s41598-017-09097-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-017-09097-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5567306</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28831083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeyachandran A, Mertens B, McKissick EA, Mitchell CS, 2015. Type I Vs. Type II Cytokine Levels as a Function of SOD1 G93A Mouse Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Disease Progression. Front. Cell. Neurosci 9, 462. 10.3389/fncel.2015.00462</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fncel.2015.00462</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4664727</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26648846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kakaroubas N, Brennan S, Keon M, Saksena NK, 2019. Pathomechanisms of blood-brain barrier disruption in ALS. Neurosci J 2019, 2537698. 10.1155/2019/2537698</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2019/2537698</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6652091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31380411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiernan MC, Vucic S, Cheah BC, Turner MR, Eisen A, Hardiman O, Burrell JR, Zoing MC, 2011. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet 377, 942&#x2013;955. 10.1016/S0140-6736(10)61156-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(10)61156-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21296405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lam L, Chin L, Haider RC, Sagong B, Famenini S, Sayre J, Montoya D, Rubbi L, Pellegrini M, Fiala M, 2016. Epigenetic changes in T-cell and monocyte signatures and production of neurotoxic cytokines in ALS patients. FASEB J. 30, 3461&#x2013;3473. 10.1096/fj.201600259RR</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1096/fj.201600259RR</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5024692</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27368295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lomen-Hoerth C, 2008. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis from bench to bedside. Seminars in neurology 28, 205&#x2013;211. 10.1055/s-2008-1062265</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-2008-1062265</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18351522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin LJ, Price AC, Kaiser A, Shaikh AY, Liu Z, 2000. Mechanisms for neuronal degeneration in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and in models of motor neuron death (Review). Int. J. Mol. Med 5, 3&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10601567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McBride C, Gaupp D, Phinney DG, 2003. Quantifying levels of transplanted murine and human mesenchymal stem cells in vivo by real-time PCR. Cytotherapy 5, 7&#x2013;18. 10.1080/14653240310000038</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14653240310000038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12745583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyazaki K, Ohta Y, Nagai M, Morimoto N, Kurata T, Takehisa Y, Ikeda Y, Matsuura T, Abe K, 2011. Disruption of neurovascular unit prior to motor neuron degeneration in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J. Neurosci. Res 89, 718&#x2013;728. 10.1002/jnr.22594</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jnr.22594</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21337372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreno-Mart&#xed;nez L, de la Torre M, Toivonen JM, Zaragoza P, Garc&#xed;a-Redondo A, Calvo AC, Osta R, 2019. Circulating Cytokines Could Not Be Good Prognostic Biomarkers in a Mouse Model of Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. Front. Immunol 10, 801. 10.3389/fimmu.2019.00801</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2019.00801</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6473074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31031774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicaise C, Mitrecic D, Demetter P, De Decker R, Authelet M, Boom A, Pochet R, 2009. Impaired blood-brain and blood-spinal cord barriers in mutant SOD1-linked ALS rat. Brain Res. 1301, 152&#x2013;162. 10.1016/j.brainres.2009.09.018</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.brainres.2009.09.018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19748495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodrigues MCO, Hernandez-Ontiveros DG, Louis MK, Willing AE, Borlongan CV, Sanberg PR, Voltarelli JC, Garbuzova-Davis S, 2012. Neurovascular aspects of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Int. Rev. Neurobiol 102, 91&#x2013;106. 10.1016/B978-0-12-386986-9.00004-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/B978-0-12-386986-9.00004-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22748827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rothstein JD, 2009. Current hypotheses for the underlying biology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann. Neurol 65 Suppl 1, S3&#x2013;9. 10.1002/ana.21543</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.21543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19191304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sasaki S, 2015. Alterations of the blood-spinal cord barrier in sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuropathology 35, 518&#x2013;528. 10.1111/neup.12221</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/neup.12221</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26242689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song L, Pachter JS, 2003. Culture of murine brain microvascular endothelial cells that maintain expression and cytoskeletal association of tight junction-associated proteins. In Vitro Cell. Dev. Biol. Anim. 39, 313&#x2013;320. 10.1290/1543-706X(2003)039&lt;0313:COMBME&gt;2.0.CO;2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1290/1543-706X(2003)039&lt;0313:COMBME&gt;2.0.CO;2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14613336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strong MJ, Kesavapany S, Pant HC, 2005. The pathobiology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a proteinopathy? J. Neuropathol. Exp. Neurol 64, 649&#x2013;664.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16106213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Talbot K, 2009. Motor neuron disease: the bare essentials. Pract. Neurol 9, 303&#x2013;309. 10.1136/jnnp.2009.188151</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp.2009.188151</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19762894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wijesekera LC, Leigh PN, 2009. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Orphanet J. Rare Dis 4, 3. 10.1186/1750-1172-4-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1750-1172-4-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2656493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19192301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winkler EA, Sengillo JD, Sullivan JS, Henkel JS, Appel SH, Zlokovic BV, 2013. Blood-spinal cord barrier breakdown and pericyte reductions in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathol. 125, 111&#x2013;120. 10.1007/s00401-012-1039-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00401-012-1039-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3535352</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22941226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhong Z, Deane R, Ali Z, Parisi M, Shapovalov Y, O&#x2019;Banion MK, Stojanovic K, Sagare A, Boillee S, Cleveland DW, Zlokovic BV, 2008. ALS-causing SOD1 mutants generate vascular changes prior to motor neuron degeneration. Nat. Neurosci 11, 420&#x2013;422. 10.1038/nn2073</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nn2073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2895310</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18344992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>