<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">33555628</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>28</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2702</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>30</Volume><Issue>13-14</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of clinical nursing</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Clin Nurs</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Coping in people with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and motor neuron disease: Systematic review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1838</StartPage><EndPage>1853</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1838-1853</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/jocn.15692</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="AIMS AND OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To systematically review previous studies on the variables associated with coping strategies in people with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and motor neuron disease (ALS/MND), such as demographics, clinical features and patient-reported outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Coping strategies are important factors for adjustment and quality of life (QOL) in patients with long-term conditions, and this topic in people with ALS/MND has not yet been the subject of a systematic review.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DESIGN" NlmCategory="METHODS">A systematic review was performed based on the PRISMA checklist.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Electronic databases, including CINAHL, MEDLINE and EMBASE, were systemically searched from their inception to December 2019 for articles meeting the following inclusion criteria: (1) written in English, (2) published in peer-reviewed journals, (3) included subjects with ALS/MND and (4) used quantitative measurements of coping strategies in people with ALS/MND.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Twenty-one articles were included. Significant relationships between participants' demographics (age and sex) and any coping strategy aspect were shown in six studies. Eight studies found significant relationships between clinical characteristics (disease duration and physical functional status) and coping strategies, and ten studies reported coping strategies that were associated with patients' QOL and mental health outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Younger people used relatively more problem-focused, emotion-focused and social support coping strategies, and women used relatively more social support coping strategies. Problem-focused coping was generally related to better QOL and mental health, and emotion-focused coping was generally related to less depression.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RELEVANCE TO CLINICAL PRACTICE" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">As the pattern of coping strategies is related to demographic and clinical characteristics, this study could be used to inform the provision of patient-centred nursing in clinical care. Coping patterns are related to mental health and QOL; thus, in clinical care, it is recommended that people with ALS be encouraged to develop skills that enable them to cope more effectively and that their coping strategies be assessed.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oh</LastName><ForeName>Juyeon</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6800-1320</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Nursing, Dankook University, Cheonan-si, South Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>An</LastName><ForeName>Jiwon</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5753-2281</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nursing, Far East University, Eumseong-gun, South Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Park</LastName><ForeName>Kyongok</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5222-1927</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nursing, Gangneung-Wonju National University, Wonju-si, South Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>Dankook University in 2020</GrantID><Agency>Dankook University</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Clin Nurs</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9207302</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0962-1067</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000223" MajorTopicYN="N">Adaptation, Psychological</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016472" MajorTopicYN="Y">Motor Neuron Disease</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012944" MajorTopicYN="N">Social Support</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anxiety</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">coping skills</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">depression</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">motor neuron disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">quality of life</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33555628</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jocn.15692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Abramson, N. (1996). Quality of life: Who can make the judgment? American Journal of Medicine, 100(3), 365-366. https://doi.org/10.1016/s0002-9343(97)89497-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Achille, M. A., &amp; Ogloff, J. R. (2003). Attitudes toward and desire for assisted suicide among persons with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Journal of Death and Dying, 48(1), 1-21. https://doi.org/10.2190/G5TA-9KV0-MT3G-RWM0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aldwin, C. M., &amp; Revenson, T. A. (1987). Does coping help? A reexamination of the relation between coping and mental health. Journal of Personality and Social Psychology, 53(2), 337-348. https://doi.org/10.1037//0022-3514.53.2.337</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benedetti, F. (2011). The patient's brain: The neuroscience behind the doctor-patient relationship. Oxford University Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bungener, C., Piquard, A., Pradat, P. F., Salachas, F., Meininger, V., &amp; Lacomblez, L. (2005). Psychopathology in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a preliminary study with 27 ALS patients. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis and Other Motor Neuron Disorders, 6(4), 221-225. https://doi.org/10.1080/14660820510037863.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carver, C. S., Scheier, M. F., &amp; Weintraub, J. K. (1989). Assessing coping strategies: A theoretically based approach. Journal of Personality and Social Psychology, 56(2), 267-283. https://doi.org/10.1037//0022-3514.56.2.267</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2;, A., Logroscino, G., Hardiman, O., Swingler, R., Mitchell, D., Beghi, E., Traynor, B. G., &amp; On Behalf of the Eurals Consortium (2009). Prognostic factors in ALS: A critical review. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis, 10(5-6), 310-323. https://doi.org/10.3109/17482960802566824</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clarke, D. M., McLeod, J. E., Smith, G. C., Trauer, T., &amp; Kissane, D. W. (2005). A comparison of psychosocial and physical functioning in patients with motor neurone disease and metastatic cancer. Journal of Palliative Care, 21(3), 173-179. https://doi.org/10.1177/082585970502100310.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coping. (n.d.). In Wikipedia. Retrieved from https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coping. August 15, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Creemers, H., de Moree, S., Veldink, J. H., Nollet, F., van den Berg, L. H., &amp; Beelen, A. (2016). Factors related to caregiver strain in ALS: a longitudinal study. Journal of Neurology, Neurosurgery &amp; Psychiatry, 87(7), 775-781. https://doi.org/10.1136/jnnp-2015-311651</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Wit, J., Bakker, L. A., van Groenestijn, A. C., van den Berg, L. H., Schr&#xf6;der, C. D., Visser-Meily, J. M. A., &amp; Beelen, A. (2018). Caregiver burden in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A systematic review. Palliative Medicine, 32(1), 231-245. https://doi.org/10.1177/0269216317709965</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Felgoise, S. H., Feinberg, R., Stephens, H. E., Barkhaus, P., Boylan, K., Caress, J., Clawson, L. L., Elman, L., Goutman, S. A., Mccluskey, L., Russell, J., Tiryaki, E., Weiss, M., &amp; Simmons, Z. (2018). Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-specific quality of life-short form (ALSSQOL-SF): A brief, reliable, and valid version of the ALSSQOL-R. Muscle &amp; Nerve, 58(5), 646-654. https://doi.org/10.1002/mus.26203</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Felton, B. J., &amp; Revenson, T. A. (1987). Age differences in coping with chronic illness. Psychology and Aging, 2(2), 164-170. https://doi.org/10.1037//0882-7974.2.2.164</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibbons, C., Thornton, E., Ealing, J., Shaw, P., Talbot, K., Tennant, A., &amp; Young, C. (2013). The impact of fatigue and psychosocial variables on quality of life for patients with motor neuron disease. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis and Frontotemporal Degeneration, 14(7-8), 537-545. https://doi.org/10.3109/21678421.2013.799700</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldstein, L. H., Adamson, M., Jeffrey, L., Down, K., Barby, T., Wilson, C., &amp; Leigh, P. N. (1998). The psychological impact of MND on patients and carers. Journal of the Neurological Sciences, 160(Suppl 1), S114-121. https://doi.org/10.1016/s0022-510x(98)00209-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hack, T. F., &amp; Degner, L. F. (2004). Coping responses following breast cancer diagnosis predict psychological adjustment three years later. Psycho-Oncology: Journal of the Psychological, Social and Behavioral Dimensions of Cancer, 13(4), 235-247.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hecht, M., Hillemacher, T., Gr&#xe4;sel, E., Tigges, S., Winterholler, M., Heuss, D., Hilz, M.-J., &amp; Neund&#xf6;rfer, B. (2002). Subjective experience and coping in ALS. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis and Other Motor Neuron Disorders, 3(4), 225-231.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hogden, A., Foley, G., Henderson, R. D., James, N., &amp; Aoun, S. M. (2017). Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Improving care with a multidisciplinary approach. Journal of Multidisciplinary Healthcare, 10, 205-215. https://doi.org/10.2147/jmdh.S134992</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jakobsson Larsson, B., Nordin, K., Askmark, H., &amp; Nygren, I. (2014). Coping strategies among patients with newly diagnosed amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Journal of Clinical Nursing, 23(21-22), 3148-3155. https://doi.org/10.1111/jocn.12557</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jakobsson Larsson, B., Nordin, K., &amp; Nygren, I. (2016). Coping with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis; from diagnosis and during disease progression. Journal of the Neurological Sciences, 361, 235-242. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jns.2015.12.042</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiernan, M. C., Vucic, S., Cheah, B. C., Turner, M. R., Eisen, A., Hardiman, O., Burrell, J. R., &amp; Zoing, M. C. (2011). Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet, 377(9769), 942-955. https://doi.org/10.1016/s0140-6736(10)61156-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lazarus, R. S., &amp; Folkman, S. (1984). Stress, appraisal, and coping. Springer Publishing Company.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, J. N., Rigby, S. A., Burchardt, F., Thornton, E. W., Dougan, C., &amp; Young, C. A. (2001). Quality of life issues in motor neurone disease: The development and validation of a coping strategies questionnaire, the MND Coping Scale. Journal of the Neurological Sciences, 191(1-2), 79-85. https://doi.org/10.1016/s0022-510x(01)00619-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Litman, J. A. (2006). The COPE inventory: Dimensionality and relationships with approach-and avoidance-motives and positive and negative traits. Personality and Individual Differences, 41(2), 273-284.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maresca, G., Pranio, F., Naro, A., De Luca, R., Maggio, M. G., Scarcella, I., De Domenico, C., Bramanti, P., Conti Nibali, V., Portaro, S., &amp; Salvatore Calabr&#xf2;, R. (2019). Augmentative and alternative communication improves quality of life in the early stages of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Functional Neurology, 34(1), 35-43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matuz, T., Birbaumer, N., Hautzinger, M., &amp; Kubler, A. (2010). Coping with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: An integrative view. Journal of Neurology, Neurosurgery &amp; Psychiatry, 81(8), 893-898. https://doi.org/10.1136/jnnp.2009.201285</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matuz, T., Birbaumer, N., Hautzinger, M., &amp; K&#xfc;bler, A. (2015). Psychosocial adjustment to ALS: A longitudinal study. Frontiers in Psychology, 6, 1197. https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2015.01197</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moher, D., Liberati, A., Tetzlaff, J., &amp; Altman, D. G. (2009). The PRISMA Group. Preferred reporting items for systematic reviews and meta-analyses: The PRISMA statement. PLoS Med, 6(7), e1000097. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pmed.1000097</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montel, S., Albertini, L., Desnuelle, C., &amp; Spitz, E. (2012a). Evolution of quality of life, mental health, and coping strategies in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A pilot study. Journal of Palliative Medicine, 15(11), 1181-1184. https://doi.org/10.1089/jpm.2012.0162</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montel, S., Albertini, L., Desnuelle, C., &amp; Spitz, E. (2012b). The impact of active coping strategies on survival in ALS: The first pilot study. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis, 13(6), 599-601. https://doi.org/10.3109/17482968.2012.711835</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montel, S., Albertini, L., &amp; Spitz, E. (2012a). Coping strategies as related to medical and demographic data in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neurologica Scandinavica, 125(2), 136-141. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1600-0404.2011.01513.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montel, S., Albertini, L., &amp; Spitz, E. (2012b). Coping strategies in relation to quality of life in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle &amp; Nerve, 45(1), 131-134. https://doi.org/10.1002/mus.22270</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morris, N., Moghaddam, N., Tickle, A., &amp; Biswas, S. (2018). The relationship between coping style and psychological distress in people with head and neck cancer: A systematic review. Psychooncology, 27(3), 734-747. https://doi.org/10.1002/pon.4509</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ng, L., &amp; Khan, F. (2011). Identification of personal factors in motor neurone disease: a pilot study. Rehabilitation Research and Practice, 871237, https://doi.org/10.1155/2011/871237.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ng, L., Talman, P., &amp; Khan, F. (2011). Neuropsychological sequelae in motor neurone disease: outcomes of a peer support programme. International Journal of Therapy and Rehabilitation, 18(8), 429-437. https://doi.org/10.12968/ijtr.2011.18.8.429.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ng, L., Talman, P., &amp; Khan, F. (2012). Neuropsychological sequelae in motor neuron disease: Outcomes of a peer support (lifemoves) program. Neurorehabilitation and Neural Repair, 26(6), 710. https://doi.org/10.1177/1545968312449454</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh, J., &amp; Kim, J. A. (2017). Supportive care needs of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis/motor neuron disease and their caregivers: A scoping review. Journal of Clinical Nursing, 26(23-24), 4129-4152. https://doi.org/10.1111/jocn.13945</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh, J., Kim, S. H., &amp; Kim, J. A. (2019). Unmet supportive care needs mediate the relationship between functional status and quality of life in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Palliative and Supportive Care, 17(6), 650-654. https://doi.org/10.1017/s1478951519000221</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rapkin, B. D., &amp; Schwartz, C. E. (2004). Toward a theoretical model of quality-of-life appraisal: Implications of findings from studies of response shift. Health and Quality of Life Outcomes, 2, 14. https://doi.org/10.1186/1477-7525-2-14</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schluter, D. K., Holland, D. P., Mills, R. J., McDermott, C. J., Williams, T. L., &amp; Young, C. A. (2019). Use of coping strategies in MND/ALS: Association with demographic and disease-related characteristics. Acta Neurologica Scandinavica, 140(2), 131-139. https://doi.org/10.1111/ane.13113</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simmons, Z. (2015). Patient-perceived outcomes and quality of life in ALS. Neurotherapeutics: the Journal of the American Society for Experimental NeuroTherapeutics, 12(2), 394-402. https://doi.org/10.1007/s13311-014-0322-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tamres, L. K., Janicki, D., &amp; Helgeson, V. S. (2002). Sex differences in coping behavior: A meta-analytic review and an examination of relative coping. Personality and Social Psychology Review, 6(1), 2-30. https://doi.org/10.1207/s15327957pspr0601_1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tramonti, F., Bongioanni, P., Fanciullacci, C., &amp; Rossi, B. (2012). Balancing between autonomy and support: coping strategies by patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Journal of the Neurological Sciences, 320(1-2), 106-109. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jns.2012.07.006</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Leeuwen, C. M., Kraaijeveld, S., Lindeman, E., &amp; Post, M. W. (2012). Associations between psychological factors and quality of life ratings in persons with spinal cord injury: A systematic review. Spinal Cord, 50(3), 174-187. https://doi.org/10.1038/sc.2011.120</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>V&#xe1;zquez Medrano, C. R., Aho-&#xd6;zhan, H. E. A., Weiland, U., Uttner, I., Ludolph, A. C., &amp; Lul&#xe9;, D. (2020). Disease progression but not physical state per se determines mental wellbeing in ALS. Journal of Neurology, 267(12), 3593-3601. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00415-020-10027-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wijesekera, L. C., &amp; Leigh, P. N. (2009). Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Orphanet Journal of Rare Diseases, 4, 3. https://doi.org/10.1186/1750-1172-4-3</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>