<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">33565111</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>26</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1531-8249</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>89</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>May</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Annals of neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Ann Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Diagnostic Utility of Gold Coast Criteria in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>979</StartPage><EndPage>986</EndPage><MedlinePgn>979-986</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/ana.26045</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">The diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) remains problematic, with current diagnostic criteria (revised El Escorial [rEEC] and Awaji) being complex and prone to error. Consequently, the diagnostic utility of the recently proposed Gold Coast criteria was determined in ALS.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">We retrospectively reviewed 506 patients (302 males, 204 females) to compare the diagnostic accuracy of the Gold Coast criteria to that of the Awaji and rEEC criteria (defined by the proportion of patients categorized as definite, probable, or possible ALS) in accordance with standards of reporting of diagnostic accuracy criteria.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">The sensitivity of Gold Coast criteria (92%, 95% confidence interval [CI] =&#x2009;88.7-94.6%) was comparable to that of Awaji (90.3%, 95% CI = 86.69-93.2%) and rEEC (88.6, 95% CI = 84.8-91.7%) criteria. Additionally, the Gold Coast criteria sensitivity was maintained across different subgroups, defined by site of onset, disease duration, and functional disability. In atypical ALS phenotypes, the Gold Coast criteria exhibited greater sensitivity and specificity.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="INTERPRETATION">The present study established the diagnostic utility of the Gold Coast criteria in ALS, with benefits evident in bulbar and limb onset disease patients, as well as atypical phenotypes. The Gold Coast criteria should be considered in clinical practice and therapeutic trials. ANN NEUROL 2021;89:979-986.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 American Neurological Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hannaford</LastName><ForeName>Andrew</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Westmead Clinical School, University of Sydney, Sydney, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pavey</LastName><ForeName>Nathan</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Westmead Clinical School, University of Sydney, Sydney, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>van den Bos</LastName><ForeName>Mehdi</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Westmead Clinical School, University of Sydney, Sydney, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Geevasinga</LastName><ForeName>Nimeshan</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Westmead Clinical School, University of Sydney, Sydney, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Menon</LastName><ForeName>Parvathi</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6935-5852</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Westmead Clinical School, University of Sydney, Sydney, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shefner</LastName><ForeName>Jeremy M</ForeName><Initials>JM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Barrow Neurological Institute, Phoenix, AZ, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kiernan</LastName><ForeName>Matthew C</ForeName><Initials>MC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9054-026X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Brain and Mind Center, University of Sydney, Sydney, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vucic</LastName><ForeName>Steve</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8323-873X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Westmead Clinical School, University of Sydney, Sydney, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D023361">Validation Study</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Ann Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7707449</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0364-5134</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="Y">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003937" MajorTopicYN="N">Diagnosis, Differential</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004185" MajorTopicYN="N">Disability Evaluation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004576" MajorTopicYN="N">Electromyography</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009431" MajorTopicYN="N">Neural Conduction</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009460" MajorTopicYN="N">Neurologic Examination</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012015" MajorTopicYN="N">Reference Standards</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015203" MajorTopicYN="N">Reproducibility of Results</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012680" MajorTopicYN="N">Sensitivity and Specificity</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33565111</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.26045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Kiernan MC, Vucic S, Cheah BC, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet 2011;377:942-955.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks B. El Escorial World Federation of Neurology criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Subcommittee on Motor Neuron Diseases/Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis of the World Federation of Neurology Research Group on Neuromuscular Diseases and the El Escorial "Clinical Limits of Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis" workshop contributors. J Neurol Sci 1994;124:96-107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks B, Miller R, Swash M, Munsat T. El Escorial revisited: revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord 2000;1:293-299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Dengler R, Eisen A, et al. Electrodiagnostic criteria for diagnosis of ALS. Clin Neurophysiol 2008;119:497-503.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chio A. ISIS survey: an international study on the diagnostic process and its implications in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol 1999;246:1-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner MR, Kiernan MC, Leigh PN, Talbot K. Biomarkers in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet Neurol 2009;8:94-109.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aggarwal S, Cudkowicz M. ALS drug development: reflections from the past and a way forward. Neurotherapeutics 2008;5:516-527.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Douglass CP, Kandler RH, Shaw PJ, McDermott CJ. An evaluation of neurophysiological criteria used in the diagnosis of motor neuron disease. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2010;81:646-649.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Swash M. Awaji diagnostic algorithm increases sensitivity of El Escorial criteria for ALS diagnosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler 2009;10:53-57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boekestein WA, Kleine BU, Hageman G, et al. Sensitivity and specificity of the 'Awaji' electrodiagnostic criteria for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: retrospective comparison of the Awaji and revised El Escorial criteria for ALS. Amyotroph Lateral Scler 2010;11:497-501.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schrooten M, Smetcoren C, Robberecht W, Van Damme P. Benefit of the Awaji diagnostic algorithm for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a prospective study. Ann Neurol 2011;70:79-83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa J, Swash M, de Carvalho M. Awaji criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis:a systematic review. Arch Neurol 2012;69:1410-1416.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okita T, Nodera H, Shibuta Y, et al. Can Awaji ALS criteria provide earlier diagnosis than the revised El Escorial criteria? J Neurol Sci 2011;302:29-32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen A, Weimer L, Brannagan T 3rd, et al. Experience with the Awaji Island modifications to the ALS diagnostic criteria. Muscle Nerve 2010;42:831-832.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krarup C. Lower motor neuron involvement examined by quantitative electromyography in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Neurophysiol 2011;122:414-422.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gawel M, Kuzma-Kozakiewicz M, Szmidt-Salkowska E, Kami&#x144;ska A. Are we really closer to improving the diagnostic sensitivity in ALS patients with Awaji criteria? Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2014;15:257-261.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higashihara M, Sonoo M, Imafuku I, et al. Fasciculation potentials in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and the diagnostic yield of the Awaji algorithm. Muscle Nerve 2012;45:175-182.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jang JS, Bae JS. Awaji criteria are not always superior to the previous criteria: a meta-analysis. Muscle Nerve 2015;51:822-829.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geevasinga N, Loy CT, Menon P, et al. Awaji criteria improves the diagnostic sensitivity in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a systematic review using individual patient data. Clin Neurophysiol 2016;127:2684-2691.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geevasinga N, Menon P, Scherman DB, et al. Diagnostic criteria in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a multicenter prospective study. Neurology 2016;87:684-690.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnsen B, Pugdahl K, Fuglsang-Frederiksen A, et al. Diagnostic criteria for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a multicentre study of inter-rater variation and sensitivity. Clin Neurophysiol 2019;130:307-314.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shefner JM, Al-Chalabi A, Baker MR, et al. A proposal for new diagnostic criteria for ALS. Clin Neurophysiol 2020;131:1975-1978.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum JM, Stambler N, Malta E, et al. The ALSFRS-R: a revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. BDNF ALS Study Group (Phase III). J Neurol Sci 1999;169:13-21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner M, Cagnin A, Turkheimer F, et al. Evidence of widespread cerebral microglial activation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: an [11C](R)-PK11195 positron emission tomography study. Neurobiol Dis 2004;15:601-609.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeng GT, Scott JR. Burmeister LF. A comparison of meta-analytic results using literature vs individual patient data: paternal cell immunization for recurrent miscarriage. JAMA 1995;274:830-836.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dharmadasa T, Henderson RD, Talman PS, et al. Motor neurone disease: progress and challenges. Med J Aust 2017;206:357-362.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aggarwal SP, Zinman L, Simpson E, et al. Safety and efficacy of lithium in combination with riluzole for treatment of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Lancet Neurol 2010;9:481-488.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cudkowicz M, Bozik ME, Ingersoll EW, et al. The effects of dexpramipexole (KNS-760704) in individuals with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat Med 2011;17:1652-1656.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Talman P, Duong T, Vucic S, et al. Identification and outcomes of clinical phenotypes in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis/motor neuron disease: Australian National Motor Neuron Disease observational cohort. BMJ Open 2016;6:e012054.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ludolph A, Drory V, Hardiman O, et al. A revision of the El Escorial criteria-2015. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2015;16:291-292.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner MR, Barohn RJ, Corcia P, et al. Primary lateral sclerosis: consensus diagnostic criteria. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2020;91:373-377.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swash M. Why are upper motor neuron signs difficult to elicit in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis? J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2012;83:659-662.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menon P, Geevasinga N, Yiannikas C, et al. The sensitivity and specificity of threshold-tracking transcranial magnetic stimulation for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a prospective study. Lancet Neurol 2015;14:478-484.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>