<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">33576026</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>10</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-4598</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>63</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>May</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Muscle &amp; nerve</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Muscle Nerve</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Diaphragmatic dysfunction at the first visit to a chest diseases outpatient clinic in 500 patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>683</StartPage><EndPage>689</EndPage><MedlinePgn>683-689</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/mus.27200</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION">In this study, we aimed to evaluate diaphragmatic dysfunction (DD) by using a practical approach in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) at the first visit to a chest diseases outpatient clinic.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Patients with ALS seen in our outpatient clinic for the past 5 y and followed up for at least 1 y, were retrospectively evaluated. Having at least one of the following three criteria was accepted as DD: (a) paradoxical abdominal movement (PAM), (b) sitting-supine forced vital capacity (FVC) difference&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;20%, (c) sitting-supine arterial oxygen saturation measured by pulse oximetry (SpO<sub>2</sub> ) difference&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;4%. Respiratory symptoms, arterial blood gas analysis, sleep studies, noninvasive mechanical ventilation use, and mortality were recorded.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Five-hundred patients with ALS were included (female/male: 220/280, age: 58.9&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;11.3&#x2009;y). Of the patients, 22.8% had daytime hypercapnia. DD was observed in 55% of the patients (PAM in 112, sitting-supine FVC difference&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;20% in 50, and sitting-supine SpO<sub>2</sub> difference&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;4% in 113 patients). Of the patients with DD, 31.6% (n = 87) had no respiratory symptoms, 46.4% had FVC&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;70% and 33.5% had FVC &lt;50%. Nocturnal hypoxemia (sleep time spent with SpO<sub>2</sub> &#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;90% &#x2265;30%) was present in 59.7%, and all patients with nocturnal hypoxemia had DD. Obstructive sleep apnea (8 severe, 14 moderate, 39 mild) was detected in 55% of the patients with polysomnography (n = 61) or polygraphy (n = 50). During follow-up, 52.2% of the patients died. Mean survival time was shorter in patients with DD (P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;.001).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">Paradoxical abdomimal movement (PAM), sitting-supine SpO<sub>2</sub> difference&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;4% and sitting-supine FVC difference&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;20% are indicators of DD, which should be routinely evaluated at every outpatient visit.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pihtili</LastName><ForeName>Aylin</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Istanbul Faculty of Medicine, Department of Pulmonary Medicine, Istanbul University, Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bingol</LastName><ForeName>Zuleyha</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Istanbul Faculty of Medicine, Department of Pulmonary Medicine, Istanbul University, Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Durmus</LastName><ForeName>Hacer</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Istanbul Faculty of Medicine, Department of Neurology, Istanbul University, Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Parman</LastName><ForeName>Yesim</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Istanbul Faculty of Medicine, Department of Neurology, Istanbul University, Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kiyan</LastName><ForeName>Esen</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Istanbul Faculty of Medicine, Department of Pulmonary Medicine, Istanbul University, Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Muscle Nerve</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7803146</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0148-639X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000554" MajorTopicYN="N">Ambulatory Care Facilities</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003964" MajorTopicYN="N">Diaphragm</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006935" MajorTopicYN="N">Hypercapnia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012129" MajorTopicYN="N">Respiratory Function Tests</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014797" MajorTopicYN="N">Vital Capacity</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">diaphragm</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">forced vital capacity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">paradoxical abdominal movement</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">weakness</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33576026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.27200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Spataro R, LoRe M, Piccoli T, Piccoli F, La Bella V. Causes and place of death in Italian patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neurol Scand. 2010;122(3):217-223.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurian KM, Forbes RB, Colville S, Swingler RJ. Cause of death and clinical grading criteria in a cohort of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis cases undergoing autopsy from the Scottish motor neurone disease register. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2009;80(1):84-87.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corcia P, Pradat PF, Salachas F, et al. Causes of death in a post-mortem series of ALS patients. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2008;9(1):59-62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Louwerse ES, Visser CE, Bossuyt PM, Weverling GJ. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: mortality risk during the course of the disease and prognostic factors. J Neurol Sci. 1997;152(1):10-17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnulf I, Similowski T, Salachas F, et al. Sleep disorders and diaphragmatic function in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2000;161(3):849-856.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bourke SC, Shaw PJ, Gibson GJ. Respiratory function vs. sleep-disordered breathing as predictors of QoL in ALS. Neurology. 2001;57(11):2040-2044.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendoza M, Gelinas DF, Moore DH, Miller RG. A comparison of maximal inspiratory pressure and forced vital capacity as potential criteria for initiating non-invasive ventilation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2007;8(2):106-111.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Czaplinski A, Yen AA, Appel SH. Forced vital capacity (FVC) as an indicator of survival and disease progression in an ALS clinic population. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2006;77(3):390-392.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller RG, Jackson CE, Kasarskis EJ, et al. Practice parameter update: the care of the patient with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: drug, nutritional, and respiratory therapies (an evidence based review): report of the quality standards Subcommittee of the American Academy of neurology. Neurology. 2009;73(15):1218-1226.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lechtzin N, Wiener CM, Shade DM, Clawson L, Diette GB. Spirometry in the supine position improves the detection of diaphragmatic weakness in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Chest. 2002;121(2):436-442.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Similowski T, Attali V, Bensimon G, et al. Diaphragmatic dysfunction and dyspnoea in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Eur Respir J. 2000;15(2):332-337.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen PM, Abrahams S, Borasio GD, et al. EFNS guidelines on the clinical management of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (MALS)-revised report of an EFNS task force on diagnosis and Management of Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. Eur J Neurol. 2012;19(3):360-375.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham BL, Steenbruggen I, Miller MR, et al. Standardization of spirometry 2019 update. An official American Thoracic Society and European Respiratory Society technical statement. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2019;200(8):70-88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lechtzin N, Cudkowicz ME, de Carvalho M, et al. Respiratory measures in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2018;19(5-6):321-330.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuenzel A, Marshall B, Verges S, Anholm JD. Positional changes in arterial oxygen saturation and end-tidal carbon dioxide at high altitude: medex 2015. High Alt Med Biol. 2020;21(2):144-151.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceylan B, Khorshid L, G&#xfc;ne&#x15f; &#xdc;Y, Zaybak A. Evaluation of oxygen saturation values in different body positions in healthy individuals. J Clin Nurs. 2016;25(7-8):1095-1100.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Driscoll BR, Howard LS, Davison AG, British Thoracic Society. BTS guideline for emergency oxygen use in adult patients. Thorax. 2008;63(Suppl 6):vi1-vi68.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berry RB, Budhiraja R, Gottlieb DJ, et al. Rules for scoring respiratory events in sleep: update of the 2007 AASM manual for the scoring of sleep and associated events. Deliberations of the sleep Apnea definitions task force of the American Academy of sleep medicine. J Clin Sleep Med. 2012;8(5):597-619.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prell T, Ringer TM, Wullenkord K, et al. Assessment of pulmonary function in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: when can polygraphy help evaluate the need for non-invasive ventilation? Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2016;87(9):1022-1026.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schiffman PL, Belsh JM. Pulmonary function at diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Rate of deterioration. Chest. 1993;103(2):508-513.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Carvalho M, Matias T, Coelho F, Evangelista T, Pinto A, Lu&#xed;s MS. Motor neuron disease presenting with respiratory failure. J Neurol Sci. 1996;139(1):117-122.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dub&#xe9; BP, Dres M. Diaphragm dysfunction: diagnostic approaches and management strategies. J Clin Med. 2016;5(12):113.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harlaar L, Ciet P, van der Ploeg AT, et al. Imaging of respiratory muscles in neuromuscular disease: a review. Neuromuscul Disord. 2018;28(3):246-256.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Carvalho M, Swash M, Pinto S. Diaphragmatic neurophysiology and respiratory markers in ALS. Front Neurol. 2019;10:143.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baumann F, Henderson RD, Morrison SC, et al. Use of respiratory function tests to predict survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2010;11(1-2):194-202.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt EP, Drachman DB, Wiener CM, Clawson L, Kimball R, Lechtzin N. Pulmonary predictors of survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: use in clinical trial design. Muscle Nerve. 2006;33(1):127-132.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinto S, Turkman A, Pinto A, Swash M, de Carvalho M. Predicting respiratory insufficiency in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: the role of phrenic nevre studies. Clin Neurophysiol. 2009;120(5):941-946.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fantini R, Mandrioli J, Zona S, et al. Ultrasound assessment of diaphragmatic function in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Respirology. 2016;21(5):932-938.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sartucci F, Pelagatti A, Santin M, Bocci T, Dolciotti C, Bongioanni P. Diaphragm ultrasonography in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a diagnostic tool to assess ventilatory dysfunction and disease severity. Neurol Sci. 2019;40(10):2065-2071.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinto S, Alves P, Pimentel B, Swash M, de Carvalho M. Ultrasound for assessment of diaphragm in ALS. Clin Neurophysiol. 2016;127(1):892-897.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinto S, Carvalho M. Correlation between forced vital capacity and slow vital capacity for the assessment of respiratory involvement in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a prospective study. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2017;18(1-2):86-91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rose L, McKim D, Leasa D, et al. Patterns of healthcare utilisation for respiratory complications of adults with neuromuscular disease: a population study. Eur Respir J. 2018;52(3):1800754.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D'Cruz RF, Murphy PB, Kaltsakas G. Sleep disordered breathing in motor neurone disease. J Thorac Dis. 2018;10(1):86-93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braun AT, Caballero-Eraso C, Lechtzin N. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and the respiratory system. Clin Chest Med. 2018;39(2):391-400.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bourke SC, Tomlinson M, Williams TL, Bullock RE, Shaw PJ, Gibson GJ. Effects of non-invasive ventilation on survival and quality of life in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a randomised controlled trial. Lancet Neurol. 2006;5(2):140-147.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>I&#x142;zecka J, Stelmasiak Z, Balicka G. Respiratory function in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurol Sci. 2003;24(4):288-289.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>