<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">33586315</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>18</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1522-2586</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>55</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>May</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of magnetic resonance imaging : JMRI</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Magn Reson Imaging</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Magnetic Resonance Iron Imaging in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1283</StartPage><EndPage>1300</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1283-1300</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jmri.27530</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) results in progressive impairment of upper and lower motor neurons. Increasing evidence from both in vivo and ex vivo studies suggest that iron accumulation in the motor cortex is a neuropathological hallmark in ALS. An in vivo neuroimaging marker of iron dysregulation in ALS would be useful in disease diagnosis and prognosis. Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI), with its unique capability to generate a variety of soft tissue contrasts, provides opportunities to image iron distribution in the human brain with millimeter to sub-millimeter anatomical resolution. Conventionally, MRI T1-weighted, T2-weighted, and T2*-weighted images have been used to investigate iron dysregulation in the brain in vivo. Susceptibility weighted imaging has enhanced contrast for para-magnetic materials that provides superior sensitivity to iron in vivo. Recently, the development of quantitative susceptibility mapping (QSM) has realized the possibility of using quantitative assessments of magnetic susceptibility measures in brain tissues as a surrogate measurement of in vivo brain iron. In this review, we provide an overview of MRI techniques that have been used to investigate iron dysregulation in ALS in vivo. The potential uses, strengths, and limitations of these techniques in clinical trials, disease diagnosis, and prognosis are presented and discussed. We recommend further longitudinal studies with appropriate cohort characterization to validate the efficacy of these techniques. We conclude that quantitative iron assessment using recent advances in MRI including QSM holds great potential to be a sensitive diagnostic and prognostic marker in ALS. The use of multimodal neuroimaging markers in combination with iron imaging may also offer improved sensitivity in ALS diagnosis and prognosis that could make a major contribution to clinical care and treatment trials. LEVEL OF EVIDENCE: 2 TECHNICAL EFFICACY: Stage 3.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 International Society for Magnetic Resonance in Medicine.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bhattarai</LastName><ForeName>Anjan</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9178-6509</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, School of Clinical Sciences at Monash Health, Monash University, Melbourne, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Monash Biomedical Imaging, Monash University, Melbourne, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Egan</LastName><ForeName>Gary F</ForeName><Initials>GF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Monash Biomedical Imaging, Monash University, Melbourne, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Talman</LastName><ForeName>Paul</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience, Barwon Health, Geelong, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chua</LastName><ForeName>Phyllis</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, School of Clinical Sciences at Monash Health, Monash University, Melbourne, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Statewide Progressive Neurological Services, Calvary Health Care Bethlehem, Melbourne, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Zhaolin</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Monash Biomedical Imaging, Monash University, Melbourne, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Magn Reson Imaging</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9105850</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1053-1807</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>E1UOL152H7</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D007501">Iron</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007501" MajorTopicYN="N">Iron</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008279" MajorTopicYN="N">Magnetic Resonance Imaging</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009682" MajorTopicYN="N">Magnetic Resonance Spectroscopy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009046" MajorTopicYN="N">Motor Neurons</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">iron</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">magnetic resonance imaging</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">quantitative susceptibility mapping</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">susceptibility weighted imaging</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33586315</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmri.27530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Kiernan MC, Vucic S, Cheah BC, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet 2011;377(9769):942-955.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adachi Y, Sato N, Saito Y, et al. Usefulness of SWI for the detection of iron in the motor cortex in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neuroimaging 2015;25(3):443-451.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S, Melhem ER, Poptani H, Woo JH. Neuroimaging in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurotherapeutics 2011;8(1):63-71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carri MT, Ferri A, Cozzolino M, Calabrese L, Rotilio G. Neurodegeneration in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: The role of oxidative stress and altered homeostasis of metals. Brain Res Bull 2003;61(4):365-374.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonafede R, Mariotti R. ALS pathogenesis and therapeutic approaches: The role of mesenchymal stem cells and extracellular vesicles. Front Cell Neurosci 2017;11:80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ward RJ, Zucca FA, Duyn JH, Crichton RR, Zecca L. The role of iron in brain ageing and neurodegenerative disorders. Lancet Neurol 2014;13(10):1045-1060.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nnah IC, Wessling-Resnick M. Brain iron homeostasis: A focus on microglial iron. Pharmaceuticals 2018;11(4):129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Contestabile A. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: From research to therapeutic attempts and therapeutic perspectives. Curr Med Chem 2011;18(36):5655-5665.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jomova K, Vondrakova D, Lawson M, Valko M. Metals, oxidative stress and neurodegenerative disorders. Mol Cell Biochem 2010;345(1-2):91-104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshida M, Takahashi Y, Koike A, Fukuda Y, Goto J, Tsuji S. A mutation database for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Hum Mutat 2010;31(9):1003-1010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheykhansari S, Kozielski K, Bill J, et al. Redox metals homeostasis in multiple sclerosis and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A review. Cell Death Dis 2018;9(3):348.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee JK, Shin JH, Gwag BJ, Choi EJ. Iron accumulation promotes TACE-mediated TNF-&#x3b1; secretion and neurodegeneration in a mouse model of ALS. Neurobiol Dis 2015;80:63-69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bu XL, Xiang Y, Guo Y. The role of iron in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Adv Exp Med Biol 2019;1173:145-152.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nandar W, Connor JR. HFE gene variants affect iron in the brain. J Nutr 2011;141(4):729s-739s.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nandar W, Neely EB, Unger E, Connor JR. A mutation in the HFE gene is associated with altered brain iron profiles and increased oxidative stress in mice. Biochim Biophys Acta 2013;1832(6):729-741.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nandar W, Neely EB, Simmons Z, Connor JR. H63D HFE genotype accelerates disease progression in animal models of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Biochim Biophys Acta 2014;1842(12 Pt A):2413-2426.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masaldan S, Bush AI, Devos D, Rolland AS, Moreau C. Striking while the iron is hot: Iron metabolism and ferroptosis in neurodegeneration. Free Radic Biol Med 2019;133:221-233.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah R, Shchepinov MS, Pratt DA. Resolving the role of lipoxygenases in the initiation and execution of Ferroptosis. ACS Cent Sci 2018;4(3):387-396.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doll S, Proneth B, Tyurina YY, et al. ACSL4 dictates ferroptosis sensitivity by shaping cellular lipid composition. Nat Chem Biol 2017;13(1):91-98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao M, Jiang X. To eat or not to eat-The metabolic flavor of ferroptosis. Curr Opin Cell Biol 2018;51:58-64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Golko-Perez S, Amit T, Bar-Am O, Youdim MB, Weinreb O. A novel iron chelator-radical scavenger ameliorates motor dysfunction and improves life span and mitochondrial biogenesis in SOD1(G93A) ALS mice. Neurotox Res 2017;31(2):230-244.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwan JY, Jeong SY, Van Gelderen P, et al. Iron accumulation in deep cortical layers accounts for MRI signal abnormalities in ALS: Correlating 7 tesla MRI and pathology. PLoS One 2012;7(4):e35241.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qian ZM, Wang Q. Expression of iron transport proteins and excessive iron accumulation in the brain in neurodegenerative disorders. Brain Res Brain Res Rev 1998;27(3):257-267.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasui M, Ota K, Garruto RM. Concentrations of zinc and iron in the brains of Guamanian patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and parkinsonism-dementia. Neurotoxicology 1993;14(4):445-450.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zecca L, Youdim MB, Riederer P, Connor JR, Crichton RR. Iron, brain ageing and neurodegenerative disorders. Nat Rev Neurosci 2004;5(11):863-873.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreau C, Danel V, Devedjian JC, et al. Could conservative iron chelation lead to neuroprotection in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis? Antioxid Redox Signal 2018;29(8):742-748.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeong SY, Rathore KI, Schulz K, Ponka P, Arosio P, David S. Dysregulation of iron homeostasis in the CNS contributes to disease progression in a mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurosci 2009;29(3):610-619.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duyn JH. High field MRI of brain Iron. Methods Mol Biol 2011;711:239-249.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haacke EM, Cheng NY, House MJ, et al. Imaging iron stores in the brain using magnetic resonance imaging. Magn Reson Imaging 2005;23(1):1-25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson LJ, Holden S, Davis B, et al. Cardiovascular T2-star (T2*) magnetic resonance for the early diagnosis of myocardial iron overload. Eur Heart J 2001;22(23):2171-2179.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L, Ulug AM, Zimmerman RD, Lin MT, Rubin M, Beal MF. The diagnostic utility of FLAIR imaging in clinically verified amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Magn Reson Imaging 2003;17(5):521-527.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kruer MC, Boddaert N, Schneider SA, et al. Neuroimaging features of neurodegeneration with brain iron accumulation. Am J Neuroradiol 2012;33(3):407-414.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsushima Y, Endo K. Hypointensities in the brain on T2*-weighted gradient-echo magnetic resonance imaging. Curr Probl Diagn Radiol 2006;35(4):140-150.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ignjatovic A, Stevic Z, Lavrnic S, Dakovic M, Bacic G. Brain iron MRI: A biomarker for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Magn Reson Imaging 2013;38(6):1472-1479.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duyn JH, van Gelderen P, Li TQ, de Zwart JA, Koretsky AP, Fukunaga M. High-field MRI of brain cortical substructure based on signal phase. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 2007;104(28):11796-11801.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oba H, Araki T, Ohtomo K, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: T2 shortening in motor cortex at MR imaging. Radiology 1993;189(3):843-846.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheung G, Gawel MJ, Cooper PW, Farb RI, Ang LC, Gawal MJ. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Correlation of clinical and MR imaging findings. Radiology 1995;194(1):263-270.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ngai S, Tang YM, Du L, Stuckey S. Hyperintensity of the precentral gyral subcortical white matter and hypointensity of the precentral gyrus on fluid-attenuated inversion recovery: Variation with age and implications for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. AJNR Am J Neuroradiol 2007;28(2):250-254.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hecht MJ, Fellner F, Fellner C, Hilz MJ, Neund&#xf6;rfer B, Heuss D. Hyperintense and hypointense MRI signals of the precentral gyrus and corticospinal tract in ALS: A follow-up examination including FLAIR images. J Neurol Sci 2002;199(1):59-65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowen BC, Pattany PM, Bradley WG, et al. MR imaging and localized proton spectroscopy of the precentral gyrus in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. AJNR Am J Neuroradiol 2000;21(4):647-658.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hecht MJ, Fellner C, Schmid A, Neundorfer B, Fellner FA. Cortical T2 signal shortening in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis is not due to iron deposits. Neuroradiology 2005;47(11):805-808.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costagli M, Donatelli G, Biagi L, et al. Magnetic susceptibility in the deep layers of the primary motor cortex in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuroimage Clin 2016;12:965-969.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haacke EM, Xu Y, Cheng YC, Reichenbach JR. Susceptibility weighted imaging (SWI). Magn Reson Med 2004;52(3):612-618.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halefoglu AM, Yousem DM. Susceptibility weighted imaging: Clinical applications and future directions. World J Radiol 2018;10(4):30-45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu S, Buch S, Chen Y, et al. Susceptibility-weighted imaging: Current status and future directions. NMR Biomed 2017;30(4):e3552.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu C, Li W, Tong KA, Yeom KW, Kuzminski S. Susceptibility-weighted imaging and quantitative susceptibility mapping in the brain. J Magn Reson Imaging 2015;42(1):23-41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chamberlain R, Reyes D, Curran GL, et al. Comparison of amyloid plaque contrast generated by T2-weighted, T2*-weighted, and susceptibility-weighted imaging methods in transgenic mouse models of Alzheimer's disease. Magn Reson Med 2009;61(5):1158-1164.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gasparotti R, Pinelli L, Liserre R. New MR sequences in daily practice: Susceptibility weighted imaging. A pictorial essay. Insights Imaging 2011;2(3):335-347.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu J, Qi F, Wang N, et al. Increased iron level in motor cortex of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients: An in vivo MR study. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2014;15(5-6):357-361.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Endo H, Sekiguchi K, Shimada H, et al. Low signal intensity in motor cortex on susceptibility-weighted MR imaging is correlated with clinical signs of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A pilot study. J Neurol 2018;265(3):552-561.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prell T, Hartung V, Tietz F, et al. Susceptibility-weighted imaging provides insight into white matter damage in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. PLoS One 2015;10(6):e0131114.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johns SLM, Ishaque A, Khan M, Yang YH, Wilman AH, Kalra S. Quantifying changes on susceptibility weighted images in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis using MRI texture analysis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2019;20(5-6):396-403.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haacke EM, Liu S, Buch S, Zheng W, Wu D, Ye Y. Quantitative susceptibility mapping: Current status and future directions. Magn Reson Imaging 2015;33(1):1-25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deistung A, Schweser F, Reichenbach JR. Overview of quantitative susceptibility mapping. NMR Biomed 2017;30:4. https://doi.org/10.1002/nbm.3569.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Spincemaille P, Liu Z, et al. Clinical quantitative susceptibility mapping (QSM): Biometal imaging and its emerging roles in patient care. J Magn Reson Imaging 2017;46(4):951-971.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Liu T. Quantitative susceptibility mapping (QSM): Decoding MRI data for a tissue magnetic biomarker. Magn Reson Med 2015;73(1):82-101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schweitzer AD, Liu T, Gupta A, et al. Quantitative susceptibility mapping of the motor cortex in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and primary lateral sclerosis. AJR Am J Roentgenol 2015;204(5):1086-1092.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langkammer C, Schweser F, Krebs N, et al. Quantitative susceptibility mapping (QSM) as a means to measure brain iron? A post mortem validation study. Neuroimage 2012;62(3):1593-1599.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng W, Nichol H, Liu S, Cheng YC, Haacke EM. Measuring iron in the brain using quantitative susceptibility mapping and X-ray fluorescence imaging. Neuroimage 2013;78:68-74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun H, Walsh AJ, Lebel RM, et al. Validation of quantitative susceptibility mapping with Perls' iron staining for subcortical gray matter. Neuroimage 2015;105:486-492.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rouault TA, Cooperman S. Brain iron metabolism. Semin Pediatr Neurol 2006;13(3):142-148.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ward PGD, Harding IH, Close TG, et al. Longitudinal evaluation of iron concentration and atrophy in the dentate nuclei in friedreich ataxia. Mov Disord 2019;34(3):335-343.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dominguez JF, Ng AC, Poudel G, et al. Iron accumulation in the basal ganglia in Huntington's disease: Cross-sectional data from the IMAGE-HD study. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2016;87(5):545-549.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langkammer C, Schweser F, Shmueli K, et al. Quantitative susceptibility mapping: Report from the 2016 reconstruction challenge. Magn Reson Med 2018;79(3):1661-1673.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morris CM, Candy JM, Oakley AE, Bloxham CA, Edwardson JA. Histochemical distribution of non-haem iron in the human brain. Acta Anat 1992;144(3):235-257.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cosottini M, Giannelli M, Siciliano G, et al. Diffusion-tensor MR imaging of corticospinal tract in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and progressive muscular atrophy. Radiology 2005;237(1):258-264.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ince PG, Evans J, Knopp M, et al. Corticospinal tract degeneration in the progressive muscular atrophy variant of ALS. Neurology 2003;60(8):1252-1258.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Denk C, Hernandez Torres E, MacKay A, Rauscher A. The influence of white matter fibre orientation on MR signal phase and decay. NMR Biomed 2011;24(3):246-252.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wharton S, Bowtell R. Effects of white matter microstructure on phase and susceptibility maps. Magn Reson Med 2015;73(3):1258-1269.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Straub S, Schneider TM, Emmerich J, et al. Suitable reference tissues for quantitative susceptibility mapping of the brain. Magn Reson Med 2017;78(1):204-214.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhattarai A, Chen Z, Ward PGD, et al. Serial assessment of iron in the motor cortex in limb-onset amyotrophic lateral sclerosis using quantitative susceptibility mapping. Quant Imaging Med Surg 2020;10(7):1465-1476.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fischl B, Salat DH, Busa E, et al. Whole brain segmentation: Automated labeling of neuroanatomical structures in the human brain. Neuron 2002;33(3):341-355.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith SM. Fast robust automated brain extraction. Hum Brain Mapp 2002;17(3):143-155.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eskildsen SF, Coupe P, Fonov V, et al. BEaST: Brain extraction based on nonlocal segmentation technique. Neuroimage 2012;59(3):2362-2373.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu T, Spincemaille P, de Rochefort L, Kressler B, Wang Y. Calculation of susceptibility through multiple orientation sampling (COSMOS): A method for conditioning the inverse problem from measured magnetic field map to susceptibility source image in MRI. Magn Reson Med 2009;61(1):196-204.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee J, Shmueli K, Fukunaga M, et al. Sensitivity of MRI resonance frequency to the orientation of brain tissue microstructure. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 2010;107(11):5130-5135.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wharton S, Bowtell R. Fiber orientation-dependent white matter contrast in gradient echo MRI. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 2012;109(45):18559-18564.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li W, Wu B, Avram AV, Liu C. Magnetic susceptibility anisotropy of human brain in vivo and its molecular underpinnings. Neuroimage 2012;59(3):2088-2097.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu C. Susceptibility tensor imaging. Magn Reson Med 2010;63(6):1471-1477.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yablonskiy DA, Sukstanskii AL. Generalized Lorentzian tensor approach (GLTA) as a biophysical background for quantitative susceptibility mapping. Magn Reson Med 2015;73(2):757-764.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang C, Foxley S, Ansorge O, et al. Methods for quantitative susceptibility and R2* mapping in whole post-mortem brains at 7T applied to amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuroimage 2020;222:117216.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Contarino VE, Conte G, Morelli C, et al. Toward a marker of upper motor neuron impairment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A fully automatic investigation of the magnetic susceptibility in the precentral cortex. Eur J Radiol 2020;124:108815.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donatelli G, Caldarazzo Ienco E, Costagli M, et al. MRI cortical feature of bulbar impairment in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuroimage Clin 2019;24:101934.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Welton T, Maller JJ, Lebel RM, Tan ET, Rowe DB, Grieve SM. Diffusion kurtosis and quantitative susceptibility mapping MRI are sensitive to structural abnormalities in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuroimage Clin 2019;24:101953.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weidman EK, Schweitzer AD, Niogi SN, et al. Diffusion tensor imaging and quantitative susceptibility mapping as diagnostic tools for motor neuron disorders. Clin Imaging 2018;53:6-11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acosta-Cabronero J, Machts J, Schreiber S, et al. Quantitative susceptibility MRI to detect brain Iron in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Radiology 2018;289(1):195-203.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee JY, Lee YJ, Park DW, et al. Quantitative susceptibility mapping of the motor cortex: A comparison of susceptibility among patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, cerebrovascular disease, and healthy controls. Neuroradiology 2017;59(12):1213-1222.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheelakumari R, Madhusoodanan M, Radhakrishnan A, Ranjith G, Thomas B. A potential biomarker in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Can assessment of brain Iron deposition with SWI and corticospinal tract degeneration with DTI help? AJNR Am J Neuroradiol 2016;37(2):252-258.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hallgren B, Sourander P. The effect of age on the non-haemin iron in the human brain. J Neurochem 1958;3(1):41-51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agosta F, Spinelli EG, Filippi M. Neuroimaging in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Current and emerging uses. Expert Rev Neurother 2018;18(5):395-406.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dehdashti F, Grigsby PW, Mintun MA, Lewis JS, Siegel BA, Welch MJ. Assessing tumor hypoxia in cervical cancer by positron emission tomography with 60Cu-ATSM: Relationship to therapeutic response-a preliminary report. Int J Radiat Oncol Biol Phys 2003;55(5):1233-1238.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dehdashti F, Mintun MA, Lewis JS, et al. In vivo assessment of tumor hypoxia in lung cancer with 60Cu-ATSM. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging 2003;30(6):844-850.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ikawa M, Okazawa H, Tsujikawa T, et al. Increased oxidative stress is related to disease severity in the ALS motor cortex: A PET study. Neurology 2015;84(20):2033-2039.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Southon A, Szostak K, Acevedo KM, et al. CuII(atsm) inhibits ferroptosis: Implications for treatment of neurodegenerative disease. Br J Pharmacol 2020;177(3):656-667.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Z, Jamadar SD, Li S, et al. From simultaneous to synergistic MR-PET brain imaging: A review of hybrid MR-PET imaging methodologies. Hum Brain Mapp 2018;39(12):5126-5144.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudarshan VP, Egan GF, Chen Z, Awate SP. Joint PET-MRI image reconstruction using a patch-based joint-dictionary prior. Med Image Anal 2020;62:101669.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eisen A, Weber M. The motor cortex and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve 2001;24(4):564-573.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bollmann S, Rasmussen KGB, Kristensen M, et al. DeepQSM-Using deep learning to solve the dipole inversion for quantitative susceptibility mapping. Neuroimage 2019;195:373-383.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jung W, Bollmann S, Lee J. Overview of quantitative susceptibility mapping using deep learning: Current status, challenges and opportunities. NMR Biomed 2020;e4292. https://doi.org/10.1002/nbm.4292.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei H, Cao S, Zhang Y, et al. Learning-based single-step quantitative susceptibility mapping reconstruction without brain extraction. Neuroimage 2019;202:116064.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>