<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">33580524</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>10</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-4598</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>63</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>May</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Muscle &amp; nerve</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Muscle Nerve</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Palliative care in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis clinics: A survey of NEALS consortium membership.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>769</StartPage><EndPage>774</EndPage><MedlinePgn>769-774</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/mus.27203</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) is a progressive neurodegenerative condition managed with a multidisciplinary approach. Palliative care is important for this approach, but there is a lack of recommendations for the role and involvement of palliative medicine (PM) specialists in multidisciplinary ALS care.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">This questionnaire-based survey assessed the state of palliative care in selective sites that are a part of Northeast Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Consortium (NEALS).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Twenty-seven percent of the sites included palliative care specialists as a part of their ALS clinics and they were introduced to the patients and family by ALS specialists (75.94%) usually at an advanced stage of ALS.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION">Our study when compared with other study results having a similar aim showed that there is a variability in the practice of palliative care specialists in ALS clinics. Having evidence-based guidelines will help in the management of ALS patients more effectively.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mehta</LastName><ForeName>Tejas R</ForeName><Initials>TR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of Missouri, Columbia, Missouri, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bayat</LastName><ForeName>Elham</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, George Washington University, Washington, District of Columbia, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Govindarajan</LastName><ForeName>Raghav</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of Missouri, Columbia, Missouri, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Muscle Nerve</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7803146</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0148-639X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019538" MajorTopicYN="N">Health Care Surveys</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010166" MajorTopicYN="Y">Palliative Care</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010348" MajorTopicYN="Y">Patient Care Team</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ALS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">clinical</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">motor neuron disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">palliative care</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">treatment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">trends</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33580524</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.27203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Quill TE, Abernethy AP. Generalist plus specialist palliative care-creating a more sustainable model. N Engl J Med. 2013;368:1173-1175.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Creutzfeldt CJ, Robinson MT, Holloway RG. Neurologists as primary palliative care providers: communication and practice approaches. Neurol Clin Pract. 2016;6:40-48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliver DJ, Borasio GD, Caraceni A, et al. A consensus review of the development of palliative care for patients with chronic and progressive neurological disease. Eur J Neurol. 2016;23:30-38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hogden A, Foley G, Henderson RD, James M, Aoun SM. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: improving care with a multidisciplinary approach. J Multidiscip Healthc. 2017;10:205-215.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blackhall LG. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and palliative care: where we are, and the road ahead. Muscle Nerve. 2012;45:311-318.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell JD, Borasio GD. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet. 2007;369(9578):2031-2041.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bede P, Oliver D, Stodart J, et al. Palliative care in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a review of current international guidelines and initiatives. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2011;82(4):413-418.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roche JC, Rojas-Garcia R, Scott KM, et al. A proposed staging system for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain. 2012;135(Pt 3):847-852.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Institute for Healthcare Improvement. The Conversation Project. Available at https://theconversationproject.org. Accessed July 2, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Advanced care planning decisions. 2010. Available at https://acpdecisions.org. Accessed July 2, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Position of the American academy of neurology on certain aspects of the care and management of the persistent vegetative state patient. Adopted by the executive board, American academy of neurology, April 21, 1988, Cincinnati, Ohio. Neurology 1989;39;125-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller RG, Rosenberg JA, Gelinas DF, et al. Practice parameter: the care of the patient with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (an evidence-based review): report of the quality standards Subcommittee of the American Academy of neurology: ALS practice parameters task force. Neurology. 1999;52:1311-1323.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holloway RG, Arnold RM, Creutzfeldt CJ, et al. Palliative and end-of-life care in stroke: a statement for healthcare professionals from the American Heart Association/ American Stroke Association. Stroke. 2014;45:1887-1916.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliver DJ, Borasio GD, Caraceni A, et al. A consensus review on the development of palliative care for patients with chronic and progressive neurological disease. Eur J Neurol. 2016;23:30-38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kukulka K, Washington KT, Govindarajan R, Mehr DR. Stakeholder perspectives on the biopsychosocial and spiritual realities of living with ALS: implications for palliative care teams. Am J Hosp Palliat Care. 2019;36(10):851-857.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyers FJ, Linder J. Simultaneous care: disease treatment and palliative care throughout illness. J Clin Oncol. 2003;21:1412-1415.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyers FJ, Linder J, Beckett L, Christensen S, Blais J, Gandara DR. Simultaneous care: a model approach to the perceived conflict between investigational therapy and palliative care. J Pain Symptom Manage. 2004;28:548-556.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelley AS, Meier DE. Palliative care: a shifting paradigm. N Engl J Med. 2010;363:781-782.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borasio GD, Shaw PJ, Hardiman O, et al. Standards of palliative care for patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: results of a European survey. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord. 2001;2(3):159-164.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brizzi K, Paganoni S, Zehm A, De Marchi F, Berry JD. Integration of a palliative care specialist in an amyotrophic lateral sclerosis clinic: observations from one center. Muscle Nerve. 2019;60(2):137-140.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>