<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">33602016</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>31</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2167-9223</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>21</Volume><Issue>sup1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis &amp; frontotemporal degeneration</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Measuring disease progression in primary lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>59</StartPage><EndPage>66</EndPage><MedlinePgn>59-66</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1080/21678421.2020.1837179</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Quantitative measures of disease severity are essential outcome measures for clinical trials. The slow progression of disease in primary lateral sclerosis (PLS) requires clinical measures that are sensitive to changes occurring within the time frame of a clinical trial. Proposed clinical outcome measures include the PLS functional rating scale (PLSFRS), burden scores derived from clinical examination findings, and quantitative measures of motor performance. The PLSFRS has good inter-rater reliability and showed greater longitudinal change over 6- and 12-months compared to the revised ALS functional rating scale. Examination-based upper motor neuron burden (UMNB) scales also have good reliability, and longitudinal studies are in process. Quantitative measures of strength, dexterity, gait, and speech have the potential to provide objective and precise measures of clinical change, but have been the least studied in persons with PLS.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gilmore</LastName><ForeName>Madison</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Columbia University Medical Center, New York, NY, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Elman</LastName><ForeName>Lauren</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Babu</LastName><ForeName>Suma</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sean M Healy &amp; AMG Center for ALS, Massachusetts General Hospital, Boston, MA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Andres</LastName><ForeName>Patricia</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurological Clinical Research Institute, Massachusetts General Hospital, Boston, MA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Floeter</LastName><ForeName>Mary Kay</ForeName><Initials>MK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Institute of Neurological Disorders and Stroke, NIH, Bethesda, MD, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>ZIA NS002976</GrantID><Acronym>ImNIH</Acronym><Agency>Intramural NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052060">Research Support, N.I.H., Intramural</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101587185</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2167-8421</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018450" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Progression</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016472" MajorTopicYN="Y">Motor Neuron Disease</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009046" MajorTopicYN="N">Motor Neurons</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015203" MajorTopicYN="N">Reproducibility of Results</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Primary lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">disease progression</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">outcome measures</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Disclosures. The authors have no conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33602016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS1664561</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7899091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/21678421.2020.1837179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>van den Berg LH, Sorenson E, Gronseth G, Macklin EA, Andrews J, Baloh RH, Benatar M, Berry JD, Chio A, Corcia P, et al. Revised Airlie House consensus guidelines for design and implementation of ALS clinical trials. Neurology. 2019;92(14):e1610&#x2013;e1623.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6448453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30850440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Group AS. The Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Functional Rating Scale. Assessment of activities of daily living in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. The ALS CNTF treatment study (ACTS) phase I-II Study Group. Arch Neurol. 1996;53(2):141&#x2013;147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8639063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon PH, Miller RG, Moore DH. ALSFRS-R. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord. 2004;5 Suppl 1:90&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15512883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitsumoto H, Brooks BR, Silani V. Clinical trials in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: why so many negative trials and how can trials be improved? Lancet Neurol. 2014;13(11):1127&#x2013;1138.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25316019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum JM, Stambler N, Malta E, Fuller C, Hilt D, Thurmond B, Nakanishi A. The ALSFRS-R: a revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. BDNF ALS Study Group (Phase III). J Neurol Sci. 1999;169(1&#x2013;2):13&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10540002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitsumoto H, Factor-Litvak P, Andrews H, Goetz RR, Andrews L, Rabkin JG, McElhiney M, Nieves J, Santella RM, Murphy J, et al. ALS Multicenter Cohort Study of Oxidative Stress (ALS COSMOS): study methodology, recruitment, and baseline demographic and disease characteristics. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2014;15(3&#x2013;4):192&#x2013;203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4310702</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24564738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitsumoto H, Chiuzan C, Gilmore M, Zhang Y, Simmons Z, Paganoni S, Kisanuki YY, Zinman L, Jawdat O, Sorenson E, et al. Primary lateral sclerosis (PLS) functional rating scale: PLS-specific clinimetric scale. Muscle Nerve. 2020;61(2):163&#x2013;172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31758557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agosta F, Galantucci S, Riva N, Chio A, Messina S, Iannaccone S, Calvo A, Silani V, Copetti M, Falini A, et al. Intrahemispheric and interhemispheric structural network abnormalities in PLS and ALS. Hum Brain Mapp. 2014;35(4):1710&#x2013;1722.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6869498</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23633431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellis CM, Simmons A, Jones DK, Bland J, Dawson JM, Horsfield MA, Williams SC, Leigh PN. Diffusion tensor MRI assesses corticospinal tract damage in ALS. Neurology. 1999;53(5):1051&#x2013;1058.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10496265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iwata NK, Aoki S, Okabe S, Arai N, Terao Y, Kwak S, Abe O, Kanazawa I, Tsuji S, Ugawa Y. Evaluation of corticospinal tracts in ALS with diffusion tensor MRI and brainstem stimulation. Neurology. 2008;70(7):528&#x2013;532.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18268244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner MR, Cagnin A, Turkheimer FE, Miller CC, Shaw CE, Brooks DJ, Leigh PN, Banati RB. Evidence of widespread cerebral microglial activation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: an [11C](R)-PK11195 positron emission tomography study. Neurobiol Dis. 2004;15(3):601&#x2013;609.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15056468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iwata NK, Kwan JY, Danielian LE, Butman JA, Tovar-Moll F, Bayat E, Floeter MK. White matter alterations differ in primary lateral sclerosis and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain. 2011;134(Pt 9):2642&#x2013;2655.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3170531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21798965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rooney WD, Miller RG, Gelinas D, Schuff N, Maudsley AA, Weiner MW. Decreased N-acetylaspartate in motor cortex and corticospinal tract in ALS. Neurology. 1998;50(6):1800&#x2013;1805.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9633731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quinn C, Edmundson C, Dahodwala N, Elman L. Reliable and efficient scale to assess upper motor neuron disease burden in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle &amp; nerve. 2020;61(4):508&#x2013;511.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31743477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellis CM, Simmons A, Andrews C, Dawson JM, Williams SC, Leigh PN. A proton magnetic resonance spectroscopic study in ALS: correlation with clinical findings. Neurology. 1998;51(4):1104&#x2013;1109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9781537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham JM, Papadakis N, Evans J, Widjaja E, Romanowski CA, Paley MN, Wallis LI, Wilkinson ID, Shaw PJ, Griffiths PD. Diffusion tensor imaging for the assessment of upper motor neuron integrity in ALS. Neurology. 2004;63(11):2111&#x2013;2119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15596758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bohannon RW, Smith MB. Interrater reliability of a modified Ashworth scale of muscle spasticity. Phys Ther. 1987;67(2):206&#x2013;207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3809245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith RA, Berg JE, Pope LE, Thisted RA. Measuring pseudobulbar affect in ALS. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and other motor neuron disorders : official publication of the World Federation of Neurology, Research Group on Motor Neuron Diseases. 2004;5 Suppl 1:99&#x2013;102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15512885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woo JH, Wang S, Melhem ER, Gee JC, Cucchiara A, McCluskey L, Elman L. Linear associations between clinically assessed upper motor neuron disease and diffusion tensor imaging metrics in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. PloS one. 2014;9(8):e105753.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4140827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25144708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brettschneider J, Toledo JB, Van Deerlin VM, Elman L, McCluskey L, Lee VM, Trojanowski JQ. Microglial activation correlates with disease progression and upper motor neuron clinical symptoms in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. PloS one. 2012;7(6):e39216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3375234</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22720079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babu S, Cernasov P, Reynolds B, Pijanowski S, Chanet J, Atassi N. Clinical relevance of quantitative upper motor neuron burden scales in ALS. Northeast ALS Consortium Meeting; Clearwater Beach, FL2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zurcher NR, Loggia ML, Lawson R, Chonde DB, Izquierdo-Garcia D, Yasek JE, Akeju O, Catana C, Rosen BR, Cudkowicz ME, et al. Increased in vivo glial activation in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: assessed with [(11)C]-PBR28. NeuroImage Clinical. 2015;7:409&#x2013;414.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4310932</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25685708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alshikho MJ, Zurcher NR, Loggia ML, Cernasov P, Reynolds B, Pijanowski O, Chonde DB, Izquierdo Garcia D, Mainero C, Catana C, et al. Integrated magnetic resonance imaging and [(11) C]-PBR28 positron emission tomographic imaging in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol. 2018;83(6):1186&#x2013;1197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6105567</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29740862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paganoni S, Alshikho MJ, Zurcher NR, Cernasov P, Babu S, Loggia ML, Chan J, Chonde DB, Garcia DI, Catana C, et al. Imaging of glia activation in people with primary lateral sclerosis. NeuroImage Clinical. 2018;17:347&#x2013;353.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5681341</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29159046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andres PL, Thibodeau LM, Finison LJ, Munsat TL. Quantitative assessment of neuromuscular deficit in ALS. Neurologic clinics. 1987;5(1):125&#x2013;141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3550414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andres PL, Skerry LM, Thornell B, Portney LG, Finison LJ, Munsat TL. A comparison of three measures of disease progression in ALS. J Neurol Sci. 1996;139 Suppl:64&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8899661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slavin MD, Jette DU, Andres PL, Munsat TL. Lower extremity muscle force measures and functional ambulation in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Archives of physical medicine and rehabilitation. 1998;79(8):950&#x2013;954.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9710168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andres PL, Skerry LM, Munsat TL, Thornell BJ, Szymonifka J, Schoenfeld DA, Cudkowicz ME. Validation of a new strength measurement device for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis clinical trials. Muscle &amp; nerve. 2012;45(1):81&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22190312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dalakas MC, Elder G, Hallett M, Ravits J, Baker M, Papadopoulos N, Albrecht P, Sever J. A long-term follow-up study of patients with post-poliomyelitis neuromuscular symptoms. The New England journal of medicine. 1986;314(15):959&#x2013;963.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3007983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rule RR, Schuff N, Miller RG, Weiner MW. Gray matter perfusion correlates with disease severity in ALS. Neurology. 2010;74(10):821&#x2013;827.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2839193</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20147656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suhy J, Miller RG, Rule R, Schuff N, Licht J, Dronsky V, Gelinas D, Maudsley AA, Weiner MW. Early detection and longitudinal changes in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis by (1)H MRSI. Neurology. 2002;58(5):773&#x2013;779.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2733360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11889242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhai P, Pagan F, Statland J, Butman JA, Floeter MK. Primary lateral sclerosis: A heterogeneous disorder composed of different subtypes? Neurology. 2003;60(8):1258&#x2013;1265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12707427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Floeter MK, Mills R. Progression in primary lateral sclerosis: a prospective analysis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2009;10(5&#x2013;6):339&#x2013;346.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3434688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19922121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang YC, Magasi SR, Bohannon RW, Reuben DB, McCreath HE, Bubela DJ, Gershon RC, Rymer WZ. Assessing dexterity function: a comparison of two alternatives for the NIH Toolbox. Journal of hand therapy : official journal of the American Society of Hand Therapists. 2011;24(4):313&#x2013;320; quiz 321.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3783205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21798715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buddenberg LA, Davis C. Test-retest reliability of the Purdue Pegboard Test. The American journal of occupational therapy : official publication of the American Occupational Therapy Association. 2000;54(5):555&#x2013;558.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11006818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pattee GL, Plowman EK, Focht Garand KL, Costello J, Brooks BR, Berry JD, Smith RA, Atassi N, Chapin JL, Yunusova Y, et al. Provisional best practices guidelines for the evaluation of bulbar dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle &amp; nerve. 2019;59(5):531&#x2013;536.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30620104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Podsiadlo D, Richardson S. The timed &#x201c;Up &amp; Go&#x201d;: a test of basic functional mobility for frail elderly persons. J Am Geriatr Soc. 1991;39(2):142&#x2013;148.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1991946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montes J, Cheng B, Diamond B, Doorish C, Mitsumoto H, Gordon PH. The Timed Up and Go test: predicting falls in ALS. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2007;8(5):292&#x2013;295.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17852012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Vries BS, Spreij LA, Rustemeijer LMM, Bakker LA, Veldink JH, van den Berg LH, Nijboer TCW, van Es MA. A neuropsychological and behavioral study of PLS. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2019;20(5&#x2013;6):376&#x2013;384.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31134825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woolley SC, York MK, Moore DH, Strutt AM, Murphy J, Schulz PE, Katz JS. Detecting frontotemporal dysfunction in ALS: utility of the ALS Cognitive Behavioral Screen (ALS-CBS). Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2010;11(3):303&#x2013;311.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20433413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abrahams S, Newton J, Niven E, Foley J, Bak TH. Screening for cognition and behaviour changes in ALS. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2014;15(1&#x2013;2):9&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23781974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke T, Hardiman O, Pinto-Grau M, Lonergan K, Heverin M, Tobin K, Staines A, Galvin M, Pender N. Longitudinal predictors of caregiver burden in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a population-based cohort of patient-caregiver dyads. J Neurol. 2018;265(4):793&#x2013;808.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29396678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burkhardt C, Neuwirth C, Weber M. Longitudinal assessment of the Edinburgh Cognitive and Behavioural Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Screen (ECAS): lack of practice effect in ALS patients? Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2017;18(3&#x2013;4):202&#x2013;209.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28165766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woolley S, Goetz R, Factor-Litvak P, Murphy J, Hupf J, Garofalo DC, Lomen-Hoerth C, Andrews H, Heitzman D, Bedlack R, et al. Longitudinal Screening Detects Cognitive Stability and Behavioral Deterioration in ALS Patients. Behavioural neurology. 2018;2018:5969137.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6234441</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30515252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menke RAL, Proudfoot M, Talbot K, Turner MR. The two-year progression of structural and functional cerebral MRI in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. NeuroImage Clinical. 2018;17:953&#x2013;961.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5752097</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29321969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proudfoot M, Menke RA, Sharma R, Berna CM, Hicks SL, Kennard C, Talbot K, Turner MR. Eye-tracking in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A longitudinal study of saccadic and cognitive tasks. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis &amp; frontotemporal degeneration. 2015;17(1&#x2013;2):101&#x2013;111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5127416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26312652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>