<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">33638255</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>12</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1468-1331</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>28</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Tau protein as a diagnostic and prognostic biomarker in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1868</StartPage><EndPage>1875</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1868-1875</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/ene.14789</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND PURPOSE">To test the hypothesis that total tau (tTau), tau phosphorylated at threonine 181 (pTau) and pTau/tTau ratio in the cerebrospinal fluid (CSF) are diagnostic and prognostic biomarkers of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS), we performed a retrospective observational study in a large cohort of ALS patients and controls.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">We enrolled 196 ALS patients and 91 controls, who included patients with ALS-mimicking diseases and those with non-neurodegenerative diseases. All patients underwent lumbar puncture for CSF analysis at the time of the diagnostic evaluation or to first referral. We measured tTau and pTau levels in the CSF by chemiluminescence enzyme immunoassay.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Patients with ALS showed significantly higher levels of CSF tTau and a lower pTau/tTau ratio than controls (tTau: 245 vs. 146&#xa0;pg/ml; p&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;0.001; pTau/tTau ratio: 0.12 vs. 0.18; p&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;0.001, respectively). No differences in pTau levels were detected. Receiver-operating characteristic curve analysis showed a good diagnostic accuracy of tTau and pTau/tTau ratio (tTau: area under the curve [AUC] 0.685, 95% confidence interval [CI] 0.616-0.754, p&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.039; pTau/tTau ratio: AUC 0.777, 95% CI 0.707-0.848, p&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;0.001). Among ALS patients, increased tTau levels were associated with advanced age of onset, increased revised amyotrophic lateral sclerosis functional rating scale (ALSFRS-R) score (&#x394;FS) rate of progression, and spinal onset. Multivariate analysis showed that in ALS patients, this biomarker was an independent negative predictor of overall survival.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Our findings suggest that tTau and pTau/tTau ratio can be diagnostic biomarkers of ALS. In addition, CSF tTau level at diagnosis might play a relevant prognostic role in the disease.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 European Academy of Neurology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Agnello</LastName><ForeName>Luisa</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedicine, Neurosciences and Advanced Diagnostics, Institute of Clinical Biochemistry, Clinical Molecular Medicine and Laboratory Medicine, University of Palermo, Palermo, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Colletti</LastName><ForeName>Tiziana</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ALS Clinical Research Center and Laboratory of Neurochemistry, Department of Biomedicine, Neuroscience and Advanced Diagnostics, University of Palermo, Palermo, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lo Sasso</LastName><ForeName>Bruna</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedicine, Neurosciences and Advanced Diagnostics, Institute of Clinical Biochemistry, Clinical Molecular Medicine and Laboratory Medicine, University of Palermo, Palermo, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Laboratory Medicine, University Hospital "P. Giaccone", Palermo, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vidali</LastName><ForeName>Matteo</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Unit of Clinical Chemistry, Maggiore della Carit&#xe0; Hospital, Novara, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Spataro</LastName><ForeName>Rossella</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>IRCSS Bonino Pulejo, Presidio Pisani, Palermo, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gambino</LastName><ForeName>Caterina Maria</ForeName><Initials>CM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedicine, Neurosciences and Advanced Diagnostics, Institute of Clinical Biochemistry, Clinical Molecular Medicine and Laboratory Medicine, University of Palermo, Palermo, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Giglio</LastName><ForeName>Rosaria Vincenza</ForeName><Initials>RV</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedicine, Neurosciences and Advanced Diagnostics, Institute of Clinical Biochemistry, Clinical Molecular Medicine and Laboratory Medicine, University of Palermo, Palermo, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Piccoli</LastName><ForeName>Tommaso</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Unit of Neurology, Department of Biomedicine, Neurosciences and Advanced Diagnostics, University of Palermo, Palermo, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bivona</LastName><ForeName>Giulia</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedicine, Neurosciences and Advanced Diagnostics, Institute of Clinical Biochemistry, Clinical Molecular Medicine and Laboratory Medicine, University of Palermo, Palermo, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>La Bella</LastName><ForeName>Vincenzo</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2045-1864</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ALS Clinical Research Center and Laboratory of Neurochemistry, Department of Biomedicine, Neuroscience and Advanced Diagnostics, University of Palermo, Palermo, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ciaccio</LastName><ForeName>Marcello</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6120-9041</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedicine, Neurosciences and Advanced Diagnostics, Institute of Clinical Biochemistry, Clinical Molecular Medicine and Laboratory Medicine, University of Palermo, Palermo, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Laboratory Medicine, University Hospital "P. Giaccone", Palermo, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D064888">Observational Study</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9506311</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1351-5101</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D015415">Biomarkers</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D016875">tau Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015415" MajorTopicYN="N">Biomarkers</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011379" MajorTopicYN="N">Prognosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012372" MajorTopicYN="N">ROC Curve</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016875" MajorTopicYN="Y">tau Proteins</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ALS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CSF</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">biomarker</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tau</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33638255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ene.14789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>EFNS Task Force on Diagnosis and Management of Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis, Andersen Peter M, Abrahams S, et al. EFNS guidelines on the Clinical Management of Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis (MALS) - revised report of an EFNS task force. Eur J Neurol. 2012;19(3):360-375.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paganoni S, Macklin EA, Lee A, et al. Diagnostic timelines and delays in diagnosing amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2014;15:453-456.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agah E, Saleh F, Sanjari Moghaddam H, Saghazadeh A, Tafakhori A, Rezaei N. CSF and blood biomarkers in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: protocol for a systematic review and meta-analysis. Syst Rev. 2018;7:237.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verber NS, Shepheard SR, Sassani M, et al. Biomarkers in motor neuron disease: a state of the art review. Front Neurol. 2019;10:291.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lo Sasso B, Agnello L, Bivona G, Bellia C, Ciaccio M. Cerebrospinal fluid analysis in multiple sclerosis diagnosis: an update. Medicina (Kaunas). 2019;55:245.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gambino CM, Sasso BL, Bivona G, Agnello L, Ciaccio M. Aging and neuroinflammatory disorders: new biomarkers and therapeutic targets. Curr Pharm Des. 2019;25:4168-4174.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarasiuk J, Ku&#x142;akowska A, Drozdowski W, Kornhuber J, Lewczuk P. CSF markers in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neural Transm (Vienna). 2012;119:747-757.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verde F, Silani V, Otto M. Neurochemical biomarkers in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Curr Opin Neurol. 2019;32:747-757.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossi D, Volanti P, Brambilla L, et al. CSF neurofilament proteins as diagnostic and prognostic biomarkers for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol. 2018;265(3):510-521.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gagliardi D, Meneri M, Saccomanno D, Bresolin N, Comi GP, Corti S. Diagnostic and prognostic role of blood and cerebrospinal fluid and blood neurofilaments in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a review of the literature. Int J Mol Sci. 2019;20:4152.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan A, Rao MV, Veeranna NRA. Neurofilaments and neurofilament proteins in health and disease. Cold Spring Harb Perspect Biol. 2017;9:a018309.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo T, Noble W, Hanger DP. Roles of tau protein in health and disease. Acta Neuropathol. 2017;133:665-704.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brunello CA, Merezhko M, Uronen RL, Huttunen HJ. Mechanisms of secretion and spreading of pathological tau protein. Cell Mol Life Sci. 2020;77:1721-1744.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agnello L, Piccoli T, Vidali M, et al. Diagnostic accuracy of cerebrospinal fluid biomarkers measured by chemiluminescent enzyme immunoassay for Alzheimer disease diagnosis. Scand J Clin Lab Invest. 2020;80:313-317.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brettschneider J, Petzold A, S&#xfc;ssmuth SD, Ludolph AC, Tumani H. Axonal damage markers in cerebrospinal fluid are increased in ALS. Neurology. 2006;66:852-856.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paladino P, Valentino F, Piccoli T, Piccoli F, La Bella V. Cerebrospinal fluid tau protein is not a biological marker in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Eur J Neurol. 2009;16:257-261.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xfc;ssmuth SD, Sperfeld AD, Hinz A, et al. CSF glial markers correlate with survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology. 2010;74:982-987.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xfc;ssmuth SD, Tumani H, Ecker D, Ludolph AC. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: disease stage related changes of tau protein and S100 beta in cerebrospinal fluid and creatine kinase in serum. Neurosci Lett. 2003;353:57-60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilke C, Deuschle C, Rattay TW, Maetzler W, Synofzik M. Total tau is increased, but phosphorylated tau not decreased, in cerebrospinal fluid in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurobiol Aging. 2015;36:1072-1074.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schreiber S, Spotorno N, Schreiber F, et al. Significance of CSF NfL and tau in ALS. J Neurol. 2018;265:2633-2645.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jim&#xe9;nez-Jim&#xe9;nez FJ, Hern&#xe1;nz A, Medina-Acebr&#xf3;n S, et al. Tau protein concentrations in cerebrospinal fluid of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neurol Scand. 2005;111:114-117.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bourbouli M, Rentzos M, Bougea A, et al. Cerebrospinal Fluid TAR DNA-Binding Protein 43 Combined with Tau Proteins as a Candidate Biomarker for Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis and Frontotemporal Dementia Spectrum Disorders. Dement Geriatr Cogn Disord. 2017;44:144-152.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grossman M, Elman L, McCluskey L, et al. Phosphorylated tau as a candidate biomarker for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. JAMA Neurol. 2014;71:442-448.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scarafino A, D'Errico E, Introna A, et al. Diagnostic and prognostic power of CSF Tau in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol. 2018;265:2353-2362.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lanznaster D, Hergesheimer RC, Bakkouche SE, et al. A&#x3b2;1-42 and Tau as potential biomarkers for diagnosis and prognosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Int J Mol Sci. 2020;21:2911.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abu-Rumeileh S, Vacchiano V, Zenesini C, et al. Diagnostic-prognostic value and electrophysiological correlates of CSF biomarkers of neurodegeneration and neuroinflammation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol. 2020;267:1699-1708.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasai T, Kojima Y, Ohmichi T, et al. Combined use of CSF NfL and CSF TDP-43 improves diagnostic performance in ALS. Ann Clin Transl Neurol. 2019;6:2489-2502.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, Miller RG, Swash M, Munsat TL. World federation of neurology research group on motor neuron diseases. El Escorial revisited: revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord. 2000;1:293-299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ALS Cntf Treatment Phase I-II Study Group. The amyotrophic lateral sclerosis functional rating scale. Assessment of activities of daily living in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Arch Neurol. 1996;53:141-147.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kimura F, Fujimura C, Ishida S, et al. Progression rate of ALSFRS-R at time of diagnosis predicts survival time in ALS. Neurology. 2006;66:265-267.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>del Campo M, Mollenhauer B, Bertolotto A, et al. Recommendations to standardize preanalytical confounding factors in Alzheimer's and Parkinson's disease cerebrospinal fluid biomarkers: an update. Biomark Med. 2012;6:419-430.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kollhoff AL, Howell JC, Hu WT. Automation vs. Experience: Measuring Alzheimer's Beta-Amyloid 1-42 Peptide in the CSF. Front Aging Neurosci. 2018;10:253.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bayart JL, Hanseeuw B, Ivanoiu A, et al. Analytical and clinical performances of the automated Lumipulse cerebrospinal fluid A&#x3b2;42 and T-Tau assays for Alzheimer's disease diagnosis. J Neurol. 2019;266:2304-2311.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ballatore C, Lee VM, Trojanowski JQ. Tau-mediated neurodegeneration in Alzheimer's disease and related disorders. Nat Rev Neurosci. 2007;8:663-672.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vickers JC, Mitew S, Woodhouse A, et al. Defining the earliest pathological changes of Alzheimer's disease. Curr Alzheimer Res. 2016;13:281-287.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pijnenburg YA, Verwey NA, van der Flier WM, Scheltens P, Teunissen CE. Discriminative and prognostic potential of cerebrospinal fluid phosphoTau/tau ratio and neurofilaments for frontotemporal dementia subtypes. Alzheimers Dement (Amst). 2015;1:505-512.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>