<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">33686758</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>12</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1468-1331</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>28</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Chinese validation of the Rasch-Built Overall Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Disability Scale.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1876</StartPage><EndPage>1883</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1876-1883</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/ene.14811</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND PURPOSE">The Rasch-Built Overall Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Disability Scale (ROADS) was developed using Rasch methodology. This scale has been demonstrated as a reliable outcome measure of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) trials. To date, there are no similar interval-weighted scales to assess disability in ALS patients. The current study aimed to validate a Chinese version of the ROADS via Rasch methodology.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">The Chinese version of the ROADS was obtained through a standardized forward-backward translation and cultural adaptation. ALS patients were recruited from the Department of Neurology of Peking University Third Hospital in Beijing, China to complete the ROADS and the revised ALS Functional Rating Scale (ALSFRS-R). Overall, 254 participants with ALS finished the Chinese scale. Rasch analysis was performed on the ROADS for validation and the ALSFRS-R for comparison.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">The Chinese version of the ROADS was modified according to the statistical results. A final 28-question scale was constructed that fulfilled all the requirements of the Rasch model with proper validity and reliability. Furthermore, the ROADS showed improved item targeting compared to the ALSFRS-R. Conversely, the ALSFRS-R did not fit the Rasch model expectations due to misfit values and disordered thresholds for all 12 items.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">The Chinese adaptation of the ROADS is a linearly weighted scale that specifically captures overall disability in ALS patients. This scale indicates a wider range of item difficulties and better responsiveness than the ALSFRS-R. The ROADS could be used as a valuable tool for use in ALS trials and in the clinic in Chinese settings.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 European Academy of Neurology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sun</LastName><ForeName>Can</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Peking University Third Hospital, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Beijing Municipal Key Laboratory of Biomarker and Translational Research in Neurodegenerative Diseases, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fournier</LastName><ForeName>Christina N</ForeName><Initials>CN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Emory University, Atlanta, GA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ye</LastName><ForeName>Shan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Peking University Third Hospital, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Beijing Municipal Key Laboratory of Biomarker and Translational Research in Neurodegenerative Diseases, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Nan</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Peking University Third Hospital, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Beijing Municipal Key Laboratory of Biomarker and Translational Research in Neurodegenerative Diseases, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ma</LastName><ForeName>Yan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Peking University Third Hospital, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Beijing Municipal Key Laboratory of Biomarker and Translational Research in Neurodegenerative Diseases, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fan</LastName><ForeName>Dongsheng</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6679-0864</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Peking University Third Hospital, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Beijing Municipal Key Laboratory of Biomarker and Translational Research in Neurodegenerative Diseases, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory for Neuroscience, National Health Commission/Ministry of Education, Peking University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9506311</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1351-5101</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D044466" MajorTopicYN="N">Asian People</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002681" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">China</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006233" MajorTopicYN="Y">Disabled Persons</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015203" MajorTopicYN="N">Reproducibility of Results</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Chinese</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Rasch analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">scale</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">validation</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33686758</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ene.14811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Westeneng H-J, Debray TPA, Visser AE, et al. Prognosis for patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: development and validation of a personalised prediction model. Lancet Neurol. 2018;17:423-433.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goyal NA, Berry JD, Windebank A, et al. Addressing heterogeneity in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis CLINICAL TRIALS. Muscle Nerve. 2020;62:156-166.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum JM, Stambler N, Malta E, et al. The ALSFRS-R: a revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. BDNF ALS Study Group (Phase III). J Neurol Sci. 1999;169:13-21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mora JS, Genge A, Chio A, et al. Masitinib as an add-on therapy to riluzole in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a randomized clinical trial. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2020;21:5-14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Statland JM, Moore D, Wang Y, et al. Rasagiline for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a randomized, controlled trial. Muscle Nerve. 2019;59:201-207.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franchignoni F, Mora G, Giordano A, Volanti P, Chio A. Evidence of multidimensionality in the ALSFRS-R Scale: a critical appraisal on its measurement properties using Rasch analysis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2013;84:1340-1345.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franchignoni F, Mandrioli J, Giordano A, Ferro S; Group E. A further Rasch study confirms that ALSFRS-R does not conform to fundamental measurement requirements. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2015;16:331-337.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rooney J, Burke T, Vajda A, Heverin M, Hardiman O. What does the ALSFRS-R really measure? A longitudinal and survival analysis of functional dimension subscores in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2017;88:381-385.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeVellis RF. Classical test theory. Med Care. 2006;44:S50-S59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rasch G. Probabilistic Models for Some Intelligence and Attainment Tests. Copenhagen: Institute of Educational Research; 1960.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Narayanaswami P. The spectrum of functional rating scales in neurology clinical trials. Neurotherapeutics. 2017;14:161-175.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vanhoutte EK, Hermans MCE, Faber CG, et al. Rasch-ionale for neurologists. J Peripher Nerv Syst. 2015;20:260-268.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khadka J, Huang J, Mollazadegan K, et al. Translation, cultural adaptation, and Rasch analysis of the visual function (VF-14) questionnaire. Invest Ophthalmol Vis Sci. 2014;55:4413-4420.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fournier CN, Bedlack R, Quinn C, et al. Development and validation of the Rasch-Built Overall Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Disability Scale (ROADS). JAMA Neurol. 2020;77:480-488.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, Miller RG, Swash M, Munsat TL; World Federation of Neurology Research Group on Motor Neuron D. El Escorial revisited: revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord. 2000;1:293-299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linacre JM. Rasch analysis of rank-ordered data. J Appl Meas. 2006;7:129-139.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Binda D, Vanhoutte EK, Cavaletti G, et al. Rasch-built Overall Disability Scale for patients with chemotherapy-induced peripheral neuropathy (CIPN-R-ODS). Eur J Cancer. 2013;49:2910-2918.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Nes SI, Vanhoutte EK, van Doorn PA, et al. Rasch-built Overall Disability Scale (R-ODS) for immune-mediated peripheral neuropathies. Neurology. 2011;76:337-345.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linacre J. Sample size and item calibration stability. Rasch Meas Trans. 1994;7:328.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wyse AE. Scale Anchoring with the Rasch model. J Appl Meas. 2017;18:43-53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher WP. Reliability statistics. Rasch Meas Trans. 1992;6:238.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bland JM, Altman DG. Cronbach's alpha. BMJ. 1997;314:572.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linacre JM. A User&#x2019;s guide to WINSTEPS Ministeps: Rasch-model computer program. Program Manual 37170 Beaverton, OR; 2011. www.winstep.com.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon PH, Miller RG, Moore DH. ALSFRS-R. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord. 2004;5(suppl 1):90-93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaufmann P, Levy G, Montes J, et al. Excellent inter-rater, intra-rater, and telephone-administered reliability of the ALSFRS-R in a multicenter clinical trial. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2007;8:42-46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hobart JC, Cano SJ, Zajicek JP, Thompson AJ. Rating scales as outcome measures for clinical trials in neurology: problems, solutions, and recommendations. Lancet Neurol. 2007;6:1094-1105.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bendotti C, Bonetto V, Pupillo E, et al. Focus on the heterogeneity of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2020;21:485-495.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>