<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">33736701</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>08</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1757-6512</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>12</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Stem cell research &amp; therapy</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Stem Cell Res Ther</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Alterations of mesenchymal stromal cells in cerebrospinal fluid: insights from transcriptomics and an ALS clinical trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>187</StartPage><MedlinePgn>187</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">187</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13287-021-02241-9</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Mesenchymal stromal cells (MSCs) have been studied with increasing intensity as clinicians and researchers strive to understand the ability of MSCs to modulate disease progression and promote tissue regeneration. As MSCs are used for diverse applications, it is important to appreciate how specific physiological environments may stimulate changes that alter the phenotype of the cells. One need for neuroregenerative applications is to characterize the spectrum of MSC responses to the cerebrospinal fluid (CSF) environment after their injection into the intrathecal space. Mechanistic understanding of cellular biology in response to the CSF environment may predict the ability of MSCs to promote injury repair or provide neuroprotection in neurodegenerative diseases.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">In this study, we characterized changes in morphology, metabolism, and gene expression occurring in human adipose-derived MSCs cultured in human (hCSF) or artificial CSF (aCSF) as well as examined relevant protein levels in the CSF of subjects treated with MSCs for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Our results demonstrated that, under intrathecal-like conditions, MSCs retained their morphology, though they became quiescent. Large-scale transcriptomic analysis of MSCs revealed a distinct gene expression profile for cells cultured in aCSF. The aCSF culture environment induced expression of genes related to angiogenesis and immunomodulation. In addition, MSCs in aCSF expressed genes encoding nutritional growth factors to expression levels at or above those of control cells. Furthermore, we observed a dose-dependent increase in growth factors and immunomodulatory cytokines in CSF from subjects with ALS treated intrathecally with autologous MSCs.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Overall, our results suggest that MSCs injected into the intrathecal space in ongoing clinical trials remain viable and may provide a therapeutic benefit to patients.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Krull</LastName><ForeName>Ashley A</ForeName><Initials>AA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Mayo Clinic, 200 First St. SW, Rochester, MN, 55905, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Setter</LastName><ForeName>Deborah O</ForeName><Initials>DO</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Mayo Clinic, 200 First St. SW, Rochester, MN, 55905, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gendron</LastName><ForeName>Tania F</ForeName><Initials>TF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience, Mayo Clinic, Jacksonville, FL, 32224, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hrstka</LastName><ForeName>Sybil C L</ForeName><Initials>SCL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Mayo Clinic, 200 First St. SW, Rochester, MN, 55905, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Polzin</LastName><ForeName>Michael J</ForeName><Initials>MJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Mayo Clinic, 200 First St. SW, Rochester, MN, 55905, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hart</LastName><ForeName>Joseph</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Mayo Clinic, 200 First St. SW, Rochester, MN, 55905, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dudakovic</LastName><ForeName>Amel</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedic Surgery, Mayo Clinic, Rochester, MN, 55905, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Madigan</LastName><ForeName>Nicolas N</ForeName><Initials>NN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Mayo Clinic, 200 First St. SW, Rochester, MN, 55905, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dietz</LastName><ForeName>Allan B</ForeName><Initials>AB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Laboratory Medicine and Pathology, Mayo Clinic, Rochester, MN, 55905, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Windebank</LastName><ForeName>Anthony J</ForeName><Initials>AJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Mayo Clinic, 200 First St. SW, Rochester, MN, 55905, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>van Wijnen</LastName><ForeName>Andre J</ForeName><Initials>AJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedic Surgery, Mayo Clinic, Rochester, MN, 55905, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Staff</LastName><ForeName>Nathan P</ForeName><Initials>NP</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6760-3859</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Mayo Clinic, 200 First St. SW, Rochester, MN, 55905, USA. Staff.Nathan@mayo.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Stem Cell Res Ther</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101527581</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1757-6512</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D016207">Cytokines</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016207" MajorTopicYN="N">Cytokines</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D056747" MajorTopicYN="N">Immunomodulation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D045164" MajorTopicYN="Y">Mesenchymal Stem Cell Transplantation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D059630" MajorTopicYN="Y">Mesenchymal Stem Cells</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D059467" MajorTopicYN="N">Transcriptome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cerebrospinal fluid</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Gene expression</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Growth factors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Human studies</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mesenchymal stromal cell</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neuroinflammation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors indicated no potential conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33736701</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7977179</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13287-021-02241-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13287-021-02241-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Akaishi T, Onishi E, Abe M, Toyama H, Ishizawa K, Kumagai M, Kubo R, Nakashima I, Aoki M, Yamauchi M, et al. The human central nervous system discharges carbon dioxide and lactic acid into the cerebrospinal fluid. Fluids Barriers CNS. 2019;16(1):8&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6440017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30922337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J, Goodlett DR, Peskind ER, Quinn JF, Zhou Y, Wang Q, Pan C, Yi E, Eng J, Aebersold RH, et al. Quantitative proteomic analysis of age-related changes in human cerebrospinal fluid. Neurobiol Aging. 2005;26(2):207&#x2013;227.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15582749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell RM, Freeman WM, Randazzo WT, Stephens HE, Beard JL, Simmons Z, Connor JR. A CSF biomarker panel for identification of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology. 2009;72(1):14&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18987350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heywood WE, Galimberti D, Bliss E, Sirka E, Paterson RW, Magdalinou NK, Carecchio M, Reid E, Heslegrave A, Fenoglio C, et al. Identification of novel CSF biomarkers for neurodegeneration and their validation by a high-throughput multiplexed targeted proteomic assay. Mol Neurodegener. 2015;10(1):64&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4666172</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26627638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kroksveen AC, Opsahl JA, Guldbrandsen A, Myhr KM, Oveland E, Torkildsen O, Berven FS. Cerebrospinal fluid proteomics in multiple sclerosis. Biochim Biophys Acta. 2015;1854(7):746&#x2013;756.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25526888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Potier E, Ferreira E, Meunier A, Sedel L, Logeart-Avramoglou D, Petite H. Prolonged hypoxia concomitant with serum deprivation induces massive human mesenchymal stem cell death. Tissue Eng. 2007;13(6):1325&#x2013;1331.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17518749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crespo-Diaz R, Behfar A, Butler GW, Padley DJ, Sarr MG, Bartunek J, Dietz AB, Terzic A. Platelet lysate consisting of a natural repair proteome supports human mesenchymal stem cell proliferation and chromosomal stability. Cell Transplant. 2011;20(6):797&#x2013;811.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21092406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ueyama H, Horibe T, Hinotsu S, Tanaka T, Inoue T, Urushihara H, Kitagawa A, Kawakami K. Chromosomal variability of human mesenchymal stem cells cultured under hypoxic conditions. J Cell Mol Med. 2012;16(1):72&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3823094</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21418515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohta M, Suzuki Y, Noda T, Ejiri Y, Dezawa M, Kataoka K, Chou H, Ishikawa N, Matsumoto N, Iwashita Y, et al. Bone marrow stromal cells infused into the cerebrospinal fluid promote functional recovery of the injured rat spinal cord with reduced cavity formation. Exp Neurol. 2004;187(2):266&#x2013;278.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15144853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zurita M, Vaquero J. Functional recovery in chronic paraplegia after bone marrow stromal cells transplantation. Neuroreport. 2004;15(7):1105&#x2013;1108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15129154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrou P, Gothelf Y, Argov Z, Gotkine M, Levy YS, Kassis I, Vaknin-Dembinsky A, Ben-Hur T, Offen D, Abramsky O, et al. Safety and clinical effects of Mesenchymal stem cells secreting Neurotrophic factor transplantation in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: results of phase 1/2 and 2a clinical trials. JAMA Neurol. 2016;73(3):337&#x2013;344.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26751635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oikonomopoulos A, van Deen WK, Manansala A-R, Lacey PN, Tomakili TA, Ziman A, Hommes DW. Optimization of human mesenchymal stem cell manufacturing: the effects of animal/xeno-free media. Sci Rep. 2015;5(1):16570.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4643287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26564250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juhl M, Tratwal J, Follin B, S&#xf8;ndergaard RH, Kirchhoff M, Ekblond A, Kastrup J, Haack-S&#xf8;rensen M. Comparison of clinical grade human platelet lysates for cultivation of mesenchymal stromal cells from bone marrow and adipose tissue. Scand J Clin Lab Invest. 2016;76(2):93&#x2013;104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26878874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brun J, Abruzzese T, Rolauffs B, Aicher WK, Hart ML. Choice of xenogenic-free expansion media significantly influences the myogenic differentiation potential of human bone marrow&#x2013;derived mesenchymal stromal cells. Cytotherapy. 2016;18(3):344&#x2013;359.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26857228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Becherucci V, Piccini L, Casamassima S, Bisin S, Gori V, Gentile F, Ceccantini R, De Rienzo E, Bindi B, Pavan P, et al. Human platelet lysate in mesenchymal stromal cell expansion according to a GMP grade protocol: a cell factory experience. Stem Cell Res Ther. 2018;9(1):124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5930506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29720245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singer W, Dietz AB, Zeller AD, Gehrking TL, Schmelzer JD, Schmeichel AM, Gehrking JA, Suarez MD, Sletten DM, Minota Pacheco KV, et al. Intrathecal administration of autologous mesenchymal stem cells in multiple system atrophy. Neurology. 2019;93(1):e77&#x2013;e87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6659003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31152011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Staff NP, Madigan NN, Morris J, Jentoft M, Sorenson EJ, Butler G, Gastineau D, Dietz A, Windebank AJ. Safety of intrathecal autologous adipose-derived mesenchymal stromal cells in patients with ALS. Neurology. 2016;87(21):2230&#x2013;2234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5123559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27784774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bydon M, Dietz AB, Goncalves S, Moinuddin FM, Alvi MA, Goyal A, Yolcu Y, Hunt CL, Garlanger KL, Del Fabro AS, et al. CELLTOP clinical trial: first report from a phase 1 trial of autologous adipose tissue-derived Mesenchymal stem cells in the treatment of paralysis due to traumatic spinal cord injury. Mayo Clin Proc. 2020;95(2):406&#x2013;414.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31785831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mader EK, Butler G, Dowdy SC, Mariani A, Knutson KL, Federspiel MJ, Russell SJ, Galanis E, Dietz AB, Peng KW. Optimizing patient derived mesenchymal stem cells as virus carriers for a phase I clinical trial in ovarian cancer. J Transl Med. 2013;11:20&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3567956</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23347343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dudakovic A, Camilleri E, Riester SM, Lewallen EA, Kvasha S, Chen X, Radel DJ, Anderson JM, Nair AA, Evans JM, et al. High-resolution molecular validation of self-renewal and spontaneous differentiation in clinical-grade adipose-tissue derived human mesenchymal stem cells. J Cell Biochem. 2014;115(10):1816&#x2013;1828.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4225070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24905804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalari KR, Nair AA, Bhavsar JD, O'Brien DR, Davila JI, Bockol MA, Nie J, Tang X, Baheti S, Doughty JB, et al. MAP-RSeq: Mayo analysis pipeline for RNA sequencing. BMC Bioinformatics. 2014;15:224.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4228501</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24972667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trapnell C, Pachter L, Salzberg SL. TopHat: discovering splice junctions with RNA-Seq. Bioinformatics. 2009;25(9):1105&#x2013;1111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2672628</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19289445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu Z, Eils R, Schlesner M. Complex heatmaps reveal patterns and correlations in multidimensional genomic data. Bioinformatics. 2016;32(18):2847&#x2013;2849.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27207943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang da W, Sherman BT, Lempicki RA. Systematic and integrative analysis of large gene lists using DAVID bioinformatics resources. Nat Protoc. 2009;4(1):44&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19131956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang da W, Sherman BT, Lempicki RA. Bioinformatics enrichment tools: paths toward the comprehensive functional analysis of large gene lists. Nucleic Acids Res. 2009;37(1):1&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2615629</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19033363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Subramanian A, Tamayo P, Mootha VK, Mukherjee S, Ebert BL, Gillette MA, Paulovich A, Pomeroy SL, Golub TR, Lander ES, et al. Gene set enrichment analysis: a knowledge-based approach for interpreting genome-wide expression profiles. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2005;102(43):15545&#x2013;15550.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1239896</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16199517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mootha VK, Lindgren CM, Eriksson KF, Subramanian A, Sihag S, Lehar J, Puigserver P, Carlsson E, Ridderstrale M, Laurila E, et al. PGC-1alpha-responsive genes involved in oxidative phosphorylation are coordinately downregulated in human diabetes. Nat Genet. 2003;34(3):267&#x2013;273.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12808457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reimand J, Isserlin R, Voisin V, Kucera M, Tannus-Lopes C, Rostamianfar A, Wadi L, Meyer M, Wong J, Xu C, et al. Pathway enrichment analysis and visualization of omics data using g:Profiler, GSEA, Cytoscape and EnrichmentMap. Nat Protoc. 2019;14(2):482&#x2013;517.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6607905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30664679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bourin P, Bunnell BA, Casteilla L, Dominici M, Katz AJ, March KL, Redl H, Rubin JP, Yoshimura K, Gimble JM. Stromal cells from the adipose tissue-derived stromal vascular fraction and culture expanded adipose tissue-derived stromal/stem cells: a joint statement of the International Federation for Adipose Therapeutics and Science (IFATS) and the International Society for Cellular Therapy (ISCT) Cytotherapy. 2013;15(6):641&#x2013;648.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3979435</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23570660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baer PC, Ku&#xe7;i S, Krause M, Ku&#xe7;i Z, Zielen S, Geiger H, Bader P, Schubert R. Comprehensive phenotypic characterization of human adipose-derived stromal/stem cells and their subsets by a high throughput technology. Stem Cells Dev. 2013;22(2):330&#x2013;339.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22920587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Camilleri ET, Gustafson MP, Dudakovic A, Riester SM, Garces CG, Paradise CR, Takai H, Karperien M, Cool S, Sampen HJ, et al. Identification and validation of multiple cell surface markers of clinical-grade adipose-derived mesenchymal stromal cells as novel release criteria for good manufacturing practice-compliant production. Stem Cell Res Ther. 2016;7(1):107&#x2013;122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4982273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27515308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Apostolou E, Hochedlinger K. Chromatin dynamics during cellular reprogramming. Nature. 2013;502(7472):462&#x2013;471.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4216318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24153299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye X, Zerlanko B, Kennedy A, Banumathy G, Zhang R, Adams Peter D. Downregulation of Wnt signaling is a trigger for formation of facultative heterochromatin and onset of cell senescence in primary human cells. Mol Cell. 2007;27(2):183&#x2013;196.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2698096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17643369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis EK, Zou Y, Ghosh A. Wnts acting through canonical and noncanonical signaling pathways exert opposite effects on hippocampal synapse formation. Neural Dev. 2008;3:32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2596118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18986540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen C-M, Orefice LL, Chiu S-L, LeGates TA, Hattar S, Huganir RL, Zhao H, Xu B, Kuruvilla R. Wnt5a is essential for hippocampal dendritic maintenance and spatial learning and memory in adult mice. Proc Natl Acad Sci. 2017;114(4):E619&#x2013;E628.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5278440</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28069946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zacchigna S, Lambrechts D, Carmeliet P. Neurovascular signalling defects in neurodegeneration. Nat Rev Neurosci. 2008;9:169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18253131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagmann S, Moradi B, Frank S, Dreher T, Kammerer PW, Richter W, Gotterbarm T. Different culture media affect growth characteristics, surface marker distribution and chondrogenic differentiation of human bone marrow-derived mesenchymal stromal cells. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2013;14:223.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3734101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23898974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berry JD, Cudkowicz ME, Windebank AJ, Staff NP, Owegi M, Nicholson K, McKenna-Yasek D, Levy YS, Abramov N, Kaspi H, et al. NurOwn, phase 2, randomized, clinical trial in patients with ALS: safety, clinical, and biomarker results. Neurology. 2019;93(24):e2294&#x2013;e2305.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6937497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31740545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh KW, Noh MY, Kwon MS, Kim HY, Oh SI, Park J, Kim HJ, Ki CS, Kim SH. Repeated intrathecal mesenchymal stem cells for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol. 2018;84(3):361&#x2013;373.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6175096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30048006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao CP, Zhang C, Zhou SN, Xie YM, Wang YH, Huang H, Shang YC, Li WY, Zhou C, Yu MJ, et al. Human mesenchymal stromal cells ameliorate the phenotype of SOD1-G93A ALS mice. Cytotherapy. 2007;9(5):414&#x2013;426.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17786603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forostyak S, Homola A, Turnovcova K, Svitil P, Jendelova P, Sykova E. Intrathecal delivery of mesenchymal stromal cells protects the structure of altered perineuronal nets in SOD1 rats and amends the course of ALS. Stem Cells. 2014;32(12):3163&#x2013;3172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4321196</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25113670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Staff NP, Jones DT, Singer W. Mesenchymal stromal cell therapies for neurodegenerative diseases. Mayo Clin Proc. 2019;94(5):892&#x2013;905.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6643282</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31054608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dominici M, Le Blanc K, Mueller I, Slaper-Cortenbach I, Marini F, Krause D, Deans R, Keating A, Prockop D, Horwitz E. Minimal criteria for defining multipotent mesenchymal stromal cells. The International Society for Cellular Therapy position statement. Cytotherapy. 2006;8(4):315&#x2013;317.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16923606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boido M, Piras A, Valsecchi V, Spigolon G, Mareschi K, Ferrero I, Vizzini A, Temi S, Mazzini L, Fagioli F, et al. Human mesenchymal stromal cell transplantation modulates neuroinflammatory milieu in a mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Cytotherapy. 2014;16(8):1059&#x2013;1072.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24794182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beers DR, Zhao W, Wang J, Zhang X, Wen S, Neal D, Thonhoff JR, Alsuliman AS, Shpall EJ, Rezvani K, et al. ALS patients&#x2019; regulatory T lymphocytes are dysfunctional, and correlate with disease progression rate and severity. JCI Insight. 2017;2(5):e89530.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5333967</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28289705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gustafson MP, Staff NP, Bornschlegl S, Butler GW, Maas ML, Kazamel M, Zubair A, Gastineau DA, Windebank AJ, Dietz AB. Comprehensive immune profiling reveals substantial immune system alterations in a subset of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Plos One. 2017;12(7):e0182002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5526569</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28742871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murdock BJ, Zhou T, Kashlan SR, Little RJ, Goutman SA, Feldman EL. Correlation of peripheral immunity with rapid amyotrophic lateral sclerosis progression. JAMA Neurol. 2017;74(12):1446&#x2013;1454.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5822195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28973548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zurcher NR, Loggia ML, Lawson R, Chonde DB, Izquierdo-Garcia D, Yasek JE, Akeju O, Catana C, Rosen BR, Cudkowicz ME, et al. Increased in vivo glial activation in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: assessed with [(11)C]-PBR28. Neuroimage Clin. 2015;7:409&#x2013;414.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4310932</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25685708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gille B, De Schaepdryver M, Dedeene L, Goossens J, Claeys KG, Van Den Bosch L, Tournoy J, Van Damme P, Poesen K. Inflammatory markers in cerebrospinal fluid: independent prognostic biomarkers in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis? J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2019;90(12):1338&#x2013;1346.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31175169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kinnaird T, Stabile E, Burnett MS, Shou M, Lee CW, Barr S, Fuchs S, Epstein SE. Local delivery of marrow-derived stromal cells augments collateral perfusion through paracrine mechanisms. Circulation. 2004;109(12):1543&#x2013;1549.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15023891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oskowitz A, McFerrin H, Gutschow M, Carter ML, Pochampally R. Serum-deprived human multipotent mesenchymal stromal cells (MSCs) are highly angiogenic. Stem Cell Res. 2011;6(3):215&#x2013;225.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4920087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21421339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung E, Rytlewski JA, Merchant AG, Dhada KS, Lewis EW, Suggs LJ. Fibrin-based 3D matrices induce angiogenic behavior of adipose-derived stem cells. Acta Biomater. 2015;17:78&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4380681</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25600400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang-Hu H, Xiao-Ming Y, Yang X, Chun-Cai X, Xi L, Fu-Biao Y, Yong C, Fei-Yue L. Systemic administration of exosomes released from mesenchymal stromal cells attenuates apoptosis, inflammation, and promotes angiogenesis after spinal cord injury in rats. J Neurotrauma. 2017;34(24):3388&#x2013;3396.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28665182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ankeny DP, McTigue DM, Jakeman LB. Bone marrow transplants provide tissue protection and directional guidance for axons after contusive spinal cord injury in rats. Exp Neurol. 2004;190(1):17&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15473977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu P, Jones LL, Tuszynski MH. BDNF-expressing marrow stromal cells support extensive axonal growth at sites of spinal cord injury. Exp Neurol. 2005;191(2):344&#x2013;360.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15649491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krakora D, Mulcrone P, Meyer M, Lewis C, Bernau K, Gowing G, Zimprich C, Aebischer P, Svendsen CN, Suzuki M. Synergistic effects of GDNF and VEGF on lifespan and disease progression in a familial ALS rat model. Mol Ther. 2013;21(8):1602&#x2013;1610.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3734670</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23712039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cruz-Martinez P, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Granero S, Molina-Navarro MM, Pacheco-Torres J, Garc&#xed;a-Verdugo JM, Geijo-Barrientos E, Jones J, Martinez S. Intraventricular injections of mesenchymal stem cells activate endogenous functional remyelination in a chronic demyelinating murine model. Cell Death Dis. 2016;7:e2223&#x2013;e2234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4917663</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27171265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oosthuyse B, Moons L, Storkebaum E, Beck H, Nuyens D, Brusselmans K, Dorpe JV, Hellings P, Gorselink M, Heymans S, et al. Deletion of the hypoxia-response element in the vascular endothelial growth factor promoter causes motor neuron degeneration. Nat Genet. 2001;28(2):131&#x2013;138.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11381259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lambrechts D, Storkebaum E, Morimoto M, Del-Favero J, Desmet F, Marklund SL, Wyns S, Thijs V, Andersson J, van Marion I. VEGF is a modifier of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in mice and humans and protects motoneurons against ischemic death. Nat Genet. 2003;34(4):383&#x2013;394.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12847526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Storkebaum E, Lambrechts D, Dewerchin M, Moreno-Murciano M-P, Appelmans S, Oh H, Van Damme P, Rutten B, Man WY, De Mol M. Treatment of motoneuron degeneration by intracerebroventricular delivery of VEGF in a rat model of ALS. Nat Neurosci. 2005;8(1):85&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15568021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun Y, Jin K, Xie L, Childs J, Mao XO, Logvinova A, Greenberg DA. VEGF-induced neuroprotection, neurogenesis, and angiogenesis after focal cerebral ischemia. J Clin Invest. 2003;111(12):1843&#x2013;1851.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC161428</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12813020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Jin K, Mao XO, Xie L, Banwait S, Marti HH, Greenberg DA. VEGF-overexpressing transgenic mice show enhanced post-ischemic neurogenesis and neuromigration. J Neurosci Res. 2007;85(4):740&#x2013;747.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17243175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazzini L, Mareschi K, Ferrero I, Miglioretti M, Stecco A, Servo S, Carriero A, Monaco F, Fagioli F. Mesenchymal stromal cell transplantation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a long-term safety study. Cytotherapy. 2012;14(1):56&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21954839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>