<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">33745185</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>07</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-0177</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>251</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Developmental dynamics : an official publication of the American Association of Anatomists</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Dev Dyn</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>BMP/TGF-&#x3b2; signaling as a modulator of neurodegeneration in ALS.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>10</StartPage><EndPage>25</EndPage><MedlinePgn>10-25</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/dvdy.333</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This commentary focuses on the emerging intersection between BMP/TGF-&#x3b2; signaling roles in nervous system function and the amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) disease state. Future research is critical to elucidate the molecular underpinnings of this intersection of the cellular processes disrupted in ALS and those influenced by BMP/TGF-&#x3b2; signaling, including synapse structure, neurotransmission, plasticity, and neuroinflammation. Such knowledge promises to inform us of ideal entry points for the targeted modulation of dysfunctional cellular processes in an effort to abrogate ALS pathologies. It is likely that different interventions are required, either at discrete points in disease progression, or across multiple dysfunctional processes which together lead to motor neuron degeneration and death. We discuss the challenging, but intriguing idea that modulation of the pleiotropic nature of BMP/TGF-&#x3b2; signaling could be advantageous, as a way to simultaneously treat defects in more than one cell process across different forms of ALS.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 American Association of Anatomists.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Russo</LastName><ForeName>Kathryn</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience, Brown University, Providence, Rhode Island, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Robert J. and Nancy D. Carney Institute for Brain Science, Brown University, Providence, Rhode Island, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wharton</LastName><ForeName>Kristi A</ForeName><Initials>KA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9625-4336</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Robert J. and Nancy D. Carney Institute for Brain Science, Brown University, Providence, Rhode Island, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Molecular Biology, Cell Biology, and Biochemistry, Brown University, Providence, Rhode Island, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>GM068118</GrantID><Acronym>GM</Acronym><Agency>NIGMS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>T32 MH020068</GrantID><Acronym>MH</Acronym><Agency>NIMH NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Dev Dyn</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9201927</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1058-8388</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D016212">Transforming Growth Factor beta</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018450" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Progression</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016212" MajorTopicYN="N">Transforming Growth Factor beta</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ALS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">BMP signaling</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">LIMK</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Smad</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">TGF-&#x3b2; signaling</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">actin dynamics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">importin-&#x3b2;</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mad</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neurodegeneration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nucleocytoplasmic transport</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">p38/MAPK</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33745185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/dvdy.333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Wang RN, Green J, Wang Z, et al. Bone morphogenetic protein (BMP) signaling in development and human diseases. Genes Dis. 2014;1(1):87-105. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.gendis.2014.07.005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Derynck R, Zhang YE. Smad-dependent and Smad-independent pathways in TGF. Nature. 2003;425(6958):577-584.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tzavlaki K, Moustakas A. TGF-&#x3b2; signaling. Biomolecules. 2020;10(3):487-525. https://doi.org/10.3390/biom10030487.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bragdon B, Moseychuk O, Saldanha S, King D, Julian J, Nohe A. Bone morphogenetic proteins: a critical review. Cell Signal. 2011;23(4):609-620. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cellsig.2010.10.003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen G, Xu H, Yao Y, et al. BMP signaling in the development and regeneration of cranium bones and maintenance of calvarial stem cells. Front Cell Dev Biol. 2020;8(March):1-9. https://doi.org/10.3389/fcell.2020.00135.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Urist MR, Mikulski A, Lietze A. Solubilized and insolubilized bone morphogenetic protein. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 1979;76(4):1828-1832. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.76.4.1828.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halloran D, Durbano HW, Nohe A. Developmental review bone morphogenetic protein-2 in development and bone homeostasis. J Dev Biol. 2020;8(3):28-30. https://doi.org/10.3390/JDB8030019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beyer TA, Narimatsu M, Weiss A, David L, Wrana JL. The TGF&#x3b2; superfamily in stem cell biology and early mammalian embryonic development. Biochim Biophys Acta Gen Subjects. 2013;1830(2):2268-2279. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bbagen.2012.08.025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>David CJ, Massagu&#xe9; J. Contextual determinants of TGF&#x3b2; action in development, immunity and cancer. Nat Rev Mol Cell Biol. 2018;19(7):419-435. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41580-018-0007-0.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu MY, Hill CS. TGF-&#x3b2; superfamily signaling in embryonic development and homeostasis. Dev Cell. 2009;16(3):329-343. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.devcel.2009.02.012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morikawa M, Derynck R, Miyazono K. TGF-&#x3b2; and the TGF-&#x3b2; family: context-dependent roles in cell and tissue physiology. Cold Spring Harbor Perspect Biol. 2016;8(5):a021873. https://doi.org/10.1101/cshperspect.a021873.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hudnall AM, Arthur JW, Lowery JW. Clinical relevance and mechanisms of antagonism between the BMP and Activin/TGF-beta signaling pathways. J Am Osteopath Assoc. 2016;116(7):452-461. https://doi.org/10.7556/jaoa.2016.089.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sotiropoulos MG, Chitnis T. Opposing and potentially antagonistic effects of BMP and TGF-&#x3b2; in multiple sclerosis: the &#x201c;yin and Yang&#x201d; of neuro-immune signaling. J Neuroimmunol. 2020;347(July):577358. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jneuroim.2020.577358.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zinski J, Tajer B, Mullins MC. TGF-&#x3b2; family signaling in early vertebrate development. Cold Spring Harb Perspect Biol. 2018;10(6):1-76. https://doi.org/10.1101/cshperspect.a033274.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carron C, Shi DL. Specification of anteroposterior axis by combinatorial signaling during Xenopus development. Wiley Interdiscip Rev Dev Biol. 2016;5(2):150-168. https://doi.org/10.1002/wdev.217.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leung B, Shimeld SM. Evolution of vertebrate spinal cord patterning. Dev Dyn. 2019;248(11):1028-1043. https://doi.org/10.1002/dvdy.77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bond AM, Bhalala OG, Kessler JA. The dynamic role of bone morphogenetic proteins in neural stem cell fate and maturation. Dev Neurobiol. 2012;72(7):1068-1084. https://doi.org/10.1002/dneu.22022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrews MG, Kong J, Novitch BG, Butler SJ. New perspectives on the mechanisms establishing the dorsal-ventral axis of the spinal cord. Curr Top Dev Biol. 2019;132:417-450. https://doi.org/10.1016/bs.ctdb.2018.12.010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keshishian H, Kim YS. Orchestrating development and function: retrograde BMP signaling in the drosophila nervous system. Trends Neurosci. 2004;27(3):143-147. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tins.2004.01.004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhong J, Zou H. BMP signaling in axon regeneration. Curr Opin Neurobiol. 2014;27:127-134. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.conb.2014.03.009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hegarty SV, O'Keeffe GW, Sullivan AM. BMP-Smad 1/5/8 signalling in the development of the nervous system. Prog Neurobiol. 2013;109:28-41. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pneurobio.2013.07.002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bayat V, Jaiswal M, Bellen HJ. The BMP signaling pathway at the drosophila neuromuscular junction and its links to neurodegenerative diseases. Curr Opin Neurobiol. 2011;21(1):182-188. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.conb.2010.08.014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kashima R, Hata A. The role of TGF-&#x3b2; superfamily signaling in neurological disorders [review]. Acta Biochim Biophys Sin. 2018;50(1):106-120. https://doi.org/10.1093/abbs/gmx124.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa C, Eixarch H, Mart&#xed;nez-S&#xe1;ez E, et al. Expression of bone morphogenetic proteins in multiple sclerosis lesions. Am J Pathol. 2019;189(3):665-676. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ajpath.2018.11.007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hart CG, Karimi-Abdolrezaee S. Bone morphogenetic proteins: new insights into their roles and mechanisms in CNS development, pathology and repair. Exp Neurol. 2020;334:113455. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.expneurol.2020.113455.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor JP, Brown RH Jr, Cleveland DW. Decoding ALS: from genes to mechanism. Nature. 2016;539(7628):197-206. https://doi.org/10.1038/nature20413.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zarei S, Carr K, Reiley L, et al. A comprehensive review of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Surg Neurol Int. 2015;6:171. https://doi.org/10.4103/2152-7806.169561.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ban J, S&#xe1;mano C, Mladini&#x107; M, Muniti&#x107; I. Glia in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and spinal cord injury: common therapeutic targets. Croat Med J. 2019;60(2):109-120. https://doi.org/10.3325/cmj.2019.60.109.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang SH, Li Y, Fukaya M, et al. Degeneration and impaired regeneration of gray matter oligodendrocytes in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat Neurosci. 2013;16(5):571-579. https://doi.org/10.1038/nn.3357.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown RH, Al-Chalabi A. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. N Engl J Med. 2017;377(2):162-172. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJMra1603471.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masrori P, Van Damme P. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a clinical review. Eur J Neurol. 2020;27(10):1918-1929. https://doi.org/10.1111/ene.14393.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salameh JS, Brown RH Jr, Berry JD. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: review. Semin Neurol. 2015;35(4):469-476. https://doi.org/10.1055/s-0035-1558984.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shuo-Chien Ling MPDWC. Converging mechanisms in ALS and FTD. Physiol Behav. 2016;176(1):139-148. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2013.07.033.Converging.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor LM, McMillan PJ, Liachko NF, et al. Pathological phosphorylation of tau and TDP-43 by TTBK1 and TTBK2 drives neurodegeneration. Mol Neurodegener. 2018;13(1):7. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13024-018-0237-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khairoalsindi OA, Abuzinadah AR. Maximizing the survival of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients: current perspectives. Neurol Res Int. 2018;2018:1-12. https://doi.org/10.1155/2018/6534150.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller RG, Mitchell JD, Moore DH. Riluzole for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS)/motor neuron disease (MND). Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2012;(3):1-28. https://doi.org/10.1002/14651858.CD001447.pub3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prasad A, Bharathi V, Sivalingam V, Girdhar A, Patel BK. Molecular mechanisms of TDP-43 Misfolding and pathology in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Front Mol Neurosci. 2019;12:25-25. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnmol.2019.00025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ling SC, Polymenidou M, Cleveland DW. Converging mechanisms in als and FTD: disrupted RNA and protein homeostasis. Neuron. 2013;79(3):416-438. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2013.07.033.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirby J, Al Sultan A, Waller R, Heath P. The genetics of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: current insights. Degener Neurol Neuromusc Dis. 2016;6:49-49. https://doi.org/10.2147/DNND.S84956.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghasemi M, Brown RH Jr. Genetics of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Cold Spring Harb Perspect Med. 2018;8(5):a024125. https://doi.org/10.1101/cshperspect.a024125.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armon C. Excess incidence of ALS in young gulf war veterans. Neurology. 2004;63(10):1986-1987; author reply 1986-7. https://doi.org/10.1212/wnl.63.10.1986.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong PC, Pardo CA, Borchelt DR, et al. An adverse property of a familial ALS-linked SOD1 mutation causes motor neuron disease characterized by vacuolar degeneration of mitochondria. Neuron. 1995;14(6):1105-1116. https://doi.org/10.1016/0896-6273(95)90259-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruijn LI, Miller TM, Cleveland DW. Unraveling the mechanisms involved in motor neuron degeneration in ALS. Annu Rev Neurosci. 2004;27:723-749. https://doi.org/10.1146/annurev.neuro.27.070203.144244.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fischer LR, Culver DG, Tennant P, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis is a distal axonopathy: evidence in mice and man [comparative study]. Exp Neurol. 2004;185(2):232-240.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackenzie IRA, Rademakers R, Neumann M. TDP-43 and FUS in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal dementia. Lancet Neurol. 2010;9(10):995-1007. https://doi.org/10.1016/S1474-4422(10)70195-2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Philips T, Robberecht W. Neuroinflammation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: role of glial activation in motor neuron disease. Lancet Neurol. 2011;10(3):253-263. https://doi.org/10.1016/S1474-4422(11)70015-1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moloney EB, De Winter F, Verhaagen J, et al. ALS as a distal axonopathy: molecular mechanisms affecting neuromuscular junction stability in the presymptomatic stages of the disease. Front Neurosci. 2014;252:1-18. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnins.2014.00252.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chand KK, Lee KM, Lee JD, et al. Defects in synaptic transmission at the neuromuscular junction precede motor deficits in a TDP-43Q331K transgenic mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. FASEB J. 2018;32(5):2676-2689. https://doi.org/10.1096/fj.201700835R.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armstrong GA, Drapeau P. Calcium channel agonists protect against neuromuscular dysfunction in a genetic model of TDP-43 mutation in ALS. J Neurosci. 2013;33(4):1741-1752. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.4003-12.2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Held A, Major P, Sahin A, Reenan RA, Lipscombe D, Wharton KA. Circuit dysfunction in SOD1-ALS model first detected in sensory feedback prior to motor neuron degeneration is alleviated by BMP signaling. J Neurosci. 2019;39(12):2347-2364. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.1771-18.2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wainger BJ, Kiskinis E, Mellin C, et al. Intrinsic membrane hyperexcitability of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patient-derived motor neurons. Cell Rep. 2014;7(1):1-11. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.celrep.2014.03.019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watson MR, Lagow RD, Xu K, Zhang B, Bonini NM. A drosophila model for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis reveals motor neuron damage by human SOD1. J Biol Chem. 2008;283(36):24972-24981. https://doi.org/10.1074/jbc.M804817200.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han-Xiang D, Hujun J, Ronggen F, et al. Molecular dissection of ALS-associated toxicity of SOD1 in transgenic mice using an exon-fusion approach. Hum Mol Genet. 2008;17(15):2310-2319. https://doi.org/10.1093/hmg/ddn131.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Philips T, Rothstein JD. Rodent models of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Curr Protoc Pharmacol. 2015;69:5 67 1-5 67 21. https://doi.org/10.1002/0471141755.ph0567s69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang K, Donnelly CJ, Haeusler AR, et al. The C9orf72 repeat expansion disrupts nucleocytoplasmic transport. Nature. 2015;525(7567):56-61. https://doi.org/10.1038/nature14973.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ash PE, Zhang YJ, Roberts CM, et al. Neurotoxic effects of TDP-43 overexpression in C. elegans. Hum Mol Genet. 2010;19(16):3206-3218. https://doi.org/10.1093/hmg/ddq230.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bories C, Amendola J, Lamotte D'Incamps B, Durand J. Early electrophysiological abnormalities in lumbar motoneurons in a transgenic mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Eur J Neurosci. 2007;25(2):451-459. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1460-9568.2007.05306.x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuva-Aydemir Y, Almeida S, Gao FB. Insights into C9ORF72-related ALS/FTD from drosophila and iPSC models. Trends Neurosci. 2018;41(7):457-469. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tins.2018.04.002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Damme P, Robberecht W, Van Den Bosch L. Modelling amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: progress and possibilities. Dis Models Mech. 2017;10(5):537-549. https://doi.org/10.1242/dmm.029058.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Picher-Martel V, Valdmanis PN, Gould PV, Julien JP, Dupr&#xe9; N. From animal models to human disease: a genetic approach for personalized medicine in ALS. Acta Neuropathol Commun. 2016;4(1):1-29. https://doi.org/10.1186/s40478-016-0340-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farg MA, Sundaramoorthy V, Sultana JM, et al. C9ORF72, implicated in amytrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal dementia, regulates endosomal trafficking. Hum Mol Genet. 2014;23(13):3579-3595. https://doi.org/10.1093/hmg/ddu068.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H, Yi J, Li X, Xiao Y, Dhakal K, Zhou J. ALS-associated mutation SOD1G93A leads to abnormal mitochondrial dynamics in osteocytes. Bone. 2018;106:126-138. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bone.2017.10.010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x15e;ahin A, Held A, Bredvik K, et al. Human SOD1 ALS mutations in a drosophila Knock-in model cause severe phenotypes and reveal dosage-sensitive gain- and loss-of-function components. Genetics. 2017;205(2):707-723. https://doi.org/10.1534/genetics.116.190850.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baskoylu SN, Yersak J, O'Hern P, et al. Single copy/knock-in models of ALS SOD1 in C. elegans suggest loss and gain of function have different contributions to cholinergic and glutamatergic neurodegeneration. PLoS Genet. 2018;14(10):e1007682. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pgen.1007682.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watanabe S, Oiwa K, Murata Y, et al. ALS-linked TDP-43M337V knock-in mice exhibit splicing deregulation without neurodegeneration. Mol Brain. 2020;13(1):13-16. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13041-020-0550-4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong W, Zhang L, Sun C, et al. Knock in of a hexanucleotide repeat expansion in the C9orf72 gene induces ALS in rats. Anim Models Exp Med. 2020;3(3):237-244. https://doi.org/10.1002/ame2.12129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee S, Huang EJ. Modeling ALS and FTD with iPSC-derived neurons. Brain Res. 1656;1(2017):88-97. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.brainres.2015.10.003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujimori K, Ishikawa M, Otomo A, et al. Modeling sporadic ALS in iPSC-derived motor neurons identifies a potential therapeutic agent. Nat Med. 2018;24(10):1579-1589. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41591-018-0140-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hawrot J, Imhof S, Wainger BJ. Modeling cell-autonomous motor neuron phenotypes in ALS using iPSCs. Neurobiol Dis. 2020;134(November 2019):104680-104680. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nbd.2019.104680.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zahavi EE, Ionescu A, Gluska S, Gradus T, Ben-Yaakov K, Perlson E. A compartmentalized microfluidic neuromuscular co-culture system reveals spatial aspects of GDNF functions. J Cell Sci. 2015;128(6):1241-1252. https://doi.org/10.1242/jcs.167544.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osaki T, Sivathanu V, Kamm RD. Engineered 3D vascular and neuronal networks in a microfluidic platform. Sci Rep. 2018;8:5168-5168. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-018-23512-1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kunze A, Lengacher S, Dirren E, Aebischer P, Magistretti PJ, Renaud P. Astrocyte-neuron co-culture on microchips based on the model of SOD mutation to mimic ALS. Integr Biol (United Kingdom). 2013;5(7):964-975. https://doi.org/10.1039/c3ib40022k.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osaki T, Uzel SGM, Kamm RD. Microphysiological 3D model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) from human iPS-derived muscle cells and optogenetic motor neurons. Sci Adv. 2018;4:5847.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slater CR. The functional organization of motor nerve terminals. Prog Neurobiol. 2015;134:55-103. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pneurobio.2015.09.004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones RA, Harrison C, Eaton SL, et al. Cellular and molecular anatomy of the human neuromuscular junction. Cell Rep. 2017;21(9):2348-2356. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.celrep.2017.11.008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chou VT, Johnson SA, Van Vactor D. Synapse development and maturation at the drosophila neuromuscular junction. Neural Dev. 2020;15(1):11. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13064-020-00147-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu H, Xiong WC, Mei L. To build a synapse: signaling pathways in neuromuscular junction assembly. Development. 2010;137(7):1017-1033. https://doi.org/10.1242/dev.038711.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menon KP, Carrillo RA, Zinn K. Development and plasticity of the drosophila larval neuromuscular junction. Wiley Interdiscip Rev Dev Biol. 2013;2(5):647-670. https://doi.org/10.1002/wdev.108.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Markmiller S, Soltanieh S, Server KL, et al. Context-dependent and disease-specific diversity in protein interactions within stress granules. Cell. 2018;172(3):590-604 e13. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2017.12.032.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuva-Aydemir Y, Almeida S, Krishnan G, Gendron TF, Gao FB. Transcription elongation factor AFF2/FMR2 regulates expression of expanded GGGGCC repeat-containing C9ORF72 allele in ALS/FTD. Nat Commun. 2019;10(1):5466. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-019-13477-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manzo E, Lorenzini I, Barrameda D, et al. Glycolysis upregulation is neuroprotective as a compensatory mechanism in ALS. Elife. 2019;8. 1-20. https://doi.org/10.7554/eLife.45114.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castellanos-Montiel M, Chaineau M, Durcan TM. The neglected genes of ALS: cytoskeletal dynamics impact synaptic degeneration in ALS. Front Cell Neurosci. 2020;14:594975. https://doi.org/10.3389/fncel.2020.594975.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leko MB, &#x17d;upunski V, Kirincich J, et al. Molecular mechanisms of neurodegeneration related to C9orf72 hexanucleotide repeat expansion. Behav Neurol. 2019;2019:1-18. https://doi.org/10.1155/2019/2909168.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casci I, Pandey UB. A fruitful endeavor: modeling ALS in the fruit fly. Brain Res. 2015; 1607:47-74. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.brainres.2014.09.064.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sha SJ, Takada LT, Rankin KP, et al. Frontotemporal dementia due to C9ORF72 mutations clinical and imaging features. Neurology. 2012;79(10):1002-1011. https://doi.org/10.1212/WNL.0b013e318268452e.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooper-Knock J, Walsh MJ, Higginbottom A, et al. Sequestration of multiple RNA recognition motif-containing proteins by C9orf72 repeat expansions. Brain. 2014;137(Pt 7):2040-2051. https://doi.org/10.1093/brain/awu120.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y, Pattamatta A, Zu T, et al. C9orf72 BAC mouse model with motor deficits and neurodegenerative features of ALS/FTD. Neuron. 2016;90(3):521-534. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2016.04.005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaur SJ, McKeown SR, Rashid S. Mutant SOD1 mediated pathogenesis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Gene. 2016;577(2):109-118. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.gene.2015.11.049.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ilieva H, Polymenidou M, Cleveland DW. Non-cell autonomous toxicity in neurodegenerative disorders: ALS and beyond. J Cell Biol. 2009;187(6):761-772. https://doi.org/10.1083/jcb.200908164.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Ara&#xfa;jo BA, de Carvalho MDC, Gerhardt E, et al. Characterization of the activity, aggregation, and toxicity of heterodimers of WT and ALS-associated mutant Sod1. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2019;116(51):25991-26000. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1902483116.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tobisawa S, Hozumi Y, Arawaka S, et al. Mutant SOD1 linked to familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, but not wild-type SOD1, induces ER stress in COS7 cells and transgenic mice. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 2003;303(2):496-503. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0006-291X(03)00353-X.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gal J, Kuang L, Barnett KR, et al. ALS mutant SOD1 interacts with G3BP1 and affects stress granule dynamics. Acta Neuropathol. 2016;132(4):563-576. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00401-016-1601-x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weisberg SJ, Lyakhovetsky R, Werdiger AC, Gitler AD, Soen Y, Kaganovich D. Compartmentalization of superoxide dismutase 1 (SOD1G93A) aggregates determines their toxicity. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2012;109(39):15811-15816. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1205829109.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baron DM, Kaushansky LJ, Ward CL, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-linked FUS/TLS alters stress granule assembly and dynamics. Mol Neurodegener. 2013;8(1):1-18. https://doi.org/10.1186/1750-1326-8-30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu-Yesucevitz L, Bilgutay A, Zhang YJ, et al. Tar DNA binding protein-43 (TDP-43) associates with stress granules: analysis of cultured cells and pathological brain tissue. PLoS One. 2010;5(10):e13250. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0013250.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mateju D, Franzmann TM, Patel A, et al. An aberrant phase transition of stress granules triggered by misfolded protein and prevented by chaperone function. EMBO J. 2017;36(12):1669-1687. https://doi.org/10.15252/embj.201695957.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loganathan S, Lehmkuhl EM, Eck RJ, Zarnescu DC. To be or not to be&#x2026;toxic-is RNA association with TDP-43 complexes deleterious or protective in neurodegeneration? Front Mol Biosci. 2020;6(January):1-11. https://doi.org/10.3389/fmolb.2019.00154.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pradat PF, Kabashi E, Desnuelle C. Deciphering spreading mechanisms in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: clinical evidence and potential molecular processes. Curr Opin Neurol. 2015;28(5):455-461. https://doi.org/10.1097/WCO.0000000000000239.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sibilla C, Bertolotti A. Prion properties of SOD1 in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and potential therapy. Cold Spring Harb Perspect Biol. 2017;9(10):a024141. https://doi.org/10.1101/cshperspect.a024141.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vassileff N, Cheng L, Hill AF. Extracellular vesicles - propagators of neuropathology and sources of potential biomarkers and therapeutics for neurodegenerative diseases. J Cell Sci. 2020;133(23):jcs243139. https://doi.org/10.1242/jcs.243139.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kankel MW, Sen A, Lu L, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis modifiers in drosophila reveal the phospholipase d pathway as a potential therapeutic target. Gene. 2020;215(3):747-766. https://doi.org/10.1534/genetics.119.302985.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yanagi KS, Wu Z, Amaya J, et al. Meta-analysis of genetic modifiers reveals candidate Dysregulated pathways in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuroscience. 2019;396:A3-A20. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuroscience.2018.10.033.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dervishi I, Gozutok O, Murnan K, et al. Protein-protein interactions reveal key canonical pathways, upstream regulators, interactome domains, and novel targets in ALS. Sci Rep. 2018;8(1):14732. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-018-32902-4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suzuki N, Akiyama T, Warita H, Aoki M. Omics approach to axonal dysfunction of motor neurons in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). Front Neurosci. 2020;14:194. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnins.2020.00194.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kori M, Aydin B, Unal S, Arga KY, Kazan D. Metabolic biomarkers and Neurodegeneration: a pathway enrichment analysis of Alzheimer's disease, Parkinson's disease, and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. OMICS. 2016;20(11):645-661. https://doi.org/10.1089/omi.2016.0106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lanznaster D, Veyrat-Durebex C, Vourc&#x2019;h P, Andres CR, Blasco H, Corcia P. Metabolomics: a tool to understand the impact of genetic mutations in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Genes. 2020;11(5):537. https://doi.org/10.3390/genes11050537.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blokhuis AM, Koppers M, Groen EJN, et al. Comparative interactomics analysis of different ALS-associated proteins identifies converging molecular pathways. Acta Neuropathol. 2016;132(2):175-196. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00401-016-1575-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu A, Niswander LA. Bone morphogenetic protein signalling and vertebrate nervous system development. Nat Rev Neurosci. 2005;6:945-954.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taetzsch T, Tenga MJ, Valdez G. Muscle fibers secrete FGFBP1 to slow degeneration of neuromuscular synapses during aging and progression of ALS. J Neurosci. 2017;37(1):70-82. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.2992-16.2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akiyama T, Marqu&#xe9;s G, Wharton KA. A large bioactive BMP ligand with distinct signaling properties is produced by alternative proconvertase processing. Sci Signal. 2012;5(218):ra28. https://doi.org/10.1126/scisignal.2002549.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi Q, Zhong YS, Ren Z, et al. Analysis of the role of the BMP7-Smad4-Id2 signaling pathway in SW480 colorectal carcinoma cells. Mol Med Rep. 2011;4(4):627-631. https://doi.org/10.3892/mmr.2011.481.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patin F, Baranek T, Vourc'h P, et al. Combined metabolomics and transcriptomics approaches to assess the IL-6 blockade as a therapeutic of ALS: deleterious alteration of lipid metabolism. Neurotherapeutics. 2016;13(4):905-917. https://doi.org/10.1007/s13311-016-0461-3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zee M. v. d., Stockhammer O., Levetzow C. v., Fonseca R. N. d., Roth S.. Sog/Chordin is required for ventral-to-dorsal Dpp/BMP transport and head formation in a short germ insect. Proc National Acad Sci.. 2006;103(44):16307-16312. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.0605154103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babitt JL, Huang FW, Wrighting DM, et al. Bone morphogenetic protein signaling by hemojuvelin regulates hepcidin expression. Nat Genet. 2006;38(5):531-539. https://doi.org/10.1038/ng1777.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia Y, Yu PB, Sidis Y, et al. Repulsive guidance molecule RGMa alters utilization of bone morphogenetic protein (BMP) type II receptors by BMP2 and BMP4. J Biol Chem. 2007;282(25):18129-18140. https://doi.org/10.1074/jbc.M701679200.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo JY, Zhang Y, Wang L, Huang Y. Regulators and effectors of bone morphogenetic protein signalling in the cardiovascular system. J Physiol. 2015;593(14):2995-3011. https://doi.org/10.1113/JP270207.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyazawa K, Miyazono K. Regulation of TGF-&#x3b2; family signaling by inhibitory smads. Cold Spring Harb Perspect Biol. 2017;9(3):1-26. https://doi.org/10.1101/cshperspect.a022095.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Massagu&#xe9; J. TGFbeta signalling in context. Nat Rev Mol Cell Biol. 2014;13(10):616-630. https://doi.org/10.1038/nrm3434.TGF.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coda DM, Gaarenstroom T, East P, et al. Distinct modes of SMAD2 chromatin binding and remodeling shape the transcriptional response to NODAL/Activin signaling. Elife. 2017;6:1-31. https://doi.org/10.7554/eLife.22474.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamada Y, Mashima H, Sakai T, Matsuhashi T, Jin M, Ohnishi H. Functional roles of TGF-&#x3b2;1 in intestinal epithelial cells through smad-dependent and non-smad pathways. Dig Dis Sci. 2013;58(5):1207-1217. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10620-012-2515-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blahna MT, Hata A. Smad-mediated regulation of microRNA biosynthesis. FEBS Lett. 2012;586(14):1906-1912. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.febslet.2012.01.041.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, O'Keefe RJ, Jonason JH. BMP-TAK1 (MAP3K7) induces adipocyte differentiation through PPARgamma signaling. J Cell Biochem. 2017;118(1):204-210. https://doi.org/10.1002/jcb.25626.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>BD MC, Marqu&#xe9;s G, Haghighi AP, et al. The BMP homolog Gbb provides a retrograde signal that regulates synaptic growth at the drosophila neuromuscular junction. [comparative study]. Neuron. 2003;39(2):241-254.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Endo F, Komine O, Fujimori-Tonou N, et al. Astrocyte-derived TGF-&#x3b2;1 accelerates disease progression in ALS mice by interfering with the Neuroprotective functions of microglia and T cells. Cell Rep. 2015;11(4):592-604. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.celrep.2015.03.053.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakamura M, Ito H, Wate R, Nakano S, Hirano A, Kusaka H. Phosphorylated Smad2/3 immunoreactivity in sporadic and familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and its mouse model. Acta Neuropathol. 2008;115(3):327-334. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00401-007-0337-z.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Si Y, Kim S, Cui X, et al. Transforming growth factor Beta (TGF-beta) is a muscle biomarker of disease progression in ALS and correlates with Smad expression. PLoS One. 2015;10(9):e0138425. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0138425.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakamura M, Kaneko S, Ito H, et al. Activation of transforming growth factor-beta/Smad signaling reduces aggregate formation of mislocalized TAR DNA-binding protein-43. Neurodegener Dis. 2013;11(4):182-193. https://doi.org/10.1159/000338151.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hazelett DJ, Chang J-C, Lakeland DL, Morton DB. Comparison of parallel high-throughput RNA sequencing between knockout of TDP-43 and its overexpression reveals primarily nonreciprocal and nonoverlapping gene expression changes in the central nervous system of Drosophila. G3 (Bethesda, Md). 2012;2(7):789-802. https://doi.org/10.1534/g3.112.002998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shijo T, Warita H, Suzuki N, et al. Antagonizing bone morphogenetic protein 4 attenuates disease progression in a rat model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Exp Neurol. 2018;307:164-179. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.expneurol.2018.06.009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marques G, Haerry TE, Crotty ML, Xue M, Zhang B, O'Connor MB. Retrograde Gbb signaling through the bmp type 2 receptor wishful thinking regulates systemic FMRFa expression in drosophila. Development. 2003;130(22):5457-5470. https://doi.org/10.1242/dev.00772.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goold CP, Davis GW. The BMP ligand Gbb gates the expression of synaptic homeostasis independent of synaptic growth control. Neuron. 2007;56(1):109-123. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2007.08.006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoover KM, Gratz SJ, Qi N, et al. The calcium channel subunit alpha2delta-3 organizes synapses via an activity-dependent and autocrine BMP signaling pathway. Nat Commun. 2019;10(1):5575. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-019-13165-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berke B, Wittnam J, McNeill E, Van Vactor DL, Keshishian H. Retrograde BMP signaling at the synapse: a permissive signal for synapse maturation and activity-dependent plasticity. J Neurosci. 2013;33(45):17937-17950. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.6075-11.2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Theys PA, Peeters E, Robberecht W. Evolution of motor and sensory deficits in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis estimated by neurophysiological techniques. J Neurol. 1999;246(6):438-442. https://doi.org/10.1007/s004150050379.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pugdahl K, Fuglsang-Frederiksen A, de Carvalho M, et al. Generalised sensory system abnormalities in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a European multicentre study. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2007;78(7):746-749. https://doi.org/10.1136/jnnp.2006.098533.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isaacs JD, Dean AF, Shaw CE, Al-Chalabi A, Mills KR, Leigh PN. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with sensory neuropathy: part of a multisystem disorder? J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2007;78(7):750-753. https://doi.org/10.1136/jnnp.2006.098798.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaughan SK, Sutherland NM, Zhang S, Hatzipetros T, Vieira F, Valdez G. The ALS-inducing factors, TDP43(A315T) and SOD1(G93A), directly affect and sensitize sensory neurons to stress. Sci Rep. 2018;8(1):16582. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-018-34510-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deal SL, Yamamoto S. Unraveling novel mechanisms of Neurodegeneration through a large-scale forward genetic screen in drosophila. Front Genet. 2018;9:700. https://doi.org/10.3389/fgene.2018.00700.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Link N, Bellen HJ. Using drosophila to drive the diagnosis and understand the mechanisms of rare human diseases. Development. 2020;147(21):dev191411. https://doi.org/10.1242/dev.191411.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higashi-Kovtun ME, Mosca TJ, Dickman DK, Meinertzhagen IA, Schwarz TL. Importin-beta11 regulates synaptic phosphorylated mothers against decapentaplegic, and thereby influences synaptic development and function at the drosophila neuromuscular junction. J Neurosci. 2010;30(15):5253-5268. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.3739-09.2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sulkowski M, Kim Y-J, Serpe M. Postsynaptic glutamate receptors regulate local BMP signaling at the drosophila neuromuscular junction. Development (Cambridge, England). 2014;141(2):436-447. https://doi.org/10.1242/dev.097758.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berke B, Le L, Keshishian H. Target-dependent retrograde signaling mediates synaptic plasticity at the drosophila neuromuscular junction. Dev Neurobiol. 2019;79(11-12):895-912. https://doi.org/10.1002/dneu.22731.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratnaparkhi A, Lawless GM, Schweizer FE, Golshani P, Jackson GR. A drosophila model of ALS: human ALS-associated mutation in VAP33A suggests a dominant negative mechanism. PLoS One. 2008;3(6):e2334. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0002334.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deshpande M, Feiger Z, Shilton AK, Luo CC, Silverman E, Rodal AA. Role of BMP receptor traffic in synaptic growth defects in an ALS model. Mol Biol Cell. 2016;27(19):2898-2910. https://doi.org/10.1091/mbc.E16-07-0519.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berke B, Wittnam J, McNeill E, Van Vactor DL, Keshishian H. Retrograde BMP signaling at the synapse: a permissive signal for synapse maturation and activity-dependent plasticity. J Neurosci. 2013;33(45):17937-17950. https://doi.org/10.1523/jneurosci.6075-11.2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartoletti M, Knight T, Held A, Rand LM, Wharton KA. Glia-neuron signaling mediated by two different BMP ligands impacts synaptic growth. bioRxiV. 2021; submitted.10.1101/2021.02.23.432606.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim HS, Neugebauer J, McKnite A, Tilak A, Christian JL. BMP7 functions predominantly as a heterodimer with BMP2 or BMP4 during mammalian embryogenesis. eLife. 2019;8. https://doi.org/10.7554/elife.48872.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gipson GR, Goebel EJ, Hart KN, et al. Structural perspective of BMP ligands and signaling. Bone. 2020;140:115549. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bone.2020.115549.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hinck AP, Mueller TD, Springer TA. Structural biology and evolution of the TGF-&#x3b2; family. [review]. Cold Spring Harbor Perspect Biol. 2016;8(12):a022103. https://doi.org/10.1101/cshperspect.a022103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson EN, Wharton KA. Alternative cleavage of the bone morphogenetic protein (BMP), Gbb, produces ligands with distinct developmental functions and receptor preferences. J Biol Chem. 2017;292(47):19160-19178. https://doi.org/10.1074/jbc.M117.793513.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fuentes-Medel Y, Ashley J, Barria R, Maloney R, Freeman M, Budnik V. Integration of a retrograde signal during synapse formation by glia-secreted TGF-beta ligand. Curr Biol. 2012;22(19):1831-1838. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cub.2012.07.063.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morooka T, Nishida E. Requirement of p38 mitogen-activated protein kinase for neuronal differentiation in PC12 cells. J Biol Chem. 1998;273(38):24285-24288. https://doi.org/10.1074/jbc.273.38.24285.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X, Zhao Y, Peng S, et al. BMP7 retards peripheral myelination by activating p38 MAPK in Schwann cells. Sci Rep. 2016;6(1):31049. https://doi.org/10.1038/srep31049.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ackerley S, Grierson AJ, Banner S, et al. P38&#x391; stress-activated protein kinase phosphorylates neurofilaments and is associated with neurofilament pathology in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Mol Cell Neurosci. 2004;26(2):354-364. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcn.2004.02.009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bendotti C, Carr&#xec; MT. Lessons from models of SOD1-linked familial ALS. Trends Mol Med. 2004;10(8):393-400. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.molmed.2004.06.009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tortarolo M, Veglianese P, Calvaresi N, et al. Persistent activation of p38 mitogen-activated protein kinase in a mouse model of familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis correlates with disease progression. Mol Cell Neurosci. 2003;23(2):180-192. https://doi.org/10.1016/S1044-7431(03)00022-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibbs KL, Kalmar B, Rhymes ER, et al. Inhibiting p38 MAPK alpha rescues axonal retrograde transport defects in a mouse model of ALS article. Cell Death Dis. 2018;9(6):1-16. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41419-018-0624-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cavalli V, Vilbois F, Corti M, et al. The stress-induced MAP kinase p38 regulates endocytic trafficking via the GDI:Rab5 complex. Mol Cell. 2001;7(2):421-432. https://doi.org/10.1016/S1097-2765(01)00189-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takeda K, Ichiijo H. Neuronal p38 MAPK signalling: an emerging regulator of cell fate and function in the nervous system. Genes Cells. 2002;7(11):1099-1111. https://doi.org/10.1046/j.1365-2443.2002.00591.x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee-Hoeflich ST, Causing CG, Podkowa M, Zhao X, Wrana JL, Attisano L. Activation of LIMK1 by binding to the BMP receptor, BMPRII, regulates BMP-dependent dendritogenesis. EMBO J. 2004;23(24):4792-4801. https://doi.org/10.1038/sj.emboj.7600418.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu CH, Fallini C, Ticozzi N, et al. Mutations in the profilin 1 gene cause familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nature. 2012;488(7412):499-503. https://doi.org/10.1038/nature11280.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang C, Danielson EW, Qiao T, et al. Mutant PFN1 causes ALS phenotypes and progressive motor neuron degeneration in mice by a gain of toxicity. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2016;113(41):E6209-E6218. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1605964113.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiaei M, Balasubramaniam M, Govind Kumar V, Shmookler Reis RJ, Moradi M, Varughese KI. ALS-causing mutations in profilin-1 alter its conformational dynamics: a computational approach to explain propensity for aggregation. Sci Rep. 2018;8(1):1-10. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-018-31199-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sivadasan R, Hornburg D, Drepper C, et al. C9ORF72 Interaction with cofilin modulates Actin dynamics in motor neurons. Nat Neurosci. 2016;19(12):1610-1618. https://doi.org/10.1038/nn.4407.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eaton BA, Davis GW. LIM Kinase1 controls synaptic stability downstream of the type II BMP receptor. Neuron. 2005;47(5):695-708. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2005.08.010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ng J. TGF&#x3b2; signals regulate axonal development through distinct Smad-independent mechanisms. Development. 2008;135(24):4025-4035. https://doi.org/10.1242/dev.028209.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gertz B, Wong M, Martin LJ. Nuclear localization of human SOD1 and mutant SOD1-specific disruption of survival motor neuron protein complex in transgenic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis mice. J Neuropathol Exp Neurol. 2012;71(2):162-177.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang X, Toro A, Sahana TG, et al. Divergence, convergence, and therapeutic implications: a cell biology perspective of C9ORF72-ALS/FTD. Mol Neurodegener. 2020;15(1):1-15. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13024-020-00383-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fallini C, Khalil B, Smith CL, Rossoll W. Traffic jam at the nuclear pore: all roads lead to nucleocytoplasmic transport defects in ALS/FTD. Neurobiol Dis. 2020;140(January):104835. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nbd.2020.104835.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hutten S, Usluer S, Bourgeois B, et al. Nuclear import receptors directly bind to arginine-rich dipeptide repeat proteins and suppress their pathological interactions. Cell Rep. 2020;33(12):108538. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.celrep.2020.108538.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hutten S, Flotho A, Melchior F, Kehlenbach RH. The Nup358-RanGAP complex is required for efficient importin alpha/beta-dependent nuclear import. Mol Biol Cell. 2008;19(5):2300-2310. https://doi.org/10.1091/mbc.E07-12-1279.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>