<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">33755993</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>04</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2990</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>47</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Neuropathology and applied neurobiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Neuropathol Appl Neurobiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Loss of the metabolism and sleep regulating neuronal populations expressing orexin and oxytocin in the hypothalamus in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>979</StartPage><EndPage>989</EndPage><MedlinePgn>979-989</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/nan.12709</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="AIMS">To determine the underlying cellular changes and clinical correlates associated with pathology of the hypothalamus in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS), as hypothalamic atrophy occurs in the preclinical phase of the disease.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">The hypothalamus was pathologically examined in nine patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in comparison to eight healthy control subjects. The severity of regional atrophy (paraventricular nucleus: PVN, fornix and total hypothalamus) and peptidergic neuronal loss (oxytocin, vasopressin, cocaine- and amphetamine-regulating transcript: CART, and orexin) was correlated with changes in eating behaviour, sleep function, cognition, behaviour and disease progression.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Tar DNA-binding protein 43 (TDP-43) inclusions were present in the hypothalamus of all patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. When compared to controls, there was atrophy of the hypothalamus (average 21% atrophy, p&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.004), PVN (average 30% atrophy p&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.014) and a loss of paraventricular oxytocin-producing neurons (average 49% loss p&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.02) and lateral hypothalamic orexin-producing neurons (average 37% loss, significance p&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.02). Factor analysis identified strong relationships between abnormal eating behaviour, hypothalamic atrophy and loss of orexin-producing neurons. With increasing disease progression, abnormal sleep behaviour and cognition associated with atrophy of the fornix.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Substantial loss of hypothalamic oxytocin-producing neurons occurs in ALS, with regional atrophy and the loss of orexin neurons relating to abnormal eating behaviour in ALS. Oxytocin- and orexin neurons display TDP43 inclusions. Our study points to significant pathology in the hypothalamus that may play a key role in metabolic and pathogenic changes in ALS.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 The Authors. Neuropathology and Applied Neurobiology published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of British Neuropathological Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gabery</LastName><ForeName>Sanaz</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Translational Neuroendocrine Research Unit, Department of Experimental Medical Science, Lund University, Lund, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ahmed</LastName><ForeName>Rebekah M</ForeName><Initials>RM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6996-8317</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Memory and Cognition Clinic, Department of Clinical Neurosciences, Royal Prince Alfred Hospital, Sydney, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Brain &amp; Mind Centre and Faculty of Medicine and Health, The University of Sydney, Sydney, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Caga</LastName><ForeName>Jashelle</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Brain &amp; Mind Centre and Faculty of Medicine and Health, The University of Sydney, Sydney, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kiernan</LastName><ForeName>Matthew C</ForeName><Initials>MC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Memory and Cognition Clinic, Department of Clinical Neurosciences, Royal Prince Alfred Hospital, Sydney, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Brain &amp; Mind Centre and Faculty of Medicine and Health, The University of Sydney, Sydney, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Halliday</LastName><ForeName>Glenda M</ForeName><Initials>GM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0422-8398</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Brain &amp; Mind Centre and Faculty of Medicine and Health, School of Medical Sciences, The University of Sydney, Sydney, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Peters&#xe9;n</LastName><ForeName>&#xc5;sa</ForeName><Initials>&#xc5;</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5488-1200</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Translational Neuroendocrine Research Unit, Department of Experimental Medical Science, Lund University, Lund, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R28 AA012725</GrantID><Acronym>AA</Acronym><Agency>NIAAA NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Neuropathol Appl Neurobiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7609829</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0305-1846</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000068797">Orexins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>50-56-6</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D010121">Oxytocin</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000369" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged, 80 and over</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001284" MajorTopicYN="N">Atrophy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007031" MajorTopicYN="N">Hypothalamus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009474" MajorTopicYN="N">Neurons</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000068797" MajorTopicYN="N">Orexins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010121" MajorTopicYN="N">Oxytocin</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012890" MajorTopicYN="N">Sleep</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">eating behaviour</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">frontotemporal dementia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">histopathology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hypothalamus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">peptidergic neurons</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33755993</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/nan.12709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Kiernan MC, Vucic S, Cheah BC, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet. 2011;377:942-955.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dupuis L, Pradat PF, Ludolph AC, Loeffler JP. Energy metabolism in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet Neurol. 2011;10:75-82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed RM, Caga J, Devenney E, et al. Cognition and eating behavior in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: effect on survival. J Neurol. 2016;263:1593-1603.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed RM, Newcombe REA, Piper AJ, et al. Sleep disorders and respiratory function in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Sleep Med Rev. 2016;26:33-42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed RM, Ke YD, Vucic S, et al. Physiological changes in neurodegeneration - mechanistic insights and clinical utility. Nat Rev Neurol. 2018;14:259-271.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jawaid A, Murthy SB, Wilson AM, et al. A decrease in body mass index is associated with faster progression of motor symptoms and shorter survival in ALS. Amyotroph Later Scler. 2010;11:542-548.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park Y, Park J, Kim Y, Baek H, Kim SH. Association between nutritional status and disease severity using the amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) functional rating scale in ALS patients. Nutrition. 2015;31:1362-1367.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huisman MHB, Seelen M, van Doormaal PTC, et al. Effect of presymptomatic body mass index and consumption of fat and alcohol on amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. JAMA Neurol. 2015;72:1155-1162.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burrell JR, Halliday GM, Kril JJ, et al. The frontotemporal dementia-motor neuron disease continuum. Lancet. 2016;388:919-931.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piguet O, Peters&#xe9;n &#xc5;, Yin Ka Lam B, et al. Eating and hypothalamus changes in behavioral-variant frontotemporal dementia. Ann Neurol. 2011;69:312-319.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed RM, Latheef S, Bartley L, et al. Eating behavior in frontotemporal dementia: peripheral hormones vs hypothalamic pathology. Neurol. 2015;85:1310-1317.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorges M, Vercruysse P, M&#xfc;ller H-P, et al. Hypothalamic atrophy is related to body mass index and age at onset in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2017;88:1033-1041.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andermann ML, Lowell BB. Toward a wiring diagram understanding of appetite control. Neuron. 2017;95:757-778.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawson EA. The effects of oxytocin on eating behaviour and metabolism in humans. Nat Rev Endocrinol. 2017;13:700-709.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heinrichs M, von Dawans B, Domes G. Oxytocin, vasopressin, and human social behavior. Front Neuroendocrinol. 2009;30:548-557.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams DL. Neural integration of satiation and food reward: role of GLP-1 and orexin pathways. Physiol Behav. 2014;136:194-199.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cykowski MD, Takei H, Schulz PE, Appel SH, Powell SZ. TDP-43 pathology in the basal forebrain and hypothalamus of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta neuropathologica communications. 2014;2:171.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed RM, Highton-Williamson E, Caga J, et al. Lipid metabolism and survival across the frontotemporal dementia-amyotrophic lateral sclerosis spectrum: relationships to eating behavior and cognition. J Alzheimers Dis. 2018;61:773-783.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ludolph A, Drory V, Hardiman O, et al. A revision of the El Escorial criteria - 2015. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2015;16:291-292.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabery S, Murphy K, Schultz K, et al. Changes in key hypothalamic neuropeptide populations in Huntington disease revealed by neuropathological analyses. Acta Neuropathol. 2010;120:777-788.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mioshi E, Dawson K, Mitchell J, Arnold R, Hodges JR. The Addenbrooke's Cognitive Examination Revised (ACE-R): a brief cognitive test battery for dementia screening. Int J Geriatr Psychiatry. 2006;21:1078-1085.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum JM, Stambler N, Malta E, et al. The ALSFRS-R: a revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. BDNF ALS Study Group (Phase III). J Neurol Sci. 1999;169:13-21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaufmann P, Levy G, Thompson JL, et al. The ALSFRSr predicts survival time in an ALS clinic population. Neurol. 2005;64:38-43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wedderburn C, Wear H, Brown J, et al. The utility of the Cambridge Behavioural Inventory in neurodegenerative disease. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2008;79:500-503.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>West MJ. Stereological methods for estimating the total number of neurons and synapses: issues of precision and bias. Trends Neurosci. 1999;22:51-61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mai J, Milan M, Paxinos G. Atlas of the Human Brain, 4th edn. San Diego: Academic Press; 2015:465.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comrey ALLH. A first course in factor analysis. Hillsdale: Erlbaum Associates; 1992.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogers CN, Ross AP, Sahu SP, et al. Oxytocin- and arginine vasopressin-containing fibers in the cortex of humans, chimpanzees, and rhesus macaques. Am J Primatol. 2018;80:e22875.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ong ZY, McNally GP. CART in energy balance and drug addiction: current insights and mechanisms. Brain Res. 2020;1740:146852.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li SB, de Lecea L. The hypocretin (orexin) system: from a neural circuitry perspective. Neuropharmacol. 2020;167:107993.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheong RY, Gabery S, Petersen A. The role of hypothalamic pathology for non-motor features of Huntington's disease. J Huntingtons Dis. 2019;8:375-391.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wierda M, Goudsmit E, Van Der Woude PF, et al. Oxytocin cell number in the human paraventricular nucleus remains constant with aging and in Alzheimer's disease. Neurobiol Aging. 1991;12:511-516.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zielonka D, Piotrowska I, Marcinkowski JT, Mielcarek M. Skeletal muscle pathology in Huntington's disease. Front Physiol. 2014;5:380.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mochel F, Charles P, Seguin F, et al. Early energy deficit in Huntington disease: identification of a plasma biomarker traceable during disease progression. PLoS One. 2007;2:e647.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benoni A, Renzini A, Cavioli G, Adamo S. Neurohypophyseal hormones and skeletal muscle: a tale of two faces. Eur J Transl Myol. 2020;30:8899.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elabd C, Cousin W, Upadhyayula P, et al. Oxytocin is an age-specific circulating hormone that is necessary for muscle maintenance and regeneration. Nat Commun. 2014;5:4082.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quinn L, Kegelmeyer D, Kloos A, Rao AK, Busse M, Fritz NE. Clinical recommendations to guide physical therapy practice for Huntington disease. Neurol. 2020;94:217-228.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martins DA, Mazibuko N, Zelaya F, et al. Effects of route of administration on oxytocin-induced changes in regional cerebral blood flow in humans. Nat Commun. 2020;11:1160.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thannickal TC, Moore RY, Nienhuis R, et al. Reduced number of hypocretin neurons in human narcolepsy. Neuron. 2000;27:469-474.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thannickal TC, Lai YY, Siegel JM. Hypocretin (orexin) cell loss in Parkinson's disease. Brain. 2007;130:1586-1595.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maejima Y, Takahashi S, Takasu K, Takenoshita S, Ueta Y, Shimomura K. Orexin action on oxytocin neurons in the paraventricular nucleus of the hypothalamus. NeuroReport. 2017;28:360-366.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scammell TE, Arrigoni E, Lipton JO. Neural circuitry of wakefulness and sleep. Neuron. 2017;93:747-765.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Follwell MJ, Ferguson AV. Cellular mechanisms of orexin actions on paraventricular nucleus neurones in rat hypothalamus. J Physiol. 2002;545:855-867.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vrang N. Anatomy of hypothalamic CART neurons. Peptides. 2006;27:1970-1980.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren S, Wang Y, Yue F, et al. The paraventricular thalamus is a critical thalamic area for wakefulness. Science. 2018;362:429-434.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parsons MP, Li S, Kirouac GJ. The paraventricular nucleus of the thalamus as an interface between the orexin and CART peptides and the shell of the nucleus accumbens. Synapse. 2006;59:480-490.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keating GL, Kuhar MJ, Bliwise DL, Rye DB. Wake promoting effects of cocaine and amphetamine-regulated transcript (CART). Neuropeptides. 2010;44:241-246.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun X, Zhao X, Liu Q, et al. Study on sleep-wake disorders in patients with genetic and non-genetic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2020;92(1):96-102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dedeene L, Van Schoor E, Vandenberghe R, Van Damme P, Poesen K, Thal DR. Circadian sleep/wake-associated cells show dipeptide repeat protein aggregates in C9orf72-related ALS and FTLD cases. Acta Neuropathol Commun. 2019;7:189.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dedeene L, Van Schoor E, Ospitalieri S, et al. Dipeptide repeat protein and TDP-43 pathology along the hypothalamic-pituitary axis in C9orf72 and non-C9orf72 ALS and FTLD-TDP cases. Acta Neuropathol. 2020;140:777-781.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bilic E, Bilic E, Rudan I, et al. Comparison of the growth hormone, IGF-1 and insulin in cerebrospinal fluid and serum between patients with motor neuron disease and healthy controls. Eur J Neurol. 2006;13:1340-1345.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zegarra-Valdivia JA, Pignatelli J, Fernandez de Sevilla ME, et al. Insulin-like growth factor I modulates sleep through hypothalamic orexin neurons. FASEB J. 2020;34:15975-15990.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shariq AS, Rosenblat JD, Alageel A, et al. Evaluating the role of orexins in the pathophysiology and treatment of depression: a comprehensive review. Prog Neuropsychopharmacol Biol Psychiatry. 2019;92:1-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finger EC, MacKinley J, Blair M, et al. Oxytocin for frontotemporal dementia: a randomized dose-finding study of safety and tolerability. Neurol. 2015;84:174-181.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mioshi E, Caga J, Lillo P, et al. Neuropsychiatric changes precede classic motor symptoms in ALS and do not affect survival. Neurol. 2014;82:149-155.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caga J, Hsieh S, Highton-Williamson E, et al. Apathy and its impact on patient outcome in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol. 2018;265:187-193.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>