<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">33763884</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>29</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-0258</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>40</Volume><Issue>13</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Jun</Month><Day>15</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Statistics in medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Stat Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A binary hidden Markov model on spatial network for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis disease spreading pattern analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>3035</StartPage><EndPage>3052</EndPage><MedlinePgn>3035-3052</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/sim.8956</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) is a neurological disease that starts at a focal point and gradually spreads to other parts of the nervous system. One of the main clinical symptoms of ALS is muscle weakness. To study spreading patterns of muscle weakness, we analyze spatiotemporal binary muscle strength data, which indicates whether observed muscle strengths are impaired or healthy. We propose a hidden Markov model-based approach that assumes the observed disease status depends on two latent disease states. The model enables us to estimate the incidence rate of ALS disease and the probability of disease state transition. Specifically, the latter is modeled by a logistic autoregression in that the spatial network of susceptible muscles follows a Markov process. The proposed model is flexible to allow both historical muscle conditions and their spatial relationships to be included in the analysis. To estimate the model parameters, we provide an iterative algorithm to maximize sparse-penalized likelihood with bias correction, and use the Viterbi algorithm to label hidden disease states. We apply the proposed approach to analyze the ALS patients' data from EMPOWER Study.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shin</LastName><ForeName>Yei Eun</ForeName><Initials>YE</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0739-1281</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biostatistics Branch, Division of Cancer Epidemiology and Genetics, National Cancer Institute, Rockville, Maryland, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Dawei</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Global Analytics and Data Sciences, Biogen, Cambridge, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sang</LastName><ForeName>Huiyan</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Statistics, Texas A&amp;M University, College Station, Texas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ferguson</LastName><ForeName>Toby A</ForeName><Initials>TA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurology Research and Early Clinical Development, Biogen, Cambridge, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Song</LastName><ForeName>Peter X K</ForeName><Initials>PXK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biostatistics, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, Michigan, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013486">Research Support, U.S. Gov't, Non-P.H.S.</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Stat Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8215016</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0277-6715</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000465" MajorTopicYN="N">Algorithms</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008390" MajorTopicYN="N">Markov Chains</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Viterbi algorithm</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">autologistic regressive model</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hidden Markov model</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">network</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">penalized likelihood</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">spatiotemporal</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33763884</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/sim.8956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Besag J. Spatial interaction and the statistical analysis of lattice systems. J Royal Stat Soc Ser B (Methodol). 1974;36(2):192-236.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Besag J. Statistical analysis of non-lattice data. Statistician. 1975;24(3):179-195.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu J, Huang HC, Wu J. Modeling spatial-temporal binary data using Markov random fields. J Agric Biol Environ Stat. 2005;10(2):212-225.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes J, Haran M, Caragea PC. Autologistic models for binary data on a lattice. Environmetrics. 2011;22(7):857-871.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rabiner LR. A tutorial on hidden Markov models and selected applications in speech recognition. Proc IEEE. 1989;77(2):257-286.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tibshirani R. Regression shrinkage and selection via the lasso. J Royal Stat Soc Ser B (Methodol). 1996;58(1):267-288.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geer S, B&#xfc;hlmann P, Ritov Y'a, Dezeure R. On asymptotically optimal confidence regions and tests for high-dimensional models. Ann Stat. 2014;42(3):1166-1202.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang L, Zhou L, Song PX-K. Distributed simultaneous inference in generalized linear models via confidence distribution. J Multivar Anal. 2020;176:104567.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z. Analysis of Binary Data via Spatial-Temporal Autologistic Regression Models. Theses and Dissertations-Statistics. Lexington, KY: University of Kentucky; 2012;3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viterbi A. Error bounds for convolutional codes and an asymptotically optimum decoding algorithm. IEEE Trans Inf Theory. 1967;13(2):260-269.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cudkowicz ME, Berg LH, Shefner JM, et al. Dexpramipexole versus placebo for patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (EMPOWER): a randomised, double-blind, phase 3 trial. Lancet Neurol. 2013;12(11):1059-1067.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caragea PC, Kaiser MS. Autologistic models with interpretable parameters. J Agric Biol Environ Stat. 2009;14(3):281-300.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes J, Haran M. Dimension reduction and alleviation of confounding for spatial generalized linear mixed models. J Royal Stat Soc Ser B (Stat Methodol). 2013;75(1):139-159.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agaskar A, Lu YM. ALARM: a logistic auto-regressive model for binary processes on networks. Paper presented at: Proceedings of the 2013 IEEE Global Conference on Signal and Information Processing. Austin, TX; 2013:305-308. https://doi.org/10.1109/GlobalSIP.2013.6736876.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Golub GH, Heath M, Wahba G. Generalized cross-validation as a method for choosing a good ridge parameter. Technometrics. 1979;21(2):215-223.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwarz G. Estimating the dimension of a model. Ann Stat. 1978;6(2):461-464.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen J, Chen Z. Extended Bayesian information criteria for model selection with large model spaces. Biometrika. 2008;95(3):759-771.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shin YE, Sang H, Liu D, Ferguson TA, Song PXK. Autologistic network model on binary data for disease progression study. Biometrics. 2019;75(4):1310-1320.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nocedal J, Wright S. Numerical Optimization. Berlin, Germany: Springer Science &amp; Business Media; 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NIMS Database of the National Isometric Muscle Strength. Muscular weakness assessment: use of normal isometric strength data. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 1996;77(12):1251-1255.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bohannon RW. Reference values for extremity muscle strength obtained by hand-held dynamometry from adults aged 20 to 79&#x2009;years. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 1997;78(1):26-32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zou H. The adaptive lasso and its oracle properties. J Am Stat Assoc. 2006;101(476):1418-1429.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan J, Li R. Variable selection via nonconcave penalized likelihood and its oracle properties. J Am Stat Assoc. 2001;96(456):1348-1360.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang C-H. Nearly unbiased variable selection under minimax concave penalty. Ann Stat. 2010;38(2):894-942.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song Q, Liang F. High-dimensional variable selection with reciprocal l1-regularization. J Am Stat Assoc. 2015;110(512):1607-1620.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wasserman L, Roeder K. High dimensional variable selection. Ann Stat. 2009;37(5A):2178.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X, Cheng G. Simultaneous inference for high-dimensional linear models. J Am Stat Assoc. 2017;112(518):757-768.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bertarelli G, Ranalli G, Bartolucci F, D'Al&#xf2; M, Solari F. Small area estimation for unemployment using latent Markov models. Survey Methodol. 2018;44(2):167-192.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei Z, Li H. A hidden spatial-temporal Markov random field model for network-based analysis of time course gene expression data. Ann Appl Stat. 2008;2(1):408-429.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen S, Langley J, Chen X, Hu X. Spatiotemporal modeling of brain dynamics using resting-state functional magnetic resonance imaging with Gaussian hidden Markov model. Brain Connect. 2016;6(4):326-334.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartolucci F, Pandolfi S, Pennoni F. LMest: an R package for latent Markov models for longitudinal categorical data. J Stat Softw. 2017;81(1):1-38.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>