<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">33764559</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>25</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1521-186X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>42</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>May</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Bioelectromagnetics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Bioelectromagnetics</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Occupational Exposure to Extremely Low-Frequency Magnetic Fields and Risk of Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis: Results of a Feasibility Study for a Pooled Analysis of Original Data.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>271</StartPage><EndPage>283</EndPage><MedlinePgn>271-283</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/bem.22335</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Previous meta-analyses have suggested an increased risk of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) associated with occupational exposure to extremely low-frequency magnetic fields (ELF-MF). However, results should be interpreted with caution since studies were methodologically heterogeneous. Here, we assessed the feasibility of a pooling study to harmonize and re-analyze available original data. A systematic literature search was conducted. Published epidemiological studies were identified in PubMed and EMF-Portal from literature databases' inception dates until January 2019. The characteristics of all studies were described, including exposure metrics, exposure categories, and confounders. A survey among the principal investigators (PI) was carried out to assess their willingness to provide their original data. The statistical power of a pooling study was evaluated. We identified 15 articles published between 1997 and 2019. Studies differed in terms of outcome, study population, exposure assessment, and exposure metrics. Most studies assessed ELF-MF as average magnetic flux density per working day; however, exposure categories varied widely. The pattern of adjustment for confounders was heterogeneous between studies, with age, sex, and socioeconomic status being most frequent. Eight PI&#xa0;expressed their willingness to provide original data. A relative risk of &#x2265;1.14 for ALS and occupational exposure to ELF-MF can be detected with a power of more than 80% in a pooled study. The pooling of original data is recommended and could contribute to a better understanding of ELF-MF in the etiology of ALS based on a large database and reduced heterogeneity due to a standardized analysis protocol with harmonized exposure metrics and exposure categories. Bioelectromagnetics. &#xa9; 2021 Bioelectromagnetics Society.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 The Authors. Bioelectromagnetics published by Wiley Periodicals LLC on behalf of Bioelectromagnetics Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Baaken</LastName><ForeName>Dan</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4498-2352</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Medical Biostatistics, Epidemiology and Informatics (IMBEI), University Medical Center of the Johannes Gutenberg-University, Mainz, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dechent</LastName><ForeName>Dagmar</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Center for Bioelectromagnetic Interaction (femu), Institute of Occupational, Social and Environmental Medicine, Medical Faculty, University Hospital RWTH, Aachen, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Blettner</LastName><ForeName>Maria</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Medical Biostatistics, Epidemiology and Informatics (IMBEI), University Medical Center of the Johannes Gutenberg-University, Mainz, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Drie&#xdf;en</LastName><ForeName>Sarah</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Center for Bioelectromagnetic Interaction (femu), Institute of Occupational, Social and Environmental Medicine, Medical Faculty, University Hospital RWTH, Aachen, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Merzenich</LastName><ForeName>Hiltrud</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Medical Biostatistics, Epidemiology and Informatics (IMBEI), University Medical Center of the Johannes Gutenberg-University, Mainz, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>3618S82451</GrantID><Agency>Bundesamt f&#xfc;r Strahlenschutz</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Bioelectromagnetics</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8008281</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0197-8462</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004574" MajorTopicYN="N">Electromagnetic Fields</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005240" MajorTopicYN="N">Feasibility Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D060526" MajorTopicYN="N">Magnetic Fields</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016273" MajorTopicYN="Y">Occupational Exposure</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012306" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">feasibility study</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">magnetic fields</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">non-ionizing radiation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">occupation</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>58</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33764559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/bem.22335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Ahlbom IC, Cardis E, Green A, Linet M, Savitz D, Swerdlow A. 2001. Review of the epidemiologic literature on EMF and health. Environ Health Perspect 109(Suppl 6):911-933.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belbasis L, Bellou V, Evangelou E. 2016. Environmental risk factors and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: An umbrella review and critical assessment of current evidence from systematic reviews and meta-analyses of observational studies. Neuroepidemiology 46:96-105.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowman JD, Touchstone JA, Yost MG. 2007. A population-based job exposure matrix for power-frequency magnetic fields. J Occup Environ Hyg 4:715-728.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bozzoni V, Pansarasa O, Diamanti L, Nosari G, Cereda C, Ceroni M. 2016. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and environmental factors. Funct Neurol 31:7-19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davanipour Z, Sobel E, Bowman JD, Qian Z, Will AD. 1997. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and occupational exposure to electromagnetic fields. Bioelectromagnetics 18:28-35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feychting M, Jonsson F, Pedersen NL, Ahlbom A. 2003. Occupational magnetic field exposure and neurodegenerative disease. Epidemiology 14:413-419.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fischer H, Kheifets L, Huss A, Peters TL, Vermeulen R, Ye W, Fang F, Wiebert P, Vergara XP, Feychting M. 2015. Occupational exposure to electric shocks and magnetic fields and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in Sweden. Epidemiology 26:824-830.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Floderus B, Persson T, Stenlund C. 1996. Magnetic-field exposures in the workplace: Reference distribution and exposures in occupational groups. Int J Occup Environ Health 2:226-238.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galobardes B, Shaw M, Lawlor DA, Lynch JW, Davey, Smith G. 2006. Indicators of socioeconomic position (part 1). J Epidemiol Community Health 60:7-12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gobba F, Bravo G, Rossi P, Contessa GM, Scaringi M. 2011. Occupational and environmental exposure to extremely low frequency-magnetic fields: A personal monitoring study in a large group of workers in Italy. J Expo Sci Environ Epidemiol 21:634-645.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon PH. 2011. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. CNS Drugs 25:1-15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hakansson N, Gustavsson P, Johansen C, Floderus B. 2003. Neurodegenerative diseases in welders and other workers exposed to high levels of magnetic fields. Epidemiology 14:420-426.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hofer SM, Piccinin AM. 2009. Integrative data analysis through coordination of measurement and analysis protocol across independent longitudinal studies. Psychol Methods 14:150-164.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huss A, Peters S, Vermeulen R. 2018. Occupational exposure to extremely low-frequency magnetic fields and the risk of ALS: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Bioelectromagnetics 39:156-163.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huss A, Spoerri A, Egger M, Kromhout H, Vermeulen R. 2015. Occupational exposure to magnetic fields and electric shocks and risk of ALS: The Swiss national cohort. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 16:80-85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huss A, Vermeulen R, Bowman JD, Kheifets L, Kromhout H. 2013. Electric shocks at work in Europe: Development of a job exposure matrix. Occup Environ Med 70:261-267.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>International Commission on Non-Ionizing Radiation Protection. 2010. Guidelines for limiting exposure to time-varying electric and magnetic fields (1 Hz to 100 kHz). Health Phys 99:818-836.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ioannidis JPA. 2018. Meta-research: Why research on research matters. PLOS Biol 16:e2005468.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johansen C. 2000. Exposure to electromagnetic fields and risk of central nervous system disease in utility workers. Epidemiology 11:539-543.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johansen C. 2001. [Exposure to electromagnetic fields and risk of central nervous system diseases among employees at Danish electric companies]. Ugeskr Laeger 164:50-54, in Danish.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johansen C, Olsen J. 1998a. Mortality from amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, other chronic disorders, and electric shocks among utility workers. Am J Epidemiol 148:362-368.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johansen C, Olsen JH. 1998b. Risk of cancer among Danish utility workers-A nationwide cohort study. Am J Epidemiol 147:548-555.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kheifets L, Bowman JD, Checkoway H, Feychting M, Harrington JM, Kavet R, Marsh G, Mezei G, Renew DC, van Wijngaarden E. 2009. Future needs of occupational epidemiology of extremely low frequency electric and magnetic fields: Review and recommendations. Occup Environ Med 66:72-80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koeman T, Slottje P, Schouten LJ, Peters S, Huss A, Veldink JH, Kromhout H, van den Brandt PA, Vermeulen R. 2017. Occupational exposure and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in a prospective cohort. Occup Environ Med 74:578-585.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korpinen LH, Elovaara JA, Kuisti HA. 2009. Evaluation of current densities and total contact currents in occupational exposure at 400 kV substations and power lines. Bioelectromagnetics 30:231-240.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kromhout H, Loomis DP, Mihlan GJ, Peipins LA, Kleckner RC, Iriye R, Savitz DA. 1995. Assessment and grouping of occupational magnetic field exposure in five electric utility companies. Scand J Work Environ Health 21:43-50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lesko CR, Jacobson LP, Althoff KN, Abraham AG, Gange SJ, Moore RD, Modur S, Lau B. 2018. Collaborative, pooled and harmonized study designs for epidemiologic research: Challenges and opportunities. Int J Epidemiol 47:654-668.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Logroscino G, Piccininni M. 2019. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis descriptive epidemiology: The origin of geographic difference. Neuroepidemiology 52:93-103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehta P, Antao V, Kaye W, Sanchez M, Williamson D, Bryan L, Muravov O, Horton K. 2014. Prevalence of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-United States 2010-2011. MMWR Suppl 63:1-14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merletti F, Mirabelli D, Richiardi L. 2014. Occupational epidemiology. In: Ahrens W, Pigeot I, editor. Handbook of Epidemiology. New York, NY: Springer New York, pp 1577-1609.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Metayer C, Milne E, Clavel J, Infante-Rivard C, Petridou E, Taylor M, Sch&#xfc;z J, Spector LG, Dockerty JD, Magnani C, Pombo-de-Oliveira MS, Sinnett D, Murphy M, Roman E, Monge P, Ezzat S, Mueller BA, Scheurer ME, Armstrong BK, Birch J, Kaatsch P, Koifman S, Lightfoot T, Bhatti P, Bondy ML, Rudant J, O&#x2032;Neill K, Miligi L, Dessypris N, Kang AY, Buffler PA. 2013. The childhood leukemia international consortium. Cancer Epidemiol 37:336-347.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moher D, Liberati A, Tetzlaff J, Altman DG. 2009. Preferred reporting items for systematic reviews and meta-analyses: The PRISMA statement. PLOS Med 6:e1000097.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morrison A, Polisena J, Husereau D, Moulton K, Clark M, Fiander M, Mierzwinski-Urban M, Clifford T, Hutton B, Rabb D. 2012. The effect of English-language restriction on systematic review-based meta-analyses: A systematic review of empirical studies. Int J Technol Assess Health Care 28:138-144.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munaf&#xf2; MR, Nosek BA, Bishop DVM, Button KS, Chambers CD, Percie du Sert N, Simonsohn U, Wagenmakers E-J, Ware JJ, Ioannidis JPA. 2017. A manifesto for reproducible science. Nat Hum Behav 1:0021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Toxicology Program. 2015. Handbook for conducting a literature-based health assessment using OHAT approach for systematic review and evidence integration. Office of Health Assessment and Translation. Available from https://ntp.niehs.nih.gov/whatwestudy/assessments/noncancer/handbook/index.html [Last accessed 8 March 2021].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noonan CW, Reif JS, Yost M, Touchstone J. 2002. Occupational exposure to magnetic fields in case-referent studies of neurodegenerative diseases. Scand J Work Environ Health 28:42-48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park RM, Schulte PA, Bowman JD, Walker JT, Bondy SC, Yost MG, Touchstone JA, Dosemeci M. 2005. Potential occupational risks for neurodegenerative diseases. Am J Ind Med 48:63-77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parlett LE, Bowman JD, van Wijngaarden E. 2011. Evaluation of occupational exposure to magnetic fields and motor neuron disease mortality in a population-based cohort. J Occup Environ Med 53:1447-1451.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedersen C, Poulsen AH, Rod NH, Frei P, Hansen J, Grell K, Raaschou-Nielsen O, Sch&#xfc;z J, Johansen C. 2017. Occupational exposure to extremely low-frequency magnetic fields and risk for central nervous system disease: An update of a Danish cohort study among utility workers. Int Arch Occup Environ Health 90:619-628.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peters S, Visser AE, D&#x2032;Ovidio F, Beghi E, Chi&#xf2; A, Logroscino G, Hardiman O, Kromhout H, Huss A, Veldink J, Vermeulen R, van den Berg LH. 2019. Electric shock and extremely low-frequency magnetic field exposure and the risk of ALS: Euro-motor. Am J Epidemiol 188:295-299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renew DC, Cook RF, Ball MC. 2003. A method for assessing occupational exposure to power-frequency magnetic fields for electricity generation and transmission workers. J Radiol Prot 23:279-303.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xf6;&#xf6;sli M, Jalilian H. 2018. A meta-analysis on residential exposure to magnetic fields and the risk of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Rev Environ Health 33:295-299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xf6;&#xf6;sli M, L&#xf6;rtscher M, Egger M, Pfluger D, Schreier N, L&#xf6;rtscher E, Locher P, Spoerri A, Minder C. 2007. Mortality from neurodegenerative disease and exposure to extremely low-frequency magnetic fields: 31 years of observations on Swiss railway employees. Neuroepidemiology 28:197-206.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rowland LP, Shneider NA. 2001. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. N Engl J Med 344:1688-1700.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Savitz DA, Checkoway H, Loomis DP. 1998. Magnetic field exposure and neurodegenerative disease mortality among electric utility workers. Epidemiology 9:398-404.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schaap LA, Peeters GM, Dennison EM, Zambon S, Nikolaus T, Sanchez-Martinez M, Musacchio E, van Schoor NM, Deeg DJ, group Er. 2011. European Project on OSteoArthritis (EPOSA): Methodological challenges in harmonization of existing data from five European population-based cohorts on aging. BMC Musculoskelet Disord 12:272.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shavers VL. 2007. Measurement of socioeconomic status in health disparities research. J Natl Med Assoc 99:1013-1023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sorahan T, Kheifets L. 2007. Mortality from Alzheimer&#x2032;s, motor neuron and Parkinson&#x2032;s disease in relation to magnetic field exposure: Findings from the study of UK electricity generation and transmission workers, 1973-2004. Occup Environ Med 64:820-826.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sorahan T, Mohammed N. 2014. Neurodegenerative disease and magnetic field exposure in UK electricity supply workers. Occup Med (Lond) 64:454-460.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stevenson M, Sergeant E, Nunes T, Heuer C, Marshall J, Sanchez J, Thornton R, Reiczigel J, Robison-Cox J, Sebastiani P, Solymos P, Yoshida K, Jones G, Pirikahu S, Firestone S, Kyle R, Popp J, Jay M, Reynard C 2020. epiR: Tools for the Analysis of Epidemiological Data. R package version 1.0-14. Available from https://CRAN.R-project.org/package=epiR [Last accessed 8 March 2021].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tikellis G, Dwyer T, Paltiel O, Phillips GS, Lemeshow S, Golding J, Northstone K, Boyd A, Olsen S, Ghantous A, Herceg Z, Ward MH, H&#xe5;berg SE, Magnus P, Olsen J, Str&#xf6;m M, Mahabir S, Jones RR, Ponsonby AL, Clavel J, Charles MA, Trevathan E, Min Qian Z, Maule MM, Qiu X, Hong YC, Brandalise S, Roman E, Wake M, He JR, Linet MS, International Childhood Cancer Cohort Consortium. 2018. The international childhood cancer cohort consortium (I4C): A research platform of prospective cohorts for studying the aetiology of childhood cancers. Paediatr Perinat Epidemiol 32:568-583.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Veen EB. 2018. Observational health research in Europe: Understanding the general data protection regulation and underlying debate. Eur J Cancer 104:70-80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vergara X, Kheifets L, Greenland S, Oksuzyan S, Cho YS, Mezei G. 2013. Occupational exposure to extremely low-frequency magnetic fields and neurodegenerative disease: A meta-analysis. J Occup Environ Med 55:135-146.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vergara X, Mezei G, Kheifets L. 2015a. Case-control study of occupational exposure to electric shocks and magnetic fields and mortality from amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in the US, 1991-1999. J Expo Sci Environ Epidemiol 25:65-71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vergara XP, Fischer HJ, Yost M, Silva M, Lombardi DA, Kheifets L. 2015b. Job exposure matrix for electric shock risks with their uncertainties. Int J Environ Res Public Health 12:3889-3902.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vergara XP, Kheifets L, Silva M, Bracken TD, Yost M. 2012. New electric-shock job exposure matrix. Am J Ind Med 55:232-240.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou H, Chen G, Chen C, Yu Y, Xu Z. 2012. Association between extremely low-frequency electromagnetic fields occupations and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A meta-analysis. PLOS One 7:e48354.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>