<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">33779087</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1976-2437</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>62</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Yonsei medical journal</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Yonsei Med J</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Clinical Course of Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis according to Initial Symptoms: An Analysis of 500 Cases.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>338</StartPage><EndPage>343</EndPage><MedlinePgn>338-343</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3349/ymj.2021.62.4.338</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">One obstacle in early diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) is its vague initial presentation, which is generally classified into limb- and bulbar-dominant types and may be mistaken for other musculoskeletal conditions. We analyzed clinical data from patients in relation to their initial presentation and prognosis from symptom onset to diagnosis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We retrospectively analyzed the medical records of patients with ALS who were admitted for pulmonary rehabilitation between January 2007 and December 2019. We collected data on time of onset, initial presenting symptoms, unnecessary operations due to misdiagnosis, and the time between symptom onset and final diagnosis of ALS.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Among 500 patients, unnecessary operations were performed in 43 patients. The median durations between symptom onset and ALS diagnosis for patients with and without operations were 11 and 9 months, respectively (<i>p</i>=0.008). 67.0%, 28.8%, and 4.2% of the patients presented with limb-, bulbar-, and respiratory-dominant symptoms, respectively, as initial presentations. The median ages at symptom onset were significantly different for limb-, bulbar-, and respiratory-dominant onset (57.5, 60.6, and 66.7 years, respectively; <i>p</i>&lt;0.001). Compared to the other two types, patients with the respiratory-dominant onset were all male and showed higher rate of emergent endotracheal intubation before ALS diagnosis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Inappropriate operations significantly delayed the diagnosis of ALS. Respiratory difficulty can account for a significant proportion among initial presentations in ALS. Compared to limb- and bulbar-dominant types, respiratory-dominant onset appears to show male predominance, older age at symptom onset, and poor respiratory prognosis.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; Copyright: Yonsei University College of Medicine 2021.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Jang Woo</ForeName><Initials>JW</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2634-0375</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, National Health Insurance Service Ilsan Hospital, Goyang, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Yonsei University Graduate School of Medicine, Seoul, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kang</LastName><ForeName>Seong Woong</ForeName><Initials>SW</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7279-3893</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Yonsei University Graduate School of Medicine, Seoul, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rehabilitation Institute of Neuromuscular Disease, Yonsei University College of Medicine, Seoul, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Medicine, Gangnam Severance Hospital, Yonsei University College of Medicine, Seoul, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Choi</LastName><ForeName>Won Ah</ForeName><Initials>WA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0403-8869</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rehabilitation Institute of Neuromuscular Disease, Yonsei University College of Medicine, Seoul, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Medicine, Gangnam Severance Hospital, Yonsei University College of Medicine, Seoul, Korea. reedlove37@yuhs.ac.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>3-2015-0264</GrantID><Acronym>YUCM</Acronym><Agency>Yonsei University College of Medicine</Agency><Country>Korea</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Korea (South)</Country><MedlineTA>Yonsei Med J</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0414003</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0513-5796</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018450" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Progression</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011379" MajorTopicYN="N">Prognosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">early diagnosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">respiratory symptoms</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">surgical procedures</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors have no potential conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33779087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8007429</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3349/ymj.2021.62.4.338</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">62.338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Joyce NC, Tolchin DW, Howard IM, Paganoni S. Motor neuron disease. In: Frontera WR, Delisa JA, Basford JR, Bockenek WL, Chae J, Robinson LR, editors. Delisa's physical medicine and rehabilitation: principles and practice. 6th ed. Philadelphia (PA): Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins Health; 2019. pp. 501&#x2013;519.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown RH, Al-Chalabi A. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. N Engl J Med. 2017;377:162&#x2013;172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28700839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nzwalo H, de Abreu D, Swash M, Pinto S, de Carvalho M. Delayed diagnosis in ALS: the problem continues. J Neurol Sci. 2014;343:173&#x2013;175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24972820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer M, Buerger M, Berlit P. Diagnostic problems and delay of diagnosis in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Neurol Neurosurg. 2010;112:103&#x2013;105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19931253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiernan MC, Vucic S, Cheah BC, Turner MR, Eisen A, Hardiman O, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet. 2011;377:942&#x2013;955.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21296405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sawada H. Clinical efficacy of edaravone for the treatment of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Expert Opin Pharmacother. 2017;18:735&#x2013;738.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28406335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller RG, Mitchell JD, Moore DH. Riluzole for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS)/motor neuron disease (MND) Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2012;2012:CD001447</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7055506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22419278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okada M, Yamashita S, Ueyama H, Ishizaki M, Maeda Y, Ando Y. Long-term effects of edaravone on survival of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. eNeurologicalSci. 2018;11:11&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6006910</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29928711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshino H. Edaravone for the treatment of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Expert Rev Neurother. 2019;19:185&#x2013;193.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30810406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>EFNS Task Force on Diagnosis and Management of Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. Andersen PM, Abrahams S, Borasio GD, de Carvalho M, Chio A, van Damme P, et al. EFNS guidelines on the clinical management of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (MALS)--revised report of an EFNS task force. Eur J Neurol. 2012;19:360&#x2013;375.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21914052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim S, Kang SW, Choi W, Park JH, Lee Y, Yu SJ. Survey on the diagnostic process of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Korean Acad Rehabil Med. 2011;35:110&#x2013;114.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim JM, Park JH, Kim HS, Lee JW, Lim HS, Choi WA, et al. Epidemiology and diagnostic process of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis as distinct from myelopathy: 5-year cohort study of whole-population in South Korea. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2018;19:547&#x2013;554.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30421999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakola E, Kokotis P, Zambelis T, Karandreas N. Inappropriate surgeries in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a still considerable issue. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2014;15:315&#x2013;317.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24533472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Onder H, Yildiz FG. Cervical spondylotic myelopathy mimicking amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Res. 2016;6:89&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Srinivasan J, Scala S, Jones HR, Saleh F, Russell JA. Inappropriate surgeries resulting from misdiagnosis of early amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 2006;34:359&#x2013;360.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16609978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshor D, Klugh A, 3rd, Appel SH, Haverkamp LJ. Incidence and characteristics of spinal decompression surgery after the onset of symptoms of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurosurgery. 2005;57:984&#x2013;989.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16284567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khishchenko N, Allen KD, Coffman CJ, Kasarskis EJ, Lindquist JH, Morgenlander JC, et al. Time to diagnosis in the National Registry of Veterans with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2010;11:125&#x2013;132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19153849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zoccolella S, Beghi E, Palagano G, Fraddosio A, Samarelli V, Lamberti P, et al. Predictors of delay in the diagnosis and clinical trial entry of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients: a population-based study. J Neurol Sci. 2006;250:45&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16920152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rothstein JD. Edaravone: a new drug approved for ALS. Cell. 2017;171:725.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29100067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jorgensen S, Arnold WD. Motor neuron diseases. In: Cifu DX, editor. Braddom's physical medicine and rehabilitation. 5th ed. Philadelphia (PA): Saunders Elsevier; 2016. pp. 883&#x2013;905.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krivickas LS, Carter GT. Adult motor neuron disease. In: Frontera WR, DeLisa JA, Gans BM, Walsh NE, Robinson LR, editors. Delisa's physical medicine and rehabilitation: principles and practice. 5th ed. Philadelphia (PA): Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins Health; 2010. pp. 717&#x2013;740.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S, Burke D, Kiernan MC. Diagnosis of motor neuron disease. In: Kiernan MC, editor. The motor neuron disease handbook. Sidney: Australasian Medical Publishing Company Limited; 2007. pp. 89&#x2013;115.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paganoni S, Macklin EA, Lee A, Murphy A, Chang J, Zipf A, et al. Diagnostic timelines and delays in diagnosing amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2014;15:453&#x2013;456.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4433003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24981792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gautier G, Verschueren A, Monnier A, Attarian S, Salort-Campana E, Pouget J. ALS with respiratory onset: clinical features and effects of non-invasive ventilation on the prognosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2010;11:379&#x2013;382.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20001486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shoesmith CL, Findlater K, Rowe A, Strong MJ. Prognosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with respiratory onset. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2007;78:629&#x2013;631.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2077959</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17088331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Matias T, Coelho F, Evangelista T, Pinto A, Lu&#xed;s ML. Motor neuron disease presenting with respiratory failure. J Neurol Sci. 1996;(139 Suppl):117&#x2013;122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8899670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sato K, Morimoto N, Deguchi K, Ikeda Y, Matsuura T, Abe K. Seven amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients diagnosed only after development of respiratory failure. J Clin Neurosci. 2014;21:1341&#x2013;1343.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24613427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chou CT, Lin CH, Choi WM. Acute respiratory failure as initial presentation of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis onset. Int J Gerontol. 2008;2:72&#x2013;75.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>