<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">33786908</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>21</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-277X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>34</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of human nutrition and dietetics : the official journal of the British Dietetic Association</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Hum Nutr Diet</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The nutritional management of people living with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A national survey of dietitians.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1064</StartPage><EndPage>1071</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1064-1071</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/jhn.12900</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">People living with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) face many challenges with respect to taking adequate nutrition. Growing evidence links weight loss with negative prognostic outcomes. We aimed to explore the practice of dietitians in the UK with regard to the nutritional management of ALS.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">A national online survey was disseminated via professional groups, social media and newsletters to UK healthcare professionals between September and November 2018. The survey examined the nutritional management of ALS. Dietitian responses are reported in the present study.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">In total, 130 dietitians responded to the survey. Two-thirds reported that ALS comprised less than 20% of their total patient caseload. Forty-two percent reported that nutritional screening took place in their organisation. One-half of dietitians reported that patients were referred for dietetic assessment at 'about the right time', although 44% reported referrals were made too late. The majority (83%) of dietitians used resting energy expenditure predictive equations not validated in ALS. When setting weight goals, dietitians reported most frequently recommending weight maintenance if the patient's body mass index was 18.5-25&#xa0;kg&#xa0;m<sup>-2</sup> (72%), 25-30&#xa0;kg&#xa0;m<sup>-2</sup> (98%), and &gt;&#xa0;30&#xa0;kg&#xa0;m<sup>-2</sup> (79%). In addition, 43% reported that people with ALS were not weighed sufficiently frequently.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Although the importance of early nutritional assessment is recognised, the timeliness of dietetic input and on-going monitoring of nutritional status in ALS care might not currently be ideal. Dietitians report using energy requirement predictive equations and setting weight goals that may not promote positive outcomes. Further research is required to understand the optimal nutritional management of ALS.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 The British Dietetic Association Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>White</LastName><ForeName>Sean</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6865-9624</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sheffield Teaching Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust, Sheffield, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zarotti</LastName><ForeName>Nicol&#xf2;</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8129-6151</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sheffield Institute for Translational Neuroscience (SITraN), The University of Sheffield, Sheffield, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Beever</LastName><ForeName>Daniel</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Health and Related Research (ScHARR), The University of Sheffield, Sheffield, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bradburn</LastName><ForeName>Mike</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Health and Related Research (ScHARR), The University of Sheffield, Sheffield, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Norman</LastName><ForeName>Paul</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, The University of Sheffield, Sheffield, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Coates</LastName><ForeName>Elizabeth</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Health and Related Research (ScHARR), The University of Sheffield, Sheffield, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stavroulakis</LastName><ForeName>Theocharis</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sheffield Institute for Translational Neuroscience (SITraN), The University of Sheffield, Sheffield, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>White</LastName><ForeName>David</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Health and Related Research (ScHARR), The University of Sheffield, Sheffield, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McGeachan</LastName><ForeName>Alexander</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sheffield Institute for Translational Neuroscience (SITraN), The University of Sheffield, Sheffield, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Williams</LastName><ForeName>Isobel</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, The University of Sheffield, Sheffield, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hackney</LastName><ForeName>Gemma</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Health and Related Research (ScHARR), The University of Sheffield, Sheffield, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Halliday</LastName><ForeName>Vanessa</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Health and Related Research (ScHARR), The University of Sheffield, Sheffield, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McDermott</LastName><ForeName>Christopher</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sheffield Institute for Translational Neuroscience (SITraN), The University of Sheffield, Sheffield, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><CollectiveName>HighCALS group</CollectiveName></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>RP-PG-1016-20006</GrantID><Acronym>DH_</Acronym><Agency>Department of Health</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Hum Nutr Diet</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8904840</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0952-3871</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D044342" MajorTopicYN="Y">Malnutrition</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015596" MajorTopicYN="N">Nutrition Assessment</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009752" MajorTopicYN="N">Nutritional Status</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D064686" MajorTopicYN="Y">Nutritionists</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">malnutrition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">motor neurone disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nutrition support</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nutritional assessment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nutritional interventions</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33786908</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jhn.12900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>McDermott CJ, Shaw PJ. Diagnosis and management of motor neurone disease. BMJ. 2008;336:658-62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ngo S, Van Eijk R, Chachay V, van den Berg LH, McCombe PA, Henderson RD, et al. Loss of appetite is associated with a loss of weight and fat mass in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2019;20(7-8):497-505.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dupuis L, Oudart H, Rene F, de Aguilar J-lG, Loeffler J-P. Evidence for defective energy homeostasis in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: benefit of a high-energy diet in a transgenic mouse model. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2004;101:11159-64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Genton L, Viatte V, Janssens J, H&#xe9;ritier A-C, Pichard C. Nutritional state, energy intakes and energy expenditure of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) patients. Clin Nutr. 2011;30:553-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xf6;rner S, Hendricks M, Kollewe K, Zapf A, Dengler R, Silani V, et al. Weight loss, dysphagia and supplement intake in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS): impact on quality of life and therapeutic options. BMC Neurol. 2013;13:84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desport JC, Preux PM, Truong TC, Vallat JM, Sautereau D, Couratier P. Nutritional status is a prognostic factor for survival in ALS patients. Neurology. 1999;53:1059-63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rio A, Ellis C, Shaw C, Willey E, Ampong M-A, Wijesekera L, et al. Nutritional factors associated with survival following enteral tube feeding in patients with motor neurone disease. J Hum Nutr Diet. 2010;23:408-15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dorst J, Cypionka J, Ludolph AC. High-caloric food supplements in the treatment of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a prospective interventional study. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2013;14:533-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva L, Mour&#xe3;o L, Silva A, Lima NMFV, Almeida SR, Franca Jr MC, et al. Effect of nutritional supplementation with milk whey proteins in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. Arq Neuropsiquiatr. 2010;2010(68):263-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ludolph A, Dorst J, Dreyhaupt J, Weishaupt JH, Kassubek J, Weiland U, et al. Effect of high-caloric nutrition on survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol. 2019;87:206-16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cawadias E, Rio A. Neurological disease, motor neurone disease. In: Gandy J, editors. Manual of Dietetic Practice. Hoboken: John Wiley and Sons, Incorporated; 2014. p. 555-62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>British Dietetic Association (BDA). Parenteral and Enteral Nutrition Specialist Group of the BDA (PENG). A pocket guide to clinical nutrition - Adult requirements section. 5th ed. Birmingham: British Dietetic Association (BDA); 2018. 3.11a-3.11b.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller R, Jackson C, Kasarskis E, England JD, Forshew D, Johnston W, et al. Practice Parameter update: the care of the patient with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: multidisciplinary care, symptom management, and cognitive/behavioural impairment (an evidence-based review). Neurology. 2009;73:1227-33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen P, Abrahams S, Borasio G, de Carvalho M, Chio A, Van Damme P, et al. EFNS guidelines on the Clinical Management of Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis (MALS) - revised report of an EFNS task force. Eur J Neurol. 2012;19:360-75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NICE. Clinical guideline NG42. Motor neurone disease: assessment and management. 2019. https://www.nice.org.uk/guidance/NG42. Accessed Jul 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stratton R, Smith T, Gabe S. Managing malnutrition to improve lives and save money. 2018. www.bapen.org.uk. Accessed Jul 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>British Dietetic Association. Model and process for nutrition and dietetic practice. 2016. https://www.bda.uk.com/professional/practice/processmodeldieteticpractice_2016_v. Accessed Nov 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wills A, Hubbard J, Macklin E, Glass J, Tandan R, Simpson EP, et al. Hypercaloric enteral nutrition in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a randomised, double-blind, placebo controlled phase 2 trial. Lancet. 2014;383:2065-72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ProGas group. Gastrostomy in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ProGas): a prospective cohort study. Lancet Neurol. 2015;14:702-709.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rio A, Cawadias E. Nutritional advice and treatment by dietitians to patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis/motor neurone disease: a survey of current practice in England, Wales, Northern Ireland and Canada. J Hum Nutr Diet. 2007;20:3-13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang M, Hubbard J, Rudnicki S, Johansen CS, Dalton K, Heiman-Patterson T, et al. Survey of current enteral nutrition practices in treatment of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. ESPEN J. 2013;8:e25-e28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zarotti N, Coates E, McGeachan A, Williams I, Beever D, Hackney G, et al. Health care professionals&#x2019; views on psychological factors affecting nutritional behaviour in people with motor neuron disease: a thematic analysis. Br J Health Psychol. 2019;24:953-69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halliday V, Zarotti N, Coates L, McGeachan A, Williams I, White S, et al. Delivery of nutritional management services to people with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2021 Jan 28;1-10. doi: 10.1080/21678421.2021.1874991. Online ahead of print.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elia M. The &#x2018;MUST&#x2019; Report. Nutritional screening of adults: a multidisciplinary responsibility. Development and use of the &#x2018;Malnutrition Universal Screening Tool&#x2019; (&#x2018;MUST&#x2019;) for adults. 2003. https://www.bapen.org.uk/pdfs/must/must-report.pdf. Accessed Jul 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henry C. Basal metabolic rate studies in humans: measurement and development of new equations. Public Health Nutr. 2005;8:1133-52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>British Dietetic Association (BDA). Parenteral and Enteral Nutrition Specialist Group of the BDA (PENG). A pocket guide to clinical nutrition - Adult requirements section. 4th ed. Birmingham: British Dietetic Association (BDA); 2011. p. 3.13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elia M. Artificial nutrition support. Med Int. 1990;82:3392-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf3;pez-G&#xf3;mez J, Torres-Torres B, G&#xf3;mez-Hoyos E, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Buey N, Ortol&#xe1;-Buigues A, Castro-Lozano &#xc1;, et al. Influence of a multidisciplinary protocol on nutritional status at diagnosis in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nutrition. 2018;48:67-72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russell C, Elia M. Nutrition screening survey in the UK and republic of Ireland in 2011. A report by the British Association for Parenteral and Enteral Nutrition (BAPEN). Hospitals, care homes and mental health units. 2011. https://www.bapen.org.uk/pdfs/nsw/nsw-2011-report.pdf. Accessed 3 Mar 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NICE. Clinical Guideline CG32. Nutrition support for adults: oral nutrition support, enteral tube feeding and parenteral nutrition. 2017. https://www.nice.org.uk/guidance/cg32. Accessed Jul 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin G, Tapsell L, Batterham M, Russell KG. Relative bias in diet history measurements: a quality control technique for dietary intervention trials. Public Health Nutr. 2002;5:537-45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desport J, Preux P, Magy L, Boirie Y, Vallat JM, Beaufr&#xe8;re B, et al. Factors correlated with hypermetabolism in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Am J Clin Nutr. 2001;74:328-34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaisman N, Lusaus M, Nefussy B, Niv E, Comaneshter D, Hallack R, et al. Do patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) have increased energy needs? J Neurol Sci. 2009;279:26-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasarskis E, Mendiondo M, Matthews D, Mitsumoto H, Tandan R, Simmons Z, et al. Estimating daily energy expenditure in individuals with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Am J Clin Nutr. 2014;99:792-803.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouteloup C, Desport J, Clavelou A, Guy N, Derumeaux-Burel H, Ferrier A, et al. Hypermetabolism in ALS patients: an early and persistent phenomenon. J Neurol. 2009;256:1236-42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steyn F, Ioannides Z, Van Eijk R, Heggie S, Thorpe KA, Ceslis A, et al. Hypermetabolism in ALS is associated with greater functional decline and shorter survival. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2018;89:1016-23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jesus P, Marin B, Fayemendy P, Nicol M, Lautrette G, Sourisseau H, et al. Resting energy expenditure equations in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, creation of an ALS-specific equation. Clin Nutr. 2018;38:1657-65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimizu T, Nakayama Y, Matsuda C, Haraguchi M, Bokuda K, Ishikawa-Takata K, et al. Prognostic significance of body weight variation after diagnosis in ALS: a single-centre prospective cohort study. J Neurol. 2019;266:1412-20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paganoni S, Deng J, Jaffa M, Cudkowicz ME, Wills A-M. Body mass index, not dyslipidemia, is an independent predictor of survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 2011;44:20-4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burgos R, Breton I, Cereda E, Desport JC, Dziewas R, Genton L, et al. ESPEN guideline clinical nutrition in neurology. Clin Nutr. 2018;37:354-96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baldwin C, Weekes C. Dietary counselling with or without oral nutritional supplements in the management of malnourished patients: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomised controlled trials. J Hum Nutr Diet. 2012;25:411-26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>BAPEN. Self-screening tool. 2018. https://www.malnutritionselfscreening.org/self-screening. Accessed Jul 2020.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>