<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">33835818</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>24</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1520-5207</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>125</Volume><Issue>15</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>22</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The journal of physical chemistry. B</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Phys Chem B</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Tryptophan Probes of TDP-43 C-Terminal Domain Amyloid Formation.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>3781</StartPage><EndPage>3789</EndPage><MedlinePgn>3781-3789</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1021/acs.jpcb.1c00767</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Aggregated TAR DNA-binding protein 43 (TDP-43) forms the cytoplasmic hallmarks associated with patients suffering from amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal lobar degeneration with ubiquitin. Under normal conditions, TDP-43 is a 414-amino acid protein; however, aggregates are enriched with N-terminal truncations which contain residues 267-414, known as the C-terminal domain of TDP-43 (TDP-43<sub>CTD</sub>). To gain residue-specific information on the aggregation process of TDP-43<sub>CTD</sub>, we created three single-Trp containing mutants (W385F/W412F, W334F/W412F, and W334F/W385F) by substituting two of the three native Trp residues with Phe, yielding fluorescent probes at W334, W385, and W412, respectively. Aggregation kinetics, secondary structure, and fibril morphology were compared to the wild-type protein using thioflavin-T fluorescence, Raman spectroscopy, and transmission electron microscopy, respectively. While only W334 is determined to be in the proteinase-K resistant core, all three sites are sensitive reporters of aggregation, revealing site-specific differences. Interestingly, W334 exhibited unusual multistep Trp kinetics, pinpointing a distinctive role for W334 and its nearby region during aggregation. This behavior is retained even upon seeding, suggesting the observed spectral change is related to fibril growth. This work provides new insights into the aggregation mechanism of TDP-43<sub>CTD</sub> and exemplifies the advantages of Trp as a site-specific environmentally sensitive fluorescent probe.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shuster</LastName><ForeName>Sydney O</ForeName><Initials>SO</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Protein Conformation and Dynamics, Biochemistry and Biophysics Center, National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute, National Institutes of Health, Bethesda, Maryland 20892, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Jennifer C</ForeName><Initials>JC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0506-8349</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Protein Conformation and Dynamics, Biochemistry and Biophysics Center, National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute, National Institutes of Health, Bethesda, Maryland 20892, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>ZIA HL001055</GrantID><Acronym>ImNIH</Acronym><Agency>Intramural NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052060">Research Support, N.I.H., Intramural</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Phys Chem B</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101157530</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1520-5207</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000682">Amyloid</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D058227">Amyloidogenic Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D004268">DNA-Binding Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C000598624">TARDBP protein, human</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>8DUH1N11BX</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D014364">Tryptophan</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000682" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyloid</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058227" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyloidogenic Proteins</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004268" MajorTopicYN="Y">DNA-Binding Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014364" MajorTopicYN="Y">Tryptophan</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no competing financial interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33835818</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS1687953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8080960</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.jpcb.1c00767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Tandan R; Bradley WG Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis: Part 1. Clinical Features, Pathology, and Ethical Issues in Management. Ann. Neurol. 1985, 18, 271&#x2013;280.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4051456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rabinovici GD; Miller BL Frontotemporal Lobar Degeneration. CNS Drugs 2010, 24 (5), 375&#x2013;398.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2916644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20369906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neumann M; Sampathu DM; Kwong LK; Truax AC; Micsenyi MC; Chou TT; Bruce J; Schuck T; Grossman M; Clark CM; et al. Ubiquitinated TDP-43 in Frontotemporal Lobar Degeneration and Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. Science 2006, 314, 130&#x2013;133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17023659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nelson PT; Dickson DW; Trojanowski JQ; Jack CR; Boyle PA; Arfanakis K; Rademakers R; Alafuzoff I; Attems J; Brayne C; et al. Limbic-predominant Age-related TDP-43 Encephalopathy (LATE): Consensus Working Group Report. Brain 2019, 142, 1503&#x2013;1527.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6536849</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31039256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Afroz T; P&#xe9;rez-Berlanga M; Polymenidou M Structural Transition, Function and Dysfunction of TDP-43 in Neurodegenerative Diseases. Chimia 2019, 73, 380&#x2013;390.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31118120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tollervey JR; Curk T; Rogelj B; Briese M; Cereda M; Kayikci M; K&#xf6;nig J; Hortob&#xe1;gyi T; Nishimura AL; &#x17d;upunski V; et al. Characterizing the RNA Targets and Position-dependent Splicing Regulation by TDP-43. Nat. Neurosci. 2011, 14, 452&#x2013;458.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3108889</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21358640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prasad A; Bharathi V; Sivalingam V; Girdhar A; Patel BK Molecular Mechanisms of TDP-43 Misfolding and Pathology in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. Front. Mol. Neurosci. 2019, 12, 25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6382748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30837838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Francois-Moutal L; Perez-Miller S; Scott DD; Miranda V; Mollasalehi N; Khanna M Structural Insights into TDP-43 Proteinopathy. Front. Mol. Neurosci. 2019, 12, 301.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6934062</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31920533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayala YM; Zago P; D&#x2019;Ambrogio A; Xu Y-F; Petrucelli L; Buratti E; Baralle FE Structural Determinants of the Cellular Localization and Shuttling of TDP-43. J. Cell Sci. 2008, 121, 3778&#x2013;3785.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18957508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchan JR; Parker R Eukaryotic Stress Granules: The Ins and Outs of Translation. Mol. Cell 2009, 36, 932&#x2013;941.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2813218</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20064460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson JL; Geser F; Stieber A; Umoh M; Kwong LK; Van Deerlin VM; Lee VM-Y; Trojanowski JQ TDP-43 Skeins Show Properties of Amyloid in a Subset of ALS Cases. Acta Neuropathol. 2013, 125, 121&#x2013;131.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3536927</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23124365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiti F; Dobson CM Protein Misfolding, Amyloid Formation, and Human Disease: A Summary of Progress over the Last Decade. Annu. Rev. Biochem. 2017, 86, 27&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28498720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iadanza MG; Jackson MP; Hewitt EW; Ranson NA; Radford SE A New Era for Understanding Amyloid Structures and Disease. Nat. Rev. Mol. Cell Biol. 2018, 19, 755&#x2013;773.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30237470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conicella AE; Zerze GH; Mittal J; Fawzi NL ALS Mutations Disrupt Phase Separation Mediated by &#x3b1;-Helical Structure in the TDP-43 Low-complexity C-terminal Domain. Structure 2016, 24, 1537&#x2013;1549.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5014597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27545621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guenther EL; Cao Q; Trinh H; Lu J; Sawaya MR; Cascio D; Boyer DR; Rodriguez JA; Hughes MP; Eisenberg DS Atomic Structures of TDP-43 LCD Segments and Insights into Reversible or Pathogenic Aggregation. Nat. Struct. Mol. Biol. 2018, 25, 463&#x2013;471.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5990464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29786080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li H-R; Chen T-C; Hsiao C-L; Shi L; Chou C-Y; Huang J-R The Physical Forces Mediating Self-association and Phase-separation in the C-terminal Domain of TDP-43. Biochim. Biophys. Acta, Proteins Proteomics 2018, 1866, 214&#x2013;223.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28988034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babinchak WM; Haider R; Dumm BK; Sarkar P; Surewicz K; Choi J-K; Surewicz WK The Role of Liquid-liquid Phase Separation in Aggregation of the TDP-43 Low-complexity Domain. J. Biol. Chem. 2019, 294, 6306&#x2013;6317.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6484124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30814253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhopatkar AA; Uversky VN; Rangachari V Granulins Modulate Liquid-liquid Phase Separation and Aggregation of the Prion-like C-terminal Domain of the Neurodegeneration-associated Protein TDP-43. J. Biol. Chem. 2020, 295, 2506&#x2013;2519.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7039568</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31911437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Capitini C; Fani G; Vivoli Vega M; Penco A; Canale C; Cabrita LD; Calamai M; Christodoulou J; Relini A; Chiti F Full-length TDP-43 and Its C-terminal Domain Form Filaments in Vitro Having Non-amyloid Properties. Amyloid 2021, 28, 56&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33026249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson BS; Snead D; Lee JJ; McCaffery JM; Shorter J; Gitler AD TDP-43 Is Intrinsically Aggregation-prone, and Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis-linked Mutations Accelerate Aggregation and Increase Toxicity. J. Biol. Chem. 2009, 284, 20329&#x2013;20339.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2740458</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19465477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arai T; Hasegawa M; Akiyama H; Ikeda K; Nonaka T; Mori H; Mann D; Tsuchiya K; Yoshida M; Hashizume Y; et al. TDP-43 Is a Component of Ubiquitin-positive Tau-negative Inclusions in Frontotemporal Lobar Degeneration and Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. Biochem. Biophys. Res. Commun. 2006, 351, 602&#x2013;611.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17084815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen AK-H; Lin RY-Y; Hsieh EZ-J; Tu P-H; Chen RP-Y; Liao T-Y; Chen W; Wang C-H; Huang JJ-T Induction of Amyloid Fibrils by the C-Terminal Fragments of TDP-43 in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2010, 132, 1186&#x2013;1187.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20055380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saini A; Chauhan VS Delineation of the Core Aggregation Sequences of TDP-43 C-terminal Fragment. ChemBioChem 2011, 12, 2495&#x2013;2501.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21905193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo W; Chen Y; Zhou X; Kar A; Ray P; Chen X; Rao EJ; Yang M; Ye H; Zhu L; et al. An ALS-associated Mutation Affecting TDP-43 Enhances Protein Aggregation, Fibril Formation and Neurotoxicity. Nat. Struct. Mol. Biol. 2011, 18, 822&#x2013;830.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3357956</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21666678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu GC-H; Chen BP-W; Ye NT-J; Wang C-H; Chen W; Lee H-M; Chan SI; Huang JJ-T Delineating the Membrane-disrupting and Seeding Properties of the TDP-43 Amyloidogenic Core. Chem. Commun. 2013, 49, 11212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24154814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhuo X-F; Wang J; Zhang J; Jiang L-L; Hu H-Y; Lu J-X Solid-state NMR Reveals the Structural Transformation of the TDP-43 Amyloidogenic Region upon Fibrillation. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2020, 142, 3412&#x2013;3421.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32003979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim L; Wei Y; Lu Y; Song J ALS-causing Mutations Significantly Perturb the Self-assembly and Interaction with Nucleic Acid of the Intrinsically Disordered Prion-like Domain of TDP-43. PLoS Biol. 2016, 14, No. e1002338.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4703307</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26735904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shenoy J; El Mammeri N; Dutour A; Berbon M; Saad A; Lends A; Morvan E; Gr&#xe9;lard A; Lecomte S; Kauffmann B; et al. Structural Dissection of Amyloid Aggregates of TDP-43 and Its C-terminal Fragments TDP-35 and TDP-16. FEBS J. 2020, 287, 2449&#x2013;2467.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31782904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang Z; Deng J; Zhao W; Yang J Amyloid-like Aggregation and Fibril Core Determination of TDP-43 C-terminal Domain. Biochem. Biophys. Res. Commun. 2020, 532, 655&#x2013;661.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32907712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Q; Babinchak WM; Surewicz WK Cryo-EM Structure of Amyloid Fibrils Formed by the Entire Low Complexity Domain of TDP-43. Nat. Commun. 2021, 12, 1620.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7955110</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33712624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prasad A; Sivalingam V; Bharathi V; Girdhar A; Patel BK The Amyloidogenicity of a C-terminal Region of TDP-43 Implicated in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Can Be Affected by Anions, Acetylation and Homodimerization. Biochimie 2018, 150, 76&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29751083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghisaidoobe ABT; Chung SJ Intrinsic Tryptophan Fluorescence in the Detection and Analysis of Proteins: A Focus on F&#xf6;rster Resonance Energy Transfer Techniques. Int. J. Mol. Sci. 2014, 15, 22518&#x2013;22538.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4284722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25490136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pfefferkorn CM; McGlinchey RP; Lee JC Effects of pH on Aggregation Kinetics of the Repeat Domain of a Functional Amyloid, Pmel17. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 2010, 107, 21447&#x2013;21452.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3003087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21106765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Messieres M; Huang RK; He Y; Lee JC Amyloid Triangles, Squares, and Loops of Apolipoprotein C-III. Biochemistry 2014, 53, 3261&#x2013;3263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4038341</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24804986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dean DN; Lee JC pH-Dependent Fibril Maturation of a Pmel17 Repeat Domain Isoform Revealed by Tryptophan Fluorescence. Biochim. Biophys. Acta, Proteins Proteomics 2019, 1867, 961&#x2013;969.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6700743</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30716507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Callis PR; Liu T Quantitative Prediction of Fluorescence Quantum Yields for Tryptophan in Proteins. J. Phys. Chem. B 2004, 108, 4248&#x2013;4259.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>LeVine H Quantification of &#x3b2;-Sheet Amyloid Fibril Structures with Thioflavin T. In. Methods Enzymol. 1999, 309, 274&#x2013;284.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10507030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conicella AE; Dignon GL; Zerze GH; Schmidt HB; D&#x2019;Ordine AM; Kim YC; Rohatgi R; Ayala YM; Mittal J; Fawzi NL TDP-43 &#x3b1;-Helical Structure Tunes Liquid-liquid Phase Separation and Function. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 2020, 117, 5883&#x2013;5894.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7084079</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32132204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kapust RB; T&#xf6;zs&#xe9;r J; Fox JD; Anderson DE; Cherry S; Copeland TD; Waugh DS Tobacco Etch Virus Protease: Mechanism of Autolysis and Rational Design of Stable Mutants with Wild-type Catalytic Proficiency. Protein Eng., Des. Sel. 2001, 14, 993&#x2013;1000.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11809930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burstein EA; Vedenkina NS; Ivkova MN Fluorescence and the Location of Tryptophan Residues in Protein Molecules. Photochem. Photobiol. 1973, 18, 263&#x2013;279.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4583619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang Z; Hess SK; Heinrich F; Lee JC Molecular Details of &#x3b1;-Synuclein Membrane Association Revealed by Neutrons and Photons. J. Phys. Chem. B 2015, 119, 4812&#x2013;4823.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4418488</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25790164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flynn JD; McGlinchey RP; Walker RL; Lee JC Structural Features of &#x3b1;-Synuclein Amyloid Fibrils Revealed by Raman Spectroscopy. J. Biol. Chem. 2018, 293, 767&#x2013;776.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5777252</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29191831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schindelin J; Arganda-Carreras I; Frise E; Kaynig V; Longair M; Pietzsch T; Preibisch S; Rueden C; Saalfeld S; Schmid B; et al. FIJI: An Open-source Platform for Biological-image Analysis. Nat. Methods 2012, 9, 676&#x2013;682.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3855844</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22743772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flynn JD; Lee JC Raman Fingerprints of Amyloid Structures. Chem. Commun. 2018, 54, 6983&#x2013;6986.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6013393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29774336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bousset L; Pieri L; Ruiz-Arlandis G; Gath J; Jensen PH; Habenstein B; Madiona K; Olieric V; B&#xf6;ckmann A; Meier BH; et al. Structural and Functional Characterization of Two &#x3b1;-Synuclein Strains. Nat. Commun. 2013, 4, 2575.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3826637</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24108358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biancalana M; Koide S Molecular Mechanism of Thioflavin-T Binding to Amyloid Fibrils. Biochim. Biophys. Acta, Proteins Proteomics 2010, 1804, 1405&#x2013;1412.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2880406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20399286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reshetnyak YK; Burstein EA Decomposition of Protein Tryptophan Fluorescence Spectra into Log-normal components. II. The Statistical Proof of Discreteness of Tryptophan Classes in Proteins. Biophys. J. 2001, 81, 1710&#x2013;1734.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1301648</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11509383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y; Barkley MD Toward Understanding Tryptophan Fluorescence in Proteins. Biochemistry 1998, 37, 9976&#x2013;9982.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9665702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chatani E; Yamamoto N Recent Progress on Understanding the Mechanisms of Amyloid Nucleation. Biophys. Rev. 2018, 10, 527&#x2013;534.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5899713</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29214606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>T&#xf6;rnquist M; Michaels TCT; Sanagavarapu K; Yang X; Meisl G; Cohen SIA; Knowles TPJ; Linse S Secondary Nucleation in Amyloid Formation. Chem. Commun. 2018, 54, 8667&#x2013;8684.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29978862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li H-R; Chiang W-C; Chou P-C; Wang W-J; Huang J-R TAR DNA-binding Protein 43 (TDP-43) Liquid-liquid Phase Separation Is Mediated by Just a Few Aromatic Residues. J. Biol. Chem. 2018, 293, 6090&#x2013;6098.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5912450</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29511089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>