<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">33871173</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1601-183X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>20</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Genes, brain, and behavior</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Genes Brain Behav</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Behavioural effects of cage systems on the G93A Superoxide Dismutase 1 transgenic mouse model for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e12735</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e12735</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/gbb.12735</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Environmental factors inherent to animal facilities can impact on the neuro-behavioural phenotype of laboratory mice and genetic mouse models for human diseases. Many facilities have upgraded from traditional 'open filter top' cages (FT) to individually ventilated cage (IVC) systems, which have been shown to modify various behavioural responses of laboratory mice. Importantly, the impact of IVC housing on the G93A superoxide dismutase 1 mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) is currently unknown. Male and female wild type-like (WT) and heterozygous SOD1<sup>G93A</sup> mice were group-housed in FT or IVC systems from PND 30&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;5 onwards. Body weight and motor function were assessed weekly from 15&#x2009;weeks onward. Mice were also tested for cognitive abilities (i.e., fear conditioning and social recognition memory) and sensorimotor gating (i.e., prepulse inhibition: PPI). SOD1<sup>G93A</sup> mice lost body weight, and their motor function degenerated over time compared with control littermates. Motor impairments developed faster when SOD1<sup>G93A</sup> females were housed in IVCs. Context and cue freezing were increased in SOD1<sup>G93A</sup> females compared with controls, whereas all SOD1<sup>G93A</sup> mice exhibited lower acoustic startle and PPI than WT mice. IVC housing led to an increase in cue freezing in males and reduced the severity of PPI deficits in SOD1<sup>G93A</sup> females. Overall, IVC housing impacted moderately on the SOD1<sup>G93A</sup> phenotype but central behavioural deficits were still evident across housing conditions. Nonetheless, our findings indicate the importance of assessing the effect of cage system in genetic mouse models as these systems can modulate the magnitude and onset of genotypic differences.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 International Behavioural and Neural Genetics Society and John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guerra</LastName><ForeName>Stefan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, Western Sydney University, Campbelltown, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chung</LastName><ForeName>Roger</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for MND Research, Macquarie University, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yerbury</LastName><ForeName>Justin</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Science, Medicine and Health, University of Wollongong, Wollongong, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Karl</LastName><ForeName>Tim</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9904-8482</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, Western Sydney University, Campbelltown, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neuroscience Research Australia, Randwick, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Genes Brain Behav</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101129617</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1601-183X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 1.15.1.1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D013482">Superoxide Dismutase</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001835" MajorTopicYN="N">Body Weight</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003071" MajorTopicYN="N">Cognition</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D046352" MajorTopicYN="N">Freezing Reaction, Cataleptic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D059647" MajorTopicYN="Y">Gene-Environment Interaction</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006799" MajorTopicYN="N">Housing, Animal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000592" MajorTopicYN="Y">standards</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008568" MajorTopicYN="N">Memory</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051379" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008810" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice, Inbred C57BL</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009068" MajorTopicYN="N">Movement</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020125" MajorTopicYN="N">Mutation, Missense</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013216" MajorTopicYN="N">Reflex, Startle</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013482" MajorTopicYN="N">Superoxide Dismutase</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="Y">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SOD1 transgenic mouse model</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">behaviour</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">body weight</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cage system</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">filter top</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">individually ventilated cage</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">motor impairments</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sensorimotor gating</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">superoxide dismutase 1</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>58</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33871173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/gbb.12735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Burrows EL, McOmish CE, Hannan AJ. Gene-environment interactions and construct validity in preclinical models of psychiatric disorders. Prog Neuro-Psychopharm Biol Psychiatry. 2011;35(6):1376-1382.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sorge RE, Martin LJ, Isbester KA, et al. Olfactory exposure to males, including men, causes stress and related analgesia in rodents. Nat Methods. 2014;11(6):629.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gouveia K, Hurst JL. Reducing mouse anxiety during handling: effect of experience with handling tunnels. PLoS One. 2013;8(6):e66401.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gouveia K, Hurst JL. Optimising reliability of mouse performance in behavioural testing: the major role of non-aversive handling. Sci Rep. 2017;7:44999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hurst JL, West RS. Taming anxiety in laboratory mice. Nat Methods. 2010;7(10):825-826.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crabbe JC, Wahlsten D, Dudek BC. Genetics of mouse behavior: interactions with laboratory environment. Science (New York, NY). 1999;284(5420):1670-1672.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paigen B, Svenson KL, Von Smith R, et al. Physiological effects of housing density on C57BL/6J mice over a 9-month period. J Anim Sci. 2012;90(13):5182-5192.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrecchia CE, Jensen K, Van Andel R. Intracage ammonia levels in static and individually ventilated cages housing C57BL/6 mice on 4 bedding substrates. J Am Assoc Lab Anim Sci. 2014;53(2):146-151.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clough G, Wallace J, Gamble M, Merryweather E, Bailey E. A positive, individually ventilated caging system: a local barrier system to protect both animals and personnel. Lab Anim. 1995;29(2):139-151.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon S, Fisher SW, Raymond RH. Elimination of mouse allergens in the working environment: assessment of individually ventilated cage systems and ventilated cabinets in the containment of mouse allergens. J Allergy Clin Immunol. 2001;108(2):288-294.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>David JM, Knowles S, Lamkin DM, Stout DB. Individually ventilated cages impose cold stress on laboratory mice: a source of systemic experimental variability. J Am Assoc Lab Anim Sci. 2013;52(6):738-744.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kostomitsopoulos N, Alexakos P, Eleni K, Doulou A, Paschidis K, Baumans V. The effects of different types of individually ventilated caging systems on growing male mice. Lab Anim. 2012;41(7):192.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mineur YS, Crusio WE. Behavioral effects of ventilated micro-environment housing in three inbred mouse strains. Physiol Behav. 2009;97(3-4):334-340.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>York JM, McDaniel AW, Blevins NA, et al. Individually ventilated cages cause chronic low-grade hypoxia impacting mice hematologically and behaviorally. Brain Behav Immun. 2012;26(6):951-958.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kallnik M, Elvert R, Ehrhardt N, et al. Impact of IVC housing on emotionality and fear learning in male C3HeB/FeJ and C57BL/6J mice. Mamm Genome. 2007;18(3):173-186.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hawkins P, Anderson D, Applebee K, et al. Individually ventilated cages and rodent welfare: report of the 2002 RSPCA/UFAW rodent welfare group meeting. Animal Technol Welfare. 2003;2:23-34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pasquarelli N, Voehringer P, Henke J, Ferger B. Effect of a change in housing conditions on body weight, behavior and brain neurotransmitters in male C57BL/6J mice. Behav Brain Res. 2017;333:35-42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polissidis A, Zelelak S, Nikita M, et al. Assessing the exploratory and anxiety-related behaviors of mice. Do different caging systems affect the outcome of behavioral tests? Physiol Behav. 2017;177:68-73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Logge W, Kingham J, Karl T. Behavioural consequences of IVC cages on male and female C57BL/6J mice. Neuroscience. 2013;237:285-293.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Logge W, Kingham J, Karl T. Do individually ventilated cage systems generate a problem for genetic mouse model research? Genes. Brain and Behavior. 2014;13(7):713-720.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shan L, Schipper P, Nonkes LJ, Homberg JR. Impaired fear extinction as displayed by serotonin transporter knockout rats housed in open cages is disrupted by IVC cage housing. PLoS One. 2014;9(3):e91472.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mueller FS, Polesel M, Richetto J, Meyer U, Weber-Stadlbauer U. Mouse models of maternal immune activation: mind your caging system! Brain Behav Immun. 2018;73:643-660.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wijesekera LC, Leigh PN. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Orphanet J Rare Dis. 2009;4(1):3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parton MJ, Broom W, Andersen PM, et al. D90A-SOD1 mediated amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a single founder for all cases with evidence for a Cis-acting disease modifier in the recessive haplotype. Hum Mutat. 2002;20(6):473-473.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner BJ, Talbot K. Transgenics, toxicity and therapeutics in rodent models of mutant SOD1-mediated familial ALS. Prog Neurobiol. 2008;85(1):94-134.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller T, Cudkowicz M, Shaw PJ, et al. Phase 1-2 trial of antisense oligonucleotide tofersen for SOD1 ALS. New Engl J Med. 2020;383(2):109-119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mueller C, Berry JD, McKenna-Yasek DM, et al. SOD1 suppression with adeno-associated virus and MicroRNA in familial ALS. New Engl J Med. 2020;383(2):151-158.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benatar M. Lost in translation: treatment trials in the SOD1 mouse and in human ALS. Neurobiol Dis. 2007;26(1):1-13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stam NC, Nithianantharajah J, Howard ML, Atkin JD, Cheema SS, Hannan AJ. Sex-specific behavioural effects of environmental enrichment in a transgenic mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Eur J Neurosci. 2008;28(4):717-723.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gurney ME, Pu H, Chiu AY, et al. Motor neuron degeneration in mice that express a human Cu, Zn superoxide dismutase mutation. Science. 1994;264(5166):1772-1772.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kreilaus F, Guerra S, Masanetz R, Menne V, Yerbury J, Karl T. Novel behavioural characteristics of the superoxide dismutase 1 G93A (SOD1G93A) mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis include sex-dependent phenotypes. Genes, Brain and Behavior. 2019;19(2):e12604.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karl T, Burne TH, Van den Buuse M, Chesworth R. Do transmembrane domain neuregulin 1 mutant mice exhibit a reliable sensorimotor gating deficit? Behav Brain Res. 2011;223(2):336-341.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olaya JC, Heusner CL, Matsumoto M, Weickert CS, Karl T. Schizophrenia-relevant behaviours of female mice overexpressing neuregulin 1 type III. Behav Brain Res. 2018;353:227-235.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rothman KJ. No adjustments are needed for multiple comparisons. Epidemiology. 1990;1(1):43-46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perneger TV. What's wrong with Bonferroni adjustments. BMJ. 1998;316(7139):1236-1238.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng D, Low JK, Logge W, Garner B, Karl T. Novel behavioural characteristics of female APPSwe/PS1&#x394;E9 double transgenic mice. Behav Brain Res. 2014;260:111-118.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zieba J, Morris MJ, Weickert CS, Karl T. Behavioural effects of high fat diet in adult Nrg1 type III transgenic mice. Behav Brain Res. 2020;377:112217.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alves CJ, de Santana LP, dos Santos AJD, et al. Early motor and electrophysiological changes in transgenic mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and gender differences on clinical outcome. Brain Res. 2011;1394:90-104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peters TM, Kwon YW, Prattis SM, Gurney&#x21b; ME. Age-dependent penetrance of disease in a transgenic mouse model of familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Mol Cell Neurosci. 1995;6:349-362.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knippenberg S, Thau N, Dengler R, Petri S. Significance of behavioural tests in a transgenic mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). Behav Brain Res. 2010;213(1):82-87.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirkinezos IG, Hernandez D, Bradley WG, Moraes CT. Regular exercise is beneficial to a mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol. 2003;53(6):804-807.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayworth C, Gonzalez-Lima F. Pre-symptomatic detection of chronic motor deficits and genotype prediction in congenic B6. SOD1G93A ALS mouse model. Neuroscience. 2009;164(3):975-985.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pfohl SR, Halicek MT, Mitchell CS. Characterization of the contribution of genetic background and gender to disease progression in the SOD1 G93A mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a meta-analysis. J Neuromuscular Dis. 2015;2(2):137-150.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kandinov B, Korczyn AD, Rabinowitz R, Nefussy B, Drory VE. Autonomic impairment in a transgenic mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Auton Neurosci. 2011;159(1-2):84-89.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dupuis L, Oudart H, Ren&#xe9; F, de Aguilar J-LG, Loeffler J-P. Evidence for defective energy homeostasis in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: benefit of a high-energy diet in a transgenic mouse model. Proc Natl Acad Sci. 2004;101(30):11159-11164.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dupuis L, Loeffler J-P. Neuromuscular junction destruction during amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: insights from transgenic models. Curr Opin Pharmacol. 2009;9(3):341-346.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acevedo-Arozena A, Kalmar B, Essa S, et al. A comprehensive assessment of the SOD1G93A low-copy transgenic mouse, which models human amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Dis Model Mech. 2011;4(5):686-700.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blaszczyk J, Tajchert K. Sex and strain differences of acoustic startle reaction development in adolescent albino Wistar and hooded rats. Acta Neurobiol Exp. 1996;56:919-926.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rohleder C, Jung F, Mertgens H, et al. Neural correlates of sensorimotor gating: a metabolic positron emission tomography study in awake rats. Front Behav Neurosci. 2014;8:178.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jouroukhin Y, Ostritsky R, Assaf Y, Pelled G, Giladi E, Gozes I. NAP (davunetide) modifies disease progression in a mouse model of severe neurodegeneration: protection against impairments in axonal transport. Neurobiol Dis. 2013;56:79-94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Browne SE, Yang L, DiMauro J-P, Fuller SW, Licata SC, Beal MF. Bioenergetic abnormalities in discrete cerebral motor pathways presage spinal cord pathology in the G93A SOD1 mouse model of ALS. Neurobiol Dis. 2006;22(3):599-610.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horvitz JC. Dopamine gating of glutamatergic sensorimotor and incentive motivational input signals to the striatum. Behav Brain Res. 2002;137(1-2):65-74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garay PA, Hsiao EY, Patterson PH, McAllister AK. Maternal immune activation causes age-and region-specific changes in brain cytokines in offspring throughout development. Brain Behav Immun. 2013;31:54-68.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bilkei-Gorz&#xf3; A, Otto M, Zimmer A. Environmental modulation of anxiety-related neuronal activity and behaviors. Behav Brain Res. 2008;186(2):289-292.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J, Zhang D, McQuade JS, Behbehani M, Tsien JZ, Xu M. C-fos regulates neuronal excitability and survival. Nat Genet. 2002;30(4):416-420.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carrion AM, Link WA, Ledo F, Mellstr&#xf6;m B, Naranjo JR. DREAM is a ca 2+&#x2212;regulated transcriptional repressor. Nature. 1999;398(6722):80-84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veldink J, B&#xe4;r P, Joosten E, Otten M, Wokke J, Van den Berg L. Sexual differences in onset of disease and response to exercise in a transgenic model of ALS. Neuromuscul Disord. 2003;13(9):737-743.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heiman-Patterson T, Deitch J, Blankenhorn E, et al. Background and gender effects on survival in the TgN (SOD1-G93A) 1Gur mouse model of ALS. J Neurol Sci. 2005;236(1-2):1-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi C-I, Lee Y-D, Gwag BJ, Cho SI, Kim S-S, Suh-Kim H. Effects of estrogen on lifespan and motor functions in female hSOD1 G93A transgenic mice. J Neurol Sci. 2008;268(1-2):40-47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>VanderHorst VG, Gustafsson J&#xc5;, Ulfhake B. Estrogen receptor-&#x3b1; and-&#x3b2; immunoreactive neurons in the brainstem and spinal cord of male and female mice: relationships to monoaminergic, cholinergic, and spinal projection systems. J Comp Neurol. 2005;488(2):152-179.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sgobio C, Trabalza A, Spalloni A, et al. Abnormal medial prefrontal cortex connectivity and defective fear extinction in the presymptomatic G93A SOD1 mouse model of ALS. Genes Brain Behav. 2008;7(4):427-434.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan S, Lu X, Huang Q, et al. IGFBP2 plays an essential role in cognitive development during early life. Adv Sci. 2019;6(23):1901152.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sim SE, Chung YH, Jeong JH, et al. Immunohistochemical localization of insulin-like growth factor binding protein 2 in the central nervous system of SOD1 G93A transgenic mice. J Mol Histol. 2009;40(2):157-163.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Den Berg WE, Lamballais S, Kushner SA. Sex-specific mechanism of social hierarchy in mice. Neuropsychopharmacology. 2015;40(6):1364-1372.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>