<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">33888768</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>08</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>11</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>22</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Characterization of the upstream and intron promoters of the gene encoding TAR DNA-binding protein.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>8720</StartPage><MedlinePgn>8720</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">8720</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-021-88015-y</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>TAR DNA-binding protein (TDP-43, encoded by TARDBP) is a multifunctional protein that regulates transcription and RNA metabolism by binding DNA or RNA. TDP-43 has been implicated in the pathogenesis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) because abnormal accumulation of cleaved and phosphorylated C-terminal fragments of TDP-43 in motor neurons is a pathological hallmark of ALS. Here, we cloned and analyzed the promoter region of the TARDBP gene. TARDBP upstream sequences and/or intron/luciferase constructs were generated, and their promoter activity was experimentally assessed. The upstream region predictably exhibited promoter activity and identified putative&#xa0;cis-acting elements, including the i-motif, was relevant for the regulation of TDP-43 expression. The cellular abundance of TDP-43 is strictly controlled, and its constancy is critically important for motor neuron survival. A machinery serving to maintain a constant level of TDP-43 is autoregulation via control of mRNA stability, a negative feedback system involving binding to the 3' untranslated region of its own pre-mRNA. However, whether transcriptional mechanisms contribute to TDP-43 autoregulation is unclear. We further showed that TDP-43 negatively regulates the TARDBP promoter and, surprisingly, that disease-causing TDP-43 mutants lacked this regulatory activity. These results allowed the elucidation of a novel transcriptional autoregulatory mechanism of TDP-43.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hasegawa-Ogawa</LastName><ForeName>Minami</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Regenerative Medicine, The Jikei University School of Medicine, 3-25-8 Nishi-Shimbashi, Minato-ku, Tokyo, 1058461, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Okano</LastName><ForeName>Hirotaka James</ForeName><Initials>HJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Regenerative Medicine, The Jikei University School of Medicine, 3-25-8 Nishi-Shimbashi, Minato-ku, Tokyo, 1058461, Japan. hjokano@jikei.ac.jp.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D004268">DNA-Binding Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C000598624">TARDBP protein, human</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001483" MajorTopicYN="N">Base Sequence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004268" MajorTopicYN="N">DNA-Binding Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="Y">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057809" MajorTopicYN="N">HEK293 Cells</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007438" MajorTopicYN="Y">Introns</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009046" MajorTopicYN="N">Motor Neurons</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011401" MajorTopicYN="Y">Promoter Regions, Genetic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33888768</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8062691</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-021-88015-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-021-88015-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Rowland LP, Shneider NA. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. N. Engl. J. Med. 2001;344:1688&#x2013;1700. doi: 10.1056/NEJM200105313442207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJM200105313442207</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11386269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wijesekera LC, Leigh PN. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Orphanet. J. Rare. Dis. 2009;4:3. doi: 10.1186/1750-1172-4-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1750-1172-4-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2656493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19192301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renton AE, Chi&#xf2; A, Traynor BJ. State of play in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis genetics. Nat. Neurosci. 2014;17:17&#x2013;23. doi: 10.1038/nn.3584.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nn.3584</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4544832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24369373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosen DR, Siddique T, Patterson D, Figlewicz DA, Sapp P, Hentati A, Donaldson D, Goto J, O'Regan JP, Deng HX. Mutations in Cu/Zn superoxide dismutase gene are associated with famsilial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nature. 1993;362:59&#x2013;62. doi: 10.1038/362059a0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/362059a0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8446170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sreedharan J, Blair IP, Tripathi VB, Hu X, Vance C, Rogelj B, Ackerley S, Durnall JC, Williams KL, Buratti E, Baralle F, de Belleroche J, Mitchell JD, Leigh PN, Al-Chalabi A, Miller CC, Nicholson G, Shaw CE. TDP-43 mutations in familial and sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Science. 2008;319:1668&#x2013;1672. doi: 10.1126/science.1154584.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.1154584</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7116650</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18309045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kabashi E, Valdmanis PN, Dion P, Spiegelman D, McConkey BJ, Vande Velde C, Bouchard JP, Lacomblez L, Pochigaeva K, Salachas F, Pradat PF, Camu W, Meininger V, Dupre N, Rouleau GA. TARDBP mutations in individuals with sporadic and familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat. Genet. 2008;40:572&#x2013;574. doi: 10.1038/ng.132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ng.132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18372902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gitcho MA, Baloh RH, Chakraverty S, Mayo K, Norton JB, Levitch D, Hatanpaa KJ, White CL, 3rd, Bigio EH, Caselli R, Baker M, Al-Lozi MT, Morris JC, Pestronk A, Rademakers R, Goate AM, Cairns NJ. TDP-43 A315T mutation in familial motor neuron disease. Ann. Neurol. 2008;63:535&#x2013;538. doi: 10.1002/ana.21344.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.21344</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2747362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18288693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yokoseki A, Shiga A, Tan CF, Tagawa A, Kaneko H, Koyama A, Eguchi H, Tsujino A, Ikeuchi T, Kakita A, Okamoto K, Nishizawa M, Takahashi H, Onodera O. TDP-43 mutation in familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann. Neurol. 2008;63:538&#x2013;542. doi: 10.1002/ana.21392.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.21392</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18438952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Deerlin VM, Leverenz JB, Bekris LM, Bird TD, Yuan W, Elman LB, Clay D, Wood EM, Chen-Plotkin AS, Martinez-Lage M, Steinbart E, McCluskey L, Grossman M, Neumann M, Wu IL, Yang WS, Kalb R, Galasko DR, Montine TJ, Trojanowski JQ, Lee VM, Schellenberg GD, Yu CE. TARDBP mutations in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with TDP-43 neuropathology: A genetic and histopathological analysis. Lancet Neurol. 2008;7:409&#x2013;416. doi: 10.1016/S1474-4422(08)70071-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1474-4422(08)70071-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3546119</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18396105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2; A, Calvo A, Mazzini L, Cantello R, Mora G, Moglia C, Corrado L, D'Alfonso S, Majounie E, Renton A, Pisano F, Ossola I, Brunetti M, Traynor BJ, Restagno G, PARALS Extensive genetics of ALS: A population-based study in Italy. Neurology. 2012;79:1983&#x2013;1989. doi: 10.1212/WNL.0b013e3182735d36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0b013e3182735d36</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3484987</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23100398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gendron TF, Josephs KA, Petrucselli L. Review: Transactive response DNA-binding protein 43 (TDP-43): Mechanisms of neurodegeneration. Neuropathol. Appl. Neurobiol. 2010;36:97&#x2013;112. doi: 10.1111/j.1365-2990.2010.01060.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2990.2010.01060.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3052765</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20202122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwiatkowski TJ, Jr, Bosco DA, Leclerc AL, Tamrazian E, Vanderburg CR, Russ C, Davis A, Gilchrist J, Kasarskis EJ, Munsat T, Valdmanis P, Rouleau GA, Hosler BA, Cortelli P, de Jong PJ, Yoshinaga Y, Haines JL, Pericak-Vance MA, Yan J, Ticozzi N, Siddique T, McKenna-Yasek D, Sapp PC, Horvitz HR, Landers JE, Brown RH., Jr Mutations in the FUS/TLS gene on chromosome 16 cause familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Science. 2009;323:1205&#x2013;1208. doi: 10.1126/science.1166066.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.1166066</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19251627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vance C, Rogelj B, Hortob&#xe1;gyi T, De Vos KJ, Nishimura AL, Sreedharan J, Hu X, Smith B, Ruddy D, Wright P, Ganesalingam J, Williams KL, Tripathi V, Al-Saraj S, Al-Chalabi A, Leigh PN, Blair IP, Nicholson G, de Belleroche J, Gallo JM, Miller CC, Shaw CE. Mutations in FUS, an RNA processing protein, cause familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis type 6. Science. 2009;323:1208&#x2013;1211. doi: 10.1126/science.1165942.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.1165942</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4516382</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19251628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maruyama H, Morino H, Ito H, Izumi Y, Kato H, Watanabe Y, Kinoshita Y, Kamada M, Nodera H, Suzuki H, Komure O, Matsuura S, Kobatake K, Morimoto N, Abe K, Suzuki N, Aoki M, Kawata A, Hirai T, Kato T, Ogasawara K, Hirano A, Takumi T, Kusaka H, Hagiwara K, Kaji R, Kawakami H. Mutations of optineurin in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nature. 2010;465:223&#x2013;226. doi: 10.1038/nature08971.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nature08971</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20428114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeJesus-Hernandez M, Mackenzie IR, Boeve BF, Boxer AL, Baker M, Rutherford NJ, Nicholson AM, Finch NA, Flynn H, Adamson J, Kouri N, Wojtas A, Sengdy P, Hsiung GY, Karydas A, Seeley WW, Josephs KA, Coppola G, Geschwind DH, Wszolek ZK, Feldman H, Knopman DS, Petersen RC, Miller BL, Dickson DW, Boylan KB, Graff-Radford NR, Rademakers R. Expanded GGGGCC hexanucleotide repeat in noncoding region of C9ORF72 causes chromosome 9p-linked FTD and ALS. Neuron. 2011;72:245&#x2013;256. doi: 10.1016/j.neuron.2011.09.011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuron.2011.09.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3202986</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21944778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renton AE, Majounie E, Waite A, Sim&#xf3;n-S&#xe1;nchez J, Rollinson S, Gibbs JR, Schymick JC, Laaksovirta H, van Swieten JC, Myllykangas L, Kalimo H, Paetau A, Abramzon Y, Remes AM, Kaganovich A, Scholz SW, Duckworth J, Ding J, Harmer DW, Hernandez DG, Johnson JO, Mok K, Ryten M, Trabzuni D, Guerreiro RJ, Orrell RW, Neal J, Murray A, Pearson J, Jansen IE, Sondervan D, Seelaar H, Blake D, Young K, Halliwell N, Callister JB, Toulson G, Richardson A, Gerhard A, Snowden J, Mann D, Neary D, Nalls MA, Peuralinna T, Jansson L, Isoviita VM, Kaivorinne AL, H&#xf6;ltt&#xe4;-Vuori M, Ikonen E, Sulkava R, Benatar M, Wuu J, Chi&#xf2; A, Restagno G, Borghero G, Sabatelli M, ITALSGEN Consortium. Heckerman D, Rogaeva E, Zinman L, Rothstein JD, Sendtner M, Drepper C, Eichler EE, Alkan C, Abdullaev Z, Pack SD, Dutra A, Pak E, Hardy J, Singleton A, Williams NM, Heutink P, Pickering-Brown S, Morris HR, Tienari PJ, Traynor BJ. A hexanucleotide repeat expansion in C9ORF72 is the cause of chromosome 9p21-linked ALS-FTD. Neuron. 2011;72:257&#x2013;268. doi: 10.1016/j.neuron.2011.09.010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuron.2011.09.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3200438</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21944779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neumann M, Sampathu DM, Kwong LK, Truax AC, Micsenyi MC, Chou TT, Bruce J, Schuck T, Grossman M, Clark CM, McCluskey LF, Miller BL, Masliah E, Mackenzie IR, Feldman H. Ubiquitinated TDP-43 in frontotemporal lobar degeneration and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Science. 2006;314:130&#x2013;133. doi: 10.1126/science.1134108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.1134108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17023659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arai T, Hasegawa M, Akiyama H, Ikeda K, Nonaka T, Mori H, Mann D, Tsuchiya K, Yoshida M, Hashizume Y, Oda T. TDP-43 is a component of ubiquitin-positive tau-negative inclusions in frontotemporal lobar degeneration and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Biochem. Biophys. Res. Commun. 2006;351:602&#x2013;611. doi: 10.1016/j.bbrc.2006.10.093.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbrc.2006.10.093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17084815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winton MJ, Igaz LM, Wong MM, Kwong LK, Trojanowski JQ, Lee VM. Disturbance of nuclear and cytoplasmic TAR DNA binding protein (TDP-43) induces disease-like redistribution, sequestration, and aggregate formation. J. Biol. Chem. 2008;283:13302&#x2013;13309. doi: 10.1074/jbc.M800342200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1074/jbc.M800342200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2442318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18305110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Igaz LM, Kwong LK, Chen-Plotkin A, Winton MJ, Unger TL, Xu Y, Neumann M, Trojanowski JQ, Lee VM. Expression of TDP-43 C-terminal fragments in vitro recapitulates pathological features of TDP-43 proteinopathies. J. Biol. Chem. 2009;284:8516&#x2013;8524. doi: 10.1074/jbc.M809462200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1074/jbc.M809462200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2659210</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19164285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasegawa M, Arai T, Nonaka T, Kametani F, Yoshida M, Hashizume Y, Beach TG, Buratti E, Baralle F, Morita M, Nakano I, Oda T, Tsuchiya K, Akiyama H. Phosphorylated TDP-43 in frontotemporal lobar degeneration and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann. Neurol. 2008;64:60&#x2013;70. doi: 10.1002/ana.21425.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.21425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2674108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18546284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neumann M, Kwong LK, Lee EB, Kremmer E, Flatley A, Xu Y, Forman MS, Troost D, Kretzschmar HA, Trojanowski JQ, Lee VM. Phosphorylation of S409/410 of TDP-43 is a consistent feature in all sporadic and familial forms of TDP-43 proteinopathies. Acta Neuropathol. 2009;117:137&#x2013;149. doi: 10.1007/s00401-008-0477-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00401-008-0477-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2693625</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19125255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee EB, Lee VM, Trojanowski JQ. Gains or losses: Molecular mechanisms of TDP43-mediated neurodegeneration. Nat. Rev. Neurosci. 2011;13:38&#x2013;50. doi: 10.1038/nrn3121.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrn3121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3285250</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22127299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ling SC, Polymenidou M, Cleveland DW. Converging mechanisms in ALS and FTD: Disrupted RNA and protein homeostasis. Neuron. 2013;79:416&#x2013;438. doi: 10.1016/j.neuron.2013.07.033.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuron.2013.07.033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4411085</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23931993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ou SH, Wu F, Harrich D, Garc&#xed;a-Mart&#xed;nez LF, Gaynor RB. Cloning and characterization of a novel cellular protein, TDP-43, that binds to human immunodeficiency virus type 1 TAR DNA sequence motifs. J. Virol. 1995;69:3584&#x2013;3596. doi: 10.1128/JVI.69.6.3584-3596.1995.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JVI.69.6.3584-3596.1995</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC189073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7745706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buratti E, Baralle FE. Characterization and functional implications of the RNA binding properties of nuclear factor TDP-43, a novel splicing regulator of CFTR exon 9. J. Biol. Chem. 2001;276:36337&#x2013;36343. doi: 10.1074/jbc.M104236200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1074/jbc.M104236200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11470789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tollervey JR, Curk T, Rogelj B, Briese M, Cereda M, Kayikci M, K&#xf6;nig J, Hortob&#xe1;gyi T, Nishimura AL, Zupunski V, Patani R, Chandran S, Rot G, Zupan B, Shaw CE, Ule J. Characterizing the RNA targets and position-dependent splicing regulation by TDP-43. Nat. Neurosci. 2011;14:452&#x2013;458. doi: 10.1038/nn.2778.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nn.2778</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3108889</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21358640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polymenidou M, Lagier-Tourenne C, Hutt KR, Huelga SC, Moran J, Liang TY, Ling SC, Sun E, Wancewicz E, Mazur C, Kordasiewicz H, Sedaghat Y, Donohue JP, Shiue L, Bennett CF, Yeo GW, Cleveland DW. Long pre-mRNA depletion and RNA missplicing contribute to neuronal vulnerability from loss of TDP-43. Nat. Neurosci. 2011;14:459&#x2013;468. doi: 10.1038/nn.2779.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nn.2779</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3094729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21358643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer BC, Schuck T, Wheeler JM, Robinson LC, Trojanowski JQ, Lee VM, Schellenberg GD. Loss of murine TDP-43 disrupts motor function and plays an essential role in embryogenesis. Acta Neuropathol. 2010;119:409&#x2013;419. doi: 10.1007/s00401-010-0659-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00401-010-0659-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2880609</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20198480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu LS, Cheng WC, Shen CK. Targeted depletion of TDP-43 expression in the spinal cord motor neurons leads to the development of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-like phenotypes in mice. J. Biol. Chem. 2012;287:27335&#x2013;27344. doi: 10.1074/jbc.M112.359000.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1074/jbc.M112.359000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3431639</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22718760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnold ES, Ling SC, Huelga SC, Lagier-Tourenne C, Polymenidou M, Ditsworth D, Kordasiewicz HB, McAlonis-Downes M, Platoshyn O, Parone PA, Da Cruz S, Clutario KM, Swing D, Tessarollo L, Marsala M, Shaw CE, Yeo GW, Cleveland DW. ALS-linked TDP-43 mutations produce aberrant RNA splicing and adult-onset motor neuron disease without aggregation or loss of nuclear TDP-43. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA. 2013;110:E736&#x2013;745. doi: 10.1073/pnas.1222809110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.1222809110</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3581922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23382207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wils H, Kleinberger G, Janssens J, Pereson S, Joris G, Cuijt I, Smits V, Ceuterick-de Groote C, Van Broeckhoven C, Kumar-Singh S. TDP-43 transgenic mice develop spastic paralysis and neuronal inclusions characteristic of ALS and frontotemporal lobar degeneration. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA. 2010;107:3858&#x2013;3863. doi: 10.1073/pnas.0912417107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.0912417107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2840518</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20133711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li W, Lee MH, Henderson L, Tyagi R, Bachani M, Steiner J, Campanac E, Hoffman DA, von Geldern G, Johnson K, Maric D, Morris HD, Lentz M, Pak K, Mammen A, Ostrow L, Rothstein J, Nath A. Human endogenous retrovirus-K contributes to motor neuron disease. Sci. Transl. Med. 2015;7:307ra153. doi: 10.1126/scitranslmed.aac8201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/scitranslmed.aac8201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6344353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26424568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayala YM, De Conti L, Avenda&#xf1;o-V&#xe1;zquez SE, Dhir A, Romano M, D'Ambrogio A, Tollervey J, Ule J, Baralle M, Buratti E, Baralle FE. TDP-43 regulates its mRNA levels through a negative feedback loop. EMBO J. 2011;30:277&#x2013;288. doi: 10.1038/emboj.2010.310.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/emboj.2010.310</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3025456</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21131904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avenda&#xf1;o-V&#xe1;zquez SE, Dhir A, Bembich S, Buratti E, Proudfoot N, Baralle FE. Autoregulation of TDP-43 mRNA levels involves interplay between transcription, splicing, and alternative polyA site selection. Genes. Dev. 2012;26:1679&#x2013;1684. doi: 10.1101/gad.194829.112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/gad.194829.112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3418585</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22855830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luquin N, Yu B, Saunderson RB, Trent RJ, Pamphlett R. Genetic variants in the promoter of TARDBP in sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuromuscul. Disord. 2009;10:696&#x2013;700. doi: 10.1016/j.nmd.2009.07.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nmd.2009.07.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19695877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D'Ambrogio A, Buratti E, Stuani C, Guarnaccia C, Romano M, Ayala YM, Baralle FE. Functional mapping of the interaction between TDP-43 and hnRNP A2 in vivo. Nucleic Acids Res. 2009;37:4116&#x2013;4126. doi: 10.1093/nar/gkp342.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/nar/gkp342</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2709582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19429692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gehring K, Leroy JL, Gu&#xe9;ron M. A tetrameric DNA structure with protonated cytosine cytosine base pairs. Nature. 1993;363:561&#x2013;565. doi: 10.1038/363561a0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/363561a0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8389423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lacroix L, Mergny JL, Leroy JL, H&#xe9;l&#xe8;ne C. Inability of RNA to form the i-motif: Implications for triplex formation. Biochemistry. 1996;35:8715&#x2013;8722. doi: 10.1021/bi960107s.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/bi960107s</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8679634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sedghi Masoud S, Nagasawa K. i-Motif-binding ligands and their effects on the structure and biological functions of i-motif. Chem. Pharm. Bull. 2018;66:1091&#x2013;1103. doi: 10.1248/cpb.c18-00720.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1248/cpb.c18-00720</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30504626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai J, Hatzakis E, Hurley LH, Yang D. i-motif structures formed in the human c-MYC promoter are highly dynamic&#x2013;insights into sequence redundancy and I-motif stability. PLoS&#xa0;One. 2010;5:e11647. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0011647.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0011647</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2906509</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20657837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun D, Hurley LH. The importance of negative superhelicity in inducing the formation of G-quadruplex and i-motif structures in the c-Myc promoter: Implications for drug targeting and control of gene expression. J. Med. Chem. 2009;52:2863&#x2013;2874. doi: 10.1021/jm900055s.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jm900055s</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2757002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19385599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takimoto M, Tomonaga T, Matunis M, Avigan M, Krutzsch H, Dreyfuss G, Levens D. Specific binding of heterogeneous ribonucleoprotein particle protein K to the human c-myc promoter, in vitro. J. Biol. Chem. 1993;268:18249&#x2013;18258. doi: 10.1016/S0021-9258(17)46837-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0021-9258(17)46837-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8349701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaiser CE, Van Ert NA, Agrawal P, Chawla R, Yang D, Hurley LH. Insight into the complexity of the i-motif and G-quadruplex DNA structures formed in the KRAS promoter and subsequent drug-induced gene repression. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2017;139:8522&#x2013;8536. doi: 10.1021/jacs.7b02046.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jacs.7b02046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5978000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28570076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bomsztyk K, Denisenko O, Ostrowski J. hnRNP K: One protein multiple processes. BioEssays. 2004;26:629&#x2013;638. doi: 10.1002/bies.20048.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/bies.20048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15170860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ritchie SA, Pasha MK, Batten DJ, Sharma RK, Olson DJ, Ross AR, Bonham K. Identification of the SRC pyrimidine-binding protein (SPy) as hnRNP K:implications in the regulation of SRC1A transcription. Nucleic. Acids. Res. 2003;31:1502&#x2013;1513. doi: 10.1093/nar/gkg246.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/nar/gkg246</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC149839</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12595559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moujalled D, Grubman A, Acevedo K, Yang S, Ke YD, Moujalled DM, Duncan C, Caragounis A, Perera ND, Turner BJ, Prudencio M, Petrucelli L, Blair I, Ittner LM, Crouch PJ, Liddell JR, White AR. TDP-43 mutations causing amyotrophic lateral sclerosis are associated with altered expression of RNA-binding protein hnRNP K and affect the Nrf2 antioxidant pathway. Hum. Mol. Genet. 2017;26:1732&#x2013;1746. doi: 10.1093/hmg/ddx093.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/hmg/ddx093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28334913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moujalled D, James JL, Yang S, Zhang K, Duncan C, Moujalled DM, Parker SJ, Caragounis A, Lidgerwood G, Turner BJ, Atkin JD, Grubman A, Liddell JR, Proepper C, Boeckers TM, Kanninen KM, Blair I, Crouch PJ, White AR. Phosphorylation of hnRNP K by cyclin-dependent kinase 2 controls cytosolic accumulation of TDP-43. Hum. Mol. Genet. 2015;24:1655&#x2013;1669. doi: 10.1093/hmg/ddu578.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/hmg/ddu578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25410660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suzuki A, Kawano S, Mitsuyama T, Suyama M, Kanai Y, Shirahige K, Sasaki H, Tokunaga K, Tsuchihara K, Sugano S, Nakai K, Suzuki Y. DBTSS/DBKERO for integrated analysis of transcriptional regulation. Nucleic Acids Res. 2018;46:D229&#x2013;238. doi: 10.1093/nar/gkx1001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/nar/gkx1001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5753362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29126224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du W, Thanos D, Maniatis T. Mechanism of transcriptional synergism between distinct virus-inducible enhancer elements. Cell. 1993;74:887&#x2013;898. doi: 10.1016/0092-8674(93)90468-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0092-8674(93)90468-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8374955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haeusler AR, Donnelly CJ, Periz G, Simko EA, Shaw PG, Kim MS, Maragakis NJ, Troncoso JC, Pandey A, Sattler R, Rothstein JD, Wang J. C9orf72 nucleotide repeat structures initiate molecular cascades of disease. Nature. 2014;507:195&#x2013;200. doi: 10.1038/nature13124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nature13124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4046618</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24598541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooper-Knock J, Higginbottom A, Stopford MJ, Highley JR, Ince PG, Wharton SB, Pickering-Brown S, Kirby J, Hautbergue GM, Shaw PJ. Antisense RNA foci in the motor neurons of C9ORF72-ALS patients are associated with TDP-43 proteinopathy. Acta Neuropathol. 2015;130:63&#x2013;75. doi: 10.1007/s00401-015-1429-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00401-015-1429-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4468790</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25943887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zamiri B, Mirceta M, Abu-Ghazalah R, Wold MS, Pearson CE, Macgregor RB., Jr Stress-induced acidification may contribute to formation of unusual structures in C9orf72-repeats. Biochim. Biophys. Acta Gen. Subj. 2018;1862:1482&#x2013;1491. doi: 10.1016/j.bbagen.2018.03.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbagen.2018.03.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29550431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pesiridis GS, Lee VM, Trojanowski JQ. Mutations in TDP-43 link glycine-rich domain functions to amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Hum. Mol. Genet. 2009;18:R156&#x2013;162. doi: 10.1093/hmg/ddp303.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/hmg/ddp303</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2758707</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19808791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watanabe S, Kaneko K, Yamanaka K. Accelerated disease onset with stabilized familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS)-linked mutant TDP-43 proteins. J. Biol. Chem. 2013;288:3641&#x2013;3654. doi: 10.1074/jbc.M112.433615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1074/jbc.M112.433615</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3561582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23235148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ichiyanagi N, Fujimori K, Yano M, Ishihara-Fujisaki C, Sone T, Akiyama T, Okada Y, Akamatsu W, Matsumoto T, Ishikawa M, Nishimoto Y, Ishihara Y, Sakuma T, Yamamoto T, Tsuiji H, Suzuki N, Warita H, Aoki M, Okano H. Establishment of in vitro FUS-associated familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis model using human induced pluripotent stem cells. Stem Cell Rep. 2016;6:496&#x2013;510. doi: 10.1016/j.stemcr.2016.02.011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.stemcr.2016.02.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4834049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26997647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schindelin J, Arganda-Carreras I, Frise E, Kaynig V, Longair M, Pietzsch T, Preibisch S, Rueden C, Saalfeld S, Schmid B, Tinevez JY, White DJ, Hartenstein V, Eliceiri K, Tomancak P, Cardona A. Fiji: An open-source platform for biological-image analysis. Nat. Methods. 2012;9:676&#x2013;682. doi: 10.1038/nmeth.2019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nmeth.2019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3855844</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22743772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>