<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">33914140</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>13</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1432-1459</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>268</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Daytime sleepiness might increase the risk of ALS: a 2-sample Mendelian randomization study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>4332</StartPage><EndPage>4339</EndPage><MedlinePgn>4332-4339</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s00415-021-10564-z</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Observational studies have indicated that there is a high prevalence of habitual sleep disturbances in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). However, the actual relationship between these symptoms and ALS remains unclear.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We used 2-sample Mendelian randomization to determine whether the sleep disturbances associated with ALS are also related to the risk of ALS. The summary statistics we used were from recent, large genome-wide association studies on daytime sleepiness and other night sleep traits (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;85,670-452,071) and ALS (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;20,806 cases, n&#x2009;=&#x2009;59,804 controls). The inverse variance-weighted (IVW) method was used as the main method for assessing causality.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Daytime sleepiness might increase the risk of ALS (IVW odds ratio&#x2009;=&#x2009;2.45, 95% confidence interval: 1.15-5.21; P&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.020). ALS was not associated with sleep efficiency, number of sleep episodes or sleep duration.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Our results provide novel evidence that daytime sleepiness increases the risk of ALS and points out the importance of daytime sleepiness that often goes unnoticed in ALS.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021. Springer-Verlag GmbH Germany, part of Springer Nature.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Gan</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Peking University Third Hospital, 49 North Garden Road, Haidian District, Beijing, 100191, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Beijing Municipal Key Laboratory of Biomarker and Translational Research in Neurodegenerative Diseases, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Linjing</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Peking University Third Hospital, 49 North Garden Road, Haidian District, Beijing, 100191, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Beijing Municipal Key Laboratory of Biomarker and Translational Research in Neurodegenerative Diseases, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xia</LastName><ForeName>Kailin</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Peking University Third Hospital, 49 North Garden Road, Haidian District, Beijing, 100191, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Beijing Municipal Key Laboratory of Biomarker and Translational Research in Neurodegenerative Diseases, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhuang</LastName><ForeName>Zhenhuang</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics, School of Public Health, Peking University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Molecular Cardiovascular Sciences (Peking University), Ministry of Education, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Tao</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics, School of Public Health, Peking University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Molecular Cardiovascular Sciences (Peking University), Ministry of Education, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Fan</LastName><ForeName>Dongsheng</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3129-9821</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Peking University Third Hospital, 49 North Garden Road, Haidian District, Beijing, 100191, China. dsfan2010@aliyun.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Beijing Municipal Key Laboratory of Biomarker and Translational Research in Neurodegenerative Diseases, Beijing, China. dsfan2010@aliyun.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>81030019</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>81873784</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>J Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0423161</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0340-5354</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006970" MajorTopicYN="Y">Disorders of Excessive Somnolence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055106" MajorTopicYN="N">Genome-Wide Association Study</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057182" MajorTopicYN="N">Mendelian Randomization Analysis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012890" MajorTopicYN="N">Sleep</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Daytime sleepiness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mendelian randomization</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sleep disturbances</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33914140</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00415-021-10564-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s00415-021-10564-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Turner MR, Hardiman O, Benatar M, Brooks BR, Chio A, de Carvalho M, Ince PG, Lin C, Miller RG, Mitsumoto H, Nicholson G, Ravits J, Shaw PJ, Swash M, Talbot K, Traynor BJ, Van den Berg LH, Veldink JH, Vucic S, Kiernan MC (2013) Controversies and priorities in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet Neurol 12:310&#x2013;322</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1474-4422(13)70036-X</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Chalabi A, Hardiman O (2013) The epidemiology of ALS: a conspiracy of genes, environment and time. Nat Rev Neurol 9:617&#x2013;628</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrneurol.2013.203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsiao YH, Chen YT, Tseng CM, Wu LA, Perng DW, Chen YM, Chen TJ, Chang SC, Chou KT (2017) Sleep disorders and an increased risk of Parkinson&#x2019;s disease in individuals with non-apnea sleep disorders: a population-based cohort study. J Sleep Res 26:623&#x2013;628</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jsr.12545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi L, Chen SJ, Ma MY, Bao YP, Han Y, Wang YM, Shi J, Vitiello MV, Lu L (2018) Sleep disturbances increase the risk of dementia: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sleep Med Rev 40:4&#x2013;16</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.smrv.2017.06.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foley D, Monjan A, Masaki K, Ross W, Havlik R, White L, Launer L (2001) Daytime sleepiness is associated with 3-year incident dementia and cognitive decline in older Japanese-American men. J Am Geriatr Soc 49:1628&#x2013;1632</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1532-5415.2001.49271.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elwood PC, Bayer AJ, Fish M, Pickering J, Mitchell C, Gallacher JE (2011) Sleep disturbance and daytime sleepiness predict vascular dementia. J Epidemiol Community Health 65:820&#x2013;824</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jech.2009.100503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsapanou A, Gu Y, Manly J, Schupf N, Tang MX, Zimmerman M, Scarmeas N, Stern Y (2015) Daytime sleepiness and sleep inadequacy as risk factors for dementia. Dement Geriatr Cogn Disord Extra 5:286&#x2013;295</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000431311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abbott RD, Ross GW, White LR, Tanner CM, Masaki KH, Nelson JS, Curb JD, Petrovitch H (2005) Excessive daytime sleepiness and subsequent development of Parkinson disease. Neurology 65:1442&#x2013;1446</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/01.wnl.0000183056.89590.0d</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lo Coco D, Mattaliano P, Spataro R, Mattaliano A, La Bella V (2011) Sleep-wake disturbances in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 82:839&#x2013;842</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp.2010.228007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gunther R, Richter N, Sauerbier A, Chaudhuri KR, Martinez-Martin P, Storch A, Hermann A (2016) Non-motor symptoms in patients suffering from motor neuron diseases. Front Neurol 7:117</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fneur.2016.00117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu S, Huang Y, Tai H, Zhang K, Wang Z, Shen D, Fu H, Su N, Shi J, Ding Q, Liu M, Guan Y, Gao J, Cui L (2018) Excessive daytime sleepiness in Chinese patients with sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and its association with cognitive and behavioural impairments. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 89:1038&#x2013;1043</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp-2018-318810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boentert M (2019) Sleep disturbances in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: current perspectives. Nat Sci Sleep 11:97&#x2013;111</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/NSS.S183504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawlor DA, Harbord RM, Sterne JA, Timpson N, Davey Smith G (2008) Mendelian randomization: using genes as instruments for making causal inferences in epidemiology. Stat Med 27:1133&#x2013;1163</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/sim.3034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amin N, Allebrandt KV, van der Spek A, Muller-Myhsok B, Hek K, Teder-Laving M, Hayward C, Esko T, van Mill JG, Mbarek H, Watson NF, Melville SA, Del Greco FM, Byrne EM, Oole E, Kolcic I, Chen TH, Evans DS, Coresh J, Vogelzangs N, Karjalainen J, Willemsen G, Gharib SA, Zgaga L, Mihailov E, Stone KL, Campbell H, Brouwer RW, Demirkan A, Isaacs A, Dogas Z, Marciante KD, Campbell S, Borovecki F, Luik AI, Li M, Hottenga JJ, Huffman JE, van den Hout MC, Cummings SR, Aulchenko YS, Gehrman PR, Uitterlinden AG, Wichmann HE, Muller-Nurasyid M, Fehrmann RS, Montgomery GW, Hofman A, Kao WH, Oostra BA, Wright AF, Vink JM, Wilson JF, Pramstaller PP, Hicks AA, Polasek O, Punjabi NM, Redline S, Psaty BM, Heath AC, Merrow M, Tranah GJ, Gottlieb DJ, Boomsma DI, Martin NG, Rudan I, Tiemeier H, van IWF, Penninx BW, Metspalu A, Meitinger T, Franke L, Roenneberg T, van Duijn CM (2016) Genetic variants in RBFOX3 are associated with sleep latency. Eur J Human Genet EJHG 24:1488&#x2013;1495</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ejhg.2016.31</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones SE, van Hees VT, Mazzotti DR, Marques-Vidal P, Sabia S, van der Spek A, Dashti HS, Engmann J, Kocevska D, Tyrrell J, Beaumont RN, Hillsdon M, Ruth KS, Tuke MA, Yaghootkar H, Sharp SA, Ji Y, Harrison JW, Freathy RM, Murray A, Luik AI, Amin N, Lane JM, Saxena R, Rutter MK, Tiemeier H, Kutalik Z, Kumari M, Frayling TM, Weedon MN, Gehrman PR, Wood AR (2019) Genetic studies of accelerometer-based sleep measures yield new insights into human sleep behaviour. Nat Commun 10:1585</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-019-09576-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dashti HS, Jones SE, Wood AR, Lane JM, van Hees VT, Wang H, Rhodes JA, Song Y, Patel K, Anderson SG, Beaumont RN, Bechtold DA, Bowden J, Cade BE, Garaulet M, Kyle SD, Little MA, Loudon AS, Luik AI, Scheer F, Spiegelhalder K, Tyrrell J, Gottlieb DJ, Tiemeier H, Ray DW, Purcell SM, Frayling TM, Redline S, Lawlor DA, Rutter MK, Weedon MN, Saxena R (2019) Genome-wide association study identifies genetic loci for self-reported habitual sleep duration supported by accelerometer-derived estimates. Nat Commun 10:1100</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-019-08917-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H, Lane JM, Jones SE, Dashti HS, Ollila HM, Wood AR, van Hees VT, Brumpton B, Winsvold BS, Kantojarvi K, Palviainen T, Cade BE, Sofer T, Song Y, Patel K, Anderson SG, Bechtold DA, Bowden J, Emsley R, Kyle SD, Little MA, Loudon AS, Scheer F, Purcell SM, Richmond RC, Spiegelhalder K, Tyrrell J, Zhu X, Hublin C, Kaprio JA, Kristiansson K, Sulkava S, Paunio T, Hveem K, Nielsen JB, Willer CJ, Zwart JA, Strand LB, Frayling TM, Ray D, Lawlor DA, Rutter MK, Weedon MN, Redline S, Saxena R (2019) Genome-wide association analysis of self-reported daytime sleepiness identifies 42 loci that suggest biological subtypes. Nat Commun 10:3503</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-019-11456-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicolas A, Kenna KP, Renton AE (2018) Genome-wide analyses identify KIF5A as a novel ALS gene. Neuron 97:1268-1283.e1266</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuron.2018.02.027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR (1994) El Escorial world federation of neurology criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Subcommittee on motor neuron diseases/amyotrophic lateral sclerosis of the world federation of neurology research group on neuromuscular diseases and the El Escorial "Clinical limits of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis" workshop contributors. J Neurol sci 124(Suppl):96&#x2013;107</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pierce BL, Burgess S (2013) Efficient design for Mendelian randomization studies: subsample and 2-sample instrumental variable estimators. Am J Epidemiol 178:1177&#x2013;1184</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/aje/kwt084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burgess S, Bowden J, Fall T, Ingelsson E, Thompson SG (2017) Sensitivity analyses for robust causal inference from mendelian randomization analyses with multiple genetic variants. Epidemiology (Cambridge, Mass) 28:30&#x2013;42</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/EDE.0000000000000559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burgess S, Thompson SG (2017) Interpreting findings from Mendelian randomization using the MR-Egger method. Eur J Epidemiol 32:377&#x2013;389</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10654-017-0255-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowden J, Davey Smith G, Haycock PC, Burgess S (2016) Consistent estimation in Mendelian randomization with some invalid instruments using a weighted median estimator. Genet Epidemiol 40:304&#x2013;314</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/gepi.21965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verbanck M, Chen CY, Neale B, Do R (2018) Detection of widespread horizontal pleiotropy in causal relationships inferred from Mendelian randomization between complex traits and diseases. Nat Genet 50:693&#x2013;698</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41588-018-0099-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie L, Kang H, Xu Q, Chen MJ, Liao Y, Thiyagarajan M, O'Donnell J, Christensen DJ, Nicholson C, Iliff JJ, Takano T, Deane R, Nedergaard M (2013) Sleep drives metabolite clearance from the adult brain. Science 342:373&#x2013;377</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.1241224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winer JR, Mander BA, Kumar S, Reed M, Baker SL, Jagust WJ, Walker MP (2020) Sleep disturbance forecasts &#x3b2;-amyloid accumulation across subsequent years. Curr Biol CB 30:4291&#x2013;4298.e4293</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cub.2020.08.017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorges M, Vercruysse P, Muller HP, Huppertz HJ, Rosenbohm A, Nagel G, Weydt P, Petersen A, Ludolph AC, Kassubek J, Dupuis L (2017) Hypothalamic atrophy is related to body mass index and age at onset in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 88:1033&#x2013;1041</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp-2017-315795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finegan E, Li Hi Shing S, Chipika RH, Doherty MA, Hengeveld JC, Vajda A, Donaghy C, Pender N, McLaughlin RL, Hardiman O, Bede P (2019) Widespread subcortical grey matter degeneration in primary lateral sclerosis: a multimodal imaging study with genetic profiling. NeuroImage Clin 24:102089</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nicl.2019.102089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westeneng HJ, Walhout R, Straathof M, Schmidt R, Hendrikse J, Veldink JH, van den Heuvel MP, van den Berg LH (2016) Widespread structural brain involvement in ALS is not limited to the C9orf72 repeat expansion. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 87:1354&#x2013;1360</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp-2016-313959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Machts J, Loewe K, Kaufmann J, Jakubiczka S, Abdulla S, Petri S, Dengler R, Heinze HJ, Vielhaber S, Schoenfeld MA, Bede P (2015) Basal ganglia pathology in ALS is associated with neuropsychological deficits. Neurology 85:1301&#x2013;1309</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000002017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu R, Sheng ZF, Cai B, Zhang YH, Fan DS (2015) Increased orexin expression promotes sleep/wake disturbances in the SOD1-G93A mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Chin Med J (Engl) 128:239&#x2013;244</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/0366-6999.149214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoo SW, Oh YS, Ryu DW, Lee KS, Lyoo CH, Kim JS (2020) Low thalamic monoamine transporter availability is related to excessive daytime sleepiness in early Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Neurol Sci 41:1081&#x2013;1087</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10072-019-04206-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pagano G, Molloy S, Bain PG, Rabiner EA, Chaudhuri KR, Brooks DJ, Pavese N (2016) Sleep problems and hypothalamic dopamine D3 receptor availability in Parkinson disease. Neurology 87:2451&#x2013;2456</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000003396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith GD, Ebrahim S (2004) Mendelian randomization: prospects, potentials, and limitations. Int J Epidemiol 33:30&#x2013;42</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ije/dyh132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>