<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">33983668</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>04</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1099-1166</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>36</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of geriatric psychiatry</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Geriatr Psychiatry</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Validation of The Edinburgh cognitive and behavioural ALS screen (ECAS) in behavioural variant frontotemporal dementia and Alzheimer's disease.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1576</StartPage><EndPage>1587</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1576-1587</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/gps.5566</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="UNLABELLED">The Edinburgh Cognitive and Behavioural ALS Screen (ECAS) was developed to assess cognitive and behavioural changes in an anterior frontotemporal syndrome (executive functions, language, fluency and behaviour), common in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis (ALS) and also assesses posterior cerebral dysfunction (memory and visuospatial abilities).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES">To validate the ECAS in behavioural variant Frontotemporal Dementia (bvFTD) without ALS, as compared with Alzheimer's disease (AD), against comprehensive neuropsychological assessment. Compare its sensitivity to that of the Addenbrooke's Cognitive Examination (ACE-III) and investigate behavioural changes in both types of dementia.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Retrospective study of 16 people with bvFTD (without ALS), 32 with AD, and 48 healthy controls completed the ECAS, ACE-III and extensive neuropsychological assessment.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">The ECAS showed higher sensitivity (94%) and marginally lower specificity (96%) than the ACE-III for both the bvFTD and AD groups. The anterior composite subscore was sensitive for bvFTD (94%), and slightly less so for AD (84%), while the posterior composite subscore was sensitive for AD (97%), and less so for bvFTD (75%). All people with bvFTD that were impaired on the ECAS total and anterior composite scores were also impaired on the anterior function's tests of the neuropsychological assessment. A cut-off of four or more behavioural domains affected differentiated well between the bvFTD and AD groups, while a qualitative analysis of the behavioural interview found different themes between groups.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">The ECAS is a valid and sensitive assessment for bvFTD without ALS and for AD. The carer behavioural interview makes it particularly suitable to detect behavioural abnormalities related to frontal lobe disorders.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 The Authors. International Journal of Geriatric Psychiatry published John Wiley&#xa0;&amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>De Icaza Valenzuela</LastName><ForeName>M&#xf3;nica M</ForeName><Initials>MM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9782-625X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Human Cognitive Neuroscience -Psychology, School of Philosophy, Psychology and Language Sciences, University of Edinburgh, Edinburgh, Midlothian, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Anne Rowling Regenerative Neurology Clinic, University of Edinburgh, Edinburgh, Midlothian, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Euan MacDonald Centre for Motor Neurone Disease Research, University of Edinburgh, Edinburgh, Midlothian, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bak</LastName><ForeName>Thomas H</ForeName><Initials>TH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Human Cognitive Neuroscience -Psychology, School of Philosophy, Psychology and Language Sciences, University of Edinburgh, Edinburgh, Midlothian, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Anne Rowling Regenerative Neurology Clinic, University of Edinburgh, Edinburgh, Midlothian, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Euan MacDonald Centre for Motor Neurone Disease Research, University of Edinburgh, Edinburgh, Midlothian, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Thompson</LastName><ForeName>Harriet E</ForeName><Initials>HE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Human Cognitive Neuroscience -Psychology, School of Philosophy, Psychology and Language Sciences, University of Edinburgh, Edinburgh, Midlothian, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Colville</LastName><ForeName>Shuna</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Anne Rowling Regenerative Neurology Clinic, University of Edinburgh, Edinburgh, Midlothian, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Euan MacDonald Centre for Motor Neurone Disease Research, University of Edinburgh, Edinburgh, Midlothian, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Clinical Brain Sciences, University of Edinburgh, Edinburgh, Midlothian, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pal</LastName><ForeName>Suvankar</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Anne Rowling Regenerative Neurology Clinic, University of Edinburgh, Edinburgh, Midlothian, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Euan MacDonald Centre for Motor Neurone Disease Research, University of Edinburgh, Edinburgh, Midlothian, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Clinical Brain Sciences, University of Edinburgh, Edinburgh, Midlothian, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abrahams</LastName><ForeName>Sharon</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Human Cognitive Neuroscience -Psychology, School of Philosophy, Psychology and Language Sciences, University of Edinburgh, Edinburgh, Midlothian, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Anne Rowling Regenerative Neurology Clinic, University of Edinburgh, Edinburgh, Midlothian, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Euan MacDonald Centre for Motor Neurone Disease Research, University of Edinburgh, Edinburgh, Midlothian, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Geriatr Psychiatry</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8710629</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0885-6230</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000544" MajorTopicYN="Y">Alzheimer Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003071" MajorTopicYN="N">Cognition</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003072" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cognition Disorders</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Frontotemporal Dementia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009483" MajorTopicYN="N">Neuropsychological Tests</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ACE-III</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ECAS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">behaviour</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cognition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dementia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">frontotemporal dementia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neuropsychology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">qualitative</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">screen</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33983668</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/gps.5566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Atkin JD, Turner BJ. Motor Neuron Diseases: Causes, Classification, and Treatments. (p. 4). New York: Nova Science Publishes Inc.; 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldstein LH, Abrahams S. Changes in cognition and behaviour in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: nature of impairment and implications for assessment. The Lancet Neurology. 2013;12(4):368-380.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strong MJ, Abrahams S, Goldstein LH, et&#xa0;al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis - frontotemporal spectrum disorder (ALS-FTD): revised diagnostic criteria. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2017;18(3-4):153-174.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abrahams S, Newton J, Niven E, Foley J, Bak TH. Screening for cognition and behaviour changes in ALS. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2014;15(1-2):9-14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foley JA, Niven EH, Paget A, et&#xa0;al. Sensitivity and specificity of the ECAS in Parkinson's disease and progressive supranuclear Palsy. Parkinson's Dis. 2018;2018:1-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kourtesis P, Christidi F, Margioti E, et&#xa0;al. The Edinburgh cognitive and behavioral amyotrophic lateral sclerosis screen (ECAS): sensitivity in differentiating between ALS and Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease in a Greek population. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2019;21(1-2):1-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rascovsky K, Hodges JR, Knopman D, et&#xa0;al. Sensitivity of revised diagnostic criteria for the behavioural variant of frontotemporal dementia. Brain. 2011;134(9):2456-2477.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niven E, Newton J, Foley J, et&#xa0;al. Validation of the Edinburgh cognitive and behavioural amyotrophic lateral sclerosis screen (ECAS): a cognitive tool for motor disorders. Amyotrop Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2015;16(3-4):172-179.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinto-Grau M, Burke T, Lonergan K, et&#xa0;al. Screening for cognitive dysfunction in ALS: validation of the Edinburgh Cognitive and Behavioural ALS Screen (ECAS) using age and education adjusted normative data. Amyotrop Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2017;18(1-2):99-106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lul&#xe9; D, Burkhardt C, Abdulla S, et&#xa0;al. The Edinburgh cognitive and behavioural amyotrophic lateral sclerosis screen: a cross-sectional comparison of established screening tools in a German-Swiss population. Amyotro Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Dement. 2015;16(1-2):16-23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poletti B, Solca F, Carelli L, et&#xa0;al. The validation of the Italian Edinburgh cognitive and behavioural ALS screen (ECAS). Amyotrop Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2016;17(7-8):489-498.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Icaza Valenzuela MM, Bak TH, Pal S, Abrahams S. The Edinburgh cognitive and behavioral ALS screen: relationship to age, education, IQ and the Addenbrooke&#x2019;s cognitive examination-III. Amyotrop Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2018;19(7-8):585-590.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saxon JA, Thompson JC, Harris JM, et&#xa0;al. The Edinburgh cognitive and behavioural ALS screen (ECAS) in frontotemporal dementia. Amyotrop Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2020;21(7-8):606-613. https://doi.org/10.1080/21678421.2020.1797090</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsieh S, Schubert S, Hoon C, Mioshi E, Hodges JR. Validation of the Addenbrooke's cognitive examination III in frontotemporal dementia and Alzheimer's disease. Dement Geriatr Cognit Disord. 2013;36:242-250.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshida H, Terada S, Honda H, et&#xa0;al. Validation of Addenbrooke's cognitive examination for detecting early dementia in a Japanese population. Psychiatr Res. 2011;185:211-214.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bier JC, Ventura M, Donckels V, et&#xa0;al. Is the Addenbrooke?s Cognitive Examination effective to detect frontotemporal dementia? J Neurology. 2004;251:428-431.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elamin M, Holloway G, Bak TH, Pal S. The utility of the Addenbrooke&#x2019;s cognitive examination version three in early-onset dementia. Dementia Geriatric Cognitive Disord. 2015;41(1-2):9-15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruiz-Tagle A, Musa G, Lillo P, Slachevsky A. Social cognition in frontotemporal dementia and Alzheimer disease. J Neurological Sci. 2015;357(1):e208-e209.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hornberger M, Savage S, Hsieh S, Mioshi E, Piguet O, Hodges JR. Orbitofrontal dysfunction discriminates behavioral variant frontotemporal dementia from Alzheimer's disease. Dement Geriatr Cognit Disord. 2010;30(6):547-552.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou J, Greicius MD, Gennatas ED, et&#xa0;al. Divergent network connectivity changes in behavioural variant frontotemporal dementia and Alzheimer's disease. Brain. 2010;133(5):1352-1367.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sj&#xf6;gren M, Gustafson L, Wikkels&#xf6; C, Wallin A. Frontotemporal dementia can Be distinguished from Alzheimer's disease and subcortical white matter dementia by an anterior-to-posterior rCBF-SPET ratio. Dement Geriatr Cognit Disord. 2000;11(5):275-285.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kourtesis P, Margioti E, Demenega C, Christidi F, Abrahams S. A comparison of the Greek ACE-III, M-ACE, ACE-R, MMSE and ECAS in the assessment and identification of Alzheimer&#x2019;s Disease. J Int Neuropsychological Soc. 2020;26(8):825-834. https://doi.org/10.1017/S1355617720000314</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKhann GM, Knopman DS, Chertkow H, et&#xa0;al. The diagnosis of dementia due to Alzheimer's disease: recommendations from the national institute on aging-Alzheimer's association workgroups on diagnostic guidelines for Alzheimer's disease. Alzheimer's Dementia. 2011;7(3):263-269.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ritchie J, Spencer L. Qualitative data analysis for applied policy research. In: Bryman A, Burgess RG, eds. Analysis qualitative data. London: Routledge; 1994:173-194.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faul F, Erdfelder E, Lang A-G, Buchner A. G*Power 3: a flexible statistical power analysis program for the social, behavioral, and biomedical sciences. Behav Res Methods. 2007;39:175-191.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trevethan R. Sensitivity, specificity, and predictive values: foundations, pliabilities, and pitfalls in research and practice. Frontiers in Public Health. 2017;5:307.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koriath CAM, Bocchetta M, Brotherhood E, et&#xa0;al. The clinical, neuroanatomical, and neuropathologic phenotype of TBK1-associated frontotemporal dementia: a longitudinal case report. Alzheimer's Dementia Diagnosis, Assess Dis Monit. 2017;6(1):75-81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radakovic R, Colville S, Cranley D, Starr JM, Pal S, Abrahams S. Multidimensional apathy in behavioral variant frontotemporal dementia, primary progressive aphasia, and Alzheimer disease. J Geriatric Psychiatry Neurology. 2020:1-8. https://doi.org/10.1177/0891988720924716</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radakovic R, Harley C, Abrahams S, Starr JM. A systematic review of the validity and reliability of apathy scales in neurodegenerative conditions. Int Psychogeriatr. 2014;27(6):903-923.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Landes AM, Sperry SD, Strauss ME. Prevalence of apathy, dysphoria, and depression in relation to dementia severity in Alzheimer's disease. Jnp. 2005;17:342-349.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendez MF, Lauterbach EC, Sampson SM. An evidence-based review of the psychopathology of frontotemporal dementia: a report of the ANPA committee on research. Jnp. 2008;20(2):130-149.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ossenkoppele R, Pijnenburg YAL, Perry DC, et&#xa0;al. The behavioural/dysexecutive variant of Alzheimer's disease: clinical, neuroimaging and pathological features. Brain. 2015;138(9):2732-2749.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saxon JA, Thompson JC, Jones M, et&#xa0;al. Examining the language and behavioural profile in FTD and ALS-FTD. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2017;88(8):675-680.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ducharme S, Price BH, Larvie M, Dougherty DD, Dickerson BC. Clinical Approach to the differential diagnosis between behavioral variant frontotemporal dementia and primary psychiatric disorders. Ajp. 2015;172(9):827-837.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendez MF, Shapira JS, Miller BL. Stereotypical movements and frontotemporal dementia. Mov Disord. 2005;20(6):742-745.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wylie MA, Shnall A, Onyike CU, Huey ED. Management of frontotemporal dementia in mental health and multidisciplinary settings. Int Rev Psychiatry. 2013;25(2):230-236.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soto ME, Secher M, Gillette-Guyonnet S, et&#xa0;al. Weight loss and rapid cognitive decline in community-dwelling patients with Alzheimer's disease. Jad. 2012;28(3):647-654.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolf-Klein GP, Silverstone FA. Weight loss in Alzheimer's disease: an international review of the literature. Int Psychogeriatr. 1994;6(2):135-142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bozeat S, Gregory CA, Lambon Ralph MA, Hodges JR. Which neuropsychiatric and behavioural features distinguish frontal and temporal variants of frontotemporal dementia from Alzheimer's disease? J Neurology, Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2000;69(2):178-186.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bathgate D, Snowden JS, Varma A, Blackshaw A, Neary D. Behaviour in frontotemporal dementia, Alzheimer's disease and vascular dementia. Acta Neurol Scand. 2001;103(6):367-378.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nyatsanza S, Shetty T, Gregory C, Lough S, Dawson K, Hodges JR. A study of stereotypic behaviours in Alzheimer's disease and frontal and temporal variant frontotemporal dementia. J Neurology, Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2003;74(10):1398-1402.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed RM, Irish M, Kam J, et&#xa0;al. Quantifying the eating abnormalities in frontotemporal dementia. JAMA Neurol. 2014;71(12):1540-1546.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong F, Flanagan E, Savage G, Hodges JR, Hornberger M. Contrasting prefrontal cortex contributions to episodic memory dysfunction in behavioural variant frontotemporal dementia and Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. PLOS One. 2014;9(2):e87778.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foley JA, Kaschel R, Logie RH, Della Sala S. Dual-task performance in Alzheimer's disease, mild cognitive impairment, and normal ageing. Archives Clin Neuropsychology. 2011;26(4):340-348.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dickerson BC, McGinnis SM, Xia C, et&#xa0;al. Approach to atypical Alzheimer's disease and case studies of the major subtypes. CNS Spectr. 2017;22:439-449.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Llad&#xf3; A, S&#xe1;nchez-Valle R. Focusing on atypical symptoms for improved diagnosis of early-onset Alzheimer's disease. Future Neurol. 2011;6(5):575-578.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hodgins F, Mulhern S, Abrahams S. The clinical impact of the Edinburgh Cognitive and Behavioural ALS Screen (ECAS) and neuropsychological intervention in routine ALS care. Amyotrop lateral scler frontotemporal degener. 2019;21(1-2):92-99.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noone P. Addenbrooke's cognitive examination-III. Occmed. 2015;65(5):418-420.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benton AL, Hamsher KdeS. Multilingual Aphasia Examination: Manual of Instructions. Iowa City: Departments of Neurology and Psychology, University of Iowa; 1983.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isaacs B, Kennie AT. The set test as an aid to the detection of dementia in old people. Br J Psychiatry. 1973;123(575):467-470.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warrington EK. The graded naming test: a restandardisation. Neuropsychol Rehabil. 1997;7(2):143-146.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bishop DVM. Test for Reception of Grammar - Version 2 (TROG-2). London: The Psychological Corporation Limited; 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reitan RM, Wolfson D. The Halstead-Reitan Neuropsychological Test Battery: Therapy and Clinical Interpretation. Tucson, AZ: Neuropsychological Press; 1985.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delis DC, Kaplan E, Kramer J. Delis-Kaplan Executive Function System. San Antonio, TX: The Psychological Corporation; 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarazin M, Berr C, De Rotrou J, et&#xa0;al. Amnestic syndrome of the medial temporal type identifies prodromal AD: a longitudinal study. Neurology. 2007;69:1859-1867.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coughlan AK, Oddy MJ, Crawford JR. BIRT Memory and Information Processing Battery (BMIPB). London: Brain Injury Rehabilitation Trust; 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warrington EK, James M. The Visual Object and Space Perception Battery. Bury St Edmunds, England: Thames Valley Test Company; 1991.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>