<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">33993457</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>06</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1179-1934</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>35</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>May</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>CNS drugs</Title><ISOAbbreviation>CNS Drugs</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Pathophysiology and Treatment of Non-motor Dysfunction in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>483</StartPage><EndPage>505</EndPage><MedlinePgn>483-505</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40263-021-00820-1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis is a progressive and fatal neurodegenerative disease typically presenting with bulbar or limb weakness. There is increasing evidence that amyotrophic lateral sclerosis is a multisystem disease with early and frequent impacts on cognition, behaviour, sleep, pain and fatigue. Dysfunction of normal physiological and metabolic processes also appears common. Evidence from pre-symptomatic studies and large epidemiological cohorts examining risk factors for the future development of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis have reported a high prevalence of changes in behaviour and mental health before the emergence of motor weakness. This suggests that changes beyond the motor system are underway at an early stage with dysfunction across brain networks regulating a variety of cognitive, behavioural and other homeostatic processes. The full impact of non-motor dysfunction continues to be established but there is now sufficient evidence that the presence of non-motor symptoms impacts overall survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, and with up to 80% reporting non-motor symptoms, there is an urgent need to develop more robust therapeutic approaches. This review provides a contemporary overview of the pathobiology of non-motor dysfunction, offering readers a practical approach with regard to assessment and management. We review the current evidence for pharmacological and non-pharmacological treatment of non-motor dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and highlight the need to further integrate non-motor dysfunction as an important outcome measure for future clinical trial design.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mahoney</LastName><ForeName>Colin J</ForeName><Initials>CJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5878-3859</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Brain and Mind Centre, The University of Sydney, 94 Mallett Street, Camperdown, NSW, Australia. colin.mahoney@sydney.edu.au.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ahmed</LastName><ForeName>Rebekah M</ForeName><Initials>RM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Brain and Mind Centre, The University of Sydney, 94 Mallett Street, Camperdown, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Royal Prince Alfred Hospital, Camperdown, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huynh</LastName><ForeName>William</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Brain and Mind Centre, The University of Sydney, 94 Mallett Street, Camperdown, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tu</LastName><ForeName>Sicong</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Brain and Mind Centre, The University of Sydney, 94 Mallett Street, Camperdown, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rohrer</LastName><ForeName>Jonathan D</ForeName><Initials>JD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dementia Research Centre, Department of Neurodegenerative Disease, UCL Queen Square Institute of Neurology, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bedlack</LastName><ForeName>Richard S</ForeName><Initials>RS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Duke University Hospital, Durham, North Carolina, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hardiman</LastName><ForeName>Orla</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Academic Unit of Neurology, Trinity Biomedical Sciences Institute, Trinity College, Dublin, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kiernan</LastName><ForeName>Matthew C</ForeName><Initials>MC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9054-026X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Brain and Mind Centre, The University of Sydney, 94 Mallett Street, Camperdown, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Royal Prince Alfred Hospital, Camperdown, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>MR/M023664/1</GrantID><Acronym>MRC_</Acronym><Agency>Medical Research Council</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>MR/T046015/1</GrantID><Acronym>MRC_</Acronym><Agency>Medical Research Council</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>New Zealand</Country><MedlineTA>CNS Drugs</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9431220</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1172-7047</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D060825" MajorTopicYN="N">Cognitive Dysfunction</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018450" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Progression</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017063" MajorTopicYN="N">Outcome Assessment, Health Care</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012107" MajorTopicYN="N">Research Design</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012307" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33993457</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40263-021-00820-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s40263-021-00820-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Kiernan MC, Vucic S, Cheah BC, Turner MR, Eisen A, Hardiman O, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet. 2011;377:942&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21296405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardiman O, Al-Chalabi A, Brayne C, Beghi E, van den Berg LH, Chio A, et al. The changing picture of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: lessons from European registers. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2017;88:557&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28285264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed RM, Irish M, Piguet O, Halliday GM, Ittner LM, Farooqi S, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal dementia: distinct and overlapping changes in eating behaviour and metabolism. Lancet Neurol. 2016;15:332&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26822748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strong MJ. Revisiting the concept of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis as a multisystems disorder of limited phenotypic expression. Curr Opin Neurol. 2017;30:599&#x2013;607.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28914734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou J, Gennatas ED, Kramer JH, Miller BL, Seeley WW. Predicting regional neurodegeneration from the healthy brain functional connectome. Neuron. 2012;73:1216&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22445348</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3361461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arthur KC, Calvo A, Price TR, Geiger JT, Chi&#xf2; A, Traynor BJ. Projected increase in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis from 2015 to 2040. Nat Commun. 2016;7:12408.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27510634</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4987527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cullerre A. Troubles mentales dans la scl&#xe9;rose lat&#xe9;: rale amyotrophique. Arch Neurol. 1906;21:433&#x2013;50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirano A, Kurland LT, Krooth RS, Lessell S. Parkinsonism-dementia complex, an endemic disease on the island of Guam. I Clinical features Brain J Neurol. 1961;84:642&#x2013;61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hudson AJ. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and its association with dementia, parkinsonism and other neurological disorders: a review. Brain J Neurol. 1981;104:217&#x2013;47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neary D, Snowden JS, Mann DM, Northen B, Goulding PJ, Macdermott N. Frontal lobe dementia and motor neuron disease. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 1990;53:23&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2303828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">1014093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renton AE, Majounie E, Waite A, Sim&#xf3;n-S&#xe1;nchez J, Rollinson S, Gibbs JR, et al. A hexanucleotide repeat expansion in C9ORF72 is the cause of chromosome 9p21-linked ALS-FTD. Neuron. 2011;72(2):257&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21944779</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3200438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dadon-Nachum M, Melamed E, Offen D. The, &#x201c;dying-back&#x201d; phenomenon of motor neurons in ALS. J Mol Neurosci. 2011;43:470&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21057983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burrell JR, Kiernan MC, Vucic S, Hodges JR. Motor neuron dysfunction in frontotemporal dementia. Brain. 2011;134:2582&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21840887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahoney CJ, Downey LE, Ridgway GR, Beck J, Clegg S, Blair M, et al. Longitudinal neuroimaging and neuropsychological profiles of frontotemporal dementia with C9ORF72 expansions. Alzheimers Res Ther. 2012;4:41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23006986</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3580398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Heuvel MP, Sporns O. A cross-disorder connectome landscape of brain dysconnectivity. Nat Rev Neurosci. 2019;20:435&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31127193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verstraete E, Veldink JH, van den Berg LH, van den Heuvel MP. Structural brain network imaging shows expanding disconnection of the motor system in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Hum Brain Mapp. 2014;35:1351&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23450820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tu S, Menke RAL, Talbot K, Kiernan MC, Turner MR. Regional thalamic MRI as a marker of widespread cortical pathology and progressive frontotemporal involvement in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2018;89:1250&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30049750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner MR, Goldacre R, Talbot K, Goldacre MJ. Psychiatric disorders prior to amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol. 2016;80:935&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27761925</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5215396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longinetti E, Mariosa D, Larsson H, Ye W, Ingre C, Almqvist C, et al. Neurodegenerative and psychiatric diseases among families with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology. 2017;89:578&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28701495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5562958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byrne S, Heverin M, Elamin M, Bede P, Lynch C, Kenna K, et al. Aggregation of neurologic and neuropsychiatric disease in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis kindreds: a population-based case-control cohort study of familial and sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol. 2013;74:699&#x2013;708.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23836460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devenney EM, Ahmed RM, Halliday G, Piguet O, Kiernan MC, Hodges JR. Psychiatric disorders in C9orf72 kindreds: study of 1,414 family members. Neurology. 2018;91(16):e1498&#x2013;507.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30258023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Brien M, Burke T, Heverin M, Vajda A, McLaughlin R, Gibbons J, et al. Clustering of neuropsychiatric disease in first-degree and second-degree relatives of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. JAMA Neurol. 2017;74:1425.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29049464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5822189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peter RS, Rosenbohm A, Dupuis L, Brehme T, Kassubek J, Rothenbacher D, et al. Life course body mass index and risk and prognosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: results from the ALS registry Swabia. Eur J Epidemiol. 2017;32:901&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28975435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mariosa D, Hammar N, Malmstr&#xf6;m H, Ingre C, Jungner I, Ye W, et al. Blood biomarkers of carbohydrate, lipid, and apolipoprotein metabolisms and risk of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A more than 20-year follow-up of the Swedish AMORIS cohort. Ann Neurol. 2017;81:718&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28437840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bertrand A, Wen J, Rinaldi D, Houot M, Sayah S, Camuzat A, et al. Early cognitive, structural, and microstructural changes in presymptomatic C9orf72 carriers younger than 40 years. JAMA Neurol. 2018;75:236.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29197216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee SE, Sias AC, Mandelli ML, Brown JA, Brown AB, Khazenzon AM, et al. Network degeneration and dysfunction in presymptomatic C9ORF72 expansion carriers. NeuroImage Clin. 2017;14:286&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28337409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rohrer JD, Nicholas JM, Cash DM, van Swieten J, Dopper E, Jiskoot L, et al. Presymptomatic cognitive and neuroanatomical changes in genetic frontotemporal dementia in the Genetic Frontotemporal dementia Initiative (GENFI) study: a cross-sectional analysis. Lancet Neurol. 2015;14:253&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25662776</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6742501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panman JL, Jiskoot LC, Bouts MJRJ, Meeter LHH, van der Ende EL, Poos JM, et al. Gray and white matter changes in presymptomatic genetic frontotemporal dementia: a longitudinal MRI study. Neurobiol Aging. 2019;76:115&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30711674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papma JM, Jiskoot LC, Panman JL, Dopper EG, den Heijer T, Donker Kaat L, et al. Cognition and gray and white matter characteristics of presymptomatic C9orf72 repeat expansion. Neurology. 2017;89:1256&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28855404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rittman T, Borchert R, Jones S, van Swieten J, Borroni B, Galimberti D, et al. Functional network resilience to pathology in presymptomatic genetic frontotemporal dementia. Neurobiol Aging. 2019;77:169&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30831384</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6491498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lillo P, Garcin B, Hornberger M, Bak TH, Hodges JR. Neurobehavioral features in frontotemporal dementia with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Arch Neurol. 2010;67:826&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20625088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mioshi E, Caga J, Lillo P, Hsieh S, Ramsey E, Devenney E, et al. Neuropsychiatric changes precede classic motor symptoms in ALS and do not affect survival. Neurology. 2014;82:149&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24336140</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Witgert M, Salamone AR, Strutt AM, Jawaid A, Massman PJ, Bradshaw M, et al. Frontal-lobe mediated behavioral dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Eur J Neurol. 2010;17:103&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19874396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Z, Ma L. Grey matter volume changes over the whole brain in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A voxel-wise meta-analysis of voxel based morphometry studies. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2010;11:549&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20929296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorges M, Del Tredici K, Dreyhaupt J, Braak H, Ludolph AC, M&#xfc;ller H-P, et al. Corticoefferent pathology distribution in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: in vivo evidence from a meta-analysis of diffusion tensor imaging data. Sci Rep. 2018;8:15389.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30337677</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6194130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2; A, Pagani M, Agosta F, Calvo A, Cistaro A, Filippi M. Neuroimaging in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: insights into structural and functional changes. Lancet Neurol. 2014;13:1228&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25453462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheng L, Ma H, Zhong J, Shang H, Shi H, Pan P. Motor and extra-motor gray matter atrophy in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: quantitative meta-analyses of voxel-based morphometry studies. Neurobiol Aging. 2015;36:3288&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26362941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang F, Chen G, He M, Dai J, Shang H, Gong Q, et al. Altered white matter microarchitecture in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a voxel-based meta-analysis of diffusion tensor imaging. NeuroImage Clin. 2018;19:122&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30035009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6051469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bede P, Bokde ALW, Byrne S, Elamin M, McLaughlin RL, Kenna K, et al. Multiparametric MRI study of ALS stratified for the C9orf72 genotype. Neurology. 2013;81:361&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23771489</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3772833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahoney CJ, Beck J, Rohrer JD, Lashley T, Mok K, Shakespeare T, et al. Frontotemporal dementia with the C9ORF72 hexanucleotide repeat expansion: clinical, neuroanatomical and neuropathological features. Brain J Neurol. 2012;135:736&#x2013;50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agosta F, Spinelli EG, Marjanovic IV, Stevic Z, Pagani E, Valsasina P, et al. Unraveling ALS due to SOD1 mutation through the combination of brain and cervical cord MRI. Neurology. 2018;90:e707&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29367447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canosa A, Pagani M, Cistaro A, Montuschi A, Iazzolino B, Fania P, et al. <sup>18</sup>F-FDG-PET correlates of cognitive impairment in ALS. Neurology. 2016;86:44&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26590270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pagani M, Chio A, Valentini MC, Oberg J, Nobili F, Calvo A, et al. Functional pattern of brain FDG-PET in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology. 2014;83:1067&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25122207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Laere K, Vanhee A, Verschueren J, De Coster L, Driesen A, Dupont P, et al. Value of <sup>18</sup>Fluorodeoxyglucose&#x2013;positron-emission tomography in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a prospective study. JAMA Neurol. 2014;71:553.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24615479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proudfoot M, Bede P, Turner MR. Imaging cerebral activity in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Front Neurol. 2019;9:1148.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30671016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6332509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou C, Hu X, Hu J, Liang M, Yin X, Chen L, et al. Altered brain network in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a resting graph theory-based network study at voxel-wise level. Front Neurosci. 2016;10(10):204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27242409</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4861727</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trojsi F, Di Nardo F, Santangelo G, Siciliano M, Femiano C, Passaniti C, et al. Resting state fMRI correlates of theory of mind impairment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Cortex. 2017;97:1&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29073458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fekete T, Zach N, Mujica-Parodi LR, Turner MR. Multiple kernel learning captures a systems-level Functional connectivity biomarker signature in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. PLoS ONE. 2013;8:e85190.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24391997</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3877396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rothstein JD. Current hypotheses for the underlying biology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol. 2009;65(Suppl 1):S3-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19191304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheong I, Deelchand DK, Eberly LE, Marja&#x144;ska M, Manousakis G, Guliani G, et al. Neurochemical correlates of functional decline in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2019;90:294&#x2013;301.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30467209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lloyd CM, Richardson MP, Brooks DJ, Al-Chalabi A, Leigh PN. Extramotor involvement in ALS: PET studies with the GABAA ligand [11C]flumazenil. Brain. 2000;123:2289&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11050028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu X, Zhu W, Guo Z, Shu G, Cui F, Yang F, et al. 18 F-fallypride PET-CT of dopamine D2/D3 receptors in patients with sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Sci. 2017;377:79&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28477714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vogels OJ, Oyen WJ, van Engelen BG, Padberg GW, Horstink MW. Decreased striatal dopamine-receptor binding in sporadic ALS: glutamate hyperactivity? Neurology. 1999;52:1275&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10214758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner MR. [11C]-WAY100635 PET demonstrates marked 5-HT1A receptor changes in sporadic ALS. Brain. 2005;128:896&#x2013;905.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15689356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lowe J. New pathological findings in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Sci. 1994;124:38&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7807140</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakano I. Temporal lobe lesions in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with or without dementia: a neuropathological study. Neuropathology. 1993;13:215&#x2013;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geser F, Brandmeir NJ, Kwong LK, Martinez-Lage M, Elman L, McCluskey L, et al. Evidence of multisystem disorder in whole-brain map of pathological TDP-43 in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Arch Neurol. 2008;65(5):636&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18474740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kimura T, Jiang H, Konno T, Seto M, Iwanaga K, Tsujihata M, et al. Bunina bodies in motor and non-motor neurons revisited: a pathological study of an ALS patient after long-term survival on a respirator. Neuropathology. 2014;34(4):392&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24444375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piao Y-S, Wakabayashi K, Kakita A, Yamada M, Hayashi S, Morita T, et al. Neuropathology with clinical correlations of sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: 102 autopsy cases examined between 1962 and 2000. Brain Pathol. 2003;13:10&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12580541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner MR, Cagnin A, Turkheimer FE, Miller CCJ, Shaw CE, Brooks DJ, et al. Evidence of widespread cerebral microglial activation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: an [11C](R)-PK11195 positron emission tomography study. Neurobiol Dis. 2004;15:601&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15056468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zucchi E, Ticozzi N, Mandrioli J. Psychiatric symptoms in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: beyond a motor neuron disorder. Front Neurosci. 2019;13:175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30914912</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6421303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atassi N, Cook A, Pineda CME, Yerramilli-Rao P, Pulley D, Cudkowicz M. Depression in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2011;12:109&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21091399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rabkin JG, Albert SM, Rowland LP, Mitsumoto H. How common is depression among ALS caregivers? A longitudinal study. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2009;10:448&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19922139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2888701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thakore NJ, Pioro EP. Depression in ALS in a large self-reporting cohort. Neurology. 2016;86:1031&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26888995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carvalho TL, de Almeida LMS, Lorega CMA, Barata MFO, Ferreira MLB, de Brito-Marques PR, et al. Depression and anxiety in individuals with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a systematic review. Trends Psychiatry Psychother. 2016;38:1&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27007942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vignola A, Guzzo A, Calvo A, Moglia C, Pessia A, Cavallo E, et al. Anxiety undermines quality of life in ALS patients and caregivers. Eur J Neurol. 2008;15:1231&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18803649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siciliano M, Trojano L, Trojsi F, Monsurr&#xf2; MR, Tedeschi G, Santangelo G. Assessing anxiety and its correlates in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: the state-trait anxiety inventory. Muscle Nerve. 2019;60(1):47&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30897219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurt A, Nijboer F, Matuz T, K&#xfc;bler A. Depression and anxiety in individuals with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: epidemiology and management. CNS Drugs. 2007;21:279&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17381183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Albert SM, Rabkin JG, Del Bene ML, Tider T, O&#x2019;Sullivan I, Rowland LP, et al. Wish to die in end-stage ALS. Neurology. 2005;65:68&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16009887</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">1201540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang F, Valdimarsd&#xf3;ttir U, F&#xfc;rst CJ, Hultman C, Fall K, Spar&#xe9;n P, et al. Suicide among patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain. 2008;131:2729&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18669498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Snowden JS, Harris J, Richardson A, Rollinson S, Thompson JC, Neary D, et al. Frontotemporal dementia with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a clinical comparison of patients with and without repeat expansions in C9orf72. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Front Degener. 2013;14:172&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mor&#xe9;lot-Panzini C, Perez T, Sedkaoui K, de Bock E, Aguilaniu B, Devillier P, et al. The multidimensional nature of dyspnoea in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients with chronic respiratory failure: air hunger, anxiety and fear. Respir Med. 2018;145:1&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30509697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harrison PJ. The neuropathology of primary mood disorder. Brain. 2002;125:1428&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12076995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grieve SM, Korgaonkar MS, Koslow SH, Gordon E, Williams LM. Widespread reductions in gray matter volume in depression. NeuroImage Clin. 2013;3:332&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24273717</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3814952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLaughlin RL, Schijven D, van Rheenen W, van Eijk KR, O&#x2019;Brien M, Kahn RS, et al. Genetic correlation between amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and schizophrenia. Nat Commun. 2017;8:14774.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28322246</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5364411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crockford C, Newton J, Lonergan K, Chiwera T, Booth T, Chandran S, et al. ALS-specific cognitive and behavior changes associated with advancing disease stage in ALS. Neurology. 2018;91:e1370&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30209236</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6177274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phukan J, Elamin M, Bede P, Jordan N, Gallagher L, Byrne S, et al. The syndrome of cognitive impairment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a population-based study. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2012;83:102&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21836033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2; A, Moglia C, Canosa A, Manera U, Vasta R, Brunetti M, et al. Cognitive impairment across ALS clinical stages in a population-based cohort. Neurology. 2019;93:e984&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31409738</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6745732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beeldman E, Raaphorst J, Twennaar MK, de Visser M, Schmand BA, de Haan RJ. The cognitive profile of ALS: a systematic review and meta-analysis update. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2016;87:611&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26283685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abrahams S, Leigh PN, Goldstein LH. Cognitive change in ALS: a prospective study. Neurology. 2005;64:1222&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15824350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ringholz GM, Appel SH, Bradshaw M, Cooke NA, Mosnik DM, Schulz PE. Prevalence and patterns of cognitive impairment in sporadic ALS. Neurology. 2005;65:586&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16116120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abrahams S, Leigh PN, Harvey A, Vythelingum GN, Gris&#xe9; D, Goldstein LH. Verbal fluency and executive dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). Neuropsychologia. 2000;38:734&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10689049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meier SL, Charleston AJ, Tippett LJ. Cognitive and behavioural deficits associated with the orbitomedial prefrontal cortex in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain. 2010;133:3444&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20889583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bora E. Meta-analysis of social cognition in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Cortex. 2017;88:1&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28002755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Girardi A, MacPherson SE, Abrahams S. Deficits in emotional and social cognition in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuropsychology. 2011;25:53&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20919762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Staios M, Fisher F, Lindell A, Ong B, Howe J, Reardon K. Exploring sarcasm detection in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis using ecologically valid measures. Front Hum Neurosci. 2013;7:178.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23734113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3659344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leslie FVC, Hsieh S, Caga J, Savage SA, Mioshi E, Hornberger M, et al. Semantic deficits in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Front Degener. 2015;16:46&#x2013;53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor LJ, Brown RG, Tsermentseli S, Al-Chalabi A, Shaw CE, Ellis CM, et al. Is language impairment more common than executive dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis? J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2013;84:494&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23033353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke T, Lonergan K, Pinto-Grau M, Elamin M, Bede P, Madden C, et al. Visual encoding, consolidation, and retrieval in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: executive function as a mediator, and predictor of performance. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Front Degener. 2017;18:193&#x2013;201.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuster C, Kasper E, Dyrba M, Machts J, Bittner D, Kaufmann J, et al. Cortical thinning and its relation to cognition in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurobiol Aging. 2014;35:240&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23992619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ash S, Olm C, McMillan CT, Boller A, Irwin DJ, McCluskey L, et al. Deficits in sentence expression in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Front Degener. 2015;16:31&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinto-Grau M, Hardiman O, Pender N. The study of language in the amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: frontotemporal spectrum disorder: a systematic review of findings and new perspectives. Neuropsychol Rev. 2018;28:251&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29705950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen C, Caga J, Mahoney CJ, Kiernan MC, Huynh W. Behavioural changes predict poorer survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain Cogn. 2021;150:105710.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33725515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braak H, Del Tredici K. Anterior cingulate cortex TDP-43 pathology in sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neuropathol Exp Neurol. 2018;77:74&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29186496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raaphorst J, Beeldman E, Visser MD, Haan RJD, Schmand B. A systematic review of behavioural changes in motor neuron disease. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2012;13:493&#x2013;501.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22424127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Vries BS, Rustemeijer LMM, Bakker LA, Schr&#xf6;der CD, Veldink JH, van den Berg LH, et al. Cognitive and behavioural changes in PLS and PMA: challenging the concept of restricted phenotypes. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2019;90:141&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30076267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller A, Pratt H, Schiffer RB. Pseudobulbar affect: the spectrum of clinical presentations, etiologies and treatments. Expert Rev Neurother. 2011;11:1077&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21539437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, Crumpacker D, Fellus J, Kantor D, Kaye RE. PRISM: a novel research tool to assess the prevalence of pseudobulbar affect symptoms across neurological conditions. PLoS ONE. 2013;8(8):e72232.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23991068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3749118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thakore NJ, Pioro EP. Laughter, crying and sadness in ALS. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2017;88:825&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28572273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5629932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke T, Pinto-Grau M, Lonergan K, Bede P, O&#x2019;Sullivan M, Heverin M, et al. A cross-sectional population-based investigation into behavioral change in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: subphenotypes, staging, cognitive predictors, and survival. Ann Clin Transl Neurol. 2017;4:305&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28491898</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5420811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor L, Wicks P, Leigh PN, Goldstein LH. Prevalence of depression in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and other motor disorders. Eur J Neurol. 2010;17:1047&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20158515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaufer DI, Cummings JL, Ketchel P, Smith V, MacMillan A, Shelley T, et al. Validation of the NPI-Q, a brief clinical form of the Neuropsychiatric Inventory. J Neuropsychiatry Clin Neurosci. 2000;12:233&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11001602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niven E, Newton J, Foley J, Colville S, Swingler R, Chandran S, et al. Validation of the Edinburgh Cognitive and Behavioural Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Screen (ECAS): a cognitive tool for motor disorders. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Front Degener. 2015;16:172&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woolley SC, York MK, Moore DH, Strutt AM, Murphy J, Schulz PE, et al. Detecting frontotemporal dysfunction in ALS: utility of the ALS Cognitive Behavioral Screen (ALS-CBSTM). Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2010;11:303&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20433413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Icaza Valenzuela MM, Bak TH, Pal S, Abrahams S. The Edinburgh cognitive and behavioral ALS screen: relationship to age, education, IQ and the Addenbrooke&#x2019;s Cognitive Examination-III. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Front Degener. 2018;19:585&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radakovic R, Stephenson L, Colville S, Swingler R, Chandran S, Abrahams S. Multidimensional apathy in ALS: validation of the Dimensional Apathy Scale. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2016;87:663&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26203157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elamin M, Pinto-Grau M, Burke T, Bede P, Rooney J, O&#x2019;Sullivan M, et al. Identifying behavioural changes in ALS: validation of the Beaumont Behavioural Inventory (BBI). Amyotroph Lateral Scler Front Degener. 2017;18:68&#x2013;73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poletti B, Carelli L, Faini A, Solca F, Meriggi P, Lafronza A, et al. The Arrows and Colors Cognitive Test (ACCT): a new verbal-motor free cognitive measure for executive functions in ALS. PLoS ONE. 2018;13:e0200953.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30091987</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6084851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen PM, Abrahams S, Borasio GD, de Carvalho M, Chio A, Van Damme P, et al. EFNS guidelines on the clinical Management of Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis (MALS): revised report of an EFNS task force: EFNS Task Force on Management of ALS. Eur J Neurol. 2012;19:360&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21914052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rooney J, Byrne S, Heverin M, Tobin K, Dick A, Donaghy C, et al. A multidisciplinary clinic approach improves survival in ALS: a comparative study of ALS in Ireland and Northern Ireland. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2015;86:496&#x2013;501.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25550416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McElhiney MC, Rabkin JG, Gordon PH, Goetz R, Mitsumoto H. Prevalence of fatigue and depression in ALS patients and change over time. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2009;80:1146&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19762902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pagnini F, Marconi A, Tagliaferri A, Manzoni GM, Gatto R, Fabiani V, et al. Meditation training for people with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a randomized clinical trial. Eur J Neurol. 2017;24:578&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28229508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Groenestijn AC, Schr&#xf6;der CD, Visser-Meily JMA, Reenen ETK-V, Veldink JH, van den Berg LH. Cognitive behavioural therapy and quality of life in psychologically distressed patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and their caregivers: results of a prematurely stopped randomized controlled trial. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Front Degener. 2015;16:309&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raglio A, Giovanazzi E, Pain D, Baiardi P, Imbriani C, Imbriani M, et al. Active music therapy approach in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a randomized-controlled trial. Int J Rehabil Res. 2016;39:365&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27437724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moretti R, Torre P, Antonello RM, Cazzato G, Griggio S, Bava A. Olanzapine as a treatment of neuropsychiatric disorders of Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease and other dementias: a 24-month follow-up of 68 patients. Am J Alzheimers Dis Other Demen. 2003;18:205&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12955785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schneider LS, Tariot PN, Dagerman KS, Davis SM, Hsiao JK, Ismail MS, et al. Effectiveness of atypical antipsychotic drugs in patients with Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. N Engl J Med. 2006;355:1525&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17035647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsai RM, Boxer AL. Therapy and clinical trials in frontotemporal dementia: past, present, and future. J Neurochem. 2016;138:211&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27306957</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5217534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lebert F, Stekke W, Hasenbroekx C, Pasquier F. Frontotemporal dementia: a randomised, controlled trial with trazodone. Dement Geriatr Cogn Disord. 2004;17:355&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15178953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finger EC, MacKinley J, Blair M, Oliver LD, Jesso S, Tartaglia MC, et al. Oxytocin for frontotemporal dementia: a randomized dose-finding study of safety and tolerability. Neurology. 2015;84:174&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25503617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4336088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panitch HS, Thisted RA, Smith RA, Wynn DR, Wymer JP, Achiron A, et al. Randomized, controlled trial of dextromethorphan/quinidine for pseudobulbar affect in multiple sclerosis. Ann Neurol. 2006;59:780&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16634036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pioro EP, Brooks BR, Cummings J, Schiffer R, Thisted RA, Wynn D, et al. Dextromethorphan plus ultra low-dose quinidine reduces pseudobulbar affect. Ann Neurol. 2010;68:693&#x2013;702.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20839238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emon MAEK, Kodamullil AT, Karki R, Younesi E, Hofmann-Apitius M. Using drugs as molecular probes: a computational chemical biology approach in neurodegenerative diseases. J Alzheimers Dis. 2017;56:677&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28035920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5271458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norris FH, Tan Y, Fallat RJ, Elias L. Trial of oral physostigmine in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Pharmacol Ther. 1993;54:680&#x2013;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8275623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kertesz A, Morlog D, Light M, Blair M, Davidson W, Jesso S, et al. Galantamine in frontotemporal dementia and primary progressive aphasia. Dement Geriatr Cogn Disord. 2008;25:178&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18196898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendez MF, Shapira JS, McMurtray A, Licht E. Preliminary findings: behavioral worsening on donepezil in patients with frontotemporal dementia. Am J Geriatr Psychiatry. 2007;15:84&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17194818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Pinto S, Costa J, Evangelista T, Ohana B, Pinto A. A randomized, placebo-controlled trial of memantine for functional disability in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2010;11:456&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20565333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newsom-Davis I, Lyall R, Leigh P, Moxham J, Goldstein L. The effect of non-invasive positive pressure ventilation (NIPPV) on cognitive function in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS): a prospective study. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2001;71:482&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11561031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">1763518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coco DL, Mattaliano P, Spataro R, Mattaliano A, Bella VL. Sleep&#x2013;wake disturbances in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2011;82:839&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21217159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaufmann C, Wehrle R, Wetter TC, Holsboer F, Auer DP, Pollm&#xe4;cher T, et al. Brain activation and hypothalamic functional connectivity during human non-rapid eye movement sleep: an EEG/fMRI study. Brain. 2006;129:655&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16339798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorges M, Vercruysse P, M&#xfc;ller H-P, Huppertz H-J, Rosenbohm A, Nagel G, et al. Hypothalamic atrophy is related to body mass index and age at onset in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2017;88:1033&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28596251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed RM, Newcombe REA, Piper AJ, Lewis SJ, Yee BJ, Kiernan MC, et al. Sleep disorders and respiratory function in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Sleep Med Rev. 2016;26:33&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26166297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boentert M, Glatz C, Helmle C, Okegwo A, Young P. Prevalence of sleep apnoea and capnographic detection of nocturnal hypoventilation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2018;89:418&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29054915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atalaia A, Carvalho MD, Evangelista T, Pinto A. Sleep characteristics of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in patients with preserved diaphragmatic function. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2007;8:101&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17453638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lo Coco D, Puligheddu M, Mattaliano P, Congiu P, Borghero G, Fantini ML, et al. REM sleep behavior disorder and periodic leg movements during sleep in ALS. Acta Neurol Scand. 2017;135:219&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27027974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coco DL, Piccoli F, Bella VL. Restless legs syndrome in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Mov Disord. 2010;25:2658&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20669314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puligheddu M, Congiu P, Aric&#xf2; D, Rundo F, Borghero G, Marrosu F, et al. Isolated rapid eye movement sleep without atonia in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Sleep Med. 2016;26:16&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28007355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daoud H, Postuma RB, Bourassa CV, Rochefort D, Gauthier MT, Montplaisir J, et al. C9orf72 repeat expansions in rapid eye movement sleep behaviour disorder. Can J Neurol Sci. 2014;41:759&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25377888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebben MR, Shahbazi M, Lange DJ, Krieger AC. REM behavior disorder associated with familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2012;13:473&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22670878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johns MW. Reliability and factor analysis of the Epworth Sleepiness Scale. Sleep. 1992;15:376&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1519015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spoormaker VI, Verbeek I, van den Bout J, Klip EC. Initial validation of the SLEEP-50 Questionnaire. Behav Sleep Med. 2005;3:227&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16190812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roth T, Zammit G, Kushida C, Doghramji K, Mathias SD, Wong JM, et al. A new questionnaire to detect sleep disorders. Sleep Med. 2002;3:99&#x2013;108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14592227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wichniak A, Wierzbicka A, Wal&#x119;cka M, Jernajczyk W. Effects of antidepressants on sleep. Curr Psychiatry Rep. 2017;19:63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28791566</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5548844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Z, Chen F, Li WA, Geng X, Li C, Meng X, et al. A review of sleep disorders and melatonin. Neurol Res. 2017;39:559&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28460563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murciano D, Armengaud MH, Cramer PH, Neveux E, L&#x2019;Heritier C, Pariente R, et al. Acute effects of zolpidem, triazolam and flunitrazepam on arterial blood gases and control of breathing in severe COPD. Eur Respir J. 1993;6:625&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8519370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roth T. Hypnotic use for insomnia management in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Sleep Med. 2009;10:19&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18693067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altman BR, Mian MN, Slavin M, Earleywine M. Cannabis expectancies for sleep. J Psychoactive Drugs. 2019;51(5):405&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31319769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S-H, Chen W-S, Tang S-E, Lin H-C, Peng C-K, Chu H-T, et al. Benzodiazepines associated with acute respiratory failure in patients with obstructive sleep apnea. Front Pharmacol. 2019;9:1513.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30666205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6330300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mason M, Cates CJ, Smith I. Effects of opioid, hypnotic and sedating medications on sleep-disordered breathing in adults with obstructive sleep apnoea. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2015;7:CCD011090.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dorst J, Ludolph AC, Huebers A. Disease-modifying and symptomatic treatment of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ther Adv Neurol Disord. 2017;9(11):1756285617734734.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vrijsen B, Buyse B, Belge C, Robberecht W, Damme PV, Decramer M, et al. Noninvasive ventilation improves sleep in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a prospective polysomnographic study. J Clin Sleep Med. 2015;11:559&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25766713</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4410930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piccione EA, Sletten DM, Staff NP, Low PA. Autonomic system and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 2015;51:676&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25211238</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4362936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayashi K, Mochizuki Y, Koide R, Kawata A, Homma T, Shimizu T, et al. A Japanese familial ALS patient with autonomic failure and a p.Cys146Arg mutation in the gene for SOD1 ( SOD1): SOD1 mutant FALS with autonomic failure. Neuropathology. 2016;36:551&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27090969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldman JS, Quinzii C, Dunning-Broadbent J, Waters C, Mitsumoto H, Brannagan TH, et al. Multiple system atrophy and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in a family with hexanucleotide repeat expansions in C9orf72. JAMA Neurol. 2014;71:771.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24733620</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4051831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimizu T, Hayashi H, Kato S, Hayashi M, Tanabe H, Oda M. Circulatory collapse and sudden death in respirator-dependent amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Sci. 1994;124:45&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7931421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arlandis S, V&#xe1;zquez-Costa JF, Mart&#xed;nez-Cuenca E, Sevilla T, Boronat F, Broseta E. Urodynamic findings in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients with lower urinary tract symptoms: results from a pilot study. Neurourol Urodyn. 2017;36:626&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26895486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho MLL, Motta R, Battaglia MA, Brichetto G. Urinary disorders in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis subjects. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2011;12:352&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N&#xfc;bling GS, Mie E, Bauer RM, Hensler M, Lorenzl S, Hapfelmeier A, et al. Increased prevalence of bladder and intestinal dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Front Degener. 2014;15:174&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>V&#xe1;zquez-Costa JF, Arlandis S, Hervas D, Mart&#xed;nez-Cuenca E, Cardona F, P&#xe9;rez-Tur J, et al. Clinical profile of motor neuron disease patients with lower urinary tract symptoms and neurogenic bladder. J Neurol Sci. 2017;378:130&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28566149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toepfer M, Folwaczny C, Klauser A, Riepl RL, Muller-Felber W, M&#xfc;ller-Felber W, et al. Gastrointestinal dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord. 2000;1:15&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hobson EV, McGeachan A, Al-Chalabi A, Chandran S, Crawley F, Dick D, et al. Management of sialorrhoea in motor neuron disease: a survey of current UK practice. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Front Degener. 2013;14:521&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giess R, Werner E, Beck M, Reiners C, Toyka KV, Naumann M. Impaired salivary gland function reveals autonomic dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol. 2002;249:1246&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12242548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pisano F, Miscio G, Mazzuero G, Lanfranchi P, Colombo R, Pinelli P. Decreased heart rate variability in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 1995;18:1225&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7565918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baltadzhieva R, Gurevich T, Korczyn AD. Autonomic impairment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Curr Opin Neurol. 2005;18:487&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16155429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sato K, Namba R, Hayabara T, Kashihara K, Morimoto K. Autonomic nervous disorder in motor neuron disease: a study of advanced stage patients. Intern Med. 1995;34:972&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8563098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pavlovic S, Stevic Z, Milovanovic B, Milicic B, Rakocevic-Stojanovic V, Lavrnic D, et al. Impairment of cardiac autonomic control in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2010;11:272&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20001491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beck M, Giess R, Magnus T, Puls I, Reiners K, Toyka KV, et al. Progressive sudomotor dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Amp Psychiatry. 2002;73:68.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sletten DM, Suarez GA, Low PA, Mandrekar J, Singer W. COMPASS 31: a refined and abbreviated composite autonomic symptom score. Mayo Clin Proc. 2012;87:1196&#x2013;201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23218087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3541923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beck M, Flachenecker P, Magnus T, Giess R, Reiners K, Toyka KV, et al. Autonomic dysfunction in ALS: a preliminary study on the effects of intrathecal BDNF. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2005;6:100&#x2013;3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fowler CJ, O&#x2019;Malley KJ. Investigation and management of neurogenic bladder dysfunction. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2003;74:iv27-31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14645464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">1765643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patterson D, Abell T, Rothstein R, Koch K, Barnett J. A double-blind multicenter comparison of domperidone and metoclopramide in the treatment of diabetic patients with symptoms of gastroparesis. Am J Gastroenterol. 1999;94:1230&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10235199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banfi P, Ticozzi N, Lax A, Guidugli GA, Nicolini A, Silani V. A review of options for treating sialorrhea in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Respir Care. 2015;60:446&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25228780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arbouw MEL, Movig KLL, Koopmann M, Poels PJE, Guchelaar H-J, Egberts TCG, et al. Glycopyrrolate for sialorrhea in Parkinson disease: a randomized, double-blind, crossover trial. Neurology. 2010;74:1203&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20385892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strutt R, Fardell B, Chye R. Nebulized glycopyrrolate for drooling in a motor neuron patient. J Pain Symptom Manage. 2002;23:2&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11779659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Odachi K, Narita Y, Machino Y, Yamada T, Nishimura Y, Ota Y, et al. Efficacy of transdermal scopolamine for sialorrhea in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Cogent Med. 2017;4:1365401.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson CE, Gronseth G, Rosenfeld J, Barohn RJ, Dubinsky R, Simpson CB, et al. Randomized double-blind study of botulinum toxin type B for sialorrhea in als patients. Muscle Nerve. 2009;39:137&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19145653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lipp A, Trottenberg T, Schink T, Kupsch A, Arnold G. A randomized trial of botulinum toxin A for treatment of drooling. Neurology. 2003;61:1279&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14610139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guidubaldi A, Fasano A, Ialongo T, Piano C, Pompili M, Mascian&#xe0; R, et al. Botulinum toxin A versus B in sialorrhea: a prospective, randomized, double-blind, crossover pilot study in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis or Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Mov Disord. 2011;26:313&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21259343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isaacson SH, Ondo W, Jackson CE, Trosch RM, Molho E, Pagan F, et al. Safety and efficacy of rimabotulinumtoxinB for treatment of sialorrhea in adults: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA Neurol. 2020;77:461.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31930364</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6990829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hawkey NM, Zaorsky NG, Galloway TJ. The role of radiation therapy in the management of sialorrhea: a systematic review. Laryngoscope. 2016;126:80&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26152655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assouline A, Levy A, Abdelnour-Mallet M, Gonzalez-Bermejo J, Lenglet T, Le Forestier N, et al. Radiation therapy for hypersalivation: a prospective study in 50 amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. Int J Radiat Oncol. 2014;88:589&#x2013;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Storms W, Farrar JR. Guaifenesin in rhinitis. Curr Allergy Asthma Rep. 2009;9:101&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19210898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheffner AL. The reduction in vitro in viscosity of mucoprotein solutions by a new mucolytic agent. N-acetyl-L-cysteine Ann N Y Acad Sci. 2008;106:298&#x2013;310.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wark P, McDonald VM. Nebulised hypertonic saline for cystic fibrosis. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2018;9(9):CD001506.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30260472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stephens HE, Lehman E, Raheja D, Yang C, Walsh S, Mcarthur DB, et al. Pain in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: patient and physician perspectives and practices. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Front Degener. 2016;17:21&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pizzimenti A, Aragona M, Onesti E, Inghilleri M. Depression, pain and quality of life in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a cross-sectional study. Funct Neurol. 2013;28:115&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24125561</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3812727</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fletcher PD, Downey LE, Golden HL, Clark CN, Slattery CF, Paterson RW, et al. Pain and temperature processing in dementia: a clinical and neuroanatomical analysis. Brain. 2015;138:3360&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26463677</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4620514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2; A, Mora G, Lauria G. Pain in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet Neurol. 2017;16:144&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27964824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caress JB, Ciarlone SL, Sullivan EA, Griffin LP, Cartwright MS. Natural history of muscle cramps in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 2016;53:513&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26332705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramirez C, Piemonte MEP, Callegaro D, Silva HCAD. Fatigue in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: frequency and associated factors. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2008;9:75&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17924237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lou J-S, Reeves A, Benice T, Sexton G. Fatigue and depression are associated with poor quality of life in ALS. Neurology. 2003;60:122&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12525733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma KR, Kent- Braun JA, Majumdar S, Huang Y, Mynhier M, Weiner MW, et al. Physiology of fatigue in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology. 1995;45:733&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7723963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanjak M, Brinkmann J, Belden DS, Roelke K, Waclawik A, Neville HE, et al. Quantitative assessment of motor fatigue in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Sci. 2001;191:55&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11676992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S, Krishnan AV, Kiernan MC. Fatigue and activity dependent changes in axonal excitability in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Amp Psychiatry. 2007;78:1202&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cleeland C, Ryan K. Pain assessment: global use of the Brief Pain Inventory. Ann Acad Med Singap. 1994;23(2):129&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8080219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallace VCJ, Ellis CM, Burman R, Knights C, Shaw CE, Al-Chalabi A. The evaluation of pain in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a case controlled observational study. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Front Degener. 2014;15:520&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smets EM, Garssen B, Bonke B, De Haes JC. The Multidimensional Fatigue Inventory (MFI) psychometric qualities of an instrument to assess fatigue. J Psychosom Res. 1995;39:315&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7636775</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abraham A, Drory VE. Fatigue in motor neuron diseases. Neuromuscul Disord. 2012;22(Suppl. 3):S198-202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23182639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aboussouan LS, Khan SU, Banerjee M, Arroliga AC, Mitsumoto H. Objective measures of the efficacy of noninvasive positive-pressure ventilation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 2001;24:403&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11353427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brettschneider J, Kurent J, Ludolph A, Mitchell JD. Drug therapy for pain in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis or motor neuron disease. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2008;3:CD005226.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newrick PG, Langton-Hewer R. Pain in motor neuron disease. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 1985;48:838&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4031936</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">1028459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McClelland S, Bethoux FA, Boulis NM, Sutliff MH, Stough DK, Schwetz KM, et al. Intrathecal baclofen for spasticity-related pain in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: efficacy and factors associated with pain relief. Muscle Nerve. 2008;37:396&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17894358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bedlack RS, Pastula DM, Hawes J, Heydt D. Open-label pilot trial of levetiracetam for cramps and spasticity in patients with motor neuron disease. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2009;10:210&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18821142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekstr&#xf6;m MP, Bornefalk-Hermansson A, Abernethy AP, Currow DC. Safety of benzodiazepines and opioids in very severe respiratory disease: national prospective study. BMJ. 2014;348:g445.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24482539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3906915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amtmann D, Weydt P, Johnson KL, Jensen MP, Carter GT. Survey of cannabis use in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Am J Hosp Palliat Med. 2004;21:95&#x2013;104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riva N, Mora G, Sorar&#xf9; G, Lunetta C, Ferraro OE, Falzone Y, et al. Safety and efficacy of nabiximols on spasticity symptoms in patients with motor neuron disease (CANALS): a multicentre, double-blind, randomised, placebo-controlled, phase 2 trial. Lancet Neurol. 2019;18:155&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30554828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Tawil S, Musa TA, Valli H, Lunn MP, Brassington R, El-Tawil T, et al. Quinine for muscle cramps. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2015;4:CD005044.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katzberg HD, Khan AH, So YT. Assessment: symptomatic treatment for muscle cramps (an evidence-based review): report of the Therapeutics and Technology Assessment Subcommittee of the American Academy of Neurology. Neurology. 2010;74:691&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20177124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weber M, Goldman B, Truniger S. Tetrahydrocannabinol (THC) for cramps in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a randomised, double-blind crossover trial. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2010;81:1135&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20498181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weiss MD, Macklin EA, Simmons Z, Knox AS, Greenblatt DJ, Atassi N, et al. A randomized trial of mexiletine in ALS: safety and effects on muscle cramps and progression. Neurology. 2016;86:1474&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26911633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4836879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudhakaran P. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: an acupuncture approach. Med Acupunct. 2017;29:260&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29067136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5653341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maggiani A, Tremolizzo L, Valentina AD, Mapelli L, Sosio S, Milano V, et al. Osteopathic manual treatment for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a feasibility pilot Study. Open Neurol J. 2016;10:59&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27651843</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5009295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carter GT, Weiss MD, Lou J-S, Jensen MP, Abresch RT, Martin TK, et al. Modafinil to treat fatigue in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: an open label pilot study. Am J Hosp Palliat Care. 2005;22:55&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15736608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rabkin JG, Gordon PH, McElhiney M, Rabkin R, Chew S, Mitsumoto H. Modafinil treatment of fatigue in patients with ALS: a placebo-controlled study. Muscle Nerve. 2009;39:297&#x2013;303.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19208404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;cke M, Mochamat, Cuhls H, Peuckmann-Post V, Minton O, Stone P, et al. Pharmacological treatments for fatigue associated with palliative care. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2015;5:88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bello-Haas VD, Florence JM, Kloos AD, Scheirbecker J, Lopate G, Hayes SM, et al. A randomized controlled trial of resistance exercise in individuals with ALS. Neurology. 2007;68:2003&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17548549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zanette G, Forgione A, Manganotti P, Fiaschi A, Tamburin S. The effect of repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation on motor performance, fatigue and quality of life in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Sci. 2008;270:18&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18304580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zucchi E, Vinceti M, Malagoli C, Fini N, Gessani A, Fasano A, et al. High-frequency motor rehabilitation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a randomized clinical trial. Ann Clin Transl Neurol. 2019;6:893&#x2013;901.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31139687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6529833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desport JC, Preux PM, Magy L, Boirie Y, Vallat JM, Beaufr&#xe8;re B, et al. Factors correlated with hypermetabolism in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Am J Clin Nutr. 2001;74:328&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11522556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed RM, Caga J, Devenney E, Hsieh S, Bartley L, Highton-Williamson E, et al. Cognition and eating behavior in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: effect on survival. J Neurol. 2016;263:1593&#x2013;603.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27260291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steyn FJ, Ioannides ZA, van Eijk RPA, Heggie S, Thorpe KA, Ceslis A, et al. Hypermetabolism in ALS is associated with greater functional decline and shorter survival. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2018;89:1016&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29706605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6166607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moglia C, Calvo A, Grassano M, Canosa A, Manera U, D&#x2019;Ovidio F, et al. Early weight loss in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: outcome relevance and clinical correlates in a population-based cohort. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2019;90:666&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30630957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Mantgem JMR, van Eijk RPA, van der Burgh HK, Tan HHG, Westeneng H-J, van Es MA, et al. Prognostic value of weight loss in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a population-based study. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2020;91:867&#x2013;75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakken O, Meyer HE, Stigum H, Holm&#xf8;y T. High BMI is associated with low ALS risk: a population-based study. Neurology. 2019;93:e424&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31243073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dupuis L, Corcia P, Fergani A, De Aguilar GJ-L, Bonnefont-Rousselot D, Bittar R, et al. Dyslipidemia is a protective factor in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology. 2008;70:1004&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18199832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed RM, Ke YD, Vucic S, Ittner LM, Seeley W, Hodges JR, et al. Physiological changes in neurodegeneration: mechanistic insights and clinical utility. Nat Rev Neurol. 2018;14:259&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29569624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dorst J, K&#xfc;hnlein P, Hendrich C, Kassubek J, Sperfeld AD, Ludolph AC. Patients with elevated triglyceride and cholesterol serum levels have a prolonged survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol. 2011;258:613&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21128082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dedic SIK, Stevic Z, Dedic V, Stojanovic VR, Milicev M, Lavrnic D. Is hyperlipidemia correlated with longer survival in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis? Neurol Res. 2012;34:576&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22732100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pradat P-F, Bruneteau G, Gordon PH, Dupuis L, Bonnefont-Rousselot D, Simon D, et al. Impaired glucose tolerance in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2010;11:166&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20184518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mariosa D, Kamel F, Bellocco R, Ye W, Fang F. Association between diabetes and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in Sweden. Eur J Neurol. 2015;22:1436&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25600257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4506907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rotermund C, Machetanz G, Fitzgerald JC. The Therapeutic potential of metformin in neurodegenerative diseases. Front Endocrinol. 2018;9:400.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peters TL, Weibull CE, Fang F, Sandler DP, Lambert PC, Ye W, et al. Association of fractures with the incidence of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Front Degener. 2017;18:419&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paganoni S, Macklin EA, Karam C, Yu H, Gonterman F, Fetterman KA, et al. Vitamin D levels are associated with gross motor function in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 2017;56:726&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28044349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wills A-M, Hubbard J, Macklin EA, Glass J, Tandan R, Simpson EP, et al. Hypercaloric enteral nutrition in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled phase 2 trial. Lancet. 2014;383:2065&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24582471</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4176708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dorst J, Dupuis L, Petri S, Kollewe K, Abdulla S, Wolf J, et al. Percutaneous endoscopic gastrostomy in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a prospective observational study. J Neurol. 2015;262:849&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25618254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ludolph AC, Dorst J, Dreyhaupt J, Weishaupt JH, Kassubek J, Weiland U, et al. Effect of high-caloric nutrition on survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol. 2020;87:206&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31849093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazzini L, Corr&#xe0; T, Zaccala M, Mora G, Del Piano M, Galante M. Percutaneous endoscopic gastrostomy and enteral nutrition in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol. 1995;242:695&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8568533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katzberg HD, Benatar M. Enteral tube feeding for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis/motor neuron disease. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2011;1:CD004030.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seelen M, van Doormaal PTC, Visser AE, Huisman MHB, Roozekrans MHJ, de Jong SW, et al. Prior medical conditions and the risk of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol. 2014;261:1949&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25059395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Golomb BA, Verden A, Messner AK, Koslik HJ, Hoffman KB. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis associated with statin use: a disproportionality analysis of the FDA&#x2019;s Adverse Event Reporting System. Drug Saf. 2018;41:403&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29427042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zinman L, Sadeghi R, Gawel M, Patton D, Kiss A. Are statin medications safe in patients with ALS? Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2008;9:223&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18608105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karam C, Barrett MJ, Imperato T, MacGowan DJL, Scelsa S. Vitamin D deficiency and its supplementation in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Clin Neurosci. 2013;20:1550&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23815870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trojsi F, Siciliano M, Passaniti C, Bisecco A, Russo A, Lavorgna L, et al. Vitamin D supplementation has no effects on progression of motor dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). Eur J Clin Nutr. 2020;74:167&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31197218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swinnen B, Robberecht W. The phenotypic variability of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat Rev Neurol. 2014;10:661&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25311585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calvo A, Chi&#xf2; A, Pagani M, Cammarosano S, Dematteis F, Moglia C, et al. Parkinsonian traits in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS): a prospective population-based study. J Neurol. 2019;266:1633&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30949819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Sarraj S, King A, Troakes C, Smith B, Maekawa S, Bodi I, et al. p62 positive, TDP-43 negative, neuronal cytoplasmic and intranuclear inclusions in the cerebellum and hippocampus define the pathology of C9orf72-linked FTLD and MND/ALS. Acta Neuropathol. 2011;122(6):691&#x2013;702.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22101323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viguera C, Wang J, Mosmiller E, Cerezo A, Maragakis NJ. Olfactory dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Clin Transl Neurol. 2018;5:976&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30128322</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6093848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrari G, Grisan E, Scarpa F, Fazio R, Comola M, Quattrini A, et al. Corneal confocal microscopy reveals trigeminal small sensory fiber neuropathy in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Front Aging Neurosci. 2014;6:278.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25360111</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4199282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S. Facial onset sensory motor neuronopathy (FOSMN) syndrome: an unusual amyotrophic lateral sclerosis phenotype? J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2014;85:951&#x2013;951.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24643461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oeckl P, Weydt P, Steinacker P, Anderl-Straub S, Nordin F, Volk AE, et al. Different neuroinflammatory profile in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal dementia is linked to the clinical phase. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2019;90:4&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30224549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rao M, Gershon MD. The bowel and beyond: the enteric nervous system in neurological disorders. Nat Rev Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2016;13:517&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27435372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5005185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Br&#xe4;uer S, Zimyanin V, Hermann A. Prion-like properties of disease-relevant proteins in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neural Transm. 2018;125:591&#x2013;613.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29417336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayers JI, Fromholt SE, O&#x2019;Neal VM, Diamond JH, Borchelt DR. Prion-like propagation of mutant SOD1 misfolding and motor neuron disease spread along neuroanatomical pathways. Acta Neuropathol (Berl). 2016;131:103&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brettschneider J, Del Tredici K, Toledo JB, Robinson JL, Irwin DJ, Grossman M, et al. Stages of pTDP-43 pathology in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: ALS stages. Ann Neurol. 2013;74:20&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23686809</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3785076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burrell JR, Halliday GM, Kril JJ, Ittner LM, G&#xf6;tz J, Kiernan MC, et al. The frontotemporal dementia-motor neuron disease continuum. Lancet. 2016;388:919&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26987909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seitz DP, Adunuri N, Gill SS, Gruneir A, Herrmann N, Rochon P. Antidepressants for agitation and psychosis in dementia. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2011;2:CD008191.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen PM, Abrahams S, Borasio GD, de Carvalho M, Chio A, EFNS Task Force on Diagnosis and Management of Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis, et al. EFNS guidelines on the clinical management of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (MALS): revised report of an EFNS task force: EFNS Task Force on Management of ALS. Eur J Neurol. 2012;19:360&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21914052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boxer AL, Knopman DS, Kaufer DI, Grossman M, Onyike C, Graf-Radford N, et al. Memantine in patients with frontotemporal lobar degeneration: a multicentre, randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Lancet Neurol. 2013;12:149&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23290598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3756890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katzberg HD, Selegiman A, Guion L, Yuan N, Cho SC, Katz JS, et al. Effects of noninvasive ventilation on sleep outcomes in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Clin Sleep Med. 2013;9(4):345&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23585750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3601313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garrison SR, Korownyk CS, Kolber MR, Allan GM, Musini VM, Sekhon RK, et al. Magnesium for skeletal muscle cramps. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2020;9:CD009402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32956536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Libonati L, Onesti E, Gori MC, Ceccanti M, Cambieri C, Fabbri A, et al. Vitamin D in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Funct Neurol. 2017;32:35&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28380322</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5505528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>