<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">34014000</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2524</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>30</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Health &amp; social care in the community</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Health Soc Care Community</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The diagnostic, therapeutic and assistance pathway for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in a north-eastern Italian region: satisfaction of patients and their caregivers.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>124</StartPage><EndPage>132</EndPage><MedlinePgn>124-132</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/hsc.13379</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>In order to evaluate the users' satisfaction degree for the diagnostic, therapeutic and assistance services for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) in the Italian region Friuli-Venezia Giulia (FVG), a self-compiled anonymous multiple-choice questionnaire was administered to ALS patients and their caregivers. The questionnaire explored 41 different issues covering the following areas: (a) access to diagnostic pathway and communication among patients, families and health professionals; (b) quality of disease monitoring and effectiveness of interventions aimed at mitigating ALS symptoms; (c) easiness of access to assistive devices (e.g. wheelchair, ankle-foot-orthosis) and home assistance; (d) patient' choices sharing and health professionals empathy. The same issues were proposed both to patients and carers, appropriately adapting the questions, during the period between June and December 2019. The answers were categorised according to criticality level. Median with interquartile range of the numeric variables and percentages of the categorical variables and of the answers to questions were calculated. The mean percentage of satisfied users was 72.8%, considering all the areas. Pain treatment and easiness of access to ambulance transport were the most positive aspects (95.7% and 92.5% of satisfied respondents, respectively), while information about possible enrolment in clinical trials and about possible registration to the regional ALS association were the most critical issues (30.9% and 43.4% of satisfied users). Although the satisfaction level of ALS patients and their caregivers for the services provided resulted generally good, there were some areas that have to be improved. For this purpose, enhancement of multidisciplinary collaboration, sharing of points of view from users and different practitioners and rising awareness among healthcare professionals through clinical audits could be useful. Further research is needed to identify a wider range of users' unexplored unmet needs.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Palese</LastName><ForeName>Francesca</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7119-4445</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Area Department, University of Udine, Udine, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gigli</LastName><ForeName>Gian Luigi</ForeName><Initials>GL</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3526-1414</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Neurology Unit, Department of Neurosciences, Santa Maria della Misericordia University Hospital, ASUFC, Udine, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mathematics, Informatics and Physics, University of Udine, Udine, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Manganotti</LastName><ForeName>Paolo</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5305-6268</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Neurology Unit, Department of Medical, Surgical, and Health Sciences, University Hospital of Trieste, ASUGI, Trieste, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Passadore</LastName><ForeName>Paolo</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurology Unit, Santa Maria degli Angeli Hospital, ASFO, Pordenone, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rana</LastName><ForeName>Michele</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurology Unit, Hospital of Gorizia, ASUGI, Gorizia, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Verriello</LastName><ForeName>Lorenzo</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurology Unit, Department of Neurosciences, Santa Maria della Misericordia University Hospital, ASUFC, Udine, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Health Soc Care Community</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9306359</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0966-0410</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017028" MajorTopicYN="Y">Caregivers</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017060" MajorTopicYN="N">Patient Satisfaction</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010549" MajorTopicYN="N">Personal Satisfaction</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011795" MajorTopicYN="N">Surveys and Questionnaires</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">caregivers</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">healthcare</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">patients</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">satisfaction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">services</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">survey</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>59</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34014000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/hsc.13379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Bolmsj&#xf6;, I., &amp; Hermer&#xe9;n, G. (2001). Interviews with patients, family, and caregivers in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Comparing needs. Journal of Palliative Care, 17, 236-240. https://doi.org/10.1177/082585970101700403</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown, J. B. (2003). User, carer, and professional experiences of care in motor neurone disease. Primary Health Care Research &amp; Development, 4, 207-217. https://doi.org/10.1191/1463423603pc151oa</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Callagher, P., Mitchell, D., Bennett, W., &amp; Addison-Jones, R. (2009). Evaluating a fast-track service for diagnosing MND/ALS against traditional pathways. British Journal of Neuroscience Nursing, 5, 322-325. https://doi.org/10.12968/bjnn.2009.5.7.43241</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2;, A. (1999). ISIS Survey: An international study on the diagnostic process and its implications in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Journal of Neurology, 246 Suppl 3, III1-5. https://doi.org/10.12968/bjnn.2009.5.7.43241</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2;, A., Montuschi, A., Cammarosano, S., De Mercanti, S., Cavallo, E., Ilardi, A., Ghiglione, P., Mutani, R., &amp; Calvo, A. (2008). ALS patients and caregivers communication preferences and information seeking behaviour. European Journal of Neurology, 15, 55-60. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1468-1331.2007.02000.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2;, A., Mora, G., &amp; Lauria, G. (2017). Pain in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. The Lancet Neurology, 16, 144-157. https://doi.org/10.1016/S1474-4422(16)30358-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cipolletta, S., Gammino, G. R., Francescon, P., &amp; Palmieri, A. (2018). Mutual support groups for family caregivers of people with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in Italy: A pilot study. Health &amp; Social Care in the Community, 26, 556-563. https://doi.org/10.1111/hsc.12558</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans, R. L., Bishop, D. S., &amp; Haselkorn, J. K. (1991). Factors predicting satisfactory home care after stroke. Archives of Physical Medicine &amp; Rehabilitation, 72, 144-147. https://doi.org/10.5555/uri:pii:000399939190123Z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foley, G., Timonen, V., &amp; Hardiman, O. (2012). Patients' perceptions of services and preferences for care in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A review. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis, 13, 11-24. https://doi.org/10.3109/17482968.2011.607500</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hocking, C., Brott, T., &amp; Paddy, A. (2006). Caring for people with motor neurone disease. International Journal of Therapy &amp; Rehabilitation, 13, 351-355. https://doi.org/10.12968/ijtr.2006.13.8.351</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes, R. A., Sinha, A., Higginson, I., Down, K., &amp; Leigh, P. N. (2005). Living with motor neurone disease: Lives, experiences of services and suggestions for change. Health &amp; Social Care in the Community, 13, 64-74. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2524.2005.00530.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalb, R. C. (1995). Families affected by multiple sclerosis: Disease impacts and coping strategies. National Multiple Sclerosis Society.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krivickas, L. S., Shockley, L., &amp; Mitsumoto, H. (1997). Home care of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Journal of the Neurological Sciences, 152, 82-89. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0022-510X(97)00251-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levvy, G. (2000). The role of the lay associations. In R. H. Brown, V. Meininger, &amp; M. Swash (Eds.), Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Martin Dunitz.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marin, B., Boum&#xe9;diene, F., Logroscino, G., Couratier, P., Babron, M. C., Leutenegger, A. L., Copetti, M., Preux, P. M., &amp; Beghi, E. (2017). Variation in worldwide incidence of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A meta-analysis. Internal Journal of Epidemiology, 46, 57-74. https://doi.org/10.1093/ije/dyw061</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCabe, M. P., Roberts, C., &amp; Firth, L. (2008). Satisfaction with services among people with progressive neurological illnesses and their carers in Australia. Nursing &amp; Health Sciences, 10, 209-215. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1442-2018.2008.00399.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muraro, L., &amp; Coccia, J. (2015). Progetto di indagine sulla qualit&#xe0; percepita da utenti coinvolti nel percorso diagnostico terapeutico assistenziale del paziente con SLA. Azienda Unit&#xe0; Sanitaria Locale di Bologna, UO Qualit&#xe0; e Accreditamento. Retrieved from http://www.assisla.it/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/RelazioneQPpdtasla.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicholson, K., Murphy, A., McDonnell, E., Shapiro, J., Simpson, E., Glass, J., Mitsumoto, H., Forshew, D., Miller, R., &amp; Atassi, N. (2018). Improving symptom management for people with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle &amp; Nerve, 57, 20-24. https://doi.org/10.1002/mus.25712</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Brien, M. R., Whitehead, B., Jack, B. A., &amp; Mitchell, J. D. (2011). From symptom onset to a diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis / motor neurone disease; experiences of people with ALS/MND and family caregivers: A qualitative study. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis, 12, 97-104. https://doi.org/10.3109/17482968.2010.546414</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olin, J. T., Schneider, L. S., &amp; Kaser-Boyd, N. (1996). Associating personality pathology with emotional distress in caregivers of patients with Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. Journal of Clinical Geropsychology, 2, 93-101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palese, F., Sartori, A., Verriello, L., Ros, S., Passadore, P., Manganotti, P., Barbone, F., &amp; Pisa, F. E. (2018). Epidemiology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in Friuli-Venezia Giulia, North-Eastern Italy, 2002-2014: A retrospective population-based study. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis &amp; Frontotemporal Degeneration, 15, 1-10. https://doi.org/10.1080/21678421.2018.1511732</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ray, C., Fisher, J., &amp; Wisniewski, T. K. M. (1986). Surgeons' attitudes toward breast cancer, its treatment, and their relationship with patients. Journal of Psychosocial Oncology, 4, 33-43. https://doi.org/10.1300/J077v04n01_03</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson, I., &amp; Hunter, M. (1988). Motor neurone disease. In R. Fitzpatrick &amp; S. Newman (Eds.), The experience of illness series. Routledge.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silverstein, M. D., Stocking, C. B., Antel, J. P., Beckwith, J., Roos, R. P., &amp; Siegler, M. (1991). Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and life-sustaining therapy: Patients' desires for information, participation in decision making, and life-sustaining therapy. Mayo Clinic Proceedings, 66, 906-913. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0025-6196(12)61577-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Teijlingen, E. R., Friend, E., &amp; Kamal, A. D. (2001). Service use and needs of people with motor neurone disease and their carers in Scotland. Health &amp; Social Care in the Community, 9, 397-403. https://doi.org/10.1046/j.1365-2524.2001.00320.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wicks, P., &amp; Frost, J. (2008). ALS patients request more information about cognitive symptoms. European Journal of Neurology, 15, 497-500. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1468-1331.2008.02107.x</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>