<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">34057094</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>03</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2214-3602</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>8</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of neuromuscular diseases</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Neuromuscul Dis</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Healthcare Utilisation and Satisfaction with Care in Patients with Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis - An Observational Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1079</StartPage><EndPage>1088</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1079-1088</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3233/JND-210687</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) need a large amount of healthcare services. Knowledge on use of and satisfaction with healthcare is, however, scarce.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The objectives were to explore use and satisfaction of healthcare in patients with ALS.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">The sample consisted of patients with ALS, recruited from the ALS clinic at the Karolinska University Hospital, Stockholm, Sweden, participating in a three-year observational study. Data on healthcare utilisation were retrieved from the computerised register at Region Stockholm, Sweden. Information regarding disability, contextual factors and satisfaction with care was collected by home visits.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Over time, half, or less of the patients used inpatient care, whereas all used outpatient care. Half of all outpatient contacts were with providers of advanced healthcare in the home and one-fifth with allied health professionals. Nurses performing home visits composed the largest proportion of outpatient contacts. A small amount of the utilised outpatient care emerged from the ALS clinic. Patients with severe disease and longer time since diagnosis had fewer contacts with the ALS clinic. Satisfaction with care was in general stable over time with around two-thirds or more of patients being satisfied. Most patients wanted to participate in care planning, but few had.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Patients with ALS use hospital-based specialist care and other outpatient care in parallel with many healthcare providers involved. Our findings highlight the need for implementation of person-centred care to improve both coordination of care, care transitions and satisfaction with healthcare services.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kierkegaard</LastName><ForeName>Marie</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurobiology, Care Sciences and Society, Karolinska Institutet, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Women's Health and Allied Health Professionals Theme, Karolinska University Hospital, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Academic Specialist Center, Stockholm Health Services, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gottberg</LastName><ForeName>Kristina</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurobiology, Care Sciences and Society, Karolinska Institutet, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Johansson</LastName><ForeName>Sverker</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurobiology, Care Sciences and Society, Karolinska Institutet, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Women's Health and Allied Health Professionals Theme, Karolinska University Hospital, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Littorin</LastName><ForeName>Susanne</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Women's Health and Allied Health Professionals Theme, Karolinska University Hospital, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sandstedt</LastName><ForeName>Petter</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurobiology, Care Sciences and Society, Karolinska Institutet, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Women's Health and Allied Health Professionals Theme, Karolinska University Hospital, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ytterberg</LastName><ForeName>Charlotte</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurobiology, Care Sciences and Society, Karolinska Institutet, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Women's Health and Allied Health Professionals Theme, Karolinska University Hospital, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Holmqvist</LastName><ForeName>Lotta Wid&#xe9;n</ForeName><Initials>LW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurobiology, Care Sciences and Society, Karolinska Institutet, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Women's Health and Allied Health Professionals Theme, Karolinska University Hospital, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D064888">Observational Study</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>J Neuromuscul Dis</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101649948</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2214-3599</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="Y">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006760" MajorTopicYN="N">Hospitalization</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="N">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010342" MajorTopicYN="N">Patient Acceptance of Health Care</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="Y">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017060" MajorTopicYN="N">Patient Satisfaction</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="Y">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013548" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Sweden</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">healthcare</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">patient satisfaction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">utilisation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors have no conflict of interest to report.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34057094</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8673529</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/JND-210687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">JND210687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Crockford C, Newton J, Lonergan K, Chiwera T, Booth T, Chandran S, et al.. ALS-specific cognitive and behavior changes associated with advancing disease stage in ALS. Neurology. 2018;91:e1370&#x2013;e8080.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6177274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30209236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandstedt P, Littorin S, Johansson S, Gottberg K, Ytterberg C, Kierkegaard M. Disability and Contextual Factors in Patients with Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis - A Three-Year Observational Study. J Neuromuscul Dis. 2018;5:439&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6218138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30282373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Logroscino G, Traynor BJ, Hardiman O, Chio A, Mitchell D, Swingler RJ, et al.. Incidence of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in Europe. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2010;81:385&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2850819</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19710046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longinetti E, Fang F. Epidemiology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: An update of recent literature. Curr Opin Neurol. 2019;32:771&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6735526</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31361627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moura MC, Novaes MR, Eduardo EJ, Zago YS, Freitas Rdel N, Casulari LA. Prognostic Factors in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis: A Population-Based Study. PLoS One. 2015;10:e0141500.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4627754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26517122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiernan MC, Vucic S, Cheah BC, Turner MR, Eisen A, Hardiman O, et al.. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet. 2011;377:942&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21296405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pupillo E, Messina P, Logroscino G, Beghi E. Long-term survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A population-based study. Ann Neurol. 2014;75:287&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24382602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lavernhe S, Antoine JC, Court-Fortune I, Dimier N, Costes F, Lacour A, et al.. Home care organization impacts patient management and survival in ALS. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2017;18:562&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28585472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen PM, Abrahams S, Borasio GD, de Carvalho M, Chio A, Van Damme P, et al.. EFNS guidelines on the Clinical Management of Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis (MALS) - revised report of an EFNS task force. Eur J Neurol. 2012;19:360&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21914052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller RG, Jackson CE, Kasarskis EJ, England JD, Forshew D, Johnston W, et al.. Practice parameter update: The care of the patient with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Drug, nutritional, and respiratory therapies (an evidence-based review): Report of the Quality Standards Subcommittee of the American Academy of Neurology. Neurology. 2009;73:1218&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2764727</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19822872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Groot IJ, Post MW, Van Heuveln T, Van Den Berg LH, Lindeman E. Measurement of decline of functioning in persons with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Responsiveness and possible applications of the Functional Independence Measure, Barthel Index, Rehabilitation Activities Profile and Frenchay Activities Index. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2006;7:167&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16963406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Groenestijn AC, Schr&#xf6;der CD, Kruitwagen-Van Reenen ET, Van Den Berg LH, Visser-Meily JMA. Participation restrictions in ambulatory amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients: Physical and psychological factors. Muscle Nerve. 2017;56:912&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28073181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandstedt P, Johansson S, Ytterberg C, Ingre C, Holmqvist LW, Kierkegaard M. Predictors of health-related quality of life in people with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Sci. 2016;370:269&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27772773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandstedt P, Littorin S, Crode Widsell G, Johansson S, Gottberg K, Ytterberg C, et al.. Caregiver experience, health-related quality of life and life satisfaction among informal caregivers to patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A cross-sectional study. J Clin Nurs. 2018;27:4321&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29964322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gladman M, Zinman L. The economic impact of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A systematic review. Expert Rev Pharmacoecon Outcomes Res. 2015;15:439&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25924979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore A, Young CA, Hughes DA. Health Utilities and Costs for Motor Neurone Disease. Value Health. 2019;22:1257&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31708062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song H, Liu JC, Cao ZP, Luo WJ, Chen JY. Medical cost and healthcare utilization of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in China: A cohort study based on hospital data from 2015 to 2018. Medicine (Baltimore). 2020;99:e23258.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7676534</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33217848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zwicker J, Qureshi D, Talarico R, Bourque P, Scott M, Chin-Yee N, et al.. Dying of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Health care use and cost in the last year of life. Neurology. 2019;93:e2083&#x2013;e93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31672715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maetens A, Deliens L, De Bleecker J, Caraceni A, De Ridder M, Beernaert K, et al.. Healthcare utilization at the end of life in people dying from amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A retrospective cohort study using linked administrative data. J Neurol Sci. 2019;406:116444.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31520967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foley G, Timonen V, Hardiman O. Experience of services as a key outcome in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) care: The case for a better understanding of patient experiences. Am J Hosp Palliat Care. 2012;29:362&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21998444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foley G, Timonen V, Hardiman O. Patients&#x2019; perceptions of services and preferences for care in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A review. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2012;13:11&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21879834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, Miller RG, Swash M, Munsat TL. El Escorial revisited: Revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord. 2000;1:293&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11464847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum JM, Stambler N, Malta E, Fuller C, Hilt D, Thurmond B, et al.. The ALSFRS-R: A revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. BDNF ALS Study Group (Phase III). J Neurol Sci. 1999;169:13&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10540002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forsberg A, de Pedro-Cuesta J, Wid&#xe9;n Holmqvist L. Use of healthcare, patient satisfaction and burden of care in Guillain-Barre syndrome. J Rehabil Med. 2006;38:230&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16801205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gottberg K, Einarsson U, Ytterberg C, Fredrikson S, von Koch L, Holmqvist LW. Use of health care services and satisfaction with care in people with multiple sclerosis in Stockholm County: A population-based study. Mult Scler. 2008;14:962&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18573818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chruzander C, Johansson S, Gottberg K, Einarsson U, Hillert J, Holmqvist LW, et al.. A 10-year population-based study of people with multiple sclerosis in Stockholm, Sweden: Use of and satisfaction with care and the value of different factors in predicting use of care. BMC Health Serv Res. 2015;15:480.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4619569</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26499940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ware JE Jr, Snyder MK, Wright WR, Davies AR. Defining and measuring patient satisfaction with medical care. Eval Program Plann. 1983;6:247&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10267253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minet LR, Peterson E, von Koch L, Ytterberg C. Healthcare Utilization After Stroke: A 1-Year Prospective Study. J Am Med Dir Assoc. 2020;21:1684&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32669239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gottberg K, Ytterberg C, Sandstedt P, Johansson S, Kierkegaard M. Experiences of next of kin to patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis using invasive ventilation via tracheostomy. Disabil Rehabil. 20191&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31847618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foley G, Timonen V, Hardiman O. Acceptance and decision making in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis from a life-course perspective. Qual Health Res. 2014;24:67&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24336481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Brien MR, Whitehead B, Murphy PN, Mitchell JD, Jack BA. Social services homecare for people with motor neurone disease/amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Why are such services used or refused? Palliat Med 2012;26:123&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21383059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foley G, Timonen V, Hardiman O. Exerting control and adapting to loss in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Soc Sci Med. 2014;101:113&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24560231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke T, Galvin M, Pinto-Grau M, Lonergan K, Madden C, Mays I, et al.. Caregivers of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Investigating quality of life, caregiver burden, service engagement, and patient survival. J Neurol. 2017;264:898&#x2013;904.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28280986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller RG, Jackson CE, Kasarskis EJ, England JD, Forshew D, Johnston W, et al.. Practice parameter update: The care of the patient with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Multidisciplinary care, symptom management, and cognitive/behavioral impairment (an evidence-based review): Report of the Quality Standards Subcommittee of the American Academy of Neurology. Neurology. 2009;73:1227&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2764728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19822873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hesselink G, Flink M, Olsson M, Barach P, Dudzik-Urbaniak E, Orrego C, et al.. Are patients discharged with care? A qualitative study of perceptions and experiences of patients, family members and care providers. BMJ Qual Saf. 2012;21(Suppl 1):i39&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23118410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verhaegh KJ, Jepma P, Geerlings SE, de Rooij SE, Buurman BM. Not feeling ready to go home: A qualitative analysis of chronically ill patients&#x2019; perceptions on care transitions. Int J Qual Health Care. 2019;31:125&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29939276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janssens AIWA, Ruytings M, Al-Chalabi A, Chio A, Hardiman O, McDermott CJ, et al.. A mapping review of international guidance on the management and care of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2016;17:325&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27078045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown JB. User, carer and professional experiences of care in motor neurone disease. Prim Health Care Res Devel. 2003;4:207&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hugel H, Grundy N, Rigby S, Young CA. How does current care practice influence the experience of a new diagnosis of motor neuron disease? A qualitative study of current guidelines-based practice. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2006;7:161&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16963405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
The Swedish Agency for Health and Care Services Analyses. Patient-centeredness in Sweden&#x2019;s health system-an external assessment and six steps for progress. https://www.vardanalys.se/rapporter/patient-centeredness-in-swedens-health-system/2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekman I, Swedberg K, Taft C, Lindseth A, Norberg A, Brink E, et al.. Person-centered care&#x2013;ready for prime time. Eur J Cardiovasc Nurs. 2011;10:248&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21764386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Institute of Medicine Committee on Quality of Health Care in A. Crossing the Quality Chasm: A New Health System for the 21st Century.Washington (DC): National Academies Press (US); 2001. pp. 39&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howard I, Potts A. Interprofessional Care for Neuromuscular Disease. Current treatment options in neurology. 2019;21:35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31264031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Teijlingen ER, Friend E, Kamal AD. Service use and needs of people with motor neurone disease and their carers in Scotland. Health Soc Care Community. 2001;9:397&#x2013;403.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11846819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes RA, Sinha A, Higginson I, Down K, Leigh PN. Living with motor neurone disease: Lives, experiences of services and suggestions for change. Health Soc Care Community. 2005;13:64&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15717908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kristjanson LJ, Aoun SM, Yates P. Are supportive services meeting the needs of Australians with neurodegenerative conditions and their families? J Palliat Care. 2006;22:151&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17058753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>