<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">34054018</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1546-4156</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>35</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><MedlineDate>2021 Oct-Dec 01</MedlineDate></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Alzheimer disease and associated disorders</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Alzheimer Dis Assoc Disord</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Patient and Relative Experiences and Decision-making About Genetic Testing and Counseling for Familial ALS and FTD: A Systematic Scoping Review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>374</StartPage><EndPage>385</EndPage><MedlinePgn>374-385</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/WAD.0000000000000458</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Genetic testing and counseling is an emerging part of care for patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) and frontotemporal dementia (FTD) and their families. This scoping review aimed to map patients' and relatives' experiences of genetic testing and counseling for familial ALS and FTD and the factors influencing their decision to proceed with testing or counseling. Informed by the Joanna Briggs Institute methodology, 5 databases were systematically searched. Thirty studies from 39 references were included. A descriptive numerical summary analysis and narrative synthesis was conducted. Mostly positive diagnostic testing experiences were reported, but issues arose due to progressive disease and discordant results. Predictive testing impacted at-risk relatives, regardless of the result received, and psychosocial sequelae ranged from relief to guilt, worry or contemplating suicide. Four reproductive testing experiences were reported. Personal, familial and practical factors, and the lived experience of disease, informed decision-making. Greater uncertainty and complexity may be faced in familial ALS/FTD than in other late-onset neurodegenerative diseases due to clinical and genetic heterogeneity, and testing limitations. Genetic counseling models of care should consider this difference to ensure that individuals with, or at risk of, ALS/FTD are effectively managed. Implications for research and practice are discussed.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2021 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Crook</LastName><ForeName>Ashley</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate School of Health, University of Technology Sydney, Chippendale.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Science, Centre for MND Research.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Medicine, Faculty of Medicine and Health Sciences, Macquarie University, Sydney, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jacobs</LastName><ForeName>Chris</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate School of Health, University of Technology Sydney, Chippendale.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Newton-John</LastName><ForeName>Toby</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate School of Health, University of Technology Sydney, Chippendale.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Richardson</LastName><ForeName>Ebony</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate School of Health, University of Technology Sydney, Chippendale.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McEwen</LastName><ForeName>Alison</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate School of Health, University of Technology Sydney, Chippendale.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Alzheimer Dis Assoc Disord</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8704771</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0893-0341</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003376" MajorTopicYN="N">Counseling</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Frontotemporal Dementia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005817" MajorTopicYN="N">Genetic Counseling</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005820" MajorTopicYN="N">Genetic Testing</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>A.C. received funding for this project from the University of Technology Sydney Chancellors Research scholarship. The remaining authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>57</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34054018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/WAD.0000000000000458</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00002093-202110000-00015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Turner MR, Al-Chalabi A, Chio A, et al. Genetic screening in sporadic ALS and FTD. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2017;88:1042&#x2013;1044.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Resta R, Biesecker BB, Bennett RL, et al. A New Definition of Genetic Counseling: National Society of Genetic Counselors&#x2019; Task Force Report. J Genet Couns. 2006;15:77&#x2013;83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohn-Hokke PE, Elting MW, Pijnenburg YA, et al. Genetics of dementia: update and guidelines for the clinician. Am J Med Genet Part B Neuropsychiatr Genet. 2012;159 B:628&#x2013;643.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2; A, Battistini S, Calvo A, et al. Genetic counselling in ALS: facts, uncertainties and clinical suggestions. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2014;85:478&#x2013;485.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roggenbuck J, Quick A, Kolb SJ. Genetic testing and genetic counseling for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: an update for clinicians. Genet Med. 2017;19:267&#x2013;274.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagner KN, Nagaraja HN, Allain DC, et al. Patients with sporadic and familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis found value in genetic testing. Mol Genet Genomic Med. 2018;6:224&#x2013;229.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roggenbuck J, Fong JC. Genetic testing for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal dementia: impact on clinical management. Clin Lab Med. 2020;40:271&#x2013;287.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dobson-Stone C, Hallupp M, Bartley L, et al. C9ORF72 repeat expansion in clinical and neuropathologic frontotemporal dementia cohorts. Neurology. 2012;79:995&#x2013;1001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCann EP, Williams KL, Fifita JA, et al. The genotype-phenotype landscape of familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in Australia. Clin Genet. 2017;92:259&#x2013;266.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klepek H, Nagaraja H, Goutman SA, et al. Lack of consensus in ALS genetic testing practices and divergent views between ALS clinicians and patients. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2019;20:216&#x2013;221.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagner K, Nagaraja H, Allain D, et al. Patients with ALS find value in genetic testing. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2017;18(suppl 2):321&#x2013;322.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagner KN, Nagaraja H, Allain DC, et al. Patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis have high interest in and limited access to genetic testing. J Genet Couns. 2017;26:604&#x2013;611.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taiwo TO, Okeke JU. Genetic testing among frontotemporal lobar degeneration (FTLD) patients: a rarity or the norm? Alzheimers Dement. 2018;14(suppl):P1109&#x2013;P1110.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marin B, Beghi E, Vial C, et al. Evaluation of the application of the European guidelines for the diagnosis and clinical care of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) patients in six French ALS centres. Eur J Neurol. 2016;23:787&#x2013;795.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riedijk SR, Niermeijer MFN, Dooijes D, et al. A decade of genetic counseling in frontotemporal dementia affected families: few counseling requests and much familial opposition to testing. J Genet Couns. 2009;18:350&#x2013;356.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steinbart EJ, Smith CO, Poorkaj P, et al. Impact of DNA testing for early-onset familial Alzheimer disease and frontotemporal dementia. Arch Neurol. 2001;58:1828&#x2013;1831.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benatar M, Polak M, Kaplan S, et al. Preventing familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: is a clinical trial feasible? J Neurol Sci. 2006;251:3&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Eijk RP, Nikolakopoulos S, Veldink JH, et al. Platform communications: C21 Hurdles for pharmacogenetic interactions in ALS clinical trials: a post-hoc analysis and simulation study. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2018;19(supp1):1&#x2013;84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCampbell A, Cole T, Wegener AJ, et al. Antisense oligonucleotides extend survival and reverse decrement in muscle response in ALS models. J Clin Invest. 2018;128:3558&#x2013;3567.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ly CV, Miller TM. Emerging antisense oligonucleotide and viral therapies for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Curr Opin Neurol. 2018;31:648&#x2013;654.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Joanna Briggs Institute Aromataris E. Methodology for JBI Scoping Reviews. Joanna Briggs Institute Reviewers&#x2019; Manual: 2015 Edition/Supplement. South Australia, Australia: The Joanna Briggs Institute; 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosen DR, Siddique T, Patterson D, et al. Mutations in Cu/Zn superoxide dismutase gene are associated with familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nature. 1993;362:59&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moher D, Liberati A, Tetzlaff J, et al. Preferred reporting items for systematic reviews and meta-analyses: the PRISMA statement. Ann Intern Med. 2009;151:264&#x2013;269.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McHugh ML. Interrater reliability: the kappa statistic. Biochem Med (Zagreb). 2012;22:276&#x2013;282.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byrt T, Bishop J, Carlin JB. Bias, prevalence and kappa. J Clin Epidemiol. 1993;46:423&#x2013;429.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levac D, Colquhoun H, O&#x2019;Brien KK. Scoping studies: Advancing the methodology. Implement Sci. 2010;5:69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arksey H, O&#x2019;Malley L. Scoping studies: towards a methodological framework. Int J Soc Res Methodol. 2005;8:19&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crook A, Hogden A, Mumford V, et al. The patient experience of familial motor neurone disease: a qualitative study. Twin Res Hum Genet. 2017;20:461.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartzfeld DEH, Siddique N, Victorson D, et al. Reproductive decision-making among individuals at risk for familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2015;16:114&#x2013;119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holley D, Siddique N, Victorson D, et al. Decision-making about reproductive choices among individuals at risk for familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in families with a known genetic mutation. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2012;13(suppl 1):21&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dayani LB. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis: Attitudes, Perceptions and Experiences of Individuals With ALS Towards Genetic Testing [MS]. Ann Arbor: University of California; 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fanos JH, Gelinas DF, Miller RG. &#x201c;You have shown me my end&#x201d;: attitudes toward presymptomatic testing for familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Am J Med Genet. 2004;129A:248&#x2013;253.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fanos JH, Gronka S, Wuu J, et al. Impact of presymptomatic genetic testing for familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Genet Med. 2011;13:342&#x2013;348.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crook A, Hogden A, Mumford V, et al. Genetic testing for familial motor neurone disease (MND): insights and challenges. Twin Res Hum Genet. 2019;22:342.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crook A, Hogden A, Mumford V, et al. Genetic testing for familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS): insights and challenges. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2019;20(suppl 1):327.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crook A, Hogden A, Mumford V, et al. Facing the challenges of genetic testing: family member experiences. Int J Qual Health Care. 2018;30(suppl 2):50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crook A, Mumford V, Hogden A, et al. Preventing amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) through reproductive genetic testing: Costs and complexities. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2019;20(suppl 1):327&#x2013;328.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crook A, McEwen A, Fifita JA, et al. The C9orf72 hexanucleotide repeat expansion presents a challenge for testing laboratories and genetic counseling. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2019;20:310&#x2013;316.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee O, Porteous M. Genetic testing and reproductive choice in neurological disorders. Pract Neurol. 2017;17:275&#x2013;281.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandich P, Mantero V, Verdiani S, et al. Complexities of genetic counseling for ALS: a case of two siblings with discordant genetic test results. J Genet Couns. 2015;24:553&#x2013;557.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith AL, Teener JW, Callaghan BC, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in a patient with a family history of huntington disease: Genetic counseling challenges. J Genet Couns. 2014;23:725&#x2013;733.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benatar M, Wuu J. Presymptomatic studies in ALS: rationale, challenges, and approach. Neurology. 2012;79:1732&#x2013;1739.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benatar M, Stanislaw C, Reyes E, et al. Presymptomatic ALS genetic counseling and testing: experience and recommendations. Neurology. 2016;86:2295&#x2013;2302.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hodgkinson-Brechenmacher V, Salman A, Lounsberry J, et al. Access to care for ALS patients in Canada: findings from the canadian ceuromuscular disease registry. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2018;19(suppl 1):369&#x2013;370.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Surampalli A, Khare M, Kubrussi G, et al. Psychological impact of predictive genetic testing in VCP inclusion body myopathy, Paget disease of bone and frontotemporal dementia. J Genet Couns. 2015;24:842&#x2013;850.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McRae CA, Diem G, Yamazaki TG, et al. Interest in genetic testing in pallido-ponto-nigral degeneration (PPND): a family with frontotemporal dementia with Parkinsonism linked to chromosome 17. Eur J Neurol. 2001;8:179&#x2013;183.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tibben A, Stevens M, de Wert GM, et al. Preparing for presymptomatic DNA testing for early onset Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease/cerebral haemorrhage and hereditary Pick disease. J Med Genet. 1997;34:63&#x2013;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greaves CV, Moore KM, Shafei R, et al. Depression and anxiety in the &#x2018;at-risk&#x2019; phase of familial frontotemporal dementia. Alzheimers Dement. 2019;15(suppl):P859&#x2013;P860.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldman JS, Adamson J, Karydas A, et al. New genes, new dilemmas: FTLD genetics and its implications for families. Am J Alzheimers Dis Other Demen. 2007;22:507&#x2013;515.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Molinuevo JL, Pintor L, Peri JM, et al. Emotional reactions to predictive testing in Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease and other inherited dementias. Am J Alzheimers Dis Other Demen. 2005;20:233&#x2013;238.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williamson J, LaRusse S. Genetics and genetic counseling: Recommendations for Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease, frontotemporal dementia, and Creutzfeldt-Jakob disease. Curr Neurol Neurosci Rep. 2004;4:351&#x2013;357.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldman JS, Farmer JM, Van Deerlin VM, et al. Frontotemporal dementia: genetics and genetic counseling dilemmas. Neurologist. 2004;10:227&#x2013;234.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sexton A, Taylor J, Higgs E, et al. Issues of consent in genetic testing for dementia: four case examples. Twin Res Hum Genet. 2017;20:474.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fostinelli S, Ciani M, Zanardini R, et al. The heritability of frontotemporal lobar degeneration: validation of pedigree classification criteria in a Northern Italy cohort. J Alzheimers Dis. 2018;61:753&#x2013;760.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crook A, Jacobs C, Newton-John T, et al. Familial MND and FTD: identifying the need for a new genetic counseling model of care. Twin Res Hum Genet. 2019;22:360.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fong JC, Karydas AM, Goldman JS. Genetic counseling for FTD/ALS caused by the C9ORF72 hexanucleotide expansion. Alzheimers Res Ther. 2012;4:27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldman JS, Huey ED, Thorne DZ. The confluence of psychiatric symptoms and neurodegenerative disease: Impact on genetic counseling. J Genet Couns. 2017;26:435&#x2013;441.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mantero V, Tarlarini C, Aliprandi A, et al. Genetic counseling dilemmas for a patient with sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, frontotemporal degeneration &amp; Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. J Genet Couns. 2017;26:442&#x2013;446.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Craufurd D, MacLeod R, Frontali M, et al. Diagnostic genetic testing for Huntington&#x2019;s disease. Pract Neurol. 2015;15:80&#x2013;84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klitzman R, Thorne D, Williamson J, et al. The roles of family members, health care workers, and others in decision-making processes about genetic testing among individuals at risk for Huntington disease. Genet Med. 2007;9:358&#x2013;371.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canosa A, Grassano M, Barberis M, et al. A familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis pedigree discordant for a novel p.Glu46Asp heterozygous OPTN variant and the p.Ala5Val heterozygous SOD1 missense mutation. J Clin Neurosci. 2020;75:223&#x2013;225.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang M, Xi Z, Misquitta K, et al. C9orf72 and ATXN2 repeat expansions coexist in a family with ataxia, dementia, and parkinsonism. Mov Disord. 2017;32:158&#x2013;162.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henegan P, Chysna K, Essad K, et al. Two mutations, one family: C9orf72 and SQSTM1 in neurodegenerative diseases. J Neurol Sci. 2019;405:116420.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Blitterswijk M, van Es MA, Hennekam EA, et al. Evidence for an oligogenic basis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Hum Mol Genet. 2012;21:3776&#x2013;3784.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCann EP, Henden L, Fifita JA, et al. Evidence for polygenic and oligogenic basis of Australian sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Med Genet. 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corrado L, Pensato V, Croce R, et al. The first case of the TARDBP p.G294V mutation in a homozygous state: is a single pathogenic allele sufficient to cause ALS? Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2020;21:273&#x2013;279.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Domoto&#x2010;Reilly K, Davis MY, Keene CD, et al. Unusually long duration and delayed penetrance in a family with FTD and mutation in MAPT (V337M). Am J Med Genet B Neuropsychiatr Genet. 2017;174:70&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foxe D, Elan E, Burrell JR, et al. Intrafamilial phenotypic variability in the C9orf72 gene expansion: 2 case studies. Front Psychol. 2018;9:1615.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Snowden JS, Adams J, Harris J, et al. Distinct clinical and pathological phenotypes in frontotemporal dementia associated with MAPT, PGRN and C9orf72 mutations. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2015;16:497&#x2013;505.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almqvist EW, Bloch M, Brinkman R, et al. A Worldwide Assessment of the Frequency of Suicide, Suicide Attempts, or Psychiatric Hospitalization after Predictive Testing for Huntington Disease. Am J Hum Genet. 1999;64:1293&#x2013;1304.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paulsen JS, Nance M, Kim JI, et al. A review of quality of life after predictive testing for and earlier identification of neurodegenerative diseases. Prog Neurobiol. 2013;110:2&#x2013;28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva-Moraes MH, Bispo-Torres AC, Barouh JL, et al. Suicidal behavior in individuals with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a systematic review. J Affect Disord. 2020;277:688&#x2013;696.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zucca M, Rubino E, Vacca A, et al. High risk of suicide in behavioral variant frontotemporal dementia. Am J Alzheimers Dis Other Demen. 2018;34:265&#x2013;271.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paulsen JS, Hoth KF, Nehl C, et al. Critical periods of suicide risk in Huntington&#x2019;s disease. Am J Psychiatry. 2005;162:725&#x2013;731.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devenney EM, Ahmed RM, Halliday G, et al. Psychiatric disorders in C9orf72 kindreds. Neurology. 2018;91:e1498&#x2013;e1507.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Synofzik M, Biskup S, Leyhe T, et al. Suicide attempt as the presenting symptom of C9orf72 dementia. Am J Psychiatry. 2012;169:1211&#x2013;1213.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacLeod R, Tibben A, Frontali M, et al. Recommendations for the predictive genetic test in Huntington&#x2019;s disease. Clin Genet. 2013;83:221&#x2013;231.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corcia P, Lumbroso S, Cazeneuve C, et al. Pre-symptomatic diagnosis in ALS. Rev Neurol (Paris). 2020;176:166&#x2013;169.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tiller&#xe5;s KH, Kjoelaas SH, Dramstad E, et al. Psychological reactions to predictive genetic testing for Huntington&#x2019;s disease: A qualitative study. J Genet Couns. 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhoads S, Rakes AL. Telehealth technology: reducing barriers for rural residents seeking genetic counseling. J Am Assoc Nurse Pract. 2020;32:190&#x2013;192.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hawkins AK, Creighton S, Ho A, et al. Providing predictive testing for Huntington disease via telehealth: results of a pilot study in British Columbia, Canada. Clin Genet. 2013;84:60&#x2013;64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stopford C, Ferrer-Duch M, Moldovan R, et al. Improving follow up after predictive testing in Huntington&#x2019;s disease: evaluating a genetic counselling narrative group session. J Community Genet. 2020;11:47&#x2013;58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson KE, Eberly S, Marder KS, et al. The choice not to undergo genetic testing for Huntington disease: results from the PHAROS study. Clin Genet. 2019;96:28&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paneque M, Felix J, Mendes A, et al. Twenty years of a pre-symptomatic testing protocol for late-onset neurological diseases in Portugal. Acta Med Port. 2019;32:295&#x2013;304.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>White S, Jacobs C, Phillips J. Mainstreaming genetics and genomics: a systematic review of the barriers and facilitators for nurses and physicians in secondary and tertiary care. Genet Med. 2020;22:1149&#x2013;1155.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vajda A, McLaughlin RL, Heverin M, et al. Genetic testing in ALS: A survey of current practices. Neurology. 2017;88:991&#x2013;999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Rij MC, De Rademaeker M, Moutou C, et al. Preimplantation genetic diagnosis (PGD) for Huntington&#x2019;s disease: the experience of three European centres. Eur J Hum Genet. 2012;20:368&#x2013;375.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klitzman R, Thorne D, Williamson J, et al. Decision-making about reproductive choices among individuals at-risk for Huntington&#x2019;s disease. J Genet Couns. 2007;16:347&#x2013;362.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Rij MC, de Die-Smulders CEM, Bijlsma EK, et al. Evaluation of exclusion prenatal and exclusion preimplantation genetic diagnosis for Huntington&#x2019;s disease in the Netherlands. Clin Genet. 2013;83:118&#x2013;124.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halpin M. Science and suffering: genetics and the lived experience of illness. Soc Probl. 2017;65:360&#x2013;376.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldman JS. Predictive genetic counseling for neurodegenerative diseases: past, present, and future. Cold Spring Harb Perspect Med. 2020;10:a036525.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogers K, Coleman H, Brodtmann A, et al. Family members&#x2019; experience of the pre-diagnostic phase of dementia: a synthesis of qualitative evidence. Int Psychogeriatr. 2017;29:1425&#x2013;1437.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weisser FB, Bristowe K, Jackson D. Experiences of burden, needs, rewards and resilience in family caregivers of people living with Motor Neurone Disease/Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis: A secondary thematic analysis of qualitative interviews. Palliat Med. 2015;29:737&#x2013;745.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gentry MT, Lapid MI, Syrjanen J, et al. Quality of life and caregiver burden in familial frontotemporal lobar degeneration: Analyses of symptomatic and asymptomatic individuals within the LEFFTDS cohort. Alzheimers Dement. 2020;16:1115&#x2013;1124.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barca ML, Thorsen K, Engedal K, et al. Nobody asked me how I felt: experiences of adult children of persons with young-onset dementia. Int Psychogeriatr. 2014;26:1935&#x2013;1944.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hawkins Virani AKH, Creighton SM, et al. Developing a comprehensive, effective patient-friendly website to enhance decision making in predictive testing for Huntington disease. Genet Med. 2013;15:466&#x2013;472.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ormond KE, Laurino MY, Barlow&#x2010;Stewart K, et al. Genetic counseling globally: Where are we now? Am J Med Genet C Semin Med Genet. 2018;178:98&#x2013;107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byrne S, Bede P, Elamin M, et al. Proposed criteria for familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2011;12:157&#x2013;159.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byrne S, Elamin M, Bede P, et al. Absence of consensus in diagnostic criteria for familial neurodegenerative diseases. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2012;83:365&#x2013;367.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wood EM, Falcone D, Suh E, et al. Development and validation of pedigree classification criteria for frontotemporal lobar degeneration. JAMA Neurol. 2013;70:1411&#x2013;1417.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>