<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">34076273</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>28</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-4598</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>64</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Muscle &amp; nerve</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Muscle Nerve</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>ALS patient and caregiver attitudes toward physician-hastened death in California.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>428</StartPage><EndPage>434</EndPage><MedlinePgn>428-434</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/mus.27343</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION/AIMS" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Since 2016, six states have legalized physician-hastened death (PHD). Neuromuscular disorders, including amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS), are common diagnoses for patients who use PHD, but how patients with ALS view PHD in California has not been systematically studied. We aimed to quantify how many patients with ALS and their caregivers have considered PHD and to assess reasons to consider using or not using it.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This is a cross-sectional study at one ALS center surveying patients with ALS and their caregivers. Data on disease characteristics, demographics, quality of life, and depression were also collected. Descriptive statistics were used to analyze the data. Qualitative data were also collected and analyzed. Patients were followed up longitudinally to assess if they died or if they used PHD.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A small majority of ALS patients surveyed had considered or would consider using PHD (16/30). Patients most commonly described having intolerable symptoms, being a burden on their loved ones, and losing independence as reasons to consider using PHD. Many patients shared that "their life has purpose" and "they are making the most of their lives" as to why they are not considering PHD. Considering PHD was not related to disease severity or depression. On longitudinal follow-up, 10 of the 30 patients have died, and none have used PHD.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Pursuing PHD is a personal decision for each individual patient. This study shows that considering PHD is relatively common in ALS patients, independent of disease severity or presence of depression.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hauswirth</LastName><ForeName>Anna G</ForeName><Initials>AG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of California, San Francisco, School of Medicine, San Francisco, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine Department, Kaiser San Francisco, San Francisco, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>George</LastName><ForeName>Hannah C</ForeName><Initials>HC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of California, San Francisco, San Francisco, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lomen-Hoerth</LastName><ForeName>Catherine</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of California, San Francisco, San Francisco, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>T32 GM007618</GrantID><Acronym>GM</Acronym><Agency>NIGMS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Muscle Nerve</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7803146</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0148-639X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000223" MajorTopicYN="N">Adaptation, Psychological</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000369" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged, 80 and over</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="Y">psychology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002140" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">California</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017028" MajorTopicYN="N">Caregivers</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="Y">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003430" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Sectional Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007722" MajorTopicYN="Y">Health Knowledge, Attitudes, Practice</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010358" MajorTopicYN="N">Patient Participation</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="Y">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010819" MajorTopicYN="N">Physician's Role</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="Y">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017236" MajorTopicYN="N">Suicide, Assisted</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="Y">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ALS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">disease severity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ethics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">palliative care</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physician-hastened death</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34076273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.27343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Oregon Death with Dignity Act. Oregon, USA; 1997.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Act 39, Vermont Patient Choice and Control at the End of Life Act. Vermont, USA; 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Washington Death with Dignity Act. Washington, USA; 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>End of Life Option Act. California, USA; 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>End of Life Options Act. Colorado, USA; 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The D.C. Death with Dignity Act. Washington, DC, USA; 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Our Care, Our Choice Act. Hawaii, USA; 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maine Death with Dignity Act. Maine, USA; 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aid in Dying for the Terminally Ill Act. New Jersey, USA; 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen HQ, Gelman EJ, Bush TA, Lee JS, Kanter MH. Characterizing Kaiser Permanente Southern California's experience with the California end of life option act in the first year of implementation. JAMA Intern Med. 2018;178:417-421.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blanke C, LeBlanc M, Hershman D, Ellis L, Meyskens F. Characterizing 18&#x2009;years of the death with dignity act in Oregon. JAMA Oncol. 2017;3:1403-1406.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al Rabadi L, Leblanc M, Bucy T, et al. Trends in medical aid in dying in Oregon and Washington. JAMA Netw Open. 2019;2:e198648.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang LH, Elliott MA, Jung Henson L, et al. Death with dignity in Washington patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology. 2016;87:2117-2122.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Albert SM, Rabkin JG, Del Bene ML, et al. Wish to die in end-stage ALS. Neurology. 2005;65:68-74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stutzki R, Schneider U, Reiter-Theil S, Weber M. Attitudes toward assisted suicide and life-prolonging measures in Swiss ALS patients and their caregivers. Front Psychol. 2012;3:2008-2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xfc;hnlein P, K&#xfc;bler A, Raubold S, et al. Palliative care and circumstances of dying in German ALS patients using non-invasive ventilation. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2008;9:91-98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ganzini L, Johnston WS, McFarland BH, Tolle SW, Lee MA. Attitudes of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and their care givers toward assisted suicide. N Engl J Med. 1998;339:967-973.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maessen M, Veldink JH, Onwuteaka-Philipsen BD, et al. Trends and determinants of end-of-life practices in ALS in The Netherlands. Neurology. 2009;73:954-961.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ganzini L, Silveira MJ, Johnston WS. Predictors and correlates of interest in assisted suicide in the final month of life among ALS patients in Oregon and Washington. J Pain Symptom Manage. 2002;24:312-317.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strong MJ, Abrahams S, Goldstein LH, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis - frontotemporal spectrum disorder (ALS-FTSD): revised diagnostic criteria. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Front Degener. 2017;18:153-174.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum JM, Stambler N, Malta E, et al. The ALSFRS-R: a revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. BDNF ALS study group (phase III). J Neurol Sci. 1999;169:13-21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Idler EL. Religious involvement and the health of the elderly: some hypotheses and an initial test. Social Forces. 1987;66:226-238.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smarr KL. Measures of depression and depressive symptoms the Beck Depression Inventory (BDI), Center for Epidemiological Studies-Depression Scale (CES-D), Geriatric Depression Scale (GDS), Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale (HADS), and Primary Care Evaluation of Mental Disorders-Mood Module (PRIME-MD). Arthritis Care Res. 2003;63:S454-466.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palliative Care Quality Network [online]. https://pcqn.org/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maessen M, Veldink JH, Onwuteaka-Philipsen BD, et al. Euthanasia and physician-assisted suicide in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a prospective study. J Neurol. 2014;261:1894-1901.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ganzini L, Goy ER, Dobscha SK. Oregonians&#x2019; reasons for requesting physician aid in dying. Arch Intern Med. 2009;169:489-492.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ganzini L, Gov ER, Dobscha SK. Prevalence of depression and anxiety in patients requesting physicians&#x2019; aid in dying: cross sectional survey. BMJ. 2008;337:973-975.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ganzini L, Beer TM, Brouns M, Mori M, Hsieh YC. Interest in physician-assisted suicide among Oregon cancer patients. J Clin Ethics. 2006;17:27-38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson KG, Scott JF, Graham ID, et al. Attitudes of terminally ill patients toward euthanasia and physician-assisted suicide. Arch Intern Med. 2000;160:2454-2460.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emanuel EJ, Fairclough DL, Daniels ER, Clarridge BR. Euthanasia and physician-assisted suicide: attitudes and experiences of oncology patients, oncologists, and the public. Lancet. 1996;347:1805-1810.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raheja D, Stephens HE, Lehman E, Walsh S, Yang C, Simmons Z. Patient-reported problematic symptoms in an ALS treatment trial. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Front Degener. 2016;17:198-205.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallace VCJ, Ellis CM, Burman R, Knights C, Shaw CE, Al-Chalabi A. The evaluation of pain in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a case controlled observational study. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Front Degener. 2014;15:520-527.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanisch F, Skudlarek A, Berndt J, Kornhuber ME. Characteristics of pain in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain Behav. 2015;5:e00296.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walsh SM, Bremer BA, Felgoise SH, Simmons Z. Religiousness is related to quality of life in patients with ALS. Neurology. 2003;60:1527-1529.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bremer BA, Simone AL, Walsh S, Simmons Z, Felgoise SH. Factors supporting quality of life over time for individuals with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: the role of positive self-perception and religiosity. Ann Behav Med. 2004;28:119-125.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lul&#xe9; D, Ehlich B, Lang D, et al. Quality of life in fatal disease: the flawed judgement of the social environment. J Neurol. 2013;260:2836-2843.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stutzki R, Weber M, Reiter-Theil S, Simmen U, Borasio GD, Jox RJ. Attitudes towards hastened death in ALS: a prospective study of patients and family caregivers. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Front Degener. 2014;15:68-76.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>