<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">34076262</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>21</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-4598</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>64</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Muscle &amp; nerve</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Muscle Nerve</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Relative effects of forced vital capacity and ALSFRS-R on survival in ALS.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>346</StartPage><EndPage>351</EndPage><MedlinePgn>346-351</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/mus.27344</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION/AIM">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) is a degenerative neuromuscular disease with marked clinical heterogeneity. This heterogeneity can be partly captured by clinical measures, such as the forced vital capacity (FVC) and ALS Functional Rating Scale-Revised (ALSFRS-R). We aimed to further characterize the performance of these clinical measures, including their independence and additivity, in predicting mortality.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">We leveraged the Pooled Resource Open-Access ALS Clinical Trials (PRO-ACT ALS) database, which includes data from 23 clinical trials (n&#x2009;=&#xa0;2050). The primary exposures were baseline FVC and ALSFRS-R. The primary outcome was 1-y mortality. We performed correlation analyses, survival analyses and assessed classification performance using receiver operator characteristic (ROC) curves.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">FVC and ALSFRS-R were weakly correlated (r&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.31, p&#xa0;&lt;&#x2009;.001). A 1-SD increase in FVC (hazard ratio [HR]: 0.66; 95% confidence interval [CI]: 0.59-0.74) and ALSFRS-R (HR: 0.75; 95% CI: 0.68-0.82) were associated with reduced risk of 1-y mortality. ROC analyses showed optimal predictive cutoffs at 80% for FVC (area under the curve [AUC]: 0.69) and 38 for ALSFRS-R (AUC: 0.67). After stratifying patients based on these cutoffs, we found a marked reduction (HR: 0.25; 95% CI: 0.19-0.33) in incident mortality for patients in the high FVC and high ALSFRS-R group relative to the low FVC and low ALSFRS-R group.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION">ALSFRS-R and FVC are comparable predictors of survival that are only weakly correlated. When considered together, they synergistically predict survival. As such, consideration of both measures should be a routine part of prognostication in care of patients with ALS.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Daghlas</LastName><ForeName>Salah A</ForeName><Initials>SA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Missouri-Columbia, School of Medicine, Columbia, Missouri, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Govindarajan</LastName><ForeName>Raghav</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of Missouri-Columbia, Columbia, Missouri, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><CollectiveName>Pooled Resource Open-Access ALS Clinical Trials Consortium</CollectiveName></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Muscle Nerve</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7803146</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0148-639X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000401" MajorTopicYN="Y">mortality</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018450" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Progression</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015996" MajorTopicYN="N">Survival Rate</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014797" MajorTopicYN="N">Vital Capacity</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ALS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ALSFRS-R</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PRO-ACT</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">forced vital capacity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">survival</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34076262</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.27344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Corcia P, Pradat PF, Salachas F, et al. Causes of death in a post-mortem series of ALS patients. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2008;9:59-62. https://doi.org/10.1080/17482960701656940</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2; A, Logroscino G, Hardiman O, et al. Prognostic factors in ALS: a critical review. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2009;10:310-323. https://doi.org/10.3109/17482960802566824</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown RH, Al-Chalabi A. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. N Engl J Med. 2017;377:162-172. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJMra1603471</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atassi N, Berry J, Shui A, et al. The PRO-ACT database design, initial analyses, and predictive features. Neurology. 2014;83:1719-1725. https://doi.org/10.1212/WNL.0000000000000951</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Czaplinski A, Yen AA, Appel SH. Forced vital capacity (FVC) as an indicator of survival and disease progression in an ALS clinic population. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2006;77:390-392. https://doi.org/10.1136/jnnp.2005.072660</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goyal NA, Berry JD, Windebank A, et al. Addressing heterogeneity in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis CLINICAL TRIALS. Muscle Nerve. 2020;62(2):156-166. https://doi.org/10.1002/mus.26801</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xfc;ffner R, Zach N, Norel R, et al. Crowdsourced analysis of clinical trial data to predict amyotrophic lateral sclerosis progression. Nat Biotechnol. 2015;33:51-57. https://doi.org/10.1038/nbt.3051</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daghlas I, Lever TE, Leary E. A retrospective investigation of the relationship between baseline covariates and rate of ALSFRS-R decline in ALS clinical trials. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Front Degener. 2018;19:206-211. https://doi.org/10.1080/21678421.2017.1418001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kueffner R, Zach N, Bronfeld M, et al. Stratification of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients: a crowdsourcing approach. Sci Rep. 2019;9:1-14. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-018-36873-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baumann F, Henderson RD, Morrison SC, et al. Use of respiratory function tests to predict survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2010;11:194-202. https://doi.org/10.3109/17482960902991773</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum JM, Stambler N, Malta E, et al. The ALSFRS-R: a revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. J Neurol Sci. 1999;169:13-21. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0022-510X(99)00210-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaufmann P, Levy G, Thompson JLP, et al. The ALSFRSr predicts survival time in an ALS clinic population. Neurology. 2005;64:38-43. https://doi.org/10.1212/01.WNL.0000148648.38313.64</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Javad Mousavi S-A, Zamani B, Shahabi Shahmiri S, et al. Pulmonary function tests in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and the association between these tests and survival. Iran J Neurol. 2014;13:131.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitsumoto H, Garofalo DC, Santella RM, et al. Plasma creatinine and oxidative stress biomarkers in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Front Degener. 2020;21:263-272. https://doi.org/10.1080/21678421.2020.1746810</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calvo A, Vasta R, Moglia C, et al. Prognostic role of slow vital capacity in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol. 2020;267:1615-1621. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00415-020-09751-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karanevich AG, Weisbrod LJ, Jawdat O, et al. Using automated electronic medical record data extraction to model ALS survival and progression. BMC Neurol. 2018;18:1-7. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12883-018-1208-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt EP, Drachman DB, Wiener CM, Clawson L, Kimball R, Lechtzin N. Pulmonary predictors of survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: use in clinical trial design. Muscle Nerve. 2006;33:127-132. https://doi.org/10.1002/mus.20450</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paganoni S, Nicholson K, Chan J, et al. Urate levels predict survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: analysis of the expanded pooled resource open-access ALS clinical trials database. Muscle Nerve. 2018;57:430-434. https://doi.org/10.1002/mus.25950</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swinscow TDV. Statistics at square one:correlation and regression. BMJ. 1997;75-84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heagerty PJ, Lumley T, Pepe MS. Time-dependent ROC curves for censored survival data and a diagnostic marker. Biometrics. 2000;56:337-344. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.0006-341X.2000.00337.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Youden WJ. Index for rating diagnostic tests. Cancer. 1950;3:32-35. https://doi.org/10.1002/1097-0142(1950)3:1&lt;32::AID-CNCR2820030106&gt;3.0.CO;2-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fluss R, Faraggi D, Reiser B. Estimation of the Youden index and its associated cutoff point. Biom J. 2005;47:458-472. https://doi.org/10.1002/bimj.200410135</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinto S, de Carvalho M. SVC is a marker of respiratory decline function, similar to FVC, in patients with ALS. Front Neurol. 2019;10:109. https://doi.org/10.3389/fneur.2019.00109</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinto S, de Carvalho M. Correlation between forced vital capacity and slow vital capacity for the assessment of respiratory involvement in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a prospective study. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Front Degener. 2017;18:86-91. https://doi.org/10.1080/21678421.2016.1249486</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pirola A, de Mattia E, Lizio A, et al. The prognostic value of spirometric tests in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. Clin Neurol Neurosurg. 2019;184. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.clineuro.2019.105456</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2; A, Canosa A, Gallo S, et al. ALS clinical trials: do enrolled patients accurately represent the ALS population? Neurology. 2011;77(15):1432-1437. https://doi.org/10.1212/WNL.0b013e318232ab9b</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Eijk RPA, Westeneng HJ, Nikolakopoulos S, et al. Refining eligibility criteria for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis clinical trials. Neurology. 2019;92(5):e451-e460. https://doi.org/10.1212/WNL.0000000000006855</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>