<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">34081813</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>18</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1468-1331</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>28</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Brain activity is contingent on neuropsychological function in a functional magnetic resonance imaging study of verbal working memory in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>3051</StartPage><EndPage>3060</EndPage><MedlinePgn>3051-3060</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/ene.14957</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND PURPOSE">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) is a devastating neurodegenerative disease that causes progressive degeneration of neurons in motor and non-motor brain regions, affecting multiple cognitive domains such as memory. A functional magnetic resonance imaging (fMRI) study was performed to explore working memory function in ALS.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">To contribute to the growing research field that employs structural and functional neuroimaging to investigate the effect of ALS on different working memory components, the localization and intensity of alterations in neural activity was explored using fMRI. Being the first study to specifically address verbal working memory via fMRI in the context of ALS, the verbal n-back task with 0-back and 2-back conditions was employed.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Despite ALS patients showing unimpaired accuracies (p&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.724) and reaction times (p&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.0785), there was significantly increased brain activity of frontotemporal and parietal regions in the 2-back minus 0-back contrast in patients compared to controls (using nonparametric statistics with 5000 permutations and a T threshold of 2.5).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION">Increased brain activity of the frontotemporal and parietal regions during working memory performance was largely associated with better neuropsychological function within the ALS group, suggesting a compensatory effect during working memory execution. This study therefore adds to the current knowledge on neural correlates of working memory in ALS and contributes to a more nuanced understanding of hyperactivity during cognitive processes in fMRI studies of ALS.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 The Authors. European Journal of Neurology published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of European Academy of Neurology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kobeleva</LastName><ForeName>Xenia</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7695-1716</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University Hospital of Bonn, Bonn, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology and Clinical Neurophysiology, Hannover Medical School, Hannover, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Machts</LastName><ForeName>Judith</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Cognitive Neurology and Dementia Research (IKND), Otto-von-Guericke University Magdeburg, Magdeburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Veit</LastName><ForeName>Maria</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Otto-von-Guericke University, Magdeburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Social Psychiatry and Psychotherapy, Hannover Medical School, Hannover, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vielhaber</LastName><ForeName>Stefan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Otto-von-Guericke University, Magdeburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Petri</LastName><ForeName>Susanne</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology and Clinical Neurophysiology, Hannover Medical School, Hannover, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schoenfeld</LastName><ForeName>Mircea Ariel</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Otto-von-Guericke University, Magdeburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kliniken Schmieder, Heidelberg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of behavioral neurology, Leibniz Institute for Neurobiology, Magdeburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9506311</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1351-5101</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001921" MajorTopicYN="N">Brain</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008279" MajorTopicYN="N">Magnetic Resonance Imaging</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008570" MajorTopicYN="N">Memory, Short-Term</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019636" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neurodegenerative Diseases</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009483" MajorTopicYN="N">Neuropsychological Tests</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fMRI</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neuroimaging</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neuropsychology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">working memory</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34081813</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ene.14957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Neumann M, Sampathu DM, Kwong LK, et al. Ubiquitinated TDP-43 in frontotemporal lobar degeneration and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Science. 2006;314:130-133.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeJesus-Hernandez M, Mackenzie IR, Boeve BF, et al. Expanded GGGGCC hexanucleotide repeat in noncoding region of C9ORF72 causes chromosome 9p-linked FTD and ALS. Neuron. 2011;72:245-256.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renton AE, Majounie E, Waite A, et al. A hexanucleotide repeat expansion in C9ORF72 is the cause of chromosome 9p21-linked ALS-FTD. Neuron. 2011;72:257-268.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abrahams S, Goldstein LH, Suckling J, et al. Frontotemporal white matter changes in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol. 2005;252:321-331.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammadi B, Kollewe K, Cole DM, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis affects cortical and subcortical activity underlying motor inhibition and action monitoring. Hum Brain Mapp. 2015;36:2878-2889.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stoppel CM, Vielhaber S, Eckart C, et al. Structural and functional hallmarks of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis progression in motor- and memory-related brain regions. NeuroImage Clin. 2014;5:277-290.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brettschneider J, Del Tredici K, Toledo JB, et al. Stages of pTDP-43 pathology in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol. 2013;74:20-38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ringholz GM, Appel SH, Bradshaw M, Cooke NA, Mosnik DM, Schulz PE. Prevalence and patterns of cognitive impairment in sporadic ALS. Neurology. 2005;65:586-590.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montuschi A, Iazzolino B, Calvo A, et al. Cognitive correlates in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a population-based study in Italy. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2015;86:168-173.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rippon GA, Scarmeas N, Gordon PH, et al. An observational study of cognitive impairment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Arch Neurol. 2006;63:345-352.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phukan J, Elamin M, Bede P, et al. The syndrome of cognitive impairment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a population-based study. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2012;83:102-108.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2; A, Moglia C, Canosa A, et al. Cognitive impairment across ALS clinical stages in a population-based cohort. Neurology. 2019;93:e984-e994.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beeldman E, Raaphorst J, Klein Twennaar M, de Visser M, Schmand BA, de Haan RJ. The cognitive profile of ALS: a systematic review and meta-analysis update. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2016;87:611-619.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Machts J, Bittner V, Kasper E, et al. Memory deficits in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis are not exclusively caused by executive dysfunction: a comparative neuropsychological study of amnestic mild cognitive impairment. BMC Neurosci. 2014;15:83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Girardi A, Macpherson SE, Abrahams S. Deficits in emotional and social cognition in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuropsychology. 2011;25:53-65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elamin M, Phukan J, Bede P, et al. Executive dysfunction is a negative prognostic indicator in patients with ALS without dementia. Neurology. 2011;76:1263-1269.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen C, Caga J, Mahoney CJ, Kiernan MC, Huynh W. Behavioural changes predict poorer survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain Cogn. 2021;150:105710.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baddeley AD. Working memory. Philos Trans R Soc B Biol Sci. 1983;302:311-324.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baddeley AD, Hitch G. Working memory. Psychol Learn Motiv. 1974;8:47-89.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baddeley A. The episodic buffer: a new component of working memory? Trends Cogn Sci. 2000;4:417-423.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Repov&#x161; G, Baddeley A. The multi-component model of working memory: explorations in experimental cognitive psychology. Neuroscience. 2006;139:5-21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volpato C, Piccione F, Silvoni S, et al. Working memory in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: auditory event-related potentials and neuropsychological evidence. J Clin Neurophysiol. 2010;27:198-206.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasper E, Zydatiss K, Schuster C, et al. No change in executive performance in ALS patients: a longitudinal neuropsychological study. Neurodegener Dis. 2016;16:184-191.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hammer A, Vielhaber S, Rodriguez-Fornells A, Mohammadi B, M&#xfc;nte TF. A neurophysiological analysis of working memory in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain Res. 2011;1421:90-99.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaehle T, Becke A, Naue N, et al. Working memory in ALS patients: preserved performance but marked changes in underlying neuronal networks. PLoS One. 2013;8:1-10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vellage AK, Veit M, Kobeleva X, Petri S, Vielhaber S, M&#xfc;ller NG. Working memory network changes in ALS: an fMRI study. Front Neurosci. 2016;10:1-10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Owen AM, McMillan KM, Laird AR, Bullmore E. N-back working memory paradigm: a meta-analysis of normative functional neuroimaging studies. Hum Brain Mapp. 2005;25:46-59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, Miller RG, Swash M, Munsat TL, World Federation of Neurology Research Group on Motor Neuron Diseases. El Escorial revisited: revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Mot Neuron Disord. 2000;1:293-299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rascovsky K, Hodges JR, Knopman D, et al. Sensitivity of revised diagnostic criteria for the behavioural variant of frontotemporal dementia. Brain. 2011;134:2456-2477.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum JM, Stambler N, Malta E, et al. The ALSFRS-R: a revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. J Neurol Sci. 1999;169:13-21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abrahams S, Newton J, Niven E, Foley J, Bak TH. Screening for cognition and behaviour changes in ALS. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Front Degener. 2014;15:9-14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strong MJ, Abrahams S, Goldstein LH, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis - frontotemporal spectrum disorder (ALS-FTSD): revised diagnostic criteria. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Front Degener. 2017;18:153-174.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lule D, Burkhardt C, Abdulla S, et al. The Edinburgh cognitive and behavioural amyotrophic lateral sclerosis screen: a cross-sectional comparison of established screening tools in a German-Swiss population. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Front Degener. 2015;16:16-23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braver TS, Cohen JD, Nystrom LE, Jonides J, Smith EE, Noll DC. A parametric study of prefrontal cortex involvement in human working memory. NeuroImage. 1997;5:49-62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The jamovi project; 2020. jamovi (Version 1.2).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jenkinson M, Bannister P, Brady M, Smith S. Improved optimization for the robust and accurate linear registration and motion correction of brain images. NeuroImage. 2002;17:825-841.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith SM. Fast robust automated brain extraction. Hum Brain Mapp. 2002;17:143-155.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beckmann CF, Smith SM. Probabilistic independent component analysis for functional magnetic resonance imaging. IEEE Trans Med Imaging. 2004;23:137-152.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abraham A, Pedregosa F, Eickenberg M, et al. Machine learning for neuroimaging with scikit-learn. Front Neuroinformatics. 2014;8:14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rottschy C, Langner R, Dogan I, et al. Modelling neural correlates of working memory: a coordinate-based meta-analysis. NeuroImage. 2012;60:830-846.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emch M, von Bastian CC, Koch K. Neural correlates of verbal working memory: an fMRI meta-analysis. Front Hum Neurosci. 2019;13:180.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charroud C, Steffener J, Le Bars E, et al. Working memory activation of neural networks in the elderly as a function of information processing phase and task complexity. Neurobiol Learn Mem. 2015;125:211-223.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demeter E, Hernandez-Garcia L, Sarter M, Lustig C. Challenges to attention: a continuous arterial spin labeling (ASL) study of the effects of distraction on sustained attention. NeuroImage. 2011;54:1518-1529.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Engstrom M, Landtblom A-M, Karlsson T. Brain and effort: brain activation and effort-related working memory in healthy participants and patients with working memory deficits. Front Hum Neurosci. 2013;7:140.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jim&#xe9;nez-Balado J, Eich TS. GABAergic dysfunction, neural network hyperactivity and memory impairments in human aging and Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. Semin Cell Dev Biol. 2021. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.semcdb.2021.01.005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Attwell D, Laughlin SB. An energy budget for signaling in the grey matter of the brain. J Cereb Blood Flow Metab. 2001;21:1133-1145.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vandoorne T, De Bock K, Van Den Bosch L. Energy metabolism in ALS: an underappreciated opportunity? Acta Neuropathol. 2018;135:489-509.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keller J, B&#xf6;hm S, Aho-&#xd6;zhan HEA, et al. Functional reorganization during cognitive function tasks in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain Imaging Behav. 2017;12:771-784.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld MA, Tempelmann C, Gaul C, et al. Functional motor compensation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol. 2005;252:944-952.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Witiuk K, Fernandez-Ruiz J, McKee R, et al. Cognitive deterioration and functional compensation in ALS measured with fMRI using an inhibitory task. J Neurosci. 2014;34:14260-14271.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scheller E, Minkova L, Leitner M, Kl&#xf6;ppel S. Attempted and successful compensation in preclinical and early manifest neurodegeneration-a review of task fMRI studies. Front Psychiatry. 2014;5:132.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cabeza R, Dennis N, Stuss DT, Knight RT. Principles of Frontal Lobe Function. 2nd ed. New York, NY: Oxford University Press Inc; 2012:628-652.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abrahams S, Leigh PN, Harvey A, Vythelingum GN, Gris&#xe9; D, Goldstein LH. Verbal fluency and executive dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). Neuropsychologia. 2000;38:734-747.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evdokimidis I, Goldstein LH, Kew JJ, et al. Frontal lobe dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Sci. 2002;195:25-33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meier SL, Charleston AJ, Tippett LJ. Cognitive and behavioural deficits associated with the orbitomedial prefrontal cortex in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain J Neurol. 2010;133:3444-3457.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gregory JM, McDade K, Bak T, et al. Executive, language and fluency dysfunction are markers of localised TDP-43 cerebral pathology in non-demented ALS. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2020;91:149-157.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trojsi F, Caiazzo G, Corbo D, et al. Microstructural changes across different clinical milestones of disease in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. PLoS One. 2015;10:e0119045.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sorrentino P, Rucco R, Baselice F, et al. Flexible brain dynamics underpins complex behaviours as observed in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Sci Rep. 2021;11:4051.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wager TD, Lindquist M, Kaplan L. Meta-analysis of functional neuroimaging data: current and future directions. Soc Cogn Affect Neurosci. 2007;2:150-158.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nyberg L, Salami A, Andersson M, et al. Longitudinal evidence for diminished frontal cortex function in aging. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2010;107:22682-22686.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poletti B, Carelli L, Faini A, et al. The Arrows and Colors Cognitive Test (ACCT): a new verbal-motor free cognitive measure for executive functions in ALS. PLoS One. 2018;13:e0200953.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keller J, Krimly A, Bauer L, et al. A first approach to a neuropsychological screening tool using eye-tracking for bedside cognitive testing based on the Edinburgh Cognitive and Behavioural ALS Screen. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Front Degener. 2017;18:443-450.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steinbach R, Gaur N, Stubendorff B, Witte OW, Grosskreutz J. Developing a neuroimaging biomarker for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: multi-center data sharing and the road to a &#x201c;Global Cohort&#x201d;. Front Neurol. 2018;9:1055.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>