<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">34080741</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>18</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2796</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>290</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of internal medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Intern Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Gut microbiome and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A systematic review of current evidence.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>758</StartPage><EndPage>788</EndPage><MedlinePgn>758-788</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/joim.13336</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS), characterized by a loss of motor neurons in the brain and spinal cord, is a relatively rare but currently incurable neurodegenerative disease. The global incidence of ALS is estimated as 1.75 per 100,000 person-years and the global prevalence is estimated as 4.1-8.4 per 100,000 individuals. Contributions from outside the central nervous system to the etiology of ALS have been increasingly recognized. Gut microbiome is one of the most quickly growing fields of research for ALS. In this article, we performed a comprehensive review of the results from existing animal and human studies, to provide an up-to-date summary of the current research on gut microbiome and ALS. In brief, we found relatively consistent results from animal studies, suggesting an altered gut microbiome composition in experimental ALS. Publication bias might however be a concern. Findings from human studies are largely inconclusive. A few animal and human studies demonstrated the usefulness of intervention with microbial-derived metabolites in modulating the disease progression of ALS. We discussed potential methodological concerns in these studies, including study design, statistical power, handling process of biospecimens and sequencing data, as well as statistical methods and interpretation of results. Finally, we made a few proposals for continued microbiome research in ALS, with the aim to provide valid, reproducible, and translatable findings.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 The Authors. Journal of Internal Medicine published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of Association for Publication of The Journal of Internal Medicine.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sun</LastName><ForeName>Jiangwei</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2252-684X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Unit of Integrative Epidemiology, Institute of Environmental Medicine, Karolinska Institutet, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Tingting</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2314-4448</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Epidemiology and Biostatistics, Karolinska Institutet, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiation Oncology, The First Affiliated Hospital of Guangxi Medical University, Nanning, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Debelius</LastName><ForeName>Justine W</ForeName><Initials>JW</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8605-3546</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Microbiology, Tumor and Cell Biology, Karolinska Institutet, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fang</LastName><ForeName>Fang</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3310-6456</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Unit of Integrative Epidemiology, Institute of Environmental Medicine, Karolinska Institutet, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>802091</GrantID><Acronym>ERC_</Acronym><Agency>European Research Council</Agency><Country>International</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Intern Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8904841</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0954-6820</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000382" MajorTopicYN="N">microbiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018450" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Progression</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000069196" MajorTopicYN="Y">Gastrointestinal Microbiome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">gut microbiota</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neurodegenerative disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">systematic review</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34080741</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/joim.13336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Marin B, Boum&#xe9;diene F, Logroscino G, Couratier P, Babron MC, Leutenegger AL, et&#xa0;al. Variation in worldwide incidence of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a meta-analysis. Int J Epidemiol. 2017;46(1):57-74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longinetti E, Fang F. Epidemiology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: an update of recent literature. Curr Opin Neurol. 2019;32(5) 771-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ingre C, Roos PM, Piehl F, Kamel F, Fang F. Risk factors for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Epidemiol. 2015;7:181-93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L, Tang L, Xia K, Huang T, Fan D. Education, intelligence, and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a Mendelian randomization study. Ann Clin Transl Neurol. 2020;7(9):1642-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L, Tang L, Huang T, Fan D. Life course adiposity and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a mendelian randomization study. Ann Neurol. 2020;87(3):434-41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang L, Lv X, Du H, Wu D, Wang M. Causal effects of serum metabolites on amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a Mendelian randomization study. Prog Neuropsychopharmacol Biol Psychiatry. 2020;97:109771.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li C, Yang W, Wei Q, Shang H. Causal association of leukocytes count and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a mendelian randomization study. Mol Neurobiol. 2020; 57(11): 4622-4627.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhan Y, Fang F. Smoking and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a mendelian randomization study. Ann Neurol. 2019;85(4):482-4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng P, Zhou X. Causal effects of blood lipids on amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a Mendelian randomization study. Hum Mol Genet. 2019;28(4):688-97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng P, Wang T, Zheng J, Zhou X. Causal association of type 2 diabetes with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: new evidence from Mendelian randomization using GWAS summary statistics. BMC Med. 2019;17(1):225.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bandres-Ciga S, Noyce AJ, Hemani G, Nicolas A, Calvo A, Mora G, et&#xa0;al. Shared polygenic risk and causal inferences in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol. 2019;85(4):470-81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang M, Liu D, Zhang Z, Xie W, Cao L, Zhu L, et&#xa0;al. Serum creatinine protects against amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a mendelian randomization study. Mol Neurobiol. 2021;58:2910-15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown RH, Al-Chalabi A. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. N Engl J Med. 2017;377(2):162-72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardiman O, Al-Chalabi A, Chio A, Corr EM, Logroscino G, Robberecht W. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat Rev Dis Primers. 2017;3:17071.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saberi S, Stauffer JE, Schulte DJ, Ravits J. Neuropathology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and its variants. Neurol Clin. 2015;33(4):855-76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mejzini R, Flynn LL, Pitout IL, Fletcher S, Wilton SD, Akkari PA. ALS genetics, mechanisms, and therapeutics: where are we now? Front Neurosci. 2019;13:1310.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor JP, Brown RH, Jr., Cleveland DW. Decoding ALS: from genes to mechanism. Nature. 2016;539(7628):197-206.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baumer D, Talbot K, Turner MR. Advances in motor neurone disease. J R Soc Med. 2014;107(1):14-21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dupuis L, Pradat PF, Ludolph AC, Loeffler JP. Energy metabolism in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet Neurology. 2011;10(1):75-82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murdock BJ, Bender DE, Segal BM, Feldman EL. The dual roles of immunity in ALS: injury overrides protection. Neurobiol Dis. 2015;77:1-12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desport JC, Preux PM, Magy L, Boirie Y, Vallat JM, Beaufr&#xe8;re B, et&#xa0;al. Factors correlated with hypermetabolism in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Am J Clin Nutr. 2001;74(3):328-34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dupuis L, Oudart H, Ren&#xe9; F, Gonzalez de Aguilar JL, Loeffler JP. Evidence for defective energy homeostasis in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: benefit of a high-energy diet in a transgenic mouse model. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2004;101(30):11159-64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mariosa D, Beard JD, Umbach DM, Bellocco R, Keller J, Peters TL, et&#xa0;al. Body mass index and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a study of US military veterans. Am J Epidemiol. 2017;185:1-10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longinetti E, Mariosa D, Larsson H, Almqvist C, Lichtenstein P, Ye W, et&#xa0;al. Physical and cognitive fitness in young adulthood and risk of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis at an early age. Eur J Neurol. 2017;24(1):137-42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Reilly EJ, Wang H, Weisskopf MG, Fitzgerald KC, Falcone G, McCullough ML, et&#xa0;al. Premorbid body mass index and risk of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2013;14(3):205-11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lian L, Liu M, Cui L, Guan Y, Liu T, Cui B, et&#xa0;al. Environmental risk factors and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS): a case-control study of ALS in China. J Clin Neurosci. 2019;66:12-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakken O, Meyer HE, Stigum H, Holm&#xf8;y T. High BMI is associated with low ALS risk: a population-based study. Neurology. 2019;93(5):e424-e432.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mariosa D, Kamel F, Bellocco R, Ye W, Fang F. Association between diabetes and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in Sweden. Eur J Neurol. 2015;22(11):1436-42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mariosa D, Hammar N, Malmstr&#xf6;m H, Ingre C, Jungner I, Ye W, et&#xa0;al. Blood biomarkers of carbohydrate, lipid, and apolipoprotein metabolisms and risk of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a more than 20-year follow-up of the Swedish AMORIS cohort. Ann Neurol. 2017;81(5):718-728.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen X, Yazdani S, Piehl F, Magnusson PKE, Fang F. Polygenic link between blood lipids and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurobiol Aging. 2018;67:202.e1-202.e6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cozzolino M, Rossi S, Mirra A, Carr&#xec; MT. Mitochondrial dynamism and the pathogenesis of Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. Front Cell Neurosci. 2015; 9: 31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowerman M, Vincent T, Scamps F, Perrin FE, Camu W, Raoul C. Neuroimmunity dynamics and the development of therapeutic strategies for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Front Cell Neurosci. 2013;7:214.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He F, Balling R. The role of regulatory T cells in neurodegenerative diseases. Wiley Interdiscip Rev Syst Biol Med. 2013;5(2):153-80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beers DR, Henkel JS, Zhao W, Wang J, Huang A, Wen S, et&#xa0;al. Endogenous regulatory T lymphocytes ameliorate amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in mice and correlate with disease progression in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain. 2011;134(Pt 5) 1293-314.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henkel JS, Beers DR, Wen S, Rivera AL, Toennis KM, Appel JE, et&#xa0;al. Regulatory T-lymphocytes mediate amyotrophic lateral sclerosis progression and survival. EMBO Mol Med. 2013; 5(1): 64-79.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murdock BJ, Bender DE, Kashlan SR, Figueroa-Romero C, Backus C, Callaghan BC, et&#xa0;al. Increased ratio of circulating neutrophils to monocytes in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurol Neuroimmunol Neuroinflamm. 2016;3(4):e242.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zondler L, M&#xfc;ller K, Khalaji S, Bliederh&#xe4;user C, Ruf WP, Grozdanov V, et&#xa0;al. Peripheral monocytes are functionally altered and invade the CNS in ALS patients. Acta Neuropathol. 2016;132(3):391-411.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murdock BJ, Zhou T, Kashlan SR, Little RJ, Goutman SA, Feldman EL. Correlation of peripheral immunity with rapid amyotrophic lateral sclerosis progression. JAMA Neurol. 2017;74:1446-54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newton R, Priyadharshini B, Turka LA. Immunometabolism of regulatory T cells. Nat Immunol. 2016; 17(6): 618-25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palmer CS, Ostrowski M, Balderson B, Christian N, Crowe SM. Glucose metabolism regulates T cell activation, differentiation, and functions. Front Immunol. 2015;6: 1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fessler MB. Regulation of adaptive immunity in health and disease by cholesterol metabolism. Curr Allergy Asthma Rep. 2015; 15(8): 48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kau AL, Ahern PP, Griffin NW, Goodman AL, Gordon JI. Human nutrition, the gut microbiome and the immune system. Nature. 2011;474(7351):327-36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCarville JL, Caminero A, Verdu EF. Novel perspectives on therapeutic modulation of the gut microbiota. Therap Adv Gastroenterol. 2016;9(4):580-93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tschop MH, Hugenholtz P, Karp CL. Getting to the core of the gut microbiome. Nat Biotechnol. 2009;27(4):344-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rook GA, Adams V, Hunt J, Palmer R, Martinelli R, Brunet LR. Mycobacteria and other environmental organisms as immunomodulators for immunoregulatory disorders. Springer Semin Immunopathol. 2004;25(3-4):237-55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harach T, Marungruang N, Duthilleul N, Cheatham V, Mc Coy KD, Frisoni G, et&#xa0;al. Reduction of Abeta amyloid pathology in APPPS1 transgenic mice in the absence of gut microbiota. Sci Rep. 2017;7:41802.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dodiya HB, Frith M, Sidebottom A, Cao Y, Koval J, Chang E, et&#xa0;al. Synergistic depletion of gut microbial consortia, but not individual antibiotics, reduces amyloidosis in APPPS1-21 Alzheimer's transgenic mice. Sci Rep. 2020;10(1):8183.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dodiya HB, Kuntz T, Shaik SM, Baufeld C, Leibowitz J, Zhang X, et&#xa0;al. Sex-specific effects of microbiome perturbations on cerebral Abeta amyloidosis and microglia phenotypes. J Exp Med. 2019;216(7):1542-60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minter MR, Zhang C, Leone V, Ringus DL, Zhang X, Oyler-Castrillo P, et&#xa0;al. Antibiotic-induced perturbations in gut microbial diversity influences neuro-inflammation and amyloidosis in a murine model of Alzheimer's disease. Sci Rep. 2016;6:30028.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tetz G, Pinho M, Pritzkow S, Mendez N, Soto C, Tetz V. Bacterial DNA promotes Tau aggregation. Sci Rep. 2020;10(1):2369.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lundmark K, Westermark GT, Ols&#xe9;n A, Westermark P. Protein fibrils in nature can enhance amyloid protein A amyloidosis in mice: Cross-seeding as a disease mechanism. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2005;102(17):6098-102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sampson TR, Challis C, Jain N, Moiseyenko A, Ladinsky MS, Shastri GG, et&#xa0;al. A gut bacterial amyloid promotes alpha-synuclein aggregation and motor impairment in mice. Elife. 2020;9:e53111.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McAlary L, Chew YL, Lum JS, Geraghty NJ, Yerbury JJ, Cashman NR. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: proteins, proteostasis, prions, and promises. Front Cell Neurosci. 2020;14:581907.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerman A, Liu HN, Croul S, Bilbao J, Rogaeva E, Zinman L, et&#xa0;al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis is a non-amyloid disease in which extensive misfolding of SOD1 is unique to the familial form. Acta Neuropathol. 2010;119(3):335-44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boddy SL, Giovannelli I, Sassani M, Cooper-Knock J, Snyder MP, Segal E, et&#xa0;al. The gut microbiome: a key player in the complexity of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). BMC Med. 2021;19(1):13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tilocca B, Pieroni L, Soggiu A, Britti D, Bonizzi L, Roncada P, et&#xa0;al. Gut-brain axis and neurodegeneration: state-of-the-art of meta-omics sciences for microbiota characterization. Int J Mol Sci. 2020;21(11):4045.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Obrenovich M, Jaworski H, Tadimalla T, Mistry A, Sykes L, Perry G, et&#xa0;al. The role of the microbiota-gut-brain axis and antibiotics in als and neurodegenerative diseases. Microorganisms. 2020;8(5):784.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang P, Kazmi SA, Jameson KG, Hsiao EY. The microbiome as a modifier of neurodegenerative disease risk. Cell Host Microbe 2020; 28(2): 201-22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liberati A, Altman DG, Tetzlaff J, Mulrow C, G&#xf8;tzsche PC, Ioannidis JPA, et al. The PRISMA statement for reporting systematic reviews and meta-analyses of studies that evaluate health care interventions: explanation and elaboration. PLoS Med 2009; 6(7): e1000100.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Figueroa-Romero C, Guo K, Murdock BJ, Paez-Colasante X, Bassis CM, Mikhail KA, et&#xa0;al. Temporal evolution of the microbiome, immune system and epigenome with disease progression in ALS mice. Dis Model Mech. 2019;13(2):dmm041947.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blacher E, Bashiardes S, Shapiro H, Rothschild D, Mor U, Dori-Bachash M, et&#xa0;al. Potential roles of gut microbiome and metabolites in modulating ALS in mice. Nature. 2019;572:474-80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haney MM, Ericsson AC, Lever TE. Effects of intraoperative vagal nerve stimulation on the gastrointestinal microbiome in a mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Comp Med. 2018;68(6):452-60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang YG, Wu S, Yi J, Xia Y, Jin D, Zhou J, et&#xa0;al. target intestinal microbiota to alleviate disease progression in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Ther. 2017;39(2):322-36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu S, Yi J, Zhang YG, Zhou J, Sun J. Leaky intestine and impaired microbiome in an amyotrophic lateral sclerosis mouse model. Physiol Rep. 2015;3(4):e12356.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burberry A, Wells MF, Limone F, Couto A, Smith KS, Keaney J, et&#xa0;al. C9orf72 suppresses systemic and neural inflammation induced by gut bacteria. Nature. 2020; 582(7810):89-94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosen DR. Mutations in Cu/Zn superoxide dismutase gene are associated with familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nature. 1993;364(6435):362.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Philips T, Rothstein JD. Rodent models of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Curr Protoc Pharmacol. 2015;69:5671-21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dawson TM, Golde TE, Lagier-Tourenne C. Animal models of neurodegenerative diseases. Nat Neurosci. 2018;21(10):1370-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gurney ME, Pu H, Chiu AY, Dal Canto MC, Polchow CY, Alexander DD, et&#xa0;al. Motor neuron degeneration in mice that express a human Cu,Zn superoxide dismutase mutation. Science. 1994;264(5166):1772-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Human Microbiome Project C. A framework for human microbiome research. Nature. 2012;486(7402):215-21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah N, Tang H, Doak TG, Ye Y. Comparing bacterial communities inferred from 16S rRNA gene sequencing and shotgun metagenomics. Pac Symp Biocomput. 2011; 165-76. https://doi.org/10.1142/9789814335058_0018</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durazzi F, ala C, Castellani G, Manfreda G, Remondini D, De Cesare A. Comparison between 16S rRNA and shotgun sequencing data for the taxonomic characterization of the gut microbiota. Sci Rep. 2021;11(1):3030.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yilmaz P, Parfrey LW, Yarza P, Gerken J, Pruesse E, Quast C, et&#xa0;al. The SILVA and &#x201c;All-species Living Tree Project (LTP)&#x201d; taxonomic frameworks. Nucleic Acids Res. 2014;42(Database issue):D643-D648.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cole JR, Wang Q, Fish JA, Chai B, McGarrell DM, Sun Y, et&#xa0;al. Ribosomal Database Project: data and tools for high throughput rRNA analysis. Nucleic Acids Res. 2014;42(Database issue):D633-D642.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDonald D, Price MN, Goodrich J, Nawrocki EP, DeSantis TZ, Probst A, et&#xa0;al. An improved Greengenes taxonomy with explicit ranks for ecological and evolutionary analyses of bacteria and archaea. ISME J 2012;6(3):610-18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Federhen S. The NCBI Taxonomy database. Nucleic Acids Res. 2012;40(Database issue):D136-D143.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balvociute M, Huson DH. SILVA, RDP, Greengenes, NCBI and OTT - how do these taxonomies compare? BMC Genomics. 2017;18(Suppl 2):114.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMurdie PJ, Holmes S. Waste not, want not: why rarefying microbiome data is inadmissible. PLoS Comput Biol. 2014;10(4):e1003531.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weiss S, Xu ZZ, Peddada S, Amir A, Bittinger K, Gonzalez A, et&#xa0;al. Normalization and microbial differential abundance strategies depend upon data characteristics. Microbiome. 2017;5(1):27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gloor GB, Macklaim JM, Pawlowsky-Glahn V, Egozcue JJ. Microbiome datasets are compositional: and this is not optional. Front Microbiol. 2017;8:2224.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim D, Hofstaedter CE, Zhao C, Mattei L, Tanes C, Clarke E, et&#xa0;al. Optimizing methods and dodging pitfalls in microbiome research. Microbiome. 2017;5(1):52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sinha R, Abu-Ali G, Vogtmann E, Fodor AA, Ren B, Amir A, et&#xa0;al. Assessment of variation in microbial community amplicon sequencing by the Microbiome Quality Control (MBQC) project consortium. Nat Biotechnol. 2017;35(11):1077-86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boers SA, Jansen R, Hays JP. Understanding and overcoming the pitfalls and biases of next-generation sequencing (NGS) methods for use in the routine clinical microbiological diagnostic laboratory. Eur J Clin Microbiol Infect Dis. 2019;38(6):1059-70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parker KD, Albeke SE, Gigley JP, Goldstein AM, Ward NL. Microbiome composition in both wild-type and disease model mice is heavily influenced by mouse facility. Front Microbiol. 2018; 9: 1598.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen TL, Vieira-Silva S, Liston A, Raes J. How informative is the mouse for human gut microbiota research? Dis Model Mech. 2015;8(1):1-16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franco A, Malhotra N, Simonovits G. Social science. Publication bias in the social sciences: unlocking the file drawer. Science. 2014;345(6203):1502-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katyal N, Govindarajan R. Shortcomings in the current amyotrophic lateral sclerosis trials and potential solutions for improvement. Front Neurol. 2017;8:521.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walter J, Armet AM, Finlay BB, Shanahan F. Establishing or exaggerating causality for the gut microbiome: lessons from human microbiota-associated rodents. Cell. 2020;180(2):221-32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng Q, Shen J, Chen K, Zhou J, Liao Q, Lu K, et&#xa0;al. The alteration of gut microbiome and metabolism in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. Sci Rep. 2020;10(1):12998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicholson K, Bjornevik K, Abu-Ali G, Chan J, Cortese M, Dedi B, et&#xa0;al. The human gut microbiota in people with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2021;22(3-4):186-94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ngo ST, Restuadi R, McCrae AF, Van Eijk RP, Garton F, Henderson RD, et&#xa0;al. Progression and survival of patients with motor neuron disease relative to their fecal microbiota. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2020;21: 1-14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhai CD, Zheng JJ, An BC, Huang HF, Tan ZC. Intestinal microbiota composition in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: establishment of bacterial and archaeal communities analyses. Chin Med J (Engl). 2019;132(15):1815-22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brenner D, Hiergeist A, Adis C, Mayer B, Gessner A, Ludolph AC, et&#xa0;al. The fecal microbiome of ALS patients. Neurobiol Aging. 2018;61:132-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rowin J, Xia Y, Jung B, Sun J. Gut inflammation and dysbiosis in human motor neuron disease. Physiol Rep. 2017;5(18):e13443.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang X, Wang X, Yang S, Meng F, Wang X, Wei H, et&#xa0;al. Evaluation of the microbial diversity in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis using high-throughput sequencing. Front Microbiol. 2016;7:1479.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Gioia D, Bozzi Cionci N, Baffoni L, Amoruso A, Pane M, Mogna L, et&#xa0;al. A prospective longitudinal study on the microbiota composition in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. BMC Med. 2020;18(1):153.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun J, Zhan Y, Mariosa D, Larsson H, Almqvist C, Ingre C, et&#xa0;al. Antibiotics use and risk of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in Sweden. Eur J Neurol. 2019;21:1355-61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paganoni S, Macklin EA, Hendrix S, Berry JD, Elliott MA, Maiser S, et&#xa0;al. Trial of sodium phenylbutyrate-taurursodiol for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. N Engl J Med. 2020;383(10):919-30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de la Rubia JE, Drehmer E, Platero JL, Benlloch M, Caplliure-Llopis J, Villaron-Casales C, et&#xa0;al. Efficacy and tolerability of EH301 for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled human pilot study. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2019;20(1-2):115-22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandrioli J, Amedei A, Cammarota G, Niccolai E, Zucchi E, D'Amico R, et&#xa0;al. FETR-ALS Study protocol: a randomized clinical trial of fecal microbiota transplantation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Front Neurol. 2019;10:1021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turnbaugh PJ, Quince C, Faith JJ, McHardy AC, Yatsunenko T, Niazi F, et&#xa0;al. Organismal, genetic, and transcriptional variation in the deeply sequenced gut microbiomes of identical twins. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2010;107(16):7503-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Falony G, Joossens M, Vieira-Silva S, Wang J, Darzi Y, Faust K, Kurilshikov A, et&#xa0;al. Population-level analysis of gut microbiome variation. Science. 2016;352(6285):560-4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knight R, Callewaert C, Marotz C, Hyde ER, Debelius JW, McDonald D, et&#xa0;al. The microbiome and human biology. Annu Rev Genomics Hum Genet. 2017;18:65-86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vujkovic-Cvijin I, Sklar J, Jiang L, Natarajan L, Knight R, Belkaid Y. Host variables confound gut microbiota studies of human disease. Nature. 2020;587(7834): 448-454.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asnicar F, Berry SE, Valdes AM, Nguyen LH, Piccinno G, Drew DA, et&#xa0;al. Microbiome connections with host metabolism and habitual diet from 1,098 deeply phenotyped individuals. Nat Med. 2021;27(2):321-32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurilshikov A, Medina-Gomez C, Bacigalupe R, Radjabzadeh D, Wang J, Demirkan A, et&#xa0;al. Large-scale association analyses identify host factors influencing human gut microbiome composition. Nat Genet. 2021;53(2):156-65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knight R, Vrbanac A, Taylor BC, Aksenov A, Callewaert C, Debelius J, et&#xa0;al. Best practices for analysing microbiomes. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2018;16(7):410-22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gloor GB, Wu JR, Pawlowsky-Glahn V, Egozcue JJ. It's all relative: analyzing microbiome data as compositions. Ann Epidemiol. 2016;26(5):322-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsilimigras MC, Fodor AA. Compositional data analysis of the microbiome: fundamentals, tools, and challenges. Ann Epidemiol. 2016;26(5):330-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weydt P, Oeckl P, Huss A, M&#xfc;ller K, Volk AE, Kuhle J, et&#xa0;al. Neurofilament levels as biomarkers in asymptomatic and symptomatic familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol. 2016;79(1):152-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodrich JK, Di Rienzi SC, Poole AC, Koren O, Walters WA, Caporaso JG, et&#xa0;al. Conducting a microbiome study. Cell. 2014;158(2):250-62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quince C, Walker AW, Simpson JT, Loman NJ, Segata N. Shotgun metagenomics, from sampling to analysis. Nat Biotechnol. 2017;35(9):833-44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forslund K, Hildebrand F, Nielsen T, Falony G, Le Chatelier E, Sunagawa S, et&#xa0;al. Disentangling type 2 diabetes and metformin treatment signatures in the human gut microbiota. Nature. 2015;528(7581):262-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yilmaz P, Kottmann R, Field D, Knight R, Cole JR, Amaral-Zettler L, et&#xa0;al. Minimum information about a marker gene sequence (MIMARKS) and minimum information about any (x) sequence (MIxS) specifications. Nat Biotechnol. 2011;29(5):415-20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vangay P, Burgin J, Johnston A, Beck KL, Berrios DC, Blumberg K, et&#xa0;al. Microbiome metadata standards: report of the national microbiome data collaborative's workshop and follow-on activities. mSystems. 2021;6(1):e01194-01120.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vandeputte D, Tito RY, Vanleeuwen R, Falony G, Raes J. Practical considerations for large-scale gut microbiome studies. FEMS Microbiol Rev. 2017;41(Supp_1):S154-S167.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costea PI, Zeller G, Sunagawa S, Pelletier E, Alberti A, Levenez F, et&#xa0;al. Towards standards for human fecal sample processing in metagenomic studies. Nat Biotechnol. 2017;35(11):1069-76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nearing JT, Douglas GM, Comeau AM, Langille MGI. Denoising the Denoisers: an independent evaluation of microbiome sequence error-correction approaches. PeerJ. 2018;6:e5364.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prodan A, Tremaroli V, Brolin H, Zwinderman AH, Nieuwdorp M, Levin E. Comparing bioinformatic pipelines for microbial 16S rRNA amplicon sequencing. PLoS One. 2020;15(1):e0227434.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allaband C, McDonald D, V&#xe1;zquez-Baeza Y, Minich JJ, Tripathi A, Brenner DA,et&#xa0;al. Microbiome 101: studying, analyzing, and interpreting gut microbiome data for clinicians. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2019;17(2):218-30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bharti R, Grimm DG. Current challenges and best-practice protocols for microbiome analysis. Brief Bioinform. 2021;22(1):178-93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Chalabi A, Hardiman O. The epidemiology of ALS: a conspiracy of genes, environment and time. Nat Rev Neurol. 2013;9(11):617-28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim G, Gautier O, Tassoni-Tsuchida E, Ma XR, Gitler AD. ALS genetics: gains, losses, and implications for future therapies. Neuron. 2020;108(5):822-42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cryan JF, O'Riordan KJ, Cowan CSM, Sandhu KV, Bastiaanssen TFS, Boehme M, et&#xa0;al. The microbiota-gut-brain axis. Physiol Rev. 2019;99(4):1877-2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tefera TW, Borges K. Metabolic dysfunctions in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis pathogenesis and potential metabolic treatments. Front Neurosci. 2016;10:611.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durack J, Lynch SV. The gut microbiome: Relationships with disease and opportunities for therapy. J Exp Med. 2019;216(1):20-40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blaser MJ. Fecal microbiota transplantation for dysbiosis - predictable risks. N Engl J Med. 2019;381(21):2064-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fong W, Li Q, Yu J. Gut microbiota modulation: a novel strategy for prevention and treatment of colorectal cancer. Oncogene. 2020;39(26):4925-43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ianiro G, Rossi E, Thomas AM, Schinzari G, Masucci L, Quaranta G, et&#xa0;al. Faecal microbiota transplantation for the treatment of diarrhoea induced by tyrosine-kinase inhibitors in patients with metastatic renal cell carcinoma. Nat Commun. 2020;11(1):4333.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>