<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">34118098</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1530-6860</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>35</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>FASEB journal : official publication of the Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>FASEB J</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Glucose clearance and uptake is increased in the SOD1<sup>G93A</sup> mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis through an insulin-independent mechanism.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e21707</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e21707</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1096/fj.202002450R</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Metabolic disturbances are associated with the progression of the neurodegenerative disorder, amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). However, the molecular events that drive energy imbalances in ALS are not completely understood. In this study, we aimed to elucidate deficits in energy homeostasis in the SOD1<sup>G93A</sup> mouse model of ALS. SOD1<sup>G93A</sup> mice and their wild-type littermates underwent indirect calorimetry and intraperitoneal glucose/insulin tolerance tests at both the onset and mid-symptomatic stages of the disease. Glucose uptake and the plasma glucoregulatory hormone profiles were analyzed. Pancreatic islet cell mass and function were assessed by measuring hormone concentrations and secretion in isolated islets, and pancreatic &#x3b1;- and &#x3b2;-cell immunoreactive areas. Finally, we profiled liver glycogen metabolism by measuring glucagon concentrations and liver metabolic gene expressions. We identified that mid-symptomatic SOD1<sup>G93A</sup> mice have increased oxygen consumption and faster exogenous glucose uptake, despite presenting with normal insulin tolerance. The capacity for pancreatic islets to secrete insulin appears intact, however, islet cell insulin concentrations and &#x3b2;-cell mass were reduced. Fasting glucose homeostasis was also disturbed, along with increased liver glycogen stores, despite elevated circulating glucagon, suggesting that glucagon signaling is impaired. Metabolic gene expression profiling of livers indicated that glucose cannot be utilized efficiently in SOD1<sup>G93A</sup> mice. Overall, we demonstrate that glucose homeostasis and uptake are altered in SOD1<sup>G93A</sup> mice, which is linked to an increase in insulin-independent glucose uptake, and a loss of &#x3b2;-cells, insulin production, and glucagon sensitivity. This suggests that the hormonal regulation of glucose concentrations may contribute to the progression of disease in this ALS mouse model.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McDonald</LastName><ForeName>Tanya S</ForeName><Initials>TS</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4325-3537</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Biomedical Sciences, The University of Queensland, St Lucia, Brisbane, QLD, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kumar</LastName><ForeName>Vinod</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Biomedical Sciences, The University of Queensland, St Lucia, Brisbane, QLD, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fung</LastName><ForeName>Jenny N</ForeName><Initials>JN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Biomedical Sciences, The University of Queensland, St Lucia, Brisbane, QLD, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Woodruff</LastName><ForeName>Trent M</ForeName><Initials>TM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Biomedical Sciences, The University of Queensland, St Lucia, Brisbane, QLD, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Queensland Brain Institute, The University of Queensland, St Lucia, Brisbane, QLD, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>John D</ForeName><Initials>JD</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9976-7396</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Biomedical Sciences, The University of Queensland, St Lucia, Brisbane, QLD, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>FASEB J</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8804484</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0892-6638</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D007328">Insulin</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>9005-79-2</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D006003">Glycogen</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 1.15.1.1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C000606291">Sod1 protein, mouse</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 1.15.1.1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000072105">Superoxide Dismutase-1</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>IY9XDZ35W2</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D005947">Glucose</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004195" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Models, Animal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015870" MajorTopicYN="N">Gene Expression</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005947" MajorTopicYN="N">Glucose</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006003" MajorTopicYN="N">Glycogen</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006706" MajorTopicYN="N">Homeostasis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007328" MajorTopicYN="N">Insulin</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D050417" MajorTopicYN="N">Insulin-Secreting Cells</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008099" MajorTopicYN="N">Liver</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051379" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008810" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice, Inbred C57BL</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008822" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice, Transgenic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015398" MajorTopicYN="N">Signal Transduction</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000072105" MajorTopicYN="N">Superoxide Dismutase-1</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">glucagon</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">glucose tolerance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">glycogen</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">insulin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">liver metabolism</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34118098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1096/fj.202002450R</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Brown RH, Al-Chalabi A. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. N Engl J Med. 2017;377(2):162-172.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dupuis L, Echaniz-Laguna A. Skeletal muscle in motor neuron diseases: therapeutic target and delivery route for potential treatments. Curr Drug Targets. 2010;11(10):1250-1261.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grad LI, Rouleau GA, Ravits J, Cashman NR. Clinical spectrum of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). Cold Spring Harb Perspect Med. 2017;7(8):a024117.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zarei S, Carr K, Reiley L, et al. A comprehensive review of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Surg Neurol Int. 2015;6(1):171.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tefera TW, Borges K. Metabolic dysfunctions in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis pathogenesis and potential metabolic treatments. Front Neurosci. 2017;10:611.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vandoorne T, De Bock K, Van Den Bosch L. Energy metabolism in ALS: an underappreciated opportunity? Acta Neuropathol. 2018;135(4):489-509.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouteloup C, Desport J-C, Clavelou P, et al. Hypermetabolism in ALS patients: an early and persistent phenomenon. J Neurol. 2009;256(8):1236-1242.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Genton L, Viatte V, Janssens J-P, H&#xe9;ritier A-C, Pichard C. Nutritional state, energy intakes and energy expenditure of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) patients. Clin Nutr. 2011;30(5):553-559.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasarskis EJ, Berryman S, Vanderleest JG, Schneider AR, McClain CJ. Nutritional status of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: relation to the proximity of death. Am J Clin Nutr. 1996;63(1):130-137.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed RM, Mioshi E, Caga J, et al. Body mass index delineates ALS from FTD: implications for metabolic health. J Neurol. 2014;261(9):1774-1780.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paganoni S, Deng J, Jaffa M, Cudkowicz ME, Wills AM. Body mass index, not dyslipidemia, is an independent predictor of survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 2011;44(1):20-24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reyes ET, Perurena OH, Festoff BW, Jorgensen R, Moore WV. Insulin resistance in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Sci. 1984;63(3):317-324.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smittkamp SE, Morris JK, Bomhoff GL, Chertoff ME, Geiger PC, Stanford JA. SOD1-G93A mice exhibit muscle-fiber-type-specific decreases in glucose uptake in the absence of whole-body changes in metabolism. Neurodegener Dis. 2014;13(1):29-37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stallings NR, Puttaparthi K, Dowling KJ, et al. TDP-43, an ALS linked protein, regulates fat deposition and glucose homeostasis. PLoS One. 2013;8(8):e71793.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saffer D, Morley J, Bill P. Carbohydrate metabolism in motor neurone disease. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 1977;40(6):533-537.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun Y, Lu C-J, Chen R-C, Hou W-H, Li C-Y. Risk of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in patients with diabetes: a nationwide population-based cohort study. J Epidemiol. 2014;25(6):445-451.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desseille C, Deforges S, Biondi O, et al. Specific physical exercise improves energetic metabolism in the skeletal muscle of amyotrophic-lateral- sclerosis mice. Front Mol Neurosci. 2017;10:332.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harno K, Rissanen A, Palo J. Glucose tolerance in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neurol Scand. 1984;70(6):451-455.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kioumourtzoglou M-A, Rotem RS, Seals RM, Gredal O, Hansen J, Weisskopf MG. Diabetes mellitus, obesity, and diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a population-based study. JAMA Neurol. 2015;72(8):905-911.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mariosa D, Kamel F, Bellocco R, Ye W, Fang F. Association between diabetes and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in Sweden. Eur J Neurol. 2015;22(11):1436-1442.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scaricamazza S, Salvatori I, Giacovazzo G, et al. Skeletal-muscle metabolic reprogramming in ALS-SOD1(G93A) mice predates disease onset and is a promising therapeutic target. iScience. 2020;23(5):101087.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee JD, Kamaruzaman NA, Fung JNT, et al. Dysregulation of the complement cascade in the hSOD1G93Atransgenic mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neuroinflammation. 2013;10(1):119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lutz C. Mouse models of ALS: past, present and future. Brain Res. 2018;1693(Pt A):1-10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valbuena GN, Cantoni L, Tortarolo M, Bendotti C, Keun HC. Spinal cord metabolic signatures in models of fast- and slow-progressing SOD1(G93A) amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Front Neurosci. 2019;13:1276.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang HA, Lee JD, Lee KM, Woodruff TM, Noakes PG. Complement C5a-C5aR1 signalling drives skeletal muscle macrophage recruitment in the hSOD1(G93A) mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Skelet Muscle. 2017;7:10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee JD, Liu N, Levin SC, et al. Therapeutic blockade of HMGB1 reduces early motor deficits, but not survival in the SOD1G93A mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neuroinflammation. 2019;16(1):45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spiers JG, Chen HC, Steyn FJ, Lavidis NA, Woodruff TM, Lee JD. Noninvasive assessment of altered activity following restraint in mice using an automated physiological monitoring system. Stress. 2017;20(1):59-67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okuno T, Yokomizo T. Basic techniques for lipid extraction from tissues and cells. In: Yokomizo T, Murakami M, eds. Bioactive Lipid Mediators: Current Reviews and Protocols. Tokyo: Springer Japan; 2015:331-336.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng M, Cao H. Fast quantification of short chain fatty acids and ketone bodies by liquid chromatography-tandem mass spectrometry after facile derivatization coupled with liquid-liquid extraction. J Chromatogr B Analyt Technol Biomed Life Sci. 2018;1083:137-145.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham KL, Fynch S, Papas EG, Tan C, Kay TWH, Thomas HE. Isolation and culture of the islets of langerhans from mouse pancreas. Bio-protocol. 2016;6(12):e1840.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liberzon A, Birger C, Thorvaldsd&#xf3;ttir H, Ghandi M, Mesirov JP, Tamayo P. The Molecular Signatures Database (MSigDB) hallmark gene set collection. Cell Syst. 2015;1(6):417-425.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee JD, Kumar V, Fung JN, Ruitenberg MJ, Noakes PG, Woodruff TM. Pharmacological inhibition of complement C5a-C5a1 receptor signalling ameliorates disease pathology in the hSOD1(G93A) mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Br J Pharmacol. 2017;174(8):689-699.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dupuis L, Oudart H, Ren&#xe9; F, Gonzalez de Aguilar J-LL, Loeffler J-PP. Evidence for defective energy homeostasis in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: benefit of a high-energy diet in a transgenic mouse model. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2004;101(30):11159-11164.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pradat P-F, Bruneteau G, Gordon PH, et al. Impaired glucose tolerance in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotrophic Lateral Scler. 2010;11(1-2):166-171.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gotoh F, Kitamura A, Koto A, Kataoka K, Atsuji H. Abnormal insulin secretion in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Sci. 1972;16(2):201-207.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karpati G, Klassen G, Tanser P. The effects of partial chronic denervation on forearm metabolism. Can J Neurol Sci. 1979;6(2):105-112.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poulton KR, Rossi ML. Peripheral nerve protein glycation and muscle fructolysis: evidence of abnormal carbohydrate metabolism in ALS. Funct Neurol. 1993;8(1):33-42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Browne SE, Yang L, DiMauro J-P, Fuller SW, Licata SC, Beal MF. Bioenergetic abnormalities in discrete cerebral motor pathways presage spinal cord pathology in the G93A SOD1 mouse model of ALS. Neurobiol Dis. 2006;22(3):599-610.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cistaro A, Valentini MC, Chi&#xf2; A, et al. Brain hypermetabolism in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a FDG PET study in ALS of spinal and bulbar onset. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging. 2012;39(2):251-259.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pagani M, Chio A, Valentini MC, et al. Functional pattern of brain FDG-PET in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology. 2014;83(12):1067-1074.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hibbar MD, Davidson MB, Rosenberg CS. Insulin antagonism is not a primary abnormality of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis but is related to disease severity. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 1986;63(1):41-46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ngo ST, Steyn FJ, Huang L, et al. Altered expression of metabolic proteins and adipokines in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Sci. 2015;357(1):22-27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hubbard RW, Will AD, Peterson GW, Sanchez A, Gillan WW, Tan SA. Elevated plasma glucagon in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology. 1992;42(8):1532-1534.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramnanan CJ, Edgerton DS, Kraft G, Cherrington AD. Physiologic action of glucagon on liver glucose metabolism. Diabetes Obes Metab. 2011;13(Suppl 1):118-125.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han H-S, Kang G, Kim JS, Choi BH, Koo S-H. Regulation of glucose metabolism from a liver-centric perspective. Exp Mol Med. 2016;48(3):e218.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dodge JC, Treleaven CM, Fidler JA, et al. Metabolic signatures of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis reveal insights into disease pathogenesis. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2013;110(26):10812-10817.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szelechowski M, Amoedo N, Obre E, et al. Metabolic reprogramming in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Sci Rep. 2018;8(1):3953.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palamiuc L, Schlagowski A, Ngo ST, et al. A metabolic switch toward lipid use in glycolytic muscle is an early pathologic event in a mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. EMBO Mol Med. 2015;7(5):526-546.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>