<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">34143516</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>19</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1530-6860</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>35</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>FASEB journal : official publication of the Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>FASEB J</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Novel reporters of mitochondria-associated membranes (MAM), MAMtrackers, demonstrate MAM disruption as a common pathological feature in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e21688</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e21688</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1096/fj.202100137R</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The mitochondria-associated membrane (MAM) is a functional subdomain of the endoplasmic reticulum membrane that tethers to the mitochondrial outer membrane and is essential for cellular homeostasis. A defect in MAM is involved in various neurological diseases, including amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). Recently, we and others reported that MAM was disrupted in the models expressing several ALS-linked genes, including SOD1, SIGMAR1, VAPB, TARDBP, and FUS, suggesting that MAM disruption is deeply involved in the pathomechanism of ALS. However, it is still uncertain whether MAM disruption is a common pathology in ALS, mainly due to the absence of a simple, quantitative tool for monitoring the status of MAM. In this study, to examine the effects of various ALS-causative genes on MAM, we created the following two novel MAM reporters: MAMtracker-Luc and MAMtracker-Green. The MAMtrackers could detect MAM disruption caused by suppression of SIGMAR1 or the overexpression of ALS-linked mutant SOD1 in living cells. Moreover, the MAMtrackers have an advantage in their ability to monitor reversible changes in the MAM status induced by nutritional conditions. We used the MAMtrackers with an expression plasmid library of ALS-causative genes and noted that 76% (16/21) of the genes altered MAM integrity. Our results suggest that MAM disruption is a common pathological feature in ALS. Furthermore, we anticipate our MAMtrackers, which are suitable for high-throughput assays, to be valuable tools to understand MAM dynamics.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 The Authors. The FASEB Journal published by Wiley Periodicals LLC on behalf of Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sakai</LastName><ForeName>Shohei</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience and Pathobiology, Research Institute of Environmental Medicine, Nagoya University, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience and Pathobiology, Nagoya University Graduate School of Medicine, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Watanabe</LastName><ForeName>Seiji</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8038-7919</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience and Pathobiology, Research Institute of Environmental Medicine, Nagoya University, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience and Pathobiology, Nagoya University Graduate School of Medicine, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Komine</LastName><ForeName>Okiru</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience and Pathobiology, Research Institute of Environmental Medicine, Nagoya University, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience and Pathobiology, Nagoya University Graduate School of Medicine, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sobue</LastName><ForeName>Akira</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience and Pathobiology, Research Institute of Environmental Medicine, Nagoya University, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience and Pathobiology, Nagoya University Graduate School of Medicine, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Interactive Research and Academia Industry Collaboration Center, Research Institute of Environmental Medicine, Nagoya University, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yamanaka</LastName><ForeName>Koji</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4655-0035</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience and Pathobiology, Research Institute of Environmental Medicine, Nagoya University, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience and Pathobiology, Nagoya University Graduate School of Medicine, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Glyco-core Research (iGCORE), Nagoya University, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>FASEB J</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8804484</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0892-6638</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D024101">Mitochondrial Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="Y">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051379" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008928" MajorTopicYN="N">Mitochondria</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="Y">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051336" MajorTopicYN="N">Mitochondrial Membranes</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="Y">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D024101" MajorTopicYN="N">Mitochondrial Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009154" MajorTopicYN="Y">Mutation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009447" MajorTopicYN="N">Neuroblastoma</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="Y">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ER-mitochondria contact</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mitochondria-associated membrane (MAM)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">organelle</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sigma-1 receptor (Sig1R)</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34143516</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1096/fj.202100137R</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Mejzini R, Flynn LL, Pitout IL, et al. ALS genetics, mechanisms, and therapeutics: where are we now? Front Neurosci. 2019;13:1-27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor JP, Brown RH, Cleveland DW. Decoding ALS: from genes to mechanism. Nature. 2016;539:197-206.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watanabe S, Ilieva H, Tamada H, et al. Mitochondria-associated membrane collapse is a common pathomechanism in SIGMAR1- and SOD1-linked ALS. EMBO Mol Med. 2016;8:1421-1437.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayashi T, Su TP. Sigma-1 receptor chaperones at the ER-mitochondrion interface regulate Ca2+ signaling and cell survival. Cell. 2007;131:596-610.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Saif A, Al-Mohanna F, Bohlega S. A mutation in sigma-1 receptor causes juvenile amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol. 2011;70:913-919.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mancuso R, Oliv&#xe1;n S, Rando A, et al. Sigma-1R agonist improves motor function and motoneuron survival in ALS mice. Neurotherapeutics. 2012;9:814-826.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ono Y, Tanaka H, Takata M, et al. SA4503, a sigma-1 receptor agonist, suppresses motor neuron damage in vitro and in vivo amyotrophic lateral sclerosis models. Neurosci Lett. 2014;559:174-178.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Vos KJ, M&#xf3;rotz GM, Stoica R, et al. VAPB interacts with the mitochondrial protein PTPIP51 to regulate calcium homeostasis. Hum Mol Genet. 2012;21:1299-1311.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suzuki H, Matsuoka M. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-linked mutant VAPB enhances TDP-43-induced motor neuronal toxicity. J Neurochem. 2011;119:1099-1107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stoica R, De Vos KJ, Paillusson S, et al. ER-mitochondria associations are regulated by the VAP-PTPIP51 interaction and are disrupted by ALS/FTD-associated TDP-43. Nat Commun. 2014;5:3996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stoica R, Paillusson S, Gomez-Suaga P, et al. ALS/FTD-associated FUS activates GSK-3&#x3b2; to disrupt the VAP-PTPIP 51 interaction and ER-mitochondria associations. EMBO Rep. 2016;17:1326-1342.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sigal YM, Zhou R, Zhuang X. Visualizing and discovering cellular structures with super-resolution microscopy. Science. 2018;361:880-887.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alam MS. Proximity ligation assay (PLA). Curr Protoc Immunol. 2018;123:e58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Z, Zhao X, Xu J, et al. A novel fluorescent reporter detects plastic remodeling of mitochondria-ER contact sites. J Cell Sci. 2018;131:jcs208686.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kakimoto Y, Tashiro S, Kojima R, et al. Visualizing multiple inter-organelle contact sites using the organelle-targeted split-GFP system. Sci Rep. 2018;8:1-13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cieri D, Vicario M, Giacomello M, et al. SPLICS: a split green fluorescent protein-based contact site sensor for narrow and wide heterotypic organelle juxtaposition. Cell Death Differ. 2018;25:1131-1145.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Motohashi K. A simple and efficient seamless DNA cloning method using SLiCE from Escherichia coli laboratory strains and its application to SLiP site-directed mutagenesis. BMC Biotechnol. 2015;15:47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watanabe S, Inami H, Oiwa K, et al. Aggresome formation and liquid-liquid phase separation independently induce cytoplasmic aggregation of TAR DNA-binding protein 43. Cell Death Dis. 2020;11:909.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watanabe S, Hayakawa T, Wakasugi K, Yamanaka K. Cystatin C protects neuronal cells against mutant copper-zinc superoxide dismutase-mediated toxicity. Cell Death Dis. 2014;5:1-13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komine O, Yamashita H, Fujimori-Tonou N, et al. Innate immune adaptor TRIF deficiency accelerates disease progression of ALS mice with accumulation of aberrantly activated astrocytes. Cell Death Differ. 2018;25:2130-2146.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan YS, Lei YL. Generation and culture of mouse embryonic fibroblasts. Methods Mol Biol. 2019;1960:85-91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wieckowski MR, Giorgi C, Lebiedzinska M, et al. Isolation of mitochondria-associated membranes and mitochondria from animal tissues and cells. Nat Protoc. 2009;4:1582-1590.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujimoto M, Hayashi T. New insights into the role of mitochondria-associated endoplasmic reticulum membrane. Inter Rev Cell Mol Biol. 2011;292:73-117.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hall MP, Unch J, Binkowski BF, et al. Engineered luciferase reporter from a deep sea shrimp utilizing a novel imidazopyrazinone substrate. ACS Chem Biol. 2012;7:1848-1857.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dixon AS, Schwinn MK, Hall MP, et al. NanoLuc complementation reporter optimized for accurate measurement of protein interactions in cells. ACS Chem Biol. 2016;11:400-408.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alford SC, Ding Y, Simmen T, Campbell RE. Dimerization-dependent green and yellow fluorescent proteins. ACS Synth Biol. 2012;1:569-575.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Csord&#xe1;s Gy&#xf6;rgy, Renken C, V&#xe1;rnai P&#xe9;ter, et al. Structural and functional features and significance of the physical linkage between ER and mitochondria. J Cell Biol. 2006;174:915-921.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Theurey P, Tubbs E, Vial G, et al. Mitochondria-associated endoplasmic reticulum membranes allow adaptation of mitochondrial metabolism to glucose availability in the liver. J Mol Cell Biol. 2016;8:129-143.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Betz C, Stracka D, Prescianotto-Baschong C, et al. mTOR complex 2-Akt signaling at mitochondria-associated endoplasmic reticulum membranes (MAM) regulates mitochondrial physiology. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2013;110:12526-12534.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chami M, Oul&#xe8;s B, Szabadkai G, et al. Role of SERCA1 truncated isoform in the proapoptotic calcium transfer from ER to mitochondria during ER stress. Mol Cell. 2008;32:641-651.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang W-Y, Pan L, Su SC, et al. Interaction of FUS and HDAC1 regulates DNA damage response and repair in neurons. Nat Neurosci. 2013;16:1383-1391.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naumann M, Pal A, Goswami A, et al. Impaired DNA damage response signaling by FUS-NLS mutations leads to neurodegeneration and FUS aggregate formation. Nat Commun. 2018;9:335.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freischmidt A, Wieland T, Richter B, et al. Haploinsufficiency of TBK1 causes familial ALS and fronto-temporal dementia. Nat Neurosci. 2015;18:631-636.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu D, Jin T, Zhu H, et al. TBK1 suppresses RIPK1-driven apoptosis and inflammation during development and in aging. Cell. 2018;174:1477-1491.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerbino V, Kaunga E, Ye J, et al. The loss of TBK1 kinase activity in motor neurons or in all cell types differentially impacts ALS disease progression in SOD1 mice. Neuron. 2020;106:1-17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hertlein V, Flores-Romero H, Das KK, et al. MERLIN: a novel BRET-based proximity biosensor for studying mitochondria-ER contact sites. Life Sci Alliance. 2020;3:1-11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wegorzewska I, Bell S, Cairns NJ, et al. TDP-43 mutant transgenic mice develop features of ALS and frontotemporal lobar degeneration. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2009;106:18809-18814.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wils H, Kleinberger G, Janssens J, et al. TDP-43 transgenic mice develop spastic paralysis and neuronal inclusions characteristic of ALS and frontotemporal lobar degeneration. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2010;107:3858-3863.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watanabe S, Kaneko K, Yamanaka K. Accelerated disease onset with stabilized familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS)-linked mutant TDP-43 proteins. J Biol Chem. 2013;288:3641-3654.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee S, Min KT. The interface between ER and mitochondria: molecular compositions and functions. Mol Cells. 2018;41:1000-1007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paillusson S, Stoica R, Gomez-Suaga P, et al. There&#x2019;s something wrong with my MAM; the ER-mitochondria axis and neurodegenerative diseases. Trends Neurosci. 2016;39:146-157.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>