<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">34185922</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2842</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>48</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of oral rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Oral Rehabil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Dysphagia in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Quantification of bulbar motor dysfunction.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1044</StartPage><EndPage>1049</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1044-1049</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/joor.13220</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Dysphagia as a sequel and possible early sign of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) is caused by progressive impaired bulbar motor function.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To evaluate bulbar motor dysfunction in patients suffering from ALS compared to a healthy reference group.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A clinical study and prospective group comparison was designed. Patients and healthy volunteers were examined in the outpatient clinic of our university medical center. Ten patients with ALS and 20 healthy volunteers were included. All participants underwent a flexible endoscopic evaluation of swallowing (FEES) and a manometric measurement of the maximal sub-palatal atmospheric pressure generated by suction as well as of the prevalent pressure during swallowing. Additionally, the Sydney Swallow Questionnaire (SSQ) was completed by all participants to score the self-rated extent of dysphagia.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Comparing maximal suction pressures, the group of patients showed significantly lower values (p&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;.001). There was a significant correlation between reduced pressures and the degree of dysphagia (SSQ score) (r&#xa0;=&#xa0;-0.73).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">As the oral cavity is an easily accessible compartment of the upper digestive tract, manometric measurements might serve as a simple instrument in order to detect or to monitor bulbar motor dysfunction. Oral manometry may facilitate early detection and monitoring of dysphagia in ALS. Larger studies are required to confirm our findings.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 The Authors. Journal of Oral Rehabilitation published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Adamske</LastName><ForeName>Deike</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Oral and Maxillofacial Surgery, Charit&#xe9; - University Medical Center Berlin, Berlin, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Heyduck</LastName><ForeName>Adrienne</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Phoniatrics and Pedaudiology, Department of Otorhinolaryngology, University Medical Center G&#xf6;ttingen, G&#xf6;ttingen, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Weidenm&#xfc;ller</LastName><ForeName>Matthias</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Phoniatrics and Pedaudiology, Department of Otorhinolaryngology, University Medical Center G&#xf6;ttingen, G&#xf6;ttingen, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>G&#xf6;ricke</LastName><ForeName>Bettina</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University Medical Center G&#xf6;ttingen, G&#xf6;ttingen, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Frank</LastName><ForeName>Tobias</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University Medical Center G&#xf6;ttingen, G&#xf6;ttingen, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Olthoff</LastName><ForeName>Arno</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6402-9759</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Phoniatrics and Pedaudiology, Department of Otorhinolaryngology, University Medical Center G&#xf6;ttingen, G&#xf6;ttingen, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Oral Rehabil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0433604</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0305-182X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003679" MajorTopicYN="N">Deglutition</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003680" MajorTopicYN="Y">Deglutition Disorders</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011446" MajorTopicYN="N">Prospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bulbar motor dysfunction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">deglutition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dysphagia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">motor neuron disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">swallowing</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34185922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/joor.13220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Paris G, Martinaud O, Hannequin D, et al. Clinical screening of oropharyngeal dysphagia in patients with ALS. An Phys Rehabil Med. 2012;55:601-608.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perry BJ, Stipancic KL, Martino R, Plowman EK, Green JR. Biomechanical biomarkers of tongue impairment during swallowing in persons diagnosed with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Dysphagia. 2021;36:147-156.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hori K, Taniguchi H, Hayashi H, et al. Role of tongue pressure production in oropharyngeal swallow biomechanics. Physiol Rep. 2013;1:1-14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ono T, Hori K, Nokubi T. Pattern of tongue pressure on hard palate during swallowing. Dysphagia. 2004;19:259-264.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshida M, Kikutani T, Tsuga K, Utanohara Y, Hayashi R, Akagawa Y. Decreased tongue pressure reflects symptom of dysphagia. Dysphagia. 2006;21:61-65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Youmans SR, Stierwalt JAG. Measures of tongue function related to normal swallowing. Dysphagia. 2006;21:102-111.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fukuoka T, Ono T, Hori K, et al. Tongue pressure measurement and videofluroscopic study of swallowing in patients with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Dyphagia. 2019;34:80-88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee JH, Choi SY. Criteria to assess tongue strength for predicting penetration and aspiration in patients with stroke having dysphagia. Eur J Phys Rehabil Med. 2020;56:375-385.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shitara S, Fujiwara S, Okawa J, Kodama S, Hori K, Ono T. Coordination between lingual motion and pressure production during dipper/tipper type swallows. J Oral Rehabil. 2020;47:1479-1488.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Engelke W, Jung K, Kn&#xf6;sel M. Intra-oral compartment pressures: a biofunctional model and experimental measurements under different conditions of posture. Clin Oral Investig. 2011;15:165-176.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Engelke W, Glombek J, Psychogios M, Schneider S, Ellenberger D, Santander P. Displacement of oropharyngeal structures during suction-swallowing cycles. Eur Arch Otorhinolaryngol. 2014;271:1987-1997.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santander P, Engelke W, Olthoff A, V&#xf6;lter C. Intraoral pressure patterns during swallowing. Eur Arch Otorhinolaryngol. 2013;270:1019-1025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olthoff A, Joseph AA, Weidenm&#xfc;ller M, Riley B, Frahm J. Real-time MRI of swallowing: intraoral pressure reduction supports larynx elevation. NMR Biomed. 2016;29:1618-1623.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR. El-Escorial World Federation of Neurology Criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J NeurolSci. 1994;124:96-107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van den Bergh PY, Hadden RD, Bouche P, et al. European Federation of Neurological Societies, Peripheral Nerve Society. European Federation of Neurological Societies/Peripheral Nerve Society guideline on management of chronic inflammatory demyelinating polyradiculoneuropathy: report of a joint task force of the European Federation of Neurological Societies and the Peripheral Nerve Society - first revision. Eur J Neurol. 2010;17:356-363.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dwivedi RC, Rose SS, Roe JWG, et al. Validation of the Sydney Swallow Questionnaire (SSQ) in a cohort of head and neck cancer patients. Oral Oncol. 2010;46:10-14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szczesniak MM, Maclean J, Zhang T, Liu R, Cook IJ. The normative range for and age and gender effects on the Sydney Swallow Questionnaire (SSQ). Dysphagia. 2014;29:535-538.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langmore SE, Schatz L, Olsen N. Fiberoptic endoscopic examination of swallowing safety: a new procedure. Dysphagia. 1988;4:216-219.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenbek JC, Robbins JA, Roecker EB, Coyle JL, Wood JL. A penetration-aspiration scale. Dysphagia. 1996;11:93-98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hiss SG, Postma GN. Fiberoptic endoscopic evaluation of swallowing. Laryngoscope. 2003;113:1386-1393.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Worms PM. The epidemiology of motor neuron diseases: a review of recent studies. J Neurol Sci. 2001;191:3-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Logroscino G, Traynor BJ, Hardiman O, et al. Incidence of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in Europe. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatr. 2010;81:385-390.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goeleven A, Robberecht W, Sonies B, Carbonez A, Dejaeger E. Manofluorographic evaluation of swallowing in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and its relationship with clinical evaluation of swallowing. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2006;7:235-240.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higo R, Tayama N, Watanabe T, Nitou T. Videomanofluorometric study in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Laryngoscope. 2002;112:911-917.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh JC. Effects of tongue-hold swallows on suprahyoid muscle activation according to the relative tongue protrusion length in the elderly individuals. Dysphagia. 2019;34:382-390.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pearson WG Jr, Hindson DF, Langmore SE, Zumwalt AC. Evaluating swallowing muscles essential for hyolaryngeal elevation by using muscle functional magnetic resonance imaging. Int J Radiat Oncol Biol Phys. 2013;85:735-740.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagashima K, Kikutani T, Miyashita T, Yajima Y, Tamura F. Tongue muscle strength affects posterior pharyngeal wall advancement during swallowing: A cross- sectional study of outpatients with dysphagia. J Oral Rehabil. 2021;48:169-175.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robbins J, Levine R, Wood J, Roecker EB, Luschei E. Age effects on lingual pressure generation as a risk factor for dysphagia. J Gerontol A BiolSci Med Sci. 1995;50:257-262.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bensimon G, Lacomblez L, Meininger V. A controlled trial of riluzole in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. ALS/Riluzole Study Group. N Engl J Med. 1994;330:585-591.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wills A-M, Hubbard J, Macklin EA, et al. MDA clinical research network. Hypercaloric enteral nutrition in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled phase 2 trial. Lancet. 2014;383:2065-2072.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>