<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">34216521</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>26</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1468-1331</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>28</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Venous creatinine as a biomarker for loss of fat-free mass and disease progression in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>3615</StartPage><EndPage>3625</EndPage><MedlinePgn>3615-3625</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/ene.15003</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND PURPOSE">To establish the utility of venous creatinine as a biomarker to monitor loss of fat-free mass in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">In this multicenter natural history study, body composition and venous creatinine were assessed in 107 patients with ALS and 52&#xa0;healthy controls. Longitudinal patterns of venous creatinine and its association with the risk of death during follow-up were determined in a cohort of patients with ALS from Australia (n&#xa0;=&#xa0;69) and the Netherlands (n&#xa0;=&#xa0;38).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">The mean levels of venous creatinine were 75.78&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;11.15&#xa0;&#x3bc;mol/L for controls, 70.25&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;12.81&#xa0;&#x3bc;mol/L for Australian patients, and 59.95&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;14.62&#xa0;&#x3bc;mol/L for Dutch patients with ALS. The relationship between measures of venous creatinine and fat-free mass was similar between all groups (r&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.36, p&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;0.001). Within patients, fat-free mass declined by 0.31 (95% confidence interval [CI]: 0.22-0.40) kg/month, and venous creatinine declined by 0.52 (95% CI: 0.38-0.66) &#x3bc;mol/L/month, with a longitudinal correlation of 0.57 (95% CI: 0.35-0.76, p&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;0.001). Lower levels of venous creatinine were associated with increased risk for earlier death in patients with ALS (hazard ratio&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.94, 95% CI: 0.90-0.98, p&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.007).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Venous creatinine is decreased in ALS and declines alongside a decline in fat-free mass over the course of the disease, and may serve as a practical marker to monitor the change of fat-free mass in patients with ALS. This could inform clinical care and provide an alternative endpoint for the evaluation of therapeutic interventions that focus on slowing the loss of fat-free mass and disease progression in ALS.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 European Academy of Neurology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Holdom</LastName><ForeName>Cory J</ForeName><Initials>CJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Australian Institute for Bioengineering and Nanotechnology, The University of Queensland, Brisbane, QLD, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Clinical Research, The University of Queensland, Brisbane, QLD, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Janse van Mantgem</LastName><ForeName>Mark R</ForeName><Initials>MR</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5782-1980</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, UMC Utrecht Brain Centre, University Medical Centre Utrecht, Utrecht, the Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>van Eijk</LastName><ForeName>Ruben P A</ForeName><Initials>RPA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7132-5967</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, UMC Utrecht Brain Centre, University Medical Centre Utrecht, Utrecht, the Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biostatistics &amp; Research Support, Julius Centre for Health Sciences and Primary Care, University Medical Centre Utrecht, Utrecht, the Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Howe</LastName><ForeName>Stephanie L</ForeName><Initials>SL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Australian Institute for Bioengineering and Nanotechnology, The University of Queensland, Brisbane, QLD, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>van den Berg</LastName><ForeName>Leonard H</ForeName><Initials>LH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, UMC Utrecht Brain Centre, University Medical Centre Utrecht, Utrecht, the Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McCombe</LastName><ForeName>Pamela A</ForeName><Initials>PA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2704-8517</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Clinical Research, The University of Queensland, Brisbane, QLD, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Royal Brisbane and Women's Hospital, Brisbane, QLD, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Henderson</LastName><ForeName>Robert D</ForeName><Initials>RD</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2820-8183</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Clinical Research, The University of Queensland, Brisbane, QLD, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Royal Brisbane and Women's Hospital, Brisbane, QLD, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ngo</LastName><ForeName>Shyuan T</ForeName><Initials>ST</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1388-2108</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Australian Institute for Bioengineering and Nanotechnology, The University of Queensland, Brisbane, QLD, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Clinical Research, The University of Queensland, Brisbane, QLD, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Royal Brisbane and Women's Hospital, Brisbane, QLD, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Steyn</LastName><ForeName>Frederik J</ForeName><Initials>FJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4782-3608</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Clinical Research, The University of Queensland, Brisbane, QLD, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Royal Brisbane and Women's Hospital, Brisbane, QLD, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Biomedical Sciences, The University of Queensland, Brisbane, QLD, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016448">Multicenter Study</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9506311</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1351-5101</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D015415">Biomarkers</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>AYI8EX34EU</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D003404">Creatinine</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001315" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Australia</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015415" MajorTopicYN="N">Biomarkers</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003404" MajorTopicYN="N">Creatinine</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018450" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Progression</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">biomarker</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">creatinine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fat-free mass</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34216521</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ene.15003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Brown RH, Al-Chalabi A. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. N Engl J Med. 2017;377(2):162-172.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heymsfield SB, Adamek M, Gonzalez MC, Jia G, Thomas DM. Assessing skeletal muscle mass: historical overview and state of the art. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle. 2014;5(1):9-18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schutte JE, Longhurst JC, Gaffney FA, Bastian BC, Blomqvist CG. Total plasma creatinine: an accurate measure of total striated muscle mass. J Appl Physiol. 1981;51(3):762-766.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chio A, Calvo A, Bovio G, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis outcome measures and the role of albumin and creatinine: a population-based study. JAMA Neurol. 2014;71(9):1134-1142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown RH, Al-Chalabi A. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. N Engl J Med. 2017;377(2):162-172.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, Miller RG, Swash M, Munsat TL. El Escorial revisited: Revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord. 2000;1(5):293-299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siri WE. Body composition from fluid spaces and density: analysis of methods. 1961. Nutrition. 1993;9(5):480-491; discussion, 92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ngo ST, van Eijk RPA, Chachay V, et al. Loss of appetite is associated with a loss of weight and fat mass in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2019;20(7-8):497-505.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCrory MA, Mole PA, Gomez TD, Dewey KG, Bernauer EM. Body composition by air-displacement plethysmography by using predicted and measured thoracic gas volumes. J Appl Physiol (1985). 1998;84(4):1475-1479.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum JM, Stambler N, Malta E, et al. The ALSFRS-R: a revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. J Neurol Sci. 1999;169(1):13-21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balendra R, Jones A, Jivraj N, et al. Estimating clinical stage of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis from the ALS Functional Rating Scale. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2014;15(3-4):279-284.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kimura F, Fujimura C, Ishida S, et al. Progression rate of ALSFRS-R at time of diagnosis predicts survival time in ALS. Neurology. 2006;66(2):265.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai B, Dunson DB. Bayesian covariance selection in generalized linear mixed models. Biometrics. 2006;62(2):446-457.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ariyo O, Lesaffre E, Verbeke G, Quintero A. Model selection for Bayesian linear mixed models with longitudinal data: sensitivity to the choice of priors. Commun Stat Simul Comput. 2019;1-25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ngo ST, Steyn FJ, McCombe PA. Body mass index and dietary intervention: implications for prognosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Sci. 2014;340(1-2):5-12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baxmann AC, Ahmed MS, Marques NC, et al. Influence of muscle mass and physical activity on serum and urinary creatinine and serum cystatin C. Clin J Am Soc Nephrol. 2008;3(2):348-354.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Eijk RPA, Eijkemans MJC, Ferguson TA, Nikolakopoulos S, Veldink JH, Van Den Berg LH. Monitoring disease progression with plasma creatinine in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis clinical trials. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2018;89(2):156-161.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wyss M, Kaddurah-Daouk R. Creatine and creatinine metabolism. Physiol Rev. 2000;80(3):1107-1213.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith EF, Shaw PJ, De Vos KJ. The role of mitochondria in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurosci Lett. 2019;710:132933.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janssen GME, Degenaar CP, Menheere PPCA, Habets HML, Geurten P. Plasma urea, creatinine, uric acid, albumin, and total protein concentrations before and after 15-, 25-, and 42-km contests. Int J Sports Med. 1989;10(Suppl 3):S132-S138.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fragala MS, Bi C, Chaump M, Kaufman HW, Kroll MH. Associations of aerobic and strength exercise with clinical laboratory test values. PLoS One. 2017;12(10):e0180840.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lippi G, Brocco G, Franchini M, Schena F, Guidi G. Comparison of serum creatinine, uric acid, albumin and glucose in male professional endurance athletes compared with healthy controls. Clin Chem Lab Med. 2004;42(6):644-647.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lippi G, Salvagno GL, Montagnana M, Schena F, Ballestrieri F, Guidi GC. Influence of physical exercise and relationship with biochemical variables of NT-pro-brain natriuretic peptide and ischemia modified albumin. Clin Chim Acta. 2006;367(1):175-180.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nair S, O&#x2019;Brien SV, Hayden K, et al. Effect of a cooked meat meal on serum creatinine and estimated glomerular filtration rate in diabetes-related kidney disease. Diabetes Care. 2014;37(2):483.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hannemann A, Friedrich N, Dittmann K, et al. Age- and sex-specific reference limits for creatinine, cystatin C and the estimated glomerular filtration rate. Clin Chem Lab Med. 2011;50(5):919-926.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heymsfield SB, Scherzer R, Pietrobelli A, Lewis CE, Grunfeld C. Body mass index as a phenotypic expression of adiposity: quantitative contribution of muscularity in a population-based sample. Int J Obes (Lond). 2009;33(12):1363-1373.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardiman O. Symptomatic treatment of respiratory and nutritional failure in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol. 2000;247(4):245-251.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Traynor BJ, Alexander M, Corr B, Frost E, Hardiman O. Effect of a multidisciplinary amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) clinic on ALS survival: a population based study, 1996-2000. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2003;74(9):1258.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Chio A, Dengler R, Hecht M, Weber M, Swash M. Neurophysiological measures in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: markers of progression in clinical trials. Amyotrophic Lateral Scler. 2005;6(1):17-28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tideman PA, Tirimacco R, Senior DP, et al. Impact of a regionalised clinical cardiac support network on mortality among rural patients with myocardial infarction. Med J Aust. 2014;200(3):157-160.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heymsfield SB, Arteaga C, McManus C, Smith J, Moffitt S. Measurement of muscle mass in humans: validity of the 24-hour urinary creatinine method. Am J Clin Nutr. 1983;37(3):478-494.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jassal SK, Wassel CL, Laughlin GA, Barrett-Connor E, Rifkin DE, Ix JH. Urine creatinine-based estimates of fat-free mass in community-dwelling older persons: the Rancho Bernardo study. J Ren Nutr. 2015;25(2):97-102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simon NG, Turner MR, Vucic S, et al. Quantifying disease progression in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol. 2014;76(5):643-657.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Umoh ME, Fournier C, Li Y, et al. Comparative analysis of C9orf72 and sporadic disease in an ALS clinic population. Neurology. 2016;87(10):1024-1030.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huynh W, Ahmed R, Mahoney CJ, et al. The impact of cognitive and behavioral impairment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Expert Rev Neurother. 2020;20(3):281-293.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iacoangeli A, Lin T, Al Khleifat A, et al. Genome-wide meta-analysis finds the ACSL5-ZDHHC6 locus is associated with ALS and links weight loss to the disease genetics. Cell Rep. 2020;33(4):108323.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>