<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">34269500</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2753</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>28</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of evaluation in clinical practice</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Eval Clin Pract</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Investigating job satisfaction in palliative rehabilitation: Reflections and perspectives of health professionals working with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>108</StartPage><EndPage>119</EndPage><MedlinePgn>108-119</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/jep.13599</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="STUDY RATIONALE">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis is a progressive neurodegenerative disease which causes impairment of the motor functions in the upper and lower limbs and bulbar muscles with a median survival time is three&#x2009;years from the first appearance of symptoms. There is massive psychological impact on health professionals to persons with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, hence the work leads to multiple challenges and stressful and demanding situations with high risk of experiencing diminished personal well-being including burnout, moral distress, and compassion fatigue.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="AIM">To investigate reflections and perspectives from health professionals working within palliative rehabilitation for elements of importance in relation to job satisfaction.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS AND MATERIALS">The design was qualitative and based on the phenomenological-hermeneutical methodology by Paul Ricoeur's interpretation theory. Data consisted of two semi-structured focus group interviews with a total of 12 specialized health professionals: Nurses, Psychologists, Physicians, Occupational Therapists, Physiotherapists, and Social workers, working within a hospital setting of specialized palliative rehabilitation for people with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and their families.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">The analysis revealed insight into four themes: fundamental drive, working conditions, value of collegiality and work-life balance. Fundamental drive was deeply rooted in the professionals' sense of having a meaningful job. Working conditions such as self-management were important for job satisfaction as were good collegial relations. Finally, a good balance between working life and private life was considered important for job satisfaction.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">Our study indicates that work within the field of palliative rehabilitation is experienced as enriching and beneficial under the right circumstances and in an appreciatory working environment. We found elements like autonomy, mastery, purpose, collegiality, and work-life balance to be of great importance. Our findings can help guide managements and health professionals in other palliative rehabilitation contexts to ensure satisfied employees and to optimize the quality of care.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gamskjaer</LastName><ForeName>Tine</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health, Faculty of Health, Aarhus University, Aarhus, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Werlauff</LastName><ForeName>Ulla</ForeName><Initials>U</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Rehabilitation Center for Neuromuscular Diseases, Aarhus, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Handberg</LastName><ForeName>Charlotte</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1378-2449</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health, Faculty of Health, Aarhus University, Aarhus, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Rehabilitation Center for Neuromuscular Diseases, Aarhus, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Eval Clin Pract</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9609066</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1356-1294</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002055" MajorTopicYN="Y">Burnout, Professional</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000068376" MajorTopicYN="Y">Compassion Fatigue</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006282" MajorTopicYN="N">Health Personnel</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007588" MajorTopicYN="N">Job Satisfaction</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019636" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neurodegenerative Diseases</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">health professionals</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">job satisfaction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">palliative care</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rehabilitation</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34269500</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jep.13599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Zarei S, Carr K, Reiley L, et al. A comprehensive review of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Surg Neurol Int. 2015;6:171-171.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozanne AO, Graneheim UH, Strang S. Finding meaning despite anxiety over life and death in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. J Clin Nurs. 2013;22(15-16):2141-2149.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh J, Oh S-I, Kim JA. The amyotrophic lateral sclerosis supportive care needs assessment instrument: development and psychometric evaluation. Palliat Support Care. 2018;16(6):692-697.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Couratier P, Corcia P, Lautrette G, Nicol M, Preux PM, Marin B. Epidemiology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a review of literature. Rev Neurol. 2016;172(1):37-45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madsen LS, Jeppesen J, Handberg C. &#x2018;Understanding my ALS&#x2019;. Experiences and reflections of persons with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and relatives on participation in peer group rehabilitation. Disabil Rehabil. 2019;41(12):1410-1418.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldstein LHP, Abrahams SP. Changes in cognition and behaviour in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: nature of impairment and implications for assessment. Lancet Neurol. 2013;12(4):368-380.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janssens AIWA, Ruytings M, Al-Chalabi A, et al. A mapping review of international guidance on the management and care of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). Amyotroph Lateral Scler Front Degener. 2016;17(5-6):325-336.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris M, Thomas G, Thomas M, et al. Supporting wellbeing in motor neurone disease for patients, carers, social networks, and health professionals: a scoping review and synthesis. Palliat Support Care. 2018;16(2):228-237.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The National Rehabilitation Centre for Neuromuscular Diseases. The National Rehabilitation Centre for Neuromuscular Diseases; 2018. http://rcfm.dk/. Accessed April 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hospice UK. What is rehabilitative palliative care? 2021. https://www.hospiceuk.org/what-we-offer/clinical-and-care-support/rehabilitative-palliative-care/what-is-rehabilitative-palliative-care. Accessed April 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parola V, Coelho A, Cardoso D, Sandgren A, Apostolo J. Prevalence of burnout in health professionals working in palliative care: a systematic review. JBI Database System Rev Implement Rep. 2017;15(7):1905-1933.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamal AH, Bull JH, Wolf SP, et al. Prevalence and predictors of burnout among Hospice and palliative care clinicians in the U.S. J Pain Symptom Manage. 2016;51(4):690-696.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanchez-Reilly S, Morrison LJ, Carey E, et al. Caring for oneself to care for others: physicians and their self-care. J Support Oncol. 2013;11(2):75-81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarcan M, Hikmet N, Schooley B, Top M, Tarcan GY. An analysis of the relationship between burnout, socio-demographic and workplace factors and job satisfaction among emergency department health professionals. Appl Nurs Res. 2017;34:40-47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lanham M, Rye M, Rimsky L, Weill S. How gratitude relates to burnout and job satisfaction in mental health professionals. J Mental Health Counsel. 2012;34(4):341-354.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maslach C, Jackson S. The measurement of experienced burnout. J Organ Behav. 1981;2:99-113.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richardsen AM, Martinussen M. The Maslach burnout inventory: factorial validity and consistency across occupational groups in Norway. J Occupat Org Psychol. 2004;77(3):377-384.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Marco D, Lopez-Cabrera R, Arenas A, Giorgi G, Arcangeli G, Mucci N. Approaching the discriminatory work environment as stressor: the protective role of job satisfaction on health. Front Psychol. 2016;7:1313.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pandita R, Dominic J. Variables of job satisfaction: a review study with special reference to LIS professionals. Int J Inform Disseminat Technol. 2016;6:258-267.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Satuf C, Monteiro S, Pereira H, Esgalhado G, Marina Afonso R, Loureiro M. The protective effect of job satisfaction in health, happiness, well-being and self-esteem. Int J Occup Saf Ergon. 2018;24(2):181-189.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ricoeur P. Interpretation Theory. Texas: Texas Christian University Press; 1976.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan H, Wilson A, Olver I. Ricoeur's theory of interpretation: an instrument for data interpretation in hermeneutic phenomenology. Int J Qual Methods. 2009;8(4):1-15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simon&#xff; C, Specht K, Andersen IC, Johansen KK, Nielsen C, Agerskov H. A Ricoeur-inspired approach to interpret participant observations and interviews. Global Qual Nurs Res. 2018;5:2333393618807395.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charalambous A, Papadopoulos IR, Beadsmoore A. Ricoeur's hermeneutic phenomenology: an implication for nursing research. Scand J Caring Sci. 2008;22(4):637-642.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ric&#x153;ur P, ed. La Philosophie de la Volont&#xe9; [Filosofiens kilder]. Copenhagen: Vinten; 1973.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dreyer PS, Pedersen BD. Distanciation in Ricoeur's theory of interpretation: narrations in a study of life experiences of living with chronic illness and home mechanical ventilation. Nurs Inq. 2009;16(1):64-73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindseth A, Norberg A. A phenomenological hermeneutical method for researching lived experience. Scand J Caring Sci. 2004;18(2):145-153.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bradbury-Jones C, Sambrook S, Irvine F. The phenomenological focus group: an oxymoron? J Adv Nurs. 2009;65(3):663-671.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Danish National Rehabilitation Center for Neuromuscular Diseases. Coporate Plan [Virksomhedsplan] 2017-2019; 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The National Rehabilitation Center for Neuromuscular Diseases. Information for professionals; 2021. https://rcfm.dk/for-fagpersoner/. Accessed April 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kvale S, Brinkman S. Interview-Introduction to a Skill [Interview-Introduktion til et h&#xe5;ndvaerk]. 2nd ed. Copenhagen: Hans Reitzels Forlag; 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Mecial Association (WMA). WMA declaration of Helsinki: ethical principles for medical research involving human subjects. JAMA. 2013;310(20):2191-2194.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harboe T. Method and projectwriting: an introduction [Metode og projektskrivning: en introduktion]. 2nd ed. Frederiksberg: Samfundslitteratur; 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Witte H, Handberg C. Survivorship care need assessment of patients with colorectal cancer-experiences and perspectives of hospital healthcare professionals. J Clin Nurs. 2019;00:1-11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pink DH. Drive-The Surprising Truth about What Motivates Us. New York: Riverhead Books; 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ilies R, Wagner D, Wilson K, et al. Flow at work and basic psychological needs: effects on well-being. Appl Psychol. 2017;66(1):3-24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farina LSA, Rodrigues GDR, Hurtz S. Flow and engagement at work: a literature review. Psico-USF. 2018;23(4):633-642.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceja L, Navarro J. &#x2018;Suddenly I get into the zone&#x2019;: examining discontinuities and nonlinear changes in flow experiences at work. Hum Relat. 2012;65(9):1101-1127.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colombo L, Zito M. Demands, resources and the three dimensions of flow at work. A study among professional nurses. Open J Nurs. 2014;4(4):255-264.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sinclair S. Impact of death and dying on the personal lives and practices of palliative and hospice care professionals. CMAJ. 2011;183(2):180-187.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanso N, Galiana L, Oliver A, Pascual A, Sinclair S, Benito E. Palliative care professionals' inner life: exploring the relationships among awareness, self-care, and compassion satisfaction and fatigue, burnout, and coping with death. J Pain Symptom Manage. 2015;50(2):200-207.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pierce B, Dougherty E, Panzarella T, Le LW, Rodin G, Zimmermann C. Staff stress, work satisfaction, and death attitudes on an oncology palliative care unit, and on a medical and radiation oncology inpatient unit. J Palliat Care. 2007;23(1):32-39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stievano A, Sabatino L, Affonso D, Olsen D, Skinner I, Rocco G. Nursing's professional dignity in palliative care: exploration of an Italian context. J Clin Nurs. 2019;28(9-10):1633-1642.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pavelkov&#xe1; H, Bu&#x17e;gov&#xe1; R. Burnout among healthcare workers in hospice care. Central Europ J Nurs Midwifery. 2015;6(1):218-223.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linley PA, Joseph S. Positive and negative changes following occupational death exposure. J Trauma Stress. 2005;18(6):751-758.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rattner M, Berzoff J. Rethinking suffering: allowing for suffering that is intrinsic at end of life. J Soc Work End Life Palliat Care. 2016;12(3):240-258.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>White K, Wilkes L, Cooper K, Barbato M. The impact of unrelieved patient suffering on palliative care nurses. Int J Palliat Nurs. 2004;10(9):438-444.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park R, Searcy D. Job autonomy as a predictor of mental well-being: the moderating role of quality-competitive environment. J Bus Psychol. 2012;27(3):305-316.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang S-B, Guy ME. The effectiveness of self-managed work teams in government organizations. J Bus Psychol. 2011;26(4):531-541.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Athey EK, Leslie MS, Briggs LA, et al. How important are autonomy and work setting to nse practitioners' job satisfaction? J Am Assoc Nurse Pract. 2016;28(6):320-326.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dobre OI. Employee motivation and organizational performance. Rev Appl Socio-Econ Res. 2013;5(1):53-60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kavalieratos D, Siconolfi DE, Steinhauser KE, et al. &#x2018;It is like heart failure. It is chronic &#x2026; And it will kill you&#x2019;: a qualitative analysis of burnout among Hospice and palliative care clinicians. J Pain Symp Manag. 2017;53(5):901-910.e901.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coventry TH, Maslin-Prothero SE, Smith G. Organizational impact of nurse supply and workload on nurses continuing professional development opportunities: an integrative review. J Adv Nurs. 2015;71(12):2715-2727.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreno-Milan B, Cano-Vindel A, Lopez-Doriga P, Medrano LA, Breitbart W. Meaning of work and personal protective factors among palliative care professionals. Palliat Support Care. 2019;17(4):381-387. https://doi.org/10.1017/S147895151800113X</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dougherty E, Pierce B, Ma C, Panzarella T, Rodin G, Zimmermann C. Factors associated with work stress and professional satisfaction in oncology staff. Am J Hosp Palliat Care. 2009;26(2):105-111.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Head B, Middleton A, Zeigler C. Work satisfaction among Hospice and palliative nurses. J Hosp Palliat Nurs. 2019;21(5):E1-E11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bromberg MB, Schenkenberg T, Brownell AA. A survey of stress among amyotrophic lateral sclerosis care providers. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2011;12(3):162-167.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swetz KM, Harrington SE, Matsuyama RK, Shanafelt TD, Lyckholm LJ. Strategies for avoiding burnout in hospice and palliative medicine: peer advice for physicians on achieving longevity and fulfillment. J Palliat Med. 2009;12(9):773-777.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mota Vargas R, Mahtani-Chugani V, Solano Pallero M, Rivero Jimenez B, Cabo Dominguez R, Robles AV. The transformation process for palliative care professionals: the metamorphosis, a qualitative research study. Palliat Med. 2016;30(2):161-170.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dharmawardene M, Givens J, Wachholtz A, Makowski S, Tjia J. A systematic review and meta-analysis of meditative interventions for informal caregivers and health professionals. BMJ Support Palliat Care. 2016;6(2):160-169.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Penman J. Finding paradise within: how spirituality protects palliative care clients and caregivers from depression. J Holist Nurs. 2018;36(3):243-254.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chittenden EH, Ritchie CS. Work-life balancing: challenges and strategies. J Palliat Med. 2011;14(7):870-874.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neumann JL, Mau LW, Virani S, et al. Burnout, moral distress, work-life balance, and career satisfaction among hematopoietic cell transplantation professionals. Biol Blood Marrow Transplant. 2018;24(4):849-860.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller PE. The relationship between job satisfaction and intention to leave of Hospice nurses in a for-profit corporation. J Hosp Palliat Nurs. 2008;10(1):56-64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandelowski M. Sample size in qualitative research. Res Nurs Health. 1995;18(2):179-183.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morse JM. Analytic strategies and sample size. Qual Health Res. 2015;25(10):1317-1318.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trotter RT 2nd. Qualitative research sample design and sample size: resolving and unresolved issues and inferential imperatives. Prev Med. 2012;55(5):398-400.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carlson E. Ethnography and participant observation [Etnografi og deltagende observation]. In: Henricson M, ed. Scientific Theory and Method-From Idea to Examination [Videnskabelig Teori Og Metode-Fra id&#xe9; Til Eksamination]. 2nd ed. K&#xf8;benhavn: Munksgaard; 2018:219-252.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>