<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">34261189</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1469-7793</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>599</Volume><Issue>17</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Journal of physiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Physiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>First-recruited motor units adopt a faster phenotype in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>4117</StartPage><EndPage>4130</EndPage><MedlinePgn>4117-4130</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1113/JP281310</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="KEY POINTS">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) is an incurable neurodegenerative disorder of motor neurons, carrying a short survival. High-density motor unit recordings permit analysis of motor unit size (amplitude) and firing behaviour (afterhyperpolarization duration and muscle fibre conduction velocity). Serial recordings from biceps brachii indicated that motor units fired faster and with greater amplitude as disease progressed. First-recruited motor units in the latter stages of ALS developed characteristics akin to fast-twitch motor units, possibly as a compensatory mechanism for the selective loss of this motor unit subset. This process may become maladaptive, highlighting a novel therapeutic target to reduce motor unit vulnerability.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="ABSTRACT">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) is a progressive neurodegenerative disorder with a median survival of 3 years. We employed serial high-density surface electromyography (HDSEMG) to characterize voluntary and ectopic patterns of motor unit (MU) firing at different stages of disease. By distinguishing MU subtypes with variable vulnerability to disease, we aimed to evaluate compensatory neuronal adaptations that accompany disease progression. Twenty patients with ALS and five patients with benign fasciculation syndrome (BFS) underwent 1-7 assessments each. HDSEMG measurements comprised 30&#xa0;min of resting muscle and 1&#xa0;min of light voluntary activity from biceps brachii bilaterally. MU decomposition was performed by the progressive FastICA peel-off technique. Inter-spike interval, firing pattern, MU potential area, afterhyperpolarization duration and muscle fibre conduction velocity were determined. In total, 373 MUs (ALS&#xa0;=&#xa0;287; BFS&#xa0;=&#xa0;86) were identified from 182 recordings. Weak ALS muscles demonstrated a lower mean inter-spike interval (82.7&#xa0;ms) than strong ALS muscles (96.0&#xa0;ms; P&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.00919) and BFS muscles (95.3&#xa0;ms; P&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.0039). Mean MU potential area (area under the curve: 487.5 vs. 98.7&#xa0;&#x3bc;V ms; P&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;0.0001) and muscle fibre conduction velocity (6.2 vs. 5.1&#xa0;m/s; P&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.0292) were greater in weak ALS muscles than in BFS muscles. Purely fasciculating MUs had a greater mean MU potential area than MUs also under voluntary command (area under the curve: 679.6 vs. 232.4 &#x3bc;V ms; P&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.00144). These results suggest that first-recruited MUs develop a faster phenotype in the latter stages of ALS, likely driven by the preferential loss of vulnerable fast-twitch MUs. Inhibition of this potentially maladaptive phenotypic drift may protect the longevity of the MU pool, stimulating a novel therapeutic avenue.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 The Authors. The Journal of Physiology published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of The Physiological Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Weddell</LastName><ForeName>Thomas</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>UK Dementia Research Institute, Department of Basic and Clinical Neuroscience, Maurice Wohl Clinical Neuroscience Institute, Institute of Psychiatry, Psychology and Neuroscience, King's College London, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bashford</LastName><ForeName>James</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5972-0748</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>UK Dementia Research Institute, Department of Basic and Clinical Neuroscience, Maurice Wohl Clinical Neuroscience Institute, Institute of Psychiatry, Psychology and Neuroscience, King's College London, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wickham</LastName><ForeName>Aidan</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Bioengineering, Imperial College London, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Iniesta</LastName><ForeName>Raquel</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biostatistics and Health Informatics, King's College London, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Maoqi</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Rehabilitation Engineering, The University of Rehabilitation, Qingdao, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Ping</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Rehabilitation Engineering, The University of Rehabilitation, Qingdao, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Drakakis</LastName><ForeName>Emmanuel</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Bioengineering, Imperial College London, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Boutelle</LastName><ForeName>Martyn</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1332-3442</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Bioengineering, Imperial College London, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mills</LastName><ForeName>Kerry</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>UK Dementia Research Institute, Department of Basic and Clinical Neuroscience, Maurice Wohl Clinical Neuroscience Institute, Institute of Psychiatry, Psychology and Neuroscience, King's College London, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shaw</LastName><ForeName>Chris</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>UK Dementia Research Institute, Department of Basic and Clinical Neuroscience, Maurice Wohl Clinical Neuroscience Institute, Institute of Psychiatry, Psychology and Neuroscience, King's College London, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>BASHFORD/JUN16/947-795</GrantID><Acronym>MNDA_</Acronym><Agency>Motor Neurone Disease Association</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>MR/P000983/1</GrantID><Acronym>MRC_</Acronym><Agency>Medical Research Council</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>MR/P000983/1</GrantID><Agency>MRC/MNDA Lady Edith Wolfson Clinical Research Training Fellowship</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Physiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0266262</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0022-3751</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004576" MajorTopicYN="N">Electromyography</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005207" MajorTopicYN="N">Fasciculation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009046" MajorTopicYN="N">Motor Neurons</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010641" MajorTopicYN="N">Phenotype</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">afterhyperpolarization</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">decomposition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">motor unit</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">surface electromyography</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34261189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/JP281310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Al-Chalabi A, Calvo A, Chio A, Colville S, Ellis CM, Hardiman O, Heverin M, Howard RS, Huisman MHB, Keren N, Leigh PN, Mazzini L, Mora G, Orrell RW, Rooney J, Scott KM, Scotton WJ, Seelen M, Shaw CE, Sidle KS, Swingler R, Tsuda M, Veldink JH, Visser AE, Van Den Berg LH &amp; Pearce N (2014). Analysis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis as a multistep process: a population-based modelling study. Lancet Neurol 13, 1108-1113.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Chalabi A &amp; Hardiman O (2013). The epidemiology of ALS: a conspiracy of genes, environment and time. Nat Rev Neurol 9, 617-628.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baldwin K, Haddad F, Pandorf C, Roy R &amp; Edgerton R (2013). Alterations in muscle mass and contractile phenotype in response to unloading models: role of transcriptional/pretranslational mechanisms. Front Physiol 4, 284.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bashford J, Mills K &amp; Shaw C (2020a). The evolving role of surface electromyography in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A systematic review. Clin Neurophysiol 131, 942-950.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bashford J, Wickham A, Iniesta R, Drakakis E, Boutelle M, Mills K &amp; Shaw C (2019). SPiQE: an automated analytical tool for detecting and characterising fasciculations in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Neurophysiol 130, 1083-1090.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bashford JA, Wickham A, Iniesta R, Drakakis EM, Boutelle MG, Mills KR &amp; Shaw CE (2020b). The rise and fall of fasciculations in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain Commun 2, fcaa018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baumer D, Talbot K &amp; Turner MR (2014). Advances in motor neurone disease. J R Soc Med 107, 14-21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beuche W, Yushchenko M, M&#xe4;der M, Maliszewska M, Felgenhauer K &amp; Weber F (2000). Matrix metalloproteinase-9 is elevated in serum of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuroreport 11, 3419-3422.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bostock H, Sharief MK, Reid G &amp; Murray NM (1995). Axonal ion channel dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain 118, 217-25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, Miller RG, Swash M &amp; Munsat TL (2000). El Escorial revisited: revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord 1, 293-299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brownstone RM &amp; Lancelin C (2018). Escape from homeostasis: spinal microcircuits and progression of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurophysiol 119, 1782-1794.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke R (2011). Motor units: anatomy, physiology, and functional organization. In Comprehensive Physiology, ed. Terjung R, pp. 345-422. Wiley &amp; Sons.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke RE, Levine DN &amp; Zajac FE, 3rd (1971). Mammalian motor units: physiological-histochemical correlation in three types in cat gastrocnemius. Science 174, 709-712.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calvin WH (1974). Three modes of repetitive firing and the role of threshold time course between spikes. Brain Res 69, 341-346.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen M, Zhang X, Chen X &amp; Zhou P (2018a). Automatic implementation of progressive FastICA peel-off for high density surface EMG decomposition. IEEE Trans Neural Syst Rehabil Eng 26, 144-152.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen M, Zhang X &amp; Zhou P (2018b). A novel validation approach for high-density surface EMG decomposition in motor neuron disease. IEEE Trans Neural Syst Rehabil Eng 26, 1161-1168.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen M &amp; Zhou P (2016). A novel framework based on FastICA for high density surface EMG decomposition. IEEE Trans Neural Syst Rehabil Eng 24, 117-127.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conradi S, Grimby L &amp; Lundemo G (1982). Pathophysiology of fasciculations in ALS as studied by electromyography of single motor units. Muscle Nerve 5, 202-208.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Carvalho M &amp; Swash M (1998). Fasciculation potentials: a study of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and other neurogenic disorders. Muscle Nerve 21, 336-44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Carvalho M &amp; Swash M (2016). Lower motor neuron dysfunction in ALS. Clin Neurophysiol 127, 2670-2681.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Carvalho M &amp; Swash M (2017). Physiology of the fasciculation potentials in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: which motor units fasciculate? J Physiol Sci 67, 569-576.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Carvalho M, Turkman A, Pinto S &amp; Swash M (2016). Modulation of fasciculation frequency in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 87, 226-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Del Vecchio A, Negro F, Felici F &amp; Farina D (2018). Distribution of muscle fibre conduction velocity for representative samples of motor units in the full recruitment range of the tibialis anterior muscle. Acta Physiol (Oxf), 222.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frey D, Schneider C, Xu L, Borg J, Spooren W &amp; Caroni P (2000). Early and selective loss of neuromuscular synapse subtypes with low sprouting competence in motoneuron diseases. J Neurosci 20, 2534-2542.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gardiner P, Dai Y &amp; Heckman CJ (2006). Effects of exercise training on alpha-motoneurons. J Appl Physiol 101, 1228-1236.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gossen ER, Ivanova TD &amp; Garland SJ (2003). The time course of the motoneurone afterhyperpolarization is related to motor unit twitch speed in human skeletal muscle. J Physiol 552, 657-664.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guiloff RJ &amp; Modarres-Sadeghi H (1992). Voluntary activation and fiber density of fasciculations in motor neuron disease. Ann Neurol 31, 416-424.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hegedus J, Putman CT, Tyreman N &amp; Gordon T (2008). Preferential motor unit loss in the SOD1 G93A transgenic mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Physiol 586, 3337-3351.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janko M, Trontelj JV &amp; Gersak K (1989). Fasciculations in motor neuron disease: discharge rate reflects extent and recency of collateral sprouting. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 52, 1375-1381.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaplan A, Spiller KJ, Towne C, Kanning KC, Choe GT, Geber A, Akay T, Aebischer P &amp; Henderson CE (2014). Neuronal matrix metalloproteinase-9 is a determinant of selective neurodegeneration. Neuron 81, 333-348.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiernan MC, Vucic S, Cheah BC, Turner MR, Eisen A, Hardiman O, Burrell JR &amp; Zoing MC (2011). Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet 377, 942-955.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuo JJ, Siddique T, Fu R &amp; Heckman CJ (2005). Increased persistent Na(+) current and its effect on excitability in motoneurones cultured from mutant SOD1 mice. J Physiol 563, 843-854.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li W &amp; Sakamoto K (1996). Distribution of muscle fiber conduction velocity of M. biceps brachii during voluntary isometric contraction with use of surface array electrodes. Appl Human Sci 15, 41-53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lutz C (2018). Mouse models of ALS: past, present and future. Brain Res 1693, 1-10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin E, Cazenave W, Cattaert D &amp; Branchereau P (2013). Embryonic alteration of motoneuronal morphology induces hyperexcitability in the mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurobiol Dis 54, 116-126.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;nez-Silva ML, Imhoff-Manuel RD, Sharma A, Heckman CJ, Shneider NA, Roselli F, Zytnicki D &amp; Manuel M (2018). Hypoexcitability precedes denervation in the large fast-contracting motor units in two unrelated mouse models of ALS. Elife 7, e30955.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matthews PB (1996). Relationship of firing intervals of human motor units to the trajectory of post-spike after-hyperpolarization and synaptic noise. The Journal of Physiology 492, 597-628.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milner-Brown HS, Stein RB &amp; Yemm R (1973). The orderly recruitment of human motor units during voluntary isometric contractions. J Physiol 230, 359-370.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morisaki Y, Niikura M, Watanabe M, Onishi K, Tanabe S, Moriwaki Y, Okuda T, Ohara S, Murayama S, Takao M, Uchida S, Yamanaka K &amp; Misawa H (2016). Selective expression of osteopontin in ALS-resistant motor neurons is a critical determinant of late phase neurodegeneration mediated by matrix metalloproteinase-9. Sci Rep 6, 27354.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pieri M, Albo F, Gaetti C, Spalloni A, Bengtson CP, Longone P, Cavalcanti S &amp; Zona C (2003). Altered excitability of motor neurons in a transgenic mouse model of familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurosci Lett 351, 153-156.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piotrkiewicz M (1999). An influence of afterhyperpolarization on the pattern of motoneuronal rhythmic activity. J Physiol Paris 93, 125-133.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piotrkiewicz M &amp; Hausmanowa-Petrusewicz I (2011). Motoneuron afterhyperpolarisation duration in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Physiol 589, 2745-2754.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piotrkiewicz M, Kudina L, Hausmanowa-Petrusewicz I, Zhoukovskaya N &amp; Mierzejewska J (2001). Discharge properties and afterhyperpolarization of human motoneurons. Biocyber Biomed Eng 21, 53-75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pun S, Santos AF, Saxena S, Xu L &amp; Caroni P (2006). Selective vulnerability and pruning of phasic motoneuron axons in motoneuron disease alleviated by CNTF. Nat Neurosci 9, 408-419.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saxena S, Roselli F, Singh K, Leptien K, Julien JP, Gros-Louis F &amp; Caroni P (2013). Neuroprotection through excitability and mTOR required in ALS motoneurons to delay disease and extend survival. Neuron 80, 80-96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soares FA, Carvalho JL, Miosso CJ, De Andrade MM &amp; Da Rocha AF (2015). Motor unit action potential conduction velocity estimated from surface electromyographic signals using image processing techniques. Biomed Eng Online 14, 84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soon CP, Crouch PJ, Turner BJ, Mclean CA, Laughton KM, Atkin JD, Masters CL, White AR &amp; Li QX (2010). Serum matrix metalloproteinase-9 activity is dysregulated with disease progression in the mutant SOD1 transgenic mice. Neuromuscul Disord 20, 260-266.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spiller KJ, Cheung CJ, Restrepo CR, Kwong LK, Stieber AM, Trojanowski JQ &amp; Lee VM (2016). Selective motor neuron resistance and recovery in a new inducible mouse model of TDP-43 proteinopathy. J Neurosci 36, 7707-7717.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trojaborg W &amp; Buchthal F (1965). Malignant and benign fasciculations. Acta Neurol Scand Suppl 13, 251-254.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Den Bos MAJ, Geevasinga N, Higashihara M, Menon P &amp; Vucic S (2019). Pathophysiology and diagnosis of ALS: insights from advances in neurophysiological techniques. Int J Mol Sci 20, 2818.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamamoto T, Murayama S, Takao M, Isa T &amp; Higo N (2017). Expression of secreted phosphoprotein 1 (osteopontin) in human sensorimotor cortex and spinal cord: Changes in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain Res 1655, 168-175.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>