<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">34296470</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1550-9613</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>41</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>May</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of ultrasound in medicine : official journal of the American Institute of Ultrasound in Medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Ultrasound Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Evaluation of Longitudinal Strain of Large and Small Abdominal Aortic Aneurysm by Two-Dimensional Speckle-Tracking Ultrasound.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1085</StartPage><EndPage>1093</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1085-1093</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jum.15792</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Abdominal aortic aneurysm (AAA) is a dangerous and lethal vascular disease. Non-invasive two-dimensional speckle-tracking imaging (2D STI) plays an important role in assessing aortic biomechanical properties. Our study aimed to evaluate the alterations of biomechanical characteristics using 2D STI in 91 AAA patients with different size.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Aneurysm strain, elastic modulus, stiffness index &#x3b2;, and aortic distensibility determined by M-Mode ultrasound (US), and longitudinal strain (LS) derived from 2D STI were compared in 40 large AAA patients (diameter&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;55&#x2009;mm) and 51 small AAA patients (diameter&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;55&#x2009;mm).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Compared with small AAA group, anterior wall longitudinal strain (ALS) and posterior wall longitudinal strain (PLS) were significantly decreased in large AAA group (all P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;.05) and not affected by age, symptom, hypertension, and thrombus. Meanwhile, ALS and PLS correlated negatively with maximal aneurysm diameters (r&#xa0;=&#xa0;-0.628 and -0.469, respectively, all P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;.001). And only ALS was associated with M-Mode US parameters (all P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;.05). Based on receiver operating characteristic (ROC) analysis, ALS and PLS had strong diagnostic values for large AAA with the area under the curve (AUC) of 0.82 and 0.72, and cut-off points of 1.71 and 1.64% with a sensitivity of 78 and 72%, and a specificity of 75 and 70%, respectively.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">LS measured by 2D STI could evaluate the biomechanical properties of aneurysm wall with different size, and add additional diagnostic value in distinguishing between small and large AAA.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 American Institute of Ultrasound in Medicine.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ning</LastName><ForeName>Hongxia</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiovascular Ultrasound, The First Hospital of China Medical University, Shenyang, Liaoning Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Xiaozheng</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiovascular Ultrasound, The First Hospital of China Medical University, Shenyang, Liaoning Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ma</LastName><ForeName>Chunyan</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3327-736X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiovascular Ultrasound, The First Hospital of China Medical University, Shenyang, Liaoning Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Jun</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiovascular Ultrasound, The First Hospital of China Medical University, Shenyang, Liaoning Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Tan</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0386-4616</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiovascular Ultrasound, The First Hospital of China Medical University, Shenyang, Liaoning Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>82001828</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2020-BS-102</GrantID><Agency>Natural Science Foundation of Liaoning Province</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Ultrasound Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8211547</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0278-4297</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001011" MajorTopicYN="N">Aorta</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001012" MajorTopicYN="N">Aorta, Abdominal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017544" MajorTopicYN="Y">Aortic Aneurysm, Abdominal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004452" MajorTopicYN="N">Echocardiography</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014463" MajorTopicYN="N">Ultrasonography</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">abdominal aortic aneurysm</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">biomechanics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">longitudinal strain</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">two-dimensional speckle-tracking imaging</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34296470</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jum.15792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Kent KC. Clinical practice. Abdominal aortic aneurysms. N Engl J Med 2014; 371:2101-2108.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moll FL, Powell JT, Fraedrich G, et al. Management of abdominal aortic aneurysms clinical practice guidelines of the European society for vascular surgery. Eur J Vasc Endovasc Surg 2011; 41:S1-s58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaikof EL, Dalman RL, Eskandari MK, et al. The Society for Vascular Surgery practice guidelines on the care of patients with an abdominal aortic aneurysm. J Vasc Surg 2018; 67:2-77.e2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wanhainen A, Verzini F, Van Herzeele I, et al. Editor's choice-European Society for Vascular Surgery (ESVS) 2019 clinical practice guidelines on the management of abdominal aorto-iliac artery aneurysms. Eur J Vasc Endovasc Surg 2019; 57:8-93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bihari P, Shelke A, Nwe TH, et al. Strain measurement of abdominal aortic aneurysm with real-time 3D ultrasound speckle tracking. Eur J Vasc Endovasc Surg 2013; 45:315-323.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soto B, Vila L, Dilm&#xe9; JF, Escudero JR, Bellmunt S, Camacho M. Increased peak wall stress, but not maximum diameter, is associated with symptomatic abdominal aortic aneurysm. Eur J Vasc Endovasc Surg 2017; 54:706-711.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Disseldorp EMJ, Petterson NJ, van de Vosse FN, van Sambeek M, Lopata RGP. Quantification of aortic stiffness and wall stress in healthy volunteers and abdominal aortic aneurysm patients using time-resolved 3D ultrasound: a comparison study. Eur Heart J Cardiovasc Imaging 2019; 20:185-191.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doyle BJ, McGloughlin TM, Miller K, Powell JT, Norman PE. Regions of high wall stress can predict the future location of rupture of abdominal aortic aneurysm. Cardiovasc Intervent Radiol 2014; 37:815-818.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khosla S, Morris DR, Moxon JV, Walker PJ, Gasser TC, Golledge J. Meta-analysis of peak wall stress in ruptured, symptomatic and intact abdominal aortic aneurysms. Br J Surg 2014; 101:1350-1357. discussion 1357.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gasser TC, Nchimi A, Swedenborg J, et al. A novel strategy to translate the biomechanical rupture risk of abdominal aortic aneurysms to their equivalent diameter risk: method and retrospective validation. Eur J Vasc Endovasc Surg 2014; 47:288-295.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mantella LE, Chan W, Bisleri G, et al. The use of ultrasound to assess aortic biomechanics: implications for aneurysm and dissection. Echocardiography 2020; 37:1844-1850.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cho JY, Kim KH. Evaluation of arterial stiffness by echocardiography: methodological aspects. Chonnam Med J 2016; 52:101-106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrini J, Eriksson MJ, Caidahl K, Larsson M. Circumferential strain by velocity vector imaging and speckle-tracking echocardiography: validation against sonomicrometry in an aortic phantom. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging 2018; 38:269-277.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bieseviciene M, Vaskelyte JJ, Mizariene V, Karaliute R, Lesauskaite V, Verseckaite R. Two-dimensional speckle-tracking echocardiography for evaluation of dilative ascending aorta biomechanics. BMC Cardiovasc Disord 2017; 17:27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batagini NC, Ventura CA, Raghavan ML, Chammas MC, Tachibana A, da Silva ES. Volumetry and biomechanical parameters detected by 3D and 2D ultrasound in patients with and without an abdominal aortic aneurysm. Vasc Med 2016; 21:209-216.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longobardo L, Carerj ML, Pizzino G, et al. Impairment of elastic properties of the aorta in bicuspid aortic valve: relationship between biomolecular and aortic strain patterns. Eur Heart J Cardiovasc Imaging 2018; 19:879-887.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lederle FA, Johnson GR, Wilson SE, et al. Rupture rate of large abdominal aortic aneurysms in patients refusing or unfit for elective repair. Jama 2002; 287:2968-2972.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nemes A, Geleijnse ML, Forster T, Soliman OI, Ten Cate FJ, Csan&#xe1;dy M. Echocardiographic evaluation and clinical implications of aortic stiffness and coronary flow reserve and their relation. Clin Cardiol 2008; 31:304-309.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oishi Y, Mizuguchi Y, Miyoshi H, Iuchi A, Nagase N, Oki T. A novel approach to assess aortic stiffness related to changes in aging using a two-dimensional strain imaging. Echocardiography 2008; 25:941-945.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maier A, Gee MW, Reeps C, Pongratz J, Eckstein HH, Wall WA. A comparison of diameter, wall stress, and rupture potential index for abdominal aortic aneurysm rupture risk prediction. Ann Biomed Eng 2010; 38:3124-3134.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raaz U, Z&#xf6;llner AM, Schellinger IN, et al. Segmental aortic stiffening contributes to experimental abdominal aortic aneurysm development. Circulation 2015; 131:1783-1795.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doyle BJ, Bappoo N, Syed MBJ, et al. Biomechanical assessment predicts aneurysm related events in patients with abdominal aortic aneurysm. Eur J Vasc Endovasc Surg 2020; 60:365-373.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabia L, Avenatti E, Cesareo M, et al. Evaluation of aortic stiffness by a new simplified 2D speckle tracking analysis. Int J Cardiovasc Imaging 2018; 34:1753-1760.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oberhoffer FS, Abdul-Khaliq H, Jung AM, Rohrer TR, Abd El Rahman M. Two-dimensional speckle tracking of the abdominal aorta: a novel approach to evaluate arterial stiffness in patients with turner syndrome. Cardiovasc Diagn Ther 2019; 9:S228-s237.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taniguchi R, Hoshina K, Hosaka A, et al. Strain analysis of wall motion in abdominal aortic aneurysms. Ann Vasc Dis 2014; 7:393-398.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Wang T, Haines P, et al. Prognostic value of right ventricular two-dimensional and three-dimensional speckle-tracking strain in pulmonary arterial hypertension: superiority of longitudinal strain over circumferential and radial strain. J Am Soc Echocardiogr 2020; 33:985-994.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longobardo L, Carerj S, Bitto A, et al. Bicuspid aortic valve and aortopathy: novel prognostic predictors for the identification of high-risk patients. Eur Heart J Cardiovasc Imaging 2021; 22:808-816. https://doi.org/10.1093/ehjci/jeaa250.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson KA, Lindholt JS, Hoskins PR, Heickendorff L, Vammen S, Bradbury AW. The relationship between abdominal aortic aneurysm distensibility and serum markers of elastin and collagen metabolism. Eur J Vasc Endovasc Surg 2001; 21:175-178.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izzo JL Jr. Arterial stiffness and the systolic hypertension syndrome. Curr Opin Cardiol 2004; 19:341-352.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson K, Bradbury A, Whyman M, et al. Relationship between abdominal aortic aneurysm wall compliance and clinical outcome: a preliminary analysis. Eur J Vasc Endovasc Surg 1998; 15:472-477.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson KA, Lee AJ, Lee AJ, et al. The relationship between aortic wall distensibility and rupture of infrarenal abdominal aortic aneurysm. J Vasc Surg 2003; 37:112-117.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>