<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">34309938</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>13</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1440-1789</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>41</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Neuropathology : official journal of the Japanese Society of Neuropathology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Neuropathology</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>An autopsy case report of neuronal intermediate filament inclusion disease presenting with predominantly upper motor neuron features.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>357</StartPage><EndPage>365</EndPage><MedlinePgn>357-365</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/neup.12741</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>We describe an autopsy case of neuronal intermediate filament inclusion disease (NIFID), a subtype of frontotemporal lobar degeneration (FTLD) with the appearance of fused-in-sarcoma (FUS) inclusions (FTLD-FUS). A 57-year-old man developed dysarthria and dysphagia. One year and five&#x2009;months later, he was admitted to a hospital, and pseudobulbar palsy and right upper motor neuron signs were observed on examination. Needle electromyography revealed no active or chronic denervation. His neurological symptoms gradually deteriorated, and behavioral alterations occurred. He died of hemoperitoneum secondary to rupture of a ureteric tumor. The total duration of the disease was six years and 10&#x2009;months. Neuropathologically, the frontal cortex, including the motor cortex, and the pyramidal tract were severely affected, whereas the lower motor neurons in the spinal cord and brainstem were mildly damaged. The striatum and substantia nigra were also severely damaged. Hyaline conglomerate inclusions, neuronal cytoplasmic inclusions with a distinct eosinophilic core (so-called cherry spot), Pick body-like inclusions, and eosinophilic round inclusions were observed in the remaining neurons. Immunohistochemical examination revealed that these inclusions were immunoreactive for FUS. HC inclusions were also immunoreactive for &#x3b1;-internexin and phosphorylated neurofilament protein. FUS-immunoreactive NCIs were abundant in the basal ganglia but not in the hippocampus, in contrast to previously reported NIFID cases. Furthermore, Bunina bodies identified by immunohistochemistry for cystatin C were also observed in the lower motor neurons. Bunina bodies may be present in NIFID. This case confirms the pathological heterogeneity of NIFID and supports the notion of the difference between amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and NIFID.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 Japanese Society of Neuropathology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Murakami</LastName><ForeName>Aya</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Kansai Medical University, Hirakata, Osaka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nakamura</LastName><ForeName>Masataka</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0439-5682</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Kansai Medical University, Hirakata, Osaka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nakamura</LastName><ForeName>Yoshimi</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Kansai Medical University, Hirakata, Osaka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kaneko</LastName><ForeName>Satoshi</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Kansai Medical University, Hirakata, Osaka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yakushiji</LastName><ForeName>Yusuke</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Kansai Medical University, Hirakata, Osaka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kusaka</LastName><ForeName>Hirofumi</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Australia</Country><MedlineTA>Neuropathology</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9606526</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0919-6544</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D034702">RNA-Binding Protein FUS</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001344" MajorTopicYN="N">Autopsy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003586" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cytomegalovirus Infections</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007382" MajorTopicYN="N">Intermediate Filaments</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016472" MajorTopicYN="Y">Motor Neuron Disease</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009046" MajorTopicYN="N">Motor Neurons</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D034702" MajorTopicYN="N">RNA-Binding Protein FUS</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bunina bodies</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">frontotemporal lobar degeneration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fused in sarcoma</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hyaline conglomerate inclusion</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neuronal intermediate filament inclusion disease</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34309938</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/neup.12741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Bigio EH, Lipton AM, White CL 3rd, Dickson DW, Hirano A. Frontotemporal and motor neurone degeneration with neurofilament inclusion bodies: Additional evidence for overlap between FTD and ALS. Neuropathol Appl Neurobiol 2003; 29: 239-253.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cairns NJ, Perry RH, Jaros E et al. Patients with a novel neurofilamentopathy: Dementia with neurofilament inclusions. Neurosci Lett 2003; 341: 177-180.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Josephs KA, Holton JL, Rossor MN et al. Neurofilament inclusion body disease: A new proteinopathy? Brain 2003; 126: 2291-2303.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cairns NJ, Grossman M, Arnold SE et al. Clinical and neuropathologic variation in neuronal intermediate filament inclusion disease. Neurology 2004; 63: 1376-1384.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armstrong RA, Kerty E, Skullerud K, Cairns NJ. Neuropathological changes in ten cases of neuronal intermediate filament inclusion disease (NIFID): A study using alpha-internexin immunohistochemistry and principal components analysis (PCA). J Neural Transm (Vienna) 2006; 113: 1207-1215.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cairns NJ, Uryu K, Bigio EH, et al. alpha-Internexin aggregates are abundant in neuronal intermediate filament inclusion disease (NIFID) but rare in other neurodegenerative diseases. Acta Neuropathol 2004; 108: 213-223.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armstrong RA, Cairns NJ. Spatial patterns of the pathological changes in neuronal intermediate filament inclusion disease (NIFID): An alpha-internexin immunohistochemical study. J Neural Transm (Vienna) 2007; 114: 451-456.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uchikado H, Li A, Lin WL, Dickson DW. Heterogeneous inclusions in neurofilament inclusion disease. Neuropathology 2006; 26: 417-421.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neumann M, Roeber S, Kretzschmar HA, Rademakers R, Baker M, Mackenzie IR. Abundant FUS-immunoreactive pathology in neuronal intermediate filament inclusion disease. Acta Neuropathol 2009; 118: 605-616.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackenzie IR, Neumann M, Bigio EH et al. Nomenclature and nosology for neuropathologic subtypes of frontotemporal lobar degeneration: An update. Acta Neuropathol 2010; 119: 1-4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inoue K, Fujimura H, Ueda K, Matsumura T, Itoh K, Sakoda S. An autopsy case of neuronal intermediate filament inclusion disease with regard to immunophenotypic and topographical analysis of the neuronal inclusions. Neuropathology 2015; 35: 545-552.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ito H. Basophilic inclusions and neuronal intermediate filament inclusions in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal lobar degeneration. Neuropathology 2014; 34: 589-595.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armstrong RA, Gearing M, Bigio EH et al. The spectrum and severity of FUS-immunoreactive inclusions in the frontal and temporal lobes of ten cases of neuronal intermediate filament inclusion disease. Acta Neuropathol 2011; 121: 219-228.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gelpi E, Llad&#xf3; A, Clarim&#xf3;n J et al. Phenotypic variability within the inclusion body spectrum of basophilic inclusion body disease and neuronal intermediate filament inclusion disease in frontotemporal lobar degenerations with FUS-positive inclusions. J Neuropathol Exp Neurol 2012; 71: 795-805.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kobayashi Z, Kawakami I, Arai T et al. Pathological features of FTLD-FUS in a Japanese population: Analyses of nine cases. J Neurol Sci 2013; 335: 89-95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mosaheb S, Thorpe JR, Hashemzadeh-Bonehi L, Bigio EH, Gearing M, Cairns NJ. Neuronal intranuclear inclusions are ultrastructurally and immunologically distinct from cytoplasmic inclusions of neuronal intermediate filament inclusion disease. Acta Neuropathol 2005; 110: 360-368.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page T, Gitcho MA, Mosaheb S et al. FUS immunogold labeling TEM analysis of the neuronal cytoplasmic inclusions of neuronal intermediate filament inclusion disease: A frontotemporal lobar degeneration with FUS proteinopathy. J Mol Neurosci 2011; 45: 409-421.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakamura M, Bieniek KF, Lin WL, et al. A truncating SOD1 mutation, p.Gly141X, is associated with clinical and pathologic heterogeneity, including frontotemporal lobar degeneration. Acta Neuropathol 2015; 130: 145-157.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ching GY, Chien CL, Flores R, Liem RK. Overexpression of alpha-internexin causes abnormal neurofilamentous accumulations and motor coordination deficits in transgenic mice. J Neurosci 1999; 19: 2974-2986.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGraw TS, Mickle JP, Shaw G, Streit WJ. Axonally transported peripheral signals regulate alpha-internexin expression in regenerating motoneurons. J Neurosci 2002; 22: 4955-4963.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okamoto K, Hirai S, Amari M, Watanabe M, Sakurai A. Bunina bodies in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis immunostained with rabbit anti-cystatin C serum. Neurosci Lett 1993; 162: 125-128.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mizuno Y, Amari M, Takatama M, Aizawa H, Mihara B, Okamoto K. Transferrin localizes in Bunina bodies in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathol 2006; 112: 597-603.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neumann M, Valori CF, Ansorge O et al. Transportin 1 accumulates specifically with FET proteins but no other transportin cargos in FTLD-FUS and is absent in FUS inclusions in ALS with FUS mutations. Acta Neuropathol 2012; 124: 705-716.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>