<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">34339378</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2168-2208</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>IEEE journal of biomedical and health informatics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>IEEE J Biomed Health Inform</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>VoxelHop: Successive Subspace Learning for ALS Disease Classification Using Structural MRI.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1128</StartPage><EndPage>1139</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1128-1139</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1109/JBHI.2021.3097735</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Deep learning has great potential for accurate detection and classification of diseases with medical imaging data, but the performance is often limited by the number of training datasets and memory requirements. In addition, many deep learning models are considered a "black-box," thereby often limiting their adoption in clinical applications. To address this, we present a successive subspace learning model, termed VoxelHop, for accurate classification of Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis (ALS) using T2-weighted structural MRI data. Compared with popular convolutional neural network (CNN) architectures, VoxelHop has modular and transparent structures with fewer parameters without any backpropagation, so it is well-suited to small dataset size and 3D imaging data. Our VoxelHop has four key components, including (1) sequential expansion of near-to-far neighborhood for multi-channel 3D data; (2) subspace approximation for unsupervised dimension reduction; (3) label-assisted regression for supervised dimension reduction; and (4) concatenation of features and classification between controls and patients. Our experimental results demonstrate that our framework using a total of 20 controls and 26 patients achieves an accuracy of 93.48 % and an AUC score of 0.9394 in differentiating patients from controls, even with a relatively small number of datasets, showing its robustness and effectiveness. Our thorough evaluations also show its validity and superiority to the state-of-the-art 3D CNN classification approaches. Our framework can easily be generalized to other classification tasks using different imaging modalities.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Xiaofeng</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xing</LastName><ForeName>Fangxu</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Chao</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kuo</LastName><ForeName>Chung-Chieh Jay</ForeName><Initials>CJ</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Babu</LastName><ForeName>Suma</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fakhri</LastName><ForeName>Georges El</ForeName><Initials>GE</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jenkins</LastName><ForeName>Thomas</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Woo</LastName><ForeName>Jonghye</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>P41 EB022544</GrantID><Acronym>EB</Acronym><Agency>NIBIB NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01 AG076153</GrantID><Acronym>AG</Acronym><Agency>NIA NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01 DC018511</GrantID><Acronym>DC</Acronym><Agency>NIDCD NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>IEEE J Biomed Health Inform</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101604520</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-2194</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008279" MajorTopicYN="N">Magnetic Resonance Imaging</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016571" MajorTopicYN="N">Neural Networks, Computer</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34339378</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS1735875</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8807766</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JBHI.2021.3097735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Goodfellow I, Bengio Y, Courville A, and Bengio Y, Deep learning. MIT press Cambridge, 2016, vol. 1, no. 2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rav&#xec; D, Wong C, Deligianni F, Berthelot M, Andreu-Perez J, Lo B, and Yang G-Z, &#x201c;Deep learning for health informatics,&#x201d; IEEE journal of biomedical and health informatics, vol. 21, no. 1, pp. 4&#x2013;21, 2016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28055930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen D, Wu G, and Suk H-I, &#x201c;Deep learning in medical image analysis,&#x201d; Annual review of biomedical engineering, vol. 19, pp. 221&#x2013;248, 2017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5479722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28301734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh SP, Wang L, Gupta S, Goli H, Padmanabhan P, and Guly&#xe1;s B, &#x201c;3d deep learning on medical images: A review,&#x201d; arXiv preprint arXiv:2004.00218, 2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7570704</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32906819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krizhevsky A, Sutskever I, and Hinton GE, &#x201c;Imagenet classification with deep convolutional neural networks,&#x201d; Communications of the ACM, vol. 60, no. 6, pp. 84&#x2013;90, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simonyan K and Zisserman A, &#x201c;Very deep convolutional networks for large-scale image recognition,&#x201d; arXiv preprint arXiv:1409.1556, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He K, Zhang X, Ren S, and Sun J, &#x201c;Identity mappings in deep residual networks,&#x201d; in European conference on computer vision. Springer, 2016, pp. 630&#x2013;645.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng H, Gong W, Beckmann CF, Vedaldi A, and Smith SM, &#x201c;Accurate brain age prediction with lightweight deep neural networks,&#x201d; BioRxiv, 2019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7610710</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33197716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuo C-CJ, &#x201c;Understanding convolutional neural networks with a mathematical model,&#x201d; Journal of Visual Communication and Image Representation, vol. 41, pp. 406&#x2013;413, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jenkins TM, Alix JJ, Fingret J, Esmail T, Hoggard N, Baster K, McDermott CJ, Wilkinson ID, and Shaw PJ, &#x201c;Longitudinal multi-modal muscle-based biomarker assessment in motor neuron disease,&#x201d; Journal of neurology, vol. 267, no. 1, pp. 244&#x2013;256, 2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6954906</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31624953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner MR, Grosskreutz J, Kassubek J, Abrahams S, Agosta F, Benatar M, Filippi M, Goldstein LH, van den Heuvel M, Kalra S et al., &#x201c;Towards a neuroimaging biomarker for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis,&#x201d; The Lancet Neurology, vol. 10, no. 5, pp. 400&#x2013;403, 2011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21511189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babu S, &#x201c;Upper motor neuron burden measurement in motor neuron diseases: Does one scale fit all?&#x201d; Muscle &amp; Nerve, vol. 61, no. 4, pp. 431&#x2013;432, 2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32068892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abrahams S, Goldstein L, Simmons A, Brammer M, Williams S, Giampietro V, and Leigh P, &#x201c;Word retrieval in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a functional magnetic resonance imaging study,&#x201d; Brain, vol. 127, no. 7, pp. 1507&#x2013;1517, 2004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15163610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang J, Lomen-Hoerth C, Murphy J, Henry R, Kramer J, Miller B, and Gorno-Tempini M, &#x201c;A voxel-based morphometry study of patterns of brain atrophy in ALS and ALS/FTLD,&#x201d; Neurology, vol. 65, no. 1, pp. 75&#x2013;80, 2005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16009889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee E, Xing F, Ahn S, Reese TG, Wang R, Green JR, Atassi N, Wedeen VJ, El Fakhri G, and Woo J, &#x201c;Magnetic resonance imaging based anatomical assessment of tongue impairment due to amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a preliminary study,&#x201d; The Journal of the Acoustical Society of America, vol. 143, no. 4, pp. EL248&#x2013;EL254, 2018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5895467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29716267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashburner J and Friston KJ, &#x201c;Voxel-based morphometry&#x2014;the methods,&#x201d; Neuroimage, vol. 11, no. 6, pp. 805&#x2013;821, 2000.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10860804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baron J, Chetelat G, Desgranges B, Perchey G, Landeau B, De La Sayette V, and Eustache F, &#x201c;In vivo mapping of gray matter loss with voxel-based morphometry in mild alzheimer&#x2019;s disease,&#x201d; Neuroimage, vol. 14, no. 2, pp. 298&#x2013;309, 2001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11467904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xe4;rk&#xe4;m&#xf6; T, Ripoll&#xe9;s P, Veps&#xe4;l&#xe4;inen H, Autti T, Silvennoinen HM, Salli E, Laitinen S, Forsblom A, Soinila S, and Rodr&#xed;guez-Fornells A, &#x201c;Structural changes induced by daily music listening in the recovering brain after middle cerebral artery stroke: a voxel-based morphometry study,&#x201d; Frontiers in Human Neuroscience, vol. 8, p. 245, 2014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4029020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24860466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gale SD, Baxter L, Roundy N, and Johnson S, &#x201c;Traumatic brain injury and grey matter concentration: a preliminary voxel based morphometry study,&#x201d; Journal of Neurology, Neurosurgery &amp; Psychiatry, vol. 76, no. 7, pp. 984&#x2013;988, 2005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1739692</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15965207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergouignan L, Chupin M, Czechowska Y, Kinkingn&#xe9;hun S, Lemogne C, Le Bastard G, Lepage M, Garnero L, Colliot O, and Fossati P, &#x201c;Can voxel based morphometry, manual segmentation and automated segmentation equally detect hippocampal volume differences in acute depression?&#x201d; Neuroimage, vol. 45, no. 1, pp. 29&#x2013;37, 2009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19071222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cha CH and Patten BM, &#x201c;Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: abnormalities of the tongue on magnetic resonance imaging,&#x201d; Annals of Neurology, vol. 25, no. 5, pp. 468&#x2013;472, 1989.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2774487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xing F, Prince JL, Stone M, Reese TG, Atassi N, Wedeen VJ, El Fakhri G, and Woo J, &#x201c;Strain map of the tongue in normal and als speech patterns from tagged and diffusion mri,&#x201d; in Medical Imaging 2018: Image Processing, vol. 10574. International Society for Optics and Photonics, 2018, p. 1057411.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5922778</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29706684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woo J, Xing F, Prince JL, Stone M, Green JR, Goldsmith T, Reese TG, Wedeen VJ, and El Fakhri G, &#x201c;Differentiating post-cancer from healthy tongue muscle coordination patterns during speech using deep learning,&#x201d; The Journal of the Acoustical Society of America, vol. 145, no. 5, pp. EL423&#x2013;EL429, 2019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6530633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31153323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y and Kuo C-CJ, &#x201c;Pixelhop: A successive subspace learning (ssl) method for object recognition,&#x201d; Journal of Visual Communication and Image Representation, p. 102749, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang M, You H, Kadam P, Liu S, and Kuo C-CJ, &#x201c;Pointhop: An explainable machine learning method for point cloud classification,&#x201d; IEEE Transactions on Multimedia, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuo C-CJ, Zhang M, Li S, Duan J, and Chen Y, &#x201c;Interpretable convolutional neural networks via feedforward design,&#x201d; Journal of Visual Communication and Image Representation, vol. 60, pp. 346&#x2013;359, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan F, Xiong J, and Wang G, &#x201c;On interpretability of artificial neural networks,&#x201d; arXiv preprint arXiv:2001.02522, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avants B, Epstein C, Grossman M, and Gee J, &#x201c;Symmetric diffeomorphic image registration with cross-correlation: Evaluating automated labeling of elderly and neurodegenerative brain,&#x201d; Medical image analysis, vol. 12, no. 1, pp. 26&#x2013;41, 2008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2276735</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17659998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y, Rouhsedaghat M, You S, Rao R, and Kuo C-CJ, &#x201c;Pixelhop++: A small successive-subspace-learning-based (ssl-based) model for image classification,&#x201d; arXiv preprint arXiv:2002.03141, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ji S, Xu W, Yang M, and Yu K, &#x201c;3D convolutional neural networks for human action recognition,&#x201d; IEEE transactions on pattern analysis and machine intelligence, vol. 35, no. 1, pp. 221&#x2013;231, 2012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22392705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nie D, Lu J, Zhang H, Adeli E, Wang J, Yu Z, Liu L, Wang Q, Wu J, and Shen D, &#x201c;Multi-channel 3D deep feature learning for survival time prediction of brain tumor patients using multi-modal neuroimages,&#x201d; Scientific reports, vol. 9, no. 1, pp. 1&#x2013;14, 2019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6355868</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30705340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korolev S, Safiullin A, Belyaev M, and Dodonova Y, &#x201c;Residual and plain convolutional neural networks for 3d brain mri classification,&#x201d; in 2017 IEEE 14th International Symposium on Biomedical Imaging (ISBI 2017). IEEE, 2017, pp. 835&#x2013;838.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruiz J, Mahmud M, Modasshir M, Kaiser MS, f. t. Alzheimer&#x2019;s Disease Neuroimaging Initiative et al., &#x201c;3D densenet ensemble in 4-way classification of alzheimer&#x2019;s disease,&#x201d; in International Conference on Brain Informatics. Springer, 2020, pp. 85&#x2013;96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polat H and Danaei Mehr H, &#x201c;Classification of pulmonary CT images by using hybrid 3D-deep convolutional neural network architecture,&#x201d; Applied Sciences, vol. 9, no. 5, p. 940, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turk M and Pentland A, &#x201c;Eigenfaces for recognition,&#x201d; Journal of cognitive neuroscience, vol. 3, no. 1, pp. 71&#x2013;86, 1991.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23964806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan T-H, Jia K, Gao S, Lu J, Zeng Z, and Ma Y, &#x201c;Pcanet: A simple deep learning baseline for image classification?&#x201d; IEEE transactions on image processing, vol. 24, no. 12, pp. 5017&#x2013;5032, 2015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26340772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vercauteren T, Pennec X, Perchant A, and Ayache N, &#x201c;Diffeomorphic demons: Efficient non-parametric image registration,&#x201d; NeuroImage, vol. 45, no. 1, pp. S61&#x2013;S72, 2009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19041946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grollemund V, Pradat P-F, Querin G, Delbot F, Le Chat G, Pradat-Peyre J-F, and Bede P, &#x201c;Machine learning in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: achievements, pitfalls, and future directions,&#x201d; Frontiers in neuroscience, vol. 13, p. 135, 2019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6403867</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30872992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foerster BR, Welsh RC, and Feldman EL, &#x201c;25 years of neuroimaging in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis,&#x201d; Nature Reviews Neurology, vol. 9, no. 9, pp. 513&#x2013;524, 2013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4182931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23917850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kassubek J and Pagani M, &#x201c;Imaging in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Mri and pet,&#x201d; Current opinion in neurology, vol. 32, no. 5, pp. 740&#x2013;746, 2019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31335337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan M and Le Q, &#x201c;Efficientnet: Rethinking model scaling for convolutional neural networks,&#x201d; in International Conference on Machine Learning. PMLR, 2019, pp. 6105&#x2013;6114.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Q, Wu YN, and Zhu S-C, &#x201c;Interpretable convolutional neural networks,&#x201d; in Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition, 2018, pp. 8827&#x2013;8836.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ibragimov B, Prince JL, Murano EZ, Woo J, Stone M, Likar B, Pernu&#x161; F, and Vrtovec T, &#x201c;Segmentation of tongue muscles from super-resolution magnetic resonance images,&#x201d; Medical image analysis, vol. 20, no. 1, pp. 198&#x2013;207, 2015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4294977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25487963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee J, Woo J, Xing F, Murano EZ, Stone M, and Prince JL, &#x201c;Semi-automatic segmentation of the tongue for 3d motion analysis with dynamic mri,&#x201d; in 2013 IEEE 10th International Symposium on Biomedical Imaging. IEEE, 2013, pp. 1465&#x2013;1468.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3892671</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24443699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woo J, Lee J, Murano EZ, Xing F, Al-Talib M, Stone M, and Prince JL, &#x201c;A high-resolution atlas and statistical model of the vocal tract from structural MRI,&#x201d; Computer Methods in Biomechanics and Biomedical Engineering: Imaging &amp; Visualization, vol. 3, no. 1, pp. 47&#x2013;60, 2015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4465978</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26082883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>