<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">34343141</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>28</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1473-6551</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>34</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Current opinion in neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Curr Opin Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Advances in the genetic classification of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>756</StartPage><EndPage>764</EndPage><MedlinePgn>756-764</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/WCO.0000000000000986</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE OF REVIEW">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) is an archetypal complex disease wherein disease risk and severity are, for the majority of patients, the product of interaction between multiple genetic and environmental factors. We are in a period of unprecedented discovery with new large-scale genome-wide association study (GWAS) and accelerating discovery of risk genes. However, much of the observed heritability of ALS is undiscovered and we are not yet approaching elucidation of the total genetic architecture, which will be necessary for comprehensive disease subclassification.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RECENT FINDINGS">We summarize recent developments and discuss the future. New machine learning models will help to address nonlinear genetic interactions. Statistical power for genetic discovery may be boosted by reducing the search-space using cell-specific epigenetic profiles and expanding our scope to include genetically correlated phenotypes. Structural variation, somatic heterogeneity and consideration of environmental modifiers represent significant challenges which will require integration of multiple technologies and a multidisciplinary approach, including clinicians, geneticists and pathologists.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUMMARY">The move away from fully penetrant Mendelian risk genes necessitates new experimental designs and new standards for validation. The challenges are significant, but the potential reward for successful disease subclassification is large-scale and effective personalized medicine.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2021 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cooper-Knock</LastName><ForeName>Johnathan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sheffield Institute for Translational Neuroscience (SITraN), University of Sheffield, Sheffield, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Harvey</LastName><ForeName>Calum</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sheffield Institute for Translational Neuroscience (SITraN), University of Sheffield, Sheffield, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Sai</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Genetics.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Genomics and Personalized Medicine, Stanford University School of Medicine, Stanford, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moll</LastName><ForeName>Tobias</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sheffield Institute for Translational Neuroscience (SITraN), University of Sheffield, Sheffield, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Timpanaro</LastName><ForeName>Ilia Sarah</ForeName><Initials>IS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, UMC Utrecht Brain Center, University Medical Center Utrecht, Utrecht University, Utrecht, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kenna</LastName><ForeName>Kevin P</ForeName><Initials>KP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, UMC Utrecht Brain Center, University Medical Center Utrecht, Utrecht University, Utrecht, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Iacoangeli</LastName><ForeName>Alfredo</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Maurice Wohl Clinical Neuroscience Institute, Department of Basic and Clinical Neuroscience.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biostatistics and Health Informatics, Institute of Psychiatry, Psychology and Neuroscience, King's College London.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Institute for Health Research Biomedical Research Centre and Dementia Unit, South London and Maudsley NHS Foundation Trust and King's College London, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Veldink</LastName><ForeName>Jan H</ForeName><Initials>JH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, UMC Utrecht Brain Center, University Medical Center Utrecht, Utrecht University, Utrecht, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Acronym>WT_</Acronym><Agency>Wellcome Trust</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>216596</GrantID><Acronym>WT_</Acronym><Agency>Wellcome Trust</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Curr Opin Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9319162</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1350-7540</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055106" MajorTopicYN="N">Genome-Wide Association Study</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000069550" MajorTopicYN="N">Machine Learning</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010641" MajorTopicYN="N">Phenotype</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>
<i>Conflicts of interest:</i> None</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34343141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">EMS132503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7612116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/WCO.0000000000000986</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00019052-202110000-00020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Kiernan MC, Vucic S, Cheah BC, Turner MR, Eisen A, Hardiman O, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet. 2011 Mar 12;377(9769):942&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21296405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shepheard SR, Parker MD, Cooper-Knock J, Verber NS, Tuddenham L, Heath P, et al. Value of systematic genetic screening of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. JNNP. 2021;92:510&#x2013;518. *This study describes screening for ALS associated mutations in a prospectively selected clinic population.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8053339</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33589474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Rheenen W, van der Spek RAA, Bakker MK, van Vugt JJFA, Hop PJ, Zwamborn RAJ, et al.  Common and rare variant association analyses in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis identify 15 risk loci with distinct genetic architectures and neuron-specific biology. bioRxiv medRxiv. 2021 [Internet]. Available from:  http://medrxiv.org/lookup/doi/10.1101/2021.03.12.21253159** This study is the new ALS GWAS which represents a step change in our understanding of the genetic architecture of ALS.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2021.03.12.21253159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8648564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34873335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tazelaar GHP, Boeynaems S, De Decker M, van Vugt JJFA, Kool L, Goedee HS, et al. ATXN1 repeat expansions confer risk for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and contribute to TDP-43 mislocalization. Brain Commun. 2020 May 19;2(2):fcaa064.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7425293</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32954321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooper-Knock J, Zhang S, Kenna KP, Moll T, Franklin J, Allen S, et al. Rare Variant Burden Analysis within Enhancers Identifies CAV1 as a New ALS Risk Gene. Cell Rep. 2020 Dec 1;33(9):108456. * This study describes identification of the first non-coding genetic risk factor for ALS which is relevant to a significant number of patients.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7710676</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33264630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohassel P, Donkervoort S, Lone MA, Nalls M, Gable K, Gupta SD, et al. Childhood amyotrophic lateral sclerosis caused by excess sphingolipid synthesis. Nat Med. 2021 May 31; doi: 10.1038/s41591-021-01346-1. [Internet].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-021-01346-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34059824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iacoangeli A, Lin T, Al Khleifat A, Jones AR, Opie-Martin S, Coleman JRI, et al. Genome-wide Meta-analysis Finds the ACSL5-ZDHHC6 Locus Is Associated with ALS and Links Weight Loss to the Disease Genetics. Cell Rep. 2020 Oct 27;33(4):108323.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7610013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33113361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakamura R, Misawa K, Tohnai G, Nakatochi M, Furuhashi S, Atsuta N, et al. A multi-ethnic meta-analysis identifies novel genes, including ACSL5, associated with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Commun Biol. 2020 Sep 23;3(1):526.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7511394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32968195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farhan SMK, Howrigan DP, Abbott LE, Klim JR, Topp SD, Byrnes AE, et al. Exome sequencing in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis implicates a novel gene, DNAJC7, encoding a heat-shock protein. Nat Neurosci. 2019 Nov 25;22(12):1966&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6919277</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31768050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith BN, Topp SD, Fallini C, Shibata H, Chen HJ, Troakes C, et al. Mutations in the vesicular trafficking protein annexin A11 are associated with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Sci Transl Med. 2017;9(388) [Internet].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6599403</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28469040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooper-Knock J, Moll T, Ramesh T, Castelli L, Beer A, Robins H, et al. Mutations in the Glycosyltransferase Domain of GLT8D1 Are Associated with Familial Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. Cell Rep. 2019;26(9):2298&#x2013;306.:e5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7003067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30811981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renton AE, Chi&#xf2; A, Traynor BJ. State of play in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis genetics. Nat Neurosci. 2014 Jan;17(1):17&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4544832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24369373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan M, Heverin M, McLaughlin RL, Hardiman O. Lifetime Risk and Heritability of Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. JAMA Neurol. 2019 Jul 22; doi: 10.1001/jamaneurol.2019.2044. [Internet]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamaneurol.2019.2044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6646974</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31329211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trabjerg BB, Garton FC, van Rheenen W, Fang F, Henderson RD, Mortensen PB, et al. ALS in Danish Registries: Heritability and links to psychiatric and cardiovascular disorders. Neurol Genet. 2020 Apr;6(2):e398.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7073454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32211514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J, Li X, Zhang S, Snyder M. Gene-Environment Interaction in the Era of Precision Medicine. Cell. 2019;177(1):38&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8108774</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30901546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hivert V, Sidorenko J, Rohart F, Goddard ME, Yang J, Wray NR, et al. Estimation of non-additive genetic variance in human complex traits from a large sample of unrelated individuals. Am J Hum Genet. 2021 May 6;108(5):962.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8206200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33961780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang S, Cooper-Knock J, Weimer AK, Shi M, Moll T, Harvey C, et al.  Genome-wide Identification of the Genetic Basis of Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis [Internet]  [cited 2021 May 28];bioRxiv. 2021 :2020.11.14.382606.  Available from:  https://www.biorxiv.org/content/10.1101/2020.11.14.382606v4** This study describes re-analysis of ALS GWAS data using epigenetic profiling from motor neurons to reduce the search space and increase statistical power.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2020.11.14.382606v4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakken T, Jorstad N, Hu Q, Lake B, Tian W, Kalmbach B, et al.  Evolution of cellular diversity in primary motor cortex of human, marmoset monkey, and mouse [Internet]  [cited 2021 Jul 13];BioRxiv. 2020  [Internet]. Available from:  http://repository.cshl.edu/id/eprint/40041/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pineda SS, Lee H, Fitzwalter BE, Mohammadi S. Single-cell profiling of the human primary motor cortex in ALS and FTLD. bioRxiv. 2021 [Internet]. Available from:  https://www.biorxiv.org/content/10.1101/2021.07.07.451374.abstract.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2021.07.07.451374.abstract</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bean DM, Al-Chalabi A, Dobson RJB, Iacoangeli A. A Knowledge-Based Machine Learning Approach to Gene Prioritisation in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. Genes. 2020 Jun 19;11(6) doi: 10.3390/genes11060668. [Internet].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/genes11060668</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7349022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32575372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu J, Lepore R, Dobson RJB, Al-Chalabi A, Bean DM, Iacoangeli A. DGLinker: flexible knowledge-graph prediction of disease-gene associations. Nucleic Acids Res. 2021 Jul 2;49(W1):W153&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8262728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34125897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neumann M, Sampathu DM, Kwong LK, Truax AC, Micsenyi MC, Chou TT, et al. Ubiquitinated TDP-43 in frontotemporal lobar degeneration and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Science. 2006;314(5796):130&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17023659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green EM, Seeley WW, Petrucelli L, Gitler AD. TDP-43 represses cryptic exon inclusion in FTD/ALS gene UNC13A. bioRxiv. 2021 [Internet]. Available from:  https://www.biorxiv.org/content/10.1101/2021.04.02.438213v1.abstract* This study (and reference 23) describes a new unifying molecular mechanism for toxicity which may be relevant to the majority of ALS patients.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2021.04.02.438213v1.abstract</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ule J, Buratti E, Humphrey J, Ward ME, Fratta P. Common ALS/FTD risk variants in UNC13A exacerbate its cryptic splicing and loss upon TDP-43 mislocalization. bioRxiv. 2021 [Internet]. Available from:  https://www.biorxiv.org/content/10.1101/2021.04.02.438170v1.abstract* This study (and reference 22) describes a new unifying molecular mechanism for toxicity which may be relevant to the majority of ALS patients.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2021.04.02.438170v1.abstract</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diekstra FP, van Vught PWJ, van Rheenen W, Koppers M, Pasterkamp RJ, van Es MA, et al. UNC13A is a modifier of survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurobiol Aging. 2012 Mar;33(3):630.:e3&#x2013;8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22118904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stephenson J, Amor S. Modelling amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in mice. Drug Discov Today Dis Models. 2017 Dec 1;25&#x2013;26:35&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicolas A, Kenna KP, Renton AE, Ticozzi N, Faghri F, Chia R, et al. Genome-wide Analyses Identify KIF5A as a Novel ALS Gene. Neuron. 2018 Mar 21;97(6):1268&#x2013;83.:e6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5867896</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29566793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Rheenen W, Shatunov A, Dekker AM, McLaughlin RL, Diekstra FP, Pulit SL, et al. Genome-wide association analyses identify new risk variants and the genetic architecture of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat Genet. 2016;48(9):1043&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5556360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27455348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halperin E, Stephan DA. SNP imputation in association studies. Nat Biotechnol. 2009 Apr;27(4):349&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19352374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castel SE, Cervera A, Mohammadi P, Aguet F, Reverter F, Wolman A, et al. Modified penetrance of coding variants by cis-regulatory variation contributes to disease risk. Nat Genet. 2018 Sep;50(9):1327&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6119105</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30127527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kvon EZ, Waymack R, Gad M, Wunderlich Z. Enhancer redundancy in development and disease. Nat Rev Genet. 2021 May;22(5):324&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8068586</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33442000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLaughlin RL, Schijven D, van Rheenen W, van Eijk KR, O&#x2019;Brien M, Kahn RS, et al. Genetic correlation between amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and schizophrenia. Nat Commun. 2017 Mar 21;8:14774.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5364411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28322246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim HJ, Kim NC, Wang Y-D, Scarborough EA, Moore J, Diaz Z, et al. Mutations in prion-like domains in hnRNPA2B1 and hnRNPA1 cause multisystem proteinopathy and ALS. Nature. 2013 Mar 28;495(7442):467&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3756911</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23455423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson JO, Mandrioli J, Benatar M, Abramzon Y, Van Deerlin VM, Trojanowski JQ, et al. Exome sequencing reveals VCP mutations as a cause of familial ALS. Neuron. 2010 Dec 9;68(5):857&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3032425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21145000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han SM, Cottee PA, Miller MA. Sperm and oocyte communication mechanisms controlling C. elegans fertility. Dev Dyn. 2010 May;239(5):1265&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2963114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20034089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benita Y, Oosting RS, Lok MC, Wise MJ, Humphery-Smith I. Regionalized GC content of template DNA as a predictor of PCR success. Nucleic Acids Res. 2003 Aug 15;31(16):e99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC169991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12907751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeJesus-Hernandez M, Mackenzie IR, Boeve BF, Boxer AL, Baker M, Rutherford NJ, et al. Expanded GGGGCC hexanucleotide repeat in noncoding region of C9ORF72 causes chromosome 9p-linked FTD and ALS. Neuron. 2011 Oct 20;72(2):245&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3202986</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21944778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renton AE, Majounie E, Waite A, Sim&#xf3;n-S&#xe1;nchez J, Rollinson S, Gibbs JR, et al. A hexanucleotide repeat expansion in C9ORF72 is the cause of chromosome 9p21-linked ALS-FTD. Neuron. 2011 Oct 20;72(2):257&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3200438</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21944779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elden AC, Kim H-J, Hart MP, Chen-Plotkin AS, Johnson BS, Fang X, et al. Ataxin-2 intermediate-length polyglutamine expansions are associated with increased risk for ALS. Nature. 2010 Aug 26;466(7310):1069&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2965417</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20740007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Course MM, Gudsnuk K, Smukowski SN, Winston K, Desai N, Ross JP, et al. Evolution of a Human-Specific Tandem Repeat Associated with ALS. Am J Hum Genet. 2020 Sep 3;107(3):445&#x2013;60. * This study is the first to examine in detail the association of ALS with changes in size of a variable number tandem repeat (VNTR)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7477013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32750315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mousavi N, Shleizer-Burko S, Yanicky R, Gymrek M. Profiling the genome-wide landscape of tandem repeat expansions. Nucleic Acids Res. 2019 Sep 5;47(15):e90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6735967</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31194863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dolzhenko E, Bennett MF, Richmond PA, Trost B, Chen S, van Vugt JJFA, et al. ExpansionHunter Denovo: a computational method for locating known and novel repeat expansions in short-read sequencing data [Internet] Genome Biology. 2020;21 doi: 10.1186/s13059-020-02017-z. [Internet].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13059-020-02017-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7187524</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32345345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kenna KP, van Doormaal PT, Dekker AM, Ticozzi N, Kenna BJ, Diekstra FP, et al. NEK1 variants confer susceptibility to amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat Genet. 2016;48(9):1037&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5560030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27455347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller T, Cudkowicz M, Shaw PJ, Andersen PM, Atassi N, Bucelli RC, et al. Phase 1&#x2013;2 Trial of Antisense Oligonucleotide Tofersen for SOD1 ALS. N Engl J Med. 2020 Jul 9;383(2):109&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32640130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Consortium TIS, The International Schizophrenia Consortium. Common polygenic variation contributes to risk of schizophrenia and bipolar disorder [Internet] Nature. 2009;460:748&#x2013;52. doi: 10.1038/nature08185.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nature08185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3912837</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19571811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheutlin AB, Ross DA. Polygenic Risk Scores: What Are They Good For? Biol Psychiatry. 2018 Jun 1;83(11):e51&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6696910</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29759133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Restuadi R, Garton FC, Benyamin B, Lin T, Williams KL, Vinkhuyzen A, et al. Polygenic risk score analysis for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis leveraging cognitive performance, educational attainment and schizophrenia. Eur J Hum Genet. 2021 Apr 27; doi: 10.1038/s41431-021-00885-y. Internet Available from * This study describes the latest application of a polygenic risk score (PRS) to describe the genetic architecture of ALS.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41431-021-00885-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33907316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>LeCun Y, Bengio Y, Hinton G. Deep learning. Nature. 2015;521:436&#x2013;44. doi: 10.1038/nature14539. [Internet]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nature14539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26017442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angermueller C, P&#xe4;rnamaa T, Parts L, Stegle O. Deep learning for computational biology. Mol Syst Biol. 2016 Jul 29;12(7):878.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4965871</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27474269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2; A, Mazzini L, D&#x2019;Alfonso S, Corrado L, Canosa A, Moglia C, et al. The multistep hypothesis of ALS revisited. Neurology. 2018;91:e635&#x2013;42. doi: 10.1212/wnl.0000000000005996. [Internet].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/wnl.0000000000005996</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6105040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30045958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Chalabi A, Calvo A, Chio A, Colville S, Ellis CM, Hardiman O, et al. Analysis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis as a multistep process: a population-based modelling study. Lancet Neurol. 2014;13(11):1108&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4197338</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25300936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Julian TH, Glascow N, Dylan Fisher Barry A, Moll T, Harvey C, Klimentidis YC, et al. Physical exercise is a risk factor for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Convergent evidence from mendelian randomisation, transcriptomics and risk genotypes. EBioMed. 2021;68:103397. doi: 10.1101/2020.11.24.20238063.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2020.11.24.20238063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8170114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34051439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bandres-Ciga S, Noyce AJ, Hemani G, Nicolas A, Calvo A, Mora G, et al. Shared polygenic risk and causal inferences in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol. 2019;85(4):470&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6450729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30723964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spiller W, Slichter D, Bowden J, Davey Smith G. Detecting and correcting for bias in Mendelian randomization analyses using Gene-by-Environment interactions. Int J Epidemiol. 2019 Jun 1;48(3):702&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6659360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30462199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boddy SL, Giovannelli I, Sassani M, Cooper-Knock J, Snyder MP, Segal E, et al. The gut microbiome: a key player in the complexity of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) BMC Med. 2021 Jan 20;19(1):13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7816375</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33468103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Klein N, Tsai EA, Vochteloo M, Baird D, Huang Y, Chen C-Y, et al.  Brain expression quantitative trait locus and network analysis reveals downstream effects and putative drivers for brain-related diseases [Internet]  [cited 2021 Jul 12];bioRxiv. 2021 :2021.03.01.433439.  [Internet]. Available from:  https://www.biorxiv.org/content/10.1101/2021.03.01.433439v2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2021.03.01.433439v2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amaya C, Fader CM, Colombo MI. Autophagy and proteins involved in vesicular trafficking. FEBS Lett. 2015 Nov 14;589(22):3343&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26450776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghasemi M, Brown RH., Jr Genetics of Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. Cold Spring Harb Perspect Med. 2018 May 1;8(5) doi: 10.1101/cshperspect.a024125. [Internet].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/cshperspect.a024125</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5932579</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28270533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hergesheimer RC, Chami AA, de Assis DR, Vourc&#x2019;h P, Andres CR, Corcia P, et al. The debated toxic role of aggregated TDP-43 in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a resolution in sight? Brain. 2019 May 1;142(5):1176&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6487324</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30938443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ling JP, Pletnikova O, Troncoso JC, Wong PC. TDP-43 repression of nonconserved cryptic exons is compromised in ALS-FTD. Science. 2015 Aug 7;349(6248):650&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4825810</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26250685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Es MA, Veldink JH, Saris CGJ, Blauw HM, van Vught PWJ, Birve A, et al. Genome-wide association study identifies 19p13.3 (UNC13A) and 9p21.2 as susceptibility loci for sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat Genet. 2009 Oct;41(10):1083&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19734901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2; A, Mora G, Restagno G, Brunetti M, Ossola I, Barberis M, et al. UNC13A influences survival in Italian amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients: a population-based study. Neurobiol Aging. 2013 Jan;34(1):357.:e1&#x2013;5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3483408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22921269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melamed Z, L&#xf3;pez-Erauskin J, Baughn MW, Zhang O, Drenner K, Sun Y, et al. Premature polyadenylation-mediated loss of stathmin-2 is a hallmark of TDP-43-dependent neurodegeneration. Nat Neurosci. 2019;22(2):180&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6348009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30643298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klim JR, Williams LA, Limone F, Juan IGS, Davis-Dusenbery BN, Mordes DA, et al. ALS-implicated protein TDP-43 sustains levels of STMN2, a mediator of motor neuron growth and repair [Internet] Nature Neuroscience. 2019;22:167&#x2013;79. doi: 10.1038/s41593-018-0300-4. [Internet].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41593-018-0300-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7153761</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30643292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klim JR, Pintacuda G, Nash LA, Guerra San Juan I, Eggan K. Connecting TDP-43 Pathology with Neuropathy. Trends Neurosci. 2021 Jun;44(6):424&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33832769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Theunissen F, Anderton RS, Mastaglia FL, Flynn LL, Winter SJ, James I, et al. Novel STMN2 Variant Linked to Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Risk and Clinical Phenotype. Front Aging Neurosci. 2021 Mar 26;13:658226.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8033025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33841129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Project MinE ALS Sequencing Consortium. Project MinE: study design and pilot analyses of a large-scale whole-genome sequencing study in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Eur J Hum Genet. 2018 Oct;26(10):1537&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6138692</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29955173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanby MF, Scott KM, Scotton W, Wijesekera L, Mole T, Ellis CE, et al. The risk to relatives of patients with sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain. 2011 Dec;134(Pt 12):3454&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3235555</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21933809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morello G, Guarnaccia M, Spampinato AG, La Cognata V, D&#x2019;Agata V, Cavallaro S. Copy Number Variations in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis: Piecing the Mosaic Tiles Together through a Systems Biology Approach. Mol Neurobiol. 2018 Feb;55(2):1299&#x2013;322.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5820374</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28120152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu EY, Russ J, Cali CP, Phan JM, Amlie-Wolf A, Lee EB. Loss of Nuclear TDP-43 Is Associated with Decondensation of LINE Retrotransposons. Cell Rep. 2019 Apr 30;27(5):1409&#x2013;21.:e6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6508629</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31042469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loomis EW, Eid JS, Peluso P, Yin J, Hickey L, Rank D, et al. Sequencing the unsequenceable: Expanded CGG-repeat alleles of the fragile X gene [Internet] Genome Research. 2013;23:121&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1101/gr.141705.112. [Internet].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/gr.141705.112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3530672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23064752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pollard MO, Gurdasani D, Mentzer AJ, Porter T, Sandhu MS. Long reads: their purpose and place. Hum Mol Genet. 2018 Aug 1;27(R2):R234&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6061690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29767702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Logsdon GA, Vollger MR, Hsieh P, Mao Y, Liskovykh MA, Koren S, et al. The structure, function and evolution of a complete human chromosome 8. Nature. 2021 May;593(7857):101&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8099727</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33828295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lodato MA, Woodworth MB, Lee S, Evrony GD, Mehta BK, Karger A, et al. Somatic mutation in single human neurons tracks developmental and transcriptional history. Science. 2015 Oct 2;350(6256):94&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4664477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26430121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Chalabi A, Hardiman O. The epidemiology of ALS: a conspiracy of genes, environment and time. Nat Rev Neurol. 2013 Nov;9(11):617&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24126629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchman VL, Cooper-Knock J, Connor-Robson N, Higginbottom A, Kirby J, Razinskaya OD, et al. Simultaneous and independent detection of C9ORF72 alleles with low and high number of GGGGCC repeats using an optimised protocol of Southern blot hybridisation. Mol Neurodegener. 2013;8:12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3626718</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23566336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi W, Ng CKY, Lim RS, Jiang T, Kumar S, Li X, et al. Reliability of Whole-Exome Sequencing for Assessing Intratumor Genetic Heterogeneity. Cell Rep. 2018 Nov 6;25(6):1446&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6261536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30404001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spence JM, Spence JP, Abumoussa A, Burack WR. Ultradeep analysis of tumor heterogeneity in regions of somatic hypermutation. Genome Med. 2015 Mar 12;7(1):24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4395979</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25874000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim J, Kim D, Lim JS, Maeng JH, Son H, Kang H-C, et al. The use of technical replication for detection of low-level somatic mutations in next-generation sequencing. Nat Commun. 2019 Mar 5;10(1):1047.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6400950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30837471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Project MinE ALS Sequencing Consortium. CHCHD10 variants in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Where is the evidence? Ann Neurol. 2018 Jul;84(1):110&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6553489</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30014597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujimori K, Ishikawa M, Otomo A, Atsuta N, Nakamura R, Akiyama T, et al. Modeling sporadic ALS in iPSC-derived motor neurons identifies a potential therapeutic agent. Nat Med. 2018 Oct;24(10):1579&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30127392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun X, Song J, Huang H, Chen H, Qian K. Correction to: Modeling hallmark pathology using motor neurons derived from the family and sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patient-specific iPS cells. Stem Cell Res Ther. 2019 Mar 15;10(1):97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6420754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30876443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer K, Ferraiuolo L, Miranda CJ, Likhite S, McElroy S, Renusch S, et al. Direct conversion of patient fibroblasts demonstrates non-cell autonomous toxicity of astrocytes to motor neurons in familial and sporadic ALS. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2014 Jan 14;111(2):829&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3896192</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24379375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>