<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">34343139</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>28</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1473-6551</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>34</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Current opinion in neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Curr Opin Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Dysregulation of energy homeostasis in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>773</StartPage><EndPage>780</EndPage><MedlinePgn>773-780</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/WCO.0000000000000982</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE OF REVIEW">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) is a neurodegenerative disease targeting upper and lower motor neurons, inexorably leading to an early death. Defects in energy metabolism have been associated with ALS, including weight loss, increased energy expenditure, decreased body fat mass and increased use of lipid nutrients at the expense of carbohydrates. We review here recent findings on impaired energy metabolism in ALS, and its clinical importance.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RECENT FINDINGS">Hypothalamic atrophy, as well as alterations in hypothalamic peptides controlling energy metabolism, have been associated with metabolic derangements. Recent studies showed that mutations causing familial ALS impact various metabolic pathways, in particular mitochondrial function, and lipid and carbohydrate metabolism, which could underlie these metabolic defects in patients. Importantly, slowing weight loss, through high caloric diets, is a promising therapeutic strategy, and early clinical trials indicated that it might improve survival in at least a subset of patients. More research is needed to improve these therapeutic strategies, define pharmacological options, and refine the population of ALS patients that would benefit from these approaches.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUMMARY">Dysfunctional energy homeostasis is a major feature of ALS clinical picture and emerges as a potential therapeutic target.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2021 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guillot</LastName><ForeName>Simon J</ForeName><Initials>SJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Strasbourg, INSERM, UMR-S1118, Central and Peripheral Mechanisms of Neurodegeneration, Strasbourg, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bolborea</LastName><ForeName>Matei</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Strasbourg, INSERM, UMR-S1118, Central and Peripheral Mechanisms of Neurodegeneration, Strasbourg, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Life Sciences, University of Warwick, Coventry, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dupuis</LastName><ForeName>Luc</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Strasbourg, INSERM, UMR-S1118, Central and Peripheral Mechanisms of Neurodegeneration, Strasbourg, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Curr Opin Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9319162</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1350-7540</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004734" MajorTopicYN="N">Energy Metabolism</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006706" MajorTopicYN="N">Homeostasis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009046" MajorTopicYN="N">Motor Neurons</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019636" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neurodegenerative Diseases</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34343139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/WCO.0000000000000982</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00019052-202110000-00022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Brown RH, Al-Chalabi A. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. N Engl J Med 2017; 377:162&#x2013;172.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Es MA, Hardiman O, Chio A, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet 2017; 390:2084&#x2013;2098.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desport JC, Preux PM, Truong TC, et al. Nutritional status is a prognostic factor for survival in ALS patients. Neurology 1999; 53:1059&#x2013;1063.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dupuis L, Pradat PF, Ludolph AC, Loeffler JP. Energy metabolism in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet Neurol 2011; 10:75&#x2013;82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desport JC, Preux PM, Truong CT, et al. Nutritional assessment and survival in ALS patients. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord 2000; 1:91&#x2013;96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janse van Mantgem MR, van Eijk RPA, van der Burgh HK, et al. Prognostic value of weight loss in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a population-based study. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2020; 91:867&#x2013;875.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei Q, Ou R, Chen Y, et al. RNM-01 Weight stability is associated with longer survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2019; 20 (sup1):309&#x2013;326.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei QQ, Ou R, Cao B, et al. Early weight instability is associated with cognitive decline and poor survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain Res Bull 2021; 171:10&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallo V, Wark PA, Jenab M, et al. Prediagnostic body fat and risk of death from amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: the EPIC cohort. Neurology 2013; 80:829&#x2013;838.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Reilly EJ, Wang H, Weisskopf MG, et al. Premorbid body mass index and risk of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2013; 14:205&#x2013;211.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Reilly EJ, Wang M, Adami HO, et al. Prediagnostic body size and risk of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis death in 10 studies. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2018; 19:396&#x2013;406.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagel G, Peter RS, Rosenbohm A, et al. Adipokines, C-reactive protein and Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis &#x2013; results from a population-based ALS registry in Germany. Sci Rep 2017; 7:4374.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peter RS, Rosenbohm A, Dupuis L, et al. Life course body mass index and risk and prognosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: results from the ALS registry Swabia. Eur J Epidemiol 2017; 32:901&#x2013;908.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pradat PF, Bruneteau G, Gordon PH, et al. Impaired glucose tolerance in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler 2010; 11:166&#x2013;171.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed RM, Phan K, Highton-Williamson E, et al. Eating peptides: biomarkers of neurodegeneration in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal dementia. Ann Clin Transl Neurol 2019; 6:486&#x2013;495.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dorst J, Kuhnlein P, Hendrich C, et al. Patients with elevated triglyceride and cholesterol serum levels have a prolonged survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol 2011; 258:613&#x2013;617.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dupuis L, Corcia P, Fergani A, et al. Dyslipidemia is a protective factor in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology 2008; 70:1004&#x2013;1009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindauer E, Dupuis L, Muller HP, et al. Adipose tissue distribution predicts survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. PLoS One 2013; 8:e67783.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moglia C, Calvo A, Grassano M, et al. Early weight loss in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: outcome relevance and clinical correlates in a population-based cohort. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2019; 90:666&#x2013;673.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marin B, Arcuti S, Jesus P, et al. Population-based evidence that survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis is related to weight loss at diagnosis. Neurodegener Dis 2016; 16:225&#x2013;234.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mariosa D, Beard JD, Umbach DM, et al. Body mass index and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a study of US Military Veterans. Am J Epidemiol 2017; 185:362&#x2013;371.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimizu T, Nakayama Y, Matsuda C, et al. Prognostic significance of body weight variation after diagnosis in ALS: a single-centre prospective cohort study. J Neurol 2019; 266:1412&#x2013;1420.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakayama Y, Shimizu T, Matsuda C, et al. Body weight variation predicts disease progression after invasive ventilation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Sci Rep 2019; 9:12262.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dorst J, Chen L, Rosenbohm A, et al. Prognostic factors in ALS: a comparison between Germany and China. J Neurol 2019; 266:1516&#x2013;1525.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harwood CA, Westgate K, Gunstone S, et al. Long-term physical activity: an exogenous risk factor for sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis? Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2016; 17:377&#x2013;384.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lacorte E, Ferrigno L, Leoncini E, et al. Physical activity, and physical activity related to sports, leisure and occupational activity as risk factors for ALS: a systematic review. Neurosci Biobehav Rev 2016; 66:61&#x2013;79.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fayemendy P, Marin B, Labrunie A, et al. Hypermetabolism is a reality in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis compared to healthy subjects. J Neurol Sci 2021; 420:117257.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jesus P, Fayemendy P, Nicol M, et al. Hypermetabolism is a deleterious prognostic factor in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Eur J Neurol 2018; 25:97&#x2013;104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouteloup C, Desport JC, Clavelou P, et al. Hypermetabolism in ALS patients: an early and persistent phenomenon. J Neurol 2009; 256:1236&#x2013;1242.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dupuis L, Oudart H, Rene F, et al. Evidence for defective energy homeostasis in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: benefit of a high-energy diet in a transgenic mouse model. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA 2004; 101:11159&#x2013;11164.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim MA, Bence KK, Sandesara I, et al. Genetically altering organismal metabolism by leptin-deficiency benefits a mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Hum Mol Genet 2014; 23:4995&#x2013;5008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferri A, Coccurello R. What is &#x2018;Hyper&#x2019; in the ALS hypermetabolism? Mediators Inflamm 2017; 2017:7821672.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steyn FJ, Ioannides ZA, van Eijk RPA, et al. Hypermetabolism in ALS is associated with greater functional decline and shorter survival. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2018; 89:1016&#x2013;1023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tschop MH, Speakman JR, Arch JR, et al. A guide to analysis of mouse energy metabolism. Nat Methods 2011; 9:57&#x2013;63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weijs PJ. Hypermetabolism, is it real? The example of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Am Diet Assoc 2011; 111:1670&#x2013;1673.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellis AC, Rosenfeld J. Which equation best predicts energy expenditure in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis? J Am Diet Assoc 2011; 111:1680&#x2013;1687.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holm T, Maier A, Wicks P, et al. Severe loss of appetite in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients: online self-assessment study. Interact J Med Res 2013; 2:e8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mezoian T, Belt E, Garry J, et al. Loss of appetite in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis is associated with weight loss and decreased calorie consumption independent of dysphagia. Muscle Nerve 2020; 61:230&#x2013;234.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steyn FJ, Ngo ST. Prognostic value of weight loss in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2020; 91:813.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed RM, Caga J, Devenney E, et al. Cognition and eating behavior in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: effect on survival. J Neurol 2016; 263:1593&#x2013;1603.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matu J, Gonzalez JT, Ispoglou T, et al. The effects of hypoxia on hunger perceptions, appetite-related hormone concentrations and energy intake: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Appetite 2018; 125:98&#x2013;108.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdalla MM. Central and peripheral control of food intake. Endocr Regul 2017; 51:52&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ngo ST, van Eijk RPA, Chachay V, et al. Loss of appetite is associated with a loss of weight and fat mass in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2019; 20:497&#x2013;505.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeltser LM, Seeley RJ, Tschop MH. Synaptic plasticity in neuronal circuits regulating energy balance. Nat Neurosci 2012; 15:1336&#x2013;1342.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cykowski MD, Takei H, Schulz PE, et al. TDP-43 pathology in the basal forebrain and hypothalamus of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathol Commun 2014; 2:171.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabery S, Ahmed RM, Caga J, et al. Loss of the metabolism and sleep regulating neuronal populations expressing orexin and oxytocin in the hypothalamus in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuropathol Appl Neurobiol 2021; doi: 10.1111/nan.12709.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/nan.12709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorges M, Roselli F, Muller HP, et al. Functional connectivity mapping in the animal model: principles and applications of resting-state fMRI. Front Neurol 2017; 8:200.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bayer D, Antonucci S, Muller HP, et al. Disruption of orbitofrontal-hypothalamic projections in a murine ALS model and in human patients. Transl Neurodegener 2021; 10:17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vercruysse P, Sinniger J, El Oussini H, et al. Alterations in the hypothalamic melanocortin pathway in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain 2016; 139 (Pt 4):1106&#x2013;1122.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed RM, Steyn F, Dupuis L. Hypothalamus and weight loss in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Handb Clin Neurol 2021; 180:327&#x2013;338.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scaricamazza S, Salvatori I, Giacovazzo G, et al. Skeletal-muscle metabolic reprogramming in ALS-SOD1(G93A) mice predates disease onset and is a promising therapeutic target. iScience 2020; 23:101087.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palamiuc L, Schlagowski A, Ngo ST, et al. A metabolic switch toward lipid use in glycolytic muscle is an early pathologic event in a mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. EMBO Mol Med 2015; 7:526&#x2013;546.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDonald TS, Kumar V, Fung JN, et al. Glucose clearance and uptake is increased in the SOD1(G93A) mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis through an insulin-independent mechanism. FASEB J 2021; 35:e21707.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stallings NR, Puttaparthi K, Dowling KJ, et al. TDP-43, an ALS linked protein, regulates fat deposition and glucose homeostasis. PLoS One 2013; 8:e71793.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shan X, Chiang PM, Price DL, Wong PC. Altered distributions of Gemini of coiled bodies and mitochondria in motor neurons of TDP-43 transgenic mice. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA 2010; 107:16325&#x2013;16330.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steyn FJ, Li R, Kirk SE, et al. Altered skeletal muscle glucose-fatty acid flux in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain Commun 2020; 2:fcaa154.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerou M, Hall B, Woof R, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis alters the metabolic aging profile in patient derived fibroblasts. Neurobiol Aging 2021; 105:64&#x2013;77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delaye JB, Patin F, Piver E, et al. Low IDL-B and high LDL-1 subfraction levels in serum of ALS patients. J Neurol Sci 2017; 380:124&#x2013;127.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allen SP, Hall B, Woof R, et al. C9orf72 expansion within astrocytes reduces metabolic flexibility in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain 2019; 142:3771&#x2013;3790.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ravanidis S, Doxakis E. RNA-binding proteins implicated in mitochondrial damage and mitophagy. Front Cell Dev Biol 2020; 8:372.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruffoli R, Bartalucci A, Frati A, Fornai F. Ultrastructural studies of ALS mitochondria connect altered function and permeability with defects of mitophagy and mitochondriogenesis. Front Cell Neurosci 2015; 9:341.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang P, Deng J, Dong J, et al. TDP-43 induces mitochondrial damage and activates the mitochondrial unfolded protein response. PLoS Genet 2019; 15:e1007947.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dupuis L, Loeffler JP. Neuromuscular junction destruction during amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: insights from transgenic models. Curr Opin Pharmacol 2009; 9:341&#x2013;346.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khalil B, Cabirol-Pol MJ, Miguel L, et al. Enhancing Mitofusin/Marf ameliorates neuromuscular dysfunction in Drosophila models of TDP-43 proteinopathies. Neurobiol Aging 2017; 54:71&#x2013;83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith EF, Shaw PJ, De Vos KJ. The role of mitochondria in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurosci Lett 2019; 710:132933.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Briese M, Saal-Bauernschubert L, Luningschror P, et al. Loss of Tdp-43 disrupts the axonal transcriptome of motoneurons accompanied by impaired axonal translation and mitochondria function. Acta Neuropathol Commun 2020; 8:116.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oakes JA, Davies MC, Collins MO. TBK1: a new player in ALS linking autophagy and neuroinflammation. Mol Brain 2017; 10:5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trabjerg MS, Andersen DC, Huntjens P, et al. Downregulating carnitine palmitoyl transferase 1 affects disease progression in the SOD1 G93A mouse model of ALS. Commun Biol 2021; 4:509.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Da Cruz S, Parone PA, Lopes VS, et al. Elevated PGC-1alpha activity sustains mitochondrial biogenesis and muscle function without extending survival in a mouse model of inherited ALS. Cell Metab 2012; 15:778&#x2013;786.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eschbach J, Schwalenstocker B, Soyal SM, et al. PGC-1alpha is a male-specific disease modifier of human and experimental amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Hum Mol Genet 2013; 22:3477&#x2013;3484.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanchis-Gomar F, Garcia-Gimenez JL, Gomez-Cabrera MC, Pallardo FV. Mitochondrial biogenesis in health and disease. Molecular and therapeutic approaches. Curr Pharm Des 2014; 20:5619&#x2013;5633.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manzo E, Lorenzini I, Barrameda D, et al. Glycolysis upregulation is neuroprotective as a compensatory mechanism in ALS. Elife 2019; 8:e58565doi: 10.7554/eLife.45114.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7554/eLife.45114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atilano ML, Gronke S, Niccoli T, et al. Enhanced insulin signalling ameliorates C9orf72 hexanucleotide repeat expansion toxicity in Drosophila. Elife 2021; 10:e58565.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coughlan KS, Halang L, Woods I, Prehn JH. A high-fat jelly diet restores bioenergetic balance and extends lifespan in the presence of motor dysfunction and lumbar spinal cord motor neuron loss in TDP-43A315T mutant C57BL6/J mice. Dis Model Mech 2016; 9:1029&#x2013;1037.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Chalabi A. High-calorie diets in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet 2014; 383:2028&#x2013;2030.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wills AM, Hubbard J, Macklin EA, et al. Hypercaloric enteral nutrition in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled phase 2 trial. Lancet 2014; 383:2065&#x2013;2072.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ludolph AC, Dorst J, Dreyhaupt J, et al. Effect of high-caloric nutrition on survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol 2020; 87:206&#x2013;216.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dorst J, Schuster J, Dreyhaupt J, et al. Effect of high-caloric nutrition on serum neurofilament light chain levels in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2020; 91:1007&#x2013;1009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Z, Lange DJ, Voustianiouk A, et al. A ketogenic diet as a potential novel therapeutic intervention in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. BMC Neurosci 2006; 7:29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manzo E, O&#x2019;Conner AG, Barrows JM, et al. Medium-chain fatty acids, beta-hydroxybutyric acid and genetic modulation of the carnitine shuttle are protective in a drosophila model of ALS based on TDP-43. Front Mol Neurosci 2018; 11:182.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fitzgerald KC, O&#x2019;Reilly EJ, Falcone GJ, et al. Dietary omega-3 polyunsaturated fatty acid intake and risk for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. JAMA Neurol 2014; 71:1102&#x2013;1110.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veldink JH, Kalmijn S, Groeneveld GJ, et al. Intake of polyunsaturated fatty acids and vitamin E reduces the risk of developing amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2007; 78:367&#x2013;371.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Israelson A, Arbel N, Da Cruz S, et al. Misfolded mutant SOD1 directly inhibits VDAC1 conductance in a mouse model of inherited ALS. Neuron 2010; 67:575&#x2013;587.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedrini S, Sau D, Guareschi S, et al. ALS-linked mutant SOD1 damages mitochondria by promoting conformational changes in Bcl-2. Hum Mol Genet 2010; 19:2974&#x2013;2986.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang Y, Kong Q, Shan X, et al. Messenger RNA oxidation occurs early in disease pathogenesis and promotes motor neuron degeneration in ALS. PLoS One 2008; 3:e2849.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen JK. Oxidative stress in neurodegeneration: cause or consequence? Nat Med 2004; 10: (Suppl 7): S18&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui H, Kong Y, Zhang H. Oxidative stress, mitochondrial dysfunction, and aging. J Signal Transduct 2012; 2012:646354.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferraiuolo L, Higginbottom A, Heath PR, et al. Dysregulation of astrocyte-motoneuron cross-talk in mutant superoxide dismutase 1-related amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain 2011; 134 (Pt 9):2627&#x2013;2641.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirkinezos IG, Bacman SR, Hernandez D, et al. Cytochrome c association with the inner mitochondrial membrane is impaired in the CNS of G93A-SOD1 mice. J Neurosci 2005; 25:164&#x2013;172.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mattiazzi M, D&#x2019;Aurelio M, Gajewski CD, et al. Mutated human SOD1 causes dysfunction of oxidative phosphorylation in mitochondria of transgenic mice. J Biol Chem 2002; 277:29626&#x2013;29633.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuo X, Zhou J, Li Y, et al. TDP-43 aggregation induced by oxidative stress causes global mitochondrial imbalance in ALS. Nat Struct Mol Biol 2021; 28:132&#x2013;142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izumikawa K, Nobe Y, Yoshikawa H, et al. TDP-43 stabilises the processing intermediates of mitochondrial transcripts. Sci Rep 2017; 7:7709.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang W, Wang L, Lu J, et al. The inhibition of TDP-43 mitochondrial localization blocks its neuronal toxicity. Nat Med 2016; 22:869&#x2013;878.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu CH, Davidson S, Harapas CR, et al. TDP-43 Triggers Mitochondrial DNA Release via mPTP to Activate cGAS/STING in ALS. Cell 2020; 183:636&#x2013;649. e18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stoll L, Rodriguez-Trejo A, Guay C, et al. A circular RNA generated from an intron of the insulin gene controls insulin secretion. Nat Commun 2020; 11:5611.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Araki K, Araki A, Honda D, et al. TDP-43 regulates early-phase insulin secretion via CaV1.2-mediated exocytosis in islets. J Clin Investig 2019; 129:3578&#x2013;3593.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Birsa N, Bentham MP, Fratta P. Cytoplasmic functions of TDP-43 and FUS and their role in ALS. Semin Cell Dev Biol 2020; 99:193&#x2013;201.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng J, Yang M, Chen Y, et al. FUS interacts with HSP60 to promote mitochondrial damage. PLoS Genet 2015; 11:e1005357.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brunet MA, Jacques JF, Nassari S, et al. The FUS gene is dual-coding with both proteins contributing to FUS-mediated toxicity. EMBO Rep 2021; 22:e50640.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balendra R, Isaacs AM. C9orf72-mediated ALS and FTD: multiple pathways to disease. Nat Rev Neurol 2018; 14:544&#x2013;558.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Odnokoz O, Nakatsuka K, Wright C, et al. Mitochondrial redox signaling is critical to the normal functioning of the neuronal system. Front Cell Dev Biol 2021; 9:613036.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Onesto E, Colombrita C, Gumina V, et al. Gene-specific mitochondria dysfunctions in human TARDBP and C9ORF72 fibroblasts. Acta Neuropathol Commun 2016; 4:47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang T, Liu H, Itoh K, et al. C9orf72 regulates energy homeostasis by stabilizing mitochondrial complex I assembly. Cell Metab 2021; 33:531&#x2013;546. e9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langhardt J, Flehmig G, Kloting N, et al. Effects of weight loss on glutathione peroxidase 3 serum concentrations and adipose tissue expression in human obesity. Obes Facts 2018; 11:475&#x2013;490.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teng AC, Adamo K, Tesson F, Stewart AF. Functional characterization of a promoter polymorphism that drives ACSL5 gene expression in skeletal muscle and associates with diet-induced weight loss. FASEB J 2009; 23:1705&#x2013;1709.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iacoangeli A, Lin T, Al Khleifat A, et al. Genome-wide meta-analysis finds the ACSL5-ZDHHC6 Locus is associated with ALS and links weight loss to the disease genetics. Cell Rep 2020; 33:108323.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>