<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">34363416</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1531-8257</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>36</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Movement disorders : official journal of the Movement Disorder Society</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Mov Disord</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Systematic Assessment of 10 Biomarker Candidates Focusing on &#x3b1;-Synuclein-Related Disorders.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2874</StartPage><EndPage>2887</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2874-2887</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/mds.28738</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Objective diagnostic biomarkers are needed to support a clinical diagnosis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES">To analyze markers in various neurodegenerative disorders to identify diagnostic biomarker candidates for mainly &#x3b1;-synuclein (aSyn)-related disorders (ASRD) in serum and/or cerebrospinal fluid (CSF).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Upon initial testing of commercially available kits or published protocols for the quantification of the candidate markers, assays for the following were selected: total and phosphorylated aSyn (pS129aSyn), neurofilament light chain (NfL), phosphorylated neurofilament heavy chain (pNfH), tau protein (tau), ubiquitin C-terminal hydrolase L1 (UCHL-1), glial fibrillary acidic protein (GFAP), calcium-binding protein B (S100B), soluble triggering receptor expressed on myeloid cells 2 (sTREM-2), and chitinase-3-like protein 1 (YKL-40). The cohort comprised participants with Parkinson's disease (PD, n&#xa0;=&#xa0;151), multiple system atrophy (MSA, n&#xa0;=&#xa0;17), dementia with Lewy bodies (DLB, n&#xa0;=&#xa0;45), tau protein-related neurodegenerative disorders (n&#xa0;=&#xa0;80, comprising patients with progressive supranuclear palsy (PSP, n&#xa0;=&#xa0;38), corticobasal syndrome (CBS, n&#xa0;=&#xa0;16), Alzheimer's disease (AD, n&#xa0;=&#xa0;11), and frontotemporal degeneration/amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (FTD/ALS, n&#xa0;=&#xa0;15), as well as healthy controls (HC, n&#xa0;=&#xa0;20). Receiver operating curves (ROC) with area under the curves (AUC) are given for each marker.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">CSF total aSyn was decreased. NfL, pNfH, UCHL-1, GFAP, S100B, and sTREM-2 were increased in patients with neurodegenerative disease versus HC (P&#xa0;&lt;&#x2009;0.05). As expected, some of the markers were highest in AD (i.e., UCHL-1, GFAP, S100B, sTREM-2, YKL-40). Within ASRD, CSF NfL levels were higher in MSA than PD and DLB (P&#xa0;&lt;&#x2009;0.05). Comparing PD to HC, interesting serum markers were S100B (AUC: 0.86), sTREM2 (AUC: 0.87), and NfL (AUC: 0.78). CSF S100B and serum GFAP were highest in DLB.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Levels of most marker candidates tested in serum and CSF significantly differed between disease groups and HC. In the stratification of PD versus other tau- or aSyn-related conditions, CSF NfL levels best discriminated PD and MSA. CSF S100B and serum GFAP best discriminated PD and DLB. &#xa9; 2021 The Authors. Movement Disorders published by Wiley Periodicals LLC on behalf of International Parkinson Movement Disorder Society.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 The Authors. Movement Disorders published by Wiley Periodicals LLC on behalf of International Parkinson Movement Disorder Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Schulz</LastName><ForeName>Isabel</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Paracelsus-Elena-Klinik, Kassel, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Kruse</LastName><ForeName>Niels</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuropathology, University Medical Centre Goettingen, Goettingen, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gera</LastName><ForeName>Roland G</ForeName><Initials>RG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Statistics, University Medical Centre Goettingen, Goettingen, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kremer</LastName><ForeName>Thomas</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Roche Pharmaceutical Research and Early Development, NRD Neuroscience and Rare Disease, Roche Innovation Center Basel, F. Hoffmann-La Roche Ltd, Basel, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cedarbaum</LastName><ForeName>Jesse</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Coeruleus Clinical Sciences LLC, Woodbidge, Connecticut, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Yale University School of Medicine, New Haven, Connecticut, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Barbour</LastName><ForeName>Robin</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Prothena Biosciences Inc., San Francisco, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zago</LastName><ForeName>Wagner</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Prothena Biosciences Inc., San Francisco, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schade</LastName><ForeName>Sebastian</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6316-6804</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University Medical Centre Goettingen, Goettingen, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Otte</LastName><ForeName>Birgit</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University Medical Centre Goettingen, Goettingen, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bartl</LastName><ForeName>Michael</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University Medical Centre Goettingen, Goettingen, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hutten</LastName><ForeName>Samantha J</ForeName><Initials>SJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Michael J. Fox Foundation for Parkinson's Research, New York, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Trenkwalder</LastName><ForeName>Claudia</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Paracelsus-Elena-Klinik, Kassel, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, University Medical Centre Goettingen, Goettingen, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mollenhauer</LastName><ForeName>Brit</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8437-3645</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Paracelsus-Elena-Klinik, Kassel, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University Medical Centre Goettingen, Goettingen, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Mov Disord</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8610688</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0885-3185</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D015415">Biomarkers</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D051844">alpha-Synuclein</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D016875">tau Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015415" MajorTopicYN="N">Biomarkers</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000134" MajorTopicYN="N">cerebrospinal fluid</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Frontotemporal Dementia</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019578" MajorTopicYN="Y">Multiple System Atrophy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051844" MajorTopicYN="N">alpha-Synuclein</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000134" MajorTopicYN="N">cerebrospinal fluid</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016875" MajorTopicYN="N">tau Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000134" MajorTopicYN="N">cerebrospinal fluid</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Parkinson's disease/parkinsonism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cohort studies</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">outcome research</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34363416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mds.28738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Adler CH, Beach TG, Hentz JG, et al. Low clinical diagnostic accuracy of early vs advanced Parkinson disease: clinicopathologic study. Neurology 2014;83:406-412.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shahnawaz M, Mukherjee A, Pritzkow S, et al. Discriminating alpha-synuclein strains in Parkinson's disease and multiple system atrophy. Nature 2020;578:273-277.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Luca CMG, Elia AE, Portaleone SM, et al. Efficient RT-QuIC seeding activity for alpha-synuclein in olfactory mucosa samples of patients with Parkinson's disease and multiple system atrophy. Transl Neurodegener 2019;8:24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang UJ, Boehme AK, Fairfoul G, et al. Comparative study of cerebrospinal fluid alpha-synuclein seeding aggregation assays for diagnosis of Parkinson's disease. Mov Disord 2019;34:536-544.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hall S, Ohrfelt A, Constantinescu R, et al. Accuracy of a panel of 5 cerebrospinal fluid biomarkers in the differential diagnosis of patients with dementia and/or parkinsonian disorders. Arch Neurol 2012;69:1445-1452.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mollenhauer B, El-Agnaf OM, Marcus K, Trenkwalder C, Schlossmacher MG. Quantification of alpha-synuclein in cerebrospinal fluid as a biomarker candidate: review of the literature and considerations for future studies. Biomark Med 2010;4:683-699.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chahine LM, Beach TG, Brumm MC, et al. In vivo distribution of alpha-synuclein in multiple tissues and biofluids in Parkinson disease. Neurology 2020;95:e1267-e1284.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mondello S, Constantinescu R, Zetterberg H, Andreasson U, Holmberg B, Jeromin A. CSF alpha-synuclein and UCH-L1 levels in Parkinson's disease and atypical parkinsonian disorders. Parkinsonism Relat Disord 2014;20(4):382-387.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Z, Wang KK. Glial fibrillary acidic protein: from intermediate filament assembly and gliosis to neurobiomarker. Trends Neurosci 2015;38:364-374.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steiner J, Bogerts B, Schroeter ML, Bernstein HG. S100B protein in neurodegenerative disorders. Clin Chem Lab Med 2011;49:409-424.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jay TR, von Saucken VE, Landreth GE. TREM2 in neurodegenerative diseases. Mol Neurodegener 2017;12:56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suarez-Calvet M, Morenas-Rodriguez E, Kleinberger G, et al. Early increase of CSF sTREM2 in Alzheimer's disease is associated with tau related-neurodegeneration but not with amyloid-beta pathology. Mol Neurodegener 2019;14:1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson EN, Swarovski MS, Linortner P, et al. Soluble TREM2 is elevated in Parkinson's disease subgroups with increased CSF tau. Brain 2020;143:932-943.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heywood WE, Galimberti D, Bliss E, et al. Identification of novel CSF biomarkers for neurodegeneration and their validation by a high-throughput multiplexed targeted proteomic assay. Mol Neurodegener 2015;10:64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mollenhauer B, Trautmann E, Sixel-Doring F, et al. Nonmotor and diagnostic findings in subjects with de novo Parkinson disease of the DeNoPa cohort. Neurology 2013;81:1226-1234.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mollenhauer B, Dakna M, Kruse N, et al. Validation of serum neurofilament light chain as a biomarker of Parkinson's disease progression. Mov Disord 2020;35:1999-2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Candelise N, Schmitz M, Llorens F, et al. Seeding variability of different alpha synuclein strains in synucleinopathies. Ann Neurol 2019;85:691-703.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foulds PG, Diggle P, Mitchell JD, et al. A longitudinal study on alpha-synuclein in blood plasma as a biomarker for Parkinson's disease. Sci Rep 2013;3:2540.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin L, Latypova X, Terro F. Post-translational modifications of tau protein: implications for Alzheimer's disease. Neurochem Int 2011;58:458-471.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stewart T, Sossi V, Aasly JO, et al. Phosphorylated alpha-synuclein in Parkinson's disease: correlation depends on disease severity. Acta Neuropathol Commun 2015;3:7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cariulo C, Martufi P, Verani M, et al. Phospho-S129 alpha-synuclein is present in human plasma but not in cerebrospinal fluid as determined by an ultrasensitive immunoassay. Front Neurosci 2019;13:889.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mattsson N, Cullen NC, Andreasson U, Zetterberg H, Blennow K. Association between longitudinal plasma neurofilament light and neurodegeneration in patients with Alzheimer disease. JAMA Neurol 2019;76:791-799.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marques TM, van Rumund A, Oeckl P, et al. Serum NFL discriminates Parkinson disease from atypical parkinsonisms. Neurology 2019;92:e1479-e1486.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hansson O, Janelidze S, Hall S, et al. Blood-based NfL: a biomarker for differential diagnosis of parkinsonian disorder. Neurology 2017;88:930-937.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Constantinescu R, Zetterberg H, Holmberg B, Rosengren L. Levels of brain related proteins in cerebrospinal fluid: an aid in the differential diagnosis of parkinsonian disorders. Parkinsonism Relat Disord 2009;15:205-212.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishiki A, Kamada M, Kawamura Y, et al. Glial fibrillar acidic protein in the cerebrospinal fluid of Alzheimer's disease, dementia with Lewy bodies, and frontotemporal lobar degeneration. J Neurochem 2016;136:258-261.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siracusa R, Fusco R, Cuzzocrea S. Astrocytes: role and functions in brain pathologies. Front Pharmacol 2019;10:1114.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Constantinescu R, Rosengren L, Johnels B, Zetterberg H, Holmberg B. Consecutive analyses of cerebrospinal fluid axonal and glial markers in Parkinson's disease and atypical Parkinsonian disorders. Parkinsonism Relat Disord 2010;16:142-145.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sussmuth SD, Uttner I, Landwehrmeyer B, et al. Differential pattern of brain-specific CSF proteins tau and amyloid-beta in Parkinsonian syndromes. Mov Disord 2010;25:1284-1288.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su X, Federoff HJ. Immune responses in Parkinson's disease: interplay between central and peripheral immune systems. Biomed Res Int 2014;2014:275178.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L, Gao T, Cai T, et al. Cerebrospinal fluid levels of YKL-40 in prodromal Alzheimer's disease. Neurosci Lett 2020;715:134658.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wennstr&#xf6;m M, Surova Y, Hall S, et al. The inflammatory marker YKL-40 is elevated in cerebrospinal fluid from patients with Alzheimer's but not Parkinson's disease or dementia with Lewy bodies. PLoS One 2015;10:e0135458.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olsson B, Constantinescu R, Holmberg B, Andreasen N, Blennow K, Zetterberg H. The glial marker YKL-40 is decreased in synucleinopathies. Mov Disord 2013;28:1882-1885.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ulland TK, Song WM, Huang SC, et al. TREM2 maintains microglial metabolic fitness in Alzheimer's disease. Cell 2017;170:649-663. e613.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mila-Aloma M, Salvado G, Gispert JD, et al. Amyloid beta, tau, synaptic, neurodegeneration, and glial biomarkers in the preclinical stage of the Alzheimer's continuum. Alzheimers Dement 2020;16:1358-1371.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>