<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">34378224</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>18</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-4598</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>64</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Muscle &amp; nerve</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Muscle Nerve</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Gold Coast diagnostic criteria: Implications for ALS diagnosis and clinical trial enrollment.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>532</StartPage><EndPage>537</EndPage><MedlinePgn>532-537</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/mus.27392</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Diagnostic criteria for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) are complex, incorporating multiple levels of certainty from possible through to definite, and are thereby prone to error. Specifically, interrater variability was previously established to be poor, thereby limiting utility as diagnostic enrollment criteria for clinical trials. In addition, the different levels of diagnostic certainty do not necessarily reflect disease progression, adding confusion to the diagnostic algorithm. Realizing these inherent limitations, the World Federation of Neurology, the International Federation of Clinical Neurophysiology, the International Alliance of ALS/MND Associations, the ALS Association (United States), and the Motor Neuron Disease Association convened a consensus meeting (Gold Coast, Australia, 2019) to consider the development of simpler criteria that better reflect clinical practice, and that could merge diagnostic categories into a single entity. The diagnostic accuracy of the novel Gold Coast criteria was subsequently interrogated through a large cross-sectional study, which established an increased sensitivity for ALS diagnosis when compared with previous criteria. Diagnostic accuracy was maintained irrespective of disease duration, functional status, or site of disease onset. Importantly, the Gold Coast criteria differentiated atypical phenotypes, such as primary lateral sclerosis, from the more typical ALS phenotype. It is proposed that the Gold Coast criteria should be incorporated into routine practice and clinical trial settings.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vucic</LastName><ForeName>Steve</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Westmead Clinical School, Sydney Medical School, University of Sydney, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ferguson</LastName><ForeName>Toby A</ForeName><Initials>TA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biogen Idec, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cummings</LastName><ForeName>Catherine</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>International Alliance of ALS/MND Associations, Melbourne, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hotchkin</LastName><ForeName>Michael T</ForeName><Initials>MT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clene, Nanomedicine, Salt Lake City, Utah, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Genge</LastName><ForeName>Angela</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Neuro, Montreal Neurological Institute, Montreal, Quebec, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Glanzman</LastName><ForeName>Robert</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clene, Nanomedicine, Salt Lake City, Utah, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Roet</LastName><ForeName>Kasper C D</ForeName><Initials>KCD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>QurAlis Corporation, Cambridge, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cudkowicz</LastName><ForeName>Merit</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Massachusetts General Hospital, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kiernan</LastName><ForeName>Matthew C</ForeName><Initials>MC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Brain and Mind Centre, University of Sydney &amp; Department of Neurology, Royal Prince Alfred Hospital, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Muscle Nerve</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7803146</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0148-639X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001315" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Australia</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003430" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Sectional Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016472" MajorTopicYN="Y">Motor Neuron Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ALS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Gold Coast criteria</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">clinical trials</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lower motor neuron</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">upper motor neuron</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>59</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34378224</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.27392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Kiernan MC, Vucic S, Talbot K, et al. Improving clinical trial outcomes in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat Rev Neurol. 2020;17:1-15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiernan MC, Vucic S, Cheah BC, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet. 2011;377:942-955.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR. El Escorial World Federation of Neurology criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Subcommittee on Motor Neuron Diseases/Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis of the World Federation of Neurology Research Group on Neuromuscular Diseases and the El Escorial &#x201c;Clinical limits of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis&#x201d; workshop contributors. J Neurol Sci. 1994;124:96-107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner MR, Hardiman O, Benatar M, et al. Controversies and priorities in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet Neurol. 2013;12:310-322.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, Miller RG, Swash M, Munsat TL. El Escorial revisited: revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord. 2000;1:293-299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Dengler R, Eisen A, et al. Electrodiagnostic criteria for diagnosis of ALS. Clin Neurophysiol. 2008;119:497-503.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hannaford A, Pavey N, van den Bos M, et al. Diagnostic utility of Gold Coast criteria in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol. 2021;89:979-986.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chio A. ISIS survey: an international study on the diagnostic process and its implications in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol. 1999;246(Suppl 3):1-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner MR, Kiernan MC, Leigh PN, Talbot K. Biomarkers in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet Neurol. 2009;8:94-109.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aggarwal S, Cudkowicz M. ALS drug development: reflections from the past and a way forward. Neurotherapeutics. 2008;5:516-527.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geevasinga N, Loy CT, Menon P, et al. Awaji criteria improves the diagnostic sensitivity in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a systematic review using individual patient data. Clin Neurophysiol. 2016;127:2684-2691.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Bentes C, Evangelista T, Luis ML. Fibrillation and sharp-waves: do we need them to diagnose ALS? Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord. 1999;1:29-32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Douglass CP, Kandler RH, Shaw PJ, McDermott CJ. An evaluation of neurophysiological criteria used in the diagnosis of motor neuron disease. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2010;81:646-649.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Swash M. Awaji diagnostic algorithm increases sensitivity of El Escorial criteria for ALS diagnosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2009;10:53-57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boekestein WA, Kleine BU, Hageman G, Schelhaas HJ, Zwarts MJ. Sensitivity and specificity of the 'Awaji' electrodiagnostic criteria for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: retrospective comparison of the Awaji and revised El Escorial criteria for ALS. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2010;11:497-501.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schrooten M, Smetcoren C, Robberecht W, Van Damme P. Benefit of the Awaji diagnostic algorithm for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a prospective study. Ann Neurol. 2011;70:79-83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa J, Swash M, de Carvalho M. Awaji criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a systematic review. Arch Neurol. 2012;69:1410-1416.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okita T, Nodera H, Shibuta Y, et al. Can Awaji ALS criteria provide earlier diagnosis than the revised El Escorial criteria? J Neurol Sci. 2011;302:29-32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen A, Weimer L, Brannagan T 3rd, et al. Experience with the Awaji Island modifications to the ALS diagnostic criteria. Muscle Nerve. 2010;42:831-832.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krarup C. Lower motor neuron involvement examined by quantitative electromyography in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Neurophysiol. 2011;122:414-422.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gawel M, Kuzma-Kozakiewicz M, Szmidt-Salkowska E, Kami&#x144;ska A. Are we really closer to improving the diagnostic sensitivity in ALS patients with Awaji criteria? Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2014;15:257-261.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jang JS, Bae JS. AWAJI criteria are not always superior to the previous criteria: a meta-analysis. Muscle Nerve. 2015;51:822-829.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnsen B, Pugdahl K, Fuglsang-Frederiksen A, et al. Diagnostic criteria for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a multicentre study of inter-rater variation and sensitivity. Clin Neurophysiol. 2019;130:307-314.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geevasinga N, Menon P, Scherman DB, et al. Diagnostic criteria in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a multicenter prospective study. Neurology. 2016;87:684-690.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Traynor BJ, Zhang H, Shefner JM, Schoenfeld D, Cudkowicz ME. Functional outcome measures as clinical trial endpoints in ALS. Neurology. 2004;63:1933-1935.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner MR, Barohn RJ, Corcia P, et al. Primary lateral sclerosis: consensus diagnostic criteria. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2020;91:373-377.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strong MJ, Abrahams S, Goldstein LH, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-frontotemporal spectrum disorder (ALS-FTSD): revised diagnostic criteria. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2017;18:153-174.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shefner JM, Al-Chalabi A, Baker MR, et al. A proposal for new diagnostic criteria for ALS. Clin Neurophysiol. 2020;131:1975-1978.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Upadhyay V, Katz M, Kiernan M, Henderson R. Review of the revised amyotrophic lateral sclerosis diagnostic criteria. Clin Neurophysiol. 2020;131:1767-1768.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ludolph A, Drory V, Hardiman O, et al. A revision of the El Escorial criteria-2015. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2015;16:291-292.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swash M. Why are upper motor neuron signs difficult to elicit in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis? J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2012;83:659-662.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swash M, Burke D, Turner MR, et al. Occasional essay: upper motor neuron syndrome in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2020;91:227-234.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simon NG, Turner MR, Vucic S, et al. Quantifying disease progression in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol. 2014;76:643-657.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simon NG, Lin CS, Lee M, et al. Segmental motoneuronal dysfunction is a feature of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Neurophysiol. 2015;126:828-836.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ince PG, Evans J, Knopp M, et al. Corticospinal tract degeneration in the progressive muscular atrophy variant of ALS. Neurology. 2003;60:1252-1258.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Visser J, van den Berg-Vos RM, Franssen H, et al. Disease course and prognostic factors of progressive muscular atrophy. Arch Neurol. 2007;64:522-528.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tartaglia MC, Rowe A, Findlater K, Orange JB, Grace G, Strong MJ. Differentiation between primary lateral sclerosis and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: examination of symptoms and signs at disease onset and during follow-up. Arch Neurol. 2007;64:232-236.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bossuyt PM, Reitsma JB, Linnet K, Moons KG. Beyond diagnostic accuracy: the clinical utility of diagnostic tests. Clin Chem. 2012;58:1636-1643.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDermott CJ. Clinical trials in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Curr Opin Neurol. 2019;32:758-763.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Eijk RPA, Westeneng HJ, Nikolakopoulos S, et al. Refining eligibility criteria for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis clinical trials. Neurology. 2019;92:e451-e460.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>