<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">34398392</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2662-4737</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>44</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Physical and engineering sciences in medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Phys Eng Sci Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Automated diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis using electromyograms and firefly algorithm based neural networks with fractional position update.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1095</StartPage><EndPage>1105</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1095-1105</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s13246-021-01046-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis (ALS) is a disorder of the neuromuscular system that causes the impairment of nerve cells from brain to spinal cord and to the voluntary muscles in every part of the human physiological system, which totally leads to paralysis. The examination of ALS using Electromyograms (EMG) is a challenging task which requires experts to investigate and diagnose. Hence, the development of an efficient and automated procedure is significant for the analysis of ALS signals. In this work, eighty time-frequency features were extricated from EMG signals transformed into time-frequency images. Further, fifteen highly substantial features were chosen using the firefly algorithm with fractional position update. Further, fractional firefly neural network is introduced and developed to examine the EMG signals. The performance metrics of the fractional firefly based neural network diagnostic system were analyzed with different fractional orders (&#x3b1;) and hidden neurons. Results demonstrated that the proposed technique is highly efficient and yields good statistical significance. Further, the accuracy of the fractional firefly neural network classifier with &#x3b1; &#x2009;=&#x2009;0.5 and 15 hidden neurons is higher (93.3%) when compared to the accuracy of the classifier with different &#x3b1; values and hidden neurons. The proposed fractional order-based feature selection algorithm and classifier model are highly suitable for development of systems for evaluation of ALS and normal EMG signals, since the proficient discrimination of normal and ALS EMG signals is essential for the identification of neuromuscular disorders.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021. Australasian College of Physical Scientists and Engineers in Medicine.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bakiya</LastName><ForeName>A</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Instrumentation Engineering, MIT Campus, Anna University, Chennai, 600044, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kamalanand</LastName><ForeName>K</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Instrumentation Engineering, MIT Campus, Anna University, Chennai, 600044, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rajinikanth</LastName><ForeName>V</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3897-4460</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electronics and Instrumentation Engineering, St. Joseph's College of Engineering, Chennai, 600119, India. v.rajinikanth@ieee.org.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Phys Eng Sci Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101760671</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2662-4729</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000465" MajorTopicYN="N">Algorithms</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004576" MajorTopicYN="N">Electromyography</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016571" MajorTopicYN="N">Neural Networks, Computer</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Electromyograms</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fractional calculus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fractional firefly algorithm</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fractional firefly based neural network</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Time&#x2013;frequency transformation</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34398392</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13246-021-01046-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s13246-021-01046-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Rowland LP, Shneider NA (2001) Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. N Engl J Med 344(22):1688&#x2013;1700</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJM200105313442207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenway MJ, Andersen PM, Russ C, Ennis S, Cashman S, Donaghy C, Morrison KE (2006) ANG mutations segregate with familial and&#x2019;sporadic&#x2019;amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat Genet 38(4):411</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ng1742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Couratier P, Corcia P, Lautrette G, Nicol M, Preux PM, Marin B (2016) Epidemiology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a review of literature. Revue Neurologique 172(1):37&#x2013;45</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neurol.2015.11.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR (2000) Risk factors in the early diagnosis of ALS: North American epidemiological studies. ALS CARE Study Group. Amyotrop Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disorder 1:S19-26</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14660820052415871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller RG, Anderson FA, Bradley WG, Brooks BR, Mitsumoto H, Munsat TL, ALS CARE Study Group (2000) The ALS Patient care database goals, design, and early results. Neurology 54(1):53&#x2013;53</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.54.1.53</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arthur KC, Calvo A, Price TR, Geiger JT, Chio A, Traynor BJ (2016) Projected increase in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis from 2015 to 2040. Nat Commun 7:12408</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ncomms12408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joshi D, Tripathi A, Sharma R, Pachori RB (2017) Computer aided detection of abnormal EMG signals based on tunable-Q wavelet transform. In: Signal Processing and Integrated Networks (SPIN), 2017 4th International Conference on. IEEE, 544&#x2013;549</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadikoglu F, Kavalcioglu C, Dagman B (2017) Electromyogram (EMG) signal detection, classification of EMG signals and diagnosis of neuropathy muscle disease. Proced Comp Sci 120:422&#x2013;429</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.procs.2017.11.259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duque CJG, Mu&#xf1;oz LD, Mej&#xed;a JG, Trejos ED (2014) Discrete wavelet transform and k-nn classification in EMG signals for diagnosis of neuromuscular disorders. In: Image, Signal Processing and Artificial Vision (STSIVA), 2014 XIX Symposium on IEEE 1&#x2013;5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Subasi A (2012) Classification of EMG signals using combined features and soft computing techniques. Appl Soft Comput 12(8):2188&#x2013;2198</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.asoc.2012.03.035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yousefi J, Hamilton-Wright A (2014) Characterizing EMG data using machine-learning tools. Comput Biol Med 51:1&#x2013;1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compbiomed.2014.04.018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phinyomark A, Phukpattaranont P, Limsakul C (2012) Feature reduction and selection for EMG signal classification. Exp Syst Appl 39(8):7420&#x2013;7431</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eswa.2012.01.102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagineni S, Taran S, Bajaj V (2018) Features based on variational mode decomposition for identification of neuromuscular disorder using EMG signals. Health Informa Sci Syst 6(1):13</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13755-018-0050-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fattah SA, Iqbal MA, Jumana MA, Doulah ASU (2012) Identifying the motor neuron disease in EMG signal using time and frequency domain features with comparison. Signal Image Process 3(2):99</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krishna VA, Thomas P (2015) Classification of EMG signals using spectral features extracted from dominant motor unit action potential. Int J Eng Adv Technol 4(5):196&#x2013;200</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakiya A, Kamalanand K, Rajinikanth V, Nayak RS, Kadry S (2018) Deep neural network assisted diagnosis of time-frequency transformed electromyograms. Multimedia Tools Appl 1&#x2013;17</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gandomi AH, Yang XS, Alavi AH (2013) Cuckoo search algorithm: a metaheuristic approach to solve structural optimization problems. Eng Comput 29(1):17&#x2013;35</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00366-011-0241-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang XS, Algorithms NIM (2008) Luniver Press. Beckington, UK, pp 242&#x2013;246</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abualigah L, Diabat A, Mirjalili S, Abd Elaziz M, Gandomi AH (2021) The arithmetic optimization algorithm. Comput Methods Appl Mech Eng 376:113609</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cma.2020.113609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abualigah L, Shehab M, Diabat A, Abraham A (2020) Selection scheme sensitivity for a hybrid Salp Swarm Algorithm: analysis and applications. Eng Comput 1&#x2013;27</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abualigah L, Diabat A (2020) A comprehensive survey of the Grasshopper optimization algorithm: results, variants, and applications. Neural Comput Appl 1&#x2013;24</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abualigah L (2020) Group search optimizer: a nature-inspired meta-heuristic optimization algorithm with its results, variants, and applications. Neural Comput Appl 1&#x2013;24</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang XS, He X (2013) Firefly algorithm: recent advances and applications. Int J Swarm Intell 1(1):36&#x2013;50</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1504/IJSI.2013.055801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang XS (2010) Firefly algorithm, stochastic test functions and design optimisation. Int J Bio-Inspired Comput 2(2):78&#x2013;84</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1504/IJBIC.2010.032124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabatier JATMJ, Agrawal OP, Machado JT (2007) Advances in fractional calculus, Springer, Dordrecht 4(9)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tenreiro Machado JA, Silva MF, Barbosa RS, Jesus IS, Reis CM, Marcos MG, Galhano AF (2010) Some applications of fractional calculus in engineering. Mathem Probl Eng 2010</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khudair AR, Haddad SAM (2017) Restricted fractional differential transform for solving irrational order fractional differential equations. Chaos, Solitons Fractals 101:81&#x2013;85</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chaos.2017.05.026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghamisi P, Couceiro MS, Benediktsson JA (2013) Classification of hyperspectral images with binary fractional order Darwinian PSO and random forests. In: Image and signal processing for remote sensing XIX. International Society for Optics and Photonics 8892:88920S</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ambikapathy B, Kirshnamurthy K, Venkatesan R (2018) Assessment of electromyograms using genetic algorithm and artificial neural networks. Evol Intell 1&#x2013;11</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garro BA, V&#xe1;zquez RA (2015) Designing artificial neural networks using particle swarm optimization algorithms. Comput Intell Neurosci 2015:61</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2015/369298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nikolic M (2001) Detailed analysis of clinical electromyography signals: EMG decomposition, findings and firing pattern analysis in controls and patients with myopathy and amytrophic lateral sclerosis (Doctoral dissertation).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quynh TL, Ardi HA, Gilat M, Rifai C, Ehgoetz MK, Georgiades M, Nguyen HT (2017) Detection of turning freeze in Parkinson's disease based on S-transform decomposition of EEG signals. In: Conference proceedings:... Annual International Conference of the IEEE Engineering in Medicine and Biology Society. IEEE Engineering in Medicine and Biology Society. Annual Conference, 2017 : 3044</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies MR, Reisman SS (1994) Time frequency analysis of the electromyogram during fatigue. In: Bioengineering conference, 1994, Proceedings of the 1994 20th Annual Northeast, IEEE, pp 93&#x2013;95</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu G, Yu M, Xu C (2017). Synchroextracting transform. IEEE transactions on industrial electronics</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuniszyk-J&#xf3;zkowiak W, Jaszczuk J, Sacewicz T, Codello I (2012) Time-frequency analysis of the EMG digital signals. In: Annales Universitatis Mariae Curie-Sklodowska. (Vol. 12, No. 2), De Gruyter Open Sp. z oo, (p 19)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magin R, Feng X, Baleanu D (2009) Solving the fractional order Bloch equation. Concepts Magnet Reson Part A 34(1):16&#x2013;23</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cmr.a.20129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vinagre BM, Petr&#xe1;&#x161; I, Podlubny I, Chen YQ (2002) Using fractional order adjustment rules and fractional order reference models in model-reference adaptive control. Nonlinear Dyn 29(1&#x2013;4):269&#x2013;279</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1023/A:1016504620249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mousavi Y, Alfi A (2018) Fractional calculus-based firefly algorithm applied to parameter estimation of chaotic systems. Chaos, Solitons Fractals 114:202&#x2013;215</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chaos.2018.07.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pires ES, Machado JT, de Moura Oliveira PB, Cunha JB, Mendes L (2010) Particle swarm optimization with fractional-order velocity. Nonlinear Dyn 61(1&#x2013;2):295&#x2013;301</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11071-009-9649-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nayak J, Naik B, Behera HS (2016) A novel nature inspired firefly algorithm with higher order neural network: performance analysis. Eng Sci Technol Int J 19(1):197&#x2013;211</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamalanand K, Mannar Jawahar P (2015) Comparison of swarm intelligence techniques for estimation of HIV-1 viral load. IETE Tech Rev 32(3):188&#x2013;195</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02564602.2014.1000981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamalanand K, Mannar Jawahar P (2016) Comparison of particle swarm and bacterial foraging optimization algorithms for therapy planning in HIV/AIDS patients. Int J Biomath 9(02):1650024</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1142/S1793524516500248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>