<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">34431795</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>17</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1537-1611</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>23</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of clinical neuromuscular disease</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Clin Neuromuscul Dis</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Nonmotor Symptoms in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis and Their Correlation With Disease Progression.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1</StartPage><EndPage>6</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1-6</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/CND.0000000000000343</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Motor neuron disease is a progressive neurodegenerative disease involving upper and lower motor neurons. Nonmotor symptoms (NMS) are part of disease manifestation.&#x202f;We aim&#x202f;to&#x202f;report the prevalence and severity of NMS in patients with motor neuron disease (MND) in Lebanon.&#x202f;.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Fifty-eight patients diagnosed with MND at the American University of Beirut Medical Center were interviewed using&#x202f;the NMS&#x202f;Scale. The prevalence of these symptoms was assessed and correlated with disease progression.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">All our patients had at least 2 NMS with an average total score of 15.8. Symptoms reported in more than half of the patients were fatigue, depression, dysphagia, lack of motivation, pain, change in weight, anxiety, constipation, and lack of pleasure. A significant correlation was found between the total NMS score and Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Functional Rating Scale score (P = 0.002) and between the NMS score corresponding to mental health and Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Functional Rating Scale score (P = 0.012). Patients with bulbar symptoms had a significantly higher NMS score corresponding to gastrointestinal symptoms (P &lt; 0.0001). It is important to note that NMS such as dysphagia could be related to motor neuron involvement.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">NMS are commonly reported in patients with MND and seem to positively correlate with disease progression. Treating NMS is a critical aspect of the clinical care delivered to patients with MND to maintain a good quality of life.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2021 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jaafar</LastName><ForeName>Nesreen</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, American University of Beirut, Beirut, Lebanon.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Malek</LastName><ForeName>Elia</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ismail</LastName><ForeName>Helen</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Salameh</LastName><ForeName>Johnny</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Clin Neuromuscul Dis</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100887391</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1522-0443</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001007" MajorTopicYN="N">Anxiety</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018450" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Progression</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019636" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neurodegenerative Diseases</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors report no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34431795</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/CND.0000000000000343</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00131402-202109000-00001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Al-Chalabi A, Hardiman O, Kiernan MC, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: moving towards a new classification system. Lancet Neurol. 2016;15:1182&#x2013;1194.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chio A, Calvo A, Moglia C, et al.; group, P.s. Phenotypic heterogeneity of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a population based study. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2011;82:740&#x2013;746.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehta P, Kaye W, Raymond J, et al. Prevalence of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis&#x2014;United States, 2015. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2018;67:1285&#x2013;1289.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byrne S, Walsh C, Lynch C, et al. Rate of familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2011;82:623&#x2013;627.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gruis KL, Lechtzin N. Respiratory therapies for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a primer. Muscle Nerve. 2012;46:313&#x2013;331.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phukan J, Elamin M, Bede P, et al. The syndrome of cognitive impairment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a population-based study. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2012;83:102&#x2013;108.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atassi N, Cook A, Pineda CM, et al. Depression in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2011;12:109&#x2013;112.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gunther R, Richter N, Sauerbier A, et al. Non-motor symptoms in patients suffering from motor neuron diseases. Front Neurol. 2016;7:117.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kacem I, Sidhom Y, Souissi W, et al. Non-motor neurological symptoms in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a study of a tunisian series. J Neurol Sci. 2017;381:712.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Es MA, Hardiman O, Chio A, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet. 2017;390:2084&#x2013;2098.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaudhuri KR, Martinez-Martin P, Brown RG, et al. The metric properties of a novel non-motor symptoms scale for Parkinson's disease: results from an international pilot study. Mov Disord. 2007;22:1901&#x2013;1911.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krishnan S, Sarma G, Sarma S, et al. Do nonmotor symptoms in Parkinson's disease differ from normal aging? Move Disord. 2011;26:2110&#x2013;2113.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum JM, Stambler N, Malta E, et al.; Group, B.A.S.; Group, A.c.l.o.t.B.S. The ALSFRS-R: a revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. J Neurol Sci. 1999;169:13&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paganoni S, McDonnell E, Schoenfeld D, et al. Functional decline is associated with hopelessness in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). J Neurol Neurophysiol. 2017;8:423.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones AR, Jivraj N, Balendra R, et al. Health utility decreases with increasing clinical stage in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2014;15:285&#x2013;291.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bock M, Duong YN, Kim A, et al. Cognitive-behavioral changes in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: screening prevalence and impact on patients and caregivers. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis and Frontotemporal Degeneration. 2016;17:366&#x2013;373.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Witgert M, Salamone AR, Strutt AM, et al. Frontal-lobe mediated behavioral dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Eur J Neurol. 2010;17:103&#x2013;110.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raaphorst J, van Tol M, De Visser M, et al. Prose memory impairment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients is related to hippocampus volume. Eur J Neurol. 2015;22:547&#x2013;554.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benbrika S, Desgranges B, Eustache F, et al. Cognitive, emotional and psychological manifestations in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis at baseline and overtime: a review. Front Neurosci. 2019;13:951.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nubling GS, Mie E, Bauer RM, et al. Increased prevalence of bladder and intestinal dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2014;15:174&#x2013;179.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toepfer M, Folwaczny C, Klauser A, et al. Gastrointestinal dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Mot Neuron Disord. 1999;1:15&#x2013;19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beck M, Giess R, Magnus T, et al. Progressive sudomotor dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2002;73:68&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarakad A, Jankovic J. Anosmia and ageusia in Parkinson's disease. Int Rev Neurobiol. 2017;133:541&#x2013;556.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>