<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">34437716</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>18</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-4598</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>64</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Muscle &amp; nerve</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Muscle Nerve</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Health services utilization prior to amyotrophic lateral sclerosis diagnosis: A province-wide study of individuals treated with riluzole in Ontario, Canada.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>691</StartPage><EndPage>700</EndPage><MedlinePgn>691-700</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/mus.27405</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION/AIMS">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) symptoms mimic those of other conditions and often require multiple physician and healthcare contacts for investigation and accurate diagnosis. We examined the type and frequency of healthcare service utilization prior to ALS diagnosis and tracheostomy-free survival by sex and rurality among individuals treated with riluzole in Ontario, Canada.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">This population-based cohort study used administrative databases to identify patients aged 18+ y diagnosed with ALS and started on riluzole between April 2002-March 2018. Using Poisson regression, rate ratios of healthcare utilization and atypical diagnostic tests and unnecessary therapeutic interventions 5 y prior to ALS diagnosis were compared by sex and rurality. Tracheostomy-free survival after diagnosis was compared between groups using Kaplan-Meier estimators and proportional hazards models.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">A total of 1071 patients with ALS were identified with a mean age of 70&#x2009;y; 563 (52.6%) were men and 134 (12.5%) were rural residents. The number of physician visits increased in the 18&#x2009;mo prior to ALS diagnosis. We observed modest sex differences in healthcare utilization. Rural patients had lower neurologist visit rates (rate ratio [RR], 0.78; 95% confidence interval [CI], 0.70-0.87) and were significantly more likely to receive an atypical diagnostic test or unnecessary therapeutic intervention (RR, 1.80; 95% CI, 1.04-3.10). Tracheostomy-free survival did not differ by sex (log-rank P-value&#xa0;=&#xa0;.78) or rurality (log-rank P-value&#xa0;=&#xa0;.84).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION">Given disparities observed in healthcare of rural ALS patients, policy strategies are needed to ensure all patients have timely access to care along the pathway from symptom onset to ALS diagnosis, to enable access to new therapeutics and clinical trials.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Campitelli</LastName><ForeName>Michael A</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ICES, Toronto, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abrahao</LastName><ForeName>Agessandro</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Neurology, Department of Medicine, Sunnybrook Health Sciences Centre, University of Toronto, Toronto, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sunnybrook Research Institute, Sunnybrook Health Sciences Centre, Toronto, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maclagan</LastName><ForeName>Laura C</ForeName><Initials>LC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ICES, Toronto, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fu</LastName><ForeName>Longdi</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ICES, Toronto, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maxwell</LastName><ForeName>Colleen J</ForeName><Initials>CJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ICES, Toronto, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Pharmacy, University of Waterloo, Waterloo, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Public Health and Health Systems, University of Waterloo, Waterloo, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Swartz</LastName><ForeName>Richard H</ForeName><Initials>RH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ICES, Toronto, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Neurology, Department of Medicine, Sunnybrook Health Sciences Centre, University of Toronto, Toronto, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sunnybrook Research Institute, Sunnybrook Health Sciences Centre, Toronto, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zinman</LastName><ForeName>Lorne</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Neurology, Department of Medicine, Sunnybrook Health Sciences Centre, University of Toronto, Toronto, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sunnybrook Research Institute, Sunnybrook Health Sciences Centre, Toronto, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bronskill</LastName><ForeName>Susan E</ForeName><Initials>SE</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7341-0655</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ICES, Toronto, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sunnybrook Research Institute, Sunnybrook Health Sciences Centre, Toronto, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Health Policy, Management &amp; Evaluation, University of Toronto, Toronto, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Muscle Nerve</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7803146</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0148-639X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>7LJ087RS6F</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D019782">Riluzole</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015331" MajorTopicYN="N">Cohort Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000078336" MajorTopicYN="N">Facilities and Services Utilization</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009864" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Ontario</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010342" MajorTopicYN="N">Patient Acceptance of Health Care</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019782" MajorTopicYN="Y">Riluzole</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">administrative data</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">health services</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34437716</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.27405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Turner MR, Talbot K. Mimics and chameleons in motor neurone disease. Pract Neurol. 2013;13(3):153-164. https://doi.org/10.1136/practneurol-2013-000557</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer M, Buerger M, Berlit P. Diagnostic problems and delay of diagnosis in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Neurol Neurosurg. 2010;112(2):103-105. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.clineuro.2009.10.014</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Srinivasan J, Scala S, Jones HR, Saleh F, Russell JA. Inappropriate surgeries resulting from misdiagnosis of early amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 2006;34(3):359-360. https://doi.org/10.1002/mus.20555</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palese F, Sartori A, Logroscino G, Pisa FE. Predictors of diagnostic delay in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a cohort study based on administrative and electronic medical records data. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2019;20(3-4):176-185. https://doi.org/10.1080/21678421.2018.1550517</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson AE, Anisimowicz Y, Miedema B, Hogg W, Wodchis WP, Aubrey-Bassler K. The influence of gender and other patient characteristics on health care-seeking behaviour: a QUALICOPC study. BMC Fam Pract. 2016;17:38. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12875-016-0440-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kazanjian A, Morettin D, Cho R. Health care utilization by Canadian women. BMC Womens Health. 2004;4(Suppl 1):S33. https://doi.org/10.1186/1472-6874-4-s1-s33</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCombe PA, Henderson RD. Effects of gender in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Gend Med. 2010;7(6):557-570. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.genm.2010.11.010</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glazier RH, Gozdyra P, Yeritsyan N. Geographic Access to Primary Care and Hospital Services for Rural and Northern Communities: Report to the Ontario Ministry of Health and Long-Term Care. Toronto, Ontario, Canada: Institute for Clinical Evaluative Sciences; 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rooney J, Byrne S, Heverin M, et al. A multidisciplinary clinic approach improves survival in ALS: a comparative study of ALS in Ireland and Northern Ireland. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2015;86(5):496-501. https://doi.org/10.1136/jnnp-2014-309601</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hodgkinson VL, Lounsberry J, Mirian A, et al. Provincial differences in the diagnosis and care of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Can J Neurol Sci. 2018;45(6):652-659. https://doi.org/10.1017/cjn.2018.311</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rose L, McKim D, Leasa D, et al. Patterns of healthcare utilisation for respiratory complications of adults with neuromuscular disease: a population study. Eur Respir J. 2018;52(3):1800754.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, Miller RG, Swash M, Munsat TL, World Federation of Neurology Research Group on Motor Neuron D. El Escorial revisited: revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord. 2000;1(5):293-299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kapral MK, Austin PC, Jeyakumar G, et al. Rural-urban differences in stroke risk factors, incidence, and mortality in people with and without prior stroke. Circ Cardiovasc Qual Outcomes. 2019;12(2):e004973. https://doi.org/10.1161/circoutcomes.118.004973</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hallet J, Law CH, Karanicolas PJ, Saskin R, Liu N, Singh S. Rural-urban disparities in incidence and outcomes of neuroendocrine tumors: a population-based analysis of 6271 cases. Cancer. 2015;121(13):2214-2221. https://doi.org/10.1002/cncr.29338</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conlon MS, Caswell JM, Santi SA, et al. Access to palliative care for cancer patients living in a northern and rural environment in Ontario, Canada: the effects of geographic region and rurality on end-of-life care in a population-based decedent cancer cohort. Clin Med Insights Oncol. 2019;13:1179554919829500. https://doi.org/10.1177/1179554919829500</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>du Plessis V, Beshiri R, Bollman R, Clemenson H (2002) Definitions of &#x201c;Rural&#x201d;: Rural and Small Town Canada Analysis Bulletin (Statistics Canada Agriculture and Rural Working Paper 61). Catalogue no. 21-006-XIE. Vol. 3, No. 3 (November 2001).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Statistics Canada. Postal Code Conversion File Plus (PCCF+) Version 7A, Reference Guide. Ottawa, Ontario, Canada: Statistics Canada; 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pefoyo AJ, Bronskill SE, Gruneir A, et al. The increasing burden and complexity of multimorbidity. BMC Public Health. 2015;15:415. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12889-015-1733-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gruneir A, Bronskill SE, Maxwell CJ, et al. The association between multimorbidity and hospitalization is modified by individual demographics and physician continuity of care: a retrospective cohort study. BMC Health Serv Res. 2016;16:154. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12913-016-1415-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lunetta C, Lizio A, Maestri E, et al. Serum C-reactive protein as a prognostic biomarker in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. JAMA Neurol. 2017;74(6):660-667. https://doi.org/10.1001/jamaneurol.2016.6179</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chio A, Calvo A, Bovio G, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis outcome measures and the role of albumin and creatinine: a population-based study. JAMA Neurol. 2014;71(9):1134-1142. https://doi.org/10.1001/jamaneurol.2014.1129</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tai H, Cui L, Guan Y, et al. Correlation of creatine kinase levels with clinical features and survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Front Neurol. 2017;8:322. https://doi.org/10.3389/fneur.2017.00322</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harrison L, Wills A, Beasley N. Diagnosing amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) in ENT. Clin Otolaryngol. 2013;38(6):564-565. https://doi.org/10.1111/coa.12186</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Witt JC, Stevens JC. Neurologic disorders masquerading as carpal tunnel syndrome: 12 cases of failed carpal tunnel release. Mayo Clin Proc. 2000;75(4):409-413. https://doi.org/10.4065/75.4.409</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshor D, Klugh A 3rd, Appel SH, Haverkamp LJ. Incidence and characteristics of spinal decompression surgery after the onset of symptoms of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurosurgery. 2005;57(5):984-989; discussion 984-989. https://doi.org/10.1227/01.neu.0000180028.64385.d3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diagnosis ETFo, Sclerosis: MoAL, Andersen PM, Abrahams S, et al. EFNS guidelines on the clinical management of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (MALS)-revised report of an EFNS task force. Eur J Neurol. 2012;19(3):360-375.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shoesmith C, Abrahao A, Benstead T, et al. Canadian best practice recommendations for the management of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. CMAJ. 2020;192(46):E1453-E1468.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zou G. A modified poisson regression approach to prospective studies with binary data. Am J Epidemiol. 2004;159(7):702-706. https://doi.org/10.1093/aje/kwh090</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNutt LA, Wu C, Xue X, Hafner JP. Estimating the relative risk in cohort studies and clinical trials of common outcomes. Am J Epidemiol. 2003;157(10):940-943. https://doi.org/10.1093/aje/kwg074</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>del Aguila MA, Longstreth WT Jr, McGuire V, Koepsell TD, van Belle G. Prognosis in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a population-based study. Neurology. 2003;60(5):813-819. https://doi.org/10.1212/01.wnl.0000049472.47709.3b</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riancho J, Lozano-Cuesta P, Santurtun A, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in northern Spain 40&#x2009;years later: what has changed? Neurodegener Dis. 2016;16(5-6):337-341. https://doi.org/10.1159/000445750</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rooney J, Heverin M, Vajda A, et al. Survival analysis of geospatial factors in the Irish ALS cohort. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2016;17(7-8):555-560. https://doi.org/10.1080/21678421.2016.1179326</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armstrong MD, Hansen G, Schellenberg KL. Rural residence and diagnostic delay for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in Saskatchewan. Can J Neurol Sci. 2020;47(4):1-5. https://doi.org/10.1017/cjn.2020.38</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quality Standards Subcommittee of the American Academy of Neurology. Practice advisory on the treatment of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with riluzole: report of the quality standards Subcommittee of the American Academy of neurology. Neurology. 1997;49(3):657-659. https://doi.org/10.1212/wnl.49.3.657</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thakore NJ, Lapin BR, Pioro EP. Stage-specific riluzole effect in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a retrospective study. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis and Frontotemporal Degeneration. 2020;21(1-2):140-143. https://doi.org/10.1080/21678421.2019.1655060</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atassi N, Berry J, Shui A, et al. The PRO-ACT database: design, initial analyses, and predictive features. Neurology. 2014;83(19):1719-1725. https://doi.org/10.1212/WNL.0000000000000951</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Traynor B, Alexander M, Corr B, Frost E, Hardiman O. Effect of a multidisciplinary amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) clinic on ALS survival: a population based study, 1996-2000. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2003;74(9):1258-1261.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benatar M, Wuu J. Presymptomatic studies in ALS: rationale, challenges, and approach. Neurology. 2012;79(16):1732-1739. https://doi.org/10.1212/WNL.0b013e31826e9b1d</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>