<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">34469619</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1742-4658</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>289</Volume><Issue>24</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The FEBS journal</Title><ISOAbbreviation>FEBS J</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Cholesterol dyshomeostasis in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: cause, consequence, or epiphenomenon?</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>7688</StartPage><EndPage>7709</EndPage><MedlinePgn>7688-7709</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/febs.16175</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS), the most common adult-onset motor neuron disease, is characterized by the selective degeneration of motor neurons leading to paralysis and eventual death. Multiple pathogenic mechanisms, including systemic dysmetabolism, have been proposed to contribute to ALS. Among them, dyslipidemia, i.e., abnormal level of cholesterol and other lipids in the circulation and central nervous system (CNS), has been reported in ALS patients, but without a consensus. Cholesterol is a constituent of cellular membranes and a precursor of steroid hormones, oxysterols, and bile acids. Consequently, optimal cholesterol levels are essential for health. Due to the blood-brain barrier (BBB), cholesterol cannot move between the CNS and the rest of the body. As such, cholesterol metabolism in the CNS is proposed to operate autonomously. Despite its importance, it remains elusive how cholesterol dyshomeostasis may contribute to ALS. In this review, we aim to describe the current state of cholesterol metabolism research in ALS, identify unresolved issues, and provide potential directions.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 Federation of European Biochemical Societies.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hartmann</LastName><ForeName>Hannelore</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology, Yong Loo Lin School of Medicine, National University of Singapore, Singapore.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ho</LastName><ForeName>Wan Yun</ForeName><Initials>WY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology, Yong Loo Lin School of Medicine, National University of Singapore, Singapore.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chang</LastName><ForeName>Jer-Cherng</ForeName><Initials>JC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology, Yong Loo Lin School of Medicine, National University of Singapore, Singapore.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ling</LastName><ForeName>Shuo-Chien</ForeName><Initials>SC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0300-8812</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology, Yong Loo Lin School of Medicine, National University of Singapore, Singapore.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Healthy Longevity Translational Research Programme, National University Health System, Singapore, Singapore.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Program in Neuroscience and Behavior Disorders, Duke-NUS Medical School, Singapore, Singapore.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013486">Research Support, U.S. Gov't, Non-P.H.S.</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>FEBS J</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101229646</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1742-464X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>97C5T2UQ7J</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D002784">Cholesterol</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009046" MajorTopicYN="N">Motor Neurons</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002490" MajorTopicYN="N">Central Nervous System</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002784" MajorTopicYN="N">Cholesterol</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001812" MajorTopicYN="N">Blood-Brain Barrier</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">TAR DNA-binding protein 43 KDa</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">apolipoprotein E</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">blood-brain barrier</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cholesterol esters</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cholesterol metabolism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">frontotemporal dementia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">low-density lipoprotein receptor</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">oxysterol</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sterol regulatory element-binding factor 2</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34469619</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/febs.16175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Kiernan MC, Vucic S, Cheah BC, Turner MR, Eisen A, Hardiman O, Burrell JR &amp; Zoing MC (2011) Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet 377, 942-955.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vieira RT, Caixeta L, Machado S, Silva AC, Nardi AE, Arias-Carrion O &amp; Carta MG (2013) Epidemiology of early-onset dementia: a review of the literature. Clin Pract Epidemiol Ment Health 9, 88-95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chio A, Logroscino G, Traynor BJ, Collins J, Simeone JC, Goldstein LA &amp; White LA (2013) Global epidemiology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a systematic review of the published literature. Neuroepidemiology 41, 118-130.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mejzini R, Flynn LL, Pitout IL, Fletcher S, Wilton SD &amp; Akkari PA (2019) ALS genetics, mechanisms, and therapeutics: where are we now? Front Neurosci 13, 1310.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Chalabi A &amp; Hardiman O (2013) The epidemiology of ALS: a conspiracy of genes, environment and time. Nat Rev Neurol 9, 617-628.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ling SC, Polymenidou M &amp; Cleveland DW (2013) Converging mechanisms in ALS and FTD: disrupted RNA and protein homeostasis. Neuron 79, 416-438.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor JP, Brown RH Jr &amp; Cleveland DW (2016) Decoding ALS: from genes to mechanism. Nature 539, 197-206.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desport JC, Preux PM, Truong CT, Courat L, Vallat JM &amp; Couratier P (2000) Nutritional assessment and survival in ALS patients. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord 1, 91-96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho WY, Chang JC, Lim K, Cazenave-Gassiot A, Nguyen AT, Foo JC, Muralidharan S, Viera-Ortiz A, Ong SJM, Hor JH et&#x2009;al. (2021) TDP-43 mediates SREBF2-regulated gene expression required for oligodendrocyte myelination. J Cell Biol 220, e201910213.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang ST, Kreutzberger AJB, Lee J, Kiessling V &amp; Tamm LK (2016) The role of cholesterol in membrane fusion. Chem Phys Lipids 199, 136-143.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bjorkhem I, Leoni V &amp; Meaney S (2010) Genetic connections between neurological disorders and cholesterol metabolism. J Lipid Res 51, 2489-2503.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Platt FM, Wassif C, Colaco A, Dardis A, Lloyd-Evans E, Bembi B &amp; Porter FD (2014) Disorders of cholesterol metabolism and their unanticipated convergent mechanisms of disease. Annu Rev Genomics Hum Genet 15, 173-194.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nelson RH (2013) Hyperlipidemia as a risk factor for cardiovascular disease. Prim Care 40, 195-211.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dietschy JM &amp; Turley SD (2004) Thematic review series: brain Lipids. Cholesterol metabolism in the central nervous system during early development and&#x2009;in the mature animal. J Lipid Res 45, 1375-1397.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orth M &amp; Bellosta S (2012) Cholesterol: its regulation and role in central nervous system disorders. Cholesterol 2012, 292598.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaylor JL (2002) Membrane-bound enzymes of cholesterol synthesis from lanosterol. Biochem Biophys Res Commun 292, 1139-1146.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeBose-Boyd RA (2008) Feedback regulation of cholesterol synthesis: sterol-accelerated ubiquitination and degradation of HMG CoA reductase. Cell Res 18, 609-621.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitsche MA, McDonald JG, Hobbs HH &amp; Cohen JC (2015) Flux analysis of cholesterol biosynthesis in&#x2009;vivo reveals multiple tissue and cell-type specific pathways. eLife 4, e07999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Genaro-Mattos TC, Anderson A, Allen LB, Korade Z &amp; Mirnics K (2019) Cholesterol biosynthesis and uptake in developing neurons. ACS Chem Neurosci 10, 3671-3681.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nieweg K, Schaller H &amp; Pfrieger FW (2009) Marked differences in cholesterol synthesis between neurons and glial cells from postnatal rats. J Neurochem 109, 125-134.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown MS, Radhakrishnan A &amp; Goldstein JL (2018)&#x2009;Retrospective on cholesterol homeostasis: the&#x2009;central role of scap. Annu Rev Biochem 87, 783-807.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yabe D, Brown MS &amp; Goldstein JL (2002) Insig-2, a second endoplasmic reticulum protein that binds SCAP and blocks export of sterol regulatory element-binding proteins. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA 99, 12753-12758.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang T, Espenshade PJ, Wright ME, Yabe D, Gong Y, Aebersold R, Goldstein JL &amp; Brown MS (2002) Crucial step in cholesterol homeostasis: sterols promote binding of SCAP to INSIG-1, a membrane protein that facilitates retention of SREBPs in ER. Cell 110, 489-500.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Engelking LJ, Cantoria MJ, Xu Y &amp; Liang G (2018) Developmental and extrahepatic physiological functions of SREBP pathway genes in mice. Semin Cell Dev Biol 81, 98-109.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Courtney R &amp; Landreth GE (2016) LXR regulation of brain cholesterol: from development to disease. Trends Endocrinol Metab 27, 404-414.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mouzat K, Chudinova A, Polge A, Kantar J, Camu W, Raoul C &amp; Lumbroso S (2019) Regulation of brain cholesterol: what role do liver X receptors play in neurodegenerative diseases? Int J Mol Sci 20, 3858.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, Zhang S, Blander G, Tse JG, Krieger M &amp; Guarente L (2007) SIRT1 deacetylates and positively regulates the nuclear receptor LXR. Mol Cell 28, 91-106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu X &amp; Lazar MA (2000) Transcriptional repression by nuclear hormone receptors. Trends Endocrinol Metab 11, 6-10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lazar MA (2003) Nuclear receptor corepressors. Nucl Recept Signal 1, e001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maqdasy S, Trousson A, Tauveron I, Volle DH, Baron S &amp; Lobaccaro JM (2016) Once and for all, LXRalpha and LXRbeta are gatekeepers of the endocrine system. Mol Aspects Med 49, 31-46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKenna NJ &amp; O&#x2019;Malley BW (2002) Minireview: nuclear receptor coactivators-an update. Endocrinology 143, 2461-2465.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang B &amp; Tontonoz P (2018) Liver X receptors in lipid signalling and membrane homeostasis. Nat Rev Endocrinol 14, 452-463.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>German JB, Smilowitz JT &amp; Zivkovic AM (2006) Lipoproteins: when size really matters. Curr Opin Colloid Interface Sci 11, 171-183.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feingold KR (2000) Introduction to lipids and lipoproteins. In Endotext (Feingold KR, Anawalt B, Boyce A, Chrousos G, de Herder WW, Dhatariya K, Dungan K, Grossman A, Hershman JM, Hofland J, Kalra S, Kaltsas G, Koch C, Kopp P, Korbonits M, Kovacs CS, Kuohung W, Laferrere B, McGee EA, McLachlan R, Morley JE, New M, Purnell J, Sahay R, Singer F, Stratakis CA, Trence DL &amp; Wilson DP, eds). South Dartmouth, MA.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pitas RE, Boyles JK, Lee SH, Hui D &amp; Weisgraber KH (1987) Lipoproteins and their receptors in the central nervous system. Characterization of the lipoproteins in cerebrospinal fluid and identification of apolipoprotein B, E(LDL) receptors in the brain. J&#x2009;Biol Chem 262, 14352-14360.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pitas RE, Boyles JK, Lee SH, Foss D &amp; Mahley RW (1987) Astrocytes synthesize apolipoprotein E and metabolize apolipoprotein E-containing lipoproteins. Biochim Biophys Acta 917, 148-161.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu Q, Bernardo A, Walker D, Kanegawa T, Mahley RW &amp; Huang Y (2006) Profile and regulation of apolipoprotein E (ApoE) expression in the CNS in mice with targeting of green fluorescent protein gene to the ApoE locus. J Neurosci 26, 4985-4994.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boschert U, Merlo-Pich E, Higgins G, Roses AD &amp; Catsicas S (1999) Apolipoprotein E expression by neurons surviving excitotoxic stress. Neurobiol Dis 6, 508-514.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zalocusky KA, Najm R, Taubes AL, Hao Y, Yoon SY, Koutsodendris N, Nelson MR, Rao A, Bennett DA, Bant J et&#x2009;al. (2021) Neuronal ApoE upregulates MHC-I expression to drive selective neurodegeneration in Alzheimer's disease. Nat Neurosci 24, 786-798.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rebeck GW, LaDu MJ, Estus S, Bu G &amp; Weeber EJ (2006) The generation and function of soluble apoE receptors in the CNS. Mol Neurodegener 1, 15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holtzman DM, Herz J &amp; Bu G (2012) Apolipoprotein E and apolipoprotein E receptors: normal biology and roles in Alzheimer disease. Cold Spring Harb Perspect Med 2, a006312.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hauser PS, Narayanaswami V &amp; Ryan RO (2011) Apolipoprotein E: from lipid transport to neurobiology. Prog Lipid Res 50, 62-74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wellington CL, Walker EK, Suarez A, Kwok A, Bissada N, Singaraja R, Yang YZ, Zhang LH, James E, Wilson JE et&#x2009;al. (2002) ABCA1 mRNA and protein distribution patterns predict multiple different roles and levels of regulation. Lab Invest 82, 273-283.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minagawa H, Gong JS, Jung CG, Watanabe A, Lund-Katz S, Phillips MC, Saito H &amp; Michikawa M (2009) Mechanism underlying apolipoprotein E (ApoE) isoform-dependent lipid efflux from neural cells in culture. J Neurosci Res 87, 2498-2508.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirsch-Reinshagen V, Zhou S, Burgess BL, Bernier L, McIsaac SA, Chan JY, Tansley GH, Cohn JS, Hayden MR &amp; Wellington CL (2004) Deficiency of ABCA1 impairs apolipoprotein E metabolism in brain. J Biol Chem 279, 41197-41207.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mauch DH, Nagler K, Schumacher S, Goritz C, Muller EC, Otto A &amp; Pfrieger FW (2001) CNS synaptogenesis promoted by glia-derived cholesterol. Science 294, 1354-1357.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schroepfer GJ Jr (2000) Oxysterols: modulators of cholesterol metabolism and other processes. Physiol Rev 80, 361-554.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gosselet F, Saint-Pol J &amp; Fenart L (2014) Effects of oxysterols on the blood-brain barrier: implications for Alzheimer's disease. Biochem Biophys Res Commun 446, 687-691.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J &amp; Liu Q (2015) Cholesterol metabolism and&#x2009;homeostasis in the brain. Protein Cell 6, 254-264.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu R, Ou Z, Ruan X &amp; Gong J (2012) Role of liver X receptors in cholesterol efflux and inflammatory signaling (review). Mol Med Rep 5, 895-900.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walther TC &amp; Farese RV Jr (2012) Lipid droplets and cellular lipid metabolism. Annu Rev Biochem 81, 687-714.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakashita N, Miyazaki A, Takeya M, Horiuchi S, Chang CC, Chang TY &amp; Takahashi K (2000) Localization of human acyl-coenzyme A: cholesterol acyltransferase-1 (ACAT-1) in macrophages and in various tissues. Am J Pathol 156, 227-236.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogers MA, Liu J, Song BL, Li BL, Chang CC &amp; Chang TY (2015) Acyl-CoA:cholesterol acyltransferases (ACATs/SOATs): enzymes with multiple sterols as substrates and as activators. J Steroid Biochem Mol Biol 151, 102-107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barber CN &amp; Raben DM (2019) Lipid metabolism crosstalk in the brain: glia and neurons. Front Cell Neurosci 13, 212.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ioannou MS, Jackson J, Sheu SH, Chang CL, Weigel AV, Liu H, Pasolli HA, Xu CS, Pang S, Matthies D et&#x2009;al. (2019) Neuron-astrocyte metabolic coupling protects against activity-induced fatty acid toxicity. Cell 177, 1522-1535 e14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar DR, Aslinia F, Yale SH &amp; Mazza JJ (2011) Jean-Martin Charcot: the father of neurology. Clin Med Res 9, 46-49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Damme P &amp; Robberecht W (2009) Recent advances in motor neuron disease. Curr Opin Neurol 22, 486-492.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Talbot K (2009) Motor neuron disease: the bare essentials. Pract Neurol 9, 303-309.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouteloup C, Desport JC, Clavelou P, Guy N, Derumeaux-Burel H, Ferrier A &amp; Couratier P (2009) Hypermetabolism in ALS patients: an early and persistent phenomenon. J Neurol 256, 1236-1242.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desport JC, Preux PM, Magy L, Boirie Y, Vallat JM, Beaufrere B &amp; Couratier P (2001) Factors correlated with hypermetabolism in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Am J Clin Nutr 74, 328-334.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jesus P, Fayemendy P, Nicol M, Lautrette G, Sourisseau H, Preux PM, Desport JC, Marin B &amp; Couratier P (2018) Hypermetabolism is a deleterious prognostic factor in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Eur J Neurol 25, 97-104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohassel P, Donkervoort S, Lone MA, Nalls M, Gable K, Gupta SD, Foley AR, Hu Y, Saute JAM, Moreira AL et&#x2009;al. (2021) Childhood amyotrophic lateral sclerosis caused by excess sphingolipid synthesis. Nat Med 27, 1197-1204.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iacoangeli A, Lin T, Al Khleifat A, Jones AR, Opie-Martin S, Coleman JRI, Shatunov A, Sproviero W, Williams KL, Garton F et&#x2009;al. (2020) Genome-wide meta-analysis finds the ACSL5-ZDHHC6 locus is associated with ALS and links weight loss to the disease genetics. Cell Rep 33, 108323.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooper-Knock J, Moll T, Ramesh T, Castelli L, Beer A, Robins H, Fox I, Niedermoser I, Van Damme P, Moisse M et&#x2009;al. (2019) Mutations in the glycosyltransferase domain of GLT8D1 are associated with familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Cell Rep 26, 2298-2306.e5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rader DJ &amp; Hovingh GK (2014) HDL and cardiovascular disease. Lancet 384, 618-625.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bandres-Ciga S, Noyce AJ, Hemani G, Nicolas A, Calvo A, Mora G, Consortium, I., International, A. L. S. G. C., Tienari PJ, Stone DJ et&#x2009;al. (2019) Shared polygenic risk and causal inferences in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol 85, 470-481.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen X, Yazdani S, Piehl F, Magnusson PKE &amp; Fang F (2018) Polygenic link between blood lipids and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurobiol Aging 67, 202 e1-202 e6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mariosa D, Hammar N, Malmstrom H, Ingre C, Jungner I, Ye W, Fang F &amp; Walldius G (2017) Blood biomarkers of carbohydrate, lipid, and apolipoprotein metabolisms and risk of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a more than 20-year follow-up of the Swedish AMORIS cohort. Ann Neurol 81, 718-728.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng P &amp; Zhou X (2019) Causal effects of blood lipids on amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a Mendelian randomization study. Hum Mol Genet 28, 688-697.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dupuis L, Corcia P, Fergani A, Gonzalez De Aguilar JL, Bonnefont-Rousselot D, Bittar R, Seilhean D, Hauw JJ, Lacomblez L, Loeffler JP et&#x2009;al. (2008) Dyslipidemia is a protective factor in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology 70, 1004-1009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delaye JB, Patin F, Piver E, Bruno C, Vasse M, Vourc'h P, Andres CR, Corcia P &amp; Blasco H (2017) Low IDL-B and high LDL-1 subfraction levels in serum of ALS patients. J Neurol Sci 380, 124-127.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ikeda K, Hirayama T, Takazawa T, Kawabe K &amp; Iwasaki Y (2012) Relationships between disease progression and serum levels of lipid, urate, creatinine and ferritin in Japanese patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a cross-sectional study. Intern Med 51, 1501-1508.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chio A, Calvo A, Ilardi A, Cavallo E, Moglia C, Mutani R, Palmo A, Galletti R, Marinou K, Papetti L et&#x2009;al. (2009) Lower serum lipid levels are related to respiratory impairment in patients with ALS. Neurology 73, 1681-1685.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim SM, Noh MY, Kim H, Cheon SY, Lee KM, Lee J, Cha E, Park KS, Lee KW, Sung JJ et&#x2009;al. (2017) 25-Hydroxycholesterol is involved in the pathogenesis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Oncotarget 8, 11855-11867.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wuolikainen A, Acimovic J, Lovgren-Sandblom A, Parini P, Andersen PM &amp; Bjorkhem I (2014) Cholesterol, oxysterol, triglyceride, and coenzyme Q homeostasis in ALS. Evidence against the hypothesis that elevated 27-hydroxycholesterol is a pathogenic factor. PLoS One 9, e113619.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdel-Khalik J, Yutuc E, Crick PJ, Gustafsson JA, Warner M, Roman G, Talbot K, Gray E, Griffiths WJ, Turner MR et&#x2009;al. (2017) Defective cholesterol metabolism in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Lipid Res 58, 267-278.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dorst J, Kuhnlein P, Hendrich C, Kassubek J, Sperfeld AD &amp; Ludolph AC (2011) Patients with elevated triglyceride and cholesterol serum levels have a prolonged survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol 258, 613-617.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sutedja NA, van der Schouw YT, Fischer K, Sizoo EM, Huisman MH, Veldink JH &amp; Van den Berg LH (2011) Beneficial vascular risk profile is associated with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 82, 638-642.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rafiq MK, Lee E, Bradburn M, McDermott CJ &amp; Shaw PJ (2015) Effect of lipid profile on prognosis in the patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Insights from the olesoxime clinical trial. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 16, 478-484.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paganoni S, Deng J, Jaffa M, Cudkowicz ME &amp; Wills AM (2011) Body mass index, not dyslipidemia, is an independent predictor of survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve 44, 20-24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ingre C, Chen L, Zhan Y, Termorshuizen J, Yin L &amp; Fang F (2020) Lipids, apolipoproteins, and prognosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology 94, e1835-e1844.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garbuzova-Davis S, Hernandez-Ontiveros DG, Rodrigues MC, Haller E, Frisina-Deyo A, Mirtyl S, Sallot S, Saporta S, Borlongan CV &amp; Sanberg PR (2012) Impaired blood-brain/spinal cord barrier in ALS patients. Brain Res 1469, 114-128.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winkler EA, Sengillo JD, Sullivan JS, Henkel JS, Appel SH &amp; Zlokovic BV (2013) Blood-spinal cord barrier breakdown and pericyte reductions in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathol 125, 111-120.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lund EG, Guileyardo JM &amp; Russell DW (1999) cDNA cloning of cholesterol 24-hydroxylase, a mediator of cholesterol homeostasis in the brain. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA 96, 7238-7243.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bjorkhem I, Lutjohann D, Diczfalusy U, Stahle L, Ahlborg G &amp; Wahren J (1998) Cholesterol homeostasis in human brain: turnover of 24S-hydroxycholesterol and evidence for a cerebral origin of most of this oxysterol in the circulation. J Lipid Res 39, 1594-1600.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lutjohann D, Breuer O, Ahlborg G, Nennesmo I, Siden A, Diczfalusy U &amp; Bjorkhem I (1996) Cholesterol homeostasis in human brain: evidence for an age-dependent flux of 24S-hydroxycholesterol from the brain into the circulation. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA 93, 9799-9804.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meaney S, Hassan M, Sakinis A, Lutjohann D, von Bergmann K, Wennmalm A, Diczfalusy U &amp; Bjorkhem I (2001) Evidence that the major oxysterols in human circulation originate from distinct pools of cholesterol: a stable isotope study. J Lipid Res 42, 70-78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meaney S, Heverin M, Panzenboeck U, Ekstrom L, Axelsson M, Andersson U, Diczfalusy U, Pikuleva I, Wahren J, Sattler W et&#x2009;al. (2007) Novel route for elimination of brain oxysterols across the blood-brain barrier: conversion into 7alpha-hydroxy-3-oxo-4-cholestenoic acid. J Lipid Res 48, 944-951.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bjorkhem I (2006) Crossing the barrier: oxysterols as cholesterol transporters and metabolic modulators in the brain. J Intern Med 260, 493-508.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bjorkhem I, Cedazo-Minguez A, Leoni V &amp; Meaney S (2009) Oxysterols and neurodegenerative diseases. Mol Aspects Med 30, 171-179.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diekstra FP, Saris CG, van Rheenen W, Franke L, Jansen RC, van Es MA, van Vught PW, Blauw HM, Groen EJ, Horvath S et&#x2009;al. (2012) Mapping of gene expression reveals CYP27A1 as a susceptibility gene for sporadic ALS. PLoS One 7, e35333.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radhakrishnan A, Ikeda Y, Kwon HJ, Brown MS &amp; Goldstein JL (2007) Sterol-regulated transport of SREBPs from endoplasmic reticulum to Golgi: oxysterols block transport by binding to Insig. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA 104, 6511-6518.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Muneton S, Sjovall J, Jovanovic JN &amp; Griffiths WJ (2008) The effect of 24S-hydroxycholesterol on cholesterol homeostasis in neurons: quantitative changes to the cortical neuron proteome. J Proteome Res 7, 1606-1614.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamanaka K, Urano Y, Takabe W, Saito Y &amp; Noguchi N (2014) Induction of apoptosis and necroptosis by 24(S)-hydroxycholesterol is dependent on activity of acyl-CoA:cholesterol acyltransferase 1. Cell Death Dis 5, e990.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dodge JC, Yu J, Sardi SP &amp; Shihabuddin LS (2021) Sterol auto-oxidation adversely affects human motor&#x2009;neuron viability and is a neuropathological feature of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Sci Rep 11, 803.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sodero AO (2020) 24S-hydroxycholesterol: cellular effects and variations in brain diseases. J Neurochem 157, 899-918.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>La Marca V, Maresca B, Spagnuolo MS, Cigliano L, Dal Piaz F, Di Iorio G &amp; Abrescia P (2016) Lecithin-cholesterol acyltransferase in brain: does oxidative stress influence the 24-hydroxycholesterol esterification? Neurosci Res 105, 19-27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cutler RG, Pedersen WA, Camandola S, Rothstein JD &amp; Mattson MP (2002) Evidence that accumulation of ceramides and cholesterol esters mediates oxidative stress-induced death of motor neurons in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol 52, 448-457.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dodge JC, Jensen EH, Yu J, Sardi SP, Bialas AR, Taksir TV, Bangari DS &amp; Shihabuddin LS (2020) Neutral lipid cacostasis contributes to disease pathogenesis in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurosci 40, 9137-9147.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaves-Filho AB, Pinto IFD, Dantas LS, Xavier AM, Inague A, Faria RL, Medeiros MHG, Glezer I, Yoshinaga MY &amp; Miyamoto S (2019) Alterations in lipid metabolism of spinal cord linked to amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Sci Rep 9, 11642.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peet DJ, Turley SD, Ma W, Janowski BA, Lobaccaro JM, Hammer RE &amp; Mangelsdorf DJ (1998) Cholesterol and bile acid metabolism are impaired in mice lacking the nuclear oxysterol receptor LXR alpha. Cell 93, 693-704.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alberti S, Schuster G, Parini P, Feltkamp D, Diczfalusy U, Rudling M, Angelin B, Bjorkhem I, Pettersson S &amp; Gustafsson JA (2001) Hepatic cholesterol metabolism and resistance to dietary cholesterol in LXRbeta-deficient mice. J Clin Invest 107, 565-573.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L, Schuster GU, Hultenby K, Zhang Q, Andersson S &amp; Gustafsson JA (2002) Liver X receptors in the central nervous system: from lipid homeostasis to neuronal degeneration. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA 99, 13878-13883.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersson S, Gustafsson N, Warner M &amp; Gustafsson JA (2005) Inactivation of liver X receptor beta leads to adult-onset motor neuron degeneration in male mice. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA 102, 3857-3862.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bigini P, Steffensen KR, Ferrario A, Diomede L, Ferrara G, Barbera S, Salzano S, Fumagalli E, Ghezzi P, Mennini T et&#x2009;al. (2010) Neuropathologic and biochemical changes during disease progression in liver X receptor beta-/- mice, a model of adult neuron disease. J Neuropathol Exp Neurol 69, 593-605.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim HJ, Fan X, Gabbi C, Yakimchuk K, Parini P, Warner M &amp; Gustafsson JA (2008) Liver X receptor beta (LXRbeta): a link between beta-sitosterol and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-Parkinson's dementia. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA 105, 2094-2099.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khabazian I, Bains JS, Williams DE, Cheung J, Wilson JM, Pasqualotto BA, Pelech SL, Andersen RJ, Wang YT, Liu L et&#x2009;al. (2002) Isolation of various forms of sterol beta-D-glucoside from the seed of Cycas circinalis: neurotoxicity and implications for ALS-parkinsonism dementia complex. J Neurochem 82, 516-528.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu Z, Lee A, Nouwens A, Henderson RD &amp; McCombe PA (2018) Mass spectrometry analysis of plasma from amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and control subjects. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 19, 362-376.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mouzat K, Molinari N, Kantar J, Polge A, Corcia P, Couratier P, Clavelou P, Juntas-Morales R, Pageot N, Lobaccaro JMA et&#x2009;al. (2018) Liver X receptor genes variants modulate ALS phenotype. Mol Neurobiol 55, 1959-1965.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun S, Sun Y, Ling SC, Ferraiuolo L, McAlonis-Downes M, Zou Y, Drenner K, Wang Y, Ditsworth D, Tokunaga S et&#x2009;al. (2015) Translational profiling identifies a cascade of damage initiated in motor neurons and spreading to glia in mutant SOD1-mediated ALS. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA 112, E6993-E7002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, Zhang J, Li D, He C, He K, Xue T, Wan L, Zhang C &amp; Liu Q (2021) Astrocytic ApoE reprograms neuronal cholesterol metabolism and histone-acetylation-mediated memory. Neuron 109, 957-970.e8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michikawa M, Fan QW, Isobe I &amp; Yanagisawa K (2000) Apolipoprotein E exhibits isoform-specific promotion of lipid efflux from astrocytes and neurons in culture. J Neurochem 74, 1008-1016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farrer LA, Cupples LA, Haines JL, Hyman B, Kukull WA, Mayeux R, Myers RH, Pericak-Vance MA, Risch N &amp; van Duijn CM (1997) Effects of age, sex, and ethnicity on the association between apolipoprotein E genotype and Alzheimer disease. A meta-analysis. APOE and Alzheimer Disease Meta Analysis Consortium. JAMA 278, 1349-1356.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanekiyo T, Xu H &amp; Bu G (2014) ApoE and Abeta in Alzheimer's disease: accidental encounters or partners? Neuron 81, 740-754.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qi G, Mi Y, Shi X, Gu H, Brinton RD &amp; Yin F (2021) ApoE4 impairs neuron-astrocyte coupling of fatty acid metabolism. Cell Rep 34, 108572.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sienski G, Narayan P, Bonner JM, Kory N, Boland S, Arczewska AA, Ralvenius WT, Akay L, Lockshin E, He L et&#x2009;al. (2021) APOE4 disrupts intracellular lipid homeostasis in human iPSC-derived glia. Sci Transl Med 13, eaaz4564.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Albani D, Pupillo E, Bianchi E, Chierchia A, Martines R, Forloni G &amp; Beghi E (2017) The role of single-nucleotide variants of the energy metabolism-linked genes SIRT3, PPARGC1A and APOE in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis risk. Genes Genet Syst 91, 301-309.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Govone F, Vacca A, Rubino E, Gai A, Boschi S, Gentile S, Orsi L, Pinessi L &amp; Rainero I (2014) Lack of association between APOE gene polymorphisms and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a comprehensive meta-analysis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 15, 551-556.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zetterberg H, Jacobsson J, Rosengren L, Blennow K &amp; Andersen PM (2008) Association of APOE with age at onset of sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Sci 273, 67-69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Praline J, Blasco H, Vourc'h P, Garrigue MA, Gordon PH, Camu W, Corcia P, Andres CR &amp; French ALSSG (2011) APOE epsilon4 allele is associated with an increased risk of bulbar-onset amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in men. Eur J Neurol 18, 1046-1052.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chio A, Brunetti M, Barberis M, Iazzolino B, Montuschi A, Ilardi A, Cammarosano S, Canosa A, Moglia C &amp; Calvo A (2016) The role of APOE in the occurrence of frontotemporal dementia in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. JAMA Neurol 73, 425-430.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jawaid A, Poon M, Strutt AM, Rice LK, McDowell EJ, Salamone AR, Qureshi SU, Simpson E, Appel SH, York MK et&#x2009;al. (2011) Does apolipoprotein E genotype modify the clinical expression of ALS? Eur J Neurol 18, 618-624.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Benedetti S, Gianazza E, Banfi C, Marocchi A, Lunetta C, Penco S, Bonomi F &amp; Iametti S (2017) Serum proteome in a sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis geographical cluster. Proteomics Clin Appl 11, 1-7. https://doi.org/10.1002/prca.201700043</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang HS, Yu L, White CC, Chibnik LB, Chhatwal JP, Sperling RA, Bennett DA, Schneider JA &amp; De Jager PL (2018) Evaluation of TDP-43 proteinopathy and hippocampal sclerosis in relation to APOE epsilon4 haplotype status: a community-based cohort study. Lancet Neurol 17, 773-781.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackenzie IR, Rademakers R &amp; Neumann M (2010) TDP-43 and FUS in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal dementia. Lancet Neurol 9, 995-1007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arai T, Hasegawa M, Akiyama H, Ikeda K, Nonaka T, Mori H, Mann D, Tsuchiya K, Yoshida M, Hashizume Y et&#x2009;al. (2006) TDP-43 is a component of ubiquitin-positive tau-negative inclusions in frontotemporal lobar degeneration and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Biochem Biophys Res Commun 351, 602-611.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan RH, Yang Y, Kim WS, Dobson-Stone C, Kwok JB, Kiernan MC &amp; Halliday GM (2017) Distinct TDP-43 inclusion morphologies in frontotemporal lobar degeneration with and without amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathol Commun 5, 76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sreedharan J, Blair IP, Tripathi VB, Hu X, Vance C, Rogelj B, Ackerley S, Durnall JC, Williams KL, Buratti E et&#x2009;al. (2008) TDP-43 mutations in familial and sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Science 319, 1668-1672.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rutherford NJ, Zhang YJ, Baker M, Gass JM, Finch NA, Xu YF, Stewart H, Kelley BJ, Kuntz K, Crook RJ et&#x2009;al. (2008) Novel mutations in TARDBP (TDP-43) in patients with familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. PLoS Genet 4, e1000193.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gitcho MA, Baloh RH, Chakraverty S, Mayo K, Norton JB, Levitch D, Hatanpaa KJ, White CL 3rd, Bigio EH, Caselli R et&#x2009;al. (2008) TDP-43 A315T mutation in familial motor neuron disease. Ann Neurol 63, 535-538.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morris LL, Hartman IZ, Jun DJ, Seemann J &amp; DeBose-Boyd RA (2014) Sequential actions of the AAA-ATPase valosin-containing protein (VCP)/p97 and the proteasome 19 S regulatory particle in sterol-accelerated, endoplasmic reticulum (ER)-associated degradation of 3-hydroxy-3-methylglutaryl-coenzyme A reductase. J Biol Chem 289, 19053-19066.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu CY, Theusch E, Lo K, Mangravite LM, Naidoo D, Kutilova M &amp; Medina MW (2014) HNRNPA1 regulates HMGCR alternative splicing and modulates cellular cholesterol metabolism. Hum Mol Genet 23, 319-332.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guzman KM, Brink LE, Rodriguez-Bey G, Bodnar RJ, Kuang L, Xing B, Sullivan M, Park HJ, Koppes E, Zhu H et&#x2009;al. (2020) Conditional depletion of Fus in oligodendrocytes leads to motor hyperactivity and increased myelin deposition associated with Akt and cholesterol activation. Glia 68, 2040-2056.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lastres-Becker I, Brodesser S, Lutjohann D, Azizov M, Buchmann J, Hintermann E, Sandhoff K, Schurmann A, Nowock J &amp; Auburger G (2008) Insulin receptor and lipid metabolism pathology in ataxin-2 knock-out mice. Hum Mol Genet 17, 1465-1481.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canet-Pons J, Sen NE, Arsovic A, Almaguer-Mederos LE, Halbach MV, Key J, Doring C, Kerksiek A, Picchiarelli G, Cassel R et&#x2009;al. (2021) Atxn2-CAG100-KnockIn mouse spinal cord shows progressive TDP43 pathology associated with cholesterol biosynthesis suppression. Neurobiol Dis 152, 105289.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin MG, Pfrieger F &amp; Dotti CG (2014) Cholesterol in brain disease: sometimes determinant and frequently implicated. EMBO Rep 15, 1036-1052.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>