<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">34486134</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>18</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-4598</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>64</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Muscle &amp; nerve</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Muscle Nerve</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Alterations in fast-twitch muscle membrane conductance regulation do not explain decreased muscle function of SOD1<sup>G93A</sup> rats.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>755</StartPage><EndPage>764</EndPage><MedlinePgn>755-764</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/mus.27413</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION/AIMS">Both neuromuscular junction (NMJ) dysfunction and altered electrophysiological properties of muscle fibers have been reported in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) patients. ALS-related preclinical studies typically use rodent SOD1<sup>G93A</sup> overexpression models, but translation to the human disease has been challenged. The present work explored NMJ function and cellular electrophysiological properties of muscles fibers in SOD1<sup>G93A</sup> overexpression rats.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Longitudinal studies of compound muscle action potentials (CMAPs) were performed in SOD1<sup>G93A</sup> rats. Cellular studies were performed to evaluate electrophysiological properties of muscle fibers, including the resting membrane conductance (G<sub>m</sub> ) and its regulation during prolonged action potential (AP) firing.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">SOD1<sup>G93A</sup> rats showed a substantial loss of gastrocnemius CMAP amplitude (35.8&#x2009;mV, P&#xa0;&lt;&#x2009;.001) and a minor increase in CMAP decrement (8.5%, P&#xa0;=&#x2009;.002) at 25&#x2009;weeks. In addition, SOD1<sup>G93A</sup> EDL muscle fibers showed a lower baseline G<sub>m</sub> (wild-type, 1325&#x2009;&#x3bc;S/cm<sup>2</sup> ; SOD1<sup>G93A</sup> , 1137&#x2009;&#x3bc;S/cm<sup>2</sup> ; P&#xa0;&lt;&#x2009;.001) and minor alterations in G<sub>m</sub> regulation during repeated firing of APs as compared with wild-type rats.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION">The current data suggest that loss of CMAP amplitude is largely explained by defects in either lower motor neuron or skeletal muscle with only minor indications of a role for neuromuscular transmission defects in SOD1<sup>G93A</sup> rats. Electrophysiological properties of muscle fibers were not markedly affected, and an elevated G<sub>m</sub> , as has been reported in motor neuron disease (MND) patients, was not replicated in SOD1<sup>G93A</sup> muscles. Collectively, the neuromuscular pathology of SOD1<sup>G93A</sup> rats appears to differ from that of ALS/MND patients with respect to neuromuscular transmission defects and electrophysiological properties of muscle fibers.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Leermakers</LastName><ForeName>Pieter A</ForeName><Initials>PA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0145-742X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedicine, Aarhus University, Aarhus, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Skov</LastName><ForeName>Martin</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedicine, Aarhus University, Aarhus, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Riisager</LastName><ForeName>Anders</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedicine, Aarhus University, Aarhus, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nielsen</LastName><ForeName>Ole B</ForeName><Initials>OB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedicine, Aarhus University, Aarhus, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pedersen</LastName><ForeName>Thomas H</ForeName><Initials>TH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedicine, Aarhus University, Aarhus, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Muscle Nerve</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7803146</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0148-639X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C000606290">SOD1 protein, human</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 1.15.1.1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C000606292">Sod1 protein, rat</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 1.15.1.1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000072105">Superoxide Dismutase-1</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004195" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Models, Animal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009046" MajorTopicYN="N">Motor Neurons</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051381" MajorTopicYN="N">Rats</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000072105" MajorTopicYN="Y">Superoxide Dismutase-1</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">excitability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">excitation-contraction coupling</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">membrane conductance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neuromuscular transmission</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34486134</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.27413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Loeffler JP, Picchiarelli G, Dupuis L, Gonzalez De Aguilar JL. The role of skeletal muscle in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain Pathol. 2016;26:227-236.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calderon JC, Bolanos P, Caputo C. The excitation-contraction coupling mechanism in skeletal muscle. Biophys Rev. 2014;6:133-160.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gruener R, Stern LZ, Markovitz D, Gerdes C. Electrophysiologic properties of intercostal muscle fibers in human neuromuscular diseases. Muscle Nerve. 1979;2:165-172.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Killian JM, Wilfong AA, Burnett L, Appel SH, Boland D. Decremental motor responses to repetitive nerve stimulation in ALS. Muscle Nerve. 1994;17:747-754.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mulder DW, Lambert EH, Eaton LM. Myasthenic syndrome in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology. 1959;9:627-631.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang FC, De Pasqua V, Gerard P, Delwaide PJ. Prognostic value of decremental responses to repetitive nerve stimulation in ALS patients. Neurology. 2001;57:897-899.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iwanami T, Sonoo M, Hatanaka Y, Hokkoku K, Oishi C, Shimizu T. Decremental responses to repetitive nerve stimulation (RNS) in motor neuron disease. Clin Neurophysiol. 2011;122:2530-2536.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun XS, Liu WX, Chen ZH, et al. Repetitive nerve stimulation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Chin Med J (Engl). 2018;131:2146-2151.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pera MC, Luigetti M, Pane M, et al. 6MWT can identify type 3 SMA patients with neuromuscular junction dysfunction. Neuromuscul Disord. 2017;27:879-882.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moloney EB, de Winter F, Verhaagen J. ALS as a distal axonopathy: molecular mechanisms affecting neuromuscular junction stability in the presymptomatic stages of the disease. Front Neurosci. 2014;8:252.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner BJ, Talbot K. Transgenics, toxicity and therapeutics in rodent models of mutant SOD1-mediated familial ALS. Prog Neurobiol. 2008;85:94-134.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong M, Martin LJ. Skeletal muscle-restricted expression of human SOD1 causes motor neuron degeneration in transgenic mice. Hum Mol Genet. 2010;19:2284-2302.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dobrowolny G, Aucello M, Rizzuto E, et al. Skeletal muscle is a primary target of SOD1G93A-mediated toxicity. Cell Metab. 2008;8:425-436.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dobrowolny G, Martini M, Scicchitano BM, et al. Muscle expression of SOD1(G93A) triggers the dismantlement of neuromuscular junction via PKC-theta. Antioxid Redox Signal. 2018;28:1105-1119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wier CG, Crum AE, Reynolds AB, et al. Muscle contractility dysfunction precedes loss of motor unit connectivity in SOD1(G93A) mice. Muscle Nerve. 2019;59:254-262.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palade PT, Barchi RL. Characteristics of the chloride conductance in muscle fibers of the rat diaphragm. J Gen Physiol. 1977;69:325-342.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwiecinski H, Lehmann-Horn F, Rudel R. The resting membrane parameters of human intercostal muscle at low, normal, and high extracellular potassium. Muscle Nerve. 1984;7:60-65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bryant SH, Morales-Aguilera A. Chloride conductance in normal and myotonic muscle fibres and the action of monocarboxylic aromatic acids. J Physiol. 1971;219:367-383.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rudel R, Senges J. Mammalian skeletal muscle: reduced chloride conductance in drug-induced myotonia and induction of myotonia by low-chloride solution. Naunyn Schmiedebergs Arch Pharmacol. 1972;274:337-347.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hutter OF, Noble D. The chloride conductance of frog skeletal muscle. J Physiol. 1960;151:89-102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedersen TH, de Paoli FV, Flatman JA, Nielsen OB. Regulation of ClC-1 and KATP channels in action potential-firing fast-twitch muscle fibers. J Gen Physiol. 2009;134:309-322.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riisager A, de Paoli FV, Yu WP, Pedersen TH, Chen TY, Nielsen OB. Protein kinase C-dependent regulation of ClC-1 channels in active human muscle and its effect on fast and slow gating. J Physiol. 2016;594:3391-3406.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedersen TH, Macdonald WA, de Paoli FV, Gurung IS, Nielsen OB. Comparison of regulated passive membrane conductance in action potential-firing fast- and slow-twitch muscle. J Gen Physiol. 2009;134:323-337.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leermakers PA, Dybdahl KLT, Husted KS, et al. Depletion of ATP limits membrane excitability of skeletal muscle by increasing both ClC1-open probability and membrane conductance. Front Neurol. 2020;11:541.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Camerino GM, Fonzino A, Conte E, et al. Elucidating the contribution of skeletal muscle ion channels to amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in search of new therapeutic options. Sci Rep. 2019;9:3185.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howland DS, Liu J, She Y, et al. Focal loss of the glutamate transporter EAAT2 in a transgenic rat model of SOD1 mutant-mediated amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2002;99:1604-1609.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith IC, Gittings W, Huang J, et al. Potentiation in mouse lumbrical muscle without myosin light chain phosphorylation: is resting calcium responsible? J Gen Physiol. 2013;141:297-308.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edstrom L, Hultman E, Sahlin K, Sjoholm H. The contents of high-energy phosphates in different fibre types in skeletal muscles from rat, guinea-pig and man. J Physiol. 1982;332:47-58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banas K, Clow C, Jasmin BJ, Renaud JM. The KATP channel Kir6.2 subunit content is higher in glycolytic than oxidative skeletal muscle fibers. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol. 2011;301:R916-R925.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riisager A, Duehmke R, Nielsen OB, Huang CL, Pedersen TH. Determination of cable parameters in skeletal muscle fibres during repetitive firing of action potentials. J Physiol. 2014;592:4417-4429.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harrigan ME, Filous AR, Tosolini AP, Morris R, Schwab JM, Arnold WD. Assessing rat forelimb and hindlimb motor unit connectivity as objective and robust biomarkers of spinal motor neuron function. Sci Rep. 2019;9:16699.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao K, Shen C, Li L, et al. Sarcoglycan alpha mitigates neuromuscular junction decline in aged mice by stabilizing LRP4. J Neurosci. 2018;38:8860-8873.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsumoto A, Okada Y, Nakamichi M, et al. Disease progression of human SOD1 (G93A) transgenic ALS model rats. J Neurosci Res. 2006;83:119-133.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>