<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">34510584</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>01</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1460-9568</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>54</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The European journal of neuroscience</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Neurosci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Dysfunction of oligodendrocyte inwardly rectifying potassium channel in a rat model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>6339</StartPage><EndPage>6354</EndPage><MedlinePgn>6339-6354</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/ejn.15451</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) is a fatal neurodegenerative disease caused by the death of motor neurons in the spinal cord and the brain. Although this disease is characterized by motoneuron degeneration, non-neuronal cells such as oligodendrocytes play an important role in the disease onset and progression. The aim of our study was to examine functional properties of oligodendrocytes in the SOD1<sup>G93A</sup> rat model of ALS with a particular focus on the inwardly rectifying potassium channel Kir4.1 that is abundantly expressed in these glial cells and plays a role in the regulation of extracellular K<sup>+</sup> . First, we demonstrate that the expression of Kir4.1 is diminished in the spinal cord oligodendrocytes of the SOD1<sup>G93A</sup> rat. Moreover, our data show an elevated number of dysmorphic oligodendrocytes in the ALS spinal cord that is indicative of a degenerative phenotype. In order to assess physiological properties of oligodendrocytes, we prepared cell cultures from the rat spinal cord. Oligodendrocytes isolated from the SOD1<sup>G93A</sup> spinal cord display similar ramification of the processes as the control but express a lower level of Kir4.1. We further demonstrate an impairment of oligodendrocyte functional properties in ALS. Remarkably, whole-cell patch-clamp recordings revealed compromised membrane biophysical properties and diminished inward currents in the SOD1<sup>G93A</sup> oligodendrocytes. In addition, the Ba<sup>2+</sup> -sensitive Kir currents were decreased in ALS oligodendrocytes. Altogether, our findings provide the evidence of impaired Kir4.1 expression and function in oligodendrocytes of the SOD1<sup>G93A</sup> spinal cord, suggesting oligodendrocyte Kir4.1 channel as a potential contributor to the ALS pathophysiology.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 Federation of European Neuroscience Societies and John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Peric</LastName><ForeName>Mina</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Physiology and Biochemistry "Ivan Djaja", Faculty of Biology, University of Belgrade, Belgrade, Serbia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nikolic</LastName><ForeName>Ljiljana</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurophysiology, Institute for Biological Research "Sini&#x161;a Stankovi&#x107;", National Institute of Republic of Serbia, University of Belgrade, Belgrade, Serbia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Andjus</LastName><ForeName>Pavle R</ForeName><Initials>PR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Physiology and Biochemistry "Ivan Djaja", Faculty of Biology, University of Belgrade, Belgrade, Serbia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bataveljic</LastName><ForeName>Danijela</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9593-8231</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Physiology and Biochemistry "Ivan Djaja", Faculty of Biology, University of Belgrade, Belgrade, Serbia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>France</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Neurosci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8918110</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0953-816X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C489455">Kcnj10 (channel)</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D024661">Potassium Channels, Inwardly Rectifying</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004195" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Models, Animal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051379" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008822" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice, Transgenic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009046" MajorTopicYN="N">Motor Neurons</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019636" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neurodegenerative Diseases</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009836" MajorTopicYN="N">Oligodendroglia</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D024661" MajorTopicYN="Y">Potassium Channels, Inwardly Rectifying</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051381" MajorTopicYN="N">Rats</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013116" MajorTopicYN="N">Spinal Cord</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ALS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Kir4.1</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">electrophysiology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neurodegeneration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">potassium channel</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34510584</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ejn.15451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Andersen, P. M. (2006). Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis associated with mutations in the CuZn superoxide dismutase gene. Current Neurology and Neuroscience Reports, 6, 37-46. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11910-996-0008-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batavelji&#x107;, D., Nikoli&#x107;, L., Milosevi&#x107;, M., Todorovi&#x107;, N., &amp; Andjus, P. R. (2012). Changes in the astrocytic aquaporin-4 and inwardly rectifying potassium channel expression in the brain of the amyotrophic lateral sclerosis SOD1 G93A rat model. Glia, 60, 1991-2003. https://doi.org/10.1002/glia.22414</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blokhuis, A. M., Groen, E. J. N., Koppers, M., van den Berg, L. H., &amp; Pasterkamp, R. J. (2013). Protein aggregation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathologica, 125, 777-794. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00401-013-1125-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boillee, S., Yamanaka, K., Lobsiger, C. S., Copeland, N. G., Jenkins, N. A., Kassiotis, G., Kollias, G., &amp; Cleveland, D. W. (2006). Onset and progression in inherited ALS determined by motor neurons and microglia. Science (80-.), 312, 1389-1392.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bolte, S., &amp; Cordeli&#xe9;res, F. P. (2006). A guided tour into subcellular colocalization analysis in light microscopy. Journal of Microscopy, 224, 213-232. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2818.2006.01706.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bordt, E. A., Block, C. L., Petrozziello, T., Sadri-Vakili, G., Smith, C. J., Edlow, A. G., &amp; Bilbo, S. D. (2020). Isolation of microglia from mouse or human tissue. STAR Protocols., 1, 100035. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.xpro.2020.100035</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brasko, C., Hawkins, V., De La Rocha, I. C., &amp; Butt, A. M. (2017). Expression of Kir4.1 and Kir5.1 inwardly rectifying potassium channels in oligodendrocytes, the myelinating cells of the CNS. Brain Structure and Function, 222(1), 41-59. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00429-016-1199-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Biase, L. M., Nishiyama, A., &amp; Bergles, D. E. (2010). Excitability and synaptic communication within the oligodendrocyte lineage. The Journal of Neuroscience, 30, 3600-3611. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.6000-09.2010</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Domingues, H. S., Portugal, C. C., Socodato, R., &amp; Relvas, J. B. (2016). Oligodendrocyte, astrocyte, and microglia crosstalk in myelin development, damage, and repair. Frontiers in Cell and Development Biology, 4, 71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferraiuolo, L., Higginbottom, A., Heath, P. R., Barber, S., Greenald, D., Kirby, J., &amp; Shaw, P. J. (2011). Dysregulation of astrocyte-motoneuron cross-talk in mutant superoxide dismutase 1-related amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain, 134, 2627-2641. https://doi.org/10.1093/brain/awr193</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferraiuolo, L., Meyer, K., Sherwood, T. W., Vick, J., Likhite, S., Frakes, A., Miranda, C. J., Braun, L., Heath, P. R., Pineda, R., Beattie, C. E., Shaw, P. J., Askwith, C. C., McTigue, D., &amp; Kaspar, B. K. (2016). Oligodendrocytes contribute to motor neuron death in ALS via SOD1-dependent mechanism. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, 113, E6496-E6505. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1607496113</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filipi, T., Hermanova, Z., Tureckova, J., Vanatko, O., &amp; Anderova, M. (2020). Glial cells-The strategic targets in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis treatment. Journal of Clinical Medicine, 9, 261. https://doi.org/10.3390/jcm9010261</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F&#xfc;nfschilling, U., Supplie, L. M., Mahad, D., Boretius, S., Saab, A. S., Edgar, J., Brinkmann, B. G., Kassmann, C. M., Tzvetanova, I. D., M&#xf6;bius, W., Diaz, F., Meijer, D., Suter, U., Hamprecht, B., Sereda, M. W., Moraes, C. T., Frahm, J., Goebbels, S., &amp; Nave, K.-A. (2012). Glycolytic oligodendrocytes maintain myelin and long-term axonal integrity. Nature, 485, 517-521. https://doi.org/10.1038/nature11007</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gipson, K., &amp; Bordey, A. (2002). Analysis of the K+ current profile of mature rat oligodendrocytes in situ. The Journal of Membrane Biology, 189, 201-212. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00232-002-1014-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gleichman, A. J., &amp; Carmichael, S. T. (2020). Glia in neurodegeneration: Drivers of disease or along for the ride? Neurobiology of Disease, 142, 104957. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nbd.2020.104957</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howland, D. S., Liu, J., She, Y., Goad, B., Maragakis, N. J., Kim, B., Erickson, J., Kulik, J., DeVito, L., Psaltis, G., DeGennaro, L. J., Cleveland, D. W., &amp; Rothstein, J. D. (2002). Focal loss of the glutamate transporter EAAT2 in a transgenic rat model of SOD1 mutant-mediated amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, 99, 1604-1609. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.032539299</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ilieva, H., Polymenidou, M., &amp; Cleveland, D. W. (2009). Non-cell autonomous toxicity in neurodegenerative disorders: ALS and beyond. The Journal of Cell Biology, 187, 761-772. https://doi.org/10.1083/jcb.200908164</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaiser, M., Maletzki, I., H&#xfc;lsmann, S., Holtmann, B., Schulz-Schaeffer, W., Kirchhoff, F., B&#xe4;hr, M., &amp; Neusch, C. (2006). Progressive loss of a glial potassium channel (KCNJ10) in the spinal cord of the SOD1 (G93A) transgenic mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Journal of Neurochemistry, 99, 900-912. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1471-4159.2006.04131.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang, S. H., Fukaya, M., Yang, J. K., Rothstein, J. D., &amp; Bergles, D. E. (2010). NG2+ CNS glial progenitors remain committed to the oligodendrocyte lineage in postnatal life and following Neurodegeneration. Neuron, 68, 668-681. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2010.09.009</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang, S. H., Li, Y., Fukaya, M., Lorenzini, I., Cleveland, D. W., Ostrow, L. W., Rothstein, J. D., &amp; Bergles, D. E. (2013). Degeneration and impaired regeneration of gray matter oligodendrocytes in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nature Neuroscience, 16, 571-579. https://doi.org/10.1038/nn.3357</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, G., Gautier, O., Tassoni-Tsuchida, E., Ma, X. R., &amp; Gitler, A. D. (2020). ALS genetics: Gains, losses, and implications for future therapies. Neuron, 108, 822-842. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2020.08.022</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, S., Chung, A., Na, J. E., Lee, S. J., Jeong, S. H., Kim, E., Sun, W., Rhyu, I. J., &amp; Park, H. (2019). Myelin degeneration induced by mutant superoxide dismutase 1 accumulation promotes amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Glia, 67, 1910-1921. https://doi.org/10.1002/glia.23669</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knapp, P. E., Skoff, R. P., &amp; Sprinkle, T. J. (1988). Differential expression of galactocerebroside, myelin basic protein, and 2&#x2032;,3&#x2032;-cyclic nucleotide 3&#x2032;-phosphohydrolase during development of oligodendrocytes in vitro. Journal of Neuroscience Research, 21, 249-259. https://doi.org/10.1002/jnr.490210217</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larson, V. A., Mironova, Y., Vanderpool, K. G., Waisman, A., Rash, J. E., Agarwal, A., &amp; Bergles, D. E. (2018). Oligodendrocytes control potassium accumulation in white matter and seizure susceptibility. eLife, 7, e34829. https://doi.org/10.7554/eLife.34829</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lassmann, H., van Horssen, J., &amp; Mahad, D. (2012). Progressive multiple sclerosis: Pathology and pathogenesis. Nature Reviews. Neurology, 8, 647-656. https://doi.org/10.1038/nrneurol.2012.168</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, J., Hyeon, S. J., Im, H., Ryu, H., Kim, Y., &amp; Ryu, H. (2016). Astrocytes and microglia as non-cell autonomous players in the pathogenesis of ALS. Experimental Neurobiology, 25, 233-240. https://doi.org/10.5607/en.2016.25.5.233</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, Y., Morrison, B. M., Li, Y., Lengacher, S., Farah, M. H., Hoffman, P. N., Liu, Y., Tsingalia, A., Jin, L., Zhang, P.-W., Pellerin, L., Magistretti, P. J., &amp; Rothstein, J. D. (2012). Oligodendroglia metabolically support axons and contribute to neurodegeneration. Nature, 487, 443-448. https://doi.org/10.1038/nature11314</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liddelow, S. A., &amp; Barres, B. A. (2017). Reactive astrocytes: Production, function, and therapeutic potential. Immunity, 46, 957-967. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.immuni.2017.06.006</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Livesey, M. R., Magnani, D., Cleary, E. M., Vasistha, N. A., James, O. T., Selvaraj, B. T., Burr, K., Story, D., Shaw, C. E., Kind, P. C., Hardingham, G. E., Wyllie, D. J. A., &amp; Chandran, S. (2016). Maturation and electrophysiological properties of human pluripotent stem cell-derived oligodendrocytes. Stem Cells, 34, 1040-1053. https://doi.org/10.1002/stem.2273</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lobsiger, C. S., &amp; Cleveland, D. W. (2007). Glial cells as intrinsic components of non-cell-autonomous neurodegenerative disease. Nature Neuroscience, 10, 1355-1360. https://doi.org/10.1038/nn1988</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lorente Pons, A., Higginbottom, A., Cooper-Knock, J., Alrafiah, A., Alofi, E., Kirby, J., Shaw, P. J., Wood, J. D., &amp; Highley, J. R. (2020). Oligodendrocyte pathology exceeds axonal pathology in white matter in human amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. The Journal of Pathology, 251, 262-271. https://doi.org/10.1002/path.5455</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu, Y., Tang, C., Zhu, L., Li, J., Liang, H., Zhang, J., &amp; Xu, R. (2016). The overexpression of TDP-43 protein in the neuron and oligodendrocyte cells causes the progressive motor neuron degeneration in the SOD1 G93A transgenic mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. International Journal of Biological Sciences, 12, 1140-1149. https://doi.org/10.7150/ijbs.15938</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marignier, R., Nicolle, A., Watrin, C., Touret, M., Cavagna, S., Varrin-Doyer, M., Cavillon, G., Rogemond, V., Confavreux, C., Honnorat, J., &amp; Giraudon, P. (2010). Oligodendrocytes are damaged by neuromyelitis optica immunoglobulin G via astrocyte injury. Brain, 133, 2578-2591. https://doi.org/10.1093/brain/awq177</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Min, R., &amp; van der Knaap, M. S. (2018). Genetic defects disrupting glial ion and water homeostasis in the brain. Brain Pathology, 28, 372-387. https://doi.org/10.1111/bpa.12602</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakajima, M., Kawamura, T., Tokui, R., Furuta, K., Sugino, M., Nakanishi, M., Okuyama, S., &amp; Furukawa, Y. (2013). Enhanced accumulation of Kir4.1 protein, but not mRNA, in a murine model of cuprizone-induced demyelination. Brain Research, 1537, 340-349.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nave, K.-A. (2010). Myelination and support of axonal integrity by glia. Nature, 468, 244-252. https://doi.org/10.1038/nature09614</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neusch, C., Rozengurt, N., Jacobs, R. E., Lester, H. A., &amp; Kofuji, P. (2001). Kir4.1 Potassium Channel subunit is crucial for oligodendrocyte development and in vivo myelination. The Journal of Neuroscience, 21, 5429-5438. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.21-15-05429.2001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nonneman, A., Robberecht, W., Den, B., &amp; Van, L. (2014). The role of oligodendroglial dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurodegenerative Disease Management, 4, 223-239. https://doi.org/10.2217/nmt.14.21</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nwaobi, S. E., Cuddapah, V. A., Patterson, K. C., Randolph, A. C., &amp; Olsen, M. L. (2016). The role of glial-specific Kir4.1 in normal and pathological states of the CNS. Acta Neuropathologica, 132, 1-21. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00401-016-1553-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olsen, M. L., Campbell, S. L., &amp; Sontheimer, H. (2007). Differential distribution of Kir4.1 in spinal cord astrocytes suggests regional differences in K+ homeostasis. Journal of Neurophysiology, 98, 786-793. https://doi.org/10.1152/jn.00340.2007</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peferoen, L., Kipp, M., van der Valk, P., van Noort, J. M., &amp; Amor, S. (2014). Oligodendrocyte-microglia cross-talk in the central nervous system. Immunology, 141, 302-313. https://doi.org/10.1111/imm.12163</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peters, O. M., Ghasemi, M., &amp; Brown, R. H. Jr. (2015). Emerging mechanisms of molecular pathology in ALS. The Journal of Clinical Investigation, 125, 1767-1779. https://doi.org/10.1172/JCI71601</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Philips, T., Bento-Abreu, A., Nonneman, A., Haeck, W., Staats, K., Geelen, V., Hersmus, N., K&#xfc;sters, B., Van Den Bosch, L., Van Damme, P., Richardson, W. D., &amp; Robberecht, W. (2013). Oligodendrocyte dysfunction in the pathogenesis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain, 136, 471-482. https://doi.org/10.1093/brain/aws339</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Philips, T., &amp; Rothstein, J. D. (2014). Glial cells in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Experimental Neurology, 262, 111-120. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.expneurol.2014.05.015</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poopalasundaram, S., Knott, C., Shamotienko, O. G., Foran, P. G., Dolly, J. O., Ghiani, C. A., Gallo, V., &amp; Wilkin, G. P. (2000). Glial heterogeneity in expression of the inwardly rectifying K+ channel, Kir4.1, in adult rat CNS. Glia, 30, 362-372. https://doi.org/10.1002/(SICI)1098-1136(200006)30:4%3C362::AID-GLIA50%3E3.0.CO;2-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puentes, F., Malaspina, A., van Noort, J. M., &amp; Amor, S. (2016). Non-neuronal cells in ALS: Role of glial, immune cells and blood-CNS barriers. Brain Pathology, 26, 248-257. https://doi.org/10.1111/bpa.12352</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ransom, C. B., &amp; Sontheimer, H. (1995). Biophysical and pharmacological characterization of inwardly rectifying K+ currents in rat spinal cord astrocytes. Journal of Neurophysiology, 73, 333-346. https://doi.org/10.1152/jn.1995.73.1.333</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reich, D. S., Lucchinetti, C. F., &amp; Calabresi, P. A. (2018). Multiple sclerosis. The New England Journal of Medicine, 378, 169-180. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJMra1401483</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosen, D. R., Siddique, T., Patterson, D, Figlewicz, D. A., Sapp, P., Hentati, A., Donaldson, D., Goto, J., O&#x2019;Regan, J. P., Deng, H. X., Rahmani, Z., Krizus, A., McKenna-Yasek, D., Cayabyab, A., Gaston, S. M., Berger, R., Tanzi, R. E., Halperin, J. J., Herzfeldt, B., &#x2026; Brown, R. H. (1993). Mutations in Cu/Zn superoxide dismutase gene are associated with familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nature, 362, 59-62. https://doi.org/10.1038/362059a0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saab, A. S., Tzvetanova, I. D., &amp; Nave, K.-A. (2013). The role of myelin and oligodendrocytes in axonal energy metabolism. Current Opinion in Neurobiology, 23, 1065-1072. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.conb.2013.09.008</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saab, A. S., Tzvetavona, I. D., Trevisiol, A., Baltan, S., Dibaj, P., Kusch, K., M&#xf6;bius, W., Goetze, B., Jahn, H. M., Huang, W., Steffens, H., Schomburg, E. D., P&#xe9;rez-Samart&#xed;n, A., P&#xe9;rez-Cerd&#xe1;, F., Bakhtiari, D., Matute, C., L&#xf6;wel, S., Griesinger, C., Hirrlinger, J., &#x2026; Nave, K.-A. (2016). Oligodendroglial NMDA receptors regulate glucose import and axonal energy metabolism. Neuron, 91, 119-132. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2016.05.016</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saberi, S., Stauffer, J. E., Schulte, D. J., &amp; Ravits, J. (2015). Neuropathology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and its variants. Neurologic Clinics, 33, 855-876. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ncl.2015.07.012</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scekic-Zahirovic, J., el Oussini, H., Mersmann, S., Drenner, K., Wagner, M., Sun, Y., Allmeroth, K., Dieterl&#xe9;, S., Sinniger, J., Dirrig-Grosch, S., Ren&#xe9;, F., Dormann, D., Haass, C., Ludolph, A. C., Lagier-Tourenne, C., Storkebaum, E., &amp; Dupuis, L. (2017). Motor neuron intrinsic and extrinsic mechanisms contribute to the pathogenesis of FUS-associated amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathologica, 133, 887-906. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00401-017-1687-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schirmer, L., M&#xf6;bius, W., Zhao, C., Cruz-Herranz, A., Ben Haim, L., Cordano, C., Shiow, L. R., Kelley, K. W., Sadowski, B., Timmons, G., Pr&#xf6;bstel, A.-K., Wright, J. N., Sin, J. H., Devereux, M., Morrison, D. E., Chang, S. M., Sabeur, K., Green, A. J., Nave, K.-A., &#x2026; Rowitch, D. H. (2018). Oligodendrocyte-encoded Kir4.1 function is required for axonal integrity. Elife, 7, e36428. https://doi.org/10.7554/eLife.36428.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schulz, K., Vulpe, C. D., Harris, L. Z., &amp; David, S. (2011). Iron efflux from oligodendrocytes is differentially regulated in gray and white matter. The Journal of Neuroscience, 31, 13301-13311. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.2838-11.2011</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song, F., Hong, X., Cao, J., Ma, G., Han, Y., Cepeda, C., Kang, Z., Xu, T., Duan, S., Wan, J., &amp; Tong, X. (2018). Kir4.1 channels in NG2-glia play a role in development, potassium signaling, and ischemia-related myelin loss. Commun. Biol., 1, 80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sontheimer, H., &amp; Kettenmann, H. (1988). Heterogeneity of potassium currents in cultured oligodendrocytes. Glia, 1, 415-420. https://doi.org/10.1002/glia.440010609</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sontheimer, H., Trotter, J., Schachner, M., &amp; Kettenmann, H. (1989). Channel expression correlates with differentiation stage during the development of Oligodendrocytes from their precursor cells in culture. Neuron, 2, 1135-1145. https://doi.org/10.1016/0896-6273(89)90180-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Srivastava, R., Aslam, M., Kalluri, S. R., Schirmer, L., Buck, D., Tackenberg, B., Rothhammer, V., Chan, A., Gold, R., Berthele, A., Bennett, J. L., Korn, T., &amp; Hemmer, B. (2012). Potassium channel KIR4.1 as an immune target in multiple sclerosis. The New England Journal of Medicine, 367, 115-123. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJMoa1110740</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stieber, A., Gonatas, J. O., &amp; Gonatas, N. K. (2000). Aggregates of mutant protein appear progressively in dendrites, in periaxonal processes of oligodendrocytes, and in neuronal and astrocytic perikarya of mice expressing the SOD1G93A mutation of familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Journal of the Neurological Sciences, 177, 114-123. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0022-510X(00)00351-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun, S., Sun, Y., Ling, S.-C., Ferraiuolo, L., McAlonis-Downes, M., Zou, Y., Drenner, K., Wang, Y., Ditsworth, D., Tokunaga, S., Kopelevich, A., Kaspar, B. K., Lagier-Tourenne, C., &amp; Cleveland, D. W. (2015). Translational profiling identifies a cascade of damage initiated in motor neurons and spreading to glia in mutant SOD1-mediated ALS. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, 112, E6993-E7002. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1520639112</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tam, O. H., Rozhkov, N. V., Shaw, R., Kim, D., Hubbard, I., Fennessey, S., Propp, N., Fagegaltier, D., Harris, B. T., Ostrow, L. W., Phatnani, H., Ravits, J., Dubnau, J., Gale Hammell, M., Phatnani, H., Kwan, J., Sareen, D., Broach, J. R., Simmons, Z., &#x2026; Harris, B. T. (2019). Postmortem cortex samples identify distinct molecular subtypes of ALS: Retrotransposon activation, oxidative stress, and activated glia. Cell Report, 29, 1164-1177.e5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor, J. P., Brown, R. H., &amp; Cleveland, D. W. (2016). Decoding ALS: From genes to mechanism. Nature, 539, 197-206. https://doi.org/10.1038/nature20413</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamanaka, K., Chun, S. J., Boillee, S., Fujimori-Tonou, N., Yamashita, H., Gutmann, D. H., Takahashi, R., Misawa, H., &amp; Cleveland, D. W. (2008). Astrocytes as determinants of disease progression in inherited amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nature Neuroscience, 11, 251-253. https://doi.org/10.1038/nn2047</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamazaki, Y., Fujiwara, H., Kaneko, K., Hozumi, Y., Xu, M., Ikenaka, K., Fujii, S., &amp; Tanaka, K. F. (2014). Short- and long-term functional plasticity of white matter induced by oligodendrocyte depolarization in the hippocampus. Glia, 62, 1299-1312. https://doi.org/10.1002/glia.22681</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>