<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">34558138</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>09</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1098-2353</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>35</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Clinical anatomy (New York, N.Y.)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Clin Anat</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Apoptosis and its therapeutic implications in neurodegenerative diseases.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>65</StartPage><EndPage>78</EndPage><MedlinePgn>65-78</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/ca.23792</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Neurodegenerative disorders are characterized by progressive loss of particular populations of neurons. Apoptosis has been implicated in the pathogenesis of neurodegenerative diseases, including Parkinson disease, Alzheimer disease, Huntington disease, and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. In this review, we focus on the existing notions relevant to comprehending the apoptotic death process, including the morphological features, mediators and regulators of cellular apoptosis. We also highlight the evidence of neuronal apoptotic death in Parkinson disease, Alzheimer disease, Huntington disease, and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Additionally, we present evidence of potential therapeutic agents that could modify the apoptotic pathway in the aforementioned neurodegenerative diseases and delay disease progression. Finally, we review the clinical trials that were conducted to evaluate the use of anti-apoptotic drugs in the treatment of the aforementioned neurodegenerative diseases, in order to highlight the essential need for early detection and intervention of neurodegenerative diseases in humans.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 American Association of Clinical Anatomists.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Erekat</LastName><ForeName>Nour S</ForeName><Initials>NS</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4727-5928</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anatomy, Faculty of Medicine, Jordan University of Science and Technology, Irbid, Jordan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Clin Anat</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8809128</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0897-3806</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000544" MajorTopicYN="Y">Alzheimer Disease</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017209" MajorTopicYN="N">Apoptosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006816" MajorTopicYN="Y">Huntington Disease</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019636" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neurodegenerative Diseases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010300" MajorTopicYN="Y">Parkinson Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Alzheimer disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">BAX</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bcl-2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Coenzyme Q10</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Huntington disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Parkinson disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">antioxidant</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">apoptosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">caspases</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">clinical trials</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">minocycline</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neurodegenerative diseases</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34558138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ca.23792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Anilkumar, U., Khacho, M., Cuillerier, A., Harris, R., Patten, D. A., Bilen, M., Iqbal, M. A., Guo, D. Y., Trudeau, L. E., Park, D. S., Harper, M. E., Burelle, Y., &amp; Slack, R. S. (2020). MCL-1 (Matrix) maintains neuronal survival by enhancing mitochondrial integrity and bioenergetic capacity under stress conditions. Cell Death &amp; Disease, 11, 321.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antunes, M. S., Ladd, F. V. L., Ladd, A., Moreira, A. L., Boeira, S. P., &amp; Cattelan, S. L. (2021). Hesperidin protects against behavioral alterations and loss of dopaminergic neurons in 6-OHDA-lesioned mice: The role of mitochondrial dysfunction and apoptosis. Metabolic Brain Disease, 36, 153-167.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balakrishnan, R., Vijayraja, D., Mohankumar, T., Manimaran, D., Ganesan, P., Choi, D. K., &amp; Elangovan, N. (2021). Isolongifolene mitigates rotenone-induced dopamine depletion and motor deficits through anti-oxidative and anti-apoptotic effects in a rat model of Parkinson's disease. Journal of Chemical Neuroanatomy, 112, 101890.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balestrino, R., &amp; Schapira, A. H. V. (2020). Parkinson disease. European Journal of Neurology, 27(1), 27-42. https://doi.org/10.1111/ene.14108</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banfalvi, G. (2017). Methods to detect apoptotic cell death. Apoptosis, 22, 306-323.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bertheloot, D., Latz, E., &amp; Franklin, B. S. (2021). Necroptosis, pyroptosis and apoptosis: An intricate game of cell death. Cellular &amp; Molecular Immunology, 18, 1106-1121.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhattacharyya, N. P., Banerjee, M., &amp; Majumder, P. (2008). Huntington's disease: Roles of huntingtin-interacting protein 1 (HIP-1) and its molecular partner HIPPI in the regulation of apoptosis and transcription. The FEBS Journal, 275, 4271-4279.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bloch, N. B., Wales, T. E., Prew, M. S., Levy, H. R., Engen, J. R., &amp; Walensky, L. D. (2021). The conformational stability of pro-apoptotic BAX is dictated by discrete residues of the protein core. Nature Communications, 12, 4932.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bogomazova, A. N., Eremeev, A. V., Pozmogova, G. E., &amp; Lagarkova, M. A. (2019). The role of mutant RNA in the pathogenesis of Huntington's disease and other polyglutamine diseases. Molekuliarnaia Biologiia (Mosk), 53, 954-967.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boice, A., &amp; Bouchier-Hayes, L. (2020). Targeting apoptotic caspases in cancer. Biochimica et Biophysica Acta (BBA) - Molecular Cell Research, 1867(6), 118688. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bbamcr.2020.118688</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borsche, M., Pereira, S. L., Klein, C., &amp; Grunewald, A. (2021). Mitochondria and Parkinson's disease: Clinical, molecular, and translational aspects. Journal of Parkinson's Disease, 11, 45-60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bose, A., &amp; Beal, M. F. (2016). Mitochondrial dysfunction in Parkinson's disease. Journal of Neurochemistry, 139, 216-231. https://doi.org/10.1111/jnc.13731</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braidy, N., Zarka, M., Welch, J., &amp; Bridge, W. (2015). Therapeutic approaches to modulating glutathione levels as a pharmacological strategy in alzheimer's disease. Current Alzheimer Research, 12(4), 298-313. https://doi.org/10.2174/1567205012666150302160308</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruzova, M., Rusina, R., Stejskalova, Z., &amp; Matej, R. (2021). Autopsy-diagnosed neurodegenerative dementia cases support the use of cerebrospinal fluid protein biomarkers in the diagnostic work-up. Scientific Reports, 11, 10837.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burr&#xe9;, J., Sharma, M., &amp; S&#xfc;dhof, T. C. (2018). Cell Biology and Pathophysiology of &#x3b1;-Synuclein. Cold Spring Harbor Perspectives in Medicine, 8(3), 1-29. https://doi.org/10.1101/cshperspect.a024091</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cankaya, S., Cankaya, B., Kilic, U., Kilic, E., &amp; Yulug, B. (2019). The therapeutic role of minocycline in Parkinson's disease. Drugs in Context, 8, 212553.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao, S., Fisher, D. W., Yu, T., &amp; Dong, H. (2019). The link between chronic pain and Alzheimer's disease. Journal of Neuroinflammation, 16, 204.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cenini, G., Lloret, A., &amp; Cascella, R. (2020). Oxidative stress and mitochondrial damage in neurodegenerative diseases: From molecular mechanisms to targeted therapies. Oxidative Medicine and Cellular Longevity, 2020, 1270256.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaabane, W., Cie&#x15b;lar-Pobuda, A., El-Gazzah, M., Jain, M. V., Rzeszowska-Wolny, J., Rafat, M., Stetefeld, J., Ghavami, S., &amp; &#x141;os, M. J. (2014). Human-gyrovirus-apoptin triggers mitochondrial death pathway-nur77 is required for apoptosis triggering. Neoplasia, 16(9), 679-693. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neo.2014.08.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheignon, C., Tomas, M., Bonnefont-Rousselot, D., Faller, P., Hureau, C., &amp; Collin, F. (2018). Oxidative stress and the amyloid beta peptide in Alzheimer's disease. Redox Biology, 14, 450-464.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, G. F., Xu, T. H., Yan, Y., Zhou, Y. R., Jiang, Y., Melcher, K., &amp; Xu, H. E. (2017). Amyloid beta: Structure, biology and structure-based therapeutic development. Acta Pharmacologica Sinica, 38, 1205-1235.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, Y., Wang, J., Zhang, J., &amp; Wang, W. (2018). Binding modes of Bcl-2 homology 3 (BH3) peptides with anti-apoptotic protein A1 and redesign of peptide inhibitors: A computational study. Journal of Biomolecular Structure &amp; Dynamics, 36, 3967-3977.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi, H., Chang, H-Y., &amp; Sang T-K. (2018). Neuronal cell death mechanisms in major neurodegenerative diseases. International Journal of Molecular Sciences, 19(10), 3082. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms19103082</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xc7;&#x131;kla-S&#xfc;zg&#xfc;n, P., &amp; K&#xfc;&#xe7;&#xfc;kg&#xfc;zel, S. G. (2019). Recent advances in apoptosis: The role of hydrazones. Mini-Reviews in Medicinal Chemistry, 19(17), 1427-1442. https://doi.org/10.2174/1389557519666190410125910</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Correia Guedes, L., Mestre, T., Outeiro, T. F., &amp; Ferreira, J. J. (2020). Are genetic and idiopathic forms of Parkinson's disease the same disease? Journal of Neurochemistry, 152, 515-522.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Derakhshan, A., Chen, Z., &amp; Van Waes, C. (2017). Therapeutic small molecules target inhibitor of apoptosis proteins in cancers with deregulation of extrinsic and intrinsic cell death pathways. Clinical Cancer Research, 23, 1379-1387.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dickey, A. S., &amp; La Spada, A. R. (2018). Therapy development in Huntington disease: From current strategies to emerging opportunities. American Journal of Medical Genetics. Part A, 176, 842-861.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong, W., Luo, B., Qiu, C., Jiang, X., Shen, B., Zhang, L., Liu, W., &amp; Zhang, W. (2020). TRIM3 attenuates apoptosis in Parkinson's disease via activating PI3K/AKT signal pathway. Aging (Albany NY), 13, 735-749.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du, Q., Zhu, X., &amp; Si, J. (2020). Angelica polysaccharide ameliorates memory impairment in Alzheimer's disease rat through activating BDNF/TrkB/CREB pathway. Experimental Biology and Medicine (Maywood, N.J.), 245, 1-10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dugger, B. N., &amp; Dickson, D. W. (2017). Pathology of neurodegenerative diseases. Cold Spring Harbor Perspectives in Biology, 9(7), a028035. https://doi.org/10.1101/cshperspect.a028035</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eberhardt, O., Coelln, R. V., Kugler, S., Lindenau, J., Rathke-Hartlieb, S., Gerhardt, E., Haid, S., Isenmann, S., Gravel, C., Srinivasan, A., Bahr, M., Weller, M., Dichgans, J., &amp; Schulz, J. B. (2000). Protection by synergistic effects of adenovirus-mediated X-chromosome-linked inhibitor of apoptosis and glial cell line-derived neurotrophic factor gene transfer in the 1-methyl-4-phenyl-1,2,3,6-tetrahydropyridine model of Parkinson's disease. The Journal of Neuroscience, 20, 9126-9134.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edlich, F. (2018). BCL-2 proteins and apoptosis: Recent insights and unknowns. Biochemical and Biophysical Research Communications, 500, 26-34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekman, F. K., Ojala, D. S., Adil, M. M., Lopez, P. A., Schaffer, D. V., &amp; Gaj, T. (2019). CRISPR-Cas9-mediated genome editing increases lifespan and improves motor deficits in a Huntington's disease mouse model. Molecular Therapy Nucleic Acids, 17, 829-839.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elena-Real, C. A., Diaz-Quintana, A., Gonzalez-Arzola, K., Velazquez-Campoy, A., Orzaez, M., Lopez-Rivas, A., Gil-Caballero, S., De la Rosa, M. A., &amp; Diaz-Moreno, I. (2018). Cytochrome c speeds up caspase cascade activation by blocking 14-3-3epsilon-dependent Apaf-1 inhibition. Cell Death &amp; Disease, 9, 365.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erekat, N. S. (2017). Cerebellar Purkinje cells die by apoptosis in the shaker mutant rat. Brain Research, 1657, 323-332.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erekat, N. S. (2018a). Apoptosis and its role in Parkinson's disease. In T. B. Stoker &amp; J. C. Greenland (Eds.), Parkinson's disease: pathogenesis and clinical aspects. Brisbane (AU): Codon Publications.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erekat, N. S. (2018). Cerebellar upregulation of cell surface death Receptor-mediated apoptotic factors in Harmaline-induced tremor: An immunohistochemistry study. Journal of Cell Death, 11, 117906601880909. https://doi.org/10.1177/1179066018809091</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erekat, N. S. (2019). Active caspase-3 upregulation is augmented in at-risk cerebellar Purkinje cells following inferior olive chemoablation in the shaker mutant rat: An immunofluorescence study. Neurological Research, 41, 234-241.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng, Y., &amp; Wang, X. (2012). Antioxidant therapies for Alzheimer's disease. Oxidative Medicine and Cellular Longevity, 2012, 472932.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferdek, P. E., &amp; Jakubowska, M. A. (2017). On BH3 mimetics and Ca2+signaling. Drug Development Research, 78(6), 313-318. https://doi.org/10.1002/ddr.21405</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Firsov, A. M., Kotova, E. A., &amp; Antonenko, Y. N. (2018). Minocycline prevents peroxidative permeabilization of cardiolipin-containing bilayer lipid membranes mediated by cytochrome c. Biochemical and Biophysical Research Communications, 507, 510-513.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fouqu&#xe9;, A., Lepvrier, E., Debure, L., Gouriou, Y., Malleter, M., Delcroix, V., Ovize, M., Ducret, T., Li, C., Hammadi, M., Vacher, P., &amp; Legembre, P. (2016). The apoptotic members CD95, BclxL, and Bcl-2 cooperate to promote cell migration by inducing Ca2+ flux from the endoplasmic reticulum to mitochondria. Cell Death &amp; Differentiation, 23(10), 1702-1716. https://doi.org/10.1038/cdd.2016.61</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujita, K., Yamafuji, M., Nakabeppu, Y., &amp; Noda, M. (2012). Therapeutic approach to neurodegenerative diseases by medical gases: Focusing on redox signaling and related antioxidant enzymes. Oxidative Medicine and Cellular Longevity, 2012, 324256.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garrido-Mesa, N., Zarzuelo, A., &amp; G&#xe1;lvez, J. (2013). Minocycline: far beyond an antibiotic. British Journal of Pharmacology, 169(2), 337-352. https://doi.org/10.1111/bph.12139</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghosh, R., Wood-Kaczmar, A., Dobson, L., Smith, E. J., Sirinathsinghji, E. C., Kriston-Vizi, J., Hargreaves, I. P., Heaton, R., Herrmann, F., Abramov, A. Y., Lam, A. J., Heales, S. J., Ketteler, R., Bates, G. P., Andre, R., &amp; Tabrizi, S. J. (2020). Expression of mutant exon 1 huntingtin fragments in human neural stem cells and neurons causes inclusion formation and mitochondrial dysfunction. The FASEB Journal, 34, 8139-8154.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon, P. H., Moore, D. H., Miller, R. G., Florence, J. M., Verheijde, J. L., Doorish, C., Hilton, J. F., Spitalny, G. M., MacArthur, R. B., Mitsumoto, H., Neville, H. E., Boylan, K., Mozaffar, T., Belsh, J. M., Ravits, J., Bedlack, R. S., Graves, M. C., McCluskey, L. F., Barohn, R. J., &#x2026; Western, A. L. S. S. G. (2007). Efficacy of minocycline in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A phase III randomised trial. Lancet Neurology, 6, 1045-1053.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guissart, C., Mouzat, K., Kantar, J., Louveau, B., Vilquin, P., Polge, A., Raoul, C., &amp; Lumbroso, S. (2020). Premature termination codons in SOD1 causing amyotrophic lateral sclerosis are predicted to escape the nonsense-mediated mRNA decay. Scientific Reports, 10, 20738.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo, C., Sun, L., Chen, X., &amp; Zhang, D. (2013). Oxidative stress, mitochondrial damage and neurodegenerative diseases. Neural Regeneration Research, 8, 2003-2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guzman-Martinez, L., Maccioni, R. B., Andrade, V., Navarrete, L. P., Pastor, M. G., &amp; Ramos-Escobar, N. (2019). Neuroinflammation as a common feature of neurodegenerative disorders. Frontiers in Pharmacology, 10. https://doi.org/10.3389/fphar.2019.01008</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haddad, D., &amp; Nakamura, K. (2015). Understanding the susceptibility of dopamine neurons to mitochondrial stressors in Parkinson's disease. FEBS Letters, 589, 3702-3713.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartmann, A., Troadec, J. D., Hunot, S., Kikly, K., Faucheux, B. A., Mouatt-Prigent, A., Ruberg, M., Agid, Y., &amp; Hirsch, E. C. (2001). Caspase-8 is an effector in apoptotic death of dopaminergic neurons in Parkinson's disease, but pathway inhibition results in neuronal necrosis. The Journal of Neuroscience, 21, 2247-2255.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, Z., Guo, J. L., McBride, J. D., Narasimhan, S., Kim, H., Changolkar, L., Zhang, B., Gathagan, R. J., Yue, C., Dengler, C., Stieber, A., Nitla, M., Coulter, D. A., Abel, T., Brunden, K. R., Trojanowski, J. Q., &amp; Lee, V. M. (2018). Amyloid-beta plaques enhance Alzheimer's brain tau-seeded pathologies by facilitating neuritic plaque tau aggregation. Nature Medicine, 24, 29-38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Honarnejad, K., Jung, C. K., Lammich, S., Arzberger, T., Kretzschmar, H., &amp; Herms, J. (2013). Involvement of presenilin holoprotein upregulation in calcium dyshomeostasis of Alzheimer's disease. Journal of Cellular and Molecular Medicine, 17, 293-302.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howard, R., Zubko, O., Bradley, R., Harper, E., Pank, L., O'Brien, J., Fox, C., Tabet, N., Livingston, G., Bentham, P., McShane, R., Burns, A., Ritchie, C., Reeves, S., Lovestone, S., Ballard, C., Noble, W., Nilforooshan, R., Wilcock, G., &#x2026; Minocycline in Alzheimer Disease Efficacy Trialist G. (2020). Minocycline at 2 different dosages vs placebo for patients with mild Alzheimer disease: A randomized clinical trial. JAMA Neurology, 77, 164-174.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, Q., Zhu, X., &amp; Xu, M. (2019). Silencing of TRIM10 alleviates apoptosis in cellular model of Parkinson's disease. Biochemical and Biophysical Research Communications, 518, 451-458.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huntington Study Group DI. (2010). A futility study of minocycline in Huntington's disease. Movement Disorders, 25, 2219-2224.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Idda, M. L., Munk, R., Abdelmohsen, K., &amp; Gorospe, M. (2018). Noncoding RNAs in Alzheimer's disease. Wiley Interdisciplinary Reviews: RNA, 9, e1463.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Investigators, N. N.-P. (2008). A pilot clinical trial of creatine and minocycline in early Parkinson disease: 18-month results. Clinical Neuropharmacology, 31, 141-150.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ji, E. S., Kim, Y. M., Shin, M. S., Kim, C. J., Lee, K. S., Kim, K., Ha, J., &amp; Chung, Y. R. (2015). Treadmill exercise enhances spatial learning ability through suppressing hippocampal apoptosis in Huntington's disease rats. Journal of Exercise Rehabilitation, 11, 133-139.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jodeiri Farshbaf, M., &amp; Ghaedi, K. (2017). Huntington's disease and mitochondria. Neurotoxicity Research, 32(3), 518-529. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12640-017-9766-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jurcau, A. (2021). The role of natural antioxidants in the prevention of dementia-where do we stand and future perspectives. Nutrients, 13(2), 282. https://doi.org/10.3390/nu13020282</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Justin Thenmozhi, A., William Raja, T. R., Manivasagam, T., Janakiraman, U., &amp; Essa, M. M. (2017). Hesperidin ameliorates cognitive dysfunction, oxidative stress and apoptosis against aluminium chloride induced rat model of Alzheimer's disease. Nutritional Neuroscience, 20, 360-368.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaczanowski, S. (2016). Apoptosis: Its origin, history, maintenance and the medical implications for cancer and aging. Physical Biology, 13, 031001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kale, J., Osterlund, E. J., &amp; Andrews, D. W. (2018). BCL-2 family proteins: Changing partners in the dance towards death. Cell Death and Differentiation, 25, 65-80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalimuthu, S., &amp; Se-Kwon, K. (2013). Cell survival and apoptosis signaling as therapeutic target for cancer: Marine bioactive compounds. International Journal of Molecular Sciences, 14, 2334-2354.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaufmann, P., Thompson, J. L., Levy, G., Buchsbaum, R., Shefner, J., Krivickas, L. S., Katz, J., Rollins, Y., Barohn, R. J., Jackson, C. E., Tiryaki, E., Lomen-Hoerth, C., Armon, C., Tandan, R., Rudnicki, S. A., Rezania, K., Sufit, R., Pestronk, A., Novella, S. P., &#x2026; Group QS. (2009). Phase II trial of CoQ10 for ALS finds insufficient evidence to justify phase III. Annals of Neurology, 66, 235-244.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ke, Y., Tang, H., Ye, C., Lei, C. T., Wang, Y. M., Su, H., Zhang, C., &amp; Jiang, H. J. (2016). Role and association of inflammatory and apoptotic caspases in renal tubulointerstitial fibrosis. Kidney &amp; Blood Pressure Research, 41, 643-653.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan, A., Das, S., &amp; Sergi, C. (2021). Therapeutic potential of Neu1 in Alzheimer's disease via the immune system. American Journal of Alzheimer's Disease and Other Dementias, 36, 1533317521996147.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, B. G., Kwon, H. Y., Sohn, E. J., Hwang, S., Kwon, O. S., &amp; Kim, S. H. (2014). Activation of caspases and inhibition of ribosome biogenesis mediate antitumor activity of Chijongdan in A549 non-small lung cancer cells. BMC Complementary and Alternative Medicine, 14, 420.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, H-S., &amp; Suh, Y-H. (2009). Minocycline and neurodegenerative diseases. Behavioural Brain Research, 196, 168-179.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, T. W., Moon, Y., Kim, K., Lee, J. E., Koh, H. C., Rhyu, I. J., Kim, H., &amp; Sun, W. (2011). Dissociation of progressive dopaminergic neuronal death and behavioral impairments by Bax deletion in a mouse model of Parkinson's diseases. PLoS One, 6, e25346.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, Y. J., Kim, S. H., Park, Y., Park, J., Lee, J. H., Kim, B. C., &amp; Song, W. K. (2020). miR-16-5p is upregulated by amyloid beta deposition in Alzheimer's disease models and induces neuronal cell apoptosis through direct targeting and suppression of BCL-2. Experimental Gerontology, 136, 110954.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiraz, Y., Adan, A., Kartal Yandim, M., &amp; Baran, Y. (2016). Major apoptotic mechanisms and genes involved in apoptosis. Tumour Biology, 37, 8471-8486.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konnova, E. A., &amp; Swanberg, M. (2018). Animal models of Parkinson's disease. In T. B. Stoker &amp; J. C. Greenland (Eds.), Parkinson's disease: pathogenesis and clinical aspects. Brisbane (AU): Codon Publications.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kupcho, K., Shultz, J., Hurst, R., Hartnett, J., Zhou, W., Machleidt, T., Grailer, J., Worzella, T., Riss, T., Lazar, D., Cali, J. J., &amp; Niles, A. (2019). A real-time, bioluminescent annexin V assay for the assessment of apoptosis. Apoptosis, 24, 184-197.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larsen, S. B., Hanss, Z., &amp; Kr&#xfc;ger, R. (2018). The genetic architecture of mitochondrial dysfunction in Parkinson's disease. Cell and Tissue Research, 373(1), 21-37. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00441-017-2768-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leonard, B. C., &amp; Johnson, D. E. (2018). Signaling by cell surface death receptors: Alterations in head and neck cancer. Advances in Biological Regulation, 67, 170-178.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>LeWitt, P. A., &amp; Taylor, D. C. (2008). Protection against Parkinson's disease progression: Clinical experience. Neurotherapeutics, 5, 210-225.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, X. L., Wang, Y. D., Yu, X. M., Li, D. W., &amp; Li, G. R. (2018). Mitochondria-mediated damage to dopaminergic neurons in Parkinson's disease (Review). International Journal of Molecular Medicine, 41, 615-623.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Z., Wild, C., Ding, Y., Ye, N., Chen, H., Wold, E. A., &amp; Zhou, J. (2016). BH4 domain of Bcl-2 as a novel target for cancer therapy. Drug Discovery Today, 21, 989-996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma, J., Gao, S. S., Yang, H. J., Wang, M., Cheng, B. F., Feng, Z. W., &amp; Wang, L. (2018). Neuroprotective effects of proanthocyanidins, natural flavonoids derived from plants, on rotenone-induced oxidative stress and apoptotic cell death in human neuroblastoma SH-SY5Y cells. Frontiers in Neuroscience, 12, 369.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maglione, V., Cannella, M., Gradini, R., Cislaghi, G., &amp; Squitieri, F. (2006). Huntingtin fragmentation and increased caspase 3, 8 and 9 activities in lymphoblasts with heterozygous and homozygous Huntington's disease mutation. Mechanisms of Ageing and Development, 127, 213-216.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maji, S., Panda, S., Samal, S. K., Shriwas, O., Rath, R., Pellecchia, M., Emdad, L., Das, S. K., Fisher, P. B., &amp; Dash, R. (2018). Bcl-2 antiapoptotic family proteins and chemoresistance in cancer. Advances in Cancer Research, 137, 37-75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Majtnerov&#xe1;, P., &amp; Rou&#x161;ar, T. (2018). An overview of apoptosis assays detecting DNA fragmentation. Molecular Biology Reports, 45(5), 1469-1478. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11033-018-4258-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marek, L. (2013). The role of the apoptosome in the activation of procaspase-9. Post&#x229;py Higieny i Medycyny Do&#x15b;wiadczalnej (Online), 67, 54-64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martini, F., Rosa, S. G., Klann, I. P., Fulco, B. C. W., Carvalho, F. B., Rahmeier, F. L., Fernandes, M. C., &amp; Nogueira, C. W. (2019). A multifunctional compound ebselen reverses memory impairment, apoptosis and oxidative stress in a mouse model of sporadic Alzheimer's disease. Journal of Psychiatric Research, 109, 107-117.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maruyama, W., Akao, Y., Carrillo, M. C., Kitani, K., Youdium, M. B., &amp; Naoi, M. (2002). Neuroprotection by propargylamines in Parkinson's disease: Suppression of apoptosis and induction of prosurvival genes. Neurotoxicology and Teratology, 24, 675-682.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McAdam, R. L., Morton, A., Gordon, S. L., Alterman, J. F., Khvorova, A., Cousin, M. A., &amp; Smillie, K. J. (2020). Loss of huntingtin function slows synaptic vesicle endocytosis in striatal neurons from the htt(Q140/Q140) mouse model of Huntington's disease. Neurobiology of Disease, 134, 104637.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McAlary, L., Chew, Y. L., Lum, J. S., Geraghty, N. J., Yerbury, J. J., &amp; Cashman, N. R. (2020). Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Proteins, proteostasis, prions, and promises. Frontiers in Cellular Neuroscience, 14, 581907.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McColgan, P., &amp; Tabrizi, S. J. (2018). Huntington's disease: A clinical review. European Journal of Neurology, 25, 24-34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGarry, A., McDermott, M., Kieburtz, K., de Blieck, E. A., Beal, F., Marder, K., Ross, C., Shoulson, I., Gilbert, P., Mallonee, W. M., Guttman, M., Wojcieszek, J., Kumar, R., LeDoux, M. S., Jenkins, M., Rosas, H. D., Nance, M., Biglan, K., Como, P., &#x2026; Coordinators. (2017). A randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial of coenzyme Q10 in Huntington disease. Neurology, 88, 152-159.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McIlwain, D. R., Berger, T., &amp; Mak, T. W. (2013). Caspase functions in cell death and disease. Cold Spring Harbor Perspectives in Biology, 5(4), a008656-a008656. https://doi.org/10.1101/cshperspect.a008656</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McIlwain, D. R., Berger, T., &amp; Mak, T. W. (2015). Caspase functions in cell death and disease: figure 1. Cold Spring Harbor Perspectives in Biology, 7(4), a026716. https://doi.org/10.1101/cshperspect.a026716</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morris, J. L., Gillet, G., Prudent, J., &amp; Popgeorgiev, N. (2021). Bcl-2 Family of proteins in the control of mitochondrial calcium signalling: An old chap with new roles. International Journal of Molecular Sciences, 22(7), 3730. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms22073730</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moujalled, D., Strasser, A., &amp; Liddell, J. R. (2021). Molecular mechanisms of cell death in neurological diseases. Cell Death and Differentiation, 28, 2029-2044.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ngoi, N. Y. L., Choong, C., Lee, J., Bellot, G., Wong, A. L. A., Goh, B. C., &amp; Pervaiz, S. (2020). Targeting mitochondrial apoptosis to overcome treatment resistance in cancer. Cancers, 12(3), 574. https://doi.org/10.3390/cancers12030574</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicolas, G., Acuna-Hidalgo, R., Keogh, M. J., Quenez, O., Steehouwer, M., Lelieveld, S., Rousseau, S., Richard, A. C., Oud, M. S., Marguet, F., Laquerriere, A., Morris, C. M., Attems, J., Smith, C., Ansorge, O., Al Sarraj, S., Frebourg, T., Campion, D., Hannequin, D., &#x2026; Hoischen, A. (2018). Somatic variants in autosomal dominant genes are a rare cause of sporadic Alzheimer's disease. Alzheimers Dement, 14, 1632-1639.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Obulesu, M., &amp; Lakshmi, M. J. (2014). Apoptosis in Alzheimer's disease: An understanding of the physiology, pathology and therapeutic avenues. Neurochemical Research, 39, 2301-2312.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Reilly, E., Tirincsi, A., Logue, S. E., &amp; Szegezdi, E. (2016). The Janus face of death receptor signaling during tumor immunoediting. Frontiers in Immunology, 7, 446.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan, Y., Cheng, A., Wang, M., Yin, Z., &amp; Jia, R. (2021). The dual regulation of apoptosis by flavivirus. Frontiers in Microbiology, 12, 654494.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pantiya, P., Thonusin, C., Chattipakorn, N., &amp; Chattipakorn, S. C. (2020). Mitochondrial abnormalities in neurodegenerative models and possible interventions: Focus on Alzheimer's disease, Parkinson's disease, Huntington's disease. Mitochondrion, 55, 14-47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park, G., Nhan, H. S., Tyan, S. H., Kawakatsu, Y., Zhang, C., Navarro, M., &amp; Koo, E. H. (2020). Caspase activation and caspase-mediated cleavage of APP is associated with amyloid beta-protein-induced synapse loss in Alzheimer's disease. Cell Reports, 31, 107839.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parkinson Study Group QEI, Beal, M. F., Oakes, D., Shoulson, I., Henchcliffe, C., Galpern, W. R., Haas, R., Juncos, J. L., Nutt, J. G., Voss, T. S., Ravina, B., Shults, C. M., Helles, K., Snively, V., Lew, M. F., Griebner, B., Watts, A., Gao, S., Pourcher, E., &#x2026; Boyar, K. (2014). A randomized clinical trial of high-dosage coenzyme Q10 in early Parkinson disease: No evidence of benefit. JAMA Neurology, 71, 543-552.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parrish, A. B., Freel, C. D., &amp; Kornbluth, S. (2013). Cellular mechanisms controlling caspase activation and function. Cold Spring Harbor Perspectives in Biology, 5(6), a008672-a008672. https://doi.org/10.1101/cshperspect.a008672</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel, B. P., Safdar, A., Raha, S., Tarnopolsky, M. A., &amp; Hamadeh, M. J. (2010). Caloric restriction shortens lifespan through an increase in lipid peroxidation, inflammation and apoptosis in the G93A mouse, an animal model of ALS. PLoS One, 5, e9386.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P&#xe9;cot, J., Maillet, L., Le Pen, J., Vuillier, C., Tr&#xe9;cesson, S. C., F&#xe9;tiveau, A., Sarosiek, K. A., Bock, F. J., Braun, F., Letai, A., Tait, S. W. G., Gautier, F., &amp; Juin, P. P. (2016). Tight sequestration of BH3 proteins by BCL-xL at subcellular membranes contributes to apoptotic resistance. Cell Reports, 17(12), 3347-3358. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.celrep.2016.11.064</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pena-Blanco, A., &amp; Garcia-Saez, A. J. (2018). Bax, Bak and beyond - mitochondrial performance in apoptosis. The FEBS Journal, 285, 416-431.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pires, G., McElligott, S., Drusinsky, S., Halliday, G., Potier, M. C., Wisniewski, T., &amp; Drummond, E. (2019). Secernin-1 is a novel phosphorylated tau binding protein that accumulates in Alzheimer's disease and not in other tauopathies. Acta Neuropathologica Communications, 7, 195.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pocernich, C. B., &amp; Butterfield, D. A. (2012). Elevation of glutathione as a therapeutic strategy in Alzheimer disease. Biochimica et Biophysica Acta, 1822, 625-630.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rathore, R., McCallum, J. E., Varghese, E., Florea, A. M., &amp; Busselberg, D. (2017). Overcoming chemotherapy drug resistance by targeting inhibitors of apoptosis proteins (IAPs). Apoptosis, 22, 898-919.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reeve, A. K., Ludtmann, M. H., Angelova, P. R., Simcox, E. M., Horrocks, M. H., Klenerman, D., Gandhi, S., Turnbull, D. M., &amp; Abramov, A. Y. (2015). Aggregated alpha-synuclein and complex I deficiency: Exploration of their relationship in differentiated neurons. Cell Death &amp; Disease, 6, e1820.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renault, T. T., Elkholi, R., Bharti, A., &amp; Chipuk, J. E. (2014). B cell lymphoma-2 (BCL-2) homology domain 3 (BH3) mimetics demonstrate differential activities dependent upon the functional repertoire of pro- and anti-apoptotic BCL-2 family proteins. The Journal of Biological Chemistry, 289, 26481-26491.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reyes, N. A., Fisher, J. K., Austgen, K., VandenBerg, S., Huang, E. J., &amp; Oakes, S. A. (2010). Blocking the mitochondrial apoptotic pathway preserves motor neuron viability and function in a mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. The Journal of Clinical Investigation, 120, 3673-3679.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rocha, A. L., Costa, A., Garrett, M. C., &amp; Meireles, J. (2018). Difficult case of a rare form of familial Alzheimer's disease with PSEN1 P117L mutation. BMJ Case Reports, 11(1), e226664. https://doi.org/10.1136/bcr-2018-226664</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rocha, E. M., De Miranda, B., &amp; Sanders, L. H. (2018). Alpha-synuclein: Pathology, mitochondrial dysfunction and neuroinflammation in Parkinson's disease. Neurobiology of Disease, 109, 249-257.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roher, A. E., Kokjohn, T. A., Clarke, S. G., Sierks, M. R., Maarouf, C. L., Serrano, G. E., Sabbagh, M. S., &amp; Beach, T. G. (2017). APP/Abeta structural diversity and Alzheimer's disease pathogenesis. Neurochemistry International, 110, 1-13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rohn, T. T. (2010). The role of caspases in Alzheimer's disease; potential novel therapeutic opportunities. Apoptosis, 15, 1403-1409.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosa, A. C., Corsi, D., Cavi, N., Bruni, N., &amp; Dosio, F. (2021). Superoxide dismutase administration: A review of proposed human uses. Molecules, 26(7), 1844. https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules26071844</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rose, M., Kurylowicz, M., Mahmood, M., Winkel, S., Moran-Mirabal, J. M., &amp; Fradin, C. (2021). Direct measurement of the affinity between tBid and bax in a mitochondria-like membrane. International Journal of Molecular Sciences, 22(15), 8240. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms22158240</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salehi, M., Nikkhah, M., Mohammadi, S., &amp; Hosseinkhani, S. (2021). Transient transfection of WT-alphaS and A53T-alphaS brought about a mild apoptosis due to degradation of released cytochrome c through PARC. International Journal of Biological Macromolecules, 166, 374-384.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanchez Mejia, R. S., &amp; Friedlander, R. M. (2001). Caspases in huntington's disease. The Neuroscientist, 7(6), 480-489. https://doi.org/10.1177/107385840100700604</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarkar, S., Raymick, J., &amp; Imam, S. (2016). Neuroprotective and therapeutic strategies against parkinson's disease: Recent perspectives. International Journal of Molecular Sciences, 17(6), 904. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms17060904</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sathasivam, S., &amp; Shaw, P. J. (2005). Apoptosis in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-what is the evidence?. The Lancet Neurology, 4(8), 500-509. https://doi.org/10.1016/s1474-4422(05)70142-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scheuing, L., Chiu, C. T., Liao, H. M., Linares, G. R., &amp; Chuang, D. M. (2014). Preclinical and clinical investigations of mood stabilizers for Huntington's disease: What have we learned? International Journal of Biological Sciences, 10, 1024-1038.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shan, S., Tian, L., &amp; Fang, R. (2019). Chlorogenic acid exerts beneficial effects in 6-hydroxydopamine-induced neurotoxicity by inhibition of endoplasmic reticulum stress. Medical Science Monitor, 25, 453-459.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shinoe, T., Wanaka, A., Nikaido, T., Kanazawa, K., Shimizu, J., Imaizumi, K., &amp; Kanazawa, I. (2001). Upregulation of the pro-apoptotic BH3-only peptide harakiri in spinal neurons of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. Neuroscience Letters, 313, 153-157.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sinyor, B., Mineo, J., &amp; Ochner, C. (2020). Alzheimer's disease, inflammation, and the role of antioxidants. Journal of Alzheimer's Disease Reports, 4, 175-183.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith, E. F., Shaw, P. J., &amp; De Vos, K. J. (2019). The role of mitochondria in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuroscience Letters, 710, 132933.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sorrentino, Z. A., &amp; Giasson, B. I. (2020). The emerging role of alpha-synuclein truncation in aggregation and disease. The Journal of Biological Chemistry, 295, 10224-10244.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soto, C., &amp; Pritzkow, S. (2018). Protein misfolding, aggregation, and conformational strains in neurodegenerative diseases. Nature Neuroscience, 21, 1332-1340.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stoker, TB, Greenland, JC. 2018. Parkinson's disease: Pathogenesis and clinical aspects.Brisbane (AU): Codon Publications.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su, J., Zhang, J., Bao, R., Xia, C., Zhang, Y., Zhu, Z., Lv, Q., Qi, Y., &amp; Xue, J. (2021). Mitochondrial dysfunction and apoptosis are attenuated through activation of AMPK/GSK-3beta/PP2A pathway in Parkinson's disease. European Journal of Pharmacology, 907, 174202.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Subburaj, Y., Cosentino, K., Axmann, M., Pedrueza-Villalmanzo, E., Hermann, E., Bleicken, S., Spatz, J., &amp; Garcia-Saez, A. J. (2015). Bax monomers form dimer units in the membrane that further self-assemble into multiple oligomeric species. Nature Communications, 6, 8042.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suhaili, S. H., Karimian, H., Stellato, M., Lee, T. H., &amp; Aguilar, M. I. (2017). Mitochondrial outer membrane permeabilization: A focus on the role of mitochondrial membrane structural organization. Biophysical Reviews, 9, 443-457.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tapia-Rojas, C., Cabezas-Opazo, F., Deaton, C. A., Vergara, E. H., Johnson, G. V. W., &amp; Quintanilla, R. A. (2019). It's all about tau. Progress in Neurobiology, 175, 54-76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teles, A. V. F. F., Rosenstock, T. R., Okuno, C. S., Lopes, G. S., Bertoncini, C. R. A., &amp; Smaili, S. S. (2008). Increase in bax expression and apoptosis are associated in Huntington's disease progression. Neuroscience Letters, 438, 59-63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teng, L., Yang, M., Jin, X., Qian, L., Yang, W., Ren, X., &amp; Qu, Q. (2020). Protective effect of compound formula Rehmannia against neurotoxicity and apoptosis induced by alpha-Syn in in vivo and in vitro models of Parkinson's disease. Evidence-based Complementary and Alternative Medicine, 2020, 5201912.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Testa, C. M., &amp; Jankovic, J. (2019). Huntington disease: A quarter century of progress since the gene discovery. Journal of the Neurological Sciences, 396, 52-68.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thal, L. J., Grundman, M., Berg, J., Ernstrom, K., Margolin, R., Pfeiffer, E., Weiner, M. F., Zamrini, E., &amp; Thomas, R. G. (2003). Idebenone treatment fails to slow cognitive decline in Alzheimer's disease. Neurology, 61, 1498-1502.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tiedt, H. O., Benjamin, B., Niedeggen, M., &amp; Lueschow, A. (2018). Phenotypic variability in autosomal dominant familial Alzheimer disease due to the S170F mutation of Presenilin-1. Neurodegenerative Diseases, 18, 57-68.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turunc Bayrakdar, E., Uyanikgil, Y., Kanit, L., Koylu, E., &amp; Yalcin, A. (2014). Nicotinamide treatment reduces the levels of oxidative stress, apoptosis, and PARP-1 activity in A&#x3b2;(1-42)-induced rat model of Alzheimer's disease. Free Radical Research, 48(2), 146-158. https://doi.org/10.3109/10715762.2013.857018</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tuzlak, S., Kaufmann, T., &amp; Villunger, A. (2016). Interrogating the relevance of mitochondrial apoptosis for vertebrate development and postnatal tissue homeostasis. Genes &amp; Development, 30, 2133-2151.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Opdenbosch, N., &amp; Lamkanfi, M. (2019). Caspases in cell death, inflammation, and disease. Immunity, 50, 1352-1364.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vauzour, D., Pinto, J. T., Cooper, A. J., &amp; Spencer, J. P. (2014). The neurotoxicity of 5-S-cysteinyldopamine is mediated by the early activation of ERK1/2 followed by the subsequent activation of ASK1/JNK1/2 pro-apoptotic signalling. The Biochemical Journal, 463, 41-52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vavrova, J., &amp; Rezacova, M. (2014). Importance of proapoptotic protein PUMA in cell radioresistance. Folia Biologica (Praha), 60, 53-56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaz, A. R., Cunha, C., Gomes, C., Schmucki, N., Barbosa, M., &amp; Brites, D. (2015). Glycoursodeoxycholic acid reduces matrix metalloproteinase-9 and caspase-9 activation in a cellular model of superoxide dismutase-1 neurodegeneration. Molecular Neurobiology, 51, 864-877.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venderova, K., &amp; Park, D. S. (2012). Programmed cell death in parkinson's disease. Cold Spring Harbor Perspectives in Medicine, 2(8), a009365-a009365. https://doi.org/10.1101/cshperspect.a009365</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vervliet, T., Parys, J. B., &amp; Bultynck, G. (2016). Bcl-2 proteins and calcium signaling: Complexity beneath the surface. Oncogene, 35, 5079-5092.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veurink, G., Perry, G., &amp; Singh, S. K. (2020). Role of antioxidants and a nutrient rich diet in Alzheimer's disease. Open Biology, 10, 200084.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waldvogel, H. J., Kim, E. H., Thu, D. C., Tippett, L. J., &amp; Faull, R. L. (2012). New perspectives on the neuropathology in Huntington's disease in the human brain and its relation to symptom variation. Journal of Huntington's Disease, 1, 143-153.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, L., Pu, Z., Li, M., Wang, K., Deng, L., &amp; Chen, W. (2020). Antioxidative and antiapoptosis: Neuroprotective effects of dauricine in Alzheimer's disease models. Life Sciences, 243, 117237.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Y., Hu, S., Tuerdi, M., Yu, X., Zhang, H., Zhou, Y., Cao, J., da Silva Vaz, I., Jr., &amp; Zhou, J. (2020). Initiator and executioner caspases in salivary gland apoptosis of Rhipicephalus haemaphysaloides. Parasites &amp; Vectors, 13, 288.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warren, C. F. A., Wong-Brown, M. W., &amp; Bowden, N. A. (2019). BCL-2 family isoforms in apoptosis and cancer. Cell Death &amp; Disease, 10, 177.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wells, C., Brennan, S. E., Keon, M., &amp; Saksena, N. K. (2019). Prionoid proteins in the pathogenesis of neurodegenerative diseases. Frontiers in Molecular Neuroscience, 12, 271.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilkins, H. M., &amp; Morris, J. K. (2017). New therapeutics to modulate mitochondrial function in neurodegenerative disorders. Current Pharmaceutical Design, 23(5), 731-752. https://doi.org/10.2174/1381612822666161230144517</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong, F. K., &amp; Mar&#xed;n, O. (2019). Developmental cell death in the cerebral cortex. Annual Review of Cell and Developmental Biology, 35(1), 523-542. https://doi.org/10.1146/annurev-cellbio-100818-125204</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, C. R., Chang, H. C., Cheng, Y. D., Lan, W. C., Yang, S. E., &amp; Ching, H. (2018). Aqueous extract of davallia mariesii attenuates 6-Hydroxydopamine-Induced oxidative damage and apoptosis in B35 cells through inhibition of caspase cascade and activation of PI3K/AKT/GSK-3&#x3b2; pathway. Nutrients, 10(10), 1449. https://doi.org/10.3390/nu10101449</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, X., Lai, Y., &amp; Hua, Z. C. (2019). Apoptosis and apoptotic body: disease message and therapeutic target potentials. Bioscience Reports, 39(1). https://doi.org/10.1042/bsr20180992</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yee, C., Yang, W., &amp; Hekimi, S. (2014). The intrinsic apoptosis pathway mediates the pro-longevity response to mitochondrial ROS in C. elegans. Cell, 157, 897-909.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Youssef, K., Tandon, A., &amp; Rezai, P. (2019). Studying Parkinson's disease using Caenorhabditis elegans models in microfluidic devices. Integrative Biology (Cambridge), 11, 186-207.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zarei, S., Carr, K., Reiley, L., Diaz, K., Guerra, O., Altamirano, P. F., Pagani, W., Lodin, D., Orozco, G., &amp; Chinea, A. (2015). A comprehensive review of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Surgical Neurology International, 6, 171.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng, L., Hu, C., Zhang, F., Xu, D. C., Cui, M-Z., &amp; Xu, X. (2015). Cellular FLICE-like inhibitory protein (c-FLIP) and PS1-associated protein (PSAP) mediate presenilin 1-induced &#x3b3;-secretase-dependent and -independent apoptosis, respectively. Journal of Biological Chemistry, 290(30), 18269-18280. https://doi.org/10.1074/jbc.m115.640177</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Q-S., Liu, W., &amp; Lu, G-X. (2017). miR-200a-3p promotes &#x3b2;-Amyloid-induced neuronal apoptosis through down-regulation of SIRT1 in Alzheimer's disease. Journal of Biosciences, 42(3), 397-404. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12038-017-9698-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, T., &amp; Saghatelian, A. (2013). Emerging roles of lipids in BCL-2 family-regulated apoptosis. Biochimica et Biophysica Acta, 1831, 1542-1554.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng, J., Long, M., Qin, Z., Wang, F., Chen, Z., &amp; Li, L. (2021). Nicorandil inhibits cardiomyocyte apoptosis and improves cardiac function by suppressing the HtrA2/XIAP/PARP signaling after coronary microembolization in rats. Pharmacology Research &amp; Perspectives, 9, e00699.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>