<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">34561341</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1751-4266</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Current opinion in supportive and palliative care</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Curr Opin Support Palliat Care</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Non-invasive ventilation support for people with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: multidisciplinary team management.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>214</StartPage><EndPage>218</EndPage><MedlinePgn>214-218</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/SPC.0000000000000570</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE OF REVIEW">To summarise recent developments in the use of noninvasive ventilation (NIV) for people with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (pwALS), with a specific focus on how multidisciplinary teams (MDT) can support best practice.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RECENT FINDINGS">We included 13 papers, 12 with observational designs and one qualitative interview design. The review is structured using four content domains: prognosis, the effectiveness of NIV, NIV tolerance, and MDT structure and delivery. Findings suggest a modest survival benefit of NIV for pwALS. Further evidence is needed to consider the appropriate time of initiation in the context of respiratory status and the influence of NIV on cognitive function over the course of the disease. A key emerging determinant of tolerability of NIV is secretion load. Palliative care professionals within the MDT can play a key role in supporting pwALS to consider the potential benefits of NIV in the context of their preferences, prognosis, symptom burden, and ALS variant.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUMMARY">ALS MDTs allow timely information sharing about NIV between experts that is likely to improve outcomes. MDT practice must continually adapt to reflect pwALS's preferences for care and ensure those caring for them at home have access to support using digital innovations.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2021 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Barry</LastName><ForeName>Caroline</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Norfolk and Norwich University Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Larner</LastName><ForeName>Emma</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Norfolk and Norwich University Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Copsey</LastName><ForeName>Helen</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Norfolk and Norwich University Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Smith</LastName><ForeName>Matthew</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of East Anglia, Norwich, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Peryer</LastName><ForeName>Guy</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of East Anglia, Norwich, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Curr Opin Support Palliat Care</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101297402</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1751-4258</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D063087" MajorTopicYN="Y">Noninvasive Ventilation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010348" MajorTopicYN="N">Patient Care Team</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012121" MajorTopicYN="N">Respiration, Artificial</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34561341</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/SPC.0000000000000570</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">01263393-202112000-00005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bourke SC, Tomlinson M, Williams TL, et al. Effects of noninvasive ventilation on survival and quality of life in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a randomised controlled trial. Lancet Neurol 2006; 5:140&#x2013;147.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim J, Bireley JD, Hayat G, Kafaie J. Effects of noninvasive ventilation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: the complication of bulbar impairment. Clin Transl Neurosci 2020; 4:8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aridegbe T, Kandler R, Walters SJ, et al. The natural history of motor neuron disease: assessing the impact of specialist care. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2013; 14:13&#x2013;19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rooney J, Byrne S, Heverin M, et al. A multidisciplinary clinic approach improves survival in ALS: a comparative study of ALS in Ireland and Northern Ireland. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2015; 86:496&#x2013;501.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Traynor BJ, Alexander M, Corr B, et al. Effect of a multidisciplinary amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) clinic on ALS survival: a population based study, 1996&#x2013;2000. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2003; 74:1258&#x2013;1261.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volanti P, Cibella F, Sarv&#xe0; M, et al. Predictors of noninvasive ventilation tolerance in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Sci 2011; 303:114&#x2013;118.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Brien D, Stavroulakis T, Baxter S, et al. The optimisation of noninvasive ventilation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a systematic review. Eur Respir J 2019; 54:1900261 https://doi.org/10.1183/13993003.00261-2019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/13993003.00261-2019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dorst J, Ludolph AC. Non-invasive ventilation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ther Adv Neurol Disord 2019;12:1756286419857040. doi:10.1177/1756286419857040.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute for Health and Care Excellence. Motor Neurone Disease: Assessment and Management [Internet]. [London]: NICE; 2016 [updated 2019 Jul; cited 2021 Jun 16]. (NICE guideline [NG42]). Available from: https://www.nice.org.uk/guidance/ng42/resources/motor-neurone-disease-assessment-and-management-pdf-1837449470149 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garritty C, Gartlehner G, Nussbaumer-Streit B, et al. Cochrane Rapid Reviews Methods Group offers evidence-informed guidance to conduct rapid reviews. J Clin Epidemiol 2021; 130:13&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klavzar P, Koritnik B, Leonardis L, et al. Improvements in the multidisciplinary care are beneficial for survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS): experience from a tertiary ALS center. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2020; 21:203&#x2013;208.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hesters A, Amador MDM, Debs R, et al. Predictive factors for prognosis after gastrostomy placement in routine noninvasive ventilation users ALS patients. Scientific Rep 2020; 10:15117.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varley LP, Denieffe S, O&#x2019;Gorman C, et al. A systematic review of noninvasive and invasive sialorrhoea management. J Clin Nurs 2019; 28:4190&#x2013;4206.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim EY, Kang SW, Jung J, et al. Safety of gastrostomy tube placement in patients with advanced amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with noninvasive ventilation. J Parenter Enteral Nutr 2021; 45:1338&#x2013;1346.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ackrivo J, Hsu JY, Hansen-Flaschen J, et al. Noninvasive ventilation use is associated with better survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Am Thorac Soc 2021; 18:486&#x2013;494.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sancho J, Bur&#xe9;s E, Ferrer S, et al. Unstable control of breathing can lead to ineffective noninvasive ventilation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. ERJ Open Res 2019; 5:00099&#x2013;2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huynh W, Sharplin LE, Caga J, et al. Respiratory function and cognitive profile in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Eur J Neurol 2020; 27:685&#x2013;691.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khin Khin E, Minor D, Holloway A, et al. Decisional capacity in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Am Acad Psychiatry Law 2015; 43:210&#x2013;217.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thakore NJ, Lapin BR, Pioro EP, et al. Variation in noninvasive ventilation use in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology 2019; 93:e306&#x2013;e316.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panchabhai TS, Mireles Cabodevila E, Pioro EP, et al. Pattern of lung function decline in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: implications for timing of noninvasive ventilation. ERJ Open Res 2019; 5:00044&#x2013;2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cazzolli PA, Brooks BR, Nakayama Y, et al. The oral secretion scale and prognostic factors for survival in subjects with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Respir Care 2020; 65:1063&#x2013;1076.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russo M, Bonanno C, Profazio C, et al. Which are the factors influencing NIV adaptation and tolerance in ALS patients? Neurol Sci 2021; 42:1023&#x2013;1029.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rudnicki SA, Bian A, Cockroft BM, et al. Noninvasive ventilation use by patients enrolled in VITALITY-ALS. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2021; 1&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1080/21678421.2021.1904993.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/21678421.2021.1904993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sukockien&#x117; E, Iancu Ferfoglia R, Truffert A, et al. Multidisciplinary care in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a 4-year longitudinal observational study. Swiss Med Wkly 2020; 150:w20258.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ando H, Ashcroft-Kelso H, Halhead R, et al. Experience of telehealth in people with motor neurone disease using noninvasive ventilation. Disabil Rehabil Assist Technol 2021; 16:490&#x2013;496.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>