<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">34585427</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1521-1878</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>43</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BioEssays : news and reviews in molecular, cellular and developmental biology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Bioessays</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A beneficial role for elevated extracellular glutamate in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis and cerebral ischemia.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e2100127</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e2100127</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/bies.202100127</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This hypothesis proposes that increased extracellular glutamate in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis (ALS) and cerebral ischemia, currently viewed as a trigger for excitotoxicity, is actually beneficial as it stimulates the utilization of glutamate as metabolic fuel. Renewed appreciation of glutamate oxidation by ischemic neurons has raised questions regarding the role of extracellular glutamate in ischemia. Is it detrimental, as suggested by excitotoxicity in early in vitro studies, or beneficial, as suggested by its oxidation in later in vivo studies? The answer may depend on the activity of N-methyl-D-aspartate (NMDA) glutamate receptors. Early in vitro procedures co-activated NMDA receptors (NMDARs) containing 2A (GluN2A) and 2B (GluN2B) subunits, an event now believed to trigger excitotoxicity; however, during in vivo ischemia D-serine and zinc molecules are released and these ensure only GluN2B receptors are stimulated. This not only prevents excitotoxicity but also initiates signaling cascades that allow ischemic neurons to import and oxidize glutamate.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 The Authors. BioEssays published by Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schiel</LastName><ForeName>Kathryn A</ForeName><Initials>KA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5262-8762</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Apt B, Albuquerque, NM, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Bioessays</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8510851</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0265-9247</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D017470">Receptors, Glutamate</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D016194">Receptors, N-Methyl-D-Aspartate</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>3KX376GY7L</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D018698">Glutamic Acid</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002545" MajorTopicYN="Y">Brain Ischemia</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018698" MajorTopicYN="N">Glutamic Acid</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009474" MajorTopicYN="N">Neurons</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017470" MajorTopicYN="N">Receptors, Glutamate</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016194" MajorTopicYN="N">Receptors, N-Methyl-D-Aspartate</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ALS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cerebral</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">excitotoxicity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">glutamate</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ischemia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">receptor</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34585427</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/bies.202100127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Zarei, S., Carr, K., Reiley, L., Diaz, K., Guerra, O., Altamirano, P. F., Pagani, W., Lodin, D., Orozco, G., &amp; Chinea, A. (2015). A comprehensive review of Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. Surgical Neurology International, 6, 171.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kahl, A., Blanco, I., Jackman, K., Baskar, J., Milaganur Mohan, H., Rodney-Sandy, R., Zhang, S., Iadecola, C., &amp; Hochrainer, K. (2018). Cerebral ischemia induces the aggregation of proteins linked to neurodegenerative diseases. Scientific Reports, 8, 2701.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olmos, G., &amp; Llado, J. (2014). Tumor necrosis factor alpha: A link between neuroinflammation and excitotoxicity. Mediators of Inflammation, 2014, 1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith, E. F., Shaw, P. J., &amp; De Vos, K. J. (2019). The role of mitochondria in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuroscience Letters, 710, 132933.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anand, A., Thakur, K., &amp; Gupta, P. K. (2013). ALS and oxidative stress: The neurovascular scenario. Oxidative Medicine and Cellular Longevity, 2013, 1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Den Bosch, L., Van Damme, P., Bogaert, E., &amp; Robberecht, W. (2006). The role of excitotoxicity in the pathogenesis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Biochimica Et Biophysica Acta, 1762, 1068-1082.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armada-Moreira, A., Gomes, J. I., Pina, C. C., Savchak, O. K., Goncalves-Ribeiro, J., Rei, N., Pinto, S., Morais, T. P., Martins, R. S., Ribeiro, F. F., Sebastiao, A. M., Crunelli, V., &amp; Vaz, S. H. (2020). Going the extra (synaptic) mile: Excitotoxicity as the road toward neurodegenerative diseases. Frontiers in Cellular Neuroscience, 14, 90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker, D. A., Xi, Z. X., Shen, H., Swanson, C. J., &amp; Kalivas, P. W. (2002). The origin and neuronal function of in vivo nonsynaptic glutamate. Journal of Neuroscience, 22, 9134-9141.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pow, D. V. (2001). Visualising the activity of the cystine-glutamate antiporter in glial cells using antibodies to aminoadipic acid, a selectively transported substrate. Glia, 34, 27-38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bannai, S. (1986). Exchange of cystine and glutamate across plasma membrane of human fibroblasts. Journal of Biological Chemistry, 261, 2256-2263.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pajarillo, E., Rizor, A., Lee, J., Aschner, M., &amp; Lee, E. (2019). The role of astrocytic glutamate transporters GLT-1 and GLAST in neurological disorders: Potential targets for neurotherapeutics. Neuropharamacology, 161, 107559.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coco, S., Verderio, C., Trotti, D., Rothstein, J. D., Volterra, A., &amp; Matteoli, M. (1997). Non-synaptic localization of glutamate transporter EAAC1 in cultured hippocampal neurons. European Journal of Neuroscience, 9, 1902-1910.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martinez-Lozada, Z., Guillem, A. M., Flores-Mendez, M., Hernandez-Kelly, L. C., Vela, C., Meza, E., Zepeda, R. C., Caba, M., Rodriguez, A., &amp; Ortega, A. (2013). GLAST/EAAT1-induced glutamine release via SNAT3 in Bergmann glial cells: Evidence of a functional and physical coupling. Journal of Neurochemistry, 125, 545-554.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tani, H., Dulla, C. G., Farzampour, Z., Taylor-Weiner, A., Huguenard, J. R., &amp; Reimer, R. J. (2014). A local glutamate-glutamine cycle sustains synaptic excitatory transmitter release. Neuron, 81, 888-900.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rothstein, J. D., Van Kammen, M., Levey, A. I., Martin, L. J., &amp; Kuncl, R. W. (1995). Selective loss of glial glutamate transporter GLT-1 in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Annals of Neurology, 38, 73-84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuster, C., Kasper, E., Machts, J., Bittner, D., Kaufmann, J., Benecke, R., Teipel, S., Vielhaber, S., &amp; Prudlo, J. (2014). Longitudinal course of cortical thickness decline in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Journal of Neurology, 261, 1871-1880.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agosta, F., Valsasina, P., Riva, N., Copetti, M., Messina, M. J., Prelle, A., Comi, G., &amp; Filippi, M. (2012). The cortical signature of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. PLoS ONE, 7, e42816.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thorns, J., Jansma, H., Peschel, T., Grosskreutz, J., Mohammadi, B., Dengler, R., &amp; Munte, T. F. (2013). Extent of cortical involvement in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-an analysis based on cortical thickness. Bmc Neurology [Electronic Resource], 13, 148.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>El Mendili, M. M., Cohen-Adad, J., Pelegrini-Issac, M., Rossignol, S., Morizot-Koutlidis, R., Marchand-Pauvert, V., Iglesias, C., Sangari, S., Katz, R., &amp; Lehericy, S., Benali, H., &amp; Pradat, P. F. (2014). Multi-parametric spinal cord MRI as potential progression marker in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. PLoS ONE, 9, e95516.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimada, N., Graf, R., Rosner, G., Wakayama, A., George, C. P., &amp; Heiss, W. D. (1989). Ischemic flow threshold for extracellular glutamate increase in cat cortex. Journal of Cerebral Blood Flow and Metabolism, 9, 603-606.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caragine, L. P., Park, H. K., Diaz, F. G., &amp; Phillis, J. W. (1998). Real-time measurement of ischemia-evoked glutamate release in the cerebral cortex of four and eleven vessel rat occlusion models. Brain Research, 793, 255-264.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michaels, R. L., &amp; Rothman, S. M. (1990). Glutamate neurotoxicity in vitro: Antagonist pharmacology and intracellular calcium concentrations. Journal of Neuroscience, 10, 283-292.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solar, P., Zamani, A., Kubickova, L., Dubovy, P., &amp; Joukal, M. (2020). Choroid plexus and the brain-cerebrospinal fluid barrier in disease. Fluids Barriers CNS, 17, 35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khasawneh, A. H., Garling, R. J., &amp; Harris, C. A. (2018). Cerebrospinal fluid circulation: What do we know and how do we know it? Brain Circulation, 4, 14-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pollay, M. (2010).The function and structure of the cerebrospinal fluid outflow system. Cerebrospinal Fluid Research, 7, 9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martins, A. N. (1973). Resistance to drainage of cerebrospinal fluid: Clinical measurement and significance. Journal of Neurology, Neurosurgery and Psychiatry, 36, 313-318.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Massicotte, E. M., &amp; Del Bigio, M. R. (1999). Human arachnoid villi response to subarachnoid hemorrhage: Possible relationship to chronic hydrocephalus. Journal of Neurosurgery, 91, 80-84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janny, P., Chazal, J., Colnet, G., Irthum, B., &amp; Georget, A. M. (1981). Benign intracranial hypertension and disorders of CSF absorption. Surgical Neurology, 15, 168-174.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellis, C. M., Suckling, J., Amaro, E., Jr., Bullmore, E. T., Simmons, A., Williams, S. C., &amp; Leigh, P. N. (2001). Volumetric analysis reveals corticospinal tract degeneration and extramotor involvement in ALS. Neurology, 57, 1571-1578.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westeneng, H. J., Verstraete, E., Walhout, R., Schmidt, R., Hendrikse, J., Veldink, J. H., van den Heuvel, M. P., &amp; van den Berg, L. H. (2015). Subcortical structures in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurobiology of Aging, 36, 1075-1082.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williamson, M. R., &amp; Colbourne, F. (2017). Evidence for decreased brain parenchymal volume after large intracerebral hemorrhages: A potential mechanism limiting intracranial pressure rises. Translational Stroke Research, 8, 386-396.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeh, T. Y., Tseng, G. F., Tseng, C. Y., Huang, Y. H., &amp; Liu, P. H. (2017). Effects of epidural compression on stellate neurons and thalamocortical afferent fibers in the rat primary somatosensory cortex. Acta Neurobiologiae Experimentalis (Wars), 77, 1-17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, J. R., Wang, Y. J., &amp; Tseng, G. F. (2003). The effect of epidural compression on cerebral cortex: A rat model. Journal of Neurotrauma, 20, 767-780.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiernan, J. A., &amp; Hudson, A. J. (1991). Changes in sizes of cortical and lower motor neurons in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain, 114, 843-853.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Genc, B., Jara, J. H., Lagrimas, A. K., Pytel, P., Roos, R. P., Mesulam, M. M., Geula, C., Bigio, E. H., &amp; Ozdinier, P. H. (2017). Apical dendrite degeration, a novel cellular pathology for Betz cells in ALS. Scientific Reports, 7, 41765.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jara, J. H., Gautam, M., Kocak, N., Xie, E. F., Mao, Q., Bigio, E. H., &amp; Ozdinier, P. H. (2019). MCP1-CCR2 and neuroinflammation in the ALS motor cortex with TDP-43 pathology. Journal of Neuroinflammation, 16, 196.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakano, I., &amp; Hirano, A. (1987). Atrophic cell processes of large motor neurons in the anterior horn in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Observation with silver impregnation method. Journal of Neuropathology and Experimental Neurology, 46, 40-49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kato, T., Hirano, A., &amp; Donnenfeld, H. (1987). A Golgi study of the large anterior horn cells of the lumbar cords in normal spinal cords and in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathologica, 75, 34-40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nihei, K., McKee, A. C., &amp; Kowall, N. W. (1993). Patterns of neuronal degeneration in the motor cortex of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. Acta Neuropathologica, 86, 55-64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kihira, T., Yoshida, S., Yoshimasu, F., Wakayama, I., &amp; Yase, Y. (1997). Involvement of Onuf's nucleus in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Journal of the Neurological Sciences, 147, 81-88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen, D. C., Xu, Y. Y., Hou, B., Tai, H. F., Zhang, K., Liu, S. W., Wang, Z. L., Feng, F., Liu, M. S., &amp; Cui, L. Y. (2018). Monitoring value of multimodal magnetic resonance imaging in disease progression of Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis: A prospective observational study. Chinese Medical Journal, 131, 2904-2909.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rule, R. R., Schuff, N., Miller, R. G., &amp; Weiner, M. W. (2010). Gray matter perfusion correlates with disease severity in ALS. Neurology, 74, 821-827.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy, M. J., Grace, G. M., Tartaglia, M. C., Orange, J. B., Chen, X., Rowe, A., Findlater, K., Kozak, R. I., Freedman, M., Lee, T. Y., &amp; Strong, M. J. (2012). Widespread cerebral haemodynamics disturbances occur early in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler, 13, 202-209.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, J. M., Song, X. J., &amp; LaMotte, R. H. (1999). Enhanced excitability of sensory neurons in rats with cutaneous hyperalgesia produced by chronic compression of the dorsal root ganglion. Journal of Neurophysiology, 82, 3359-3366.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Y., Cai, G., Ni, X., &amp; Sun, J. (2007). The role of ERK activation in the neuronal excitability in the chronically compressed dorsal root ganglia. Neuroscience Letters, 153-157, 419, 153-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zanette, G., Tamburin, S., Manganotti, P., Refatti, N., Forgione, A., &amp; Rizzuto, N. (2002). Different mechanisms contribute to motor cortex hyperexcitability in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clinical Neurophysiology, 113, 1688-1697.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mills, K. R., &amp; Nithi, K. A. (1997). Corticomotor threshold is reduced in early sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle &amp; Nerve, 20, 1137-1141.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, M. C., Nam, T. S., Jung, S. J., Gwak, Y. S., &amp; Leem, J. W. (2015). Modulation of spinal GABAergic inhibition and mechanical hypersensitivity following chronic compression of dorsal root ganglion in the rat. Neural Plasticity, 2015, 1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foerster, B. R., Callaghan, B. C., Petrou, M., Edden, R. A., Chenevert, T. L., &amp; Feldman, E. L. (2012). Decreased motor cortex &#x3b3;-aminobutyric acid in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology, 78, 1596-1600.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faraco, G., Fossati, S., Bianchi, M. E., Patrone, M., Pedrazzi, M., Sparatore, B., Moroni, F., &amp; Chiarugi, A. (2007). High mobility group box 1 protein is released by neural cells upon different stresses and worsens ischemic neurodegeneration in vitro and in vivo. Journal of Neurochemistry, 103, 590-603.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, X., Zhang, J., Kim, B., Jaitpal, S., Meng, S. S., Adjepong, K., Imamura, S., Wake, H., Nishibori, M., Stopa, E. G., &amp; Stonestreet, B. S. (2019). High-mobility group box-1 translocation and release after hypoxic ischemic brain injury in neonatal rats. Experimental Neurology, 311, 1-14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, X., Wu, S., Chen, C., Xie, B., Fang, Z., Hu, W., Chen, J., Fu, H., &amp; He, H. (2017). Omega-3 polyunsaturated fatty acid supplementation attenuates microglial-induced inflammation by inhibiting the HMGB1/TLR4/NFkB pathway following experimental traumatic brain injury. Journal of Neuroinflammation, 14, 143.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, X. X., Wang, C., Huang, S. F., Chen, Q., Hu, Y. F., Zhou, L., &amp; Gu, Y. (2016). Regnase -1 in microglia negatively regulates high mobility group box 1-mediated inflammation and neuronal injury. Scientific Reports, 6, 24073.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackman, N. A., Uliasz, T. F., Hewett, J. A., &amp; Hewett, S. J. (2010). Regulation of system x(c)(-) activity and expression in astrocytes by interleukin-1B: Implications for hypoxic neuronal injury. Glia, 58, 1806-1815.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fogal, B., Li, J., Lobner, D., McCullough, L. D., &amp; Hewett, S. J. (2007). System x(c)- activity and astrocytes are necessary for interleukin-1 beta-mediated hypoxic neuronal injury. Journal of Neuroscience, 27, 10094-10105.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su, Z. Z., Leszczyniecka, M., Kang, D. C., Sarkar, D., Chao, W., Volsky, D. J., &amp; Fisher, P. B. (2003). Insights into glutamate transport regulation in human astrocytes: Cloning of the promoter for excitatory amino acid transporter 2 (EAAT2). PNAS, 100, 1955-1960.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sitcheran, R., Gupta, P., Fisher, P. B., &amp; Baldwin, A. S. (2005). Positive and negative regulation of EAAT2 by NF-kappaB: A role for N-myc in TNFalpha-controlled repression. Embo Journal, 24, 510-520.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rothstein, J. D., Martin, L. J., &amp; Kuncl, R. W. (1992). Decreased glutamate transport by the brain and spinal cord in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. New England Journal of Medicine, 326, 1464-1468.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hwang, C. S., Liu, G. T., Chang, M. D., Liao, I. L., &amp; Chang, H. T. (2013). Elevated serum autoantibody against high mobility group box 1 as a potent surrogate biomarker for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurobiology of Disease, 58, 13-18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cereda, C., Baiocchi, C., Bongioanni, P., Cova, E., Guareschi, S., Metelli, M. R., Rossi, B., Sbalsi, I., Cuccia, M. C., &amp; Ceroni, M. (2008). TNF and sTNFR1/2 plasma levels in ALS patients. Journal of Neuroimmunology, 194, 123-131.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brohawn, D. G., O'Brien, L. C., &amp; Bennett, J. P., Jr. (2016). RNAseq analyses identify tumor necrosis factor - mediated inflammation as a major abnormality in ALS spinal cord. PLoS ONE, 11, e0160520.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corcia, P., Tauber, C., Vercoullie, J., Arlicot, N., Prunier, C., Praline, J., Nicolas, G., Venel, Y., Hommet, C., Baulier, J. L., Cottier, J. P., Roussel, C., Kassiou, M., Guilloteau, D., &amp; Ribeiro, M. J., (2012). Molecular imaging of microglial activation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. PLoS ONE, 7, e52941</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kazama, M., Kato, Y., Kakita, A., Noguchi, N., Urano, Y., Masui, K., Niida-Kawaguchi, M., Yamamoto, T., Watabe, K., Kitagawa, K., &amp; Shibata, N. (2020). Astrocytes release glutamate via cystine/glutamate antiporter upregulated in response to increased oxidative stress related to sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuropathology, 40, 587-598.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, Q. W., Wang, J. Z., Li, J. C., Zhou, Y., Zhong, Q., Lu, F. L., &amp; Xiang, J. (2010). High-mobility group protein box-1 and its relevance to cerebral ischemia. Journal of Cerebral Blood Flow and Metabolism, 30, 243-254.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lambertsen, K. L., Biber, K., &amp; Finsen, B. (2012). Inflammatory cytokines in experimental and human stroke. Journal of Cerebral Blood Flow and Metabolism, 32, 1677-1698.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soria, F. N., Perez-Samartin, A., Martin, A., Gona, K. B., Llop, J., Szczupak, B., Chara, J. C., Matute, C., &amp; Domercq, M. (2014). Extrasynaptic glutamate release through cystine/glutamate antiporter contributes to ischemic damage. Journal of Clinical Investigation, 124, 3645-3655.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haslam, R. J., &amp; Krebs, H. A. (1963). The metabolism of glutamate in homogenates and slices of brain cortex. Biochemical Journal, 88, 566-578.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rink, C., Gnyawali, S., Stewart, R., Teplitsky, S., Harris, H., Roy, S., Sen, C. K., &amp; Khanna, S. (2017). Glutamate oxaloacetate transaminase enables anapleurotic refilling of TCA cycle intermediates in stroke-affected brain. Faseb Journal, 31, 1709-1718.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rink, C., Gnyawali, S., Peterson, L., &amp; Khanna, S. (2011). Oxygen-inducible glutamate oxaloacetate transaminase as protective switch transforming neurotoxic glutamate to metabolic fuel during acute ischemic stroke. Antioxid Redox Signaling, 14, 1777-1785.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piccirillo, S., Castaldo, P., Macri, M. L., Amoroso, S., &amp; Magi, S. (2018). Glutamate as a potential &#x201c;survival factor&#x201d; in an in vitro model of neuronal hypoxia/reoxygenation injury: Leading role of the Na+/Ca2+ exchanger. Cell Death &amp; Disease., 9, 731.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Traynelis, S. F., Wollmuth, L. P., McBain, C. J., Menniti, F. S., Vance, K. M., Ogden, K. K., Hansen, K. B., Yuan, H., Myers, S. J., &amp; Dingledine, R., (2010). Glutamate receptor ion channels: Structure, regulation, and function. Pharmacological Reviews, 62, 405-496</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greger, I. H., Watson, J. F., &amp; Cull-Candy, S. G. (2017). Structural and functional architecture of AMPA-type glutamate receptors and their auxiliary proteins. Neuron, 94, 713-730.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joshi, D. C., Singh, M., Krishnamurthy, K., Joshi, P. G., &amp; Joshi, N. B. (2011). AMPA induced Ca2+ influx in motor neurons occurs through voltage gated Ca2+ channel and Ca2+ permeable AMPA receptor. Neurochemistry International, 59, 913-921.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pal, B. (2018). Involvement of extrasynaptic glutamate in physiological and pathophysiological changes of neuronal excitability. Cellular and Molecular Life Sciences, 75, 2917-2949.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scimemi, A., Fine, A., Kullmann, D. M., &amp; Rusakov, D. A. (2004). NR2B-containing receptors mediate cross talk among hippocampal synapses. Journal of Neuroscience, 24, 4767-4777.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leonoudakis, D., Zhao, P., &amp; Beattie, E. C. (2008). Rapid tumor necrosis factor alpha-induced exocytosis of glutamate receptor 2-lacking AMPA receptors to extrasynaptic plasma membrane potentiates excitotoxicity. Journal of Neuroscience, 28, 2119-2130.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stellwagen, D., Beattie, E. C., Seo, J. Y., &amp; Malenka, R. C. (2005). Differential regulation of AMPA receptor and GABA receptor trafficking by tumor necrosis factor-alpha. Journal of Neuroscience, 25, 3219-3228.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, S., Uno, Y., Rudolph, U., Cobb, J., Liu, J., Anderson, T., Levy, D., Balu, D. T., &amp; Coyle, J. T. (2018). Astrocytes in primary cultures express serine racemase, synthesize d-serine and acquire A1 reactive astrocyte features. Biochemical Pharmacology, 151, 245-251.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perez, E. J., Tapanes, S. A., Loris, Z. B., Balu, D. T., Sick, T. J., Coyle, J. T., &amp; Liebl, D. J. (2017). Enhanced astrocytic d-serine underlies synaptic damage after traumatic brain injury. Journal of Clinical Investigation, 127, 3114-3125.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, X., Zhang, Y. Y., Chen, Z. Q., Jiang, Z. L., Sun, L., Xu, L. H., Yang, Y., &amp; Zhang, Y. F. (2014). D-serine-induced inactivation of NMDA receptors in cultured rat hippocampal neurons expressing NR2A subunits is Ca2+ -dependent. CNS Neuroscience &amp; Therapeutics, 20, 951-960.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kitamura, Y., Iida, Y., Abe, J., Mifune, M., Kasuya, F., Ohta, M., Igarashi, K., Saito, Y., &amp; Saji, H. (2006). In vivo measurement of presynaptic Zn2+ release during forebrain ischemia in rats. Biological &amp; Pharmaceutical Bulletin, 29, 821-823.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, N., Moshaver, A., &amp; Raymond, L. A. (1997). Differential sensitivity of recombinant N-methyl-D-aspartate receptor subtypes to zinc inhibition. Molecular Pharmacology, 51, 1015-1023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erreger, K., &amp; Traynelis, S. F. (2008). Zinc inhibition of rat NR1/NR2A N-methyl-D-aspartate receptors. Journal of Physiology, 586, 763-778.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rachline, J., Perin-Dureau, F., Le Goff, A., Neyton, J., &amp; Paoletti, P. (2005). The micromolar zinc-binding domain on the NMDA receptor subunit NR2B. Journal of Neuroscience, 25, 308-317.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sasabe, J., Chiba, T., Yamada, M., Okamoto, K., Nishimoto, I., Matsuoka, M., &amp; Aiso, S. (2007). D-serine is a key determinant of glutamate toxicity in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Embo Journal, 26, 4149-4159.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fuchs, S. A., Peeters-Scholte, C. M., de Barse, M. M., Roeleveld, M. W., Klomp, L. W., Berger, R., &amp; de Koning, T. J. (2012). Increased concentrations of both NMDA receptor co-agonists D-serine and glycine in global ischemia: A potential novel treatment target for perinatal asphyxia. Amino Acids, 43, 355-363.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rameau, G. A., Chiu, L. Y., &amp; Ziff, E. B. (2004). Bidirectional regulation of neuronal nitric-oxide synthase phosphorylation at serine 847 by the N-methyl-D-aspartate receptor. Journal of Biological Chemistry, 279, 14307-14314.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Francis, S. H., Busch, J. L., Corbin, J. D., &amp; Sibley, D. (2010). cGMP-dependent protein kinases and cGMP phosphodiesterases in nitric oxide and cGMP action. Pharmacological Reviews, 62, 525-563.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ha, K. S., Kim, K. M., Kwon, Y. G., Bai, S. K., Nam, W. D., Yoo, Y. M., Kim, P. K., Chung, H. T., Billiar, T. R., &amp; Kim, Y. M. (2003). Nitric oxide prevents 6-hydroxydopamine-induced apoptosis in PC12 cells through cGMP-dependent PI3 kinase/Akt activation. Faseb Journal, 17, 1036-1047.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mejia-Garcia, T. A., Portugal, C. C., Encarnacao, T. G., Prado, M. A., &amp; Paes-de-Carvalho, R. (2013). Nitric oxide regulates AKT phosphorylation and nuclear translocation in cultured retinal cells. Cellular Signalling, 25, 2424-2439.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Datta, K., Bellacosa, A., Chan, T. O., &amp; Tsichlis, P. N. (1996). Akt is a direct target of the phosphatidylinositol 3-kinase. Activation by growth factors, v-src and v-Ha-ras in Sf9 and mammalian cells. Journal of Biological Chemistry, 271, 30835-30839.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sasaki, S., Shibata, N., &amp; Iwata, M. (2001). Neuronal nitric oxide synthase immunoreactivity in the spinal cord in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathologica, 101, 351-357.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kashiwado, K., Yoshiyama, Y., Arai, K., &amp; Hattori, T. (2002). Expression of nitric oxide synthases in the anterior horn cells of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Progress in Neuro-Psychopharmacology &amp; Biological Psychiatry, 26, 163-167.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagey, R., Pelech, S. L., Duronio, V., &amp; Krieger, C. (1998). Phosphatidylinositol 3-kinase: Increased activity and protein level in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Journal of Neurochemistry, 71, 716-722.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitra, J., Hegde, P. M., &amp; Hegde, M. L. (2019). Loss of endosomal recycling factor RAB11 coupled with complex regulation of MAPK/ERK/AKT signaling in postmortem spinal cord specimens of sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. Mol Brain, 12, 55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eliasson, M. J., Huang, Z., Ferrante, R. J., Sasamata, M., Molliver, M. E., Snyder, S. H., &amp; Moskowitz, M. A. (1999). Neuronal nitric oxide synthase activation and peroxynitrite formation in ischemic stroke linked to neural damage. Journal of Neuroscience, 19, 5910-5918.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, J., Du, T., Li, B., Rong, Y., Verkhratsky, A., &amp; Peng, L. (2015). Crosstalk between MAPK/ERK and PI3K/AKT signal pathways during brain ischemia/reperfusion. ASN Neuro, 7, 175909141560246.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang, X., Tian, F., Mearow, K., Okagaki, P., Lipsky, R. H., &amp; Marini, A. M. (2005). The excitoprotective effect of N-methyl-D-aspartate receptors is mediated by a brain-derived neurotrophic factor autocrine loop in cultured hippocampal neurons. Journal of Neurochemistry, 94, 713-722.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tecuatl, C., Herrrera-Lopez, G., Martin-Avila, A., Yin, B., Weber, S., Barrionuevo, G., &amp; Galvan, E. J. (2018). TrkB-mediated activation of the phosphatidylinositol-3-kinase/Akt cascade reduces the damage inflicted by oxygen-glucose deprivation in area CA3 of the rat hippocampus. European Journal of Neuroscience, 47, 1096-1109.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, C. H., Chen, C. C., Hung, T. H., Chuang, Y. C., Chao, M., Shyue, S. K., &amp; Chen, S. F. (2019). Activation of TrkB/Akt signaling by a TrkB receptor agonist improves long-term histological and functional outcomes in experimental intracerebral hemorrhage. Journal of Biomedical Science, 26, 53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seeburger, J. L., Tarras, S., Natter, H., &amp; Springer, J. E. (1993). Spinal cord motoneurons express p75NGFR and p145trkB mRNA in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain Research, 621, 111-115.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mutoh, T., Sobue, G., Hamano, T., Kuriyama, M., Hirayama, M., Yamamoto, M., &amp; Mitsuma, T. (2000). Decreased phosphorylation levels of TrkB neurotrophin receptor in the spinal cords from patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurochemical Research, 25, 239-245.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pradhan, J., Noakes, P. G., &amp; Bellingham, M. C. (2019). The role of altered BDNF/TrkB signaling in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. Frontiers in Cell Neuroscience, 13, 368.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jourdi, H., Hsu, Y. T., Zhou, M., Qin, Q., Bi, X., &amp; Baudry, M. (2009). Positive AMPA receptor modulation rapidly stimulates BDNF release and increases dendritic mRNA translation. Journal of Neuroscience, 29, 8688-8697.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, H. H., Lee, K. H., Lee, D., Han, Y. E., Lee, S. H., Sohn, J. W., &amp; Ho, W. K. (2015). Costimulation of AMPA and metabotropic glutamate receptors underlies phospholipase C activation by glutamate in hippocampus. Journal of Neuroscience, 35, 6401-6412.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scartabelli, T., Gerace, E., Landucci, E., Moroni, F., &amp; Pellegrini-Giampietro, D. E. (2008). Neuroprotection by group I mGlu receptors in a rat hippocampal slice model of cerebral ischemia is associated with the PI3K-Akt signaling pathway: A novel postconditioning strategy? Neuropharmacology, 55, 509-516.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, T., Zhang, L., Qu, Y., Huo, K., Jiang, X., &amp; Fei, Z. (2012). The selective mGluR5 agonist CHPG protects against traumatic brain injury in vitro and in vivo via ERK and Akt pathway. International Journal of Molecular Medicine, 29, 630-636.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muller Herde, A., Schibli, R., Weber, M., &amp; Ametamey, S. M. (2019). Metabotropic glutamate receptor subtype 5 is altered in LPS-induced murine neuroinflammation model and in the brains of AD and ALS patients. European Journal of Nuclear Medicine and Molecular Imaging, 46, 407-420.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strack, S., &amp; Colbran, R. J. (1998). Autophosphorylation-dependent targeting of calcium/calmodulin-dependent protein kinase II by the NR2B subunit of the N-methyl-D-aspartate receptor. Journal of Biological Chemistry, 273, 20689-20692.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, W. K., Choi, Y. B., Rayudu, P. V., Das, P., Asaad, W., Arnelle, D. R., Stamler, J. S., &amp; Lipton, S. A. (1999). Attenuation of NMDA receptor activity and neurotoxicity by nitroxyl anion. NO&#x2212;. Neuron, 24, 461-469.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krizman-Genda, E., Gonzalez, M. I., Zelenaia, O., &amp; Robinson, M. B. (2005). Evidence that Akt mediates platelet-derived growth factor-dependent increases in activity and surface expression of the neuronal glutamate transporter, EAAC1. Neuropharmacology, 49, 872-882.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du, K., &amp; Montminy, M. (1998). CREB is a regulatory target for the protein kinase Akt/PKB. Journal of Biological Chemistry, 273, 32377-32379.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menga, A., Iacobazzi, V., Infantino, V., Avantaggiati, M. L., &amp; Palmieri, F. (2015). The mitochondrial aspartate/glutamate carrier isoform 1 gene expression is regulated by CREB in neuronal cells. International Journal of Biochemistry &amp; Cell Biology, 60, 157-166.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amoedo, N. D., Punzi, G., Obre, E., Lacombe, D., De Grassi, A., Pierri, C. L., &amp; Rossignol, R. (2016). AGC1/2, the mitochondrial aspartate-glutamate carriers. Biochimica Et Biophysica Acta, 1863, 2394-2412.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thangaratnarajah, C., Ruprecht, J. J., &amp; Kunji, E. R. (2014). Calcium-induced conformational changes of the regulatory domain of human mitochondrial aspartate/glutamate carriers. Nature Communications, 5, 5491.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pardo, B., Contreras, L., Serrano, A., Ramos, M., Kobayashi, K., Iijima, M., Saheki, T., &amp; Satrustegui, J. (2006). Essential role of aralar in the transduction of small Ca2+ signals to neuronal mitochondria. Journal of Biological Chemistry, 281, 1039-1047.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gellerich, F. N., Gizatullina, Z., Arandarcikaite, O., Jerzembek, D., Vielhaber, S., Seppet, E., &amp; Striggow, F. (2009). Extramitochondrial Ca2+ in the nanomolar range regulates glutamate-dependent oxidative phosphorylation on demand. PLoS ONE, 4, e8181.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bijur, G. N., &amp; Jope, R. S. (2003). Rapid accumulation of Akt in mitochondria following phosphatidylinositol 3-kinase activation. Journal of Neurochemistry, 87, 1427-1435.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chae, Y. C., Vaira, V., Caino, M. C., Tang, H. Y., Seo, J. H., Kossenkov, A. V., Ottobrini, L., Martelli, C., Lucignani, G., Bertolini, I., Locatelli, M., Bryant, K. B., Ghosh, J. C., Lisanti, S., Ku, B., Bosari, S., Languino, L. R., Speicher, D. W., &amp; Altieri, D. C. (2016). Mitochondrial Akt regulation of hypoxic tumor reprogramming. Cancer Cell, 30, 257-272.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Champe, P. C., &amp; Harvey, R. A. (1994). Lippincott's illustrated reviews: Biochemistry (2nd ed., p. 443), Lippincott-Raven.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Denton, R. M., Randle, P. J., &amp; Martin, B. R. (1972). Stimulation by calcium ions of pyruvate dehydrogenase phosphate phosphatase. Biochemical Journal, 128, 161-163.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szado, T., Vanderheyden, V., Parys, J. B., De Smedt, H., Rietdorf, K., Kotelevets, L., Chastre, E., Khan, F., Landegren, U., Soderberg, O., Bootman, M. D., &amp; Roderick, H. L. (2008). Phosphorylation of inositol 1,4,5-trisphophate receptors by protein kinase B/Akt inhibits Ca2+ release and apoptosis. PNAS, 105, 2427-2432.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marchi, S., Marinello, M., Bononi, A., Bonora, M., Giorgi, C., Rimessi, A., &amp; Pinton, P. (2012). Selective modulation of subtype III IP3R by Akt regulates ER Ca2+ release and apoptosis. Cell Death &amp; Disease, 3, e304.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gottlieb, M., Domercq, M., &amp; Matute, C. (2000). Altered expression of the glutamate transporter EAAC1 in neurons and immature oligodendrocytes after transient forebrain ischemia. Journal of Cerebral Blood Flow and Metabolism, 20, 678-687.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sapir, G., Shaul, D., Lev-Cohain, N., Sosna, J., Gomori, M. J., &amp; Katz-Brull, R. (2021). LDH and PDH activities in the ischemic brain and the effect of reperfusion - An ex vivo MR study in rat brain slices using hyperpolarized, [ 1-13C] Pyruvate. Metabolites, 11, 210.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shih, A. Y., Erb, H., Sun, X., Toda, S., Kalivas, P. W., &amp; Murphy, T. H. (2006). Cystine/glutamate exchange modulates glutathione supply for neuroprotection from oxidative stress and cell proliferation. Journal of Neuroscience, 26, 10514-10523.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banjac, A., Perisic, T., Sato, H., Seiler, A., Bannai, S., Weiss, N., Kolle, P., Tschoep, K., Issels, R. D., Daniel, P. T., Conrad, M., &amp; Bornkamm, G. W. (2008). The cystine/cysteine cycle: A redox cycle regulating susceptibility versus resistance to cell death. Oncogene, 27, 1618-1628.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dringen, R., Pfeiffer, B., &amp; Hamprecht, B. (1999). Synthesis of the antioxidant glutathione in neurons: Supply by astrocytes of CysGly as precursor for neuronal glutathione. Journal of Neuroscience, 19, 562-569.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dringen, R., Gutterer, J. M., Gros, C., &amp; Hirrlinger, J. (2001). Aminopeptidase N mediates the utilization of GSH precursor CysGly by cultured neurons. Journal of Neuroscience Research, 66, 1003-1008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Himi, T., Ikeda, M., Yasuhara, T., Nishida, M., &amp; Morita, I. (2003). Role of neuronal glutamate transporter in the cysteine uptake and intracellular glutathione levels in cultured cortical neurons. Journal of Neural Transmission (Vienna), 110, 1337-1348.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bannai, S., &amp; Kitamura, E. (1980). Transport interaction of L-cystine and L-glutamate in human diploid fibroblasts in culture. Journal of Biological Chemistry, 255, 2372-2376.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schubert, D., &amp; Piasecki, D. (2001). Oxidative glutamate toxicity can be a component of the excitotoxicity cascade. Journal of Neuroscience, 21, 7455-7462.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewerenz, J., Klein, M., &amp; Methner, A. (2006). Cooperative action of glutamate transporters and cystine/glutamate antiporter sys Xc&#x2212; protects from oxidative glutamate toxicity. Journal of Neurochemistry, 98, 916-925.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Y., Wong, T. P., Aarts, M., Rooyakkers, A., Liu, L., Lai, T. W., Wu, D. C., Lu, J., Tymianski, M., Craig, A. M., &amp; Wang, Y. T. (2007). NMDA receptor subunits have differential roles in mediating excitotoxic neuronal death both in vitro and in vivo. Journal of Neuroscience, 27, 2846-2857.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, X., Hollern, D., Liao, J., Andrechek, E., &amp; Wang, H. (2013). NMDA receptor-mediated excitotoxicity depends on the coactivation of synaptic and extrasynaptic receptors. Cell Death &amp; Disease, 4, e560.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>