<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">34624328</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1090-2430</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>347</Volume><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Experimental neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Exp Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Acute intermittent hypoxia and respiratory muscle recruitment in people with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A preliminary study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>113890</StartPage><MedlinePgn>113890</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.expneurol.2021.113890</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0014-4886(21)00298-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Respiratory failure is the main cause of death in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). Since no effective treatments to preserve independent breathing are available, there is a critical need for new therapies to preserve or restore breathing ability. Since acute intermittent hypoxia (AIH) elicits spinal respiratory motor plasticity in rodent ALS models, and may restore breathing ability in people with ALS, we performed a proof-of-principle study to investigate this possibility in ALS patients. Quiet breathing, sniff nasal inspiratory pressure (SNIP) and maximal inspiratory pressure (MIP) were tested in 13 persons with ALS and 10 age-matched controls, before and 60&#xa0;min post-AIH (15, 1&#xa0;min episodes of 10% O<sub>2</sub>, 2&#xa0;min normoxic intervals) or sham AIH (continuous normoxia). The root mean square (RMS) of the right and left diaphragm, 2nd parasternal, scalene and sternocleidomastoid muscles were monitored. A vector analysis was used to calculate summated vector magnitude (Mag) and similarity index (SI) of collective EMG activity during quiet breathing, SNIP and MIP maneuvers. AIH facilitated tidal volume and minute ventilation (treatment main effects: p&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;0.05), and Mag (ie. collective respiratory muscle activity; p&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;0.001) during quiet breathing in ALS and control subjects, but there was no effect on SI during quiet breathing. SNIP SI decreased in both groups post-AIH (p&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;0.005), whereas Mag was unchanged (p&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.09). No differences were observed in SNIP or MIP post AIH in either group. Discomfort was not reported during AIH by any subject, nor were adverse events observed. Thus, AIH may be a safe way to increase collective inspiratory muscle activity during quiet breathing in ALS patients, although a single AIH presentation was not sufficient to significantly increase peak inspiratory pressure generation. These preliminary results provide evidence that AIH may improve breathing function in people with ALS, and that future studies of prolonged, repetitive AIH protocols are warranted.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2021. Published by Elsevier Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sajjadi</LastName><ForeName>Elaheh</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Breathing Research and Therapeutics Center, University of Florida, Gainesville, FL 32610, USA; McKnight Brain Institute, University of Florida, Gainesville, FL 32610, USA; Department of Physical Therapy, University of Florida, Gainesville, FL 32610, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Seven</LastName><ForeName>Yasin B</ForeName><Initials>YB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Breathing Research and Therapeutics Center, University of Florida, Gainesville, FL 32610, USA; McKnight Brain Institute, University of Florida, Gainesville, FL 32610, USA; Department of Physical Therapy, University of Florida, Gainesville, FL 32610, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ehrbar</LastName><ForeName>Jessica G</ForeName><Initials>JG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy, University of Florida, Gainesville, FL 32610, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wymer</LastName><ForeName>James P</ForeName><Initials>JP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Breathing Research and Therapeutics Center, University of Florida, Gainesville, FL 32610, USA; McKnight Brain Institute, University of Florida, Gainesville, FL 32610, USA; Neurology, University of Florida, Gainesville, FL 32610, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mitchell</LastName><ForeName>Gordon S</ForeName><Initials>GS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Breathing Research and Therapeutics Center, University of Florida, Gainesville, FL 32610, USA; McKnight Brain Institute, University of Florida, Gainesville, FL 32610, USA; Department of Physical Therapy, University of Florida, Gainesville, FL 32610, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Smith</LastName><ForeName>Barbara K</ForeName><Initials>BK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Breathing Research and Therapeutics Center, University of Florida, Gainesville, FL 32610, USA; Department of Physical Therapy, University of Florida, Gainesville, FL 32610, USA; Pediatrics, University of Florida, Gainesville, FL 32610, USA. Electronic address: bksmith@phhp.ufl.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>UL1 TR001427</GrantID><Acronym>TR</Acronym><Agency>NCATS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016430">Clinical Trial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Exp Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0370712</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0014-4886</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000860" MajorTopicYN="Y">Hypoxia</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015656" MajorTopicYN="N">Respiratory Mechanics</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012132" MajorTopicYN="N">Respiratory Muscles</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">AIH</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ALS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Acute intermittent hypoxia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Control of breathing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Respiratory muscle activity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Respiratory plasticity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Surface EMG</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34624328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS1773847</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9488543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.expneurol.2021.113890</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0014-4886(21)00298-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Aslan SC, Chopra MK, McKay WB, Folz RJ, Ovechkin AV, 2013. Evaluation of respiratory muscle activation using respiratory motor control assessment (RMCA) in individuals with chronic spinal cord injury. Journal of visualized experiments : JoVE.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3740445</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23912611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aslan SC, McKay WB, Singh G, Ovechkin AV, 2019. Respiratory muscle activation patterns during maximum airway pressure efforts are different in women and men. Respir Physiol Neurobiol 259, 143&#x2013;148.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6252128</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30227268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babcock MA, Badr MS, 1998. Long-term facilitation of ventilation in humans during NREM sleep. Sleep 21, 709&#x2013;716.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11286347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bach KB, Mitchell GS, 1996. Hypoxia-induced long-term facilitation of respiratory activity is serotonin dependent. Respir Physiol 104, 251&#x2013;260.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8893371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker TL, Mitchell GS, 2000. Episodic but not continuous hypoxia elicits long-term facilitation of phrenic motor output in rats. J Physiol 529 Pt 1, 215&#x2013;219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2270180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11080263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker-Herman TL, Fuller DD, Bavis RW, Zabka AG, Golder FJ, Doperalski NJ, Johnson RA, Watters JJ, Mitchell GS, 2004. BDNF is necessary and sufficient for spinal respiratory plasticity following intermittent hypoxia. Nat Neurosci 7, 48&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14699417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker-Herman TL, Mitchell GS, 2002. Phrenic long-term facilitation requires spinal serotonin receptor activation and protein synthesis. J Neurosci 22, 6239&#x2013;6246.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6757927</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12122082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartolo A, Dzwonczyk RR, Roberts C, Goldman E, 1996. Description and validation of a technique for the removal of ECG contamination from diaphragmatic EMG signal. Med Biol Eng Comput 34, 76&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8857315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baumann F, Henderson RD, Morrison SC, Brown M, Hutchinson N, Douglas JA, Robinson PJ, McCombe PA, 2010. Use of respiratory function tests to predict survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler 11, 194&#x2013;202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19452343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benowitz NL, 1990. Clinical pharmacology of caffeine. Annu Rev Med 41, 277&#x2013;288.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2184730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berlowitz DJ, Howard ME, Fiore JF Jr., Vander Hoorn S, O&#x2019;Donoghue FJ, Westlake J, Smith A, Beer F, Mathers S, Talman P, 2016. Identifying who will benefit from non-invasive ventilation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis/motor neurone disease in a clinical cohort. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 87, 280&#x2013;286.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25857659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Black LF, Hyatt RE, 1971. Maximal static respiratory pressures in generalized neuromuscular disease. Am Rev Respir Dis 103, 641&#x2013;650.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5579907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dale EA, Ben Mabrouk F, Mitchell GS, 2014. Unexpected benefits of intermittent hypoxia: enhanced respiratory and nonrespiratory motor function. Physiology (Bethesda) 29, 39&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4073945</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24382870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dale EA, Fields DP, Devinney MJ, Mitchell GS, 2017. Phrenic motor neuron TrkB expression is necessary for acute intermittent hypoxia-induced phrenic long-term facilitation. Exp Neurol 287, 130&#x2013;136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5193112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27185271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dale-Nagle EA, Hoffman MS, MacFarlane PM, Satriotomo I, Lovett-Barr MR, Vinit S, Mitchell GS, 2010. Spinal plasticity following intermittent hypoxia: implications for spinal injury. Annals of the New York Academy of Sciences 1198, 252&#x2013;259.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3030965</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20536940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Dengler R, Eisen A, England JD, Kaji R, Kimura J, Mills K, Mitsumoto H, Nodera H, Shefner J, Swash M, 2008. Electrodiagnostic criteria for diagnosis of ALS. Clin Neurophysiol 119, 497&#x2013;503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18164242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dorst J, Ludolph AC, 2019. Non-invasive ventilation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ther Adv Neurol Disord 12, 1756286419857040.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6589990</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31258624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fallat RJ, Jewitt B, Bass M, Kamm B, Norris FH Jr., 1979. Spirometry in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Arch Neurol 36, 74&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">420626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feldman JL, Mitchell GS, Nattie EE, 2003. Breathing: rhythmicity, plasticity, chemosensitivity. Annual review of neuroscience 26, 239&#x2013;266.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2811316</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12598679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fields DP, Mitchell GS, 2017. Divergent cAMP signaling differentially regulates serotonin-induced spinal motor plasticity. Neuropharmacology 113, 82&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5193111</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27663700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fuglevand AJ, Winter DA, Patla AE, 1993. Models of recruitment and rate coding organization in motor-unit pools. J Neurophysiol 70, 2470&#x2013;2488.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8120594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fuller DD, Johnson SM, Olson EB Jr., Mitchell GS, 2003. Synaptic pathways to phrenic motoneurons are enhanced by chronic intermittent hypoxia after cervical spinal cord injury. J Neurosci 23, 2993&#x2013;3000.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6742063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12684486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gandevia SC, McKenzie DK, 1986. Human diaphragmatic EMG: changes with lung volume and posture during supramaximal phrenic stimulation. J Appl Physiol (1985) 60, 1420&#x2013;1428.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3700318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Golder FJ, Mitchell GS, 2005. Spinal synaptic enhancement with acute intermittent hypoxia improves respiratory function after chronic cervical spinal cord injury. J Neurosci 25, 2925&#x2013;2932.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6725150</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15772352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Golder FJ, Ranganathan L, Satriotomo I, Hoffman M, Lovett-Barr MR, Watters JJ, Baker-Herman TL, Mitchell GS, 2008. Spinal adenosine A2a receptor activation elicits long-lasting phrenic motor facilitation. J Neurosci 28, 2033&#x2013;2042.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6671860</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18305238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gong H Jr., Simmons MS, Tashkin DP, Hui KK, Lee EY, 1986. Bronchodilator effects of caffeine in coffee. A dose-response study of asthmatic subjects. Chest 89, 335&#x2013;342.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3948545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez-Rothi EJ, Lee KZ, Dale EA, Reier PJ, Mitchell GS, Fuller DD, 2015. Intermittent hypoxia and neurorehabilitation. J Appl Physiol (1985) 119, 1455&#x2013;1465.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4683349</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25997947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griffin HS, Pugh K, Kumar P, Balanos GM, 2012. Long-term facilitation of ventilation following acute continuous hypoxia in awake humans during sustained hypercapnia. J Physiol 590, 5151&#x2013;5165.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3497569</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22826133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardiman O, van den Berg LH, Kiernan MC, 2011. Clinical diagnosis and management of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat Rev Neurol 7, 639&#x2013;649.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21989247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris DP, Balasubramaniam A, Badr MS, Mateika JH, 2006. Long-term facilitation of ventilation and genioglossus muscle activity is evident in the presence of elevated levels of carbon dioxide in awake humans. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol 291, R1111&#x2013;1119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16627688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hart N, Polkey MI, Sharshar T, Falaize L, Fauroux B, Raphael JC, Lofaso F, 2003. Limitations of sniff nasal pressure in patients with severe neuromuscular weakness. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 74, 1685&#x2013;1687.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1757414</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14638890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayashi K, Ito N, Ichikawa Y, Suzuki Y, 2019. Effect of food intake on the ventilatory response to increasing core temperature during exercise. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab 44, 22&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29944847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayes HB, Jayaraman A, Herrmann M, Mitchell GS, Rymer WZ, Trumbower RD, 2014. Daily intermittent hypoxia enhances walking after chronic spinal cord injury: a randomized trial. Neurology 82, 104&#x2013;113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3897437</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24285617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hazenberg A, Kerstjens HA, Prins SC, Vermeulen KM, Wijkstra PJ, 2016. Is chronic ventilatory support really effective in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis? J Neurol 263, 2456&#x2013;2461.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5110605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27638636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hodges PW, Gandevia SC, 2000. Changes in intra-abdominal pressure during postural and respiratory activation of the human diaphragm. J Appl Physiol (1985) 89, 967&#x2013;976.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10956340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman MS, Golder FJ, Mahamed S, Mitchell GS, 2010. Spinal adenosine A2(A) receptor inhibition enhances phrenic long term facilitation following acute intermittent hypoxia. J Physiol 588, 255&#x2013;266.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2821563</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19900961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janssens JP, Adler D, Iancu Ferfoglia R, Poncet A, Genton Graf L, Leuchter I, Escher Imhof M, Heritier Barras AC, 2019. Assessing Inspiratory Muscle Strength for Early Detection of Respiratory Failure in Motor Neuron Disease: Should We Use MIP, SNIP, or Both? Respiration 98, 114&#x2013;124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31018212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kreitzer SM, Saunders NA, Tyler HR, Ingram RH Jr., 1978. Respiratory muscle function in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Am Rev Respir Dis 117, 437&#x2013;447.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">629478</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laveneziana P, Albuquerque A, Aliverti A, Babb T, Barreiro E, Dres M, Dube BP, Fauroux B, Gea J, Guenette JA, Hudson AL, Kabitz HJ, Laghi F, Langer D, Luo YM, Neder JA, O&#x2019;Donnell D, Polkey MI, Rabinovich RA, Rossi A, Series F, Similowski T, Spengler CM, Vogiatzis I, Verges S, 2019. ERS statement on respiratory muscle testing at rest and during exercise. Eur Respir J 53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30956204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawrence JH, De Luca CJ, 1983. Myoelectric signal versus force relationship in different human muscles. Journal of applied physiology: respiratory, environmental and exercise physiology 54, 1653&#x2013;1659.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6874489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee DC, Lim HK, McKay WB, Priebe MM, Holmes SA, Sherwood AM, 2004. Toward an objective interpretation of surface EMG patterns: a voluntary response index (VRI). J Electromyogr Kinesiol 14, 379&#x2013;388.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15094151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Llado J, Haenggeli C, Pardo A, Wong V, Benson L, Coccia C, Rothstein JD, Shefner JM, Maragakis NJ, 2006. Degeneration of respiratory motor neurons in the SOD1 G93A transgenic rat model of ALS. Neurobiology of disease 21, 110&#x2013;118.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16084734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lofaso F, Nicot F, Lejaille M, Falaize L, Louis A, Clement A, Raphael JC, Orlikowski D, Fauroux B, 2006. Sniff nasal inspiratory pressure: what is the optimal number of sniffs? Eur Respir J 27, 980&#x2013;982.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16455823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lovett-Barr MR, Satriotomo I, Muir GD, Wilkerson JE, Hoffman MS, Vinit S, Mitchell GS, 2012. Repetitive intermittent hypoxia induces respiratory and somatic motor recovery after chronic cervical spinal injury. J Neurosci 32, 3591&#x2013;3600.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3349282</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22423083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luu BL, Saboisky JP, Taylor JL, Gandevia SC, Butler JE, 2015. TMS-evoked silent periods in scalene and parasternal intercostal muscles during voluntary breathing. Respir Physiol Neurobiol 216, 15&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26025647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mateika JH, Mendello C, Obeid D, Badr MS, 2004. Peripheral chemoreflex responsiveness is increased at elevated levels of carbon dioxide after episodic hypoxia in awake humans. J Appl Physiol (1985) 96, 1197&#x2013;1205; discussion 1196.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14617525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mateika JH, Sandhu KS, 2011. Experimental protocols and preparations to study respiratory long term facilitation. Respir Physiol Neurobiol 176, 1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3055930</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21292044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell GS, 2008. Respiratory plasticity following intermittent hypoxia: a guide for novel therapeutic approaches to ventilatory control disorders?, in: Gaultier C. (Ed.), Genetic Basis for Respiratory Control Disorders. Springer, New York, NY, pp. 291&#x2013;311.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell GS, Baker TL, Nanda SA, Fuller DD, Zabka AG, Hodgeman BA, Bavis RW, Mack KJ, Olson EB Jr., 2001. Invited review: Intermittent hypoxia and respiratory plasticity. J Appl Physiol 90, 2466&#x2013;2475.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11356815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murray NP, McKenzie DK, Gorman RB, Gandevia SC, Butler JE, 2008. Reproducibility of the short-latency reflex inhibition to loading of human inspiratory muscles. Respir Physiol Neurobiol 162, 216&#x2013;222.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18692604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakamura A, Olson EB Jr., Terada J, Wenninger JM, Bisgard GE, Mitchell GS, 2010. Sleep state dependence of ventilatory long-term facilitation following acute intermittent hypoxia in Lewis rats. J Appl Physiol (1985) 109, 323&#x2013;331.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2928603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20360430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nava S, Ambrosino N, Crotti P, Fracchia C, Rampulla C, 1993. Recruitment of some respiratory muscles during three maximal inspiratory manoeuvres. Thorax 48, 702&#x2013;707.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC464649</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8153917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Navarrete-Opazo A, Alcayaga J, Sepulveda O, Rojas E, Astudillo C, 2017a. Repetitive Intermittent Hypoxia and Locomotor Training Enhances Walking Function in Incomplete Spinal Cord Injury Subjects: A Randomized, Triple-Blind, Placebo-Controlled Clinical Trial. J Neurotrauma 34, 1803&#x2013;1812.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27329506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Navarrete-Opazo A, Dougherty BJ, Mitchell GS, 2017b. Enhanced recovery of breathing capacity from combined adenosine 2A receptor inhibition and daily acute intermittent hypoxia after chronic cervical spinal injury. Exp Neurol 287, 93&#x2013;101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5193117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27079999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Navarrete-Opazo A, Mitchell GS, 2014a. Recruitment and plasticity in diaphragm, intercostal, and abdominal muscles in unanesthetized rats. J Appl Physiol (1985) 117, 180&#x2013;188.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4101609</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24833779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Navarrete-Opazo A, Mitchell GS, 2014b. Therapeutic potential of intermittent hypoxia: a matter of dose. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol 307, R1181&#x2013;1197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4315448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25231353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Navarrete-Opazo A, Vinit S, Dougherty BJ, Mitchell GS, 2015. Daily acute intermittent hypoxia elicits functional recovery of diaphragm and inspiratory intercostal muscle activity after acute cervical spinal injury. Exp Neurol 266, 1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4716671</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25687551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Navarrete-Opazo AA, Vinit S, Mitchell GS, 2014. Adenosine 2A receptor inhibition enhances intermittent hypoxia-induced diaphragm but not intercostal long-term facilitation. J Neurotrauma 31, 1975&#x2013;1984.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4245839</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25003645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nichols NL, Dale EA, Mitchell GS, 2012. Severe acute intermittent hypoxia elicits phrenic long-term facilitation by a novel adenosine-dependent mechanism. J Appl Physiol (1985) 112, 1678&#x2013;1688.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3365407</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22403346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nichols NL, Gowing G, Satriotomo I, Nashold LJ, Dale EA, Suzuki M, Avalos P, Mulcrone PL, McHugh J, Svendsen CN, Mitchell GS, 2013. Intermittent hypoxia and stem cell implants preserve breathing capacity in a rodent model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Am J Respir Crit Care Med 187, 535&#x2013;542.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3733409</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23220913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nichols NL, Satriotomo I, Allen LL, Grebe AM, Mitchell GS, 2017. Mechanisms of Enhanced Phrenic Long-Term Facilitation in SOD1(G93A) Rats. J Neurosci 37, 5834&#x2013;5845.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5473203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28500219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nichols NL, Satriotomo I, Harrigan DJ, Mitchell GS, 2015. Acute intermittent hypoxia induced phrenic long-term facilitation despite increased SOD1 expression in a rat model of ALS. Exp Neurol 273, 138&#x2013;150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4644466</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26287750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niedermeyer S, Murn M, Choi PJ, 2019. Respiratory Failure in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. Chest 155, 401&#x2013;408.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29990478</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olson EB Jr., Bohne CJ, Dwinell MR, Podolsky A, Vidruk EH, Fuller DD, Powell FL, Mitchel GS, 2001. Ventilatory long-term facilitation in unanesthetized rats. J Appl Physiol (1985) 91, 709&#x2013;716.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11457785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ovechkin A, Vitaz T, de Paleville DT, Aslan S, McKay W, 2010. Evaluation of respiratory muscle activation in individuals with chronic spinal cord injury. Respir Physiol Neurobiol 173, 171&#x2013;178.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20692382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panchabhai TS, Mireles Cabodevila E, Pioro EP, Wang X, Han X, Aboussouan LS, 2019. Pattern of lung function decline in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: implications for timing of noninvasive ventilation. ERJ Open Res 5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6759589</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31579678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pierchala LA, Mohammed AS, Grullon K, Mateika JH, Badr MS, 2008. Ventilatory long-term facilitation in non-snoring subjects during NREM sleep. Respir Physiol Neurobiol 160, 259&#x2013;266.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18088567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polkey MI, Lyall RA, Yang K, Johnson E, Leigh PN, Moxham J, 2017. Respiratory Muscle Strength as a Predictive Biomarker for Survival in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. Am J Respir Crit Care Med 195, 86&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5214920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27494149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prosser-Loose EJ, Hassan A, Mitchell GS, Muir GD, 2015. Delayed Intervention with Intermittent Hypoxia and Task Training Improves Forelimb Function in a Rat Model of Cervical Spinal Injury. J Neurotrauma 32, 1403&#x2013;1412.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25664481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roesthuis LH, van der Hoeven JG, van Hees HWH, Schellekens WM, Doorduin J, Heunks LMA, 2020. Recruitment pattern of the diaphragm and extradiaphragmatic inspiratory muscles in response to different levels of pressure support. Ann Intensive Care 10, 67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7256918</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32472272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rowland LP, Shneider NA, 2001. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. N Engl J Med 344, 1688&#x2013;1700.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11386269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandhu MS, Gray E, Kocherginsky M, Jayaraman A, Mitchell GS, Rymer WZ, 2019. Prednisolone Pretreatment Enhances Intermittent Hypoxia-Induced Plasticity in Persons With Chronic Incomplete Spinal Cord Injury. Neurorehabil Neural Repair 33, 911&#x2013;921.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31524075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seven YB, Nichols NL, Kelly MN, Hobson OR, Satriotomo I, Mitchell GS, 2018. Compensatory plasticity in diaphragm and intercostal muscle utilization in a rat model of ALS. Exp Neurol 299, 148&#x2013;156.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5951687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29056361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silver JR, Lehr RP, 1981. Electromyographic investigation of the diaphragm and intercostal muscles in tetraplegics. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 44, 837&#x2013;841.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC491146</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7310425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simonson TS, Baker TL, Banzett RB, Bishop T, Dempsey JA, Feldman JL, Guyenet PG, Hodson EJ, Mitchell GS, Moya EA, Nokes BT, Orr JE, Owens RL, Poulin M, Rawling JM, Schmickl CN, Watters JJ, Younes M, Malhotra A, 2021. Silent hypoxaemia in COVID-19 patients. J Physiol 599, 1057&#x2013;1065.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7902403</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33347610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stegeman DF, Zwarts MJ, Anders C, Hashimoto T, 2000. Multi-channel surface EMG in clinical neurophysiology. Suppl Clin Neurophysiol 53, 155&#x2013;162.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12740990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sutor T, Cavka K, Vose AK, Welch JF, Davenport P, Fuller DD, Mitchell GS, Fox EJ, 2021. Single-session effects of acute intermittent hypoxia on breathing function after human spinal cord injury. Exp Neurol 342, 113735.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8616729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33951477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tester NJ, Fuller DD, Fromm JS, Spiess MR, Behrman AL, Mateika JH, 2014. Long-term facilitation of ventilation in humans with chronic spinal cord injury. Am J Respir Crit Care Med 189, 57&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3919124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24224903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson ML, Thickbroom GW, Mastaglia FL, 1997. Corticomotor representation of the sternocleidomastoid muscle. Brain 120 ( Pt 2), 245&#x2013;255.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9117372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tobin MJ, Laghi F, Jubran A, 2010. Narrative review: ventilator-induced respiratory muscle weakness. Ann Intern Med 153, 240&#x2013;245.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2924757</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20713792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trumbower RD, Hayes HB, Mitchell GS, Wolf SL, Stahl VA, 2017. Effects of acute intermittent hypoxia on hand use after spinal cord trauma: A preliminary study. Neurology 89, 1904&#x2013;1907.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5664298</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28972191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trumbower RD, Jayaraman A, Mitchell GS, Rymer WZ, 2012. Exposure to acute intermittent hypoxia augments somatic motor function in humans with incomplete spinal cord injury. Neurorehabil Neural Repair 26, 163&#x2013;172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21821826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vender RL, Mauger D, Walsh S, Alam S, Simmons Z, 2007. Respiratory systems abnormalities and clinical milestones for patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with emphasis upon survival. Amyotroph Lateral Scler 8, 36&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17364434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vermeulen TD, Benbaruj J, Brown CV, Shafer BM, Floras JS, Foster GE, 2020. Peripheral chemoreflex contribution to ventilatory long-term facilitation induced by acute intermittent hypercapnic hypoxia in males and females. J Physiol 598, 4713&#x2013;4730.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32744340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vitacca M, Montini A, Lunetta C, Banfi P, Bertella E, De Mattia E, Lizio A, Volpato E, Lax A, Morini R, Paneroni M, Group ARS, 2018. Impact of an early respiratory care programme with non-invasive ventilation adaptation in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Eur J Neurol 25, 556&#x2013;e533.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29266547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Welch JF, Sutor T, Vose AK, Perim RR, Fox EJ, Mitchell GS, 2020. Synergy Between Acute Intermittent Hypoxia and Task-Specific Training. Exerc Sport Sci Rev.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7416561</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32412926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>