<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">34632672</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>04</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1468-1331</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>29</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Fiber-specific white matter analysis reflects upper motor neuron impairment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>432</StartPage><EndPage>440</EndPage><MedlinePgn>432-440</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/ene.15136</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND PURPOSE">To clarify the relationship between fiber-specific white matter changes in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) and clinical signs of upper motor neuron (UMN) involvement, we performed a fixel-based analysis (FBA), a novel framework for diffusion-weighted imaging analysis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">We enrolled 96 participants, including 48 nonfamilial ALS patients and 48 age- and sex-matched healthy controls (HCs), in this study and conducted whole-brain FBA and voxel-based morphometry analysis. We compared the fiber density (FD), fiber morphology (fiber cross-section [FC]), and a combined index of FD and FC (FDC) between the ALS and HC groups. We performed a tract-of-interest analysis to extract FD values across the significant regions in the whole-brain analysis. Then, we evaluated the associations between FD values and clinical variables.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">The bilateral corticospinal tracts (CSTs) and the corpus callosum (CC) showed reduced FD and FDC in ALS patients compared with HCs (p&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;0.05, familywise error-corrected), and the comparison of FCs revealed no region that was significantly different from another. Voxel-based morphometry showed cortical volume reduction in the regions, including the primary motor area. Clinical scores showed correlations with FD values in the CSTs (UMN score: rho&#xa0;=&#xa0;-0.530, p&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;0.001; central motor conduction time [CMCT] in the upper limb: rho&#xa0;=&#xa0;-0.474, p&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.008; disease duration: rho&#xa0;=&#xa0;-0.383, p&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.007; ALS Functional Rating Scale-Revised: rho&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.340, p&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.018). In addition, patients whose CMCT was not calculated due to unevoked waves also showed FD reduction in the CSTs.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Our findings suggest that FD values in the CST estimated via FBA can be potentially used in evaluating UMN impairments.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 European Academy of Neurology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ogura</LastName><ForeName>Aya</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0928-8605</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Nagoya University Graduate School of Medicine, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kawabata</LastName><ForeName>Kazuya</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8851-4377</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Nagoya University Graduate School of Medicine, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Watanabe</LastName><ForeName>Hirohisa</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8553-8536</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Brain and Mind Research Center, Nagoya University, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, School of Medicine, Fujita Health University, Toyoake, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Choy</LastName><ForeName>Shao Wei</ForeName><Initials>SW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Intelligent Signal and Imaging Research, Universiti Teknologi PETRONAS, Seri Iskandar, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bagarinao</LastName><ForeName>Epifanio</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5000-6943</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Brain and Mind Research Center, Nagoya University, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Integrated Health Sciences, Nagoya University Graduate School of Medicine, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kato</LastName><ForeName>Toshiyasu</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Nagoya University Graduate School of Medicine, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Imai</LastName><ForeName>Kazunori</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Nagoya University Graduate School of Medicine, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Masuda</LastName><ForeName>Michihito</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Nagoya University Graduate School of Medicine, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ohdake</LastName><ForeName>Reiko</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Brain and Mind Research Center, Nagoya University, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hara</LastName><ForeName>Kazuhiro</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Nagoya University Graduate School of Medicine, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nakamura</LastName><ForeName>Ryoichi</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Nagoya University Graduate School of Medicine, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Atsuta</LastName><ForeName>Naoki</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Nagoya University Graduate School of Medicine, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nakamura</LastName><ForeName>Tomohiko</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7622-4527</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Nagoya University Graduate School of Medicine, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Laboratory Medicine, Nagoya University Hospital, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Katsuno</LastName><ForeName>Masahisa</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9453-9311</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Nagoya University Graduate School of Medicine, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sobue</LastName><ForeName>Gen</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4769-5922</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Brain and Mind Research Center, Nagoya University, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Division of Dementia and Neurodegenerative Disease, Nagoya University Graduate School of Medicine, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Aichi Medical University, Nagakute, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9506311</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1351-5101</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D056324" MajorTopicYN="N">Diffusion Tensor Imaging</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009046" MajorTopicYN="N">Motor Neurons</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011712" MajorTopicYN="N">Pyramidal Tracts</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D066127" MajorTopicYN="Y">White Matter</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">corticospinal tract</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">diffusion-weighted imaging</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fixel-based analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">upper motor neuron signs</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34632672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ene.15136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Charil A, Corbo M, Filippi M, et al. Structural and metabolic changes in the brain of patients with upper motor neuron disorders: a multiparametric MRI study. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2009;10(5-6):269-279.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iwata NK, Aoki S, Okabe S, et al. Evaluation of corticospinal tracts in ALS with diffusion tensor MRI and brainstem stimulation. Neurology. 2008;70(7):528-532.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huynh W, Simon NG, Grosskreutz J, Turner MR, Vucic S, Kiernan MC. Assessment of the upper motor neuron in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Neurophysiol. 2016;127(7):2643-2660. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.clinph.2016.04.025</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Senda J, Atsuta N, Watanabe H, et al. Structural MRI correlates of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis progression. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2017;88(11):901-907.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masuda M, Senda J, Watanabe H, et al. Involvement of the caudate nucleus head and its networks in sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-frontotemporal dementia continuum. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Front Degener. 2016;17(7-8):571-579.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huynh W, Simon NG, Grosskreutz J, Turner MR, Vucic S, Kiernan MC. Assessment of the upper motor neuron in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Neurophysiol. Elsevier Ireland Ltd; 2016;127:2643-2660.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cirillo M, Esposito F, Tedeschi G, et al. Widespread microstructural white matter involvement in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A whole-brain DTI study. Am J Neuroradiol. 2012;33(6):1102-1108.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raffelt DA, Smith RE, Ridgway GR, et al. NeuroImage Connectivity-based fi xel enhancement&#x202f;: Whole-brain statistical analysis of diffusion MRI measures in the presence of crossing fi bres. Neuroimage. 2015;117:40-55. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuroimage.2015.05.039</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raffelt DA, Tournier J, Smith RE, et al. Investigating white matter fibre density and morphology using fixel-based analysis. NeuroImage. 2017;144:58-73. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuroimage.2016.09.029</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeurissen B, Leemans A, Tournier JD, Jones DK, Sijbers J. Investigating the prevalence of complex fiber configurations in white matter tissue with diffusion magnetic resonance imaging. Hum Brain Mapp. 2013;34(11):2747-2766.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, Miller RG, Swash M, Munsat TL. El Escorial revisited: revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2000;1(5):293-299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohashi Y, Tashiro K, Itoyama Y, et al. Study of functional rating scale for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: revised ALSFRS(ALSFRS-R) Japanese version. Brain Nerve. 2001;53(4):346-355.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner MR, Cagnin A, Turkheimer FE, et al. Evidence of widespread cerebral microglial activation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: an [11C](R)-PK11195 positron emission tomography study. Neurobiol Dis. 2004;15(3):601-609.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pellecchia MT, Pivonello R, Monsurr&#xf2; MR, et al. The GH-IGF system in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: correlations between pituitary GH secretion capacity, insulin-like growth factors and clinical features. Eur J Neurol. 2010;17(5):666-671.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Younger DS, Rowland LP, Latov N, et al. Motor neuron disease and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: relation of high csf protein content to paraproteinemia and clinical syndromes. Neurology. 1990;40(4):595-599.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellis CM, Simmons A, Jones DK, et al. Diffusion tensor MRI assesses corticospinal tract damage in ALS. Neurology. 1999;53:1051-1058.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bagarinao E, Watanabe H, Maesawa S, et al. An unbiased data-driven age-related structural brain parcellation for the identification of intrinsic brain volume changes over the adult lifespan. NeuroImage. 2018;169:134-144. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuroimage.2017.12.014</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bagarinao E, Watanabe H, Maesawa S, et al. Reorganization of brain networks and its association with general cognitive performance over the adult lifespan. Sci Rep. 2019;9(1):1-15. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-019-47922-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho DE, Imai K, King G, Stuart EA. MatchIt: nonparametric preprocessing for parametric causal inference. J Stat Softw. 2011;42(8):1-28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kimura J. Somatosensory and motor evoked potentials. In: Kimura J, ed. Electrodiagnosis in Diseases of Nerve and Muscle, 2nd edn. F.A. Davis Company; 1989:409-426.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujiwatra T. Motor evoked potentials with magnetic and electrical stimulation. A Manual of Electromyography and Evoked Potentials, 4th edn. Kinpodo; 2004:115-141.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choy SW, Bagarinao E, Watanabe H, et al. Changes in white matter fiber density and morphology across the adult lifespan: a cross-sectional fixel-based analysis. Hum Brain Mapp. 2020;41:3198-3211.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersson JLR, Sotiropoulos SN. An integrated approach to correction for off-resonance effects and subject movement in diffusion MR imaging. NeuroImage. 2016;125:1063-1078. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuroimage.2015.10.019</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith SM, Jenkinson M, Woolrich MW, et al. Advances in functional and structural MR image analysis and implementation as FSL. NeuroImage. 2004;23(SUPPL. 1):208-219.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jenkinson M, Beckmann CF, Behrens TEJ, Woolrich MW, Smith SM. Review FSL. NeuroImage. 2012;62:782-790.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith RE, Tournier JD, Calamante F, Connelly A. SIFT: Spherical-deconvolution informed filtering of tractograms. NeuroImage. 2013;67:298-312. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuroimage.2012.11.049</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hua K, Zhang J, Wakana S, et al. Tract probability maps in stereotaxic spaces: analyses of white matter anatomy and tract-specific quantification. NeuroImage. 2008;39(1):336-347.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swash M. Why are upper motor neuron signs difficult to elicit in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis? J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2012;83(6):659-662.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pecheva D, Kelly C, Kimpton J, et al. Recent advances in diffusion neuroimaging: applications in the developing preterm brain [version 1; referees: 2 approved]. F1000Research. 2018;7:1-12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Floyd AG, Yu QP, Piboolnurak P, et al. Transcranial magnetic stimulation in ALS: utility of central motor conduction tests. Neurology. 2009;72(6):498-504.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miscio G, Pisano F, Mora G, Mazzini L. Motor neuron disease: Usefulness of transcranial magnetic stimulation in improving the diagnosis. Clin Neurophysiol. 1999;110(5):975-981.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hofer S, Frahm J. Topography of the human corpus callosum revisited-Comprehensive fiber tractography using diffusion tensor magnetic resonance imaging. NeuroImage. 2006;32:989-994.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith MC. Nerve fibre degeneration in the brain in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 1960;23(4):269-282.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sugiyama M, Takao M, Hatsuta H, et al. Increased number of astrocytes and macrophages/microglial cells in the corpus callosum in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuropathology. 2013;33:591-599.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardenas AM, Sarlls JE, Kwan JY, et al. Pathology of callosal damage in ALS: an ex-vivo, 7 T diffusion tensor MRI study. NeuroImage Clin. 2017;15:200-208.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grolez G, Moreau C, Danel-Brunaud V, et al. The value of magnetic resonance imaging as a biomarker for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a systematic review. BMC Neurol. 2016;16:155.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filippini N, Douaud G, MacKay CE, Knight S, Talbot K, Turner MR. Corpus callosum involvement is a consistent feature of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology. 2010;75(18):1645-1652.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J, Zhang L, Chu Y, et al. Astrocytes in oligodendrocyte lineage development and white matter pathology. Front Cell Neurosci. 2016;10:1-13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou T, Ahmad TK, Gozda K, Truong J, Kong J, Namaka M. Implications of white matter damage in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (review). Mol Med Rep. 2017;16(4):4379-4392.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cosottini M, Giannelli M, Siciliano G, et al. Diffusion-tensor MR imaging of corticospinal tract in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and progressive muscular atrophy. Radiology. 2005;237(1):258-264.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gatto RG, Mustafi SM, Amin MY, Mareci TH, Wu Y-C, Magin RL. Neurite orientation dispersion and density imaging can detect presymptomatic axonal degeneration in the spinal cord of ALS mice. Funct Neurol. 2018;33(3):155-163.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakamura R, Sone J, Atsuta N, et al. Next-generation sequencing of 28 ALS-related genes in a Japanese ALS cohort. Neurobiol Aging. 2016;39:219.e1-219.e8. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2015.11.030</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raffelt D, Tournier JD, Rose S, et al. Apparent fibre density: a novel measure for the analysis of diffusion-weighted magnetic resonance images. NeuroImage. 2012;59(4):3976-3994. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuroimage.2011.10.045</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>