<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">34657086</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>03</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1537-7385</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>101</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>American journal of physical medicine &amp; rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Am J Phys Med Rehabil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis and Noninvasive Positive Pressure Ventilatory Support: "Nasal Noninvasive Ventilation" or "Noninvasive Ventilatory Support"?</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>400</StartPage><EndPage>404</EndPage><MedlinePgn>400-404</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/PHM.0000000000001905</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Many studies suggest a brief statistical benefit on survival and quality of life by using nasal noninvasive ventilation for patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and other neuromuscular conditions. Indeed, nasal noninvasive ventilation has become synonymous with continuous positive airway pressure and lo-span bilevel positive airway pressure. Nasal noninvasive ventilation, however, may not normalize CO2 levels and continuous positive airway pressure and O2 exacerbate hypercapnia and often lead to CO2 narcosis, intubation, and ultimately tracheostomy or palliative care death. However, a third option can be to offer up to continuous noninvasive ventilatory support and extubation to it. Noninvasive ventilatory support can be effective for full, definitive ventilatory support, even for people with no measurable vital capacity, and has maintained classic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients for up to 12 yrs without resort to tracheotomies. Nineteen centers have reported 335 amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients using continuous noninvasive ventilatory support instead of tracheostomy mechanical ventilation for an average of 14 mos (6 mos to 14 yrs). The noninvasive ventilatory support must also be used in conjunction with mechanical insufflation-exsufflation to clear airway debris and normalize or renormalize ambient air oxyhemoglobin saturation, both to avoid intubation and to facilitate extubation. People with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis satisfying specific criteria, even when continuously dependent on tracheostomy mechanical ventilation, can be decannulated and placed on continuous noninvasive ventilatory support with mechanical insufflation-exsufflation.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2021 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bach</LastName><ForeName>John R</ForeName><Initials>JR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, Rutgers University-New Jersey Medical School, Newark, New Jersey (JRB); Center for Ventilator Management Alternatives, University Hospital of Newark, Newark, New Jersey (JRB); and Rutgers University-New Jersey Medical School, Newark, New Jersey (HP).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pham</LastName><ForeName>Hoa</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Am J Phys Med Rehabil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8803677</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0894-9115</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>142M471B3J</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D002245">Carbon Dioxide</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002245" MajorTopicYN="N">Carbon Dioxide</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006935" MajorTopicYN="N">Hypercapnia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D063087" MajorTopicYN="Y">Noninvasive Ventilation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012121" MajorTopicYN="N">Respiration, Artificial</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012131" MajorTopicYN="Y">Respiratory Insufficiency</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>Financial disclosure statements have been obtained, and no conflicts of interest have been reported by the authors or by any individuals in control of the content of this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34657086</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/PHM.0000000000001905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00002060-202204000-00013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Chiou M, Bach JR, Saporito LR, et al.: Quantitation of oxygen-induced hypercapnia in respiratory pump failure. Rev Port Pneumol (2006) 2016;22:262&#x2013;5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bach JR, Kazi AW, Pinto T, et al.: Noninvasive respiratory management of morbid obesity and concomitant conditions. Pulmonology 2021;27:386&#x2013;93</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bach JR, Alba AS, Saporito LR: Intermittent positive pressure ventilation via the mouth as an alternative to tracheostomy for 257 ventilator users. Chest 1993;103:174&#x2013;82</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bach JR: Noninvasive respiratory management of patients with neuromuscular disease. Ann Rehabil Med 2017;41:1&#x2013;20</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alba A, Pilkington LA, Kaplan E, et al.: Long-term pulmonary care in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Respir Ther 1976;6:49&#x2013;56</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goncalves MR, Bach JR, Ishikawa Y, et al.: Continuous noninvasive ventilatory support outcomes for patients with neuromuscular disease: a multicenter data collaboration. Pulmonology 2021;27:509&#x2013;17</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carter RE, Donovan WH, Halstead L, et al.: Comparative study of electrophrenic nerve stimulation and mechanical ventilatory support in traumatic spinal cord injury. Paraplegia 1987;25:86&#x2013;91</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bach JR: Alternative methods of ventilatory support for the patient with ventilatory failure due to spinal cord injury. J Am Paraplegia Soc 1991;14:158&#x2013;74</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bach JR, Alba AS: Noninvasive options for ventilatory support of the traumatic high level quadriplegic patient. Chest 1990;98:613&#x2013;9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishikawa Y, Miura T, Ishikawa Y, et al.: Duchenne muscular dystrophy: survival by cardio-respiratory interventions. Neuromuscul Disord 2011;21:47&#x2013;51</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bach JR: Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: communication status and survival with ventilatory support. Am J Phys Med Rehabil 1993;72:343&#x2013;9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bach JR, Gon&#xe7;alves MR, Hamdani I, et al.: Extubation of patients with neuromuscular weakness: a new management paradigm. Chest 2010;137:1033&#x2013;9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bach JR, Sinquee DM, Saporito LR, et al.: Efficacy of mechanical insufflation-exsufflation in extubating unweanable subjects with restrictive pulmonary disorders. Respir Care 2015;60:477&#x2013;83</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bach JR, Zaneuski R, Lee H: Cardiac arrhythmias from a malpositioned Greenfield filter in a traumatic quadriplegic. Am J Phys Med Rehabil 1990;69:251&#x2013;3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bach JR, Gupta K, Reyna M, et al.: Spinal muscular atrophy type 1: prolongation of survival by noninvasive respiratory aids. Pediatr Asthma Allergy Immunol 2009;22:151&#x2013;62</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bach JR, Upadhyaya N: Association of need for tracheotomy with decreasing mechanical in-exsufflation flows in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Am J Phys Med Rehabil 2018;97:e20&#x2013;2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen T, Sandnes A, Brekka AK, et al.: Laryngeal response patterns influence the efficacy of mechanical assisted cough in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Thorax 2017;72:221&#x2013;9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veldink JH, Wokke JH, van der Wal G, et al.: Euthanasia and physician-assisted suicide among patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in the Netherlands. N Engl J Med 2002;346:1638&#x2013;44</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ganzini L, Johnston WS, McFarland BH, et al.: Attitudes of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and their care givers toward assisted suicide. N Engl J Med 1998;339:967&#x2013;73</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell ML, Carlson RW: Terminal weaning from mechanical ventilation: ethical and practical considerations for patient management. Am J Crit Care 1992;1:52&#x2013;6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ganzini L, Silveira MJ, Johnston WS: Predictors and correlates of interest in assisted suicide in the final month of life among ALS patients in Oregon and Washington. J Pain Symptom Manage 2002;24:312&#x2013;7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Albert SM, Del Bene ML, Rabkin JG, et al.: The decision to hasten death in people with ALS. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord 2003;4(supp 1):39</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Albert SM, Murphy PM, Del Bene ML, et al.: A prospective study of palliative care in ALS: choice, timing, outcomes. J Neurol Sci 1999;169:108&#x2013;13</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Annas GJ: The promised end&#x2014;constitutional aspects of physician-assisted suicide. N Engl J Med 1996;335:683&#x2013;7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borasio GD, Walsh D: Palliative Care in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis . New York, Oxford University Press, 2000</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horn RC III, Keeler G: Who&#x2019;s Right?: Seeking Answers and Dignity in the Debate Over the Right to Die . Sanford, FL, DC Press, 2001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Field MJ, Cassel CK: Approaching Death: Improving Care at the End of Life . Washington, DC, National Academic Press, 1997</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ganzini L, Johnston WS, Silveira MJ: The final month of life in patients with ALS. Neurology 2002;59:428&#x2013;31</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller RG, Anderson FA Jr., Bradley WG, et al.: The ALS patient care database: goals, design, and early results. ALS C.A.R.E. Study Group. Neurology 2000;54:53&#x2013;7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller RG, Rosenberg JA, Gelinas DF, et al.: Practice parameter: the care of the patient with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (an evidence-based review). Muscle Nerve 1999;22:1104&#x2013;18</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitsumoto H: Patient choices in ALS: life-sustaining treatment versus palliative care? Neurology 1999;53:248&#x2013;9</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>