<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">34679204</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>10</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-4159</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>159</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of neurochemistry</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Neurochem</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Proteostasis deregulation as a driver of C9ORF72 pathogenesis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>941</StartPage><EndPage>957</EndPage><MedlinePgn>941-957</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/jnc.15529</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) and frontotemporal dementia (FTD) are two related neurodegenerative disorders that display overlapping features. The hexanucleotide repeat expansion GGGGCC (G<sub>4</sub> C<sub>2</sub> ) in C9ORF72&#xa0;gene has been causally linked to both ALS and FTD emergence, thus opening a novel potential therapeutic target for disease intervention. The main driver of C9ORF72 pathology is the disruption of distinct cellular processes involved in the function of the proteostasis network. Here we discuss main findings relating to the induction of neurodegeneration by C9ORF72&#xa0;mutation and proteostasis deregulation, highlighting the role of the endoplasmic reticulum stress, nuclear transport, and autophagy in the disease process. We further discuss possible points of intervention to target proteostasis mediators to treat C9ORF72-linked ALS/FTD.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 International Society for Neurochemistry.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Torres</LastName><ForeName>Paulina</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biomedical Neuroscience Institute (BNI), Faculty of Medicine, University of Chile, Santiago, Chile.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>FONDAP Center for Geroscience, Brain Health, and Metabolism (GERO), Santiago, Chile.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Program of Cellular and Molecular Biology, Institute of Biomedical Science, University of Chile, Santiago, Chile.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cabral-Miranda</LastName><ForeName>Felipe</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Instituto de Ci&#xea;ncias Biom&#xe9;dicas, Universidade do Rio de Janeiro, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gonzalez-Teuber</LastName><ForeName>Vicente</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biomedical Neuroscience Institute (BNI), Faculty of Medicine, University of Chile, Santiago, Chile.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>FONDAP Center for Geroscience, Brain Health, and Metabolism (GERO), Santiago, Chile.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Program of Cellular and Molecular Biology, Institute of Biomedical Science, University of Chile, Santiago, Chile.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hetz</LastName><ForeName>Claudio</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1120-7966</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biomedical Neuroscience Institute (BNI), Faculty of Medicine, University of Chile, Santiago, Chile.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>FONDAP Center for Geroscience, Brain Health, and Metabolism (GERO), Santiago, Chile.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Program of Cellular and Molecular Biology, Institute of Biomedical Science, University of Chile, Santiago, Chile.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Buck Institute for Research on Aging, Novato, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013486">Research Support, U.S. Gov't, Non-P.H.S.</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Neurochem</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>2985190R</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0022-3042</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000073885">C9orf72 Protein</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C568651">C9orf72 protein, human</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001343" MajorTopicYN="N">Autophagy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000073885" MajorTopicYN="N">C9orf72 Protein</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D059865" MajorTopicYN="N">Endoplasmic Reticulum Stress</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057180" MajorTopicYN="N">Frontotemporal Dementia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000074702" MajorTopicYN="N">Proteostasis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ALS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">C9ORF72</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ER stress</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">FTD</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ISR</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">UPR</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">proteostasis</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34679204</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jnc.15529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Amick, J., Roczniak-Ferguson, A., &amp; Ferguson, S. M. (2016). C9orf72 binds SMCR8, localizes to lysosomes, and regulates mTORC1 signaling. Molecular Biology of the Cell, 27(20), 3040-3051. https://doi.org/10.1091/mbc.e16-01-0003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson, N., &amp; Haynes, C. (2020). Folding the mitochondrial UPR into the integrated stress response. Trends in Cell Biology, 30, 428-439. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tcb.2020.03.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ao, X., Zou, L., &amp; Wu, Y. (2014). Regulation of autophagy by the Rab GTPase network. Cell Death and Differentiation, 213(21), 348-358.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arai, T., Hasegawa, M., Akiyama, H., Ikeda, K., Nonaka, T., Mori, H., Mann, D., Tsuchiya, K., Yoshida, M., Hashizume, Y., &amp; Oda, T. (2006). TDP-43 is a component of ubiquitin-positive tau-negative inclusions in frontotemporal lobar degeneration and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Biochemical and Biophysical Research Communications, 351, 602-611.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ash, P. E. A., Bieniek, K. F., Gendron, T. F., Caulfield, T., Lin, W.-L., DeJesus-Hernandez, M., van Blitterswijk, M. M., Jansen-West, K., Paul, J. W., Rademakers, R., Boylan, K. B., Dickson, D. W., &amp; Petrucelli, L. (2013). Unconventional translation of C9ORF72 GGGGCC expansion generates insoluble polypeptides specific to c9FTD/ALS. Neuron, 77, 639-646. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2013.02.004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atanasio, A., Decman, V., White, D., Ramos, M., Ikiz, B., Lee, H.-C., Siao, C.-J., Brydges, S., LaRosa, E., Bai, Y., Fury, W., Burfeind, P., Zamfirova, R., Warshaw, G., Orengo, J., Oyejide, A., Fralish, M., Auerbach, W., Poueymirou, W., &#x2026; Lai, K.-M. V. (2016). C9orf72 ablation causes immune dysregulation characterized by leukocyte expansion, autoantibody production and glomerulonephropathy in mice. Scientific Reports, 6(1). https://doi.org/10.1038/srep23204</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baleriola, J., Walker, C. A., Jean, Y. Y., Crary, J. F., Troy, C. M., Nagy, P. L., &amp; Hengst, U. (2014). Axonally synthesized ATF4 transmits a neurodegenerative signal across brain regions. Cell, 158, 1159-1172. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2014.07.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berndsen, C. E., &amp; Wolberger, C. (2014). New insights into ubiquitin E3 ligase mechanism. Nature Structural and Molecular Biology, 214(21), 301-307.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boeynaems, S., Bogaert, E., Michiels, E., Gijselinck, I., Sieben, A., Jovi&#x10d;i&#x107;, A., De Baets, G., Scheveneels, W., Steyaert, J., Cuijt, I., Verstrepen, K. J., Callaerts, P., Rousseau, F., Schymkowitz, J., Cruts, M., Van Broeckhoven, C., Van Damme, P., Gitler, A. D., Robberecht, W., &amp; Van Den Bosch, L. (2016). Drosophila screen connects nuclear transport genes to DPR pathology in c9ALS/FTD. Scientific Reports, 6(1). https://doi.org/10.1038/srep20877</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boivin, M., Pfister, V., Gaucherot, A., Ruffenach, F., Negroni, L., Sellier, C., &amp; Charlet-Berguerand, N. (2020). Reduced autophagy upon C9ORF72 loss synergizes with dipeptide repeat protein toxicity in G4C2 repeat expansion disorders. EMBO Journal, 39, e100574. https://doi.org/10.15252/embj.2018100574</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boland, B., Yu, W. H., Corti, O., Mollereau, B., Henriques, A., Bezard, E., Pastores, G. M., Rubinsztein, D. C., Nixon, R. A., Duchen, M. R., Mallucci, G. R., Kroemer, G., Levine, B., Eskelinen, E.-L., Mochel, F., Spedding, M., Louis, C., Martin, O. R., &amp; Millan, M. J. (2018). Promoting the clearance of neurotoxic proteins in neurodegenerative disorders of ageing. Nature Reviews Drug Discovery, 17, 660-688. https://doi.org/10.1038/nrd.2018.109</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borroni, B., Bonvicini, C., Alberici, A., Buratti, E., Agosti, C., Archetti, S., Papetti, A., Stuani, C., Di Luca, M., Gennarelli, M., &amp; Padovani, A. (2009). Mutation within TARDBP leads to frontotemporal dementia without motor neuron disease. Human Mutation, 30(11), E974-E983. https://doi.org/10.1002/humu.21100</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boyce, M., Bryant, K. F., Jousse, C., Long, K., Harding, H. P., Scheuner, D., Kaufman, R. J., Ma, D., Coen, D. M., Ron, D., &amp; Yuan, J. (2005). A selective inhibitor of eIF2&#x3b1; dephosphorylation protects cells from ER stress. Science, 307(5711), 935-939. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.1101902</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braakman, I., &amp; Bulleid, N. J. (2011). Protein folding and modification in the mammalian endoplasmic reticulum. Annual Review of Biochemistry, 80, 71-99.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braems, E., Swinnen, B., Bosch, L., &amp; Den, V. (2020). C9orf72 loss-of-function: a trivial, stand-alone or additive mechanism in C9 ALS/FTD? Acta Neuropathologica, 140(5), 625-643. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00401-020-02214-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burberry, A., Suzuki, N., Wang, J.-Y., Moccia, R., Mordes, D. A., Stewart, M. H., Suzuki-Uematsu, S., Ghosh, S., Singh, A., Merkle, F. T., Koszka, K., Li, Q.-Z., Zon, L., Rossi, D. J., Trowbridge, J. J., Notarangelo, L. D., &amp; Eggan, K. (2016). Loss-of-function mutations in the C9ORF72 mouse ortholog cause fatal autoimmune disease. Science Translational Medicine, 8(347). https://doi.org/10.1126/scitranslmed.aaf6038</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burberry, A., Wells, M. F., Limone, F., Couto, A., Smith, K. S., Keaney, J., Gillet, G., van Gastel, N., Wang, J.-Y., Pietilainen, O., Qian, M., Eggan, P., Cantrell, C., Mok, J., Kadiu, I., Scadden, D. T., &amp; Eggan, K. (2020). C9orf72 suppresses systemic and neural inflammation induced by gut bacteria. Nature, 582(7810), 89-94. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41586-020-2288-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burguete, A., Almeida, S., Gao, F., Kalb, R., Akins, M., &amp; Bonini, N. (2015). GGGGCC microsatellite RNA is neuritically localized, induces branching defects, and perturbs transport granule function. Elife, 4, e08881. https://doi.org/10.7554/eLife.08881</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burrell, J. R., Halliday, G. M., Kril, J. J., Ittner, L. M., G&#xf6;tz, J., Kiernan, M. C., &amp; Hodges, J. R. (2016). The frontotemporal dementia-motor neuron disease continuum. The Lancet, 388(10047), 919-931. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0140-6736(16)00737-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, J.-J. (2007). Regulation of protein synthesis by the heme-regulated eIF2&#x3b1; kinase: relevance to anemias. Blood, 109, 2693-2699. https://doi.org/10.1182/blood-2006-08-041830</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng, W., Wang, S., Mestre, A. A., Fu, C., Makarem, A., Xian, F., Hayes, L. R., Lopez-Gonzalez, R., Drenner, K., Jiang, J., Cleveland, D. W., &amp; Sun, S. (2018). C9ORF72 GGGGCC repeat-associated non-AUG translation is upregulated by stress through eIF2&#x3b1; phosphorylation. Nature Communications, 9(1), 1-12. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-017-02495-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen-Plotkin, A. S., Lee, V.-M.-Y., &amp; Trojanowski, J. Q. (2010). TAR DNA-binding protein 43 in neurodegenerative disease. Nature Reviews. Neurology, 64(6), 211-220.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheroni, C., Peviani, M., Cascio, P., Debiasi, S., Monti, C., &amp; Bendotti, C. (2005). Accumulation of human SOD1 and ubiquitinated deposits in the spinal cord of SOD1G93A mice during motor neuron disease progression correlates with a decrease of proteasome. Neurobiology of Diseases, 18, 509-522.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chew, J., Cook, C., Gendron, T. F., Jansen-West, K., del Rosso, G., Daughrity, L. M., Castanedes-Casey, M., Kurti, A., Stankowski, J. N., Disney, M. D., Rothstein, J. D., Dickson, D. W., Fryer, J. D., Zhang, Y.-J., &amp; Petrucelli, L. (2019). Aberrant deposition of stress granule-resident proteins linked to C9orf72-associated TDP-43 proteinopathy. Molecular Neurodegeneration, 14(1). https://doi.org/10.1186/s13024-019-0310-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chew, J., Gendron, T. F., Prudencio, M., Sasaguri, H., Zhang, Y.-J., Castanedes-Casey, M., Lee, C. W., Jansen-West, K., Kurti, A., Murray, M. E., Bieniek, K. F., Bauer, P. O., Whitelaw, E. C., Rousseau, L., Stankowski, J. N., Stetler, C., Daughrity, L. M., Perkerson, E. A., Desaro, P., &#x2026; Petrucelli, L. (2015). C9ORF72 repeat expansions in mice cause TDP-43 pathology, neuronal loss, and behavioral deficits. Science, 348(6239), 1151-1154. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.aaa9344</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiang, H.-H., Andersen, P. M., Tysnes, O.-B., Gredal, O., Christensen, P. B., &amp; Graff, C. (2012). Novel TARDBP mutations in Nordic ALS patients. Journal of Human Genetics, 575(57), 316-319.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ciechanover, A., &amp; Kwon, Y. T. (2015). Degradation of misfolded proteins in neurodegenerative diseases: therapeutic targets and strategies. Experimental and Molecular Medicine, 47, e147. https://doi.org/10.1038/emm.2014.117</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ciechanover, A., &amp; Kwon, Y. T. (2017). Protein quality control by molecular chaperones in neurodegeneration. Frontiers in Neuroscience, 11, 185.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ciura, S., Lattante, S., Ber, I., Le, L. M., Tostivint, H., Brice, A., &amp; Kabashi, E. (2013). Loss of function of C9orf72 causes motor deficits in a zebrafish model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Annals of Neurology, 74, 180-187.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen, T., Lee, V., &amp; Trojanowski, J. (2011). TDP-43 functions and pathogenic mechanisms implicated in TDP-43 proteinopathies. Trends in Molecular Medicine, 17, 659-667.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook, C. N., Wu, Y., Odeh, H. M., Gendron, T. F., Jansen-West, K., del Rosso, G., Yue, M., Jiang, P., Gomes, E., Tong, J., Daughrity, L. M., Avendano, N. M., Castanedes-Casey, M., Shao, W., Oskarsson, B., Tomassy, G. S., McCampbell, A., Rigo, F., Dickson, D. W., &#x2026; Petrucelli, L. (2020). C9orf72 poly(GR) aggregation induces TDP-43 proteinopathy. Science Translational Medicine, 12(559). https://doi.org/10.1126/scitranslmed.abb3774</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooper-Knock, J., Higginbottom, A., Connor-Robson, N., Bayatti, N., Bury, J. J., Kirby, J., Ninkina, N., Buchman, V. L., &amp; Shaw, P. J. (2013). Clinical/Scientific Notes C9ORF72 transcription in a frontotemporal dementia case with two expanded alleles. Neurology, 81, 1719-1721. https://doi.org/10.1212/01.wnl.0000435295.41974.2e</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooper-Knock, J., Higginbottom, A., Stopford, M. J., Highley, J. R., Ince, P. G., Wharton, S. B., Pickering-Brown, S., Kirby, J., Hautbergue, G. M., &amp; Shaw, P. J. (2015). Antisense RNA foci in the motor neurons of C9ORF72-ALS patients are associated with TDP-43 proteinopathy. Acta Neuropathologica, 130(1), 63-75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corrionero, A., &amp; Horvitz, H. (2018). A C9orf72 ALS/FTD ortholog acts in endolysosomal degradation and lysosomal homeostasis. Current Biology, 28, 1522-1535.e5. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cub.2018.03.063</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa-Mattioli, M., &amp; Walter, P. (2020). The integrated stress response: From mechanism to disease. Science, 368(6489), 1-11. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.aat5314</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coyne, A. N., Zaepfel, B. L., Hayes, L., Fitchman, B., Salzberg, Y., Luo, E.-C., Bowen, K., Trost, H., Aigner, S., Rigo, F., Yeo, G. W., Harel, A., Svendsen, C. N., Sareen, D., &amp; Rothstein, J. D. (2020). G4C2 repeat RNA initiates a POM121-mediated reduction in specific nucleoporins in C9orf72 ALS/FTD. Neuron, 107, 1124-1140.e11. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2020.06.027</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuervo, A. (2004). Autophagy: in sickness and in health. Trends in Cell Biology, 14, 70-77. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tcb.2003.12.002</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dafinca, R., Scaber, J., Ababneh, N., Lalic, T., Weir, G., Christian, H., Vowles, J., Douglas, A. G. L., Fletcher-Jones, A., Browne, C., Nakanishi, M., Turner, M. R., Wade-Martins, R., Cowley, S. A., &amp; Talbot, K. (2016). C9orf72 hexanucleotide expansions are associated with altered endoplasmic reticulum calcium homeostasis and stress granule formation in induced pluripotent stem cell-derived neurons from patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal demen. Stem Cells, 34, 2063-2078. https://doi.org/10.1002/stem.2388</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeJesus-Hernandez, M., Finch, N. C. A., Wang, X., Gendron, T. F., Bieniek, K. F., Heckman, M. G., Vasilevich, A., Murray, M. E., Rousseau, L., Weesner, R., Lucido, A., Parsons, M., Chew, J., Josephs, K. A., Parisi, J. E., Knopman, D. S., Petersen, R. C., Boeve, B. F., Graff-Radford, N. R., &#x2026; Rademakers, R. (2017). In-depth clinico-pathological examination of RNA foci in a large cohort of C9ORF72 expansion carriers. Acta Neuropathologica, 134, 255-269. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00401-017-1725-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeJesus-Hernandez, M., Mackenzie, I. R., Boeve, B. F., Boxer, A. L., Baker, M., Rutherford, N. J., Nicholson, A. M., Finch, N. C. A., Flynn, H., Adamson, J., Kouri, N., Wojtas, A., Sengdy, P., Hsiung, G.-Y., Karydas, A., Seeley, W. W., Josephs, K. A., Coppola, G., Geschwind, D. H., &#x2026; Rademakers, R. (2011). Expanded GGGGCC hexanucleotide repeat in noncoding region of C9ORF72 causes chromosome 9p-linked FTD and ALS. Neuron, 72, 245-256. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2011.09.011</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng, H.-X., Chen, W., Hong, S.-T., Boycott, K. M., Gorrie, G. H., Siddique, N., Yang, Y. I., Fecto, F., Shi, Y., Zhai, H., Jiang, H., Hirano, M., Rampersaud, E., Jansen, G. H., Donkervoort, S., Bigio, E. H., Brooks, B. R., Ajroud, K., Sufit, R. L., &#x2026; Siddique, T. (2011). Mutations in UBQLN2 cause dominant X-linked juvenile and adult-onset ALS and ALS/dementia. Nature, 477, 211. https://doi.org/10.1038/nature10353</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deval, C., Chaveroux, C., Maurin, A.-C., Cherasse, Y., Parry, L., Carraro, V., Milenkovic, D., Ferrara, M., Bruhat, A., Jousse, C., &amp; Fafournoux, P. (2009). Amino acid limitation regulates the expression of genes involved in several specific biological processes through GCN2-dependent and GCN2-independent pathways. FEBS Journal, 276, 707-718. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1742-4658.2008.06818.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doherty, J., &amp; Baehrecke, E. H. (2018). Life, death and autophagy. Nature Cell Biology, 20(10), 1110-1117.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donnaloja, F., Jacchetti, E., Soncini, M., &amp; Raimondi, M. T. (2019). Mechanosensing at the nuclear envelope by nuclear pore complex stretch activation and its effect in physiology and pathology. Frontiers in Physiology, 10, 896.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duran-Aniotz, C., Mart&#xed;nez, G., &amp; Hetz, C. (2014). Memory loss in Alzheimer's disease: are the alterations in the UPR network involved in the cognitive impairment? Frontiers in Aging Neuroscience, 6, 8. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnagi.2014.00008</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elliott, E., Bailey, O., Waldron, F. M., Hardingham, G. E., Chandran, S., &amp; Gregory, J. M. (2020). Therapeutic targeting of proteostasis in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-a systematic review and meta-analysis of preclinical research. Frontiers in Neuroscience, 14(511), 1-16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Espay, A. J., Vizcarra, J. A., Marsili, L., Lang, A. E., Simon, D. K., Merola, A., Josephs, K. A., Fasano, A., Morgante, F., Savica, R., Greenamyre, J. T., Cambi, F., Yamasaki, T. R., Tanner, C. M., Gan-Or, Z., Litvan, I., Mata, I. F., Zabetian, C. P., Brundin, P., &#x2026; Leverenz, J. B. (2019). Revisiting protein aggregation as pathogenic in sporadic Parkinson and Alzheimer diseases. Neurology, 92, 329-337. https://doi.org/10.1212/WNL.0000000000006926</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farg, M. A., Sundaramoorthy, V., Sultana, J. M., Yang, S., Atkinson, R. A. K., Levina, V., Halloran, M. A., Gleeson, P. A., Blair, I. P., Soo, K. Y., King, A. E., &amp; Atkin, J. D. (2014). C9ORF72, implicated in amytrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal dementia, regulates endosomal trafficking. Human Molecular Genetics, 23(13), 3579-3595. https://doi.org/10.1093/hmg/ddu068</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fratta, P., Poulter, M., Lashley, T., Rohrer, J. D., Polke, J. M., Beck, J., Ryan, N., Hensman, D., Mizielinska, S., Waite, A. J., Lai, M.-C., Gendron, T. F., Petrucelli, L., Fisher, E. M. C., Revesz, T., Warren, J. D., Collinge, J., Isaacs, A. M., &amp; Mead, S. (2013). Homozygosity for the C9orf72 GGGGCC repeat expansion in frontotemporal dementia. Acta Neuropathologica, 126, 401-409. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00401-013-1147-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freibaum, B. D., Lu, Y., Lopez-Gonzalez, R., Kim, N. C., Almeida, S., Lee, K.-H., Badders, N., Valentine, M., Miller, B. L., Wong, P. C., Petrucelli, L., Kim, H. J., Gao, F.-B., &amp; Taylor, J. P. (2015). GGGGCC repeat expansion in C9orf72 compromises nucleocytoplasmic transport. Nature, 525, 129-133. https://doi.org/10.1038/nature14974</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freibaum, B. D., &amp; Taylor, J. P. (2017). The role of dipeptide repeats in C9ORF72-related ALS-FTD. Frontiers in Molecular Neuroscience, 10, 35. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnmol.2017.00035</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frick, P., Sellier, C., Mackenzie, I. R. A., Cheng, C.-Y., Tahraoui-Bories, J., Martinat, C., Pasterkamp, R. J., Prudlo, J., Edbauer, D., Oulad-Abdelghani, M., Feederle, R., Charlet-Berguerand, N., &amp; Neumann, M. (2018). Novel antibodies reveal presynaptic localization of C9orf72 protein and reduced protein levels in C9orf72 mutation carriers. Acta Neuropathologica Communications, 6(1). https://doi.org/10.1186/s40478-018-0579-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gami-Patel, P., van Dijken, I., Meeter, L. H., Melhem, S., Morrema, T. H. J., Scheper, W., van Swieten, J. C., Rozemuller, A. J. M., Dijkstra, A. A., &amp; Hoozemans, J. J. M. (2021). Unfolded protein response activation in C9orf72 frontotemporal dementia is associated with dipeptide pathology and granulovacuolar degeneration in granule cells. Brain Pathology, 31, 163-173.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gardner, B. M., Pincus, D., Gotthardt, K., Gallagher, C. M., &amp; Walter, P. (2013). Endoplasmic reticulum stress sensing in the unfolded protein response. Cold Spring Harbor Perspectives in Biology, 5, a013169. https://doi.org/10.1101/cshperspect.a013169</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gendron, T. F., &amp; Petrucelli, L. (2018). Disease mechanisms of c9orf72 repeat expansions. Cold Spring Harbor Perspectives in Medicine, 8, a024224.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glineburg, M. R., Zhang, Y., Krans, A., Tank, E. M., Barmada, S. J., &amp; Todd, P. K. (2021). Enhanced detection of expanded repeat mRNA foci with hybridization chain reaction. Acta Neuropathologica Communications, 91(9), 1-16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green, K. M., Glineburg, M. R., Kearse, M. G., Flores, B. N., Linsalata, A. E., Fedak, S. J., Goldstrohm, A. C., Barmada, S. J., &amp; Todd, P. K. (2017). RAN translation at C9orf72-associated repeat expansions is selectively enhanced by the integrated stress response. Nature Communications, 8(1), 1-13. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-017-02200-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo, Q., Lehmer, C., Mart&#xed;nez-S&#xe1;nchez, A., Rudack, T., Beck, F., Hartmann, H., P&#xe9;rez-Berlanga, M., Frottin, F., Hipp, M. S., Hartl, F. U., Edbauer, D., Baumeister, W., &amp; Fern&#xe1;ndez-Busnadiego, R. (2018). In situ structure of neuronal C9orf72 poly-GA aggregates reveals proteasome recruitment. Cell, 172, 696-705.e12. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2017.12.030</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta, R., Lan, M., Mojsilovic-Petrovic, J., Choi, W. H., Safren, N., Barmada, S., Lee, M. J., &amp; Kalb, R. (2017). The proline/arginine dipeptide from hexanucleotide repeat expanded C9ORF72 inhibits the proteasome. Eneuro, 4, 249-265.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haeusler, A. R., Donnelly, C. J., Periz, G., Simko, E. A. J., Shaw, P. G., Kim, M.-S., Maragakis, N. J., Troncoso, J. C., Pandey, A., Sattler, R., Rothstein, J. D., &amp; Wang, J. (2014). C9orf72 nucleotide repeat structures initiate molecular cascades of disease. Nature, 507, 195. https://doi.org/10.1038/nature13124</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halliday, M., Radford, H., Zents, K. A. M., Molloy, C., Moreno, J. A., Verity, N. C., Smith, E., Ortori, C. A., Barrett, D. A., Bushell, M., &amp; Mallucci, G. R. (2017). Repurposed drugs targeting eIF2&#x3b1;-P-mediated translational repression prevent neurodegeneration in mice. Brain, 140, 1768-1783. https://doi.org/10.1093/brain/awx074</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardiman, O., Al-Chalabi, A., Chio, A., Corr, E. M., Logroscino, G., Robberecht, W., Shaw, P. J., Simmons, Z., &amp; van den Berg, L. H. (2017). Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nature Reviews Disease Primers, 3(1). https://doi.org/10.1038/nrdp.2017.71</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harding, H. P., Novoa, I., Zhang, Y., Zeng, H., Wek, R., Schapira, M., &amp; Ron, D. (2000). Regulated translation initiation controls stress-induced gene expression in mammalian cells. Molecular Cell, 6, 1099-1108. https://doi.org/10.1016/S1097-2765(00)00108-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harding, H. P., Zhang, Y., Bertolotti, A., Zeng, H., &amp; Ron, D. (2000). Perk is essential for translational regulation and cell survival during the unfolded protein response. Molecular Cell, 5, 897-904. https://doi.org/10.1016/S1097-2765(00)80330-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayes, L. R., Duan, L., Bowen, K., Kalab, P., &amp; Rothstein, J. D. (2020). C9orf72 arginine-rich dipeptide repeat proteins disrupt karyopherin-mediated nuclear import. Elife, 9, e51685. https://doi.org/10.7554/eLife.51685</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haze, K., Yoshida, H., Yanagi, H., Yura, T., &amp; Mori, K. (1999). Mammalian transcription factor ATF6 is synthesized as a transmembrane protein and activated by proteolysis in response to endoplasmic reticulum stress. Molecular Biology of the Cell, 10, 3787.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heard, D. S., Tuttle, C. S. L., Lautenschlager, N. T., &amp; Maier, A. B. (2018). Repurposing proteostasis-modifying drugs to prevent or treat age-related dementia: a systematic review. Frontiers in Physiology, 9, 1520. https://doi.org/10.3389/fphys.2018.01520</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hetz, C., Axten, J., &amp; Patterson, J. (2019). Pharmacological targeting of the unfolded protein response for disease intervention. Nature Chemical Biology, 15, 764-775.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hetz, C., &amp; Mollereau, B. (2014). Disturbance of endoplasmic reticulum proteostasis in neurodegenerative diseases. Nature Reviews Neuroscience, 15, 233.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hetz, C., &amp; Papa, F. R. (2018). The unfolded protein response and cell fate control. Molecular Cell, 69, 169-181.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hetz, C., &amp; Saxena, S. (2017). ER stress and the unfolded protein response in neurodegeneration. Nature Reviews. Neurology, 13, 477-491.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hetz, C., Zhang, K., &amp; Kaufman, R. (2020). Mechanisms, regulation and functions of the unfolded protein response. Nature Reviews Molecular Cell Biology, 21, 421-438.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iacoangeli, A., Al Khleifat, A., Jones, A. R., William, S., Shatunov, A., Opie-Martin, S., Morrison, K. E., Shaw, P. J., Shaw, C. E., Fogh, I., Dobson, R. J., Newhouse, S. J., &amp; Al-Chalabi, A. (2019). C9orf72 intermediate expansions of 24-30 repeats are associated with ALS. Acta Neuropathologica Communications, 7(1). https://doi.org/10.1186/s40478-019-0724-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang, J., Zhu, Q., Gendron, T. F., Saberi, S., McAlonis-Downes, M., Seelman, A., Stauffer, J. E., Jafar-nejad, P., Drenner, K., Schulte, D., Chun, S., Sun, S., Ling, S.-C., Myers, B., Engelhardt, J., Katz, M., Baughn, M., Platoshyn, O., Marsala, M., &#x2026; Lagier-Tourenne, C. (2016). Gain of toxicity from ALS/FTD-linked repeat expansions in C9ORF72 is alleviated by antisense oligonucleotides targeting GGGGCC-containing RNAs. Neuron, 90, 535-550. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2016.04.006</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson, J. O., Mandrioli, J., Benatar, M., Abramzon, Y., Van Deerlin, V. M., Trojanowski, J. Q., Gibbs, J. R., Brunetti, M., Gronka, S., Wuu, J., Ding, J., McCluskey, L., Martinez-Lage, M., Falcone, D., Hernandez, D. G., Arepalli, S., Chong, S., Schymick, J. C., Rothstein, J., &#x2026; Traynor, B. J. (2010). Exome sequencing reveals VCP mutations as a cause of familial ALS. Neuron, 68, 857-864. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2010.11.036</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jovi&#x10d;i&#x107;, A., Mertens, J., Boeynaems, S., Bogaert, E., Chai, N., Yamada, S. B., Paul, J. W., Sun, S., Herdy, J. R., Bieri, G., Kramer, N. J., Gage, F. H., Van Den Bosch, L., Robberecht, W., &amp; Gitler, A. D. (2015). Modifiers of C9orf72 dipeptide repeat toxicity connect nucleocytoplasmic transport defects to FTD/ALS. Nature Neuroscience, 18(9), 1226-1229. https://doi.org/10.1038/nn.4085</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jovi&#x10d;i&#x107;, A., Paul, J. W., &amp; Gitler, A. D. (2016). Nuclear transport dysfunction: a common theme in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal dementia. Journal of Neurochemistry, 138, 134-144. https://doi.org/10.1111/jnc.13642</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kabashi, E., Agar, J., Taylor, D., Minotti, S., &amp; Durham, H. (2004). Focal dysfunction of the proteasome: a pathogenic factor in a mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Journal of Neurochemistry, 89, 1325-1335. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1471-4159.2004.02453.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaneb, H. M., Folkmann, A. W., Belzil, V. V., Jao, L.-E., Leblond, C. S., Girard, S. L., Daoud, H., Noreau, A., Rochefort, D., Hince, P., Szuto, A., Levert, A., Vidal, S., Andr&#xe9;-Guimont, C., Camu, W., Bouchard, J.-P., Dupr&#xe9;, N., Rouleau, G. A., Wente, S. R., &amp; Dion, P. A. (2015). Deleterious mutations in the essential mRNA metabolism factor, hGle1, in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Human Molecular Genetics, 24(5), 1363-1373. https://doi.org/10.1093/hmg/ddu545</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanekura, K., Yagi, T., Cammack, A. J., Mahadevan, J., Kuroda, M., Harms, M. B., Miller, T. M., &amp; Urano, F. (2016). Poly-dipeptides encoded by the C9ORF72 repeats block global protein translation. Human Molecular Genetics, 25, 1803-1813.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelly, J. (2020). Pharmacologic approaches for adapting proteostasis in the secretory pathway to ameliorate protein conformational diseases. Cold Spring Harbor Perspectives in Biology, 12(5), a034108. https://doi.org/10.1101/cshperspect.a034108</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khosravi, B., LaClair, K. D., Riemenschneider, H., Zhou, Q., Frottin, F., Mareljic, N., Czuppa, M., Farny, D., Hartmann, H., Michaelsen, M., Arzberger, T., Hartl, F. U., Hipp, M. S., &amp; Edbauer, D. (2020). Cell-to-cell transmission of C9orf72 poly-(Gly-Ala) triggers key features of ALS/FTD. The EMBO Journal, 39(8). https://doi.org/10.15252/embj.2019102811</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, H. J., &amp; Taylor, J. P. (2017). Lost in transportation: nucleocytoplasmic transport defects in ALS and other neurodegenerative diseases. Neuron, 96, 285-297. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2017.07.029</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klionsky, D. J., Petroni, G., Amaravadi, R. K., Baehrecke, E. H., Ballabio, A., Boya, P., Bravo-San Pedro, J. M., Cadwell, K., Cecconi, F., Choi, A. M. K., Choi, M. E., Chu, C. T., Codogno, P., Colombo, M. I., Cuervo, A. M., Deretic, V., Dikic, I., Elazar, Z., Eskelinen, E.-L., &#x2026; Pietrocola, F. (2021). Autophagy in major human diseases. The EMBO Journal, 40(19). https://doi.org/10.15252/embj.2021108863</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koppers, M., Blokhuis, A. M., Westeneng, H.-J., Terpstra, M. L., Zundel, C. A. C., Vieira de S&#xe1;, R., Schellevis, R. D., Waite, A. J., Blake, D. J., Veldink, J. H., Van Den Berg, L. H., &amp; Pasterkamp, R. J. (2015). C9orf72 ablation in mice does not cause motor neuron degeneration or motor deficits. Annals of Neurology, 78(3), 426-438. https://doi.org/10.1002/ana.24453</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kramer, N. J., Haney, M. S., Morgens, D. W., Jovi&#x10d;i&#x107;, A., Couthouis, J., Li, A., Ousey, J., Ma, R., Bieri, G., Tsui, C. K., Shi, Y., Hertz, N. T., Tessier-Lavigne, M., Ichida, J. K., Bassik, M. C., &amp; Gitler, A. D. (2018). CRISPR-Cas9 screens in human cells and primary neurons identify modifiers of C9ORF72 dipeptide-repeat-protein toxicity. Nature Genetics, 50(4), 603-612. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41588-018-0070-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraskiewicz, H., &amp; FitzGerald, U. (2012). InterfERing with endoplasmic reticulum stress. Trends in Pharmacological Sciences, 33, 53-63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lansbury, P. T., &amp; Lashuel, H. A. (2006). A century-old debate on protein aggregation and neurodegeneration enters the clinic. Nature, 443(7113), 774-779.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lattante, S., Rouleau, G., &amp; Kabashi, E. (2013). TARDBP and FUS mutations associated with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: summary and update. Human Mutation, 34, 812-826.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leskel&#xe4;, S., Huber, N., Rostalski, H., Natunen, T., Remes, A. M., Takalo, M., Hiltunen, M., &amp; Haapasalo, A. (2019) C9orf72 proteins regulate autophagy and undergo autophagosomal or proteasomal degradation in a cell type-dependent manner. Cells, 8, 1233.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levine, T. P., Daniels, R. D., Gatta, A. T., Wong, L. H., &amp; Hayes, M. J. (2013). The product of C9orf72, a gene strongly implicated in neurodegeneration, is structurally related to DENN Rab-GEFs. Bioinformatics, 29, 499-503. https://doi.org/10.1093/bioinformatics/bts725</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, Y.-C., Kumar, M. S., Ramesh, N., Anderson, E. N., Nguyen, A. T., Kim, B., Cheung, S., McDonough, J. A., Skarnes, W. C., Lopez-Gonzalez, R., Landers, J. E., Fawzi, N. L., Mackenzie, I. R. A., Lee, E. B., Nickerson, J. A., Grunwald, D., Pandey, U. B., &amp; Bosco, D. A. (2021). Interactions between ALS-linked FUS and nucleoporins are associated with defects in the nucleocytoplasmic transport pathway. Nature Neuroscience, 24(8), 1077-1088. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41593-021-00859-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ling, S. C., Polymenidou, M., &amp; Cleveland, D. W. (2013). Converging mechanisms in als and FTD: Disrupted RNA and protein homeostasis. Neuron, 79, 416-438. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2013.07.033</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Y., Pattamatta, A., Zu, T., Reid, T., Bardhi, O., Borchelt, D. R., Yachnis, A. T., &amp; Ranum, L. P. W. (2016). C9orf72 BAC mouse model with motor deficits and neurodegenerative features of ALS/FTD. Neuron, 90, 521-534. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2016.04.005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma, T., Trinh, M. A., Wexler, A. J., Clarisse, B., Evelina, G., Philippe, P., Cavener Douglas, R., &amp; Eric, K. (2013). Suppression of eIF2&#x3b1; kinases alleviates Alzheimer's disease-related plasticity and memory deficits. Nature Neuroscience, 16(9), 1299-1305. https://doi.org/10.1038/nn.3486</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackenzie, I. R., Arzberger, T., Kremmer, E., Troost, D., Lorenzl, S., Mori, K., Weng, S.-M., Haass, C., Kretzschmar, H. A., Edbauer, D., &amp; Neumann, M. (2013). Dipeptide repeat protein pathology in C9ORF72 mutation cases: clinico-pathological correlations. Acta Neuropathologica, 126(6), 859-879. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00401-013-1181-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackenzie, I. R. A., Frick, P., Gr&#xe4;sser, F. A., Gendron, T. F., Petrucelli, L., Cashman, N. R., Edbauer, D., Kremmer, E., Prudlo, J., Troost, D., &amp; Neumann, M. (2015). Quantitative analysis and clinico-pathological correlations of different dipeptide repeat protein pathologies in C9ORF72 mutation carriers. Acta Neuropathologica, 130, 845-861. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00401-015-1476-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackenzie, I., Rademakers, R., &amp; Neumann, M. (2010). TDP-43 and FUS in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal dementia. The Lancet Neurology, 9, 995-1007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Majounie, E., Renton, A. E., Mok, K., Dopper, E. G. P., Waite, A., Rollinson, S., Chi&#xf2;, A., Restagno, G., Nicolaou, N., Simon-Sanchez, J., van Swieten, J. C., Abramzon, Y., Johnson, J. O., Sendtner, M., Pamphlett, R., Orrell, R. W., Mead, S., Sidle, K. C., Houlden, H., &#x2026; Traynor, B. J. (2012). Frequency of the C9orf72 hexanucleotide repeat expansion in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal dementia: a cross-sectional study. The Lancet Neurology, 11, 323-330. https://doi.org/10.1016/S1474-4422(12)70043-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>May, S., Hornburg, D., Schludi, M. H., Arzberger, T., Rentzsch, K., Schwenk, B. M., Gr&#xe4;sser, F. A., Mori, K., Kremmer, E., Banzhaf-Strathmann, J., Mann, M., Meissner, F., &amp; Edbauer, D. (2014). C9orf72 FTLD/ALS-associated Gly-Ala dipeptide repeat proteins cause neuronal toxicity and Unc119 sequestration. Acta Neuropathologica, 128(4), 485-503. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00401-014-1329-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McEachin, Z. T., Parameswaran, J., Raj, N., Bassell, G. J., &amp; Jiang, J. (2020). RNA-mediated toxicity in C9orf72 ALS and FTD. Neurobiology of Diseases, 145, 105055.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Medeiros, H., Colturato-Kido, C., Ferraz, L., Costa, C., Moraes, V., Paredes-Gamero, E., Tersariol, I., &amp; Rodrigues, T. (2020). AMPK activation induced by promethazine increases NOXA expression and Beclin-1 phosphorylation and drives autophagy-associated apoptosis in chronic myeloid leukemia. Chemico-Biological Interactions, 315, 108888-https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cbi.2019.108888</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Medinas, D. B., Valenzuela, V., &amp; Hetz, C. (2017). Proteostasis disturbance in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Human Molecular Genetics, 26, R91-R104. https://doi.org/10.1093/hmg/ddx274</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mercado, G., Castillo, V., Soto, P., L&#xf3;pez, N., Axten, J. M., Sardi, S. P., Hoozemans, J. J. M., &amp; Hetz, C. (2018). Targeting PERK signaling with the small molecule GSK2606414 prevents neurodegeneration in a model of Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Neurobiology of Diseases, 112, 136-148.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mizielinska, S., Gronke, S., Niccoli, T., Ridler, C. E., Clayton, E. L., Devoy, A., Moens, T., Norona, F. E., Woollacott, I. O. C., Pietrzyk, J., Cleverley, K., Nicoll, A. J., Pickering-Brown, S., Dols, J., Cabecinha, M., Hendrich, O., Fratta, P., Fisher, E. M. C., Partridge, L., &amp; Isaacs, A. M. (2014). C9orf72 repeat expansions cause neurodegeneration in Drosophila through arginine-rich proteins. Science, 345(6201), 1192-1194. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.1256800</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mizielinska, S., Lashley, T., Norona, F. E., Clayton, E. L., Ridler, C. E., Fratta, P., &amp; Isaacs, A. M. (2013). C9orf72 frontotemporal lobar degeneration is characterised by frequent neuronal sense and antisense RNA foci. Acta Neuropathologica, 126, 845-857. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00401-013-1200-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mordes, D. A., Morrison, B. M., Ament, X. H., Cantrell, C., Mok, J., Eggan, P., Xue, C., Wang, J. Y., Eggan, K., &amp; Rothstein, J. D. (2020). Absence of survival and motor deficits in 500 repeat C9ORF72 BAC mice. Neuron, 108, 775-783.e4. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2020.08.009</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreno, J. A., Halliday, M., Molloy, C., Radford, H., Verity, N., Axten, J. M., Ortori, C. A., Willis, A. E., Fischer, P. M., Barrett, D. A., &amp; Mallucci, G. R. (2013). Oral treatment targeting the unfolded protein response prevents neurodegeneration and clinical disease in prion-infected mice. Science Translational Medicine, 5(206), 206. https://doi.org/10.1126/scitranslmed.3006767</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreno, J. A., Radford, H., Peretti, D., Steinert, J. R., Verity, N., Martin, M. G., Halliday, M., Morgan, J., Dinsdale, D., Ortori, C. A., Barrett, D. A., Tsaytler, P., Bertolotti, A., Willis, A. E., Bushell, M., &amp; Mallucci, G. R. (2012). Sustained translational repression by eIF2&#x3b1;-P mediates prion neurodegeneration. Nature, 485, 507-511. https://doi.org/10.1038/nature11058</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mori, K., Arzberger, T., Gr&#xe4;sser, F. A., Gijselinck, I., May, S., Rentzsch, K., Weng, S.-M., Schludi, M. H., van der Zee, J., Cruts, M., Van Broeckhoven, C., Kremmer, E., Kretzschmar, H. A., Haass, C., &amp; Edbauer, D. (2013). Bidirectional transcripts of the expanded C9orf72 hexanucleotide repeat are translated into aggregating dipeptide repeat proteins. Acta Neuropathologica, 126, 881-893. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00401-013-1189-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mori, K., Weng, S.-M., Arzberger, T., May, S., Rentzsch, K., Kremmer, E., Schmid, B., Kretzschmar, H. A., Cruts, M., Van Broeckhoven, C., Haass, C., &amp; Edbauer, D. (2013). The C9orf72 GGGGCC repeat is translated into aggregating dipeptide-repeat proteins in FTLD/ALS. Science, 339(6125), 1335-1338. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.1232927</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nassif, M., Woehlbier, U., &amp; Manque, P. A. (2017). The enigmatic role of C9ORF72 in autophagy. Frontiers in Neuroscience, 11, 442. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnins.2017.00442</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neumann, M., Sampathu, D. M., Kwong, L. K., Truax, A. C., Micsenyi, M. C., Chou, T. T., Bruce, J., Schuck, T., Grossman, M., Clark, C. M., McCluskey, L. F., Miller, B. L., Masliah, E., Mackenzie, I. R., Feldman, H., Wolfgang, F., Kretzschmar, H. A., Trojanowski, J. Q., &amp; Lee Virginia, M.-Y. (2006). Ubiquitinated TDP-43 in frontotemporal lobar degeneration and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Science, 314(5796), 130-133. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.1134108</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Rourke, J. G., Bogdanik, L., Y&#xe1;&#xf1;ez, A., Lall, D., Wolf, A. J., Muhammad, A. K. M. G., Ho, R., Carmona, S., Vit, J. P., Zarrow, J., Kim, K. J., Bell, S., Harms, M. B., Miller, T. M., Dangler, C. A., Underhill, D. M., Goodridge, H. S., Lutz, C. M., &amp; Baloh, R. H. (2016). C9orf72 is required for proper macrophage and microglial function in mice. Science, 351(6279), 1324-1329. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.aaf1064</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ortega, J. A., Daley, E. L., Kour, S., Samani, M., Tellez, L., Smith, H. S., Hall, E. A., Esengul, Y. T., Tsai, Y.-H., Gendron, T. F., Donnelly, C. J., Siddique, T., Savas, J. N., Pandey, U. B., &amp; Kiskinis, E. (2020). Nucleocytoplasmic proteomic analysis uncovers eRF1 and nonsense-mediated decay as modifiers of ALS/FTD C9orf72 toxicity. Neuron, 106, 90-107.e13. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2020.01.020</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pakos-Zebrucka, K., Koryga, I., Mnich, K., Ljujic, M., Samali, A., &amp; Gorman, A. M. (2016). The integrated stress response. EMBO Reports, 17, 1374-1395. https://doi.org/10.15252/embr.201642195</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palam, L., Baird, T., &amp; Wek, R. (2011). Phosphorylation of eIF2 facilitates ribosomal bypass of an inhibitory upstream ORF to enhance CHOP translation. Journal of Biological Chemistry, 286, 10939-10949.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parzych, K., &amp; Klionsky, D. (2014). An overview of autophagy: morphology, mechanism, and regulation. Antioxidants and Redox Signaling, 20, 460-473.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pasinelli, P., &amp; Brown, R. H. (2006). Molecular biology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: insights from genetics. Nature Reviews Neuroscience, 7, 710-723. https://doi.org/10.1038/nrn1971</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prasad, A., Bharathi, V., Sivalingam, V., Girdhar, A., &amp; Patel, B. K. (2019). Molecular mechanisms of TDP-43 misfolding and pathology in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Frontiers in Molecular Neuroscience, 12, 25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Preissler, S., &amp; Ron, D. (2019). Early events in the endoplasmic reticulum unfolded protein response. Cold Spring Harbor Perspectives in Biology, 11(4), a033894.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prudencio, M., Belzil, V. V., Batra, R., Ross, C. A., Gendron, T. F., Pregent, L. J., Murray, M. E., Overstreet, K. K., Piazza-Johnston, A. E., Desaro, P., Bieniek, K. F., DeTure, M., Lee, W. C., Biendarra, S. M., Davis, M. D, Baker, M. C., Perkerson, R. B., van Blitterswijk, M., Stetler, C. T., &#x2026; Petrucelli, L. (2015). Distinct brain transcriptome profiles in C9orf72-associated and sporadic ALS. Nature Neuroscience, 18(8), 1175-1182. https://doi.org/10.1038/nn.4065</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renton, A. E., Majounie, E., Waite, A., Sim&#xf3;n-S&#xe1;nchez, J., Rollinson, S., Gibbs, J. R., Schymick, J. C., Laaksovirta, H., van&#xa0;Swieten, J. C., Myllykangas, L., Kalimo, H., Paetau, A., Abramzon, Y., Remes, A. M., Kaganovich, A., Scholz, S. W., Duckworth, J., Ding, J., Harmer, D. W., &#x2026; Traynor, B. J. (2011). A Hexanucleotide repeat expansion in C9ORF72 is the cause of chromosome 9p21-linked ALS-FTD. Neuron, 72, 257-268. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2011.09.010</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rojas, M., Arias, C. F., &amp; L&#xf3;pez, S. (2010). Protein kinase R is responsible for the phosphorylation of eIF2&#x3b1; in rotavirus infection. Journal of Virology, 84(20), 10457-10466. https://doi.org/10.1128/jvi.00625-10</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rowland, L. P., &amp; Shneider, N. A. (2001). Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. New England Journal of Medicine, 344, 1688-1700.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruegsegger, C., &amp; Saxena, S. (2016). Proteostasis impairment in ALS. Brain Research, 1648, 571-579. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.brainres.2016.03.032</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sareen, D., O&#x2019;Rourke, J. G., Meera, P., Muhammad, A. K. M. G., Grant, S., Simpkinson, M., Bell, S., Carmona, S., Ornelas, L., Sahabian, A., Gendron, T., Petrucelli, L., Baughn, M., Ravits, J., Harms, M. B., Rigo, F., Bennett, C. F., Otis, T. S., Svendsen, C. N., &amp; Baloh, R. H. (2013). Targeting RNA foci in iPSC-derived motor neurons from ALS patients with a C9ORF72 repeat expansion. Science Translational Medicine, 5(208). https://doi.org/10.1126/scitranslmed.3007529</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saxena, S., Cabuy, E., &amp; Caroni, P. (2009). A role for motoneuron subtype-selective ER stress in disease manifestations of FALS mice. Nature Neuroscience, 12, 627.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saxena, S., &amp; Caroni, P. (2011). Selective neuronal vulnerability in neurodegenerative diseases: from stressor thresholds to degeneration. Neuron, 71, 35-48. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2011.06.031</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt, J., Braggio, E., Kortuem, K. M., Egan, J. B., Zhu, Y. X., Xin, C. S., Tiedemann, R. E., Palmer, S. E., Garbitt, V. M., McCauley, D., Kauffman, M., Shacham, S., Chesi, M., Bergsagel, P. L., &amp; Stewart, A. K. (2013). Genome-wide studies in multiple myeloma identify XPO1/CRM1 as a critical target validated using the selective nuclear export inhibitor KPT-276. Leukemia, 27(12), 2357-2365. https://doi.org/10.1038/leu.2013.172</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt, M. F., Gan, Z. Y., Komander, D., &amp; Dewson, G. (2021). Ubiquitin signalling in neurodegeneration: mechanisms and therapeutic opportunities. Cell Death and Differentiation, 282(28), 570-590.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scrivo, A., Bourdenx, M., Pampliega, O., &amp; Cuervo, A. (2018). Selective autophagy as a potential therapeutic target for neurodegenerative disorders. The Lancet Neurology, 17, 802-815.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sellier, C., Campanari, M. L., Julie Corbier, C., Gaucherot, A., Kolb-Cheynel, I., Oulad-Abdelghani, M., Ruffenach, F., Page, A., Ciura, S., Kabashi, E., &amp; Charlet-Berguerand, N. (2016). Loss of C9ORF72 impairs autophagy and synergizes with polyQ Ataxin-2 to induce motor neuron dysfunction and cell death. The EMBO Journal, 35(12), 1276-1297. https://doi.org/10.15252/embj.201593350</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shahheydari, H., Ragagnin, A., Walker, A. K., Toth, R. P., Vidal, M., Jagaraj, C. J., Perri, E. R., Konopka, A., Sultana, J. M., &amp; Atkin, J. D. (2017). Protein quality control and the amyotrophic lateral sclerosis/frontotemporal dementia continuum. Frontiers in Molecular Neuroscience, 10, 119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaw, M. P., Higginbottom, A., McGown, A., Castelli, L. M., James, E., Hautbergue, G. M., Shaw, P. J., &amp; Ramesh, T. M. (2018). Stable transgenic C9orf72 zebrafish model key aspects of the ALS/FTD phenotype and reveal novel pathological features. Acta Neuropathologica Communications, 6, 125.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi, Y., Lin, S., Staats, K. A., Li, Y., Chang, W.-H., Hung, S.-T., Hendricks, E., Linares, G. R., Wang, Y., Son, E. Y., Wen, X., Kisler, K., Wilkinson, B., Menendez, L., Sugawara, T., Woolwine, P., Huang, M., Cowan, M. J., Ge, B., &#x2026; Ichida, J. K. (2018). Haploinsufficiency leads to neurodegeneration in C9ORF72 ALS/FTD human induced motor neurons. Nature Medicine, 24(3), 313-325. https://doi.org/10.1038/nm.4490</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sidrauski, C., Acosta-Alvear, D., Khoutorsky, A., Vedantham, P., Hearn, B. R., Li, H., Gamache, K., Gallagher, C. M., Ang, K.-H., Wilson, C., Okreglak, V., Ashkenazi, A., Hann, B., Nader, K., Arkin, M. R., Renslo, A. R., Sonenberg, N., &amp; Walter, P. (2013). Pharmacological brake-release of mRNA translation enhances cognitive memory. Elife, 2, e00498. https://doi.org/10.7554/eLife.00498</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simone, R., Balendra, R., Moens, T. G., Preza, E., Wilson, K. M., Heslegrave, A., Woodling, N. S., Niccoli, T., Gilbert-Jaramillo, J., Abdelkarim, S., Clayton, E. L., Clarke, M., Konrad, M.-T., Nicoll, A. J., Mitchell, J. S., Calvo, A., Chio, A., Houlden, H., Polke, J. M., &#x2026; Isaacs, A. M. (2018). G-quadruplex-binding small molecules ameliorate C9orf72 FTD/ALS pathology in vitro and in vivo. EMBO Molecular Medicine, 10(1), 22-31. https://doi.org/10.15252/emmm.201707850</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smeyers, J., Banchi, E.-G., &amp; Latouche, M. (2021). C9ORF72: what it is, what it does, and why it matters. Frontiers in Cellular Neuroscience, 15, 109.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sonobe, Y., Ghadge, G., Masaki, K., Sendoel, A., Fuchs, E., &amp; Roos, R. P. (2018). Translation of dipeptide repeat proteins from the C9ORF72 expanded repeat is associated with cellular stress. Neurobiology of Diseases, 116, 155-165.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su, M.-Y., Fromm, S. A., Zoncu, R., &amp; Hurley, J. H. (2020). Structure of the C9orf72 ARF GAP complex that is haploinsufficient in ALS and FTD. Nature, 585(7824), 251-255.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su, Z., Zhang, Y., Gendron, T. F., Bauer, P. O., Chew, J., Yang, W.-Y., Fostvedt, E., Jansen-West, K., Belzil, V. V., Desaro, P., Johnston, A., Overstreet, K., Oh, S.-Y., Todd, P. K., Berry, J. D., Cudkowicz, M. E., Boeve, B. F., Dickson, D., Floeter, M. K., &#x2026; Disney, M. D. (2014). Discovery of a biomarker and lead small molecules to target r(GGGGCC)-associated defects in c9FTD/ALS. Neuron, 83(5), 1043-1050. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2014.07.041</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sullivan, P. M., Zhou, X., Robins, A. M., Paushter, D. H., Kim, D., Smolka, M. B., &amp; Hu, F. (2016). The ALS/FTLD associated protein C9orf72 associates with SMCR8 and WDR41 to regulate the autophagy-lysosome pathway. Acta Neuropathologica Communications, 41(4), 1-16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang, B. L. (2016). C9orf72&#x2019;s interaction with Rab GTPases-modulation of membrane traffic and autophagy. Frontiers in Cellular Neuroscience, 10, 228.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang, D., Sheng, J., Xu, L., Zhan, X., Liu, J., Jiang, H., Shu, X., Liu, X., Zhang, T., Jiang, L., Zhou, C., Li, W., Cheng, W., Li, Z., Wang, K., Lu, K., Yan, C., &amp; Qi, S. (2020). Cryo-EM structure of C9ORF72-SMCR8-WDR41 reveals the role as a GAP for Rab8a and Rab11a. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, 117(18), 9876-9883. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2002110117</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor, J. P., Brown, R. H. Jr, &amp; Cleveland, D. W. (2016). Decoding ALS: from genes to mechanism. Nature, 539, 197. https://doi.org/10.1038/nature20413</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Therrien, M., Rouleau, G. A., Dion, P. A., &amp; Parker, J. A. (2013). Deletion of C9ORF72 results in motor neuron degeneration and stress sensitivity in C. elegans. PLoS One, 8, 83450. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0083450</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Todd, T. W., &amp; Petrucelli, L. (2018). Neurodegenerative diseases and RNA-mediated toxicity. In M. S. Wolfe (Ed.), The molecular and cellular basis of neurodegenerative diseases (pp. 441-475). Elsevier Inc. https://www.elsevier.com/books/the-molecular-and-cellular-basis-of-neurodegenerative-diseases/wolfe/978-0-12-811304-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ugolino, J., Ji, Y. J., Conchina, K., Chu, J., Nirujogi, R. S., Pandey, A., Brady, N. R., Hamacher-Brady, A., &amp; Wang, J. (2016). Loss of C9orf72 enhances autophagic activity via deregulated mTOR and TFEB signaling. PLoS Genetics, 12, e1006443. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pgen.1006443</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Urra, H., Dufey, E., Lisbona, F., Rojas-Rivera, D., &amp; Hetz, C. (2013). When ER stress reaches a dead end. Biochimica Et Biophysica Acta (BBA) - Molecular Cell Research, 1833, 3507-3517.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valenzuela, V., Jackson, K. L., Sardi, S. P., &amp; Hetz, C. (2018). Gene therapy strategies to restore ER proteostasis in disease. Molecular Therapy, 26, 1404-1413.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Blitterswijk, M., Gendron, T. F., Baker, M. C., DeJesus-Hernandez, M., Finch, N. C. A., Brown, P. H., Daughrity, L. M., Murray, M. E., Heckman, M. G., Jiang, J., Lagier-Tourenne, C., Edbauer, D., Cleveland, D. W., Josephs, K. A., Parisi, J. E., Knopman, D. S., Petersen, R. C., Petrucelli, L., Boeve, B. F., &#x2026; Rademakers, R. (2015). Novel clinical associations with specific C9ORF72 transcripts in patients with repeat expansions in C9ORF72. Acta Neuropathologica, 130, 863-876. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00401-015-1480-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van, L. T., Van Der, Z. J., &amp; Van, B. C. (2012). The molecular basis of the frontotemporal lobar degeneration-amyotrophic lateral sclerosis spectrum. Annals of Medicine, 44, 817-828.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vatsavayai, S., Nana, A., Yokoyama, J., &amp; Seeley, W. (2019). C9orf72-FTD/ALS pathogenesis: evidence from human neuropathological studies. Acta Neuropathologica, 137. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00401-018-1921-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vatsavayai, S. C., Yoon, S. J., Gardner, R. C., Gendron, T. F., Vargas, J. N. S., Trujillo, T., Pribadi, M., Phillips, J. J., Gaus, S. E., Hixson, J. D., Garcia, P. A., Rabinovici, G. D., Coppola, G., Geschwind, D. H., Petrucelli, L., Miller, B. L., &amp; Seeley, W. W. (2016). Timing and significance of pathological features inC9orf72 expansion-associated frontotemporal dementia. Brain, 139(12), 3202-3216. https://doi.org/10.1093/brain/aww250</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vattem, K., &amp; Wek, R. (2004). Reinitiation involving upstream ORFs regulates ATF4 mRNA translation in mammalian cells. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 101, 11269-11274.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viod&#xe9;, A., Fournier, C., Camuzat, A., Fenaille, F., Latouche, M., Elahi, F., Ber, I. L., Junot, C., Lamari, F., Anquetil, V., &amp; Becher, F. (2018). New antibody-free mass spectrometry-based quantification reveals that C9ORF72 long protein isoform is reduced in the frontal cortex of hexanucleotide-repeat expansion carriers. Frontiers in Neuroscience, 12. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnins.2018.00589</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waite, A. J., B&#xe4;umer, D., East, S., Neal, J., Morris, H. R., Ansorge, O., &amp; Blake, D. J. (2014). Reduced C9orf72 protein levels in frontal cortex of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal degeneration brain with the C9ORF72 hexanucleotide repeat expansion. Neurobiology of Aging, 35, 1779.e5-1779.e13. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2014.01.016</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walter, P., &amp; Ron, D. (2011). The unfolded protein response: from stress pathway to homeostatic regulation. Science, 334, 1081-1086. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.1209038</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Q., Conlon, E. G., Manley, J. L., &amp; Rio, D. C. (2020). Widespread intron retention impairs protein homeostasis in C9orf72 ALS brains. Genome Research, 31, 1705-1715. https://doi.org/10.1101/gr.265298.120</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, R., Xu, X., Hao, Z., Zhang, S., Wu, D., Sun, H., Mu, C., Ren, H., &amp; Wang, G. (2019). Poly-PR in C9ORF72-related amyotrophic lateral sclerosis/frontotemporal dementia causes neurotoxicity by clathrin-dependent endocytosis. Neuroscience Bulletin, 35(5), 889-900. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12264-019-00395-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Webster, C. P., Smith, E. F., Bauer, C. S., Moller, A., Hautbergue, G. M., Ferraiuolo, L., Myszczynska, M. A., Higginbottom, A., Walsh, M. J., Whitworth, A. J., Kaspar, B. K., Meyer, K., Shaw, P. J., Grierson, A. J., &amp; De Vos, K. J. (2016). The C9orf72 protein interacts with Rab1a and the ULK 1 complex to regulate initiation of autophagy. The EMBO Journal, 35(15), 1656-1676. https://doi.org/10.15252/embj.201694401</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wen, X., Tan, W., Westergard, T., Krishnamurthy, K., Markandaiah, S. S., Shi, Y., Lin, S., Shneider, N. A., Monaghan, J., Pandey, U. B., Pasinelli, P., Ichida, J. K., &amp; Trotti, D. (2014). Antisense proline-arginine RAN dipeptides linked to C9ORF72-ALS/FTD form toxic nuclear aggregates that initiate in vitro and in vivo neuronal death. Neuron, 84, 1213-1225. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2014.12.010</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wente, S. R., &amp; Rout, M. P. (2010). The nuclear pore complex and nuclear transport. Cold Spring Harbor Perspectives in Biology, 2(10), a000562. https://doi.org/10.1101/cshperspect.a000562</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westergard, T., McAvoy, K., Russell, K., Wen, X., Pang, Y., Morris, B., Pasinelli, P., Trotti, D., &amp; Haeusler, A. (2019). Repeat-associated non-AUG translation in C9orf72-ALS/FTD is driven by neuronal excitation and stress. EMBO Molecular Medicine, 11, e9423.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams, K. L., Topp, S., Yang, S., Smith, B., Fifita, J. A., Warraich, S. T., Zhang, K. Y., Farrawell, N., Vance, C., Hu, X., Chesi, A., Leblond, C. S., Lee, A., Rayner, S. L., Sundaramoorthy, V., Dobson-Stone, C., Molloy, M. P., van Blitterswijk, M., Dickson, D. W., &#x2026; Blair, I. P. (2016). CCNF mutations in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal dementia. Nature Communications, 7(1). https://doi.org/10.1038/ncomms11253</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao, S., MacNair, L., McGoldrick, P., McKeever, P. M., McLean, J. R., Zhang, M., Keith, J., Zinman, L., Rogaeva, E., &amp; Robertson, J. (2015). Isoform-specific antibodies reveal distinct subcellular localizations of C9orf72 in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Annals of Neurology, 78, 568-583.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao, S., McKeever, P. M., Lau, A., &amp; Robertson, J. (2019). Synaptic localization of C9orf72 regulates post-synaptic glutamate receptor 1 levels. Acta Neuropathologica Communications, 71(7), 1-13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, M., Liang, C., Swaminathan, K., Herrlinger, S., Lai, F., Shiekhattar, R., &amp; Chen, J.-F. (2016). A C9ORF72/SMCR8-containing complex regulates ULK1 and plays a dual role in autophagy. Science Advances, 2, e1601167. https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.1601167</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeh, T. H., Liu, H. F., Li, Y. W., Lu, C. S., Shih, H. Y., Chiu, C. C., Lin, S. J., Huang, Y. C., &amp; Cheng, Y. C. (2018). C9orf72 is essential for neurodevelopment and motility mediated by Cyclin G1. Experimental Neurology, 304, 114-124.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zamiri, B., Reddy, K., Macgregor, R., &amp; Pearson, C. (2014). TMPyP4 porphyrin distorts RNA G-quadruplex structures of the disease-associated r(GGGGCC)n repeat of the C9orf72 gene and blocks interaction of RNA-binding proteins. Journal of Biological Chemistry, 289, 4653-4659.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, D., Iyer, L. M., He, F., &amp; Aravind, L. (2012). Discovery of novel DENN proteins: Implications for the evolution of eukaryotic intracellular membrane structures and human disease. Frontiers in Genetics, 3, 1-10. https://doi.org/10.3389/fgene.2012.00283</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, K., Donnelly, C. J., Haeusler, A. R., Grima, J. C., Machamer, J. B., Steinwald, P., Daley, E. L., Miller, S. J., Cunningham, K. M., Vidensky, S., Gupta, S., Thomas, M. A., Hong, I., Chiu, S.-L., Huganir, R. L., Ostrow, L. W., Matunis, M. J., Wang, J., Sattler, R., &#x2026; Rothstein, J. D. (2015). The C9orf72 repeat expansion disrupts nucleocytoplasmic transport. Nature, 525(7567), 56-61. https://doi.org/10.1038/nature14973</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, K. E., Daigle, J. G., Cunningham, K. M., Coyne, A. N., Ruan, K., Grima, J. C., Bowen, K. E., Wadhwa, H., Yang, P., Rigo, F., Taylor, J. P., Gitler, A. D., Rothstein, J. D., &amp; Lloyd, T. E. (2018). Stress granule assembly disrupts nucleocytoplasmic transport. Cell, 173, 958-971.e17. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2018.03.025</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Y., Burberry, A., Wang, J. Y., Sandoe, J., Ghosh, S., Udeshi, N. D., Svinkina, T., Mordes, D. A., Mok, J., Charlton, M., &amp; Li, Q. Z. (2018). The C9orf72-interacting protein Smcr8 is a negative regulator of autoimmunity and lysosomal exocytosis. Genes and Development, 32, 929-943.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Y.-J., Gendron, T. F., Ebbert, M. T. W., O&#x2019;Raw, A. D., Yue, M., Jansen-West, K., Zhang, X., Prudencio, M., Chew, J., Cook, C. N., Daughrity, L. M., Tong, J., Song, Y., Pickles, S. R., Castanedes-Casey, M., Kurti, A., Rademakers, R., Oskarsson, B., Dickson, D. W., &#x2026; Petrucelli, L. (2018). Poly(GR) impairs protein translation and stress granule dynamics in C9orf72-associated frontotemporal dementia and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nature Medicine, 24(8), 1136-1142. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41591-018-0071-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Y.-J., Gendron, T. F., Grima, J. C., Sasaguri, H., Jansen-West, K., Xu, Y.-F., Katzman, R. B., Gass, J., Murray, M. E., Shinohara, M., Lin, W.-L., Garrett, A., Stankowski, J. N., Daughrity, L., Tong, J., Perkerson, E. A., Yue, M., Chew, J., Castanedes-Casey, M., &#x2026; Petrucelli, L. (2016). C9ORF72 poly(GA) aggregates sequester and impair HR23 and nucleocytoplasmic transport proteins. Nature Neuroscience, 19(5), 668-677. https://doi.org/10.1038/nn.4272</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Y.-J., Jansen-West, K., Xu, Y.-F., Gendron, T. F., Bieniek, K. F., Lin, W.-L., Sasaguri, H., Caulfield, T., Hubbard, J., Daughrity, L., Chew, J., Belzil, V. V., Prudencio, M., Stankowski, J. N., Castanedes-Casey, M., Whitelaw, E., Ash, P. E. A., DeTure, M., Rademakers, R., &#x2026; Petrucelli, L. (2014). Aggregation-prone c9FTD/ALS poly(GA) RAN-translated proteins cause neurotoxicity by inducing ER stress. Acta Neuropathologica, 128(4), 505-524. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00401-014-1336-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu, Q., Jiang, J., Gendron, T. F., McAlonis-Downes, M., Jiang, L., Taylor, A., Diaz Garcia, S., Ghosh Dastidar, S., Rodriguez, M. J., King, P., Zhang, Y., La Spada, A. R., Xu, H., Petrucelli, L., Ravits, J., Da Cruz, S., Lagier-Tourenne, C., &amp; Cleveland, D. W. (2020). Reduced C9ORF72 function exacerbates gain of toxicity from ALS/FTD-causing repeat expansion in C9orf72. Nature Neuroscience, 23(5), 615-624. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41593-020-0619-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zu, T., Guo, S., Bardhi, O., Ryskamp, D. A., Li, J., Khoramian, T. S., Engelbrecht, A., Klippel, K., Chakrabarty, P., Nguyen, L., Golde, T. E., Sonenberg, N. Ranum, L. P. W. (2020). Metformin inhibits RAN translation through PKR pathway and mitigates disease inC9orf72ALS/FTD mice. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, 117(31), 18591-18599. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2005748117</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zu, T., Liu, Y., Banez-Coronel, M., Reid, T., Pletnikova, O., Lewis, J., Miller, T. M., Harms, M. B., Falchook, A. E., Subramony, S. H., Ostrow, L. W., Rothstein, J. D., Troncoso, J. C., &amp; Ranum, L. P. W. (2013). RAN proteins and RNA foci from antisense transcripts in C9ORF72 ALS and frontotemporal dementia. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, 110(51), E4968-E4977. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1315438110</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>