<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">34687220</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>18</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-4598</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>65</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Muscle &amp; nerve</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Muscle Nerve</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Reinnervation as measured by the motor unit size index is associated with preservation of muscle strength in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, but not all muscles reinnervate.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>203</StartPage><EndPage>210</EndPage><MedlinePgn>203-210</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/mus.27444</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION/AIMS">The motor unit size index (MUSIX) may provide insight into reinnervation patterns in diseases such as amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). However, it is not known whether MUSIX detects clinically relevant changes in reinnervation, or if all muscles manifest changes in MUSIX in response to reinnervation after motor unit loss.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Fifty-seven patients with ALS were assessed at 3-month intervals for 12&#x2009;months in four centers. Muscles examined were abductor pollicis brevis, abductor digiti minimi, biceps brachii, and tibialis anterior. Results were split into two groups: muscles with increases in MUSIX and those without increases. Longitudinal changes in MUSIX, motor unit number index (MUNIX), compound muscle action potential amplitude, and Medical Research Council strength score were investigated.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">One hundred thirty-three muscles were examined. Fifty-nine percent of the muscles exhibited an increase in MUSIX during the study. Muscles with MUSIX increases lost more motor units (58% decline in MUNIX at 12&#x2009;months, P&#xa0;&lt;&#x2009;.001) than muscles that did not increase MUSIX (34.6% decline in MUNIX at 12&#x2009;months, P&#xa0;&lt;&#x2009;.001). However, longitudinal changes in muscle strength were similar. When motor unit loss was similar, the absence of a MUSIX increase was associated with a significantly greater loss of muscle strength (P&#xa0;=&#x2009;.002).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION">MUSIX increases are associated with greater motor unit loss but relative preservation of muscle strength. Thus, MUSIX appears to be measuring a clinically relevant response that can provide a quantitative outcome measure of reinnervation in clinical trials. Furthermore, MUSIX suggests that reinnervation may play a major role in determining the progression of weakness.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chan</LastName><ForeName>Young</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8092-4830</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sheffield Institute for Translational Neuroscience, University of Sheffield, Sheffield, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alix</LastName><ForeName>James J P</ForeName><Initials>JJP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sheffield Institute for Translational Neuroscience, University of Sheffield, Sheffield, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Neuwirth</LastName><ForeName>Christoph</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neuromuscular Diseases Unit/ALS Clinic, Kantonsspital, St. Gallen, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Barkhaus</LastName><ForeName>Paul E</ForeName><Initials>PE</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8268-8643</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical College of Wisconsin, Milwaukee, Wisconsin, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Castro</LastName><ForeName>Jos&#xe9;</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosciences, Centro Hospitalar Lisboa Norte-Hospital de Santa Maria, Instituto de Medicina Molecular, Faculty of Medicine, University of Lisbon, Lisboa, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jenkins</LastName><ForeName>Thomas M</ForeName><Initials>TM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sheffield Institute for Translational Neuroscience, University of Sheffield, Sheffield, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McDermott</LastName><ForeName>Christopher J</ForeName><Initials>CJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sheffield Institute for Translational Neuroscience, University of Sheffield, Sheffield, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shaw</LastName><ForeName>Pamela J</ForeName><Initials>PJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sheffield Institute for Translational Neuroscience, University of Sheffield, Sheffield, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>de Carvalho</LastName><ForeName>Mamede</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7556-0158</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosciences, Centro Hospitalar Lisboa Norte-Hospital de Santa Maria, Instituto de Medicina Molecular, Faculty of Medicine, University of Lisbon, Lisboa, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nandedkar</LastName><ForeName>Sanjeev</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Natus Medical, Inc, Hopewell Junction, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>St&#xe5;lberg</LastName><ForeName>Erik</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience, Clinical Neurophysiology, Uppsala University, Uppsala, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Weber</LastName><ForeName>Markus</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neuromuscular Diseases Unit/ALS Clinic, Kantonsspital, St. Gallen, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>IS-BRC-1215-20017</GrantID><Acronym>DH_</Acronym><Agency>Department of Health</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>NF-SI-0617-1007</GrantID><Acronym>DH_</Acronym><Agency>Department of Health</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Muscle Nerve</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7803146</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0148-639X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004576" MajorTopicYN="N">Electromyography</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009046" MajorTopicYN="N">Motor Neurons</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">motor unit number index</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">motor unit size index</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">reinnervation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">strength</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34687220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.27444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, Miller RG, Swash M, et al. El Escorial revisited: revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord. 2000;1:293-299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Dengler R, Eisen A, et al. Electrodiagnostic criteria for diagnosis of ALS. Clin Neurophysiol. 2008;119:497-503.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shefner JM, Al-Chalabi A, Baker MR, et al. A proposal for new diagnostic criteria for ALS. Clin Neurophysiol. 2020;131:1975-1978.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bromberg MB, Forshew DA, Nau KL, Bromberg J, Simmons Z, Fries TJ. Motor unit number estimation, isometric strength, and electromyographic measures in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 1993;16:1213-1219.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neuwirth C, Barkhaus PE, Burkhardt C, et al. Tracking motor neuron loss in a set of six muscles in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis using the motor unit number index (MUNIX): a 15-month longitudinal multicentre trial. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2015;86:1172-1179.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Escorcio-Bezerra ML, Abrahao A, Nunes KF, et al. Motor unit number index and neurophysiological index as candidate biomarkers of presymptomatic motor neuron loss in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 2018;58:204-212.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neuwirth C, Braun N, Claeys KG, et al. Implementing motor unit number index (MUNIX) in a large clinical trial: real world experience from 27 centres. Clin Neurophysiol. 2018;129:1756-1762.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neuwirth C, Burkhardt C, Alix J, et al. Quality control of motor unit number index (MUNIX) measurements in 6 muscles in a single-subject "round-robin" setup. PLoS One. 2016;11:e0153948.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alix JJP, Neuwirth C, Gelder L, et al. Assessment of the reliability of the motor unit size index (MUSIX) in single subject "round-robin" and multi-centre settings. Clin Neurophysiol. 2019;130:666-674.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S, Kiernan MC, Menon P, et al. Study protocol of RESCUE-ALS: a phase 2, randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled study in early symptomatic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients to assess bioenergetic catalysis with CNM-Au8 as a mechanism to slow disease progression. BMJ Open. 2021;11:e041479.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neuwirth C, Barkhaus PE, Burkhardt C, et al. Motor unit number index (MUNIX) detects motor neuron loss in pre-symptomatic muscles in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Neurophysiol. 2017;128:495-500.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobsen AB, Bostock H, Tankisi H. Following disease progression in motor neuron disorders with 3 motor unit number estimation methods. Muscle Nerve. 2019;59:82-87.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jenkins TM, Alix JJP, Fingret J, et al. Longitudinal multi-modal muscle-based biomarker assessment in motor neuron disease. J Neurol. 2020;267:244-256.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nandedkar SD, Barkhaus PE, Stalberg EV. Motor unit number index (MUNIX): principle, method, and findings in healthy subjects and in patients with motor neuron disease. Muscle Nerve. 2010;42:798-807.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swihart BJ, Caffo B, James BD, Strand M, Schwartz BS, Punjabi NM. Lasagna plots: a saucy alternative to spaghetti plots. Epidemiology. 2010;21:621-625.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hines HM, Wehrmacher WH, Thomson JD. Functional changes in nerve and muscle after partial denervation. Am J Physiol. 1945;145:48-53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman H. Local re-innervation in partially denervated muscle: a histophysiological study. Aust J Exp Biol Med Sci. 1950;28:383-397.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wohlfart G. Collateral regeneration in partially denervated muscles. Neurology. 1958;8:175-180.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wohlfart G, Feinstein B, Fex J. The relation of electromyographic to anatomical findings in healthy muscles and neuromuscular diseases. Arch Psychiatr Nervenkr Z Gesamte Neurol Psychiatry. 1954;191:478-492.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McComas AJ, Sica RE, Campbell MJ, Upton AR. Functional compensation in partially denervated muscles. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 1971;34:453-460.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hansen S, Ballantyne JP. A quantitative electrophysiological study of motor neurone disease. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 1978;41:773-783.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dengler R, Konstanzer A, Kuther G, Hesse S, Wolf W, Struppler A. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: macro-EMG and twitch forces of single motor units. Muscle Nerve. 1990;13:545-550.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venkatesh S, Shefner JM, Logigian EL. Does muscle reinnervation produce electromechanical dissociation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis? Muscle Nerve. 1995;18:1335-1337.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Einarsson G, Grimby G, Stalberg E. Electromyographic and morphological functional compensation in late poliomyelitis. Muscle Nerve. 1990;13:165-171.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandberg A, Stalberg E. Changes in macro electromyography over time in patients with a history of polio: a comparison of 2 muscles. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2004;85:1174-1182.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galea V, Fehlings D, Kirsch S, McComas A. Depletion and sizes of motor units in spinal muscular atrophy. Muscle Nerve. 2001;24:1168-1172.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ballantyne JP, Hansen S. A quantitative assessment of reinnervation in the polyneuropathies. Muscle Nerve. 1982;5(Suppl):S127-S134.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bromberg MB. Updating motor unit number estimation (MUNE). Clin Neurophysiol. 2007;118:1-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Turkman A, Swash M. Sensitivity of MUP parameters in detecting change in early ALS. Clin Neurophysiol. 2014;125:166-169.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krarup C. Lower motor neuron involvement examined by quantitative electromyography in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Neurophysiol. 2011;122:414-422.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stalberg E, Schwartz MS, Trontelj JV. Single fibre electromyography in various processes affecting the anterior horn cell. J Neurol Sci. 1975;24:403-415.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dantes M, McComas A. The extent and time course of motoneuron involvement in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 1991;14:416-421.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martineau E, Di Polo A, Vande Velde C, Robitaille R. Dynamic neuromuscular remodeling precedes motor-unit loss in a mouse model of ALS. Elife. 2018;7:e41973.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Sarraj S, King A, Cleveland M, et al. Mitochondrial abnormalities and low grade inflammation are present in the skeletal muscle of a minority of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis; an observational myopathology study. Acta Neuropathol Commun. 2014;2:165.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stalberg E. Electrophysiological studies of reinnervation in ALS. Adv Neurol. 1982;36:47-59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barkhaus PE, Nandedkar SD. Recording characteristics of the surface EMG electrodes. Muscle Nerve. 1994;17:1317-1323.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piasecki M, Ireland A, Piasecki J, et al. Failure to expand the motor unit size to compensate for declining motor unit numbers distinguishes sarcopenic from non-sarcopenic older men. J Physiol. 2018;596:1627-1637.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinelli P, Pisano F, Ceriani F, Miscio G. EMG evaluation of motor neuron sprouting in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ital J Neurol Sci. 1991;12:359-367.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sonjak V, Jacob K, Morais JA, et al. Fidelity of muscle fibre reinnervation modulates ageing muscle impact in elderly women. J Physiol. 2019;597:5009-5023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brandsma JW, Schreuders TA, Birke JA, Piefer A, Oostendorp R. Manual muscle strength testing: intraobserver and interobserver reliabilities for the intrinsic muscles of the hand. J Hand Ther. 1995;8:185-190.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bostock H, Jacobsen AB, Tankisi H. Motor unit number index and compound muscle action potential amplitude. Clin Neurophysiol. 2019;130:1734-1740.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nandedkar SD, Barkhaus PE, Stalberg EV. Motor unit number index (MUNIX) and compound muscle action potential amplitude: a reappraisal. Clin Neurophysiol. 2019;130:2010-2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boekestein WA, Schelhaas HJ, van Putten MJ, Stegeman DF, Zwarts MJ, van Dijk JP. Motor unit number index (MUNIX) versus motor unit number estimation (MUNE): a direct comparison in a longitudinal study of ALS patients. Clin Neurophysiol. 2012;123:1644-1649.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>