<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">34704267</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1531-8249</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>91</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Annals of neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Ann Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Promise of Nucleic Acid Therapeutics for Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>13</StartPage><EndPage>20</EndPage><MedlinePgn>13-20</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/ana.26259</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Nucleic acid therapeutics have been attracting attention as novel drug discovery modalities for intractable diseases, including amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. This review provides an overview of the current status and prospects of antisense oligonucleotide treatment for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Recently, the results of a phase I/II study using the antisense oligonucleotides Tofersen to treat familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with superoxide dismutase 1 mutation have been reported. Intrathecal Tofersen administration resulted in a 36% reduction in superoxide dismutase 1 level in the cerebrospinal fluid. Another report described 2 patients with mutant superoxide dismutase 1 treated with an adeno-associated virus encoding a microRNA targeting superoxide dismutase 1. The first patient, who possessed the fast progressive mutant A5V, received a single intrathecal infusion. Although the patient died of respiratory arrest 16&#xa0;months after treatment, autopsy findings showed a reduction of &gt;90% in superoxide dismutase 1 level in the spinal cord. Clinical trials on antisense oligonucleotide therapies targeting other major amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-causative genes, fused in sarcoma and chromosome 9 open reading frame 72, are ongoing. To attenuate the pathology of TDP-43, strategies targeting regulators of TDP-43 (ataxin 2) and proteins downstream of TDP-43 (stathmin 2) by antisense oligonucleotides are being developed. The advent of nucleic acid therapeutics has enabled to specifically attack the molecules in the amyotrophic lateral sclerosis pathological cascade, expanding the options for therapeutic targets. ANN NEUROL 2022;91:13-20.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 American Neurological Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ito</LastName><ForeName>Daisuke</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4740-1675</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Keio University School of Medicine, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>Serika Fund</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><Agency>the Foundation of Japan Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Association</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><Agency>the Ice Bucket Challenge Grant (Japan Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Association)</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>21H02812</GrantID><Agency>the Ministry of Education, Culture, Sports, Science and Technology of Japan</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Ann Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7707449</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0364-5134</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D009696">Nucleic Acids</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="Y">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005786" MajorTopicYN="N">Gene Expression Regulation</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="Y">drug effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009696" MajorTopicYN="N">Nucleic Acids</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34704267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.26259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Charcot JM. Lecons du Mardi: Policlinique: 1887-1888. Paris: Bureaux du Progr&#xe8;s M&#xe9;dical, 1888.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goetz CG. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: early contributions of Jean-Martin Charcot. Muscle Nerve 2000;23:336-343.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charcot JM. De la scl&#xe9;rose lat&#xe9;rale amyotrophique - Symptomatologie Le&#xe7;ons sur les maladies du syst&#xe8;me nerveux, faites &#xe0; la Salp&#xea;tri&#xe8;re. Paris: Delahaye, 1880.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abel O, Powell JF, Andersen PM, Al-Chalabi A. ALSoD: a user-friendly online bioinformatics tool for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis genetics. Hum Mutat 2012;33:1345-1351.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renton AE, Majounie E, Waite A, et al. A hexanucleotide repeat expansion in C9ORF72 is the cause of chromosome 9p21-linked ALS-FTD. Neuron 2011;72:257-268.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeJesus-Hernandez M, Mackenzie IR, Boeve BF, et al. Expanded GGGGCC hexanucleotide repeat in noncoding region of C9ORF72 causes chromosome 9p-linked FTD and ALS. Neuron 2011;72:245-256.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shahrizaila N, Sobue G, Kuwabara S, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and motor neuron syndromes in Asia. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2016;87:821-830.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marangi G, Traynor BJ. Genetic causes of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: new genetic analysis methodologies entailing new opportunities and challenges. Brain Res 2015;1607:75-93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabatelli M, Moncada A, Conte A, et al. Mutations in the 3&#x2032; untranslated region of FUS causing FUS overexpression are associated with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Hum Mol Genet 2013;22:4748-4755.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujimori K, Ishikawa M, Otomo A, et al. Modeling sporadic ALS in iPSC-derived motor neurons identifies a potential therapeutic agent. Nat Med 2018;24:1579-1589.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brundin P, Melki R, Kopito R. Prion-like transmission of protein aggregates in neurodegenerative diseases. Nat Rev Mol Cell Biol 2010;11:301-307.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayers JI, Paras NA, Prusiner SB. Expanding spectrum of prion diseases. Emerg Top Life Sci 2020;4:155-167.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polymenidou M, Cleveland DW. Biological spectrum of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis prions. Cold Spring Harb Perspect Med 2017;7:a024133.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ito D, Hatano M, Suzuki N. RNA binding proteins and the pathological cascade in ALS/FTD neurodegeneration. Sci Transl Med 2017;9:eaah5436.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swanson CJ, Zhang Y, Dhadda S, et al. A randomized, double-blind, phase 2b proof-of-concept clinical trial in early Alzheimer's disease with lecanemab, an anti-A&#x3b2; protofibril antibody. Alzheimers Res Ther 2021;13:80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finkel RS, Mercuri E, Darras BT, et al. Nusinersen versus sham control in infantile-onset spinal muscular atrophy. N Engl J Med 2017;377:1723-1732.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lefebvre S, Burglen L, Reboullet S, et al. Identification and characterization of a spinal muscular atrophy-determining gene. Cell 1995;80:155-165.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hua Y, Vickers TA, Okunola HL, et al. Antisense masking of an hnRNP A1/A2 intronic splicing silencer corrects SMN2 splicing in transgenic mice. Am J Hum Genet 2008;82:834-848.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hua Y, Sahashi K, Hung G, et al. Antisense correction of SMN2 splicing in the CNS rescues necrosis in a type III SMA mouse model. Genes Dev 2010;24:1634-1644.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Syed YY. Eteplirsen: first global approval. Drugs 2016;76:1699-1704.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dzierlega K, Yokota T. Optimization of antisense-mediated exon skipping for Duchenne muscular dystrophy. Gene Ther 2020;27:407-416.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benson MD, Waddington-Cruz M, Berk JL, et al. Inotersen treatment for patients with hereditary transthyretin amyloidosis. N Engl J Med 2018;379:22-31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosen DR, Siddique T, Patterson D, et al. Mutations in Cu/Zn superoxide dismutase gene are associated with familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nature 1993;362:59-62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borchelt DR, Lee MK, Slunt HS, et al. Superoxide dismutase 1 with mutations linked to familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis possesses significant activity. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 1994;91:8292-8296.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith RA, Miller TM, Yamanaka K, et al. Antisense oligonucleotide therapy for neurodegenerative disease. J Clin Invest 2006;116:2290-2296.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller T, Cudkowicz M, Shaw PJ, et al. Phase 1-2 trial of antisense oligonucleotide Tofersen for SOD1 ALS. N Engl J Med 2020;383:109-119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maki K. Preclinical safety assessments of mRNA-targeting oligonucleotide therapeutics. Transl Regul Sci 2020;2:90-93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borroni B, Gardoni F, Parnetti L, et al. Pattern of Tau forms in CSF is altered in progressive supranuclear palsy. Neurobiol Aging 2009;30:34-40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagshal D, Sankaranarayanan S, Guss V, et al. Divergent CSF tau alterations in two common tauopathies: Alzheimer's disease and progressive supranuclear palsy. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2015;86:244-250.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farlow M, Arnold SE, van Dyck CH, et al. Safety and biomarker effects of solanezumab in patients with Alzheimer's disease. Alzheimers Dement 2012;8:261-271.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roche Group Media Relations. Roche provides update on tominersen programme in manifest Huntington's disease. 2021. Available at: https://www.roche.com/media/releases/med-cor-2021-03-22b.htm. Accessed March 22, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fischer LR, Li Y, Asress SA, et al. Absence of SOD1 leads to oxidative stress in peripheral nerve and causes a progressive distal motor axonopathy. Exp Neurol 2012;233:163-171.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park JH, Elpers C, Reunert J, et al. SOD1 deficiency: a novel syndrome distinct from amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain 2019;142:2230-2237.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendell JR, Al-Zaidy S, Shell R, et al. Single-dose gene-replacement therapy for spinal muscular atrophy. N Engl J Med 2017;377:1713-1722.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mueller C, Berry JD, McKenna-Yasek DM, et al. SOD1 suppression with Adeno-associated virus and MicroRNA in familial ALS. N Engl J Med 2020;383:151-158.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juneja T, Pericak-Vance MA, Laing NG, et al. Prognosis in familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: progression and survival in patients with glu100gly and ala4val mutations in Cu, Zn superoxide dismutase. Neurology 1997;48:55-57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen PM, Forsgren L, Binzer M, et al. Autosomal recessive adult-onset amyotrophic lateral sclerosis associated with homozygosity for Asp90Ala CuZn-superoxide dismutase mutation. A clinical and genealogical study of 36 patients. Brain 1996;119:1153-1172.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polymenidou M, Lagier-Tourenne C, Hutt KR, et al. Long pre-mRNA depletion and RNA missplicing contribute to neuronal vulnerability from loss of TDP-43. Nat Neurosci 2011;14:459-468.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ling JP, Pletnikova O, Troncoso JC, Wong PC. TDP-43 repression of nonconserved cryptic exons is compromised in ALS-FTD. Science 2015;349:650-655.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ling SC, Polymenidou M, Cleveland DW. Converging mechanisms in ALS and FTD: disrupted RNA and protein homeostasis. Neuron 2013;79:416-438.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le Gall L, Anakor E, Connolly O, et al. Molecular and cellular mechanisms affected in ALS. J Pers Med 2020;10:101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaiswal MK. Riluzole and edaravone: a tale of two amyotrophic lateral sclerosis drugs. Med Res Rev 2019;39:733-748.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ito D, Suzuki N. Conjoint pathologic cascades mediated by ALS/FTLD-U linked RNA-binding proteins TDP-43 and FUS. Neurology 2011;77:1636-1643.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer BC, Schuck T, Wheeler JM, et al. Loss of murine TDP-43 disrupts motor function and plays an essential role in embryogenesis. Acta Neuropathol 2010;119:409-419.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sephton CF, Good SK, Atkin S, et al. TDP-43 is a developmentally regulated protein essential for early embryonic development. J Biol Chem 2010;285:6826-6834.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu LS, Cheng WC, Hou SC, et al. TDP-43, a neuro-pathosignature factor, is essential for early mouse embryogenesis. Genesis 2010;48:56-62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishimoto Y, Ito D, Yagi T, et al. Characterization of alternative isoforms and inclusion body of the TAR DNA-binding protein-43. J Biol Chem 2010;285:608-619.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pulst SM, Nechiporuk A, Nechiporuk T, et al. Moderate expansion of a normally biallelic trinucleotide repeat in spinocerebellar ataxia type 2. Nat Genet 1996;14:269-276.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiehl TR, Nechiporuk A, Figueroa KP, et al. Generation and characterization of Sca2 (ataxin-2) knockout mice. Biochem Biophys Res Commun 2006;339:17-24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elden AC, Kim HJ, Hart MP, et al. Ataxin-2 intermediate-length polyglutamine expansions are associated with increased risk for ALS. Nature 2010;466:1069-1075.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Becker LA, Huang B, Bieri G, et al. Therapeutic reduction of ataxin-2 extends lifespan and reduces pathology in TDP-43 mice. Nature 2017;544:367-371.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melamed Z, Lopez-Erauskin J, Baughn MW, et al. Premature polyadenylation-mediated loss of stathmin-2 is a hallmark of TDP-43-dependent neurodegeneration. Nat Neurosci 2019;22:180-190.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prudencio M, Humphrey J, Pickles S, et al. Truncated stathmin-2 is a marker of TDP-43 pathology in frontotemporal dementia. J Clin Invest 2020;130:6080-6092.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown AL, Wilkins OG, Keuss MJ, et al. Common ALS/FTD risk variants in UNC13A exacerbate its cryptic splicing and loss upon TDP-43 mislocalization. bioRxiv 2021. https://doi.org/10.1101/2021.04.02.438170</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang K, Donnelly CJ, Haeusler AR, et al. The C9orf72 repeat expansion disrupts nucleocytoplasmic transport. Nature 2015;525:56-61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freibaum BD, Lu Y, Lopez-Gonzalez R, et al. GGGGCC repeat expansion in C9orf72 compromises nucleocytoplasmic transport. Nature 2015;525:129-133.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jovicic A, Mertens J, Boeynaems S, et al. Modifiers of C9orf72 dipeptide repeat toxicity connect nucleocytoplasmic transport defects to FTD/ALS. Nat Neurosci 2015;18:1226-1229.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim HJ, Kim NC, Wang YD, et al. Mutations in prion-like domains in hnRNPA2B1 and hnRNPA1 cause multisystem proteinopathy and ALS. Nature 2013;495:467-473.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamakawa M, Ito D, Honda T, et al. Characterization of the dipeptide repeat protein in the molecular pathogenesis of c9FTD/ALS. Hum Mol Genet 2015;24:1630-1645.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mori K, Weng SM, Arzberger T, et al. The C9orf72 GGGGCC repeat is translated into aggregating dipeptide-repeat proteins in FTLD/ALS. Science 2013;339:1335-1338.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ash PE, Bieniek KF, Gendron TF, et al. Unconventional translation of C9ORF72 GGGGCC expansion generates insoluble polypeptides specific to c9FTD/ALS. Neuron 2013;77:639-646.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang YJ, Jansen-West K, Xu YF, et al. Aggregation-prone c9FTD/ALS poly(GA) RAN-translated proteins cause neurotoxicity by inducing ER stress. Acta Neuropathol 2014;128:505-524.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang YJ, Gendron TF, Grima JC, et al. C9ORF72 poly(GA) aggregates sequester and impair HR23 and nucleocytoplasmic transport proteins. Nat Neurosci 2016;19:668-677.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo Q, Lehmer C, Martinez-Sanchez A, et al. In situ structure of neuronal C9orf72 poly-GA aggregates reveals proteasome recruitment. Cell 2018;172:696-705 e12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang J, Zhu Q, Gendron TF, et al. Gain of toxicity from ALS/FTD-linked repeat expansions in C9ORF72 is alleviated by antisense oligonucleotides targeting GGGGCC-containing RNAs. Neuron 2016;90:535-550.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y, Dodart JC, Tran H, et al. Variant-selective stereopure oligonucleotides protect against pathologies associated with C9orf72-repeat expansion in preclinical models. Nat Commun 2021;12:847.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tran H, Moazami MP, Yang H, et al. Potent mixed backbone antisense oligonucleotide safely suppresses expression of mutant C9ORF72 transcripts and polydipeptides: first in human pilot study. Research Square preprint 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwiatkowski TJ Jr, Bosco DA, Leclerc AL, et al. Mutations in the FUS/TLS gene on chromosome 16 cause familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Science 2009;323:1205-1208.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vance C, Rogelj B, Hortobagyi T, et al. Mutations in FUS, an RNA processing protein, cause familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis type 6. Science 2009;323:1208-1211.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hicks GG, Singh N, Nashabi A, et al. Fus deficiency in mice results in defective B-lymphocyte development and activation, high levels of chromosomal instability and perinatal death. Nat Genet 2000;24:175-179.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma A, Lyashchenko AK, Lu L, et al. ALS-associated mutant FUS induces selective motor neuron degeneration through toxic gain of function. Nat Commun 2016;7:10465.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnold C. Tailored treatment for ALS poised to move ahead. Nat Med 2019. https://www.nature.com/articles/d41591-019-00013-w</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miccio A, Antoniou P, Ciura S, Kabashi E. Novel genome-editing-based approaches to treat motor neuron diseases: promises and challenges. Mol Ther 2021. (Online ahead of print): https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ymthe.2021.04.003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nieuwenhuis B, Haenzi B, Hilton S, et al. Optimization of adeno-associated viral vector-mediated transduction of the corticospinal tract: comparison of four promoters. Gene Ther 2021;28:56-74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dogbevia GK, Robetamanith M, Sprengel R, Hasan MT. Flexible, AAV-equipped genetic modules for inducible control of gene expression in mammalian brain. Mol Ther Nucleic Acids 2016;5:e309.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>