<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">34748270</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>04</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1468-1331</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>29</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Multimodal assessment of autonomic dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>715</StartPage><EndPage>723</EndPage><MedlinePgn>715-723</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/ene.15177</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND PURPOSE">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) is a neurodegenerative disorder with predominant progressive degeneration of motor neurons and motor deficits, but non-motor symptoms (NMS) such as cognitive and behavioural deficits are frequent and underestimated in current diagnostic pathways. Autonomic dysfunction has occasionally been described, although its frequency and relevance are unclear. The aim of this study was to investigate the role of the autonomic nervous system in ALS using a multimodal approach.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Thirty-seven ALS patients and 40&#xa0;healthy sex- and age-matched controls were included. NMS were studied with the NMS assessment scale for Parkinson's disease and an autonomic subscale was calculated. Cardioautonomic innervation at rest and whilst standing was assessed by different parameters of heart rate variability. Morphological changes (cross-sectional area) of the vagus and median nerves for control were measured with high-resolution ultrasound.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Non-motor symptoms in general were more frequent in ALS patients and correlated inversely with the ALS Functional Rating Scale whereas the autonomic subscore of the NMS assessment scale for Parkinson's disease did not differ between the two groups and was not related to functional impairment. Cardioautonomic assessment solely revealed an increased heart rate at rest in ALS patients, whereas the other heart rate variability parameters did not differ from controls. Structural sonographic investigation of the vagus and median nerves was similar in both groups.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Using a multimodal approach evidence was found for a rather mild cardio-sympathetic overactivity in ALS patients. Overall, autonomic dysfunction seems to be subtle and is not related to the functional state of ALS patients.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 The Authors. European Journal of Neurology published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of European Academy of Neurology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Weise</LastName><ForeName>David</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5772-6609</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Leipzig University Hospital, Leipzig, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Asklepios Fachklinikum Stadtroda, Stadtroda, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Menze</LastName><ForeName>Ina</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Leipzig University Hospital, Leipzig, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Metelmann</LastName><ForeName>Moritz C F</ForeName><Initials>MCF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Leipzig University Hospital, Leipzig, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Woost</LastName><ForeName>Timo B</ForeName><Initials>TB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Leipzig University Hospital, Leipzig, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry and Psychotherapy, Center for Psychosocial Medicine, University Medical Center Hamburg-Eppendorf (UKE), Hamburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Classen</LastName><ForeName>Joseph</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Leipzig University Hospital, Leipzig, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Otto Pelz</LastName><ForeName>Johann</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4391-2280</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Leipzig University Hospital, Leipzig, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9506311</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1351-5101</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001341" MajorTopicYN="N">Autonomic Nervous System</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001342" MajorTopicYN="Y">Autonomic Nervous System Diseases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006339" MajorTopicYN="N">Heart Rate</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008475" MajorTopicYN="N">Median Nerve</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">autonomic nervous system</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">heart rate variability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">high-resolution ultrasound</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">non-motor symptoms</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">vagus nerve</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34748270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ene.15177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Pender N, Pinto-Grau M, Hardiman O. Cognitive and behavioural impairment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Curr Opin Neurol. 2020;33:649-654.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phukan J, Pender NP, Hardiman O. Cognitive impairment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet Neurol. 2007;6:994-1003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardiman O, Al-Chalabi A, Chio A, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat Rev Dis Primers. 2017;3:17071.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swinnen B, Robberecht W. The phenotypic variability of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat Rev Neurol. 2014;10:661-670.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xfc;nther R, Richter N, Sauerbier A, et al. Non-motor symptoms in patients suffering from motor neuron diseases. Front Neurol. 2016;7:117.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piccione EA, Sletten DM, Staff NP, Low PA. Autonomic system and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 2015;51:676-679.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baltadzhieva R, Gurevich T, Korczyn AD. Autonomic impairment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Curr Opin Neurol. 2005;18:487-493.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pavlovic S, Stevic Z, Milovanovic B, et al. Impairment of cardiac autonomic control in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2010;11:272-276.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimizu T. Sympathetic hyperactivity and sympathovagal imbalance in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Eur Neurol Review. 2013;8:46-50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimizu T, Hayashi H, Kato S, Hayashi M, Tanabe H, Oda M. Circulatory collapse and sudden death in respirator-dependent amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Sci. 1994;124:45-55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimizu T, Hayashi M, Kawata A, Mizutani T, Watabe K, Matsubara S. A morphometric study of the vagus nerve in amyotropic lateral sclerosis with circulatory collapse. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2011;12:356-362.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenbohm A, Schmid B, Buckert D, et al. Cardiac findings in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a magnetic resonance imaging study. Front Neurol. 2017;8:479.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pelz JO, Belau E, Henn P, Hammer N, Classen J, Weise D. Sonographic evaluation of the vagus nerves: protocol, reference values and side-to-side differences. Muscle Nerve. 2018;2018(57):766-771.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pelz JO, Belau E, Menze I, Woost TB, Classen J, Weise D. Correlation between sonographic morphology and function of the cervical vagus nerves. Auton Neurosci. 2019;220:102552.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nodera H, Takamatsu N, Shimatani Y, et al. Thinning of cervical nerve roots and peripheral nerves in ALS as measured by sonography. Clin Neurophysiol. 2014;125:1906-1911.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pelz JO, Belau E, Fricke C, Classen J, Weise D. Axonal degeneration of the vagus nerve in Parkinson's disease-a high-resolution ultrasound study. Front Neurol. 2018;9:951.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks B, Miller RG, Munsat SM, TL. El Escorial revisited: revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disorders. 2000;1:293-299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Storch A, Odin P, Trender-Gerhard I, et al. Non-motor symptoms Questionnaire und Scale f&#xfc;r das idiopathische Parkinson-syndrom. Interkulturell adaptierte versionen in deutscher sprache. Nervenarzt. 2010;81:980-985.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaudhuri KR, Martinez-Martin P, Brown RG, et al. The metric properties of a novel non-motor symptoms scale for Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: results from an international pilot study. Mov Disord. 2007;22:1901-1911.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martinez-Martin P, Rodriguez-Blazquez C, Abe K, et al. International study on the psychometric attributes of the non-motor symptoms scale in Parkinson disease. Neurology. 2009;73:1584-1591.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nasreddine ZS, Phillips NA, Bedirian V, et al. The Montreal Cognitive Assessment, MoCA: a brief screening tool for mild cognitive impairment. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2005;53:695-699.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Functional Rating Scale. Assessment of activities of daily living in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Arch Neurol. 1996;53:141-147. doi:10.1001/archneur.1996.00550020045014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heart rate variability: standards of measurement, physiological interpretation and clinical use. Task Force of the European Society of Cardiology and the North American Society of Pacing and Electrophysiology. Circulation 1996;93:1043-1065.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eckberg DL. Sympathovagal balance: a critical appraisal. Circulation. 1997;96:3224-3232.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pelz JO, Busch M, Weinreich A, Saur D, Weise D. Evaluation of freehand high-resolution 3-dimensional ultrasound of the median nerve. Muscle Nerve. 2017;55:206-212.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krzywinski M, Altman N. Visualizing samples with box plots. Nat Methods. 2014;11:119-120.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zucchi E, Ticozzi N, Mandrioli J. Psychiatric symptoms in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: beyond a motor neuron disorder. Front Neurosci. 2019;13:175.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalra S. Magnetic resonance spectroscopy in ALS. Front Neurol. 2019;10:482.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merico A, Cavinato M. Autonomic dysfunction in the early stage of ALS with bulbar involvement. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2011;12:363-367.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pisano F, Miscio G, Mazzuero G, Lanfranchi P, Colombo R, Pinelli P. Decreased heart rate variability in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 1995;18:1225-1231.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linden D, Diehl RR, Berlit P. Reduced baroreflex sensitivity and cardiorespiratory transfer in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Electroencephalogr Clin Neurophysiol. 1998;109:387-390.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nygren I, Fagius J. High resting level and weak response of baroreflex-governed sympathetic outflow in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 2011;43:432-440.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanaka Y, Yamada M, Koumura A, et al. Cardiac sympathetic function in the patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: analysis using cardiac [123I] MIBG scintigraphy. J Neurol. 2013;260:2380-2386.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallo V, Vanacore N, Bueno-de-Mesquita HB, et al. Physical activity and risk of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in a prospective cohort study. Eur J Epidemiol. 2016;31:255-266.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tebar WR, Ritti-Dias RM, Mota J, et al. Relationship between domains of physical activity and cardiac autonomic modulation in adults: a cross-sectional study. Sci Rep. 2020;10:15510.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsukita K, Taguchi T, Sakamaki-Tsukita H, Tanaka K, Suenaga T. The vagus nerve becomes smaller in patients with Parkinson's disease: a preliminary cross-sectional study using ultrasonography. Parkinsonism Relat Disord. 2018;55:148-149.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walter U, Tsiberidou P, Kersten M, Storch A, L&#xf6;hle M. Atrophy of the vagus nerve in Parkinson's disease revealed by high-resolution ultrasonography. Front Neurol. 2018;9:805.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klingelhoefer L, Reichmann H. Pathogenesis of Parkinson disease-the gut-brain axis and environmental factors. Nat Rev Neurol. 2015;11:625-636.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grimm A, D&#xe9;card BF, Athanasopoulou I, Schweikert K, Sinnreich M, Axer H. Nerve ultrasound for differentiation between amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and multifocal motor neuropathy. J Neurol. 2015;262:870-880.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holzapfel K, Naumann M. Ultrasound detection of vagus nerve atrophy in bulbar amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neuroimaging. 2020;30:762-765.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Femminella GD, Rengo G, Komici K, et al. Autonomic dysfunction in Alzheimer's disease: tools for assessment and review of the literature. J Alzheimers Dis. 2014;42:369-377.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellosta Diago E, P&#xe9;rez P&#xe9;rez J, Santos Lasaosa S, et al. Circadian rhythm and autonomic dysfunction in presymptomatic and early Huntington's disease. Parkinsonism Relat Disord. 2017;44:95-100.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hobson-Webb LD, Simmons Z. Ultrasound in the diagnosis and monitoring of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a review. Muscle Nerve. 2019;60:114-123.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schreiber S, Abdulla S, Debska-Vielhaber G, et al. Peripheral nerve ultrasound in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis phenotypes. Muscle Nerve. 2015;51:669-675.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beck M, Giess R, Magnus T, et al. Progressive sudomotor dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2002;73:68-70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shindo K, Watanabe H, Ohta E, Nagasaka T, Shiozawa Z, Takiyama Y. Sympathetic sudomotor neural function in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2011;12:39-44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toepfer M, Folwaczny C, Klauser A, Riepl RL, M&#xfc;ller-Felber W, Pongratz D. Gastrointestinal dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord. 1999;1:15-19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janse van Mantgem MR, van Eijk RPA, van der Burgh HK, et al. Prognostic value of weight loss in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a population-based study. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2020;91:867-875.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenbohm A, Liu M, Nagel G, et al. Phenotypic differences of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) in China and Germany. J Neurol. 2018;265:774-782.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xe1;nchez-Mart&#xed;nez CM, Chore&#xf1;o-Parra JA, Nu&#xf1;ez-Orozco L, Placencia-&#xc1;lvarez N, Alvis-Casta&#xf1;o LM, Guadarrama-Ortiz P. A retrospective study of the clinical phenotype and predictors of survival in non-Caucasian Hispanic patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. BMC Neurol. 2019;19:261.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>