<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">34748676</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>04</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1468-1331</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>29</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Epidemiology and survival trends of motor neurone disease in Northern Ireland from 2015 to 2019.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>707</StartPage><EndPage>714</EndPage><MedlinePgn>707-714</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/ene.15172</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND PURPOSE">This study evaluates the incidence, prevalence and survival trends of motor neurone disease (MND) in Northern Ireland from 2015 to 2019.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">A capture-recapture analysis was performed using five independent data sources. Incidence and prevalence rates were standardized to the European Standard Population. Survival outcomes were analysed using Kaplan-Meier curves and Cox regression analysis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Amongst 254 total cases of MND, capture-recapture analysis estimated three missing cases (case ascertainment 98.8%). Age standardized incidence of captured cases was 3.12 per 100,000 (2.73, 3.50) and standardized prevalence ranged from 9.45 to 6.49 per 100,000 from 2015 to 2019. Standardized incidence and prevalence rates in 2006 were 1.4 and 3.3 per 100,000 respectively. Of identified cases, 133 (52.4%) were male; 94.5% had amyotrophic lateral sclerosis; median age of onset was 67&#xa0;years; median time to diagnosis was 12&#xa0;months (95% confidence interval 11.2, 12.8); survival from diagnosis was 12&#xa0;months (95% confidence interval 10.6, 15.4); 25 (9.8%) reported a family history of MND or frontotemporal dementia; and a known MND-associated genetic mutation was identified in 7.9% of total cases, of which the most common was C9orf72 (5.7% of all patients). Factors associated with improved survival were younger age at onset, longer time to diagnosis, attendance at regional MND clinic, and initial neurology presentation as outpatient (all p&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;0.001).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">The incidence and prevalence of MND in Northern Ireland has increased over the last 10&#xa0;years, in line with increasing rates reported from other European countries. Improved survival was associated with younger age at onset, longer time to diagnosis, attendance at a regional MND clinic and outpatient presentation to a Neurology Department.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 European Academy of Neurology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McCluskey</LastName><ForeName>Gavin</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1008-598X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Royal Victoria Hospital, Belfast, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Northern Ireland Centre for Stratified Medicine, Altnagelvin Hospital Campus, Ulster University, Derry, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Duddy</LastName><ForeName>William</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Northern Ireland Centre for Stratified Medicine, Altnagelvin Hospital Campus, Ulster University, Derry, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Haffey</LastName><ForeName>Stephen</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurophysiology, Royal Victoria Hospital, Belfast, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Morrison</LastName><ForeName>Karen</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Royal Victoria Hospital, Belfast, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, Health and Life Sciences, Queen's University Belfast, Belfast, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Donaghy</LastName><ForeName>Colette</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Altnagelvin Hospital, Derry, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Duguez</LastName><ForeName>Stephanie</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Northern Ireland Centre for Stratified Medicine, Altnagelvin Hospital Campus, Ulster University, Derry, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9506311</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1351-5101</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015994" MajorTopicYN="N">Incidence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016472" MajorTopicYN="Y">Motor Neuron Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009660" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Northern Ireland</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015995" MajorTopicYN="N">Prevalence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">incidence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">motor neurone disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">survival</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34748676</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ene.15172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2; A, Logroscino G, Hardiman O, et al. Prognostic factors in ALS: a critical review. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2009;10(5-6):310-323.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yedavalli V, Patil A, Shah P. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and its mimics/variants: a comprehensive review. J Clin Imaging Sci. 2018;8(1):53. doi:10.4103/jcis.JCIS_40_18</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Connolly O, Le Gall L, McCluskey G, Donaghy CG, Duddy WJ, Duguez S. A systematic review of genotype-phenotype correlation across cohorts having causal mutations of different genes in ALS. J Pers Med. 2020;10(3):58. doi:10.3390/jpm10030058</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arthur KC, Calvo A, Price TR, Geiger JT, Chi&#xf2; A, Traynor BJ. Projected increase in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis from 2015 to 2040. Nat Commun. 2016;7(1):12408.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longinetti E, Fang F. Epidemiology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: an update of recent literature. Curr Opin Neurol. 2019;32(5):771-776.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore A, Young CA, Hughes DA. Health utilities and costs for motor neurone disease. Value Health. 2019;22(11):1257-1265. 10.1016/j.jval.2019.05.011</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenbohm A, Peter RS, Erhardt S, et al. Epidemiology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in southern Germany. J Neurol. 2017;264(4):749-757.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leighton DJ, Newton J, Stephenson LJ, et al. Changing epidemiology of motor neurone disease in Scotland. J Neurol. 2019;266(4):817-825.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donaghy C, Clarke J, Patterson C, Kee F, Hardiman O, Patterson V. The epidemiology of motor neuron disease in Northern Ireland using capture-recapture methodology. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2010;11(4):374-378.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hulsen T, de Vlieg J, Alkema W. BioVenn-a web application for the comparison and visualization of biological lists using area-proportional Venn diagrams. BMC Genom. 2008;9(1):488.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eurostat. Revision of the European Standard Population: Report of the Eurostat's task force. 2013 Edition ed. European Union; 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Traynor BJ, Codd MB, Corr B, Ford C, Frost E, Hardiman O. Incidence and prevalence of ALS in Ireland, 1995-1997: a population-based study. Neurology. 1999;52(3):504-509. doi:10.1212/WNL.52.3.504</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rooney J, Byrne S, Heverin M, et al. A multidisciplinary clinic approach improves survival in ALS: a comparative study of ALS in Ireland and Northern Ireland. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2015;86(5):496-501. doi:10.1136/jnnp-2014-309601</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Opie-Martin S, Ossher L, Bredin A, et al. Motor neuron disease register for England, Wales and Northern Ireland-an analysis of incidence in England. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2021;22(102):86-93. doi:10.1080/21678421.2020.1812661</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palese F, Sartori A, Verriello L, et al. Epidemiology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in Friuli-Venezia Giulia, north-eastern Italy, 2002-2014: a retrospective population-based study. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2019;20(1-2):90-99. doi:10.1080/21678421.2018.1511732</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benjaminsen E, Alstadhaug KB, Gulsvik M, Baloch FK, Odeh F. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in Nordland County, Norway, 2000-2015: prevalence, incidence, and clinical features. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2018;19(7-8):522-527. doi:10.1080/21678421.2018.1513534</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longinetti E, Regod&#xf3;n Wallin A, Samuelsson K, et al. The Swedish motor neuron disease quality registry. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2018;19(7-8):528-537. doi:10.1080/21678421.2018.1497065</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marin B, Boum&#xe9;diene F, Logroscino G, et al. Variation in worldwide incidence of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a meta-analysis. Int J Epidemiol. 2017;46(1):57-74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huisman MHB, de Jong SW, van Doormaal PTC, et al. Population based epidemiology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis using capture-recapture methodology. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2011;82(10):1165-1170.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wittie M, Nelson LM, Usher S, Ward K, Benatar M. Utility of capture-recapture methodology to assess completeness of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis case ascertainment. Neuroepidemiology. 2013;40(2):133-141.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brittain S, B&#xf6;hning D. Estimators in capture-recapture studies with two sources. Adv Stat Anal. 2009;93(1):23-47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chao A. An overview of closed capture-recapture models. J Agri Biol Environ Stat. 2001;6(2):158-175.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renton AE, Chi&#xf2; A, Traynor BJ. State of play in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis genetics. Nat Neurosci. 2014;17(1):17-23. doi:10.1038/nn.3584</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shepheard SR, Parker MD, Cooper-Knock J, et al. Value of systematic genetic screening of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2021;92(5):510-518. doi:10.1136/jnnp-2020-325014</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jayaprakash K, Glasmacher SA, Pang B, et al. Riluzole prescribing, uptake and treatment discontinuation in people with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in Scotland. J Neurol. 2020;267(8):2459-2461.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nygren I, Antonova K, Mattsson P, Askmark H. The ALS/MND prevalence in Sweden estimated by riluzole sales statistics. Acta Neurol Scand. 2005;111(3):180-184.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rooney J, Byrne S, Heverin M, et al. Survival analysis of Irish amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients diagnosed from 1995-2010. PLoS One. 2013;8(9):e74733. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0074733</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stavroulakis T, Walsh T, Shaw PJ, McDermott CJ. Gastrostomy use in motor neurone disease (MND): a review, meta-analysis and survey of current practice. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2013;14(2):96-104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang B, Shi X. Percutaneous endoscopic gastrostomy versus fluoroscopic gastrostomy in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) sufferers with nutritional impairment: a meta-analysis of current studies. Oncotarget. 2017;8(60):102244-102253.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>