<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">34779525</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>17</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1531-8257</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>37</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Movement disorders : official journal of the Movement Disorder Society</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Mov Disord</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A Novel TFG Mutation in a Korean Family with &#x3b1;-Synucleinopathy and Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>384</StartPage><EndPage>391</EndPage><MedlinePgn>384-391</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/mds.28857</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Tropomyosin-receptor kinase fused gene (TFG) functions as a regulator of intracellular protein packaging and trafficking at the endoplasmic reticulum exit sites. TFG has recently been proposed as a cause of multisystem proteinopathy.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES">Here, we describe a Korean family presenting with Parkinson's disease or amyotrophic lateral sclerosis caused by a novel variant of TFG (c.1148&#x2009;G&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;A, p.Arg383His).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">We collected clinical, genetic, dopamine transporter imaging, nerve conduction, and electromyography data from the seven subjects. To verify the pathogenicity of the R383H variant, we studied cell viability and the abnormal aggregation of &#x3b1;-synuclein and TAR DNA-binding protein 43 (TDP-43) in HeLa cells expressing R383H-TFG.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">The clinical phenotypes of the R383H-TFG mutation varied; of the five family members, one had Parkinson's disease, three had subclinical parkinsonism, and one (the proband) had amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. The individual with multiple system atrophy was the proband's paternal cousin, but the TFG genotype was not confirmed due to unavailability of samples. Our in vitro studies showed that R383H-TFG overexpression impaired cell viability. In cells co-expressing R383H-TFG and &#x3b1;-synuclein, insoluble &#x3b1;-synuclein aggregates increased in concentration and were secreted from the cells and co-localized with R383H-TFG. The levels of cytoplasmic insoluble aggregates of TDP-43 increased in HeLa cells expressing R383H-TFG and co-localized with R383H-TFG.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Clinical and in vitro studies have supported the pathogenic role of the novel TFG mutation in &#x3b1;-synucleinopathy and TDP-43 proteinopathy. These findings expand the phenotypic spectrum of TFG and suggest a pivotal role of endoplasmic reticulum dysfunction during neurodegeneration. &#xa9; 2021 International Parkinson and Movement Disorder Society.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 International Parkinson and Movement Disorder Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yoo</LastName><ForeName>Dallah</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9736-6118</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Kyung Hee University Hospital, Kyung Hee University College of Medicine, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Wonjae</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Sciences, Neuroscience Research Institute, and Department of Medicine, Seoul National University College of Medicine, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neuramedy Co., Ltd, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Seung-Jae</ForeName><Initials>SJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Sciences, Neuroscience Research Institute, and Department of Medicine, Seoul National University College of Medicine, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sung</LastName><ForeName>Jung-Joon</ForeName><Initials>JJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Seoul National University Hospital, Seoul National University College of Medicine, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jeon</LastName><ForeName>Gye Sun</ForeName><Initials>GS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Seoul National University Hospital, Seoul National University College of Medicine, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biomedical Research Institute, Seoul National University Hospital, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ban</LastName><ForeName>Jae-Jun</ForeName><Initials>JJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Seoul National University Hospital, Seoul National University College of Medicine, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biomedical Research Institute, Seoul National University Hospital, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shin</LastName><ForeName>Chaewon</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4157-492X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Neuroscience Center, Chungnam National University Sejong Hospital, Chungnam National University College of Medicine, Sejong-si, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Jungho</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Molecular and Cellular Biology, Department of Life Science, Sogang University, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Hyo Sun</ForeName><Initials>HS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Molecular and Cellular Biology, Department of Life Science, Sogang University, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ahn</LastName><ForeName>Tae-Beom</ForeName><Initials>TB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Kyung Hee University Hospital, Kyung Hee University College of Medicine, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Mov Disord</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8610688</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0885-3185</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D011506">Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C096163">TFG protein, human</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006367" MajorTopicYN="N">HeLa Cells</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009154" MajorTopicYN="N">Mutation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011506" MajorTopicYN="Y">Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D056910" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Republic of Korea</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000080874" MajorTopicYN="Y">Synucleinopathies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">endoplasmic reticulum</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">parkinsonism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tropomyosin-receptor kinase fused gene (TFG)</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>57</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34779525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mds.28857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Greco A, Mariani C, Miranda C, et al. The DNA rearrangement that generates the TRK-T3 oncogene involves a novel gene on chromosome 3 whose product has a potential coiled-coil domain. Mol Cell Biol 1995;15(11):6118-6127.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hern&#xe1;ndez L, Pinyol M, Hern&#xe1;ndez S, et al. TRK-fused gene (TFG) is a new partner of ALK in anaplastic large cell lymphoma producing two structurally different TFG-ALK translocations. Blood 1999;94(9):3265-3268.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takeuchi S, Masuda C, Maebayashi H, Tooyama I. Immunohistochemical mapping of TRK-fused gene products in the rat brainstem. Acta Histochem Cytochem 2012;45(1):57-64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Witte K, Schuh AL, Hegermann J, et al. TFG-1 function in protein secretion and oncogenesis. Nat Cell Biol 2011;13(5):550-558.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yagi T, Ito D, Suzuki N. Evidence of TRK-fused gene (TFG1) function in the ubiquitin-proteasome system. Neurobiol Dis 2014;66:83-91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishiura H, Sako W, Yoshida M, et al. The TRK-fused gene is mutated in hereditary motor and sensory neuropathy with proximal dominant involvement. Am J Hum Genet 2012;91(2):320-329.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slosarek EL, Schuh AL, Pustova I, et al. Pathogenic TFG mutations underlying hereditary spastic paraplegia impair secretory protein trafficking and axon fasciculation. Cell Rep 2018;24(9):2248-2260.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee S-S, Lee HJ, Park J-M, et al. Proximal dominant hereditary motor and sensory neuropathy with proximal dominance association with mutation in the TRK-fused gene. JAMA Neurol 2013;70(5):607-615.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elsayed LEO, Mohammed IN, Hamed AAA, et al. Hereditary spastic paraplegias: identification of a novel SPG57 variant affecting TFG oligomerization and description of HSP subtypes in Sudan. Eur J Hum Genet 2016;25(1):100-110.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsai PC, Huang YH, Guo YC, et al. A novel TFG mutation causes Charcot-Marie-tooth disease type 2 and impairs TFG function. Neurology 2014;83(10):903-912.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li H, Durbin R. Fast and accurate long-read alignment with Burrows-Wheeler transform. Bioinformatics 2010;26(5):589-595.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKenna A, Hanna M, Banks E, et al. The genome analysis toolkit: a MapReduce framework for analyzing next-generation DNA sequencing data. Genome Res 2010;20(9):1297-1303.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLaren W, Gil L, Hunt SE, et al. The Ensembl variant effect predictor. Genome Biol 2016;17(1):122</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X, Wu C, Li C, Boerwinkle E. dbNSFP v3.0: a one-stop database of functional predictions and annotations for human nonsynonymous and splice-site SNVs. Hum Mutat 2016;37(3):235-241.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Auton A, Abecasis GR, Altshuler DM, et al. A global reference for human genetic variation. Nature 2015;526(7571):68-74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karczewski KJ, Weisburd B, Thomas B, et al. The ExAC browser: displaying reference data information from over 60 000 exomes. Nucleic Acids Res 2017;45(D1):D840-D845.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanna MG, Block S, Frankel EB, et al. TFG facilitates outer coat disassembly on COPII transport carriers to promote tethering and fusion with ER-Golgi intermediate compartments. Proc Natl Acad Sci 2017;114(37):E7707-E7716.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamashita S, Kimura E, Zhang Z, et al. Muscle pathology of hereditary motor and sensory neuropathy with proximal dominant involvement with TFG mutation. Muscle Nerve 2019;60(6):739-744.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richards S, Aziz N, Bale S, et al. Standards and guidelines for the interpretation of sequence variants: a joint consensus recommendation of the American College of Medical Genetics and Genomics and the Association for Molecular Pathology. Genet Med 2015;17(5):405-423.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeJesus-Hernandez M, Mackenzie IR, Boeve BF, et al. Expanded GGGGCC hexanucleotide repeat in noncoding region of C9ORF72 causes chromosome 9p-linked FTD and ALS. Neuron 2011;72(2):245-256.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lesage S, Le Ber I, Condroyer C, et al. C9orf72 repeat expansions are a rare genetic cause of parkinsonism. Brain 2013;136(Pt 2):385-391.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jang A, Lee HJ, Suk JE, Jung JW, Kim KP, Lee SJ. Non-classical exocytosis of alpha-synuclein is sensitive to folding states and promoted under stress conditions. J Neurochem 2010;113(5):1263-1274.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jankovic J, Rajput AH, McDermott MP, Perl DP. Group ftPS. The evolution of diagnosis in early Parkinson disease. Arch Neurol 2000;57(3):369-372.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor JP. Multisystem proteinopathy: intersecting genetics in muscle, bone, and brain degeneration. Neurology 2015;85(8):658-660.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watts GD, Wymer J, Kovach MJ, et al. Inclusion body myopathy associated with Paget disease of bone and frontotemporal dementia is caused by mutant valosin-containing protein. Nat Genet 2004;36(4):377-381.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson JO, Mandrioli J, Benatar M, et al. Exome sequencing reveals VCP mutations as a cause of familial ALS. Neuron 2010;68(5):857-864.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Obeidi E, Al-Tahan S, Surampalli A, et al. Genotype-phenotype study in patients with valosin-containing protein mutations associated with multisystem proteinopathy. Clin Genet 2018;93(1):119-125.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van de Warrenburg BP, Schouten MI, de Bot ST, et al. Clinical exome sequencing for cerebellar ataxia and spastic paraplegia uncovers novel gene-disease associations and unanticipated rare disorders. Eur J Hum Genet 2016;24(10):1460-1466.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicolau S, Liewluck T. TFG: at the crossroads of motor neuron disease and myopathy. Muscle Nerve 2019;60(6):645-647.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peotter J, Kasberg W, Pustova I, Audhya A. COPII-mediated trafficking at the ER/ERGIC interface. Traffic 2019;20(7):491-503.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spillantini MG, Crowther RA, Jakes R, Hasegawa M, Goedert M. Alpha-synuclein in filamentous inclusions of Lewy bodies from Parkinson's disease and dementia with Lewy bodies. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 1998;95(11):6469-6473.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kitada T, Asakawa S, Hattori N, et al. Mutations in the parkin gene cause autosomal recessive juvenile parkinsonism. Nature 1998;392(6676):605-608.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leroy E, Boyer R, Auburger G, et al. The ubiquitin pathway in Parkinson's disease. Nature 1998;395(6701):451-452.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neumann M, Sampathu DM, Kwong LK, et al. Ubiquitinated TDP-43 in frontotemporal lobar degeneration and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Science 2006;314(5796):130-133.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackenzie IRA, Rademakers R, Neumann M. TDP-43 and FUS in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal dementia. Lancet Neurol 2010;9(10):995-1007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cicardi ME, Cristofani R, Rusmini P, et al. Tdp-25 routing to autophagy and proteasome ameliorates its aggregation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis target cells. Sci Rep 2018;8(1):12390</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Che MX, Jiang LL, Li HY, Jiang YJ, Hu HY. TDP-35 sequesters TDP-43 into cytoplasmic inclusions through binding with RNA. FEBS Lett 2015;589(15):1920-1928.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maeda K, Idehara R, Mukaisho KI. Presence of colocalised phosphorylated TDP-43 and TFG proteins in the frontotemporal lobes of HMSN-P. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2020;91(11):1231-1232.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>