<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">34787317</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>18</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-4598</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>65</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Muscle &amp; nerve</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Muscle Nerve</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Documentation of advance care planning forms in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>187</StartPage><EndPage>192</EndPage><MedlinePgn>187-192</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/mus.27462</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION/AIMS">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) is a neurodegenerative disorder characterized by progressive weakness. Survival is typically only a few years from symptom onset. The often-predictable disease course creates opportunities to complete advance care planning (ACP) forms. The Physician Orders for Life-Sustaining Treatment (POLST) is a broadly used ACP paradigm to communicate end-of-life wishes but has not been well-studied in the ALS population.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">In this retrospective chart review study, patients diagnosed with ALS seen between 2014 and 2018 at an academic ALS center were identified. Demographic information, clinical characteristics, and ACP data were collected.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Of 513 patients identified, 30% had an ACP document. POLST forms were competed in 16.6% of patients with 73.8% of forms signed by a neurologist. Only 5.1% of patients saw a palliative care physician. Palliative care consultation was associated with having an POLST on file (P&#xa0;&lt;&#x2009;.001). Patients with completed POLST forms were significantly more likely to have been seen in clinic more frequently (P&#xa0;&lt;&#x2009;.001) and have a lower ALS Functional Rating Scale-Revised score on last visit (P&#xa0;=&#x2009;.005).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION">Less than one third of patients with ALS completed an ACP document, and only a small percentage completed POLST forms. The data suggest a need for greater documentation of goals of care in the ALS population.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Takacs</LastName><ForeName>Sara M</ForeName><Initials>SM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8125-2987</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Indiana University School of Medicine, Indiana University Health, Indianapolis, Indiana, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Comer</LastName><ForeName>Amber R</ForeName><Initials>AR</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6242-8940</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Sciences, Indiana University School of Health and Human Sciences, Indianapolis, Indiana, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Muscle Nerve</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7803146</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0148-639X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D032722" MajorTopicYN="Y">Advance Care Planning</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004282" MajorTopicYN="N">Documentation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010166" MajorTopicYN="N">Palliative Care</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ALSFRS-R</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">POLST</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">advance care planning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">motor neuron disease</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34787317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.27462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Everett EA, Pedowitz E, Maiser S, et al. Top ten tips palliative care clinicians should know about amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Palliat Med. 2020;23:842-847.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comer AR, Gaffney M, Stone CL, Torke A. Physician understanding and application of surrogate decision-making laws in clinical practice. AJOB Empir Bioeth. 2017;8:198-204.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shalowitz DI, Garrett-Mayer E, Wendler D. The accuracy of surrogate decision makers: a systematic review. Arch Intern Med. 2006;166:493-497.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levi BH, Simmons Z, Hanna C, et al. Advance care planning for patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2017;18:388-396.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comer AR, Hickman SE, Slaven JE, et al. Assessment of discordance between surrogate care goals and medical treatment provided to older adults with serious illness. JAMA Netw Open. 2020;3:e205179.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rao JK, Anderson LA, Lin FC, Laux JP. Completion of advance directives among U.S. consumers. Am J Prev Med. 2014;46:65-70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borasio GD, Shaw PJ, Hardiman O, et al. Standards of palliative care for patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: results of a European survey. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord. 2001;2:159-164.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ganzini L, Johnston WS, Silveira MJ. The final month of life in patients with ALS. Neurology. 2002;59:428-431.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silverstein MD, Stocking CB, Antel JP, Beckwith J, Roos RP, Siegler M. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and life-sustaining therapy: patients' desires for information, participation in decision making, and life-sustaining therapy. Mayo Clin Proc. 1991;66:906-913.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munroe CA, Sirdofsky MD, Kuru T, Anderson ED. End-of-life decision making in 42 patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Respir Care. 2007;52:996-999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seeber AA, Hijdra A, Vermeulen M, Willems DL. Discussions about treatment restrictions in chronic neurologic diseases: a structured review. Neurology. 2012;78:590-597.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van den Berg JP, Kalmijn S, Lindeman E, et al. Multidisciplinary ALS care improves quality of life in patients with ALS. Neurology. 2005;65:1264-1267.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Traynor BJ, Alexander M, Corr B, Frost E, Hardiman O. Effect of a multidisciplinary amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) clinic on ALS survival: a population based study, 1996-2000. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2003;74:1258-1261.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benditt JO, Smith TS, Tonelli MR. Empowering the individual with ALS at the end-of-life: disease-specific advance care planning. Muscle Nerve. 2001;24:1706-1709.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National POLST. Directory of POLST programs. https://polst.org/state-programs. Accessed July 15, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hickman SE, Keevern E, Hammes BJ. Use of the physician orders for life-sustaining treatment program in the clinical setting: a systematic review of the literature. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2015;63:341-350.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hickman SE, Nelson CA, Moss AH, et al. Use of the Physician Orders for Life-Sustaining Treatment (POLST) paradigm program in the hospice setting. J Palliat Med. 2009;12:133-141.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hafer J, Jensen S, Wiedau-Pazos M, Mehta AK. Assessment of feasibility and utility of universal referral to specialty palliative care in a multidisciplinary amyotrophic lateral sclerosis clinic: a cohort study. Muscle Nerve. 2021;63:818-823.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehta AK, Blackhall LJ. Physician orders for life-sustaining treatment and ICU admission near the end of life. JAMA. 2020;324:608.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hickman SE, Nelson CA, Perrin NA, Moss AH, Hammes BJ, Tolle SW. A comparison of methods to communicate treatment preferences in nursing facilities: traditional practices versus the physician orders for life-sustaining treatment program. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2010;58:1241-1248.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanson LC, Rodgman E. The use of living wills at the end of life. A national study. Arch Intern Med. 1996;156:1018-1022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burchardi N, Rauprich O, Hecht M, Beck M, Vollmann J. Discussing living wills. A qualitative study of a German sample of neurologists and ALS patients. J Neurol Sci. 2005;237:67-74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Truog RD, Fried TR. Physician orders for life-sustaining treatment and limiting overtreatment at the end of life. JAMA. 2020;323:934-935.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y, Kline D, Aerts S, et al. Inpatient palliative care for neurological disorders: lessons from a large retrospective series. J Palliat Med. 2017;20:59-64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Back AL, Arnold RM, Tulsky JA, Baile WF, Fryer-Edwards KA. Teaching communication skills to medical oncology fellows. J Clin Oncol. 2003;21:2433-2436.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelley AS, Back AL, Arnold RM, et al. Geritalk: communication skills training for geriatric and palliative medicine fellows. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2012;60:332-337.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnold RM, Back AL, Barnato AE, et al. The critical care communication project: improving fellows' communication skills. J Crit Care. 2015;30:250-254.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Creutzfeldt CJ, Kluger B, Kelly AG, et al. Neuropalliative care: priorities to move the field forward. Neurology. 2018;91:217-226.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehta AK, Najjar S, May N, Shah B, Blackhall L. A needs assessment of palliative care education among the United States adult neurology e-pub residency programs. J Palliat Med. 2018;21:1448-1457.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brizzi K, Paganoni S, Zehm A, De Marchi F, Berry JD. Integration of a palliative care specialist in an amyotrophic lateral sclerosis clinic: observations from one center. Muscle Nerve. 2019;60:137-140.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips JN, Besbris J, Foster LA, Kramer NM, Maiser S, Mehta AK. Models of outpatient neuropalliative care for patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology. 2020;95:782-788.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grogan J, Simmons Z. Palliative specialists for patients with ALS: making best use of a limited resource. Muscle Nerve. 2021;63:790-792.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stephens HE, Young J, Felgoise SH, Simmons Z. A qualitative study of multidisciplinary ALS clinic use in the United States. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2015;17:55-61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Traxinger K, Kelly C, Johnson BA, Lyles RH, Glass JD. Prognosis and epidemiology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: analysis of a clinic population, 1997-2011. Neurol Clin Pract. 2013;3:313-320.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ringholz GM, Appel SH, Bradshaw M, Cooke NA, Mosnik DM, Schulz PE. Prevalence and patterns of cognitive impairment in sporadic ALS. Neurology. 2005;65:586-590.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Connolly S, Galvin M, Hardiman O. End-of-life management in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet Neurol. 2015;14:435-442.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Creutzfeldt CJ, Robinson MT, Holloway RG. Neurologists as primary palliative care providers: communication and practice approaches. Neurol Clin Pract. 2016;6:40-48.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>