<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">34841512</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>07</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1600-0404</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>145</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Acta neurologica Scandinavica</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Acta Neurol Scand</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Novel TBK1 variant associated with Frontotemporal Dementia overlap syndrome.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>399</StartPage><EndPage>406</EndPage><MedlinePgn>399-406</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/ane.13562</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Recently, TANK binding kinase 1 (TBK1) mutation has been reported as a causative gene for overlap frontotemporal dementia (FTD)-amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) syndrome. However, there are no reports from families of South Asian ethnicity.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To report a case study of a family with the proband having overlap FTD-ALS syndrome caused by a novel TBK1 variant.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Clinical, brain imaging, genetic analysis and laboratory data of the patient with FTD-ALS were performed. In addition, family-based segregation analysis of identified novel variants was also done.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">This study pertains to genetic analysis in 11&#xa0;members in a family with only one member affected with overlap FTD-ALS syndrome. The whole-exome sequencing analysis in the symptomatic member showed a novel loss-of-function (LoF) variant c.1810G&gt;T(p.E604X) in the TBK1&#xa0;gene. Neuroimaging showed a pattern of asymmetric frontotemporal atrophy and hypometabolism. Segregation analysis of the variation demonstrated its presence in several family members, although none of the other members was symptomatic. Further, we observed another missense variation in the NEFH gene (p.Pro683Leu) which was seen in the symptomatic and two asymptomatic family members, the pathogenicity of which is unclear.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This is the first study of a rare novel TBK1 variant associated with FTD-ALS from India. Asymptomatic family members with the variant have important clinical implications and necessitate the genetic evaluation and long-term follow-up of family members of patients detected with TBK1&#xa0;mutations. Therefore, although infrequent, genetic screening for the TBK1&#xa0;gene should be considered when encountering overlap FTD syndromes.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 John Wiley &amp; Sons A/S. Published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Arshad</LastName><ForeName>Faheem</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2102-7937</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, National Institute of Mental Health and Neurosciences (NIMHANS), Bengaluru, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vengalil</LastName><ForeName>Seena</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, National Institute of Mental Health and Neurosciences (NIMHANS), Bengaluru, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nalini</LastName><ForeName>Atchayaram</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, National Institute of Mental Health and Neurosciences (NIMHANS), Bengaluru, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Polavarapu</LastName><ForeName>Kiran</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, National Institute of Mental Health and Neurosciences (NIMHANS), Bengaluru, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Genomics and Molecular Medicine, CSIR-Institute of Genomics and Integrative Biology, New Delhi, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shamim</LastName><ForeName>Uzma</ForeName><Initials>U</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Neurology, Department of Medicine, The Ottawa Hospital, Ottawa, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jabeen</LastName><ForeName>Shumyla</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuroimaging and Interventional Radiology, NIMHANS, Bengaluru, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nagaraj</LastName><ForeName>Chandana</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuroimaging and Interventional Radiology, NIMHANS, Bengaluru, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ramakrishnan</LastName><ForeName>Subasree</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, National Institute of Mental Health and Neurosciences (NIMHANS), Bengaluru, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Faruq</LastName><ForeName>Mohammad</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Neurology, Department of Medicine, The Ottawa Hospital, Ottawa, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alladi</LastName><ForeName>Suvarna</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, National Institute of Mental Health and Neurosciences (NIMHANS), Bengaluru, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Denmark</Country><MedlineTA>Acta Neurol Scand</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0370336</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0001-6314</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 2.7.11.1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D017346">Protein Serine-Threonine Kinases</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 2.7.11.1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C403191">TBK1 protein, human</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Frontotemporal Dementia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005820" MajorTopicYN="N">Genetic Testing</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009154" MajorTopicYN="N">Mutation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017346" MajorTopicYN="Y">Protein Serine-Threonine Kinases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">
TBK1
</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">frontotemporal dementia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">loss-of-function</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">missense variation</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34841512</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ane.13562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>McKhann GM, Albert MS, Grossman M, Miller B, Dickson D, Trojanowski JQ. Clinical and pathological diagnosis of frontotemporal dementia: report of the work group on frontotemporal dementia and pick's disease. Arch Neurol. 2001;58(11):1803-1809.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldman JS, Farmer JM, Wood EM, et al. Comparison of family histories in FTLD subtypes and related tauopathies. Neurology. 2005;65(11):1817-1819.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rohrer JD, Guerreiro R, Vandrovcova J, et al. The heritability and genetics of frontotemporal lobar degeneration. Neurology. 2009;73(18):1451-1456.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lomen-Hoerth C, Anderson T, Miller B. The overlap of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal dementia. Neurology. 2002;59(7):1077-1079.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gijselinck I, Van Langenhove T, van der Zee J, et al. A C9orf72 promoter repeat expansion in a Flanders-Belgian cohort with disorders of the frontotemporal lobar degeneration-amyotrophic lateral sclerosis spectrum: a gene identification study. Lancet Neurol. 2012;11(1):54-65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsuji H, Arai T, Kametani F, et al. Molecular analysis and biochemical classification of TDP-43 proteinopathy. Brain. 2012;135(11):3380-3391.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Majo M, Topp SD, Smith BN, et al. ALS-associated missense and nonsense TBK1 mutations can both cause loss of kinase function. Neurobiol Aging. 2018;71:266.e1-266.e10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui R, Tuo M, Li P, Zhou C. Association between TBK1 mutations and risk of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis/frontotemporal dementia spectrum: a meta-analysis. Neurol Sci. 2018;39(5):811-820.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Blitterswijk M, Baker MC, DeJesus-Hernandez M, et al. C9ORF72 repeat expansions in cases with previously identified pathogenic mutations. Neurology. 2013;81(15):1332-1341.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Chalabi A, Andersen PM, Nilsson P, et al. Deletions of the heavy neurofilament subunit tail in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Hum Mol Genet. 1999;8(2):157-164.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Figlewicz DA, Krizus A, Martinoli MG, et al. Variants of the heavy neurofilament subunit are associated with the development of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Hum Mol Genet. 1994;3(10):1757-1761.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strong MJ, Abrahams S, Goldstein LH, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis - frontotemporal spectrum disorder (ALS-FTSD): revised diagnostic criteria. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2017;18(3-4):153-174.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan J, Qiao L, Peng H, et al. A novel missense pathogenic variant in NEFH causing rare Charcot-Marie-Tooth neuropathy type 2CC. Neurol Sci. 2021;42:757-763.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rebelo AP, Abrams AJ, Cottenie E, et al. Cryptic Amyloidogenic elements in the 3&#x2032; UTRs of Neurofilament genes trigger axonal neuropathy. Am J Hum Genet. 2016;98(4):597-614.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cirulli ET, Lasseigne BN, Petrovski S, et al. Exome sequencing in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis identifies risk genes and pathways. Science. 2015;347(6229):1436-1441.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freischmidt A, Wieland T, Richter B, et al. Haploinsufficiency of TBK1 causes familial ALS and fronto-temporal dementia. Nat Neurosci. 2015;18(5):631-636.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le Ber I, De Septenville A, Millecamps S, et al. TBK1 mutation frequencies in French frontotemporal dementia and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis cohorts. Neurobiol Aging. 2015;36(11):3116.e5-3116.e8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pozzi L, Valenza F, Mosca L, et al. TBK1 mutations in Italian patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: genetic and functional characterisation. J NeurolNeurosurg Psychiatry. 2017;88(10):869-875.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pottier C, Bieniek KF, Finch N, et al. Whole-genome sequencing reveals important role for TBK1 and OPTN mutations in frontotemporal lobar degeneration without motor neuron disease. Acta Neuropathol. 2015;130(1):77-92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Zee J, Gijselinck I, Van Mossevelde S, et al. TBK1 mutation spectrum in an extended european patient cohort with frontotemporal dementia and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Hum Mutat. 2017;38(3):297-309.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Mossevelde S, van der Zee J, Gijselinck I, et al. Clinical features of TBK1 carriers compared with C9orf72, GRN and non-mutation carriers in a Belgian cohort. Brain. 2016;139(Pt 2):452-467.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMeekin LJ, Lucas EK, Meador-Woodruff JH, et al. Cortical PGC-1&#x3b1;-dependent transcripts are reduced in postmortem tissue from patients with schizophrenia. Schizophr Bull. 2016;42(4):1009-1017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gijselinck I, Van Mossevelde S, van der Zee J, et al. Loss of TBK1 is a frequent cause of frontotemporal dementia in a Belgian cohort. Neurology. 2015;85(24):2116-2125.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caroppo P, Camuzat A, De Septenville A, et al. Semantic and nonfluent aphasic variants, secondarily associated with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, are predominant frontotemporal lobar degeneration phenotypes in TBK1 carriers. Alzheimers Dement (Amst). 2015;1(4):481-486.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shu S, Li XL, Liu Q, et al. Screening of the TBK1 gene in familial and sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients of Chinese origin. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2016;17(7-8):605-607.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiao B, Sun Q, Yuan Z, et al. Rare TBK1 variants in patients with frontotemporal dementia and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in a Chinese cohort. TranslNeurodegener. 2018;7:31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsai PC, Liu YC, Lin KP, et al. Mutational analysis of TBK1 in Taiwanese patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurobiol Aging. 2016;40:191.e11-191.e16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim YE, Oh KW, Noh MY, et al. Genetic and functional analysis of TBK1 variants in Korean patients with sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurobiol Aging. 2017;50:170.e1-170.e6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tohnai G, Nakamura R, Sone J, et al. Frequency and characteristics of the TBK1 gene variants in Japanese patients with sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurobiol Aging. 2018;64:158.e15-158.e19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aswathy PM, Jairani PS, Verghese J, Gopala S, Mathuranath PS. Microtubule-associated protein tau genetic variations are uncommon cause of frontotemporal dementia in south India. Neurobiol Aging. 2014;35(2):443.e23-443.e24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mukherjee O, Das G, Sen S, Dutt A, Alladi S, Ghosh A. C9orf72 mutations may be rare in frontotemporal lobar degeneration patients in India. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2015;17(1-2):151-153.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>