<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">34981890</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>29</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1748-1716</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>234</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Acta physiologica (Oxford, England)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Acta Physiol (Oxf)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Transient increase in recurrent inhibition in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis as a putative protection from neurodegeneration.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e13758</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e13758</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/apha.13758</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="AIM">Adaptive mechanisms in spinal circuits are likely involved in homeostatic responses to maintain motor output in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Given the role of Renshaw cells in regulating the motoneuron input/output gain, we investigated the modulation of heteronymous recurrent inhibition.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Electrical stimulations were used to activate recurrent collaterals resulting in the Hoffmann reflex depression. Inhibitions from soleus motor axons to quadriceps motoneurons, and vice versa, were tested in 38 patients and matched group of 42 controls.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Compared with controls, the mean depression of quadriceps reflex was larger in patients, while that of soleus was smaller, suggesting that heteronymous recurrent inhibition was enhanced in quadriceps but reduced in soleus. The modulation of recurrent inhibition was linked to the size of maximal direct motor response and lower limb dysfunctions, suggesting a significant relationship with the integrity of the target motoneuron pool and functional abilities. No significant link was found between the integrity of motor axons activating Renshaw cells and the level of inhibition. Enhanced inhibition was particularly observed in patients within the first year after symptom onset and with slow progression of lower limb dysfunctions. Normal or reduced inhibitions were mainly observed in patients with motor weakness first in lower limbs and greater dysfunctions in lower limbs.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">We provide the first evidence for enhanced recurrent inhibition and speculate that Renshaw cells might have transient protective role on motoneuron by counteracting hyperexcitability at early stages. Several mechanisms likely participate including cortical influence on Renshaw cell and reinnervation by slow motoneurons.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022 Scandinavian Physiological Society. Published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sangari</LastName><ForeName>Sina</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7800-9959</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratoire d'Imagerie Biom&#xe9;dicale, Sorbonne Universit&#xe9;, INSERM, CNRS, Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shirley Ryan AbilityLab, Chicago, Illinois, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, Northwestern University, Chicago, Illinois, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Peyre</LastName><ForeName>Iseline</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratoire d'Imagerie Biom&#xe9;dicale, Sorbonne Universit&#xe9;, INSERM, CNRS, Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lackmy-Vall&#xe9;e</LastName><ForeName>Alexandra</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratoire d'Imagerie Biom&#xe9;dicale, Sorbonne Universit&#xe9;, INSERM, CNRS, Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bayen</LastName><ForeName>El&#xe9;onore</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0286-5521</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratoire d'Imagerie Biom&#xe9;dicale, Sorbonne Universit&#xe9;, INSERM, CNRS, Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>P&#xf4;le MSN, H&#xf4;pital Piti&#xe9;-Salp&#xea;tri&#xe8;re, AP-HP, Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pradat</LastName><ForeName>Pierre-Fran&#xe7;ois</ForeName><Initials>PF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratoire d'Imagerie Biom&#xe9;dicale, Sorbonne Universit&#xe9;, INSERM, CNRS, Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>P&#xf4;le MSN, H&#xf4;pital Piti&#xe9;-Salp&#xea;tri&#xe8;re, AP-HP, Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Marchand-Pauvert</LastName><ForeName>V&#xe9;ronique</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0226-7169</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratoire d'Imagerie Biom&#xe9;dicale, Sorbonne Universit&#xe9;, INSERM, CNRS, Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT02429492</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Acta Physiol (Oxf)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101262545</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1748-1708</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="CommentIn"><RefSource>Acta Physiol (Oxf). 2022 Apr;234(4):e13801</RefSource><PMID Version="1">35170853</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009046" MajorTopicYN="N">Motor Neurons</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009433" MajorTopicYN="N">Neural Inhibition</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D066293" MajorTopicYN="Y">Renshaw Cells</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013116" MajorTopicYN="N">Spinal Cord</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">H-reflex</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Renshaw cells</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">interneurons</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">motoneurons</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">spinal cord</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">spinal excitability</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34981890</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/apha.13758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Gromicho M, Figueiral M, Uysal H, et al. Spreading in ALS: the relative impact of upper and lower motor neuron involvement. Ann Clin Transl Neurol. 2020;7(7):1181-1192.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pender N, Pinto-Grau M, Hardiman O. Cognitive and behavioural impairment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Curr Opin Neurol. 2020;33(5):649-654.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Talbott EO, Malek AM, Lacomis D. The epidemiology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Handb Clin Neurol. 2016;138:225-238.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masrori P, Van Damme P. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a clinical review. Eur J Neurol. 2020;27(10):1918-1929.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leroy F, Lamotte d&#x2019;Incamps B, Imhoff-Manuel RD, Zytnicki D. Early intrinsic hyperexcitability does not contribute to motoneuron degeneration in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Elife. 2014;3: doi:10.7554/eLife.04046</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delestr&#xe9;e N, Manuel M, Iglesias C, Elbasiouny SM, Heckman CJ, Zytnicki D. Adult spinal motoneurones are not hyperexcitable in a mouse model of inherited amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Physiol (Lond). 2014;592(7):1687-1703.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fogarty MJ, Mu EWH, Noakes PG, Lavidis NA, Bellingham MC. Marked changes in dendritic structure and spine density precede significant neuronal death in vulnerable cortical pyramidal neuron populations in the SOD1(G93A) mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathol Commun. 2016;4(1):77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozdinler PH, Benn S, Yamamoto TH, G&#xfc;zel M, Brown RH, Macklis JD. Corticospinal motor neurons and related subcerebral projection neurons undergo early and specific neurodegeneration in hSOD1G93A transgenic ALS mice. J Neurosci. 2011;31(11):4166-4177.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neuwirth C, Barkhaus PE, Burkhardt C, et al. Motor Unit Number Index (MUNIX) detects motor neuron loss in pre-symptomatic muscles in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. Clin Neurophysiol. 2017;128(3):495-500.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Vocht J, Blommaert J, Devrome M, et al. Use of Multimodal Imaging and Clinical Biomarkers in Presymptomatic Carriers of C9orf72 Repeat Expansion. JAMA Neurol. 2020;77(8):1008-1017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S, Nicholson GA, Kiernan MC. Cortical hyperexcitability may precede the onset of familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain. 2008;131(Pt 6):1540-1550.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harten ACMV, Phatnani H, Przedborski S. Non-cell-autonomous pathogenic mechanisms in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Trends Neurosci. 2021;. doi:10.1016/j.tins.2021.04.008</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiernan MC, Ziemann U, Eisen A. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: origins traced to impaired balance between neural excitation and inhibition in the neonatal period. Muscle Nerve. 2019;60(3):232-235.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Falgairolle M, O&#x2019;Donovan MJ. Motoneuronal spinal circuits in degenerative motoneuron disease. Front Mol Neurosci. 2020;13:74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fogarty MJ. Driven to decay: excitability and synaptic abnormalities in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain Res Bull. 2018;140:318-333.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brownstone RM, Lancelin C. Escape from homeostasis: spinal microcircuits and progression of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurophysiol. 2018;119(5):1782-1794.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oyanagi K, Ikuta F, Horikawa Y. Evidence for sequential degeneration of the neurons in the intermediate zone of the spinal cord in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a topographic and quantitative investigation. Acta Neuropathol. 1989;77(4):343-349.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oyanagi K, Makifuchi T, Ikuta F. The anterolateral funiculus in the spinal cord in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathol. 1995;90(3):221-227.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stephens B, Guiloff RJ, Navarrete R, Newman P, Nikhar N, Lewis P. Widespread loss of neuronal populations in the spinal ventral horn in sporadic motor neuron disease. A morphometric study. J Neurol Sci. 2006;244(1-2):41-58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin LJ, Liu Z, Chen K, et al. Motor neuron degeneration in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis mutant superoxide dismutase-1 transgenic mice: mechanisms of mitochondriopathy and cell death. J Comp Neurol. 2007;500(1):20-46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang Q, Martin LJ. Glycinergic innervation of motoneurons is deficient in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis mice: a quantitative confocal analysis. Am J Pathol. 2009;174(2):574-585.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin LJ, Chang Q. Inhibitory synaptic regulation of motoneurons: a new target of disease mechanisms in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Mol Neurobiol. 2012;45(1):30-42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim SM, Guiloff RJ, Navarrete R. Interneuronal survival and calbindin-D28k expression following motoneuron degeneration. J Neurol Sci. 2000;180(1-2):46-51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frey D, Schneider C, Xu L, Borg J, Spooren W, Caroni P. Early and selective loss of neuromuscular synapse subtypes with low sprouting competence in motoneuron diseases. J Neurosci. 2000;20(7):2534-2542.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schaefer AM, Sanes JR, Lichtman JW. A compensatory subpopulation of motor neurons in a mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Comp Neurol. 2005;490(3):209-219.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Winter F, Vo T, Stam FJ, et al. The expression of the chemorepellent Semaphorin 3A is selectively induced in terminal Schwann cells of a subset of neuromuscular synapses that display limited anatomical plasticity and enhanced vulnerability in motor neuron disease. Mol Cell Neurosci. 2006;32(1-2):102-117.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pun S, Santos AF, Saxena S, Xu L, Caroni P. Selective vulnerability and pruning of phasic motoneuron axons in motoneuron disease alleviated by CNTF. Nat Neurosci. 2006;9(3):408-419.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hegedus J, Putman CT, Gordon T. Time course of preferential motor unit loss in the SOD1 G93A mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurobiol Dis. 2007;28(2):154-164.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allodi I, Monta&#xf1;ana-Rosell R, Selvan R, L&#xf6;w P, Kiehn O. Locomotor deficits in a mouse model of ALS are paralleled by loss of V1-interneuron connections onto fast motor neurons. Nat Commun. 2021;12(1):3251.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jankowska E. Interneuronal relay in spinal pathways from proprioceptors. Prog Neurogibol. 1992;38(4):335-378.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schneider SP, Fyffe RE. Involvement of GABA and glycine in recurrent inhibition of spinal motoneurons. J Neurophysiol. 1992;68(2):397-406.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez-Forero D, Alvarez FJ. Differential postnatal maturation of GABAA, glycine receptor, and mixed synaptic currents in Renshaw cells and ventral spinal interneurons. J Neurosci. 2005;25(8):2010-2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alaynick WA, Jessell TM, Pfaff SL. SnapShot: spinal cord development. Cell. 2011;146(1):178-178.e1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wootz H, Fitzsimons-Kantamneni E, Larhammar M, et al. Alterations in the motor neuron-Renshaw cell circuit in the Sod 1(G93A) mouse model. J Comp Neurol. 2013;521(7):1449-1469.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ram&#xed;rez-Jarqu&#xed;n UN, Lazo-G&#xf3;mez R, Tovar-Y-Romo LB, Tapia R. Spinal inhibitory circuits and their role in motor neuron degeneration. Neuropharmacology. 2014;82:101-107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raynor EM, Shefner JM. Recurrent inhibition is decreased in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology. 1994;44(11):2148-2153.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xd6;zyurt MG, Topkara B, &#x130;&#x15f;ak B, T&#xfc;rker KS. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis weakens spinal recurrent inhibition and post-activation depression. Clin Neurophysiol. 2020;131(12):2875-2886.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casas C, Herrando-Grabulosa M, Manzano R, Mancuso R, Osta R, Navarro X. Early presymptomatic cholinergic dysfunction in a murine model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain Behav. 2013;3(2):145-158.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazzocchio R, Rossi A. Role of Renshaw cells in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 2010;41(4):441-443.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shefner JM, Logigian EL. The mixed nerve silent period in normal subjects and patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Electromyogr Clin Neurophysiol. 1998;38(8):505-510.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossi A, Mazzocchio R. Presence of homonymous recurrent inhibition in motoneurones supplying different lower limb muscles in humans. Exp Brain Res. 1991;84(2):367-373.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katz R, Mazzocchio R, P&#xe9;nicaud A, Rossi A. Distribution of recurrent inhibition in the human upper limb. Acta Physiol Scand. 1993;149(2):183-198.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drory VE, Kovach I, Groozman GB. Electrophysiologic evaluation of upper motor neuron involvement in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord. 2001;2(3):147-152.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pierrot-Deseilligny E, Burke D. Recurrent Inhibition (Chapter 4). The circuitry of the human spinal cord. Cambridge University Press; 2005:151-196. https://www.cambridge.org/core/books/circuitry-of-the-human-spinal-cord/BBDFC31B44453B61DD5FD801B34CFFFF#. Accessed January 14, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katz R, Pierrot-Deseilligny E. Recurrent inhibition in humans. Prog Neurogibol. 1999;57(3):325-355.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meunier S, Pierrot-Deseilligny E, Simonetta-Moreau M. Pattern of heteronymous recurrent inhibition in the human lower limb. Exp Brain Res. 1994;102(1):149-159.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meunier S, Penicaud A, Pierrot-Deseilligny E, Rossi A. Monosynaptic Ia excitation and recurrent inhibition from quadriceps to ankle flexors and extensors in man. J Physiol. 1990;423:661-675.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crone C, Hultborn H, Mazi&#xe8;res L, Morin C, Nielsen J, Pierrot-Deseilligny E. Sensitivity of monosynaptic test reflexes to facilitation and inhibition as a function of the test reflex size: a study in man and the cat. Exp Brain Res. 1990;81(1):35-45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical power analysis for the behavioral sciences, 2nd ed. Lawrence Earlbaum Associates; 1988.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosnow R, Rosenthal R. Computing contrasts, effect sizes, and counternulls on other people&#x2019;s published data: general procedures for research consumers. Psychol Methods. 1996;1(4):331.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marchand-Pauvert V. Suppression of the H reflex in humans by disynaptic autogenetic inhibitory pathways activated by the test volley. J Physiol. 2002;542(3):963-976. 10.1113/jphysiol.2002.021683</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iglesias C, Nielsen JB, Marchand-Pauvert V. Corticospinal inhibition of transmission in propriospinal-like neurones during human walking. Eur J Neurosci. 2008;28(7):1351-1361. 10.1111/j.1460-9568.2008.06414.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marchand-Pauvert V. Beyond muscular effects: depression of spinal recurrent inhibition after botulinum neurotoxin A. J Physiol. 2013;591(4):1017-1029. 10.1113/jphysiol.2012.239178</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selya AS, Rose JS, Dierker LC, Hedeker D, Mermelstein RJ. A practical guide to calculating Cohen&#x2019;s f(2), a measure of local effect size, from PROC MIXED. Front Psychol. 2012;3:111.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum JM, Stambler N, Malta E, et al. The ALSFRS-R: a revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. BDNF ALS Study Group (Phase III). J Neurol Sci. 1999;169(1-2):13-21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simon NG, Lin CS-Y, Lee M, et al. Segmental motoneuronal dysfunction is a feature of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Neurophysiol. 2015;126(4):828-836.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marchand-Pauvert V, Peyre I, Lackmy-Vallee A, et al. Absence of hyperexcitability of spinal motoneurons in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Physiol. 2019;597(22):5445-5467.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M. Electrodiagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a review of existing guidelines. J Clin Neurophysiol. 2020;37(4):294-298.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gunes T, Sirin NG, Sahin S, Kose E, Isak B. Use of CMAP, MScan fit-MUNE, and MUNIX in understanding neurodegeneration pattern of ALS and detection of early motor neuron loss in daily practice. Neurosci Lett. 2021;741: 135488.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meunier S, Mogyoros I, Kiernan MC, Burke D. Effects of femoral nerve stimulation on the electromyogram and reflex excitability of tibialis anterior and soleus. Muscle Nerve. 1996;19(9):1110-1115.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iles JF, Pardoe J. Changes in transmission in the pathway of heteronymous spinal recurrent inhibition from soleus to quadriceps motor neurons during movement in man. Brain. 1999;122(Pt 9):1757-1764.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbeau H, Marchand-Pauvert V, Meunier S, Nicolas G, Pierrot-Deseilligny E. Posture-related changes in heteronymous recurrent inhibition from quadriceps to ankle muscles in humans. Exp Brain Res. 2000;130(3):345-361.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bussel B, Pierrot-Deseilligny E. Inhibition of human motoneurons, probably of Renshaw origin, elicited by an orthodromic motor discharge. J Physiol. 1977;269(2):319-339.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hultborn H, Pierrot-Deseilligny E, Wigstr&#xf6;m H. Recurrent inhibition and afterhyperpolarization following motoneuronal discharge in the cat. J Physiol. 1979;297:253-266.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piotrkiewicz M, Hausmanowa-Petrusewicz I. Motoneuron afterhyperpolarisation duration in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Physiol (Lond). 2011;589(Pt 11):2745-2754.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hultborn H, Meunier S, Morin C, Pierrot-Deseilligny E. Assessing changes in presynaptic inhibition of I a fibres: a study in man and the cat. J Physiol. 1987;389:729-756.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meunier S, Pierrot-Deseilligny E. Cortical control of presynaptic inhibition of Ia afferents in humans. Exp Brain Res. 1998;119(4):415-426.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howells J, Sangari S, Matamala JM, Kiernan MC, Marchand-Pauvert V, Burke D. Interrogating interneurone function using threshold tracking of the H reflex in healthy subjects and patients with motor neurone disease. Clin Neurophysiol. 2020;131(8):1986-1996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schieppati M, Poloni M, Nardone A. Voluntary muscle release is not accompanied by H-reflex inhibition in patients with upper moto neuron lesions. Neurosci Lett. 1985;61(1-2):177-181.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morin C, Pierrot-Deseilligny E. Spinal mechanism of the antispastic action of TRH in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Rev Neurol (Paris). 1988;144(11):701-703.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sangari S, Iglesias C, El Mendili M-M, Benali H, Pradat P-F, Marchand-Pauvert V. Impairment of sensory-motor integration at spinal level in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Neurophysiol. 2016;127(4):1968-1977.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hongo T, Lundberg A, Phillips CG, Thompson RF. The pattern of monosynaptic Ia-connections to hindlimb motor nuclei in the baboon: a comparison with the cat. Proc R Soc Lond B Biol Sci. 1984;221(1224):261-289.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baldissera F, Hultborn H, Illert M. Integration in spinal neuronal systems. In: Brookhart JM, Mountcastle VB, eds. Handbook of physiology. American Physiological Society; 1981:508-595.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baret M, Katz R, Lamy JC, P&#xe9;nicaud A, Wargon I. Evidence for recurrent inhibition of reciprocal inhibition from soleus to tibialis anterior in man. Exp Brain Res. 2003;152(1):133-136.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazzocchio R, Rossi A, Rothwell JC. Depression of Renshaw recurrent inhibition by activation of corticospinal fibres in human upper and lower limb. J Physiol. 1994;481(Pt 2):487-498.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iles JF. Recruitment of the vastus lateralis motor pool by corticospinal volleys in man during the activation of recurrent inhibition. J Physiol. 1996;494:P65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hultborn H, Pierrot-Deseilligny E. Changes in recurrent inhibition during voluntary soleus contractions in man studied by an H-reflex technique. J Physiol. 1979;297:229-251.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hultborn H, Brownstone RB, Toth TI, Gossard J-P. Key mechanisms for setting the input-output gain across the motoneuron pool. Prog Brain Res. 2004;143:77-95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alvarez FJ, Jonas PC, Sapir T, et al. Postnatal phenotype and localization of spinal cord V1 derived interneurons. J Comp Neurol. 2005;493(2):177-192.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xd6;zyurt MG, Shabsog M, Dursun M, T&#xfc;rker KS. Optimal location for eliciting the tibial H-reflex and motor response. Muscle Nerve. 2018;58(6):828-833.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xd6;zyurt MG, Piotrkiewicz M, Topkara B, Weisskircher H-W, T&#xfc;rker KS. Motor units as tools to evaluate profile of human Renshaw inhibition. J Physiol. 2019;597(8):2185-2199.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Querin G, Bede P, El Mendili MM, et al. Presymptomatic spinal cord pathology in c9orf72 mutation carriers: a longitudinal neuroimaging study. Ann Neurol. 2019;86(2):158-167.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dentel C, Palamiuc L, Henriques A, et al. Degeneration of serotonergic neurons in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a link to spasticity. Brain. 2013;136(Pt 2):483-493.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katz R, Pierrot-Deseilligny E. Recurrent inhibition of alpha-motoneurons in patients with upper motor neuron lesions. Brain. 1982;105(Pt 1):103-124.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shefner JM, Berman SA, Sarkarati M, Young RR. Recurrent inhibition is increased in patients with spinal cord injury. Neurology. 1992;42(11):2162-2168.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossi A, Decchi B, Vecchione V. Supraspinal influences on recurrent inhibition in humans. Paralysis of descending control of Renshaw cells in patients with mental retardation. Electroencephalogr Clin Neurophysiol. 1992;85(6):419-424.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazzocchio R, Schieppati M, Scarpini C, Rossi A. Enhancement of recurrent inhibition by intravenous administration of L-acetylcarnitine in spastic patients. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 1990;53(4):321-326.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazzocchio R, Rossi A. Involvement of spinal recurrent inhibition in spasticity. Further insight into the regulation of Renshaw cell activity. Brain. 1997;120(Pt 6):991-1003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Floeter MK, Andermann F, Andermann E, Nigro M, Hallett M. Physiological studies of spinal inhibitory pathways in patients with hereditary hyperekplexia. Neurology. 1996;46(3):766-772.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Windhorst U. On the role of recurrent inhibitory feedback in motor control. Prog Neurogibol. 1996;49(6):517-587.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iglesias C, Sangari S, El Mendili M-M, Benali H, Marchand-Pauvert V, Pradat P-F. Electrophysiological and spinal imaging evidences for sensory dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. BMJ Open. 2015;5(2):e007659.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaughan SK, Kemp Z, Hatzipetros T, Vieira F, Valdez G. Degeneration of proprioceptive sensory nerve endings in mice harboring amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-causing mutations. J Comp Neurol. 2015;523(17):2477-2494.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marchand-Pauvert V. Interrogating interneurone function using threshold tracking of the H reflex in healthy subjects and patients with motor neurone disease. Clin Neurophysiol. 2020;. doi:10.1016/j.clinph.2020.03.028</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruneteau G, Simonet T, Bauch&#xe9; S, et al. Muscle histone deacetylase 4 upregulation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: potential role in reinnervation ability and disease progression. Brain. 2013;136(Pt 8):2359-2368.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruneteau G, Bauch&#xe9; S, Gonzalez de Aguilar JL, et al. Endplate denervation correlates with Nogo-A muscle expression in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. Ann Clin Transl Neurol. 2015;2(4):362-372.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Turkman A, Swash M. Sensitivity of MUP parameters in detecting change in early ALS. Clin Neurophysiol. 2014;125(1):166-169.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devlin A-C, Burr K, Borooah S, et al. Human iPSC-derived motoneurons harbouring TARDBP or C9ORF72 ALS mutations are dysfunctional despite maintaining viability. Nat Commun. 2015;6:5999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuo S-W, Binder MD, Heckman CJ. Excessive Homeostatic Gain in Spinal Motoneurons in a Mouse Model of Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. Sci Rep. 2020;10(1):9049.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venugopal S, Hamm TM, Crook SM, Jung R. Modulation of inhibitory strength and kinetics facilitates regulation of persistent inward currents and motoneuron excitability following spinal cord injury. J Neurophysiol. 2011;106(5):2167-2179.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fornai F, Longone P, Cafaro L, et al. Lithium delays progression of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2008;105(6):2052-2057.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pasquali L, Longone P, Isidoro C, Ruggieri S, Paparelli A, Fornai F. Autophagy, lithium, and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 2009;40(2):173-194.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gamez J, Salvado M, Mart&#xed;nez de la Ossa A, Badia M. Lithium for treatment of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: much ado about nothing. Neurologia. 2016;31(8):550-561.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sasaki K. Electrophysiological studies on oculomotor neurons of the cat. Jpn J Physiol. 1963;13:287-302.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simonetta-Moreau M, Marque P, Marchand-Pauvert V, Pierrot-Deseilligny E. The pattern of excitation of human lower limb motoneurones by probable group II muscle afferents. J Physiol (Lond). 1999;517(1):287-300.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, Miller RG, Swash M, Munsat TL. World federation of neurology research group on motor neuron diseases. El Escorial revisited: revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord. 2000;1(5):293-299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oldfield RC. The assessment and analysis of handedness: the Edinburgh inventory. Neuropsychologia. 1971;9(1):97-113.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>