<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35020950</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>04</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-4598</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>65</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Muscle &amp; nerve</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Muscle Nerve</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Automatic detection of F waves and F-MUNE in two types of motor neuron diseases.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>422</StartPage><EndPage>432</EndPage><MedlinePgn>422-432</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/mus.27494</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION/AIMS">Motor unit number estimation by F waves (F-MUNE) is an uncommonly used MUNE technique. Our aim in this study was to assess the sensitivity of F-MUNE values elicited with newly developed software in motor neuron diseases.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">F waves were recorded by 300 submaximal stimuli from abductor digiti minimi and abductor pollicis brevis muscles of 35 patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, 18 with previous poliomyelitis, and 20 controls. The software determined the surface motor unit action potentials (sMUAPs) and calculated the F-MUNE values. Compound muscle action potential scans were also recorded to obtain MScanFit.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">The sMUAP amplitudes were higher and F-MUNE values were lower in both muscles of the patients when compared with controls. F-MUNE values could distinguish patients from controls. Significant correlations were found between F-MUNE and MScanFit in the patient groups.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION">The new F-MUNE software offered promising results in revealing motor unit loss caused by motor neuron diseases.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oguz-Akarsu</LastName><ForeName>Emel</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology and Clinical Neurophysiology, Faculty of Medicine, Istanbul University, Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Faculty of Medicine, Bursa Uludag University, Bursa, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sirin</LastName><ForeName>Nermin Gorkem</ForeName><Initials>NG</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8792-2929</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology and Clinical Neurophysiology, Faculty of Medicine, Istanbul University, Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Artug</LastName><ForeName>Tugrul</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9259-2458</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical and Electronics Engineering, Faculty of Engineering, Izmir Democracy University, Izmir, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Erbas</LastName><ForeName>Bahar</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology and Clinical Neurophysiology, Faculty of Medicine, Istanbul University, Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacology, Faculty of Medicine, Demiroglu Bilim University, Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kocasoy Orhan</LastName><ForeName>Elif</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology and Clinical Neurophysiology, Faculty of Medicine, Istanbul University, Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Idriso&#x11f;lu</LastName><ForeName>Halil Atilla</ForeName><Initials>HA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology and Clinical Neurophysiology, Faculty of Medicine, Istanbul University, Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ketenci</LastName><ForeName>Aysegul</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, Faculty of Medicine, Istanbul University, Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Baslo</LastName><ForeName>Mehmet Baris</ForeName><Initials>MB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology and Clinical Neurophysiology, Faculty of Medicine, Istanbul University, Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oge</LastName><ForeName>Ali Emre</ForeName><Initials>AE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology and Clinical Neurophysiology, Faculty of Medicine, Istanbul University, Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Muscle Nerve</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7803146</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0148-639X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000200" MajorTopicYN="N">Action Potentials</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004576" MajorTopicYN="N">Electromyography</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016472" MajorTopicYN="Y">Motor Neuron Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009046" MajorTopicYN="N">Motor Neurons</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">F wave</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">MScanFit</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">motor unit number estimation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">poliomyelitis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">signal processing</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35020950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.27494</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>McComas A, Fawcett PRW, Campbell M, Sica R. Electrophysiological estimation of the number of motor units within a human muscle. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 1971;34:121-131.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doherty TJ, Brown WF. The estimated numbers and relative sizes of thenar motor units as selected by multiple point stimulation in young and older adults. Muscle Nerve. 1993;16:355-366.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobsen AB, Bostock H, Tankisi H. Following disease progression in motor neuron disorders with 3 motor unit number estimation methods. Muscle Nerve. 2019;59:82-87.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shefner JM. Motor unit number estimation in human neurological diseases and animal models. Clin Neurophysiol. 2001;112:955-964.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Scotto M, Lopes A, Swash M. Quantitating progression in ALS. Neurology. 2005;64:1783-1785.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daube JR. Estimating the number of motor units in a muscle. J Clin Neurophysiol. 1995;12:585-594.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stashuk DW, Doherty TJ, Kassam A, Brown WF. Motor unit number estimates based on the automated analysis of F-responses. Muscle Nerve. 1994;17:881-890.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bostock H. Estimating motor unit numbers from a CMAP scan. Muscle Nerve. 2016;53:889-896.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Barkhaus PE, Nandedkar SD, Swash M. Motor unit number estimation (MUNE): where are we now? Clin Neurophysiol. 2018;129:1507-1516.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nandedkar SD, Barkhaus PE, Stalberg EV. Motor unit number index (MUNIX): principle, method, and findings in healthy subjects and in patients with motor neuron disease. Muscle Nerve. 2010;42:798-807.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gooch CL, Doherty TJ, Chan KM, et al. Motor unit number estimation: a technology and literature review. Muscle Nerve. 2014;50:884-893.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chroni E, Veltsista D, Papapaulou C, Trachani E. Generation of repeater F waves in healthy subjects. J Clin Neurophysiol. 2017;34:236-242.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doherty TJ, Komori T, Stashuk DW, Kassam A, Brown WF. Physiological properties of single thenar motor units in the F-response of younger and older adults. Muscle Nerve. 1994;17:860-872.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feasby TE, Brown WF. Variation of motor unit size in the human extensor digitorum brevis and thenar muscles. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 1974;37:916-926.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akarsu EO, Sirin NG, Orhan EK, et al. Repeater F-waves in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: electrophysiologic indicators of upper or lower motor neuron involvement? Clin Neurophysiol. 2020;131:96-105.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chroni E, Tendero IS, Punga AR, Stalberg E. Usefulness of assessing repeater F-waves in routine studies. Muscle Nerve. 2012;45:477-485.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hara Y, Akaboshi K, Masakado Y, Chino N. Physiologic decrease of single thenar motor units in the F-response in stroke patients. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2000;81:418-423.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi IS, Kim JH, Han JY, Lee SG. The correlation between F-wave motor unit number estimation (F-MUNE) and functional recovery in stroke patients. J Korean Med Sci. 2007;22:1002-1006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Felice KJ. Nerve conduction velocities of single thenar motor axons based on the automated analysis of F waves in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 1998;21:756-761.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veltsista D, Papapavlou C, Chroni E. F wave analyzer, a system for repeater F-waves detection: application in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Neurophysiol. 2019;130:1954-1961.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Artu&#x11f; NT, &#x15e;irin NG, Akarsu EO, Baslo MB, &#xd6;ge AE. An algorithm for automatic detection of repeater F-waves and MUNE studies. Biomed Signal Process Control. 2019;51:264-276.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kristensen AG, Bostock H, Finnerup N, et al. Detection of early motor involvement in diabetic polyneuropathy using a novel MUNE method-MScanFit MUNE. Clin Neurophysiol. 2019;130:1981-1987.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kesim-Sahin O, Sirin NG, Erbas B, et al. Compound muscle action potential scan and MScanFit motor unit number estimation during Wallerian degeneration after nerve transections. Muscle Nerve. 2020;62:239-246.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sleutjes BT, Wijngaarde CA, Wadman RI, et al. Assessment of motor unit loss in patients with spinal muscular atrophy. Clin Neurophysiol. 2020;131(6):1280-1286.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sirin NG, Oguz Akarsu E, Kocasoy Orhan E, et al. Parameters derived from compound muscle action potential scan for discriminating amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-related denervation. Muscle Nerve. 2019;60:400-408.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum JM, Stambler N, Malta E, et al. The ALSFRS-R: a revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. J Neurol Sci. 1999;169:13-21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hermans G, Clerckx B, Vanhullebusch T, et al. Interobserver agreement of Medical Research Council sum-score and handgrip strength in the intensive care unit. Muscle Nerve. 2012;45:18-25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Dengler R, Eisen A, et al. Electrodiagnostic criteria for diagnosis of ALS. Clin Neurophysiol. 2008;119:497-503.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sorenson EJ, Daube JR, Windebank AJ. Electrophysiological findings in a cohort of old polio survivors. J Peripher Nerv Syst. 2006;11:241-246.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher MA. AAEM Minimonograph #13: H reflexes and F waves: physiology and clinical indications. Muscle Nerve. 1992;15:1223-1233.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panayiotopoulos CP, Chroni E. F-waves in clinical neurophysiology: a review, methodological issues and overall value in peripheral neuropathies. Electroencephalogr Clin Neurophysiol. 1996;101:365-374.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schober P, Boer C, Schwarte LA. Correlation coefficients: appropriate use and interpretation. Anesth Analg. 2018;126:1763-1768.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, Fisher M, Rymer WZ, Zhou P. Application of the F-response for estimating motor unit number and amplitude distribution in hand muscles of stroke survivors. IEEE Trans Neural Syst Rehabil Eng. 2016;24:674-681.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McComas AJ, Quartly C, Griggs RC. Early and late losses of motor units after poliomyelitis. Brain. 1997;120:1415-1421.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sorenson EJ, Daube JR, Windebank AJ. A 15-year follow-up of neuromuscular function in patients with prior poliomyelitis. Neurology. 2005;64:1070-1072.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stalberg E, Grimby G. Dynamic electromyography and muscle biopsy changes in a 4-year follow-up: study of patients with a history of polio. Muscle Nerve. 1995;18:699-707.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guiloff RJ, Modarres-Sadeghi H. Preferential generation of recurrent responses by groups of motor neurons in man. Conventional and single unit F wave studies. Brain. 1991;114:1771-1801.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dengler R, Kossev A, Wohlfahrt K, Schubert M, Elek J, Wolf W. F waves and motor unit size. Muscle Nerve. 1992;15:1138-1142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kimura J, Yanagisawa H, Yamada T, Mitsudome A, Sasaki H, Kimura A. Is the F wave elicited in a select group of motoneurons? Muscle Nerve. 1984;7:392-399.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yates SK, Brown WF. Characteristics of the F response: a single motor unit study. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 1979;42:161-170.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drory VE, Kovach I, Groozman GB. Electrophysiologic evaluation of upper motor neuron involvement in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord. 2001;2:147-152.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang J, Cui LY, Liu MS, et al. F wave study in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: assessment of segmental Motoneuronal dysfunction. Chin Med J (Engl). 2015;128:1738-1742.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veltsista D, Chroni E. Repeater F-waves detection in upper motor neuron dysfunction. Clin Neurophysiol. 2020;131:1419-1420.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Argyriou AA, Polychronopoulos P, Talelli P, Chroni E. F wave study in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: assessment of balance between upper and lower motor neuron involvement. Clin Neurophysiol. 2006;117:1260-1265.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Scotto M, Lopes A, Swash M. Clinical and neurophysiological evaluation of progression in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 2003;28:630-633.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Chio A, Dengler R, Hecht M, Weber M, Swash M. Neurophysiological measures in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: markers of progression in clinical trials. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord. 2005;6:17-28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang J, Cui L, Liu M, et al. Differences in dysfunction of thenar and hypothenar motoneurons in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Front Hum Neurosci. 2016;10:99.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Scotto M, Lopes A, Swash M. F-waves and the corticospinal lesion in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord. 2002;3:131-136.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawamura Y, Sonoo M, Higashihara M, Chiba T, Hatanaka Y. Origin of surface motor unit potentials in hypothenar motor unit number estimation. Muscle Nerve. 2013;48:185-190.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>