<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35023098</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0065-2598</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>1339</Volume><PubDate><Year>2021</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Advances in experimental medicine and biology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Adv Exp Med Biol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Importance of Diagnostic and Prognostic Biomarker Identification and Classification Towards Understanding ALS Pathogenesis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>119</StartPage><EndPage>120</EndPage><MedlinePgn>119-120</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/978-3-030-78787-5_16</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>ALS is increasingly perceived as a multisystem neurodegenerative disorder, and the identification of a panel of biomarkers that accurately reflect features of pathology is a priority, not only for diagnostic purposes but also for prognostic or predictive applications [1]. Thus, as a multisystemic disease, it is likely that a panel of biomarkers will be needed to fully capture the features of ALS pathology. Taking also into consideration the fact that its causes remain unknown to their majority, it remains a complex disease driven by a combination of several systemic parameters [2]. Beyond the monogenic causes, representing the 15% of the ALS cases, which list up to 30 gene mutations with the most frequent being C9orf72, SOD1, FUS, and TARDBP/TDP43 [3-5], much research is being done to identify and associate possible causes for the 80% of ALS cases (sALS and fALS combined) which at the moment are not explained by a known mutation [2, 4]. ALS sporadic cases are related to a multigenic component, and/or involve epigenetic modification, and/or result from DNA damage, environmental risk factors, behavioural factors, oxidative stress or viral infections leading to cellular dysfunctions [4, 6-10]. ALS diagnosis is lengthy and there is a typical diagnostic delay of 9-15&#xa0;months from onset to diagnostic confirmation based on clinical and electrophysiological criteria as well as the exclusion of diseases with similar behaviour to ALS. Three major exclusion criteria are involved in the diagnosis process: the Revised El Escorial Criteria (REEC), the Airlie House Criteria (AHC) and the Awaji Criteria [11, 12]. Taking into consideration that the average survival is 2-4&#xa0;years, it makes it urgent for the researchers to improve diagnostic speed and accuracy for ALS [13, 14]. In the absence of a reliable diagnostic test for ALS, biomarkers are a strong weapon not only for its diagnosis but also for understanding the pathomechanism as well as a basis for the development of therapeutics. Recent global research has accepted the fact that biomarkers will facilitate the combination of therapeutics with diagnostics and will thus play an important role in the development of personalized medicine [15]. This paper proposes a combination of diagnostic and prognostic biomarkers to meet the scope of global research. Thus, biomarkers specific to ALS pathology need to be identified towards the development of a reliable fast diagnostic test, while at the same time prognostic biomarkers should also be identified to monitor the status of the pathology as various candidates may serve both purposes. Finally, since different sub-cohorts of ALS patients respond differently to treatments [16], the identification of ALS biomarkers will contribute to a better understanding of the disease pathogenesis and permit targeted drug development and patient stratification leading to more efficient clinical trials.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021. The Author(s), under exclusive license to Springer Nature Switzerland AG.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kadena</LastName><ForeName>Katerina</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ionian University, Corfu, Greece. katerina.kadena@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vlamos</LastName><ForeName>Panayiotis</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ionian University, Corfu, Greece.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Adv Exp Med Biol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0121103</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0065-2598</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057210" MajorTopicYN="N">Delayed Diagnosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009154" MajorTopicYN="N">Mutation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011379" MajorTopicYN="N">Prognosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ALS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Biomarkers</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Diagnostic biomarkers</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Personalized medicine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Prognostic biomarkers</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35023098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-3-030-78787-5_16</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>S. M. Turner MR, The expanding syndrome of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a clinical and molecular odyssey, Journal of Neurology, Neurosurgery &amp; Psychiatry 2015;86:667&#x2013;673.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A.-C. A. C. A. H. O. K. M. R. J. e. a. Turner MR, Genetic screening in sporadic ALS and FTD., J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. (2017) 88:1042&#x2013;4. https://doi.org/10.1136/jnnp-2017-315995 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. J. A. P. L. A. K. C. Volk AE, Current knowledge and recent insights into the genetic basis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis., Med Genet. (2018) 30:252&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11825-018-0185-3 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. A. T. B. Chia R, Novel genes associated with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: diagnostic and clinical implications., Lancet Neurol. (2018) 17:94&#x2013;102. https://doi.org/10.1016/S1474-4422(17)30401-5 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. K. R. A. T. N. F. F. C. R. e. a. Nicolas A, Genome-wide analyses identify KIF5A as a novel ALS gene., Neuron. (2018) 97:1268&#x2013;83.e6. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2018.02.027 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A.-C. A. Brown RH, Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis., N Engl J Med. (2017) 377:1602. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJMc1710379 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. C., From snow to hill to ALS: an epidemiological odyssey in search of ALS causation., J Neurol Sci. (2018) 391:134&#x2013;40. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jns.2018.05.016 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. R. C. N. L. H. Xue YC, Enteroviral infection: the forgotten link to amyotrophic lateral sclerosis?, Front Mol Neurosci. (2018) 11:63. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnmol.2018.00063 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N. A. S. M. M. J. P. M. P. C. e. a. Mackenzie IR, TIA1 mutations in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal dementia promote phase separation and alter stress granule dynamics., Neuron. (2017) 95:808&#x2013;16.e9. doi: 10.1016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>V. D. B. L. V. J. Al-Chalabi A, Gene discovery in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: implications for clinical management., Nat Rev Neurol. (2017) 13:96&#x2013;104. https://doi.org/10.1038/nrneurol.2016.182 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N. H. S. Y. N. A. A. K. S. Y. e. a. Okita T, Can Awaji ALS criteria provide earlier diagnosis than the revised El Escorial criteria?, J Neurol Sci. (2011) 302:29&#x2013;32. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jns.2010.12.007 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. O. K. M. C. A. R.-B. B. v. d. B. L. Al-Chalabi A, Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: moving towards a new classification system., Lancet Neurol. (2016) 15:1182&#x2013;94. https://doi.org/10.1016/S1474-4422(16)30199-5 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. A. L. D. Talbott EO, The epidemiology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis., Handb Clin Neurol. 138:225&#x2013;38. https://doi.org/10.1016/B978-0-12-802973-2.00013-6 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. W. M. V. K. T. v. B. G. del Aguila MA, Prognosis in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a population-based study., Neurology. (2003) 60:813&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.1212/01.WNL.0000049472.47709.3B .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biomarkers - Technologies, Markets &amp; Companies, ID: 4748179 Report September 2020 Region: Global 1027 Pages Jain PharmaBiotech.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. Camu, M. Mickunas, J.-L. Veyrune, C. Payan, C. Garlanda, M. Locati, R. Juntas-Morales, N. Pageot, A. Malaspina, U. Andreasson, J. Kirby, C. Suehs, S. Saker and e. al, Repeated 5-day cycles of low dose aldesleukin in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (IMODALS) : A phase 2a randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial., A phase 2a randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. In: EBioMedicine. 2020 ; Vol. 59. pp. 102844.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>