<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35044815</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>19</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2375-2548</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>8</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Science advances</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Adv</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Targeted gene silencing in the nervous system with CRISPR-Cas13.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>eabk2485</StartPage><MedlinePgn>eabk2485</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">eabk2485</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1126/sciadv.abk2485</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Cas13 nucleases are a class of programmable RNA-targeting CRISPR effector proteins that are capable of silencing target gene expression in mammalian cells. Here, we demonstrate that RfxCas13d, a Cas13 ortholog with favorable characteristics to other family members, can be delivered to the mouse spinal cord and brain to silence neurodegeneration-associated genes. Intrathecally delivering an adeno-associated virus vector encoding an RfxCas13d variant programmed to target superoxide dismutase 1 (SOD1), a protein whose mutation can cause amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, reduced SOD1 mRNA and protein in the spinal cord by &gt;50% and improved outcomes in a mouse model of the disorder. We further show that intrastriatally delivering an RfxCas13d variant programmed to target huntingtin (HTT), a protein whose mutation is causative for Huntington&#x2019;s disease, led to a ~50% reduction in HTT protein in the mouse brain. Our results establish RfxCas13d as a versatile platform for knocking down gene expression in the nervous system.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Powell</LastName><ForeName>Jackson E</ForeName><Initials>JE</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2207-4468</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Bioengineering, University of Illinois, Urbana, IL 61801, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lim</LastName><ForeName>Colin K W</ForeName><Initials>CKW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Bioengineering, University of Illinois, Urbana, IL 61801, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Krishnan</LastName><ForeName>Ramya</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Bioengineering, University of Illinois, Urbana, IL 61801, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McCallister</LastName><ForeName>Tristan X</ForeName><Initials>TX</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1386-7311</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Bioengineering, University of Illinois, Urbana, IL 61801, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saporito-Magri&#xf1;a</LastName><ForeName>Christian</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4512-6251</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Bioengineering, University of Illinois, Urbana, IL 61801, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zeballos</LastName><ForeName>Maria A</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5194-2909</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Bioengineering, University of Illinois, Urbana, IL 61801, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McPheron</LastName><ForeName>Garrett D</ForeName><Initials>GD</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4956-5486</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Bioengineering, University of Illinois, Urbana, IL 61801, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gaj</LastName><ForeName>Thomas</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6004-9664</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Bioengineering, University of Illinois, Urbana, IL 61801, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Carl R. Woese Institute for Genomic Biology, University of Illinois, Urbana, IL 61801, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Adv</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101653440</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2375-2548</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 1.15.1.1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D013482">Superoxide Dismutase</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 1.15.1.1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000072105">Superoxide Dismutase-1</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D064113" MajorTopicYN="Y">CRISPR-Cas Systems</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020868" MajorTopicYN="N">Gene Silencing</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008322" MajorTopicYN="N">Mammals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051379" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013116" MajorTopicYN="N">Spinal Cord</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013482" MajorTopicYN="N">Superoxide Dismutase</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000072105" MajorTopicYN="N">Superoxide Dismutase-1</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35044815</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8769545</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/sciadv.abk2485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Jinek M., Chylinski K., Fonfara I., Hauer M., Doudna J. A., Charpentier E., A programmable dual-RNA&#x2013;guided DNA endonuclease in adaptive bacterial immunity. Science 337, 816&#x2013;821 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6286148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22745249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cong L., Ran F. A., Cox D., Lin S., Barretto R., Habib N., Hsu P. D., Wu X., Jiang W., Marraffini L. A., Zhang F., Multiplex genome engineering using CRISPR/Cas systems. Science 339, 819&#x2013;823 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3795411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23287718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abudayyeh O. O., Gootenberg J. S., Konermann S., Joung J., Slaymaker I. M., Cox D. B. T., Shmakov S., Makarova K. S., Semenova E., Minakhin L., Severinov K., Regev A., Lander E. S., Koonin E. V., Zhang F., C2c2 is a single-component programmable RNA-guided RNA-targeting CRISPR effector. Science 353, aaf5573 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5127784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27256883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smargon A. A., Cox D. B. T., Pyzocha N. K., Zheng K., Slaymaker I. M., Gootenberg J. S., Abudayyeh O. A., Essletzbichler P., Shmakov S., Makarova K. S., Koonin E. V., Zhang F., Cas13b is a type VI-B CRISPR-associated RNA-guided rnase differentially regulated by accessory proteins Csx27 and Csx28. Mol. Cell 65, 618&#x2013;630.e7 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5432119</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28065598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konermann S., Lotfy P., Brideau N. J., Oki J., Shokhirev M. N., Hsu P. D., Transcriptome engineering with RNA-targeting type VI-D CRISPR effectors. Cell 173, 665&#x2013;676.e14 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5910255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29551272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan W. X., Chong S., Zhang H., Makarova K. S., Koonin E. V., Cheng D. R., Scott D. A., Cas13d is a compact RNA-targeting type VI CRISPR effector positively modulated by a WYL-domain-containing accessory protein. Mol. Cell 70, 327&#x2013;339.e5 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5935466</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29551514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>East-Seletsky A., O&#x2019;Connell M. R., Knight S. C., Burstein D., Cate J. H., Tjian R., Doudna J. A., Two distinct RNase activities of CRISPR-C2c2 enable guide-RNA processing and RNA detection. Nature 538, 270&#x2013;273 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5576363</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27669025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abudayyeh O. O., Gootenberg J. S., Essletzbichler P., Han S., Joung J., Belanto J. J., Verdine V., Cox D. B. T., Kellner M. J., Regev A., Lander E. S., Voytas D. F., Ting A. Y., Zhang F., RNA targeting with CRISPR&#x2013;Cas13. Nature 550, 280&#x2013;284 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5706658</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28976959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slaymaker I. M., Mesa P., Kellner M. J., Kannan S., Brignole E., Koob J., Feliciano P. R., Stella S., Abudayyeh O. O., Gootenberg J. S., Strecker J., Montoya G., Zhang F., High-resolution structure of Cas13b and biochemical characterization of RNA targeting and cleavage. Cell Rep. 26, 3741&#x2013;3751.e5 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6659120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30917325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cox D. B. T., Gootenberg J. S., Abudayyeh O. O., Franklin B., Kellner M. J., Joung J., Zhang F., RNA editing with CRISPR-Cas13. Science 358, 1019&#x2013;1027 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5793859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29070703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu C., Zhou Y., Xiao Q., He B., Geng G., Wang Z., Cao B., Dong X., Bai W., Wang Y., Wang X., Zhou D., Yuan T., Huo X., Lai J., Yang H., Programmable RNA editing with compact CRISPR&#x2013;Cas13 systems from uncultivated microbes. Nat. Methods 18, 499&#x2013;506 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33941935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wessels H.-H., M&#xe9;ndez-Mancilla A., Guo X., Legut M., Daniloski Z., Sanjana N. E., Massively parallel Cas13 screens reveal principles for guide RNA design. Nat. Biotechnol. 38, 722&#x2013;727 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7294996</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32518401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huynh N., Depner N., Larson R., King-Jones K., A versatile toolkit for CRISPR-Cas13-based RNA manipulation in Drosophila. Genome Biol. 21, 279 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7670108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33203452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He B., Peng W., Huang J., Zhang H., Zhou Y., Yang X., Liu J., Li Z., Xu C., Xue M., Yang H., Huang P., Modulation of metabolic functions through Cas13d-mediated gene knockdown in liver. Protein Cell 11, 518&#x2013;524 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7095259</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32185621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou C., Hu X., Tang C., Liu W., Wang S., Zhou Y., Zhao Q., Bo Q., Shi L., Sun X., Zhou H., Yang H., CasRx-mediated RNA targeting prevents choroidal neovascularization in a mouse model of age-related macular degeneration. Natl. Sci. Rev. 7, 835&#x2013;837 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8288881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34692105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosen D. R., Siddique T., Patterson D., Figlewicz D. A., Sapp P., Hentati A., Donaldson D., Goto J., O&#x2019;Regan J. P., Deng H.-X., Rahmani Z., Krizus A., McKenna-Yasek D., Cayabyab A., Gaston S. M., Berger R., Tanzi R. E., Halperin J. J., Herzfeldt B., Van den Bergh R., Hung W.-Y., Bird T., Deng G., Mulder D. W., Smyth C., Laing N. G., Soriano E., Pericak-Vance M. A., Haines J., Rouleau G. A., Gusella J. S., Horvitz H. R., Brown R. H., Mutations in Cu/Zn superoxide dismutase gene are associated with familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nature 362, 59&#x2013;62 (1993).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8446170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown R. H., Al-Chalabi A., Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. N. Engl. J. Med. 377, 162&#x2013;172 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28700839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mueller C., Berry J. D., McKenna-Yasek D. M., Gernoux G., Owegi M. A., Pothier L. M., Douthwright C. L., Gelevski D., Luppino S. D., Blackwood M., Wightman N. S., Oakley D. H., Frosch M. P., Flotte T. R., Cudkowicz M. E., Brown R. H., SOD1 suppression with adeno-associated virus and MicroRNA in familial ALS. N. Engl. J. Med. 383, 151&#x2013;158 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32640133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller T., Cudkowicz M., Shaw P. J., Andersen P. M., Atassi N., Bucelli R. C., Genge A., Glass J., Ladha S., Ludolph A. L., Maragakis N. J., McDermott C. J., Pestronk A., Ravits J., Salachas F., Trudell R., Van Damme P., Zinman L., Bennett C. F., Lane R., Sandrock A., Runz H., Graham D., Houshyar H., McCampbell A., Nestorov I., Chang I., McNeill M., Fanning L., Fradette S., Ferguson T. A., Phase 1&#x2013;2 trial of antisense oligonucleotide tofersen for SOD1 ALS. N. Engl. J. Med. 383, 109&#x2013;119 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32640130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blanchard E. L., Vanover D., Bawage S. S., Tiwari P. M., Rotolo L., Beyersdorf J., Peck H. E., Bruno N. C., Hincapie R., Michel F., Murray J., Sadhwani H., Vanderheyden B., Finn M. G., Brinton M. A., Lafontaine E. R., Hogan R. J., Zurla C., Santangelo P. J., Treatment of influenza and SARS-CoV-2 infections via mRNA-encoded Cas13a in rodents. Nat. Biotechnol. 39, 717&#x2013;726 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33536629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boill&#xe9;e S., Yamanaka K., Lobsiger C. S., Copeland N. G., Jenkins N. A., Kassiotis G., Kollias G., Cleveland D. W., Onset and progression in inherited ALS determined by motor neurons and microglia. Science 312, 1389&#x2013;1392 (2006).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16741123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foust K. D., Salazar D. L., Likhite S., Ferraiuolo L., Ditsworth D., Ilieva H., Meyer K., Schmelzer L., Braun L., Cleveland D. W., Kaspar B. K., Therapeutic AAV9-mediated suppression of mutant SOD1 slows disease progression and extends survival in models of inherited ALS. Mol. Ther. 21, 2148&#x2013;2159 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3863799</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24008656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagai M., Re D. B., Nagata T., Chalazonitis A., Jessell T. M., Wichterle H., Przedborski S., Astrocytes expressing ALS-linked mutated SOD1 release factors selectively toxic to motor neurons. Nat. Neurosci. 10, 615&#x2013;622 (2007).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3799799</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17435755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamanaka K., Chun S. J., Boillee S., Fujimori-Tonou N., Yamashita H., Gutmann D. H., Takahashi R., Misawa H., Cleveland D. W., Astrocytes as determinants of disease progression in inherited amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat. Neurosci. 11, 251&#x2013;253 (2008).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3137510</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18246065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haidet-Phillips A. M., Hester M. E., Miranda C. J., Meyer K., Braun L., Frakes A., Song S., Likhite S., Murtha M. J., Foust K. D., Rao M., Eagle A., Kammesheidt A., Christensen A., Mendell J. R., Burghes A. H. M., Kaspar B. K., Astrocytes from familial and sporadic ALS patients are toxic to motor neurons. Nat. Biotechnol. 29, 824&#x2013;828 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3170425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21832997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim C. K. W., Gapinske M., Brooks A. K., Woods W. S., Powell J. E., Zeballos M. A., Winter C. J., Perez-Pinera P., Gaj T., Treatment of a mouse model of ALS by in vivo base editing. Mol. Ther. 28, 1177&#x2013;1189 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7132599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31991108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H., Yang B., Qiu L., Yang C., Kramer J., Su Q., Guo Y., Brown R. H. Jr., Gao G., Xu Z., Widespread spinal cord transduction by intrathecal injection of rAAV delivers efficacious RNAi therapy for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Hum. Mol. Genet. 23, 668&#x2013;681 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3888258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24108104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bey K., Ciron C., Dubreil L., Deniaud J., Ledevin M., Cristini J., Blouin V., Aubourg P., Colle M. A., Efficient CNS targeting in adult mice by intrathecal infusion of single-stranded AAV9-GFP for gene therapy of neurological disorders. Gene Ther. 24, 325&#x2013;332 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28425480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gurney M., Pu H., Chiu A., Dal Canto M., Polchow C., Alexander D., Caliendo J., Hentati A., Kwon Y., Deng H., Chen W., Zhai P., Sufit R. L., Siddique T., Motor neuron degeneration in mice that express a human Cu,Zn superoxide dismutase mutation. Science 264, 1772&#x2013;1775 (1994).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8209258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vinsant S., Mansfield C., Jimenez-Moreno R., Del Gaizo Moore V., Yoshikawa M., Hampton T. G., Prevette D., Caress J., Oppenheim R. W., Milligan C., Characterization of early pathogenesis in the SOD1(G93A) mouse model of ALS: Part II, results and discussion. Brain Behav. 3, 431&#x2013;457 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3869683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24381813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaj T., Ojala D. S., Ekman F. K., Byrne L. C., Limsirichai P., Schaffer D. V., In vivo genome editing improves motor function and extends survival in a mouse model of ALS. Sci. Adv. 3, eaar3952 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5738228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29279867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L., Gutmann D. H., Roos R. P., Astrocyte loss of mutant SOD1 delays ALS disease onset and progression in G85R transgenic mice. Hum. Mol. Genet. 20, 286&#x2013;293 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20962037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saudou F., Humbert S., The biology of huntingtin. Neuron 89, 910&#x2013;926 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26938440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tabrizi S. J., Flower M. D., Ross C. A., Wild E. J., Huntington disease: New insights into molecular pathogenesis and therapeutic opportunities. Nat. Rev. Neurol. 16, 529&#x2013;546 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32796930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kordasiewicz H. B., Stanek L. M., Wancewicz E. V., Mazur C., McAlonis M. M., Pytel K. A., Artates J. W., Weiss A., Cheng S. H., Shihabuddin L. S., Hung G., Bennett C. F., Cleveland D. W., Sustained therapeutic reversal of Huntington&#x2019;s disease by transient repression of huntingtin synthesis. Neuron 74, 1031&#x2013;1044 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3383626</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22726834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tabrizi S. J., Leavitt B. R., Landwehrmeyer G. B., Wild E. J., Saft C., Barker R. A., Blair N. F., Craufurd D., Priller J., Rickards H., Rosser A., Kordasiewicz H. B., Czech C., Swayze E. E., Norris D. A., Baumann T., Gerlach I., Schobel S. A., Paz E., Smith A. V., Bennett C. F., Lane R. M., Targeting huntingtin expression in patients with Huntington&#x2019;s disease. N. Engl. J. Med. 380, 2307&#x2013;2316 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31059641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maynard C. J., B&#xf6;ttcher C., Ortega Z., Smith R., Florea B. I., D&#xed;az-Hern&#xe1;ndez M., Brundin P., Overkleeft H. S., Li J. Y., Lucas J. J., Dantuma N. P., Accumulation of ubiquitin conjugates in a polyglutamine disease model occurs without global ubiquitin/proteasome system impairment. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A. 106, 13986&#x2013;13991 (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2729007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19666572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchman A. B., Brogan D. J., Sun R., Yang T., Hsu P. D., Akbari O. S., Programmable RNA targeting using CasRx in flies. CRISPR J. 3, 164&#x2013;176 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7307691</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32584145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez-Lebron E., Denovan-Wright E. M., Nash K., Lewin A. S., Mandel R. J., Intrastriatal rAAV-mediated delivery of anti-huntingtin shRNAs induces partial reversal of disease progression in R6/1 Huntington&#x2019;s disease transgenic mice. Mol. Ther. 12, 618&#x2013;633 (2005).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2656966</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16019264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harper S. Q., Staber P. D., He X., Eliason S. L., Martins I. H., Mao Q., Yang L., Kotin R. M., Paulson H. L., Davidson B. L., RNA interference improves motor and neuropathological abnormalities in a Huntington&#x2019;s disease mouse model. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A. 102, 5820&#x2013;5825 (2005).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC556303</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15811941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mangiarini L., Sathasivam K., Seller M., Cozens B., Harper A., Hetherington C., Lawton M., Trottier Y., Lehrach H., Davies S. W., Bates G. P., Exon 1 of the HD gene with an expanded CAG repeat is sufficient to cause a progressive neurological phenotype in transgenic mice. Cell 87, 493&#x2013;506 (1996).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8898202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekman F. K., Ojala D. S., Adil M. M., Lopez P. A., Schaffer D. V., Gaj T., CRISPR-Cas9-mediated genome editing increases lifespan and improves motor deficits in a Huntington&#x2019;s disease mouse model. Mol. Ther. Nucleic Acids 17, 829&#x2013;839 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6717077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31465962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boudreau R. L., McBride J. L., Martins I., Shen S., Xing Y., Carter B. J., Davidson B. L., Nonallele-specific silencing of mutant and wild-type huntingtin demonstrates therapeutic efficacy in Huntington&#x2019;s disease mice. Mol. Ther. 17, 1053&#x2013;1063 (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2835182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19240687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McBride J. L., Boudreau R. L., Harper S. Q., Staber P. D., Monteys A. M., Martins I., Gilmore B. L., Burstein H., Peluso R. W., Polisky B., Carter B. J., Davidson B. L., Artificial miRNAs mitigate shRNA-mediated toxicity in the brain: Implications for the therapeutic development of RNAi. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A. 105, 5868&#x2013;5873 (2008).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2311380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18398004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nieuwenhuis B., Haenzi B., Hilton S., Carnicer-Lombarte A., Hobo B., Verhaagen J., Fawcett J. W., Optimization of adeno-associated viral vector-mediated transduction of the corticospinal tract: Comparison of four promoters. Gene Ther. 28, 56&#x2013;74 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7902269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32576975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J. Y., Popovic N., Brundin P., The use of the R6 transgenic mouse models of Huntington&#x2019;s disease in attempts to develop novel therapeutic strategies. NeuroRx 2, 447&#x2013;464 (2005).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1144488</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16389308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bennett C. F., Krainer A. R., Cleveland D. W., Antisense oligonucleotide therapies for neurodegenerative diseases. Annu. Rev. Neurosci. 42, 385&#x2013;406 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7427431</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31283897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva A. C., Lobo D. D., Martins I. M., Lopes S. M., Henriques C., Duarte S. P., Dodart J.-C., Nobre R. J., Pereira de Almeida L., Antisense oligonucleotide therapeutics in neurodegenerative diseases: The case of polyglutamine disorders. Brain 143, 407&#x2013;429 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31738395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martier R., Konstantinova P., Gene therapy for neurodegenerative diseases: Slowing down the ticking clock. Front. Neurosci. 14, 580179 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7530328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33071748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghosh R., Tabrizi S. J., Gene suppression approaches to neurodegeneration. Alzheimer&#x2019;s Res. Ther. 9, 82 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5629803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28982376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vall&#xe8;s A., Evers M. M., Stam A., Sogorb-Gonzalez M., Brouwers C., Vendrell-Tornero C., Acar-Broekmans S., Paerels L., Klima J., Bohuslavova B., Pintauro R., Fodale V., Bresciani A., Liscak R., Urgosik D., Starek Z., Crha M., Blits B., Petry H., Ellederova Z., Motlik J., van Deventer S., Konstantinova P., Widespread and sustained target engagement in Huntington&#x2019;s disease minipigs upon intrastriatal microRNA-based gene therapy. Sci. Transl. Med. 13, eabb8920 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33827977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janas M. M., Schlegel M. K., Harbison C. E., Yilmaz V. O., Jiang Y., Parmar R., Zlatev I., Castoreno A., Xu H., Shulga-Morskaya S., Rajeev K. G., Manoharan M., Keirstead N. D., Maier M. A., Jadhav V., Selection of GalNAc-conjugated siRNAs with limited off-target-driven rat hepatotoxicity. Nat. Commun. 9, 723 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5818625</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29459660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li C., Samulski R. J., Engineering adeno-associated virus vectors for gene therapy. Nat. Rev. Genet. 21, 255&#x2013;272 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32042148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kay C., Collins J. A., Skotte N. H., Southwell A. L., Warby S. C., Caron N. S., Doty C. N., Nguyen B., Griguoli A., Ross C. J., Squitieri F., Hayden M. R., Huntingtin haplotypes provide prioritized target panels for allele-specific silencing in huntington disease patients of european ancestry. Mol. Ther. 23, 1759&#x2013;1771 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4817952</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26201449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chao M. J., Gillis T., Atwal R. S., Mysore J. S., Arjomand J., Harold D., Holmans P., Jones L., Orth M., Myers R. H., Kwak S., Wheeler V. C., MacDonald M. E., Gusella J. F., Lee J.-M., Haplotype-based stratification of Huntington&#x2019;s disease. Eur. J. Hum. Genet. 25, 1202&#x2013;1209 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5643960</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28832564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee J.-M., Kim K.-H., Shin A., Chao M. J., Elneel K. A., Gillis T., Mysore J. S., Kaye J. A., Zahed H., Kratter I. H., Daub A. C., Finkbeiner S., Li H., Roach J. C., Goodman N., Hood L., Myers R. H., MacDonald M. E., Gusella J. F., Sequence-level analysis of the major European huntington disease haplotype. Am. J. Hum. Genet. 97, 435&#x2013;444 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4564985</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26320893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borel F., Gernoux G., Cardozo B., Metterville J. P., Toro Cabreja G. C., Song L., Su Q., Gao G. P., Elmallah M. K., Brown R. H. Jr., Mueller C., Therapeutic rAAVrh10 mediated SOD1 silencing in adult SOD1(G93A) mice and nonhuman primates. Hum. Gene Ther. 27, 19&#x2013;31 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4741242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26710998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCampbell A., Cole T., Wegener A. J., Tomassy G. S., Setnicka A., Farley B. J., Schoch K. M., Hoye M. L., Shabsovich M., Sun L., Luo Y., Zhang M., Comfort N., Wang B., Amacker J., Thankamony S., Salzman D. W., Cudkowicz M., Graham D. L., Bennett C. F., Kordasiewicz H. B., Swayze E. E., Miller T. M., Antisense oligonucleotides extend survival and reverse decrement in muscle response in ALS models. J. Clin. Investig. 128, 3558&#x2013;3567 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6063493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30010620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raoul C., Abbas-Terki T., Bensadoun J.-C., Guillot S., Haase G., Szulc J., Henderson C. E., Aebischer P., Lentiviral-mediated silencing of SOD1 through RNA interference retards disease onset and progression in a mouse model of ALS. Nat. Med. 11, 423&#x2013;428 (2005).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15768028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DiFiglia M., Sena-Esteves M., Chase K., Sapp E., Pfister E., Sass M., Yoder J., Reeves P., Pandey R. K., Rajeev K. G., Manoharan M., Sah D. W. Y., Zamore P. D., Aronin N., Therapeutic silencing of mutant huntingtin with siRNA attenuates striatal and cortical neuropathology and behavioral deficits. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A. 104, 17204&#x2013;17209 (2007).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2040405</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17940007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oikemus S. R., Pfister E., Sapp E., Chase K. O., Kennington L. A., Hudgens E., Miller R., Zhu L. J., Chaudhary A., Mick E. O., Sena-Esteves M., Wolfe S. A., DiFiglia M., Aronin N., Brodsky M. H., Allele-specific knockdown of mutant HTT protein via editing at coding region SNP heterozygosities. Hum. Gene Ther. (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8819514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34376056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shin J. W., Kim K.-H., Chao M. J., Atwal R. S., Gillis T., MacDonald M. E., Gusella J. F., Lee J.-M., Permanent inactivation of Huntington&#x2019;s disease mutation by personalized allele-specific CRISPR/Cas9. Hum. Mol. Genet. 25, 4566&#x2013;4576 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6078600</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28172889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monteys A. M., Ebanks S. A., Keiser M. S., Davidson B. L., CRISPR/Cas9 editing of the mutant huntingtin allele in vitro and in vivo. Mol. Ther. 25, 12&#x2013;23 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5363210</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28129107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charlesworth C. T., Deshpande P. S., Dever D. P., Camarena J., Lemgart V. T., Cromer M. K., Vakulskas C. A., Collingwood M. A., Zhang L., Bode N. M., Behlke M. A., Dejene B., Cieniewicz B., Romano R., Lesch B. J., Gomez-Ospina N., Mantri S., Pavel-Dinu M., Weinberg K. I., Porteus M. H., Identification of preexisting adaptive immunity to Cas9 proteins in humans. Nat. Med. 25, 249&#x2013;254 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7199589</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30692695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chew W. L., Tabebordbar M., Cheng J. K. W., Mali P., Wu E. Y., Ng A. H. M., Zhu K., Wagers A. J., Church G. M., A multifunctional AAV&#x2013;CRISPR&#x2013;Cas9 and its host response. Nat. Med. 13, 868&#x2013;874 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5374744</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27595405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou G., Soufan O., Ewald J., Hancock R. E. W., Basu N., Xia J., NetworkAnalyst 3.0: A visual analytics platform for comprehensive gene expression profiling and meta-analysis. Nucleic Acids Res. 47, W234&#x2013;W241 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6602507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30931480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashburner M., Ball C. A., Blake J. A., Botstein D., Butler H., Cherry J. M., Davis A. P., Dolinski K., Dwight S. S., Eppig J. T., Harris M. A., Hill D. P., Issel-Tarver L., Kasarskis A., Lewis S., Matese J. C., Richardson J. E., Ringwald M., Rubin G. M., Sherlock G., Gene ontology: Tool for the unification of biology. Nat. Genet. 25, 25&#x2013;29 (2000).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3037419</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10802651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaj T., Schaffer D. V., Adeno-associated virus&#x2013;mediated delivery of CRISPR-Cas systems for genome engineering in mammalian cells. Cold Spring Harb. Protoc. 2016, pdb.prot086868 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6850213</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27803249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>