<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35048358</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>06</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1476-5381</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>179</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>British journal of pharmacology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Br J Pharmacol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Altered blood-brain barrier and blood-spinal cord barrier dynamics in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Impact on medication efficacy and safety.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2577</StartPage><EndPage>2588</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2577-2588</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/bph.15802</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The access of drugs into the central nervous system (CNS) is regulated by the blood-brain barrier (BBB) and blood-spinal cord barrier (BSCB). A large body of evidence supports perturbation of these barriers in neurodegenerative diseases, including Alzheimer's disease and Parkinson's disease. Modifications to the BBB and BSCB are also reported in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS), albeit these modifications have received less attention relative to those in other neurodegenerative diseases. Such alterations to the BBB and BSCB have the potential to impact on CNS exposure of drugs in ALS, modulating the effectiveness of drugs intended to reach the brain and the toxicity of drugs that are not intended to reach the brain. Given the clinical importance of these phenomena, this review will summarise reported modifications to the BBB and BSCB in ALS, discuss their impact on CNS drug exposure, and suggest further research directions so as to optimise medicine use in people with ALS.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022 The British Pharmacological Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pan</LastName><ForeName>Yijun</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1442-3333</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Drug Delivery, Disposition and Dynamics, Monash Institute of Pharmaceutical Sciences, Monash University, Parkville, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nicolazzo</LastName><ForeName>Joseph A</ForeName><Initials>JA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0983-7152</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Drug Delivery, Disposition and Dynamics, Monash Institute of Pharmaceutical Sciences, Monash University, Parkville, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Br J Pharmacol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7502536</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0007-1188</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001812" MajorTopicYN="N">Blood-Brain Barrier</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002490" MajorTopicYN="N">Central Nervous System</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013116" MajorTopicYN="N">Spinal Cord</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">P-glycoprotein</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">blood-brain barrier</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">breast cancer resistance protein</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tight junctions</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35048358</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bph.15802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Abbott, N. J., Patabendige, A. A., Dolman, D. E., Yusof, S. R., &amp; Begley, D. J. (2010). Structure and function of the blood-brain barrier. Neurobiology of Disease, 37, 13-25. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nbd.2009.07.030</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abrahao, A., Meng, Y., Llinas, M., Huang, Y., Hamani, C., Mainprize, T., Aubert, I., Heyn, C., Black, S. E., Hynynen, K., Lipsman, N., &amp; Zinman, L. (2019). First-in-human trial of blood-brain barrier opening in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis using MR-guided focused ultrasound. Nature Communications, 10, 4373. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-019-12426-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Bachari, S., Naish, J. H., Parker, G. J. M., Emsley, H. C. A., &amp; Parkes, L. M. (2020). Blood-brain barrier leakage is increased in Parkinson's disease. Frontiers in Physiology, 11, 593026. https://doi.org/10.3389/fphys.2020.593026</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alexander, S. P., Kelly, E., Mathie, A., Peters, J. A., Veale, E. L., Armstrong, J. F., Faccenda, E., Harding, S. D., Pawson, A. J., Southan, C., Davies, J. A., Amarosi, L., Anderson, C. M. H., Beart, P. M., Broer, S., Dawson, P. A., Hagenbuch, B., Hammond, J. R., Inui, K.-I., &#x2026; Verri, T. (2021). THE CONCISE GUIDE TO PHARMACOLOGY 2021/22: Transporters. British Journal of Pharmacology, 178(S1), S412-S513. https://doi.org/10.1111/bph.15543</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andjus, P. R., Batavelji&#x107;, D., Vanhoutte, G., Mitrecic, D., Pizzolante, F., Djogo, N., Nicaise, C., Kengne, F. G., Gangitano, C., Michetti, F., van der Linden, A., Pochet, R., &amp; Baci&#x107;, G. (2009). In vivo morphological changes in animal models of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and Alzheimer's-like disease: MRI approach. The Anatomical Record, 292, 1882-1892. https://doi.org/10.1002/ar.20995</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartels, A. L., Willemsen, A. T., Kortekaas, R., de Jong, B. M., de Vries, R., de Klerk, O., van Oostrom, J. C. H., Portman, A., &amp; Leenders, K. L. (2008). Decreased blood-brain barrier P-glycoprotein function in the progression of Parkinson's disease, PSP and MSA. Journal of Neural Transmission, 115, 1001-1009. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00702-008-0030-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beghi, E., Mennini, T., Bendotti, C., Bigini, P., Logroscino, G., Chi&#xf2;, A., Hardiman, O., Mitchell, D., Swingler, R., Traynor, B. J., &amp; Al-Chalabi, A. (2007). The heterogeneity of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A possible explanation of treatment failure. Current Medicinal Chemistry, 14, 3185-3200. https://doi.org/10.2174/092986707782793862</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruijn, L. I., Becher, M. W., Lee, M. K., Anderson, K. L., Jenkins, N. A., Copeland, N. G., Sisodia, S. S., Rothstein, J. D., Borchelt, D. R., Price, D. L., &amp; Cleveland, D. W. (1997). ALS-linked SOD1 mutant G85R mediates damage to astrocytes and promotes rapidly progressive disease with SOD1-containing inclusions. Neuron, 18, 327-338. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0896-6273(00)80272-X</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan, G. N. Y., Evans, R. A., Banks, D. B., Mesev, E. V., Miller, D. S., &amp; Cannon, R. E. (2017). Selective induction of P-glycoprotein at the CNS barriers during symptomatic stage of an ALS animal model. Neuroscience Letters, 639, 103-113. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neulet.2016.12.049</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2;, A., Logroscino, G., Hardiman, O., Swingler, R., Mitchell, D., Beghi, E., Traynor, B. G., &amp; On Behalf of the Eurals Consortium (2009). Prognostic factors in ALS: A critical review. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis, 10, 310-323. https://doi.org/10.3109/17482960802566824</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis, T. P., Sanchez-Covarubias, L., &amp; Tome, M. E. (2014). P-glycoprotein trafficking as a therapeutic target to optimize CNS drug delivery. Advances in Pharmacology, 71, 25-44. https://doi.org/10.1016/bs.apha.2014.06.009</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donnenfeld, H., Kascsak, R. J., &amp; Bartfeld, H. (1984). Deposits of IgG and C3 in the spinal cord and motor cortex of ALS patients. Journal of Neuroimmunology, 6, 51-57. https://doi.org/10.1016/0165-5728(84)90042-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Engelhardt, J. I., &amp; Appel, S. H. (1990). IgG reactivity in the spinal cord and motor cortex in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Archives of Neurology, 47, 1210-1216. https://doi.org/10.1001/archneur.1990.00530110068019</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garbuzova-Davis, S., Haller, E., Saporta, S., Kolomey, I., Nicosia, S. V., &amp; Sanberg, P. R. (2007). Ultrastructure of blood-brain barrier and blood-spinal cord barrier in SOD1 mice modeling ALS. Brain Research, 1157, 126-137. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.brainres.2007.04.044</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garbuzova-Davis, S., Hernandez-Ontiveros, D. G., Rodrigues, M. C. O., Haller, E., Frisina-Deyo, A., Mirtyl, S., Sallot, S., Saporta, S., Borlongan, C. V., &amp; Sanberg, P. R. (2012). Impaired blood-brain/spinal cord barrier in ALS patients. Brain Research, 1469, 114-128. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.brainres.2012.05.056</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garbuzova-Davis, S., Saporta, S., Haller, E., Kolomey, I., Bennett, S. P., Potter, H., &amp; Sanberg, P. R. (2007). Evidence of compromised blood-spinal cord barrier in early and late symptomatic SOD1 mice modeling ALS. PLoS ONE, 2, e1205-e1205. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0001205</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ge, S., &amp; Pachter, J. S. (2006). Isolation and culture of microvascular endothelial cells from murine spinal cord. Journal of Neuroimmunology, 177, 209-214. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jneuroim.2006.05.012</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Golden, P. L., &amp; Pardridge, W. M. (1999). P-glycoprotein on astrocyte foot processes of unfixed isolated human brain capillaries. Brain Research, 819, 143-146. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0006-8993(98)01305-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grande, G., Morin, L., Vetrano, D. L., Fastbom, J., &amp; Johnell, K. (2017). Drug use in older adults with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis near the end of life. Drugs &amp; Aging, 34, 529-533. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40266-017-0469-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gurney, M. E., Pu, H., Chiu, A. Y., Dal Canto, M. C., Polchow, C. Y., Alexander, D. D., Caliendo, J., Hentati, A., Kwon, Y. W., Deng, H. X., Chen, W., Zhai, P., Sufit, R. L., &amp; Siddique, T. (1994). Motor neuron degeneration in mice that express a human Cu,Zn superoxide dismutase mutation. Science, 264, 1772-1775. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.8209258</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han-Xiang, D., Hujun, J., Ronggen, F., Hong, Z., Yong, S., Erdong, L., Makito, H., Mauro, C. D. C., &amp; Teepu, S. (2008). Molecular dissection of ALS-associated toxicity of SOD1 in transgenic mice using an exon-fusion approach. Human Molecular Genetics, 17, 2310-2319. https://doi.org/10.1093/hmg/ddn131</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henkel, J. S., Beers, D. R., Wen, S., Bowser, R., &amp; Appel, S. H. (2009). Decreased mRNA expression of tight junction proteins in lumbar spinal cords of patients with ALS. Neurology, 72, 1614-1616. https://doi.org/10.1212/WNL.0b013e3181a41228</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hobson, E. V., &amp; McDermott, C. J. (2016). Supportive and symptomatic management of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nature Reviews. Neurology, 12, 526-538. https://doi.org/10.1038/nrneurol.2016.111</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howland, D. S., Liu, J., She, Y., Goad, B., Maragakis, N. J., Kim, B., Erickson, J., Kulik, J., DeVito, L., Psaltis, G., DeGennaro, L. J., Cleveland, D. W., &amp; Rothstein, J. D. (2002). Focal loss of the glutamate transporter EAAT2 in a transgenic rat model of SOD1 mutant-mediated amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 99, 1604-1609. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.032539299</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iguchi, Y., Katsuno, M., Niwa, J.-i., Takagi, S., Ishigaki, S., Ikenaka, K., Kawai, K., Watanabe, H., Yamanaka, K., Takahashi, R., Misawa, H., Sasaki, S., Tanaka, F., &amp; Sobue, G. (2013). Loss of TDP-43 causes age-dependent progressive motor neuron degeneration. Brain, 136, 1371-1382. https://doi.org/10.1093/brain/awt029</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jablonski, M. R., Jacob, D. A., Campos, C., Miller, D. S., Maragakis, N. J., Pasinelli, P., &amp; Trotti, D. (2012). Selective increase of two ABC drug efflux transporters at the blood-spinal cord barrier suggests induced pharmacoresistance in ALS. Neurobiology of Disease, 47, 194-200. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nbd.2012.03.040</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jablonski, M. R., Markandaiah, S. S., Jacob, D., Meng, N. J., Li, K., Gennaro, V., Lepore, A. C., Trotti, D., &amp; Pasinelli, P. (2014). Inhibiting drug efflux transporters improves efficacy of ALS therapeutics. Annals of Clinical Translational Neurology, 1, 996-1005. https://doi.org/10.1002/acn3.141</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang, J., Zhu, Q., Gendron Tania, F., Saberi, S., McAlonis-Downes, M., Seelman, A., Stauffer, J. E., Jafar-Nejad, P., Drenner, K., Schulte, D., &amp; Chun, S. (2016). Gain of toxicity from ALS/FTD-linked repeat expansions in C9ORF72 is alleviated by antisense oligonucleotides targeting GGGGCC-containing RNAs. Neuron, 90, 535-550. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2016.04.006</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keep, M., Elm&#xe9;r, K., Fong, K. S., &amp; Csiszar, K. (2001). Intrathecal cyclosporin prolongs survival of late-stage ALS mice. Brain Research, 894, 327-331. https://doi.org/10.1016/s0006-8993(01)02012-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leonardi, A., Abbruzzese, G., Arata, L., Cocito, L., &amp; Vische, M. (1984). Cerebrospinal fluid (CSF) findings in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Journal of Neurology, 231, 75-78. https://doi.org/10.1007/BF00313720</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Y., Pattamatta, A., Zu, T., Reid, T., Bardhi, O., Borchelt, D. R., Yachnis, A. T., &amp; Ranum, L. P. (2016). C9orf72 BAC mouse model with motor deficits and neurodegenerative features of ALS/FTD. Neuron, 90, 521-534. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2016.04.005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longinetti, E., &amp; Fang, F. (2019). Epidemiology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: An update of recent literature. Current Opinion in Neurology, 32, 771-776. https://doi.org/10.1097/WCO.0000000000000730</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehta, D. C., Short, J., &amp; Nicolazzo, J. (2013). Altered brain uptake of therapeutics in a triple transgenic mouse model of Alzheimer's disease. Pharmaceutical Research, 30, 2868-2879. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11095-013-1116-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mejzini, R., Flynn, L. L., Pitout, I. L., Fletcher, S., Wilton, S. D., &amp; Akkari, P. A. (2019). ALS genetics, mechanisms, and therapeutics: Where are we now? Frontiers in Neuroscience, 13, 01310. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnins.2019.01310</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer, T., Kettemann, D., Maier, A., Grehl, T., Weyen, U., Grosskreutz, J., Steinbach, R., Norden, J., George, A., Hermann, A., Guenther, R., Petri, S., Schreiber-Katz, O., Dorst, J., Ludolph, A. C., Walter, B., M&#xfc;nch, C., &amp; Spittel, S. (2020). Symptomatic pharmacotherapy in ALS: Data analysis from a platform-based medication management programme. Journal of Neurology, Neurosurgery, and Psychiatry, 91, 783-785. https://doi.org/10.1136/jnnp-2020-322938</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milane, A., Fernandez, C., Dupuis, L., Buyse, M., Loeffler, J. P., Farinotti, R., Meininger, V., &amp; Bensimon, G. (2010). P-glycoprotein expression and function are increased in an animal model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuroscience Letters, 472, 166-170. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neulet.2010.01.078</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller, T., Cudkowicz, M., Shaw, P. J., Andersen, P. M., Atassi, N., Bucelli, R. C., Genge, A., Glass, J., Ladha, S., Ludolph, A. L., Maragakis, N. J., McDermott, C. J., Pestronk, A., Ravits, J., Salachas, F., Trudell, R., Van Damme, P., Zinman, L., Bennett, C. F., &#x2026; Ferguson, T. A. (2020). Phase 1-2 trial of antisense oligonucleotide tofersen for SOD1 ALS. New England Journal of Medicine, 383, 109-119. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJMoa2003715</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyazaki, K., Ohta, Y., Nagai, M., Morimoto, N., Kurata, T., Takehisa, Y., Ikeda, Y., Matsuura, T., &amp; Abe, K. (2011). Disruption of neurovascular unit prior to motor neuron degeneration in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Journal of Neuroscience Research, 89, 718-728. https://doi.org/10.1002/jnr.22594</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen, L., Montrasio, F., Pattamatta, A., Tusi, S. K., Bardhi, O., Meyer, K. D., Hayes, L., Nakamura, K., Banez-Coronel, M., Coyne, A., Guo, S., Laboissonniere, L. A., Gu, Y., Narayanan, S., Smith, B., Nitsch, R. M., Kankel, M. W., Rushe, M., Rothstein, J., &#x2026; Ranum, L. P. W. (2020). Antibody therapy targeting RAN proteins rescues C9 ALS/FTD phenotypes in C9orf72 mouse model. Neuron, 105, 645-662.e611. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2019.11.007</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicaise, C., Mitrecic, D., Demetter, P., De Decker, R., Authelet, M., Boom, A., &amp; Pochet, R. (2009). Impaired blood-brain and blood-spinal cord barriers in mutant SOD1-linked ALS rat. Brain Research, 1301, 152-162. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.brainres.2009.09.018</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicolazzo, J. A., Charman, S. A., &amp; Charman, W. N. (2006). Methods to assess drug permeability across the blood-brain barrier. The Journal of Pharmacy and Pharmacology, 58, 281-293.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh, K.-W., Noh, M.-Y., Kwon, M.-S., Kim, H. Y., Oh, S.-i., Park, J., Kim, H. J., Ki, C. S., &amp; Kim, S. H. (2018). Repeated intrathecal mesenchymal stem cells for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Annals of Neurology, 84, 361-373. https://doi.org/10.1002/ana.25302</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ono, S., Imai, T., Munakata, S., Takahashi, K., Kanda, F., Hashimoto, K., Yamano, T., Shimizu, N., Nagao, K., &amp; Yamauchi, M. (1998). Collagen abnormalities in the spinal cord from patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Journal of the Neurological Sciences, 160, 140-147. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0022-510X(98)00223-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Rourke, J. G., Bogdanik, L., Muhammad, A. K. M. G., Gendron, T. F., Kim, K. J., Austin, A., Cady, J., Liu, E. Y., Zarrow, J., Grant, S., Ho, R., Bell, S., Carmona, S., Simpikinson, M., Lall, D., Wu, K., Daughrity, L., Dickson, D. W., Harms, M. B., &#x2026; Baloh, R. (2015). C9orf72 BAC transgenic mice display typical pathologic features of ALS/FTD. Neuron, 88, 892-901. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2015.10.027</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan, W., Banks, W. A., &amp; Kastin, A. J. (1997). Permeability of the blood-brain and blood-spinal cord barriers to interferons. Journal of Neuroimmunology, 76, 105-111. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0165-5728(97)00034-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan, Y., &amp; Nicolazzo, J. A. (2018). Impact of aging, Alzheimer's disease and Parkinson's disease on the blood-brain barrier transport of therapeutics. Advanced Drug Delivery Reviews, 135, 62-74. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.addr.2018.04.009</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pandya, V. A., &amp; Patani, R. (2020). Decoding the relationship between ageing and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A cellular perspective. Brain, 143, 1057-1072.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peters, O. M., Cabrera Gabriela, T., Tran, H., Gendron Tania, F., McKeon Jeanne, E., Metterville, J., Weiss, A., Wightman, N., Salameh, J., Kim, J., &amp; Sun, H. (2015). Human C9ORF72 hexanucleotide expansion reproduces RNA foci and dipeptide repeat proteins but not neurodegeneration in BAC transgenic mice. Neuron, 88, 902-909. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2015.11.018</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Philips, T., &amp; Rothstein, J. D. (2015). Rodent models of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Current Protocols in Pharmacology, 69, 5.67.1-5.67.21. https://doi.org/10.1002/0471141755.ph0567s69</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Picher-Martel, V., Valdmanis, P. N., Gould, P. V., Julien, J.-P., &amp; Dupr&#xe9;, N. (2016). From animal models to human disease: A genetic approach for personalized medicine in ALS. Acta Neuropathologica Communications, 4, 70. https://doi.org/10.1186/s40478-016-0340-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puris, E., Gynther, M., Auriola, S., &amp; Huttunen, K. M. (2020). L-type amino acid transporter 1 as a target for drug delivery. Pharmaceutical Research, 37, 88-88. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11095-020-02826-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosen, D. R., Siddique, T., Patterson, D., Figlewicz, D. A., Sapp, P., Hentati, A., Donaldson, D., Goto, J., O'Regan, J. P., Deng, H. X., Rahmani, Z., Krizus, A., McKenna-Yasek, D., Cayabyab, A., Gaston, S. M., Berger, R., Tanzi, R. E., Halperin, J. J., Herzfeldt, B., &#x2026; Brown, R. H. Jr. (1993). Mutations in Cu/Zn superoxide dismutase gene are associated with familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nature, 362, 59-62. https://doi.org/10.1038/362059a0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sasaki, S. (2015). Alterations of the blood-spinal cord barrier in sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuropathology, 35, 518-528. https://doi.org/10.1111/neup.12221</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sasaki, S., Iguchi, Y., Katsuno, M., &amp; Sobue, G. (2015). Alterations in the blood-spinal cord barrier in TDP-43 conditional knockout mice. Neuroscience Letters, 598, 1-5. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neulet.2015.05.005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saul, J., Hutchins, E., Reiman, R., Saul, M., Ostrow, L. W., Harris, B. T., Van Keuren-Jensen, K., Bowser, R., &amp; Bakkar, N. (2020). Global alterations to the choroid plexus blood-CSF barrier in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathologica Communications, 8, 92. https://doi.org/10.1186/s40478-020-00968-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shefner, J., Heiman-Patterson, T., Pioro, E. P., Wiedau-Pazos, M., Liu, S., Zhang, J., Agnese, W., &amp; Apple, S. (2020). Long-term edaravone efficacy in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Post-hoc analyses of Study 19 (MCI186-19). Muscle &amp; Nerve, 61, 218-221. https://doi.org/10.1002/mus.26740</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shelkovnikova, T. A., Peters, O. M., Deykin, A. V., Connor-Robson, N., Robinson, H., Ustyugov, A. A., Bachurin, S. O., Ermolkevich, T. G., Goldman, I. L., Sadchikova, E. R., Kovrazhkina, E. A., Skvortsova, V. I., Ling, S. C., da Cruz, S., Parone, P. A., Buchman, V. L., &amp; Ninkina, N. N. (2013). Fused in sarcoma (FUS) protein lacking nuclear localization signal (NLS) and major RNA binding motifs triggers proteinopathy and severe motor phenotype in transgenic mice. The Journal of Biological Chemistry, 288, 25266-25274. https://doi.org/10.1074/jbc.M113.492017</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sweeney, M. D., Sagare, A. P., &amp; Zlokovic, B. V. (2018). Blood-brain barrier breakdown in Alzheimer disease and other neurodegenerative disorders. Nature Reviews. Neurology, 14, 133-150. https://doi.org/10.1038/nrneurol.2017.188</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uchida, Y., Yagi, Y., Takao, M., Tano, M., Umetsu, M., Hirano, S., Usui, T., Tachikawa, M., &amp; Terasaki, T. (2020). Comparison of absolute protein abundances of transporters and receptors among blood-brain barriers at different cerebral regions and the blood-spinal cord barrier in humans and rats. Molecular Pharmaceutics, 17, 2006-2020. https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.molpharmaceut.0c00178</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Assema, D. M. E., Lubberink, M., Bauer, M., van der Flier, W. M., Schuit, R. C., Windhorst, A. D., Comans, E. F. I., Hoetjes, N. J., Tolboom, N., Langer, O., Muller, M., Scheltens, P., Lammertsma, A. A., &amp; van Berckel, B. N. M. (2012). Blood-brain barrier P-glycoprotein function in Alzheimer's disease. Brain, 135, 181-190. https://doi.10.1093/brain/awr298</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Damme, P., &amp; Robberecht, W. (2014). Developments in treatments for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis via intracerebroventricular or intrathecal delivery. Expert Opinion on Investigational Drugs, 23, 955-963. https://doi.org/10.1517/13543784.2014.912275</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Vliet, E. A., Iyer, A. M., Mesarosova, L., &#xc7;olakoglu, H., Anink, J. J., van Tellingen, O., Maragakis, N. J., Shefner, J., Bunt, T., &amp; Aronica, E. (2020). Expression and cellular distribution of P-glycoprotein and breast cancer resistance protein in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. Journal of Neuropathology and Experimental Neurology, 79, 266-276.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, J., Xu, G., Li, H., Gonzales, V., Fromholt, D., Karch, C., Copeland, N. G., Jenkins, N. A., &amp; Borchelt, D. R. (2005). Somatodendritic accumulation of misfolded SOD1-L126Z in motor neurons mediates degeneration: &#x3b1;B-crystallin modulates aggregation. Human Molecular Genetics, 14, 2335-2347. https://doi.org/10.1093/hmg/ddi236</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waters, S., Swanson, M. E. V., Dieriks, B. V., Zhang, Y. B., Grimsey, N. L., Murray, H. C., Turner, C., Waldvogel, H. J., Faull, R. L. M., An, J., Bowser, R., Curtis, M. A., Dragunow, M., &amp; Scotter, E. (2021). Blood-spinal cord barrier leakage is independent of motor neuron pathology in ALS. Acta Neuropathologica Communications, 9, 144. https://doi.org/10.1186/s40478-021-01244-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wegorzewska, I., Bell, S., Cairns, N. J., Miller, T. M., &amp; Baloh, R. H. (2009). TDP-43 mutant transgenic mice develop features of ALS and frontotemporal lobar degeneration. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 106, 18809-18814. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.0908767106</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winkler, E. A., Sengillo, J. D., Bell, R. D., Wang, J., &amp; Zlokovic, B. V. (2012). Blood-spinal cord barrier pericyte reductions contribute to increased capillary permeability. Journal of Cerebral Blood Flow and Metabolism, 32, 1841-1852. https://doi.org/10.1038/jcbfm.2012.113</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winkler, E. A., Sengillo, J. D., Sullivan, J. S., Henkel, J. S., Appel, S. H., &amp; Zlokovic, B. V. (2013). Blood-spinal cord barrier breakdown and pericyte reductions in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathologica, 125, 111-120. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00401-012-1039-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong, P. C., Pardo, C. A., Borchelt, D. R., Lee, M. K., Copeland, N. G., Jenkins, N. A., Sisodia, S. S., Cleveland, D. W., &amp; Price, D. L. (1995). An adverse property of a familial ALS-linked SOD1 mutation causes motor neuron disease characterized by vacuolar degeneration of mitochondria. Neuron, 14, 1105-1116. https://doi.org/10.1016/0896-6273(95)90259-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wyss-Coray, T. (2016). Ageing, neurodegeneration and brain rejuvenation. Nature, 539, 180-186. https://doi.org/10.1038/nature20411</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamadera, M., Fujimura, H., Inoue, K., Toyooka, K., Mori, C., Hirano, H., &amp; Sakoda, S. (2015). Microvascular disturbance with decreased pericyte coverage is prominent in the ventral horn of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener, 16, 393-401. https://doi.org/10.3109/21678421.2015.1011663</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, A. C., Stevens, M. Y., Chen, M. B., Lee, D. P., St&#xe4;hli, D., Gate, D., Contrepois, K., Chen, W., Iram, T., Zhang, L., Vest, R. T., Chaney, A., Lehallier, B., Olsson, N., du Bois, H., Hsieh, R., Cropper, H. C., Berdnik, D., Li, L., &#x2026; Wyss-Coray, T. (2020). Physiological blood-brain transport is impaired with age by a shift in transcytosis. Nature, 583, 425-430. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41586-020-2453-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhong, Z., Deane, R., Ali, Z., Parisi, M., Shapovalov, Y., O'Banion, M. K., Stojanovic, K., Sagare, A., Boillee, S., Cleveland, D. W., &amp; Zlokovic, B. V. (2008). ALS-causing SOD1 mutants generate vascular changes prior to motor neuron degeneration. Nature Neuroscience, 11, 420-422. https://doi.org/10.1038/nn2073</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, Q., Mareljic, N., Michaelsen, M., Parhizkar, S., Heindl, S., Nuscher, B., Farny, D., Czuppa, M., Schludi, C., Graf, A., &amp; Krebs, S. (2020). Active poly-GA vaccination prevents microglia activation and motor deficits in a C9orf72 mouse model. EMBO Molecular Medicine, 12, e10919.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zoccolella, S., Beghi, E., Palagano, G., Fraddosio, A., Guerra, V., Samarelli, V., Lepore, V., Simone, I. L., Lamberti, P., Serlenga, L., Logroscino, G., &amp; for the SLAP registry. (2007). Riluzole and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis survival: A population-based study in southern Italy. European Journal of Neurology, 14, 262-268. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1468-1331.2006.01575.x</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>