<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35062955</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>25</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1477-7525</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>20</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Health and quality of life outcomes</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Health Qual Life Outcomes</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Qualitative measures that assess functional disability and quality of life in ALS.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>12</StartPage><MedlinePgn>12</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">12</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12955-022-01919-9</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Selection of appropriate trial endpoints and outcome measures is particularly important in rare disease and rapidly progressing disease such as amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) where the challenges to conducting clinical trials, are substantial: patient and disease heterogeneity, limited understanding of exact disease pathophysiology, and lack of robust and available biomarkers. To address these challenges in ALS, the Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Functional Rating Scale-Revised version (ALSFRS-R) was developed and has become a key primary endpoint in ALS clinical trials to assess functional disability and disease progression, often replacing survival as a primary outcome. However, increased understanding of the ALS disease journey and improvements in assistive technology for ALS patients have exposed issues with the ALSFRS-R, including non-linearity, multidimensionality and floor and ceiling effects that could challenge its continued utility as a primary outcome measure in ALS clinical trials. Recently, other qualitative scale measures of functioning disability have been developed to help address these issues. With this in mind, we conducted&#xa0;a&#xa0;literature search aimed at identifying both established and promising new measures for potential use in clinical trials.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We searched PubMed, Google, Google Scholar, and the reference sections of key studies to identify papers that discussed qualitative measures of functional status for potential use in ALS studies. We also searched clinicaltrials.gov to identify functional status and health-related quality of life (HRQoL) measures that have been used in ALS interventional studies.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">In addition to the ALSFRS-R, we identified several newer qualitative scales including ALSFRS-EX, ALS-MITOS, CNS-BFS, DALS-15, MND-DS, and ROADS. Strengths and limitations of each measure were identified and discussed, along with their potential to act as a primary or secondary outcome to assess patient functional status in ALS clinical trials.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This paper serves as a reference guide for researchers deciding which qualitative measures to use as endpoints in their ALS clinical trials to assess functional status. This paper also discusses the importance of including ALS HRQoL and ALS cognitive screens in future clinical trials to assess the value of a new ALS therapy more comprehensively.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hartmaier</LastName><ForeName>Susan L</ForeName><Initials>SL</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2559-5667</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>CERobs Consulting, LLC, Wrightsville Beach, NC, USA. drsusan@bhstrategy.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rhodes</LastName><ForeName>Thomas</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>CERobs Consulting, LLC, Wrightsville Beach, NC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cook</LastName><ForeName>Suzanne F</ForeName><Initials>SF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>CERobs Consulting, LLC, Wrightsville Beach, NC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schlusser</LastName><ForeName>Courtney</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>CERobs Consulting, LLC, Wrightsville Beach, NC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Gillings School of Public Health, University of North Carolina-Chapel Hill, Chapel Hill, NC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Chao</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Takeda Development Center Americas, Inc., Cambridge, MA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Han</LastName><ForeName>Steve</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Takeda Development Center Americas, Inc., Cambridge, MA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zach</LastName><ForeName>Neta</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Takeda Development Center Americas, Inc., Cambridge, MA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Murthy</LastName><ForeName>Venkatesha</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Takeda Development Center Americas, Inc., Cambridge, MA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dav&#xe9;</LastName><ForeName>Shreya</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Takeda Development Center Americas, Inc., Cambridge, MA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Health Qual Life Outcomes</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101153626</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1477-7525</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006233" MajorTopicYN="Y">Disabled Persons</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018450" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Progression</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ALS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ALS cognitive screens</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ALSFRS-R</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Clinical trials</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">HRQoL</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Qualitative outcome measures</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Takeda Pharmaceuticals contracted with CERobs Consulting, LLC, a consulting firm with focus on real-world evidence, outcomes research, epidemiology and clinical outcome assessments, including patient reported outcomes; S. Hartmaier, T. Rhodes, S. Cook, and C. Schlusser consulted on this project through CERobs Consulting, LLC. C. Chao, S. Han, N Zach, V. Murthy, and S. Dave are/were salaried employees of Takeda Pharmaceuticals at the time the publication was written.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35062955</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8781297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12955-022-01919-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12955-022-01919-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Quereshi M, Schoenfeld DA, Paliwal Y, Shui A, Cudkowicz ME. The natural history of ALS is changing: improved survival. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2009;10(5&#x2013;6):324&#x2013;331.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19922119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norris FH, Calanchini PR, Fallat RJ, Panchari S, Jewett B. The administration of guanidine in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology. 1974;24(8):721&#x2013;728.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4858705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Appel V, Stewart S, Smith G, Appel SH. A rating scale for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: description and preliminary experience. Ann Neurol. 1987;22(3):328&#x2013;333.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3118763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum JM, Stambler N. Performance of the Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Functional Rating Scale (ALSFRS) in multicenter clinical trials. J Neurol Sci. 1997;152(Suppl 1):S1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9419047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum JM, Stambler N, Malta E, Fuller C, Hilt D, Thurmond B, et al. The ALSFRS-R: a revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. BDNF ALS Study Group (Phase III) J Neurol Sci. 1999;169(1&#x2013;2):13&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10540002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ALS Pathways. Assessing ALS function. 2021. https://alspathways.com/assessing-function/. Accessed 16 Mar 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum JM, Mitsumoto H, Pestronk A, Ringel S, Florence J, Sanjak M, et al. The ALSFRS @ 20: Evolution of the ALSFRS-R, history, clinimetric properties and future directions. 2015. https://cytokinetics.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/2011ALS_MND_ASLFRS20.pdf. Assessed 16 Mar 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>European Medicines Agency (EMA). Guideline on clinical investigation of medicinal products for the treatment of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). 19 November 2015 EMA/531686/2015, Corr.1 Committee for Medicinal Product for Human Use (CHMP).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Food and Drug Administration (FDA). Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: developing drugs for treatment. Guidance for industry. 2019. https://www.fda.gov/drugs/guidance-compliance-regulatory-information/guidances-drugs. Assessed 16 Mar 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ALS Crowd News. Do we need a new scale for measuring ALS? 2020. https://alscrowd.org/do-we-need-a-new-scale-for-measuring-als/. Accessed 19 Mar 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon PH, Cheng B, Salachas F, Pradat PF, Bruneteau G, Corcia P, et al. Progression in ALS is not linear but curvilinear. J Neurol. 2010;257(10):1713&#x2013;1717.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20532545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kollewe K, Mauss U, Krampfl K, Petri S, Dengler R, Mohammadi B. ALSFRS-R score and its ratio: a useful predictor for ALS progression. J Neurol Sci. 2008;275(1&#x2013;2):69&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18721928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castrillo-Viguera C, Grasso DL, Simpson E, Shefner J, Cudkowicz ME. Clinical significance in the change of decline in ALSFRS-R. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2010;11(1&#x2013;2):178&#x2013;180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19634063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proudfoot M, Jones A, Talbot K, Al-Chalabi A, Turner MR. The ALSFRS as an outcome measure in therapeutic trials and its relationship to symptom onset. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2016;17(5&#x2013;6):414&#x2013;425.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4950444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26864085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rooney J, Burke T, Vajda A, Heverin M, Hardiman O. What does the ALSFRS-R really measure? A longitudinal and survival analysis of functional dimension subscores in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2017;88(5):381&#x2013;385.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27888187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandrioli J, Biguzzi S, Guidi C, Sette E, Terlizzi E, Ravasio A, et al. Heterogeneity in ALSFRS-R decline and survival: a population-based study in Italy. Neuro Sci. 2015;36(12):2243&#x2013;2252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26205535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franchignoni F, Mora G, Giordano A, Volanti P, Chi&#xf2; A. Evidence of multidimensionality in the ALSFRS-R Scale: a critical appraisal on its measurement properties using Rasch analysis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2013;84(12):1340&#x2013;1345.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23516308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franchignoni F, Mandrioli J, Giordano A, Ferro S. ERRALS Group. A further Rasch study confirms that ALSFRS-R does not conform to fundamental measurement requirements. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2015;16(5&#x2013;6):331&#x2013;337.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25916346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bacci ED, Staniewska D, Coyne KS, Boyer S, White LA, Zach N, et al. Item response theory analysis of the Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Functional Rating Scale-Revised in the pooled resource open-access ALS clinical trials database. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2016;17(3&#x2013;4):157&#x2013;167.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26473473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fournier CN, Bedlack R, Quin C, Russell J, Beckwith D, Kaminski KH, et al. Development and validation of the Rasch&#x2013;Built Overall Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Disability Scale (ROADS) JAMA Neurol. 2020;77(4):480&#x2013;488.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6990811</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31886839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atassi N, Berry J, Shui A, Zach N, Sherman A, Sinani E, et al. The PRO-ACT database: design, initial analyses, and predictive features. Neurology. 2014;83(19):1719&#x2013;1725.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4239834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25298304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Food and Drug Administration. Guidance for industry patient-reported outcome measures: use in medical product development to support labeling claims. 2009. https://www.fda.gov/media/77832/download. Accessed 30 Mar 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simmons Z. Patient-perceived outcomes and quality of life in ALS. Neurotherapeutics. 2015;12(2):394&#x2013;402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4404446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25502407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeMarchi F, Berry JD, Chan J, Caldwell S, Ellrodt A, Scalia J, et al. Patient reported outcome measures (PROMs) in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol. 2020;267(6):1754&#x2013;1759.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32125520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gosselt IK, Tanja C, Nijboer W, Van Es MA. An overview of screening instruments for cognition and behavior in patients with ALS: selecting the appropriate tool for clinical practice. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2020;21(5&#x2013;6):324&#x2013;336.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32157912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magnus T, Beck M, Giess R, Puls I, Naumann M, Toyka KV. Disease progression in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: predictors of survival. Muscle Nerve. 2002;25(5):709&#x2013;714.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11994965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaufmann P, Levy G, Thompson JL, DelBene ML, Battista V, Gordon PH, et al. The ALSFRS-R predicts survival time in an ALS population. Neurology. 2005;64(1):38&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15642901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaufmann P, Levy G, Montes J, Buchsbaum R, Barsdorf AI, Battista V, et al. Excellent inter-rater, intra-rater, and telephone-administered reliability of the ALSFRS-R in a multicenter clinical trial. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2007;8(1):42&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17364435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakker LA, Shroder CD, Tan HHG, Vugts SMAG, van Eijk RPA, van Es MA. Development and assessment of the inter-rater and intra-rater reproducibility of a self-administered version of the ALSFRS-R. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2020;91(1):75&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31558653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lo Coco D, Marchese S, La Bella V, Piccoli T, Lo CA. The Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Functional Rating Scale predicts survival time in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients on invasive mechanical ventilation. Chest. 2007;132(1):64&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17475635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montes J, Levy G, Albert S, Kaufmann P, Buchsbaum R, Gordon PH, et al. Development and evaluation of a self-administered version of the ALSFRS-R. Neurology. 2006;67(7):1294&#x2013;1296.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17030772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasarskis EJ, Dempsey-Hall L, Malley Thompson M, Luu LC, Mendiondo M, Kryscio R. Rating the severity of ALS by caregivers over the telephone using the ALSFRS-R. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord. 2005;6(1):50&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16036426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berry JD, Paganoni S, Carlson K, Burke K, Weber H, Staples P, et al. Design and results of a smartphone-based digital phenotyping study to quantify ALS progression. Ann Clin Transl Neurol. 2019;6(5):873&#x2013;881.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6529832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31139685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newton J, Jayaprakash K, Glasmacher SA, McEleney A, Bethell A, Fraser E, et al. Excellent reliability of the ALSFRS-R administered via videoconferencing: a study of people with motor neuron disease in Scotland. J Neurol Sci. 2020;416:116991.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32599295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahlstrom J. Phase II ALS clinical trial produces promising results for AMX0035. ALSCrowd Foundation web site. 2020. https://alscrowd.org/phase-ii-clinical-trial-produces-promising-results-for-amx0035/. Accessed 22 Nov 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wicks P, Massagli MP, Wolf C, Heywood J. Measuring function in advance ALS: validation of ALSFRS-EX extension items. Eur J Neurol. 2009;16(3):353&#x2013;359.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19364363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2; A, Hammond ER, Mora G, Bonito V, Filippini G. Development and evaluation of a clinical staging system for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2015;86(1):38&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24336810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roche JC, Rojas-Garcia R, Scott KM, et al. A proposed staging system for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain. 2012;135(Pt 3):847&#x2013;852. doi: 10.1093/brain/awr351.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awr351</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3286327</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22271664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filippini G, Bonito V, Chio A, et al. Quality of life in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: the QuaC-ALS study database. J Neurol. 2003;250(Suppl 2):23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tramacere I, Dalla Bella E, Chi&#xf2; A, Mora G, Filippini G, Lauria G, et al. The MITOS system predicts long-term survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2015;86(11):1180&#x2013;1185.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25886781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen A, Garrett CG. Otolaryngologic presentations of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg. 2005;132(3):500&#x2013;504.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15746870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sorenson EJ, Crum B, Stevens JC. Incidence of aspiration pneumonia in ALS in Olmsted County. MN Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2007;8(2):87&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17453635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tabor L, Gaziano J, Watts S, Robison R, Plowman EK. Defining swallowing-related quality of life profiles in individuals with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Dysphagia. 2016;31(3):376&#x2013;382.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4871719</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26837611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chapin JL, Gray LT, Vasilopoulos T, Anderson A, DiBiase L, York JD, et al. Diagnostic utility of the amyotrophic lateral sclerosis Functional Rating Scale&#x2014;Revised to detect pharyngeal dysphagia in individuals with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. PLoS ONE. 2020;15(8):e0236804.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7425890</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32790801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith RA, Macklin EA, Myers KL, Pattee GL, Goslin KL, Meekins GD, et al. Assessment of bulbar function in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: validation of a self-report scale (Center for Neurologic Study Bulbar Function Scale) Eur J Neurol. 2018;25(10):907&#x2013;e66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6005752</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29577526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicholson K, Murphy A, McDonnell E, Shapiro J, Simpson E, Glass J, et al. Improving symptom management for people with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 2018;57(1):20&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28561886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vogt S, Petri S, Dengler R, Heinze HJ, Vielhaber S. Dyspnea in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Rasch-based development and validation of a patient-reported outcome (DALS-15) J Pain Symptom Manag. 2018;56(5):736&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30145215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vogt S, Schreiber S, Heinze HJ, Dengler R, Petri S, Vielhaber S. The Dyspnea-ALS (DALS-15) optimizes individual treatment in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) suffering from dyspnea. Health Qual Life Outcomes. 2019;17(1):95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6547457</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31159830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helleman J, Kruitwagen-van Reenen ET, Bakers J, Kruithof WJ, van Groenestijn AC, Jaspers Focks RJH, et al. Using patient-reported symptoms of dyspnea for screening reduced respiratory function in patients with motor neuron diseases. J Neurol. 2020;267(11):3310&#x2013;3318.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7578163</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32577867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linacre JM. Rasch analysis of rank-ordered data. J Appl Meas. 2006;7(1):129&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16385155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fournier C, Bedlack R, Quinn C, Russell J, Beckwith D, Kaminski K, et al. The Rasch&#x2013;Built overall ALS disability scale: ROADS to a better ALS outcome measure (1706) Neurology. 2020;94(15 Supplement):1706.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jenkinson C, Fitzpatrick R, Brennan C, Bromberg M, Swash M. Development and validation of a short measure of health status for individuals with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis/motor neurone disease: the ALSAQ-40. J Neurol. 1999;246(Suppl 3):16&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10631656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jenkinson C, Levvy G, Fitzpatrick R, Garratt A. The Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Assessment Questionnaire (ALSAQ-40): tests of data quality, score reliability and response rate in a survey of patients. J Neurol Sci. 2000;180(1&#x2013;2):94&#x2013;100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11090872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jenkinson C, Fitzpatrick R. A reduced item set for the Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Assessment Questionnaire: development and validation of the ALSAQ-5. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2001;70(1):70&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1763474</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11118250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Felgoise SH, Feinberg R, Stephens HE, Barkhaus P, Boylan K, Caress J, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis&#x2014;specific quality of life&#x2014;short form (ALSSQOL-SF): a brief, reliable, and valid version of the ALSSQOL-R. Muscle Nerve. 2018;58(5):646&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30028537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandstedt P, Johannsson S, Ytterberg C, Ingre C, Holmqvist LW, Kierkegaard M. Predictors of health-related quality of life in people with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Sci. 2016;370:269&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27772773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>UKMND-LiCALS Study Group Lithium in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (LiCALS): a phase 3 multicentre, randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Lancet Neurol. 2013;12(4):339&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3610091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23453347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiebert GM, Green C, Murphy C, Mitchell JD, O'Brien M, Burrell A, et al. Patients&#x2019; health-related quality of life and utilities associated with different stages of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Sci. 2001;191(1&#x2013;2):87&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11676997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young CA, Mills R, Al-Chalabi A, Burke G, Chandran S, Dick DJ, et al. Measuring quality of life in ALS/MND: validation of the WHOQOL-BREF. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2020;21:1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32597226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cella D, Lai JS, Nowinski CJ, Victorson D, Peterman A, Miller D, et al. Neuro-QOL: brief measures of health-related quality of life for clinical research in neurology. Neurology. 2012;78(23):1860&#x2013;1867.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3369516</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22573626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hays RD, Bjorner J, Revicki DA, Spritzer K, Cella D. Development of physical and mental health summary scores from the Patient Reported Outcomes Measurement Information System (PROMIS) global items. Qual Life Res. 2009;18(7):873&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2724630</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19543809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crockford C, Newton J, Lonergan K, Madden C, Mays I, O'Sullivan M, et al. Measuring reliable change in cognition using the Edinburgh Cognitive and Behavioural ALS Screen (ECAS) Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2018;19(1&#x2013;2):65&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6510059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29214872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitsumoto H, Brooks BR, Silani V. Clinical trials in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: why so many negative trials and how can trials be improved? Lancet Neurol. 2014;13(11):1127&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25316019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woolley SC. Utility of the Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Cognitive Behavioral Screen (ALS CBSTM) Neurodegener Dis Manag. 2011;1(6):473&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woolley SC, York MK, Moore DH, Strutt AM, Murphy J, Schulz PE, et al. Detecting frontotemporal dysfunction in ALS: utility of the ALS Cognitive Behavioral Screen (ALS-CBS) Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2010;11(3):303&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20433413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy J, Factor-Litvak P, Goetz R, Lomen-Hoerth C, Nagy PL, Hupf J, et al. Cognitive-behavioral screening reveals prevalent impairment in a large multicenter ALS cohort. Neurology. 2016;86(9):813&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4793785</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26802094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abrahams S, Newton J, Niven E, Foley J, Bak TH. Screening for cognition and behaviour changes in ALS. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2014;15(1&#x2013;2):9&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23781974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niven E, Newton J, Foley J, Colville S, Swingler R, Chandran S, et al. Validation of the Edinburgh Cognitive and Behavioural Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Screen (ECAS): a cognitive tool for motor disorders. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2015;16(3&#x2013;4):172&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25967542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Motor Neuron Disease Association, UK. The Edinburgh Cognitive and Behavioural ALS Screen (ECAS). Administration and Guidance Notes 2013. English Version. 2013. https://www.encals.eu/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/ECAS-Guidelines-administration-and-translation.pdf. Accessed 28 Oct 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cappelleri JC, Zou KH, Bushmakin AG, Alvir JM, D Alemayehu D, Symonds T. Patient-Reported Outcomes. Measurement, Implementation and Interpretation. CRC Press; 2014. p. 4, 31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>European Medicines Agency. Committee for Medicinal Products for Human use (CHMP): reflection paper on the regulatory guidance for the use of health-related quality of life (HRQL) measures in the evaluation of medicinal products. 2005. http://www.emea.europa.eu/docs/en_GB/document_library/Scientific_guideline/2009/09/WC500003637.pdf. Accessed 17 May 2021.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>