<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35066529</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>04</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1537-1603</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>40</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of clinical neurophysiology : official publication of the American Electroencephalographic Society</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Clin Neurophysiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Sensitivity of Quantitative Sonographic Assessment of Muscle Thickness for Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Diagnosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>529</StartPage><EndPage>534</EndPage><MedlinePgn>529-534</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/WNP.0000000000000917</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">In the current proof-of-concept study, we aimed to examine the sensitivities and specificities of previously reported normal values for muscle ultrasound thickness in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Muscle ultrasound was performed in 65 healthy control subjects and 91 amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients using a standardized assessment of eight relaxed muscles and four contracted muscles. Normal values for muscle thickness were determined as values above the 5th percentile stratified by age and gender using the weighted average method. Sensitivity for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis diagnosis was determined for muscles with and without the addition of muscle contraction.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients showed reduced muscle sum thickness both in relaxed and in contracted states compared with control subjects. Muscle ultrasound of muscles with and without contraction showed excellent diagnostic accuracy for differentiating amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients from control subjects (area under curve = 0.96, sensitivity: 93%-95%, specificity: 84-87). Muscle ultrasound sensitivity was lower within 6 months of symptom onset (83%) compared with longer disease duration (&gt;92%).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Quantitative sonographic assessment of muscle thickness can be complementary in the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with excellent accuracy for differentiating patients from healthy subjects, and might be useful in other neuromuscular disorders, although additional studies are required.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022 by the American Clinical Neurophysiology Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Avidan</LastName><ForeName>Reuven</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Tel Aviv Sourasky Medical Center, Tel Aviv, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fainmesser</LastName><ForeName>Yaara</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neuromuscular Diseases Unit, Department of Neurology, Tel Aviv Sourasky Medical Center, Tel Aviv, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Drory</LastName><ForeName>Vivian E</ForeName><Initials>VE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neuromuscular Diseases Unit, Department of Neurology, Tel Aviv Sourasky Medical Center, Tel Aviv, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sackler Faculty of Medicine, Tel Aviv University, Tel Aviv, Israel; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bril</LastName><ForeName>Vera</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ellen and Martin Prosserman Centre for Neuromuscular Diseases, Division of Neurology, Department of Medicine, University Health Network, University of Toronto, Toronto, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abraham</LastName><ForeName>Alon</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9020-2399</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neuromuscular Diseases Unit, Department of Neurology, Tel Aviv Sourasky Medical Center, Tel Aviv, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sackler Faculty of Medicine, Tel Aviv University, Tel Aviv, Israel; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Clin Neurophysiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8506708</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0736-0258</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012680" MajorTopicYN="N">Sensitivity and Specificity</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003937" MajorTopicYN="N">Diagnosis, Differential</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014463" MajorTopicYN="N">Ultrasonography</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>V. E . Drory reports consultancy fees from Biogen, Neurosense Therapeutics and Eyecontrol outside the submitted work. V. Bril is a consultant to CSL Behring, Grifols, Union Chimique Belge, ArgenX, Alexion, Alnylam, Akcea, Takeda, Octapharma, Sanofi, Immunovant, Roche, and Novo-Nordisk. She serves on the Myasthenia Gravis Foundation of America and Canadian Guillain&#x2013;Barr&#xe9; Syndrome/Chronic Inflammatory Demyelinating Polyneuropathy (CIDP/GBS) Foundation boards and has received research support from CSL Behring, Grifols, Union Chimique Belge, ArgenX, Immunovant, Momenta, Takeda, Octapharma, Akcea, and Alexion. The remaining authors have no funding or conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35066529</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/WNP.0000000000000917</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00004691-900000000-99224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez NL, Hobson-Webb LD. Neuromuscular ultrasound in clinical practice: a review. Clin Neurophysiol Pract 2019;4:148&#x2013;163.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abraham A, Drory VE, Fainmesser Y, Lovblom LE, Bril V. Quantitative sonographic evaluation of muscle thickness and fasciculation prevalence in healthy subjects. Muscle Nerve 2020;61:234&#x2013;238.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Misawa S, Noto Y, Shibuya K, et al. Ultrasonographic detection of fasciculations markedly increases diagnostic sensitivity of ALS. Neurology 2011;77:1532&#x2013;1537.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hobson-Webb LD, Simmons Z. Ultrasound in the diagnosis and monitoring of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a review. Muscle Nerve 2019;60:114&#x2013;123.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsuji Y, Noto Y, Shiga K, Teramukai S, Nakagawa M, Mizuno T. A muscle ultrasound score in the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Neurophysiol 2017;128:1069&#x2013;1074.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johansson MT, Ellegaard HR, Tankisi H, Fuglsang-Frederiksen A, Qerama E. Fasciculations in nerve and muscle disorders &#x2013; a prospective study of muscle ultrasound compared to electromyography. Clin Neurophysiol 2017;128:2250&#x2013;2257.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juan W, Fang L, Qi W, et al. Muscle ultrasonography in the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurol Res 2020;42:458&#x2013;462.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seok HY, Park J, Kim YH, Oh KW, Kim SH, Kim BJ. Split hand muscle echo intensity index as a reliable imaging marker for differential diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2018;89:943&#x2013;948.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McIlduff CE, Martucci MG, Shin C, et al. Quantitative ultrasound of the tongue: echo intensity is a potential biomarker of bulbar dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Neurophysiol 2020;131:2423&#x2013;2428.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arts IMP, Overeem S, Pillen S, et al. Muscle ultrasonography: a diagnostic tool for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Neurophysiol 2012;123:1662&#x2013;1667.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grimm A, Prell T, D&#xe9;card BF, et al. Muscle ultrasonography as an additional diagnostic tool for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Neurophysiol 2015;126:820&#x2013;827.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abraham A, Fainmesser Y, Lovblom LE, Bril V, Drory VE. Superiority of sonographic evaluation of contracted versus relaxed muscle thickness in motor neuron diseases. Clin Neurophysiol Int Fed Clin Neurophysiol 2020;131:1480&#x2013;1486.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abraham A, Drory VE, Fainmesser Y, Algom AA, Lovblom LE, Bril V. Muscle thickness measured by ultrasound is reduced in neuromuscular disorders and correlates with clinical and electrophysiological findings. Muscle Nerve 2019;60:687&#x2013;692.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paganoni S, Macklin EA, Lee A, et al. Diagnostic timelines and delays in diagnosing amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). Amyotroph Lateral Scler Front Degener 2014;15:453&#x2013;456.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, Miller RG, Swash M, Munsat TL. El Escorial revisited: revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler 2000;1:293&#x2013;299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum JM, Stambler N, Malta E, et al. The ALSFRS-R: a revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. J Neurol Sci 1999;169:13&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kleyweg RP, Van Der Mech&#xe9; FGA, Schmitz PIM. Interobserver agreement in the assessment of muscle strength and functional abilities in Guillain&#x2010;Barr&#xe9; syndrome. Muscle Nerve 1991;14:1103&#x2013;1109.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abraham A, Fainmesser Y, Drory VE, Bril V. Split-hand phenomenon in motor neuron diseases: sonographic assessment of muscle thickness. Clin Neurophysiol Int Fed Clin Neurophysiol 2020;131:1721&#x2013;1725.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eisen A, Kuwabara S. The split hand syndrome in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2012:399&#x2013;403.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilbourn AJ. The &#x201c;split hand syndrome. Muscle Nerve 2000;23:138.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avidan R, Fainmesser Y, Drory VE, Bril V, Abraham A. Fasciculation frequency at the biceps brachii and brachialis muscles is associated with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis disease burden and activity. Muscle Nerve 2021;63:204&#x2013;208.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loewenbr&#xfc;ck KF, Liesenberg J, Dittrich M, et al. Nerve ultrasound in the differentiation of multifocal motor neuropathy (MMN) and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with predominant lower motor neuron disease (ALS/LMND). J Neurol 2016;263:35&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nodera H, Takamatsu N, Shimatani Y, et al. Thinning of cervical nerve roots and peripheral nerves in ALS as measured by sonography. Clin Neurophysiol 2014;125:1906&#x2013;1911.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>