<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35066895</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1521-186X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>43</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Bioelectromagnetics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Bioelectromagnetics</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Receipt of Electroconvulsive Therapy and Subsequent Development of Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis: A Cohort Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>81</StartPage><EndPage>89</EndPage><MedlinePgn>81-89</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/bem.22389</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>We investigated the potential relationship between receipt of electroconvulsive therapy (ECT) and development of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). We conducted a cohort study using a sample of more than one million beneficiaries enrolled in the U.S. Medicare health insurance program from 1997 to 2017. Using time-varying proportional hazard modeling, we compared ALS occurrence among patients diagnosed with psychiatric conditions who received ECT to ALS occurrence among patients diagnosed with psychiatric conditions but who did not receive ECT. We observed moderately increased, but imprecise, hazard ratios (HR) for ALS following ECT (HR&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.39, 95% confidence interval [CI]: 0.69-2.80). A statistically significant increase in the HR of ALS was observed among those who received more than 10 ECT treatments (&gt;10 treatments, HR&#x2009;=&#x2009;2.24, 95% CI: 1.00-5.01), compared to those receiving no ECT, with an even stronger association observed among subjects older than 65 years (HR&#x2009;=&#x2009;3.03, 95% CI: 1.13-8.10). No monotonic exposure-response relationship was detected in categorical analyses. Our results provide weak support for the hypothesis that receipt of ECT increases the risk of developing ALS. Additional studies in larger populations, or in populations where ECT is more common, will be needed to refute or confirm an association between receipt of ECT and subsequent development of ALS. Bioelectromagnetics. 43:81-89, 2022. &#xa9; 2021 Bioelectromagnetics Society.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 Bioelectromagnetics Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mezei</LastName><ForeName>Gabor</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6562-7857</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Health Sciences, Exponent Inc., Oakland, California.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lau</LastName><ForeName>Edmund</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Health Sciences, Exponent Inc., Menlo Park, California.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pace</LastName><ForeName>Nelson D</ForeName><Initials>ND</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>AllStripes Research, San Francisco, California.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schenk</LastName><ForeName>Jamie</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Health Sciences, Exponent Inc., Oakland, California.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kheifets</LastName><ForeName>Leeka</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Epidemiology, University of California, Los Angeles, Los Angeles, California.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Bioelectromagnetics</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8008281</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0197-8462</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015331" MajorTopicYN="N">Cohort Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004565" MajorTopicYN="Y">Electroconvulsive Therapy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006278" MajorTopicYN="N">Medicare</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014481" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">United States</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">electric and magnetic fields</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">electric current</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">electroconvulsive therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">motor neuron disease</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35066895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/bem.22389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Al-Chalabi A, Hardiman O. 2013. The epidemiology of ALS: A conspiracy of genes, environment and time. Nat Rev Neurol 9:617-628.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR. 1994. El Escorial World Federation of Neurology criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Subcommittee on Motor Neuron Diseases/Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis of the World Federation of Neurology Research Group on Neuromuscular Diseases and the El Escorial &#x2018;Clinical limits of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis' workshop contributors. J Neurol Sci 124(suppl):96-107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chanpattan W. 2007. A questionnaire survey of ECT practice in Australia. J ECT 23:89-92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen GX, Mannetje A, Douwes J, van den Berg LH, Pearce N, Kromhout H, Glass B, Brewer N, McLean DJ. 2021. Associations of occupational exposure to electric shocks and extremely low-frequency magnetic fields and motor neuron disease. Am J Epidemiol 190(3):393-402.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2; A, Logroscino G, Hardiman O, Swingler R, Mitchell D, Beghi E, Traynor BG, Eurals Consortium. 2009. Prognostic factors in ALS: A critical review. Amyotroph Lateral Sclero 10(5-6):310-323.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chuquilin M, Wymer S, Wymer J. 2017. Increasing evidence for an association between amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and psychiatric disorders. JAMA Neurol 74(12):1396-1398.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deapen DM, Henderson BE. 1986. A case-control study of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Am J Epidemiol 123(5):790-799.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filippini T, Tesauro M, Fiore M, Malagoli C, Consonni M, Violi F, Iacuzio L, Arcolin E, Oliveri Conti G, Cristaldi A, Zuccarello P, Zucchi E, Mazzini L, Pisano F, Gagliardi I, Patti F, Mandrioli J, Ferrante M, Vinceti M. 2020. Environmental and occupational risk factors of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A population-based case-control study. Int J Environ Res Public Health 17(8):2882.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fine J, Gray R. 1999. A proportional hazards model for the subdistribution of a competing risk. J Am Stat Assoc 94(446):496-509.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fischer H, Kheifets L, Huss A, Peters TL, Vermeulen R, Ye W, Fang F, Wiebert P, Vergara XP, Feychting M. 2015. Occupational exposure to electric shocks and magnetic fields and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in Sweden. Epidemiology 26(6):824-830.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gazdag G, Tak&#xe1;cs R, Tolna J, Iv&#xe1;nyi Z. 2013. Electroconvulsive therapy in a Hungarian academic centre (1999-2010). Psychiatria Danub 25(4):366-370.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon P. 2013. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: An update for 2013 clinical features, pathophysiology, management and therapeutic trials. Aging Dis 4(5):295-310.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenland S, Schwartzbaum JA, Finkle WD. 2000. Problems due to small samples and sparse data in conditional logistic regression analysis. Am J Epidemiol 151:531-539.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenland S, Mansournia MA, Altman DG. 2016. Sparse data bias: a problem hiding in plain sight. BMJ 353:i1981.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenwood M 1926. The errors of sampling of the survivorship tables. In: Reports on Public Health and Statistical Subjects, no. 33, Appendix 1. London: Her Majesty's Stationary Office (HMSO), pp. 1-26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gunnarsson L-G, Bodin L. 2019. Occupational exposures and neurodegenerative diseases-A systematic literature review and meta-analyses. Int J Environ Res Public Health 16(3):337.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huss A, Spoerri A, Egger M, Kromhout H, Vermeulen R. 2015. Occupational exposure to magnetic fields and electric shocks and risk of ALS-The Swiss National Cohort. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 16(1-2):80-85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huss A, Peters S, Vermeulen R. 2018. Occupational exposure to extremely low-frequency magnetic fields and the risk of ALS: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Bioelectromagnetics 39(2):156-163.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jalilian H, Najafi K, Khosravi Y, R&#xf6;&#xf6;sli M. 2020. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, occupational exposure to extremely low frequency magnetic fields and electric shocks: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Rev Environ Health 36(1):129-142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaiser Family Foundation. 2019. https://www.kff.org/medicare/issue-brief/a-dozen-facts-about-medicare-advantage-in-2019/. [Last accessed 11 November 2021].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kheifets L, Bowman JD, Checkoway H, Feychting M, Harrington JM, Kavet R, Marsh G, Mezei G, Renew DC, van Wijngaarden E. 2009. Future needs of occupational epidemiology of extremely low frequency electric and magnetic fields: Review and recommendations. Occup Environ Med 66(2):72-80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiernan MC, Vucic S, Cheah BC, Turner MR, Eisen A, Hardiman O, Burrell JR, Xoing MC. 2011. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet 377(9769):942-955.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koeman T, Slottje P, Schouten LJ. 2017. Occupational exposure and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in a prospective cohort. Occup Environ Med 74(8):578-585.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loh N, Nickl-Jockschat T, Sheldrick AJ, Gr&#xf6;zinger M. 2013. Accessibility, standards and challenges of electroconvulsive therapy in Western industrialized countries: A German example. World J Biol Psychiatry 14:432-440.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mankad MV, Beyer JL, Weiner RD, Krystal A. 2010. Clinical Manual of Electroconvulsive Therapy. Washington, DC: American Psychiatric Publishing. pp. 3-187.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin S, Al Khleifat A, Al-Chalabi A. 2017. What causes amyotrophic lateral sclerosis? F1000Res 28(6):371.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nelson LM, McGuire V. 2006. Epidemiology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. In: Brown RH, Swash M, Pasinelli P (Eds), Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. Abingdon, England: Informa Healthcare. pp. 25-36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noonan CW, White MC, Thurman D, Wong LY. 2005. Temporal and geographic variation in United States motor neuron disease mortality, 1969-1998. Neurology 64(7):1215-1221.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peters S, Visser AE, D'Ovidio F, Beghi E, Chio A, Logroscino G, Hardiman O, Kromhout H, Huss A, Veldink J, Vermeulen R, van den Berg LH, Euro-MOTOR Consortium. 2019. Associations of electric shock and extremely low-frequency magnetic field exposure with the risk of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Am J Epidemiol 188(4):796-805.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vergara X, Kheifets L, Greenland S, Oksuzyan S, Cho YS, Mezei G. 2013. Occupational exposure to extremely low-frequency magnetic fields and neurodegenerative diseases: A meta-analysis. J Occup Environ Med 55(2):135-146.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vergara X, Mezei G, Kheifets L. 2015. Case-control study of occupational exposure to electric shocks and magnetic fields and mortality from amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in the US, 1991-1999. J Expo Sci Environ Epidemiol 25(1):65-71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization (WHO). 2007. Environmental Health Criteria 238, Extremely Low Frequency Fields. Geneva, Switzerland: World Health Organization. pp. 1-519.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>