<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35093159</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>11</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1750-1172</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>29</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Orphanet journal of rare diseases</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Orphanet J Rare Dis</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Development of a standard of care for patients with valosin-containing protein associated multisystem proteinopathy.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>23</StartPage><MedlinePgn>23</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">23</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13023-022-02172-5</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Valosin-containing protein (VCP) associated multisystem proteinopathy (MSP) is a rare inherited disorder that may result in multisystem involvement of varying phenotypes including inclusion body myopathy, Paget's disease of bone (PDB), frontotemporal dementia (FTD), parkinsonism, and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS), among others. An international multidisciplinary consortium of 40+ experts in neuromuscular disease, dementia, movement disorders, psychology, cardiology, pulmonology, physical therapy, occupational therapy, speech and language pathology, nutrition, genetics, integrative medicine, and endocrinology were convened by the patient advocacy organization, Cure VCP Disease, in December 2020 to develop a standard of care for this heterogeneous and under-diagnosed disease. To achieve this goal, working groups collaborated to generate expert consensus recommendations in 10 key areas: genetic diagnosis, myopathy, FTD, PDB, ALS, Charcot Marie Tooth disease (CMT), parkinsonism, cardiomyopathy, pulmonology, supportive therapies, nutrition and supplements, and mental health. In April 2021, facilitated discussion of each working group's conclusions with consensus building techniques enabled final agreement on the proposed standard of care for VCP patients. Timely referral to a specialty neuromuscular center is recommended to aid in efficient diagnosis of VCP MSP via single-gene testing in the case of a known familial VCP variant, or multi-gene panel sequencing in undifferentiated cases. Additionally, regular and ongoing multidisciplinary team follow up is essential for proactive screening and management of secondary complications. The goal of our consortium is to raise awareness of VCP MSP, expedite the time to accurate diagnosis, define gaps and inequities in patient care, initiate appropriate pharmacotherapies and supportive therapies for optimal management, and elevate the recommended best practices guidelines for multidisciplinary care internationally.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Korb</LastName><ForeName>Manisha</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4626-4007</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of California - Irvine School of Medicine, Orange, CA, USA. mkak@uci.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Peck</LastName><ForeName>Allison</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cure VCP Disease, Americus, GA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alfano</LastName><ForeName>Lindsay N</ForeName><Initials>LN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Abigail Wexner Research Institute at Nationwide Children's Hospital, Columbus, OH, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Berger</LastName><ForeName>Kenneth I</ForeName><Initials>KI</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine (Pulmonary), NYU Grossman School of Medicine, New York, NY, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>James</LastName><ForeName>Meredith K</ForeName><Initials>MK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The John Walton Muscular Dystrophy Research Centre, Newcastle University and Newcastle Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust, Newcastle Upon Tyne, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ghoshal</LastName><ForeName>Nupur</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology and Psychiatry, Washington University in St. Louis, St. Louis, MO, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Healzer</LastName><ForeName>Elise</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Thriving Hope Consulting, Vinton, IA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Henchcliffe</LastName><ForeName>Claire</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of California - Irvine School of Medicine, Orange, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khan</LastName><ForeName>Shaida</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology &amp; Neurotherapeutics, University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center, Dallas, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mammen</LastName><ForeName>Pradeep P A</ForeName><Initials>PPA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine (Cardiology), University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center, Dallas, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Patel</LastName><ForeName>Sujata</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wellness with Sujata, Wadsworth, OH, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pfeffer</LastName><ForeName>Gerald</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hotchkiss Brain Institute, University of Calgary Cumming School of Medicine, Calgary, AB, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ralston</LastName><ForeName>Stuart H</ForeName><Initials>SH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Genetics and Cancer at the University of Edinburgh, Edinburgh, SCT, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Roy</LastName><ForeName>Bhaskar</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Yale School of Medicine, New Haven, CT, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Seeley</LastName><ForeName>William W</ForeName><Initials>WW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Weill Institute for Neurosciences, University of California San Francisco, San Francisco, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Swenson</LastName><ForeName>Andrea</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of Iowa Hospitals and Clinics, Iowa City, IA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mozaffar</LastName><ForeName>Tahseen</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of California - Irvine School of Medicine, Orange, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathology &amp; Laboratory Medicine, University of California - Irvine School of Medicine, Orange, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Weihl</LastName><ForeName>Conrad</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Washington University in St. Louis, St. Louis, MO, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Hope Center, Washington University in St. Louis, St. Louis, MO, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kimonis</LastName><ForeName>Virginia</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, University of California - Irvine School of Medicine, Orange, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathology &amp; Laboratory Medicine, University of California - Irvine School of Medicine, Orange, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><CollectiveName>VCP Standards of Care Working Group</CollectiveName></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>P50HD087351</GrantID><Acronym>NH</Acronym><Agency>NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>MR/L501529/1</GrantID><Acronym>MRC_</Acronym><Agency>Medical Research Council</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>UL1 TR001863</GrantID><Acronym>TR</Acronym><Agency>NCATS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>ALCHALABI-TALBOT/APR14/926-794</GrantID><Acronym>MNDA_</Acronym><Agency>Motor Neurone Disease Association</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01AR074457</GrantID><Acronym>NH</Acronym><Agency>NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>K24 AR073317</GrantID><Acronym>AR</Acronym><Agency>NIAMS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01 AG031867</GrantID><Acronym>AG</Acronym><Agency>NIA NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>G0600974</GrantID><Acronym>MRC_</Acronym><Agency>Medical Research Council</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>MR/R024804/1</GrantID><Acronym>MRC_</Acronym><Agency>Medical Research Council</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>UL1 TR001414</GrantID><Acronym>TR</Acronym><Agency>NCATS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>ALCHALABI-DOBSON/APR14/829-791</GrantID><Acronym>MNDA_</Acronym><Agency>Motor Neurone Disease Association</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Orphanet J Rare Dis</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101266602</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1750-1172</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D018797">Cell Cycle Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 3.6.4.6</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000074405">Valosin Containing Protein</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018797" MajorTopicYN="N">Cell Cycle Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009154" MajorTopicYN="N">Mutation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018979" MajorTopicYN="Y">Myositis, Inclusion Body</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010001" MajorTopicYN="Y">Osteitis Deformans</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D059039" MajorTopicYN="N">Standard of Care</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000074405" MajorTopicYN="N">Valosin Containing Protein</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>MK has served on advisory boards for Biogen, Argenx, and CSL Behring, and on the speaker's bureau for Biogen. AP does not have any competing interests to disclose. LA reports grant support from Cure VCP Disease; provides consultancy services for training and quality control through ATOM International for the following companies: Amicus Therapeutics Pty Ltd, Catabasis, Genethon, Italfarmaco, NS Pharma, Pfizer, PTC Therapeutics; reports royalties and other support through Nationwide Children&#x2019;s Hospital from Sarepta Therapeutics; royalties for licensed technologies; other support through Nationwide Children&#x2019;s Hospital from Novartis Gene Therapies; advisory board for Biogen. KB has consulted for and/or served as a member of advisory boards for Sanofi&#x2014;Genzyme, Inventiva Pharma, Amicus Therapeutics, Valerion Therapeutics, and Spark Therapeutics. MJ provides consultancy services for the following companies: ATOM International (covers consultancy services provided to Amicus Therapeutics Pty Ltd, Ascendis Pharma, Biomarin, Catabasis, Faraday, FibroGen, Genethon, Italfarmaco, NS Pharma, Pfizer, PTC Therapeutics, QED Therapeutics Ltd, Reveragen, Sarepta Therapeutics, outside the submitted work. MKJ has received payment for participation on Advisory Boards for F. Hoffman La Roche AG, PTC Therapeutics and fee support for PhD studies from the Jain Foundation, outside the submitted work. NG has participated or is currently participating in clinical trials of anti-dementia drugs sponsored by the following companies: Bristol Myers Squibb, Eli Lilly/Avid Radiopharmaceuticals, Janssen Immunotherapy, Novartis, Pfizer, Wyeth, SNIFF (The Study of Nasal Insulin to Fight Forgetfulness) study, and A4 (The Anti-Amyloid Treatment in Asymptomatic Alzheimer&#x2019;s Disease) trial. She receives research support from NIH, Tau Consortium, and the Association for Frontotemporal Degeneration. EH does not have any competing interests to disclose. CH has served on advisory boards for Axent Biosciences Inc, Acorda Therapeutics, Amneal Pharmaceuticals, Mitsubishi Tanabe Pharma, and US WorldMeds, and as a consultant for Zywie Bio. SK has served on advisory boards for Alexion Pharmaceuticals, Inc, UCB Pharmaceuticals, Inc, Immunovant, Inc, and Argenx. PM declares the following competing interests: American Heart Association (member of the AHA Career Development Research Grant Committee), California Institute of Regenerative Medicine (member of the Grants Working Group), CareDx Inc. (Site PI for the SHORE Registry), Catabasis Inc. (research grant), Dyne Therapeutics (consultant and member of the DMD Scientific Advisory Board), National Institute of Health (research grants and ad hoc grant reviewer for the NIH SMEP and MOSS Study Sections), Novartis Gene Therapies (member of the Data Monitoring and Safety Committee), and PhaseBio Inc. (research grant and member of the Scientific Advisory Board). SP owns a wellness company for supplements called Wellness with Sujata. GP does not have any competing interests to disclose. SR does not have any competing interests to disclose. BR has served as a consultant for Alexion Pharmaceuticals. WS does not have any competing interests to disclose. AS receives research support from Amylyx Pharmaceuticals, Alexion Pharmaceuticals, ALS Association, Mass General Hospital, NIH/NINDS, and Cytokinetics Inc, and serves on an IDMC for Alexion. TM has served in an advisory capacity for Abbvie, Alexion, Amicus, Argenx, Audentes, Maze Therapeutics, Modis, Momenta, Ra Pharmaceuticals, Sanofi-Genzyme, Sarepta, Spark Therapeutics, UCB, and Ultragenyx. He serves on the speaker&#x2019;s bureau for Sanofi-Genzyme. Dr. Mozaffar serves on the medical advisory board for the Myositis Association, Neuromuscular Disease Foundation, Myasthenia Gravis Foundation of California and Myasthenia Gravis Foundation of America. Dr. Mozaffar receives research funding from the Myositis Association, the Muscular Dystrophy Association, the National Institutes for Health and from the following sponsors: Alexion, Amicus, Argenx, Audentes, Bristol-Myers-Squib, Cartesian Therapeutics, Grifols, Momenta, Ra Pharmaceuticals, Sanofi-Genzyme, Spark Therapeutics, UCB, and Valerion. He serves on the data safety monitoring board for Acceleron, Avexis, Sarepta, and the NIH. CW has served on advisory boards for Acceleron, Sarepta, Abata, and Orphazyme, and as a consultant for Sarepta. VK does not have any competing interests to disclose.</CoiStatement><InvestigatorList><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fanganiello</LastName><ForeName>Roberto</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Grace</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mahoney</LastName><ForeName>Ryan Patrick</ForeName><Initials>RP</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Diaz-Manera</LastName><ForeName>Jordi</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Evangelista</LastName><ForeName>Teresinha</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Freimer</LastName><ForeName>Miriam</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lloyd</LastName><ForeName>Thomas E</ForeName><Initials>TE</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Keung</LastName><ForeName>Benison</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kushlaf</LastName><ForeName>Hani</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Milone</LastName><ForeName>Margherita</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Needham</LastName><ForeName>Merrilee</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Palmio</LastName><ForeName>Johanna</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stojkovic</LastName><ForeName>Tanya</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Villar-Quiles</LastName><ForeName>Roc&#xed;o-Nur</ForeName><Initials>RN</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Leo H</ForeName><Initials>LH</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wicklund</LastName><ForeName>Matthew P</ForeName><Initials>MP</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Singer</LastName><ForeName>Frederick R</ForeName><Initials>FR</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jones</LastName><ForeName>Mallory</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Miller</LastName><ForeName>Bruce L</ForeName><Initials>BL</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ahmad Sajjadi</LastName><ForeName>S</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Obenaus</LastName><ForeName>Andre</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Geschwind</LastName><ForeName>Michael D</ForeName><Initials>MD</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Al-Chalabi</LastName><ForeName>Ammar</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wymer</LastName><ForeName>James</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Nita</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kompoliti</LastName><ForeName>Katie</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Stephani C</ForeName><Initials>SC</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Boissoneault</LastName><ForeName>Catherine A</ForeName><Initials>CA</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cruz-Coble</LastName><ForeName>Betsaida</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Garand</LastName><ForeName>Kendrea L</ForeName><Initials>KL</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rinholen</LastName><ForeName>Anna J</ForeName><Initials>AJ</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tabor-Gray</LastName><ForeName>Lauren</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rosenfeld</LastName><ForeName>Jeffrey</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guo</LastName><ForeName>Ming</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Peck</LastName><ForeName>Nathan</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials></Investigator></InvestigatorList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35093159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8800193</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13023-022-02172-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13023-022-02172-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Korb MK, Kimonis VE, Mozaffar T. Multisystem proteinopathy: where myopathy and motor neuron disease converge. Muscle Nerve. 2021;63:442&#x2013;454.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33145792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leoni TB, Gonzalez-Salazar C, Rezende TJR, et al. A novel multisystem proteinopathy caused by a Missense ANXA11 variant. Ann Neurol. 2021;90:239&#x2013;252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34048612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill N, Frappier-Davignon L, Morrison B. The periodic health examination. Canadian Task Force on the Periodic Health Examination. Can Med Assoc J. 1979;121:1193&#x2013;1254.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1704686</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">115569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Obeidi E, Al-Tahan S, Surampalli A, et al. Genotype&#x2013;phenotype study in patients with valosin-containing protein mutations associated with multisystem proteinopathy. Clin Genet. 2018;93:119&#x2013;125.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5739971</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28692196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer H, Weihl CC. The VCP/p97 system at a glance: connecting cellular function to disease pathogenesis. J Cell Sci. 2014;127:3877&#x2013;3883.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4163641</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25146396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Boom J, Meyer H. VCP/p97-mediated unfolding as a principle in protein homeostasis and signaling. Mol Cell. 2018;69:182&#x2013;194.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29153394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watts GD, Wymer J, Kovach MJ, et al. Inclusion body myopathy associated with Paget disease of bone and frontotemporal dementia is caused by mutant valosin-containing protein. Nat Genet. 2004;36:377&#x2013;381.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15034582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Tahan S, Al-Obeidi E, Yoshioka H, et al. Novel valosin-containing protein mutations associated with multisystem proteinopathy. Neuromuscul Disord. 2018;28:491&#x2013;501.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29754758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim HJ, Kim NC, Wang YD, et al. Mutations in prion-like domains in hnRNPA2B1 and hnRNPA1 cause multisystem proteinopathy and ALS. Nature. 2013;495:467&#x2013;473.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3756911</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23455423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bucelli RC, Arhzaouy K, Pestronk A, et al. SQSTM1 splice site mutation in distal myopathy with rimmed vacuoles. Neurology. 2015;85:665&#x2013;674.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4553032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26208961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor JP. Multisystem proteinopathy: intersecting genetics in muscle, bone, and brain degeneration. Neurology. 2015;85:658&#x2013;660.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26208960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin KP, Tsai PC, Liao YC, et al. Mutational analysis of MATR3 in Taiwanese patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurobiol Aging. 2005;2015(36):e2001&#x2013;2004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25771394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackenzie IR, Nicholson AM, Sarkar M, et al. TIA1 mutations in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal dementia promote phase separation and alter stress granule dynamics. Neuron. 2017;95:808&#x2013;816.e809.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5576574</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28817800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maruyama H, Morino H, Ito H, et al. Mutations of optineurin in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nature. 2010;465:223&#x2013;226.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20428114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Albagha OM, Visconti MR, Alonso N, et al. Genome-wide association study identifies variants at CSF1, OPTN and TNFRSF11A as genetic risk factors for Paget's disease of bone. Nat Genet. 2010;42:520&#x2013;524.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3217192</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20436471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scotto di Carlo F, Pazzaglia L, Esposito T, Gianfrancesco F. The loss of profilin 1 causes early onset Paget's disease of bone. J Bone Miner Res. 2020;35:1387&#x2013;1398.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31991009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merlotti D, Materozzi M, Bianciardi S, et al. Mutation of PFN1 gene in an early onset, polyostotic Paget-like disease. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2020;105:2553&#x2013;2565.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32392277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu CH, Fallini C, Ticozzi N, et al. Mutations in the profilin 1 gene cause familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nature. 2012;488:499&#x2013;503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3575525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22801503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weihl CC, Pestronk A, Kimonis VE. Valosin-containing protein disease: inclusion body myopathy with Paget's disease of the bone and fronto-temporal dementia. Neuromuscul Disord. 2009;19:308&#x2013;315.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2859037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19380227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richards S, Aziz N, Bale S, et al. Standards and guidelines for the interpretation of sequence variants: a joint consensus recommendation of the American College of Medical Genetics and Genomics and the Association for Molecular Pathology. Genet Med. 2015;17:405&#x2013;424.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4544753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25741868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scuffham TM, MacMillan JC. Huntington disease: who seeks presymptomatic genetic testing, why and what are the outcomes? J Genet Couns. 2014;23:754&#x2013;761.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24399092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crozier S, Robertson N, Dale M. The psychological impact of predictive genetic testing for Huntington's disease: a systematic review of the literature. J Genet Couns. 2015;24:29&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25236481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tilleras KH, Kjoelaas SH, Dramstad E, Feragen KB, von der Lippe C. Psychological reactions to predictive genetic testing for Huntington's disease: a qualitative study. J Genet Couns. 2020;29:1093&#x2013;1105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32162754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehta SG, Khare M, Ramani R, et al. Genotype&#x2013;phenotype studies of VCP-associated inclusion body myopathy with Paget disease of bone and/or frontotemporal dementia. Clin Genet. 2013;83:422&#x2013;431.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3618576</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22909335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bugiardini E, Morrow JM, Shah S, et al. The diagnostic value of MRI pattern recognition in distal myopathies. Front Neurol. 2018;9:456.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6028608</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29997562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evangelista T, Weihl CC, Kimonis V, Lochmuller H, Consortium VCPrd 215th ENMC International Workshop VCP-related multi-system proteinopathy (IBMPFD) 13&#x2013;15 November 2015, Heemskerk, The Netherlands. Neuromuscul Disord. 2016;26:535&#x2013;547.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5967615</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27312024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kazamel M, Sorenson EJ, McEvoy KM, et al. Clinical spectrum of valosin containing protein (VCP)-opathy. Muscle Nerve. 2016;54:94&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26574898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diaz-Manera J, Llauger J, Gallardo E, Illa I. Muscle MRI in muscular dystrophies. Acta Myol. 2015;34:95&#x2013;108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4859076</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27199536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weihl CC, Temiz P, Miller SE, et al. TDP-43 accumulation in inclusion body myopathy muscle suggests a common pathogenic mechanism with frontotemporal dementia. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2008;79:1186&#x2013;1189.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2586594</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18796596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Figueroa-Bonaparte S, Hudson J, Barresi R, et al. Mutational spectrum and phenotypic variability of VCP-related neurological disease in the UK. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2016;87:680&#x2013;681.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4893144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26105173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Llewellyn KJ, Nalbandian A, Weiss LN, et al. Myogenic differentiation of VCP disease-induced pluripotent stem cells: a novel platform for drug discovery. PLoS ONE. 2017;12:e0176919.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5456028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28575052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang T, Mishra P, Hay BA, Chan D, Guo M. Valosin-containing protein (VCP/p97) inhibitors relieve mitofusin-dependent mitochondrial defects due to VCP disease mutants. Elife. 2017;6:e17834.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5360448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28322724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang B, Maxwell BA, Joo JH, et al. ULK1 and ULK2 regulate stress granule disassembly through phosphorylation and activation of VCP/p97. Mol Cell. 2019;74:742&#x2013;757.e748.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6859904</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30979586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim EJ, Park YE, Kim DS, et al. Inclusion body myopathy with Paget disease of bone and frontotemporal dementia linked to VCP p.Arg155Cys in a Korean family. Arch Neurol. 2011;68:787&#x2013;796.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21320982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ducharme S, Dols A, Laforce R, et al. Recommendations to distinguish behavioural variant frontotemporal dementia from psychiatric disorders. Brain. 2020;143:1632&#x2013;1650.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7849953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32129844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papadimas GK, Paraskevas GP, Zambelis T, et al. The multifaceted clinical presentation of VCP-proteinopathy in a Greek family. Acta Myol. 2017;36:203&#x2013;206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5953233</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29770363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hubbers CU, Clemen CS, Kesper K, et al. Pathological consequences of VCP mutations on human striated muscle. Brain. 2007;130:381&#x2013;393.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16984901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rascovsky K, Hodges JR, Knopman D, et al. Sensitivity of revised diagnostic criteria for the behavioural variant of frontotemporal dementia. Brain. 2011;134:2456&#x2013;2477.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3170532</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21810890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casaletto KB, Staffaroni AM, Wolf A, et al. Active lifestyles moderate clinical outcomes in autosomal dominant frontotemporal degeneration. Alzheimers Dement. 2020;16:91&#x2013;105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6953618</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31914227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiousi V, Arnaoutoglou M, Printza A. Speech and language intervention for language impairment in patients in the FTD-ALS spectrum. Hell J Nucl Med. 2019;22(Suppl):133&#x2013;146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30877731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsai RM, Boxer AL. Treatment of frontotemporal dementia. Curr Treat Options Neurol. 2014;16:319.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4920050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25238733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leroy M, Bertoux M, Skrobala E, et al. Characteristics and progression of patients with frontotemporal dementia in a regional memory clinic network. Alzheimers Res Ther. 2021;13:19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7796569</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33419472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noufi P, Khoury R, Jeyakumar S, Grossberg GT. Use of cholinesterase inhibitors in non-Alzheimer's dementias. Drugs Aging. 2019;36:719&#x2013;731.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31201687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boxer AL, Knopman DS, Kaufer DI, et al. Memantine in patients with frontotemporal lobar degeneration: a multicentre, randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Lancet Neurol. 2013;12:149&#x2013;156.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3756890</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23290598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Staa TP, Selby P, Leufkens HG, Lyles K, Sprafka JM, Cooper C. Incidence and natural history of Paget's disease of bone in England and Wales. J Bone Miner Res. 2002;17:465&#x2013;471.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11878305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan A, Ralston SH. Paget's disease of bone. QJM. 2014;107:865&#x2013;869.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24757095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ralston SH, Corral-Gudino L, Cooper C, et al. Diagnosis and management of Paget's disease of bone in adults: a clinical guideline. J Bone Miner Res. 2019;34:579&#x2013;604.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6522384</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30803025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ralston SH. Bisphosphonates in the management of Paget's disease. Bone. 2020;138:115465.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32512166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merlotti D, Rendina D, Muscariello R, et al. Preventive role of vitamin D supplementation for acute phase reaction after bisphosphonate infusion in Paget's disease. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2020;105:e466&#x2013;e476.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31634910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cronin O, Forsyth L, Goodman K, et al. Zoledronate in the prevention of Paget's (ZiPP): protocol for a randomised trial of genetic testing and targeted zoledronic acid therapy to prevent SQSTM1-mediated Paget's disease of bone. BMJ Open. 2019;9:e030689.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6731944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31488492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan A, Goodman K, Walker A, et al. Long-term randomized trial of intensive versus symptomatic management in Paget's disease of bone: the PRISM-EZ study. J Bone Miner Res. 2017;32:1165&#x2013;1173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28176386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, Miller RG, Swash M, Munsat TL, World Federation of Neurology Research Group on Motor Neuron D El Escorial revisited: revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord. 2000;1:293&#x2013;299.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11464847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Dengler R, Eisen A, et al. Electrodiagnostic criteria for diagnosis of ALS. Clin Neurophysiol. 2008;119:497&#x2013;503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18164242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hannaford A, Pavey N, van den Bos M, et al. Diagnostic utility of gold coast criteria in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol. 2021;89:979&#x2013;986.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33565111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diagnosis ETFo. Management of Amyotrophic Lateral S. Andersen PM, et al. EFNS guidelines on the clinical management of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (MALS)&#x2014;revised report of an EFNS task force. Eur J Neurol. 2012;19:360&#x2013;375.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21914052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jerath NU, Crockett CD, Moore SA, et al. Rare manifestation of a c.290 C&gt;T, p.Gly97Glu VCP mutation. Case Rep Genet. 2015;2015:239167.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4386706</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25878907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez MA, Feely SM, Speziani F, et al. A novel mutation in VCP causes Charcot-Marie-Tooth Type 2 disease. Brain. 2014;137:2897&#x2013;2902.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4208462</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25125609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Ridder W, Azmi A, Clemen CS, et al. Multisystem proteinopathy due to a homozygous p.Arg159His VCP mutation: a tale of the unexpected. Neurology. 2019;94:e785&#x2013;e796.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31848255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Postuma RB, Berg D, Stern M, et al. MDS clinical diagnostic criteria for Parkinson's disease. Mov Disord. 2015;30:1591&#x2013;1601.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26474316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kimonis VE, Kovach MJ, Waggoner B, et al. Clinical and molecular studies in a unique family with autosomal dominant limb-girdle muscular dystrophy and Paget disease of bone. Genet Med. 2000;2:232&#x2013;241.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6173187</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11252708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feingold B, Mahle WT, Auerbach S, et al. Management of cardiac involvement associated with neuromuscular diseases: a scientific statement from the American Heart Association. Circulation. 2017;136:e200&#x2013;e231.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28838934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kimonis VE, Fulchiero E, Vesa J, Watts G. VCP disease associated with myopathy, Paget disease of bone and frontotemporal dementia: review of a unique disorder. Biochim Biophys Acta. 2008;1782:744&#x2013;748.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18845250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang SC, Smith CD, Lombardo DM, Kimonis V. Characteristics of VCP mutation-associated cardiomyopathy. Neuromuscul Disord. 2021;31:701&#x2013;705.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34244020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ikenaga C, Findlay AR, Seiffert M, et al. Phenotypic diversity in an international Cure VCP Disease registry. Orphanet J Rare Dis. 2020;15:267.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7523394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32993728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plewa J, Surampalli A, Wencel M, et al. A cross-sectional analysis of clinical evaluation in 35 individuals with mutations of the valosin-containing protein gene. Neuromuscul Disord. 2018;28:778&#x2013;786.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6490182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30097247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finder JD, Birnkrant D, Carl J, et al. Respiratory care of the patient with Duchenne muscular dystrophy: ATS consensus statement. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2004;170:456&#x2013;465.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15302625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ragette R, Mellies U, Schwake C, Voit T, Teschler H. Patterns and predictors of sleep disordered breathing in primary myopathies. Thorax. 2002;57:724&#x2013;728.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1746391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12149535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian A, Donkervoort S, Dec E, et al. The multiple faces of valosin-containing protein-associated diseases: inclusion body myopathy with Paget's disease of bone, frontotemporal dementia, and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Mol Neurosci. 2011;45:522&#x2013;531.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21892620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian A, Nguyen C, Katheria V, et al. Exercise training reverses skeletal muscle atrophy in an experimental model of VCP disease. PLoS ONE. 2013;8:e76187.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3794032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24130765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kimonis V, Hamorsky K, Surampalli A, Wencel M, Khare M. The influence of diet and exercise on the physical health of affected individuals with VCP diseae. Int J Biotechnol Wellness Ind. 2014;3:46&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kleim JA, Jones TA. Principles of experience-dependent neural plasticity: implications for rehabilitation after brain damage. J Speech Lang Hear Res. 2008;51:S225&#x2013;239.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18230848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bogart KR, Dermody SS. Relationship of rare disorder latent clusters to anxiety and depression symptoms. Health Psychol. 2020;39:307&#x2013;315.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31855040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A standard framework for levels of integrated healthcare and update throughout the document. Available at https://www.integration.samhsa.gov/integrated-care-models/A_Standard_Framework_for_Levels_of_Integrated_Healthcare.pdf. Accessed 13 May 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roth JD, Pariser JJ, Stout TE, Misseri R, Elliott SP. Presentation and management patterns of lower urinary tract symptoms in adults due to rare inherited neuromuscular diseases. Urology. 2020;135:165&#x2013;170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31626855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morse CI, Higham K, Bostock EL, Jacques MF. Urinary incontinence in men with Duchenne and Becker muscular dystrophy. PLoS ONE. 2020;15:e0233527.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7259643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32469921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petty RKH, Eugenicos MP, Hamilton MJ, et al. The prevalence of faecal incontinence in myotonic dystrophy type 1. Neuromuscul Disord. 2019;29:562&#x2013;566.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31266721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Llewellyn KJ, Nalbandian A, Jung KM, et al. Lipid-enriched diet rescues lethality and slows down progression in a murine model of VCP-associated disease. Hum Mol Genet. 2014;23:1333&#x2013;1344.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3919004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24158850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romagnolo DF, Selmin OI. Mediterranean diet and prevention of chronic diseases. Nutr Today. 2017;52:208&#x2013;222.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5625964</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29051674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>