<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35133737</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>10</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0028-2200</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>129</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Nederlands tijdschrift voor tandheelkunde</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Ned Tijdschr Tandheelkd</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>[Oral hygiene in patients with motor neuron disease: a cross-sectional survey].</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>73</StartPage><EndPage>80</EndPage><MedlinePgn>73-80</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5177/ntvt.2022.02.21061</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Neuromuscular disorders cause damage to the motor nerves. Arm-hand function can severely be impaired. The needs of and limitations of patients with neuromuscular disorders and the role of their carers in providing oral hygiene were studied. To this end, an online survey was sent to 706 patients with a neuromuscular disorder (amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, spinal muscular atrophy, primary lateral sclerosis and progressive bulbar palsy). The survey questions concerned, among other things, self-reliance, the oral situation and oral hygiene. Oral health-related quality of life and subjective well-being were also measured. A total of 259 patients (36.7%) responded, of whom 71.9% declared themselves not to have been informed about the importance of maintaining good oral health. Moreover, 40.4% wished to receive help from an oral care professional regarding their oral hygiene; 19.8% was not satisfied with the oral care they provided for themselves or as provided by their carers. It was concluded that attention to oral hygiene for patients with neuromuscular disorders by both multidisciplinary treatment teams and oral care professionals is required.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Makizodila</LastName><ForeName>B A M</ForeName><Initials>BAM</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>van de Wijdeven</LastName><ForeName>J H E</ForeName><Initials>JHE</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>de Soet</LastName><ForeName>J J</ForeName><Initials>JJ</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Selms</LastName><ForeName>M K A van</ForeName><Initials>MKAV</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Volgenant</LastName><ForeName>C M C</ForeName><Initials>CMC</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>dut</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><VernacularTitle>Mondzorg bij pati&#xeb;nten met neuromusculaire aandoeningen: een cross-sectioneel vragenlijstonderzoek.</VernacularTitle></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Ned Tijdschr Tandheelkd</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0400771</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0028-2200</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003430" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Sectional Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016472" MajorTopicYN="Y">Motor Neuron Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009910" MajorTopicYN="N">Oral Hygiene</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="dut"><AbstractText>Bij neuromusculaire aandoeningen worden de motorische zenuwen aangetast. Hierdoor kan de arm-handfunctie sterk achteruitgaan. De behoeften en barri&#xe8;res van pati&#xeb;nten met neuromusculaire aandoeningen en de rol van hun mantelzorgers of zorgverleners bij het uitvoeren van mondzorg werd onderzocht. Hiertoe werd een online vragenlijst gestuurd naar 706 pati&#xeb;nten met een neuromusculaire aandoening (amyotrofische laterale sclerose, progressieve spinale musculaire atrofie, primaire laterale sclerose en progressieve bulbaire parese). De vragen betroffen onder meer zelfredzaamheid, mondsituatie en mondhygi&#xeb;ne. De mondgezondheid gerelateerde kwaliteit van leven en het subjectieve welzijn werden ook gemeten. In totaal reageerden 259 pati&#xeb;nten (36,7%), van wie 71,9% aangaf niet ge&#xef;nformeerd te zijn over het belang van een goede mondgezondheid. Bovendien wilde 40,4% graag hulp van een professionele mondzorgverlener ontvangen op het gebied van mondhygi&#xeb;ne, 19,8% was niet tevreden over de mondzorg zoals die door henzelf of hun verzorgers werd uitgevoerd. Geconcludeerd werd dat mondzorg bij pati&#xeb;nten met neuromusculaire aandoeningen aandacht nodig heeft van zowel multidisciplinaire behandelteams als mondzorgverleners.</AbstractText></OtherAbstract></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35133737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5177/ntvt.2022.02.21061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>