<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35156152</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1590-3478</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>43</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Neurological sciences : official journal of the Italian Neurological Society and of the Italian Society of Clinical Neurophysiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Neurol Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Psychoeducational groups for people with Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis and their caregiver: a qualitative study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>4239</StartPage><EndPage>4255</EndPage><MedlinePgn>4239-4255</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s10072-022-05930-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The current study aimed to describe the implementation of a structured psychoeducational intervention in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis (ALS), identifying the needs of both patients and their caregivers.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Five patients and thirteen caregivers attended eight psychoeducational group meetings at the Respiratory Rehabilitation Unit of IRCCS Santa Maria Nascente of Fondazione Don Carlo Gnocchi, Milan (Italy) and eight participants underwent semi-structured interviews once the group sessions ended. Group sessions and semi-structured interviews were audio-recorded and transcribed verbatim. Then, data obtained by group meetings' transcripts have been analysed using the grounded theory (GT) paradigm, while those obtained by interviews have been analysed using the interpretative phenomenological analysis (IPA).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The analysis of the meetings allowed us to identify seven main themes: "practical advice", "explanation of the pathology", "recognition of emotions", "adaptation", "family and relationships", "being caregiver of oneself", and "sharing". Twenty-one sub-themes also emerged from the transcripts' analysis. The analysis of the interviews allowed us to deduce the main reasons to participate (i.e., to have information and to be able to share experiences), the positive and negative aspects of the experiences. These results suggested the usefulness of psychoeducational groups in the regular clinical practise to allow patients and caregivers to share advice, emotions, and experiences with others in the same situation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This study displays the utility of psychoeducational group intervention in supporting people with ALS and their caregivers because of two main reasons: first for the psychoeducation provided by professionals; second for the possibility of sharing experiences and emotions with people in the same situation.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022. Fondazione Societ&#xe0; Italiana di Neurologia.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bilenchi</LastName><ForeName>Vittoria Anita</ForeName><Initials>VA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6406-7365</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, Catholic University of the Sacred Heart, Largo A. Gemelli 1, 20123, Milan, Italy. vittoriabilenchi@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Banfi</LastName><ForeName>Paolo</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8162-0751</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>IRCCS Fondazione Don Carlo Gnocchi, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pagnini</LastName><ForeName>Francesco</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1612-4211</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, Catholic University of the Sacred Heart, Largo A. Gemelli 1, 20123, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, Harvard University, Cambridge, MA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Volpato</LastName><ForeName>Eleonora</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0266-6386</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, Catholic University of the Sacred Heart, Largo A. Gemelli 1, 20123, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>IRCCS Fondazione Don Carlo Gnocchi, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Italy</Country><MedlineTA>Neurol Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100959175</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1590-1874</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000223" MajorTopicYN="N">Adaptation, Psychological</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017028" MajorTopicYN="Y">Caregivers</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000072858" MajorTopicYN="N">Psychosocial Support Systems</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D036301" MajorTopicYN="N">Qualitative Research</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis (ALS)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Caregivers</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Grounded theory (GT)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Interpretative phenomenological analysis (IPA)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Psychoeducational groups</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Qualitative methodology</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35156152</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10072-022-05930-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s10072-022-05930-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Zarei S, Carr K, Reiley L, Diaz K, Guerra O, Altamirano P et al (2015) A comprehensive review of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Surg Neurol Int 6(1):171</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/2152-7806.169561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2; A, Benzi G, Dossena M, Mutani R, Mora G (2005) Severely increased risk of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis among Italian professional football players. Brain 128(3):472&#x2013;476</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awh373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2; A, Logroscino G, Hardiman O, Swingler R, Mitchell D, Beghi E et al (2009) Prognostic factors in ALS: a critical review. Amyotroph Lateral Scler 10(5&#x2013;6):310&#x2013;323</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/17482960802566824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell JD, Borasio GD (2007) Seminar Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet 369(9578):2031&#x2013;2041</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(07)60944-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown RH, Al&#xad;Chalabi A. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. N Engl J Med. 2017;377,2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pagnini F (2013) Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis&#x202f;: a review 48(3):194&#x2013;205</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wicks P, Abrahams S, Masi D, Hejda-Forde S, Leigh PN, Goldstein LH (2007) Prevalence of depression in a 12-month consecutive sample of patients with ALS. Eur J Neurol 14(9):993&#x2013;1001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1468-1331.2007.01843.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurt A, Nijboer F, Matuz T, K&#xfc;bler A (2007) Illness trajectories in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: how illness progression is related to life narratives and interpersonal relationships. CNS Drugs 21(4):279&#x2013;291</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00023210-200721040-00003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cipolletta S, Gammino GR, Palmieri A (2017) Illness trajectories in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: how illness progression is related to life narratives and interpersonal relationships. J Clin Nurs 26(21&#x2013;24):5033&#x2013;5043</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jocn.14003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caputo A (2019) of Clinical Psychology sclerosis&#x202f;: a qualitative phenomenological study. Mediterr J Clin Psychol 7(2):1&#x2013;15</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palmieri A, Abrahams S, Sorar&#xf9; G, Mattiuzzi L, D&#x2019;Ascenzo C, Pegoraro E, et al. Emotional lability in MND: relationship to cognition and psychopathology and impact on caregivers. J Neurol Sci [Internet]. 2009;278(1&#x2013;2):16&#x2013;20. Available from: https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jns.2008.10.025</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palmieri A, Sorar&#xf9; G, Albertini E, Semenza C, Vottero-Ris F, D&#x2019;Ascenzo C et al (2010) Psychopathological features and suicidal ideation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. Neurol Sci 31(6):735&#x2013;740</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10072-010-0332-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hogden A, Foley G, Henderson RD, James N. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis&#x202f;: improving care with a multidisciplinary approach. J Multidiscip Healthc. 2017;205&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aoun SM, Connors S, Priddis L, Breen LJ, Colyer S. Motor neurone disease family carers &#x2019; experiences of caring , palliative care and bereavement&#x202f;: an exploratory qualitative study. 2015;26(6):842&#x2013;50</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cipolletta S, Amicucci L (2015) The family experience of living with a person with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis&#x202f;: a qualitative study. Int J Psychol 50(4):288&#x2013;294</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ijop.12085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Wit J, Beelen A, van den Heerik MS, van den Berg LH, Visser-Meily JMA, Schr&#xf6;der CD. Psychological distress in partners of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and progressive muscular atrophy: what&#x2019;s the role of care demands and perceived control? Psychol Heal Med [Internet]. 2020;25(3):319&#x2013;30. Available from: https://doi.org/10.1080/13548506.2019.1686646</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pagnini F, Lunetta C, Banfi P, Rossi G, Gorni K, Molinari E. Anxiety and depression in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and their caregivers. 2012;79&#x2013;87.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gauthier A, Vignola A, Calvo A, Cavallo E, Moglia C, Sellitti L, et al. A longitudinal study on quality of life and depression in ALS patient &#x2013; caregiver couples. 2007;15&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rabkin JG, Wagner GJ, Del Bene M (2000) Resilience and distress among amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients and caregivers. Psychosom Med 62(2):271&#x2013;279</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00006842-200003000-00020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pagnini F, Simmons Z, Corbo M, Molinari E (2012) Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: time for research on psychological intervention? Amyotroph Lateral Scler 13(5):416&#x2013;417</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/17482968.2011.653572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gould RL, Coulson MC, Brown RG, Goldstein LH, Al-Chalabi A, Howard RJ (2015) Psychotherapy and pharmacotherapy interventions to reduce distress or improve well-being in people with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a systematic review. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Front Degener 16(5&#x2013;6):293&#x2013;302</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/21678421.2015.1062515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bentley B, O&#x2019;Connor M, Kane R, Breen LJ (2014) Feasibility, acceptability, and potential effectiveness of dignity therapy for people with motor neurone disease. PLoS ONE 9(5):1&#x2013;8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0096888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palmieri A, Kleinbub JR, Calvo V, Sorar&#xf9; G, Grasso I, Messina I, et al. Efficacy of hypnosis-based treatment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a pilot study. Front Psychol. 2012;3(NOV):1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kleinbub JR, Palmieri A, Broggio A, Pagnini F. Hypnosis-based psychodynamic treatment in ALS&#x202f;: a longitudinal study on patients and their caregivers. 2015;6(June):1&#x2013;14</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palmieri A, Kleinbub JR, Pagnini F, Sorar&#xf9; G, Cipolletta S. Empathy-based supportive treatment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a pragmatic study. Am J Clin Hypn [Internet]. 2021;63(3):202&#x2013;16. Available from: https://doi.org/10.1080/00029157.2020.1797623</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jensen MP, Smith AE, Bombardier CH, Yorkston KM, Mir J, Molton IR (2013) Social support, depression, and physical disability&#x202f;: age and diagnostic group effects. Disabil Health J 7(2):164&#x2013;172</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.dhjo.2013.11.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parkyn H, Coveney J (2011) Child&#x202f;: An exploration of the value of social interaction in a boys &#x2019; group for adolescents with muscular dystrophy. Child Care Health Dev 39(1):1&#x2013;9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirk S, Milnes L (2016) An exploration of how young people and parents use online support in the context of living with cystic fibrosis. Heal Expect 19(2):309&#x2013;321</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/hex.12352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macdonald K, Greggans A (2010) &#x2018; Cool friends &#x2019;: an evaluation of a community befriending programme for young people with cystic fibrosis. J Clin Nurs 19(17&#x2013;18):2406&#x2013;2414</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2702.2010.03294.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meade O, Buchanan H, Coulson N. The use of an online support group for neuromuscular disorders&#x202f;: a thematic analysis of message postings analysis of message postings. 2017;8288(June)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cipolletta S, Gammino GR, Francescon P, Palmieri A. Mutual support groups for family caregivers of people with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in Italy&#x202f;: a pilot study. 2018;(January):556&#x2013;63</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Locock L, Brown JB. Social Science &amp; Medicine &#x2018; All in the same boat &#x2019;&#x202f;? Patient and carer attitudes to peer support and social comparison in motor neurone disease ( MND ). Soc Sci Med [Internet]. 2010;71(8):1498&#x2013;505. Available from: https://doi.org/10.1016/j.socscimed.2010.06.043</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madsen LS, Jeppesen J, Handberg C. &#x201c; Understanding my ALS &#x201d;. Experiences and reflections of persons with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and relatives on participation in peer group rehabilitation. Disabil Rehabil [Internet]. 2018;0(0):1&#x2013;9. Available from: https://doi.org/10.1080/09638288.2018.1429499</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Wit J, Beelen A, Drossaert CHC, Kolijn R, Van Den Berg LH, Schr&#xd6;der CD et al (2020) Blended psychosocial support for partners of patients with ALS and PMA: results of a randomized controlled trial. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Front Degener 21(5&#x2013;6):344&#x2013;354</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/21678421.2020.1757114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corbin J, Strauss A. Basics of qualitative research: techniques and procedures for developing grounded theory. Sage Publications;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pietkiewicz I, Smith JA, Pietkiewicz I, Smith JA. A practical guide to using interpretative phenomenological analysis in qualitative research psychology. 2014;(2012):7&#x2013;14</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, Miller RG, Swash M, Munsat TL (2000) El Escorial revisited: revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler 1(5):293&#x2013;299</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siciliano M, Trojano L, Trojsi F, Greco R, Santangelo G (2017) Edinburgh Cognitive and Behavioural ALS Screen ( ECAS ) - Italian version&#x202f;: regression based norms and equivalent scores. Neurol Sci 38(6):1059&#x2013;1068</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10072-017-2919-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Measso G, Cavarzeran F, Zappal&#xe0; G, Lebowitz BD, Crook TH, Pirozzolo FJ et al (1993) The Mini-Mental State Examination: normative study of an Italian random sample. Dev Neuropsychol 9(2):77&#x2013;85</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/87565649109540545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charmaz K. Constructing grounded theory: a practical guide through Qualitative. 2014379.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Passoni S, Moroni L, Toraldo A, Mazza MT, Bertolotti G, Vanacore N, et al. Cognitive behavioral group intervention for Alzheimer caregivers. Alzheimer Dis Assoc Disord [Internet]. 2014;28(3):275&#x2013;82. Available from: https://doi.org/10.1097/WAD.0000000000000033</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marconi A, Gragnano G, Lunetta C, Gatto R, Fabiani V, Tagliaferri A et al (2016) The experience of meditation for people with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and their caregivers &#x2013; a qualitative analysis. Psychol Heal Med 21(6):762&#x2013;768</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13548506.2015.1115110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galin S, Heruti I, Barak N, Gotkine M. Hope and self-efficacy are associated with better satisfaction with life in people with ALS. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Front Degener [Internet]. 2018;19(7&#x2013;8):611&#x2013;8. Available from: https://doi.org/10.1080/21678421.2018.1476546</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsieh S, Leyton CE, Caga J, Flanagan E, Kaizik C, OConnor CM, et al. The evolution of caregiver burden in frontotemporal dementia with and without amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Alzheimer&#x2019;s Dis. 2015;49(3):875&#x2013;85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bungener C (2012) Les &#xe9;motions et la scl&#xe9;rose lat&#xe9;rale amyotrophique&#x202f;: une perspective psychopathologique. Geriatr Psychol Neuropsychiatr Vieil 10(1):57&#x2013;64</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22414400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walklet E, Muse K, Meyrick J, Moss T (2016) Do psychosocial interventions improve quality of life and wellbeing in adults with neuromuscular disorders? A systematic review and narrative synthesis. J Neuromuscul Dis 3(3):347&#x2013;362</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/JND-160155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abrahams S, Borasio GD, Carvalho M De, Chio A, Damme V, Hardiman O, et al. EFNS GUIDELINES EFNS guidelines on the clinical management of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis ( MALS ) &#x2013; revised report of an EFNS task force. 2012;</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>