<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35172853</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>11</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1750-1172</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>16</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Orphanet journal of rare diseases</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Orphanet J Rare Dis</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Assessing the role of blood pressure in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a Mendelian randomization study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>56</StartPage><MedlinePgn>56</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">56</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13023-022-02212-0</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Observational studies have suggested a close but controversial relationship between blood pressure (BP) and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). It remains unclear whether this association is causal. The authors employed a bidirectional two-sample Mendelian randomization (MR) approach to evaluate the causal relationship between BP and ALS. Genetic proxies for systolic blood pressure (SBP), diastolic blood pressure (DBP), antihypertensive drugs (AHDs), ALS, and their corresponding genome-wide association study (GWAS) summary datasets were obtained from the most recent studies with the largest sample sizes. The inverse variance weighted (IVW) method was adopted as the main approach to examine the effect of BP on ALS and four other MR methods were used for sensitivity analyses. To exclude the interference between SBP and DBP, a multivariable MR approach was used.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">We found that genetically determined increased DBP was a protective factor for ALS (OR&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.978, 95% CI 0.960-0.996, P&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.017) and that increased SBP was an independent risk factor for ALS (OR&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.014, 95% CI 1.003-1.025, P&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.015), which is supported by sensitivity analyses. The use of calcium channel blocker (CCB) showed a causal relationship with ALS (OR&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.985, 95% CI 0.971-1.000, P&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.049). No evidence was revealed that ALS caused changes in BP.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">This study provides genetic support for a causal effect of BP and ALS that increased DBP has a protective effect on ALS, and increased SBP is a risk factor for ALS, which may be related to sympathetic excitability. Blood pressure management is essential in ALS, and CCB may be a promising candidate.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xia</LastName><ForeName>Kailin</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Peking University Third Hospital, Garden North Road No. 49, Beijing, 100191, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Beijing Municipal Key Laboratory of Biomarker and Translational Research in Neurodegenerative Diseases, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Linjing</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Peking University Third Hospital, Garden North Road No. 49, Beijing, 100191, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Beijing Municipal Key Laboratory of Biomarker and Translational Research in Neurodegenerative Diseases, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tang</LastName><ForeName>Lu</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Peking University Third Hospital, Garden North Road No. 49, Beijing, 100191, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Beijing Municipal Key Laboratory of Biomarker and Translational Research in Neurodegenerative Diseases, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Tao</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics, School of Public Health, Peking University, Beijing, China. huangtao@bjmu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Molecular Cardiovascular Sciences (Peking University), Ministry of Education, Beijing, China. huangtao@bjmu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Fan</LastName><ForeName>Dongsheng</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3129-9821</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Peking University Third Hospital, Garden North Road No. 49, Beijing, 100191, China. dsfan2010@aliyun.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Beijing Municipal Key Laboratory of Biomarker and Translational Research in Neurodegenerative Diseases, Beijing, China. dsfan2010@aliyun.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory for Neuroscience, National Health Commission/Ministry of Education, Peking University, Beijing, China. dsfan2010@aliyun.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Orphanet J Rare Dis</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101266602</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1750-1172</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001794" MajorTopicYN="N">Blood Pressure</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055106" MajorTopicYN="N">Genome-Wide Association Study</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057182" MajorTopicYN="N">Mendelian Randomization Analysis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020641" MajorTopicYN="N">Polymorphism, Single Nucleotide</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012307" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Blood pressure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Calcium channel blocker</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mendelian randomization</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors do not have any conflicts of interest to declare.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35172853</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8848798</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13023-022-02212-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13023-022-02212-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Pandya VA, Patani R. Decoding the relationship between ageing and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a cellular perspective. Brain. 2019;143(4):1057&#x2013;1072.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7174045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31851317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masrori P, Van Damme P. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a clinical review. Eur J Neurol. 2020;27(10):1918&#x2013;1929.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7540334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32526057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2; A, Moglia C, Canosa A, Manera U, Vasta R, Brunetti M, et al. Cognitive impairment across ALS clinical stages in a population-based cohort. Neurology. 2019;93(10):e984&#x2013;e994.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6745732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31409738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2; A, Mora G, Lauria G. Pain in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet Neurol. 2017;16(2):144&#x2013;157.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27964824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>GBD 2017 Risk Factor Collaborators et al. Global, regional, and national comparative risk assessment of 84 behavioural, environmental and occupational, and metabolic risks or clusters of risks for 195 countries and territories, 1990&#x2013;2017: a systematic analysis for the Global Burden of Disease Study 2017. Lancet. 2018;392(10159):1923&#x2013;1994.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6227755</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30496105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang B, Liao C, Zhou B, Cao W, Lv J, Yu C, et al. Genetic contribution to the variance of blood pressure and heart rate: a systematic review and meta-regression of twin studies. Twin Res Hum Genet. 2015;18(2):158&#x2013;170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25744168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moglia C, Calvo A, Canosa A, Bertuzzo D, Cugnasco P, Solero L, et al. Influence of arterial hypertension, type 2 diabetes and cardiovascular risk factors on ALS outcome: a population-based study. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Front Degener. 2017;18(7&#x2013;8):590&#x2013;597.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28616937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xf6;rner S, Kollewe K, Ilsemann J, M&#xfc;ller-Heine A, Dengler R, Krampfl K, et al. Prevalence and prognostic impact of comorbidities in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Eur J Neurol. 2013;20(4):647&#x2013;654.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23094606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreau C, Brunaud-Danel V, Dallongeville J, Duhamel A, Laurier-Grymonprez L, de Reuck J, et al. Modifying effect of arterial hypertension on amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2012;13(2):194&#x2013;201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21913867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hollinger SK, Okosun IS, Mitchell CS. Antecedent disease and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: what is protecting whom? Front Neurol. 2016;7:47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4810157</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27065942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lian L, Liu M, Cui L, Guan Y, Liu T, Cui B, et al. Environmental risk factors and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS): a case-control study of ALS in China. J Clin Neurosci. 2019;66:12&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31155341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith GD, Ebrahim S. 'Mendelian randomization': can genetic epidemiology contribute to understanding environmental determinants of disease? Int J Epidemiol. 2003;32(1):1&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12689998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haycock PC, Burgess S, Wade KH, Bowden J, Relton C, Davey SG. Best (but oft-forgotten) practices: the design, analysis, and interpretation of Mendelian randomization studies. Am J Clin Nutr. 2016;103(4):965&#x2013;978.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4807699</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26961927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Disney-Hogg L, Cornish AJ, Sud A, Law PJ, Kinnersley B, Jacobs DI, et al. Impact of atopy on risk of glioma: a Mendelian randomisation study. BMC Med. 2018;16(1):42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5853158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29540232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evangelou E, Warren HR, Mosen-Ansorena D, Mifsud B, Pazoki R, Gao H, et al. Genetic analysis of over 1 million people identifies 535 new loci associated with blood pressure traits. Nat Genet. 2018;50(10):1412&#x2013;1425.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6284793</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30224653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicolas A, Kenna KP, Renton AE, Ticozzi N, Faghri F, Chia R, et al. Genome-wide analyses identify KIF5A as a novel ALS gene. Neuron. 2018;97(6):1268&#x2013;83.e6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5867896</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29566793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ou YN, Yang YX, Shen XN, Ma YH, Chen SD, Dong Q, et al. Genetically determined blood pressure, antihypertensive medications, and risk of Alzheimer's disease: a Mendelian randomization study. Alzheimers Res Ther. 2021;13(1):41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7874453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33563324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emdin CA, Khera AV, Natarajan P, Klarin D, Zekavat SM, Hsiao AJ, et al. Genetic association of waist-to-hip ratio with cardiometabolic traits, type 2 diabetes, and coronary heart disease. JAMA. 2017;317(6):626&#x2013;634.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5571980</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28196256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burgess S, Bowden J, Fall T, Ingelsson E, Thompson SG. Sensitivity analyses for robust causal inference from Mendelian randomization analyses with multiple genetic variants. Epidemiology. 2017;28(1):30&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5133381</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27749700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowden J, Davey Smith G, Haycock PC, Burgess S. Consistent estimation in Mendelian randomization with some invalid instruments using a weighted median estimator. Genet Epidemiol. 2016;40(4):304&#x2013;314.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4849733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27061298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burgess S, Thompson SG. Interpreting findings from Mendelian randomization using the MR-Egger method. Eur J Epidemiol. 2017;32(5):377&#x2013;389.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5506233</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28527048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verbanck M, Chen CY, Neale B, Do R. Detection of widespread horizontal pleiotropy in causal relationships inferred from Mendelian randomization between complex traits and diseases. Nat Genet. 2018;50(5):693&#x2013;698.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6083837</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29686387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hemani G, Zheng J, Elsworth B, Wade KH, Haberland V, Baird D, et al. The MR-Base platform supports systematic causal inference across the human phenome. eLife. 2018;7:e34408.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5976434</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29846171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kandinov B, Drory VE, Tordjman K, Korczyn AD. Blood pressure measurements in a transgenic SOD1-G93A mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2012;13(6):509&#x2013;513.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22424128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bandres-Ciga S, Noyce AJ, Hemani G, Nicolas A, Calvo A, Mora G, et al. Shared polygenic risk and causal inferences in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol. 2019;85(4):470&#x2013;481.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6450729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30723964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whelton PK, Carey RM, Aronow WS, Casey DE, Jr, Collins KJ, Dennison Himmelfarb C, et al. 2017 ACC/AHA/AAPA/ABC/ACPM/AGS/APhA/ASH/ASPC/NMA/PCNA guideline for the prevention, detection, evaluation, and management of high blood pressure in adults: a report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Task Force on Clinical Practice Guidelines. Hypertension. 2018;71(6):e13&#x2013;e115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29133356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flint AC, Conell C, Ren X, Banki NM, Chan SL, Rao VA, et al. Effect of systolic and diastolic blood pressure on cardiovascular outcomes. N Engl J Med. 2019;381(3):243&#x2013;251.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31314968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin F-C, Tsai C-P, Kuang-Wu Lee J, Wu M-T, Tzu-Chi LC. Angiotensin-converting enzyme inhibitors and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis risk: a total population-based case-control study. JAMA Neurol. 2015;72(1):40&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25383557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee K, Lim C-Y. Mendelian randomization analysis in observational epidemiology. J Lipid Atheroscler. 2019;8(2):67&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7379124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32821701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benatar M, Turner MR, Wuu J. Defining pre-symptomatic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Front Degener. 2019;20(5&#x2013;6):303&#x2013;309.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6613999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30892087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glodzik L, Rusinek H, Tsui W, Pirraglia E, Kim HJ, Deshpande A, et al. Different relationship between systolic blood pressure and cerebral perfusion in subjects with and without hypertension. Hypertension. 2019;73(1):197&#x2013;205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7986962</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30571554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiu C, von Strauss E, Fastbom J, Winblad B, Fratiglioni L. Low blood pressure and risk of dementia in the Kungsholmen project: a 6-year follow-up study. Arch Neurol. 2003;60(2):223&#x2013;228.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12580707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daulatzai MA. Cerebral hypoperfusion and glucose hypometabolism: key pathophysiological modulators promote neurodegeneration, cognitive impairment, and Alzheimer's disease. J Neurosci Res. 2017;95(4):943&#x2013;972.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27350397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muhire G, Iulita MF, Vallerand D, Youwakim J, Gratuze M, Petry FR, et al. Arterial stiffness due to carotid calcification disrupts cerebral blood flow regulation and leads to cognitive deficits. J Am Heart Assoc. 2019;8(9):e011630.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6512142</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31057061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Velebit J, Horvat A, Smoli&#x10d; T, Prpar Mihevc S, Rogelj B, Zorec R, et al. Astrocytes with TDP-43 inclusions exhibit reduced noradrenergic cAMP and Ca(2+) signaling and dysregulated cell metabolism. Sci Rep. 2020;10(1):6003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7138839</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32265469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dalla Vecchia L, De Maria B, Marinou K, Sideri R, Lucini A, Porta A, et al. Cardiovascular neural regulation is impaired in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. A study by spectral and complexity analysis of cardiovascular oscillations. Physiol Meas. 2015;36(4):659&#x2013;670.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25798998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pimentel RMM, Macedo H, Jr, Valenti VE, Rocha FO, Abreu LC, Monteiro CBM, et al. Decreased heart rate variability in individuals with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Respir Care. 2019;64(9):1088&#x2013;1095.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31138737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keskin I, Forsgren E, Lehmann M, Andersen PM, Br&#xe4;nnstr&#xf6;m T, Lange DJ, et al. The molecular pathogenesis of superoxide dismutase 1-linked ALS is promoted by low oxygen tension. Acta Neuropathol. 2019;138(1):85&#x2013;101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6570705</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30863976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bursch F, Kalmbach N, Naujock M, Staege S, Eggenschwiler R, Abo-Rady M, et al. Altered calcium dynamics and glutamate receptor properties in iPSC-derived motor neurons from ALS patients with C9orf72, FUS, SOD1 or TDP43 mutations. Hum Mol Genet. 2019;28(17):2835&#x2013;2850.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31108504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tedeschi V, Petrozziello T, Sisalli MJ, Boscia F, Canzoniero LMT, Secondo A. The activation of Mucolipin TRP channel 1 (TRPML1) protects motor neurons from L-BMAA neurotoxicity by promoting autophagic clearance. Sci Rep. 2019;9(1):10743.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6656764</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31341250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tedeschi V, Petrozziello T, Secondo A. Calcium dyshomeostasis and lysosomal Ca2+ dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Cells. 2019;8(10):1216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6829585</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31597311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davey Smith G, Hemani G. Mendelian randomization: genetic anchors for causal inference in epidemiological studies. Hum Mol Genet. 2014;23(R1):R89&#x2013;R98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4170722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25064373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>