<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">35188908</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1537-1611</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>23</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of clinical neuromuscular disease</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Clin Neuromuscul Dis</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>What Is in the Literature.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>124</StartPage><EndPage>132</EndPage><MedlinePgn>124-132</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/CND.0000000000000399</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This issue of What Is in the Literature focuses on articles on amyotrophic lateral sclerosis over the past year. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis remains a challenging disorder with progression to death. Within the past year, a phase 2 trial of a drug combination showed slowing in the rate of progression. While awaiting a phase 3 trial or approval by the Food and Drug Administration, selected articles that aid the diagnosis, contribute to care, or add to general knowledge about the disease are reviewed.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bromberg</LastName><ForeName>Mark B</ForeName><Initials>MB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of Utah, Salt Lake City, UT.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Clin Neuromuscul Dis</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100887391</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1522-0443</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018450" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Progression</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The author reports no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35188908</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/CND.0000000000000399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00131402-202203000-00002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Shefner JM, Al-Chalabi A, Baker MR, et al. A proposal for new diagnostic criteria for ALS. Clin Neurophysiol. 2020;131:1975&#x2013;1978.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hannaford A, Higashihara M, Pavey N, et al. Split-hand index: a diagnostic and prognostic marker in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis across varying regions of onset. Clin Neurophysiol. 2021;132:2130&#x2013;2135.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pugdahl K, Camdessanche JP, Cengiz B, et al. Gold Coast diagnostic criteria increase sensitivity in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Neurophysiol. 2021;132:3183&#x2013;3189.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wijesekera LC, Mathers S, Talman P, et al. Natural history and clinical features of the flail arm and flail leg ALS variants. Neurology. 2009;72:1087&#x2013;1094.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen L, Tang L, Fan D. Twelve-month duration as an appropriate criterion for flail arm syndrome. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2020;21:29&#x2013;33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corcia P, Bede P, Pradat PF, et al. Split-hand and split-limb phenomena in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: pathophysiology, electrophysiology and clinical manifestations. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2021;92:1126&#x2013;1130.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J, Wang Z, Shen D, et al. Split phenomenon of antagonistic muscle groups in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: relative preservation of flexor muscles. Neurol Res. 2021;43:372&#x2013;380.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva CS, Santos MO, Gromicho M, et al. Electromyographic findings in primary lateral sclerosis during disease progression. Clin Neurophysiol. 2021;132:2996&#x2013;3001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hassan A, Mittal SO, Hu WT, et al. Natural history of &#x201c;pure&#x201d; primary lateral sclerosis. Neurology. 2021;96:e2231&#x2013;e2238.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paganoni S, Hendrix S, Dickson SP, et al. Long-term survival of participants in the CENTAUR trial of sodium phenylbutyrate-taurursodiol in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 2021;63:31&#x2013;39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H, Chen L, Tian J, et al. Disease duration of progression is helpful in identifying isolated bulbar palsy of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. BMC Neurol. 2021;21:405.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vacchiano V, Di Stasi V, Donadio V, et al. Needle electromyography of craniobulbar muscles in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: direct comparison between genioglossus and masseter muscles. Clin Neurophysiol. 2021;132:744&#x2013;745.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paganoni S, Macklin EA, Hendrix S, et al. Trial of sodium phenylbutyrate-taurursodiol for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. N Engl J Med. 2020;383:919&#x2013;930.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shepheard SR, Parker MD, Cooper-Knock J, et al. Value of systematic genetic screening of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2021;92:510&#x2013;518.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roggenbuck J, Fong JC. Genetic testing for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal dementia: impact on clinical management. Clin Lab Med. 2020;40:271&#x2013;287.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roggenbuck J, Rich KA, Vicini L, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis genetic access program: paving the way for genetic characterization of ALS in the clinic. Neurol Genet. 2021;7:e615.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barp A, Ada Sansone V, Lunetta C. Challenges in diagnosis of motor neuron disease: a case series of ALS mimic syndromes. Rev Neurol (Paris). 2021;177:699&#x2013;706.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lucia D, McCombe PA, Henderson RD, et al. Disorders of sleep and wakefulness in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS): a systematic review. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2021;22:161&#x2013;169.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heiman-Patterson TD, Khazaal O, Yu D, et al. Pulmonary function decline in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2021;22:54&#x2013;61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russo M, Bonanno C, Profazio C, et al. Which are the factors influencing NIV adaptation and tolerance in ALS patients? Neurol Sci. 2021;42:1023&#x2013;1029.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gottberg K, Ytterberg C, Sandstedt P, et al. Experiences of next of kin to patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis using invasive ventilation via tracheostomy. Disabil Rehabil. 2021;43:2403&#x2013;2410.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi PJ, Murn M, Turner R, et al. Continuing non-invasive ventilation during amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-related hospice care is medically, administratively, and financially feasible. Am J Hosp Palliat Care. 2021;38:1238&#x2013;1241.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samara VC, Jerant P, Gibson S, et al. Bowel, bladder, and sudomotor symptoms in ALS patients. J Neurol Sci. 2021;427:117543.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakayama R, Nishiyama A, Matsuda C, et al. Oral health status of hospitalized amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients: a single-centre observational study. Acta Odontol Scand. 2018;76:294&#x2013;298.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaudroz V, Kiliaridis S, Antonarakis GS. What can a dentist learn from an astrophysicist? A photographic evaluation of the long-term impact of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis on the orofacial sphere, using the example of Stephen Hawking: a historical case report. Spec Care Dentist. 2021:1&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKee AC, Cairns NJ, Dickson DW, et al. The first NINDS/NIBIB consensus meeting to define neuropathological criteria for the diagnosis of chronic traumatic encephalopathy. Acta Neuropathol. 2016;131:75&#x2013;86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russell ER, Mackay DF, Stewart K, et al. Association of field position and career length with risk of neurodegenerative disease in male former professional soccer players. JAMA Neurol. 2021;78:1057&#x2013;1063.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrew AS, Bradley WG, Peipert D, et al. Risk factors for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a regional United States case-control study. Muscle Nerve. 2021;63:52&#x2013;59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKay KA, Smith KA, Smertinaite L, et al. Military service and related risk factors for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neurol Scand. 2021;143:39&#x2013;50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farace C, Fenu G, Lintas S, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and lead: a systematic update. Neurotoxicology. 2020;81:80&#x2013;88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peters S, Broberg K, Gallo V, et al. Blood metal levels and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis risk: a prospective cohort. Ann Neurol. 2021;89:125&#x2013;133.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitsumoto H, Garofalo DC, Gilmore M, et al. Case-control study in ALS using the National ALS Registry: lead and agricultural chemicals are potential risk factors. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2021;17:1&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>