<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">35229461</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>22</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1521-6551</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>74</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>IUBMB life</Title><ISOAbbreviation>IUBMB Life</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>TAR DNA-binding protein 43 oligomers in physiology and pathology.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>794</StartPage><EndPage>811</EndPage><MedlinePgn>794-811</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/iub.2603</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>TAR DNA-binding protein 43 (TDP-43) is an RNA/DNA-binding protein involved in RNA regulation and diseases. In 2006, TDP-43 inclusions were found in the disease lesions of several neurodegenerative diseases. It is the pathological hallmark in both amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal lobar dementia. It also presents in a large portion of patients with Alzheimer's disease. TDP-43 is prone to aggregate; however, the role of TDP-43 oligomers remains poorly understood in both physiological and pathological conditions. In this review, we emphasize the role of oligomeric TDP-43 in both physiological and pathological conditions and discuss the potential mechanisms of oligomer formation. Finally, we suggest therapeutic strategies against the TDP-43 oligomers in neurodegenerative diseases.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022 International Union of Biochemistry and Molecular Biology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lye</LastName><ForeName>Yuh Shen</ForeName><Initials>YS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Genomics Research Center, Academia Sinica, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Taiwan International Graduate Program in Interdisciplinary Neuroscience, National Cheng Kung University and Academia Sinica, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Yun-Ru</ForeName><Initials>YR</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6596-6338</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Genomics Research Center, Academia Sinica, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Taiwan International Graduate Program in Interdisciplinary Neuroscience, National Cheng Kung University and Academia Sinica, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>MOST 108-2113-M-001-027</GrantID><Agency>Ministry of Sciences and Technology, Taiwan</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>IUBMB Life</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100888706</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1521-6543</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D004268">DNA-Binding Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D016601">RNA-Binding Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C000598624">TARDBP protein, human</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004268" MajorTopicYN="Y">DNA-Binding Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019636" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neurodegenerative Diseases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016601" MajorTopicYN="N">RNA-Binding Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ALS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">FTLD</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">TDP-43</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neurodegenerative diseases</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">oligomers</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35229461</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/iub.2603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Long JM, Holtzman DM. Alzheimer disease: An update on pathobiology and treatment strategies. Cell. 2019;179:312-339.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prasad A, Bharathi V, Sivalingam V, Girdhar A, Patel BK. Molecular mechanisms of TDP-43 misfolding and pathology in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Front Mol Neurosci. 2019;12:25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo JL, Lee VM. Cell-to-cell transmission of pathogenic proteins in neurodegenerative diseases. Nat Med. 2014;20:130-138.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forman MS, Trojanowski JQ, Lee VM. Neurodegenerative diseases: A decade of discoveries paves the way for therapeutic breakthroughs. Nat Med. 2004;10:1055-1063.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eisenberg D, Jucker M. The amyloid state of proteins in human diseases. Cell. 2012;148:1188-1203.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eichner T, Radford SE. A diversity of assembly mechanisms of a generic amyloid fold. Mol Cell. 2011;43:8-18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salahuddin P, Fatima MT, Abdelhameed AS, Nusrat S, Khan RH. Structure of amyloid oligomers and their mechanisms of toxicities: Targeting amyloid oligomers using novel therapeutic approaches. Eur J Med Chem. 2016;114:41-58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willbold D, Strodel B, Schroder GF, Hoyer W, Heise H. Amyloid-type protein aggregation and prion-like properties of amyloids. Chem Rev. 2021;121:8285-8307.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma S, Modi P, Sharma G, Deep S. Kinetics theories to understand the mechanism of aggregation of a protein and to design strategies for its inhibition. Biophys Chem. 2021;278:106665.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pellarin R, Caflisch A. Interpreting the aggregation kinetics of amyloid peptides. J Mol Biol. 2006;360:882-892.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dear AJ, Meisl G, Saric A, et al. Identification of on- and off-pathway oligomers in amyloid fibril formation. Chem Sci. 2020;11:6236-6247.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kayed R, Head E, Thompson JL, et al. Common structure of soluble amyloid oligomers implies common mechanism of pathogenesis. Science. 2003;300:486-489.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sengupta U, Nilson AN, Kayed R. The role of amyloid-beta oligomers in toxicity, propagation, and immunotherapy. EBioMedicine. 2016;6:42-49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cerf E, Sarroukh R, Tamamizu-Kato S, et al. Antiparallel beta-sheet: A signature structure of the oligomeric amyloid beta-peptide. Biochem J. 2009;421:415-423.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Celej MS, Sarroukh R, Goormaghtigh E, Fidelio GD, Ruysschaert JM, Raussens V. Toxic prefibrillar alpha-synuclein amyloid oligomers adopt a distinctive antiparallel beta-sheet structure. Biochem J. 2012;443:719-726.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu Z, Aucoin D, Davis J, Van Nostrand WE, Smith SO. Mechanism of nucleated conformational conversion of Abeta42. Biochemistry. 2015;54:4197-4207.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Apetri MM, Maiti NC, Zagorski MG, Carey PR, Anderson VE. Secondary structure of alpha-synuclein oligomers: Characterization by Raman and atomic force microscopy. J Mol Biol. 2006;355:63-71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghosh D, Singh PK, Sahay S, et al. Structure based aggregation studies reveal the presence of helix-rich intermediate during alpha-synuclein aggregation. Sci Rep. 2015;5:9228.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bargsted L, Medinas DB, Traub FM, et al. Disulfide cross-linked multimers of TDP-43 and spinal motoneuron loss in a TDP-43 A315T ALS/FTD mouse model. Sci Rep. 2017;7:1-11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang YS, Tsai KJ, Chang YJ, et al. Full-length TDP-43 forms toxic amyloid oligomers that are present in frontotemporal lobar dementia-TDP patients. Nat Commun. 2014;5:4824.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selkoe DJ. Folding proteins in fatal ways. Nature. 2003;426:900-904.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uversky VN, Yamin G, Souillac PO, Goers J, Glaser CB, Fink AL. Methionine oxidation inhibits fibrillation of human alpha-synuclein in vitro. FEBS Lett. 2002;517:239-244.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen SW, Drakulic S, Deas E, et al. Structural characterization of toxic oligomers that are kinetically trapped during alpha-synuclein fibril formation. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2015;112:E1994-E2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campioni S, Mannini B, Zampagni M, et al. A causative link between the structure of aberrant protein oligomers and their toxicity. Nat Chem Biol. 2010;6:140-147.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laganowsky A, Liu C, Sawaya MR, et al. Atomic view of a toxic amyloid small oligomer. Science. 2012;335:1228-1231.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serra-Batiste M, Ninot-Pedrosa M, Bayoumi M, Gairi M, Maglia G, Carulla N. Abeta42 assembles into specific beta-barrel pore-forming oligomers in membrane-mimicking environments. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2016;113:10866-10871.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paslawski W, Mysling S, Thomsen K, Jorgensen TJ, Otzen DE. Co-existence of two different alpha-synuclein oligomers with different core structures determined by hydrogen/deuterium exchange mass spectrometry. Angew Chem Int Ed Engl. 2014;53:7560-7563.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chimon S, Shaibat MA, Jones CR, Calero DC, Aizezi B, Ishii Y. Evidence of fibril-like beta-sheet structures in a neurotoxic amyloid intermediate of Alzheimer's beta-amyloid. Nat Struct Mol Biol. 2007;14:1157-1164.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quist A, Doudevski I, Lin H, et al. Amyloid ion channels: A common structural link for protein-misfolding disease. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2005;102:10427-10432.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lesne S, Koh MT, Kotilinek L, et al. A specific amyloid-beta protein assembly in the brain impairs memory. Nature. 2006;440:352-357.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin M, Shepardson N, Yang T, Chen G, Walsh D, Selkoe DJ. Soluble amyloid beta-protein dimers isolated from Alzheimer cortex directly induce Tau hyperphosphorylation and neuritic degeneration. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2011;108:5819-5824.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ingelsson M. Alpha-synuclein oligomers-neurotoxic molecules in Parkinson's disease and other Lewy body disorders. Front Neurosci. 2016;10:408.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dahlgren KN, Manelli AM, Stine WB Jr, Baker LK, Krafft GA, LaDu MJ. Oligomeric and fibrillar species of amyloid-beta peptides differentially affect neuronal viability. J Biol Chem. 2002;277:32046-32053.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ono K, Condron MM, Teplow DB. Structure-neurotoxicity relationships of amyloid beta-protein oligomers. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2009;106:14745-14750.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramdzan YM, Trubetskov MM, Ormsby AR, et al. Huntingtin inclusions trigger cellular quiescence, deactivate apoptosis, and lead to delayed necrosis. Cell Rep. 2017;19:919-927.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sangwan S, Zhao A, Adams KL, et al. Atomic structure of a toxic, oligomeric segment of SOD1 linked to amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2017;114:8770-8775.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ehrnhoefer DE, Bieschke J, Boeddrich A, et al. EGCG redirects amyloidogenic polypeptides into unstructured, off-pathway oligomers. Nat Struct Mol Biol. 2008;15:558-566.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee MC, Yu WC, Shih YH, et al. Zinc ion rapidly induces toxic, off-pathway amyloid-beta oligomers distinct from amyloid-beta derived diffusible ligands in Alzheimer's disease. Sci Rep. 2018;8:4772.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu YH, Bu XL, Liang CR, et al. An N-terminal antibody promotes the transformation of amyloid fibrils into oligomers and enhances the neurotoxicity of amyloid-beta: The dust-raising effect. J Neuroinflammation. 2015;12:153.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ladiwala ARA, Litt J, Kane RS, et al. Conformational differences between two amyloid &#x3b2; oligomers of similar size and dissimilar toxicity. J Biol Chem. 2012;287:24765-24773.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deas E, Cremades N, Angelova PR, et al. Alpha-synuclein oligomers interact with metal ions to induce oxidative stress and neuronal death in Parkinson's disease. Antioxid Redox Signal. 2016;24:376-391.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin H, Bhatia R, Lal R. Amyloid beta protein forms ion channels: Implications for Alzheimer's disease pathophysiology. FASEB J. 2001;15:2433-2444.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Strooper B, Karran E. The cellular phase of Alzheimer's disease. Cell. 2016;164:603-615.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haass C, Selkoe DJ. Soluble protein oligomers in neurodegeneration: Lessons from the Alzheimer's amyloid beta-peptide. Nat Rev Mol Cell Biol. 2007;8:101-112.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luth ES, Stavrovskaya IG, Bartels T, Kristal BS, Selkoe DJ. Soluble, prefibrillar alpha-synuclein oligomers promote complex I-dependent, Ca2+-induced mitochondrial dysfunction. J Biol Chem. 2014;289:21490-21507.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ou S, Wu F, Harrich D, Garc&#xed;a-Mart&#xed;nez LF, Gaynor RB. Cloning and characterization of a novel cellular protein, TDP-43, that binds to human immunodeficiency virus type 1 TAR DNA sequence motifs. J Virol. 1995;69:3584-3596.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Purice MD, Taylor JP. Linking hnRNP function to ALS and FTD pathology. Front Neurosci. 2018;12:326.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sephton CF, Cenik B, Cenik BK, Herz J, Yu G. TDP-43 in central nervous system development and function: Clues to TDP-43-associated neurodegeneration. Biol Chem. 2012;393:589-594.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neumann M, Sampathu DM, Kwong LK, et al. Ubiquitinated TDP-43 in frontotemporal lobar degeneration and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Science. 2006;314:130-133.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackenzie IR, Rademakers R, Neumann M. TDP-43 and FUS in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal dementia. Lancet Neurol. 2010;9:995-1007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang L-L, Xue W, Hong J-Y, et al. The N-terminal dimerization is required for TDP-43 splicing activity. Sci Rep. 2017;7:1-12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winton MJ, Igaz LM, Wong MM, Kwong LK, Trojanowski JQ, Lee VM-Y. Disturbance of nuclear and cytoplasmic TAR DNA-binding protein (TDP-43) induces disease-like redistribution, sequestration, and aggregate formation. J Biol Chem. 2008;283:13302-13309.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buratti E, Brindisi A, Giombi M, Tisminetzky S, Ayala YM, Baralle FE. TDP-43 binds heterogeneous nuclear ribonucleoprotein A/B through its C-terminal tail: An important region for the inhibition of cystic fibrosis transmembrane conductance regulator exon 9 splicing. J Biol Chem. 2005;280:37572-37584.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson BS, Snead D, Lee JJ, McCaffery JM, Shorter J, Gitler AD. TDP-43 is intrinsically aggregation-prone, and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-linked mutations accelerate aggregation and increase toxicity. J Biol Chem. 2009;284:20329-20339.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lagier-Tourenne C, Polymenidou M, Cleveland DW. TDP-43 and FUS/TLS: Emerging roles in RNA processing and neurodegeneration. Hum Mol Genet. 2010;19:R46-R64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buratti E. Functional significance of TDP-43 mutations in disease. Adv Genet. 2015;91:1-53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo W, Chen Y, Zhou X, et al. An ALS-associated mutation affecting TDP-43 enhances protein aggregation, fibril formation and neurotoxicity. Nat Struct Mol Biol. 2011;18:822-830.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang C-k, Wu T-H, Wu C-Y, et al. The N-terminus of TDP-43 promotes its oligomerization and enhances DNA binding affinity. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 2012;425:219-224.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsoi PS, Choi KJ, Leonard PG, et al. The N-terminal domain of ALS-linked TDP-43 assembles without misfolding. Angew Chemie. 2017;129:12764-12767.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang A, Conicella AE, Schmidt HB, et al. A single N-terminal phosphomimic disrupts TDP-43 polymerization, phase separation, and RNA splicing. EMBO J. 2018;37:e97452.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y-J, Caulfield T, Xu Y-F, et al. The dual functions of the extreme N-terminus of TDP-43 in regulating its biological activity and inclusion formation. Hum Mol Genet. 2013;22:3112-3122.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Afroz T, Hock EM, Ernst P, et al. Functional and dynamic polymerization of the ALS-linked protein TDP-43 antagonizes its pathologic aggregation. Nat Commun. 2017;8:45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang H-Y, Hou S-C, Way T-D, Wong C-H, Wang I-F. Heat-shock protein dysregulation is associated with functional and pathological TDP-43 aggregation. Nat Commun. 2013;4:1-11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carter GC, Hsiung CH, Simpson L, Yang H, Zhang X. N-terminal domain of TDP43 enhances liquid-liquid phase separation of globular proteins. J Mol Biol. 2021;433:166948.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasegawa M, Arai T, Nonaka T, et al. Phosphorylated TDP-43 in frontotemporal lobar degeneration and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol. 2008;64:60-70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasai T, Tokuda T, Ishigami N, et al. Increased TDP-43 protein in cerebrospinal fluid of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathol. 2009;117:55-62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsai KJ, Yang CH, Fang YH, et al. Elevated expression of TDP-43 in the forebrain of mice is sufficient to cause neurological and pathological phenotypes mimicking FTLD-U. J Exp Med. 2010;207:1661-1673.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wils H, Kleinberger G, Janssens J, et al. TDP-43 transgenic mice develop spastic paralysis and neuronal inclusions characteristic of ALS and frontotemporal lobar degeneration. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2010;107:3858-3863.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu YF, Zhang YJ, Lin WL, et al. Expression of mutant TDP-43 induces neuronal dysfunction in transgenic mice. Mol Neurodegener. 2011;6:73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang SL, Wu LS, Lee M, et al. A robust TDP-43 knock-in mouse model of ALS. Acta Neuropathol Commun. 2020;8:3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebstein SY, Yagudayeva I, Shneider NA. Mutant TDP-43 causes early-stage dose-dependent motor neuron degeneration in a TARDBP knockin mouse model of ALS. Cell Rep. 2019;26:364-373.e4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnold ES, Ling SC, Huelga SC, et al. ALS-linked TDP-43 mutations produce aberrant RNA splicing and adult-onset motor neuron disease without aggregation or loss of nuclear TDP-43. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2013;110:E736-E745.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>French RL, Grese ZR, Aligireddy H, et al. Detection of TAR DNA-binding protein 43 (TDP-43) oligomers as initial intermediate species during aggregate formation. J Biol Chem. 2019;294:6696-6709.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rane JS, Kumari A, Panda D. An acetylation mimicking mutation, K274Q, in tau imparts neurotoxicity by enhancing tau aggregation and inhibiting tubulin polymerization. Biochem J. 2019;476:1401-1417.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gasset-Rosa F, Lu S, Yu HY, et al. Cytoplasmic TDP-43 De-mixing independent of stress granules drives inhibition of nuclear import, loss of nuclear TDP-43, and cell death. Neuron. 2019;102:339-357.e7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vogler TO, Wheeler JR, Nguyen ED, et al. TDP-43 and RNA form amyloid-like myo-granules in regenerating muscle. Nature. 2018;563:508-513.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shodai A, Ido A, Fujiwara N, et al. Conserved acidic amino acid residues in a second RNA recognition motif regulate assembly and function of TDP-43. PLoS One. 2012;7:e52776.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shodai A, Morimura T, Ido A, et al. Aberrant assembly of RNA recognition motif 1 links to pathogenic conversion of TAR DNA-binding protein of 43 kDa (TDP-43). J Biol Chem. 2013;288:14886-14905.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang T, Mullane PC, Periz G, Wang J. TDP-43 neurotoxicity and protein aggregation modulated by heat shock factor and insulin/IGF-1 signaling. Hum Mol Genet. 2011;20:1952-1965.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen TJ, Hwang AW, Unger T, Trojanowski JQ, Lee VM. Redox signalling directly regulates TDP-43 via cysteine oxidation and disulphide cross-linking. EMBO J. 2012;31:1241-1252.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choksi DK, Roy B, Chatterjee S, et al. TDP-43 phosphorylation by casein kinase I&#x3b5; promotes oligomerization and enhances toxicity in vivo. Hum Mol Genet. 2014;23:1025-1035.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feiler MS, Strobel B, Freischmidt A, et al. TDP-43 is intercellularly transmitted across axon terminals. J Cell Biol. 2015;211:897-911.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kao PF, Chen YR, Liu XB, DeCarli C, Seeley WW, Jin LW. Detection of TDP-43 oligomers in frontotemporal lobar degeneration-TDP. Ann Neurol. 2015;78:211-221.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bozzo F, Salvatori I, Iacovelli F, et al. Structural insights into the multi-determinant aggregation of TDP-43 in motor neuron-like cells. Neurobiol Dis. 2016;94:63-72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smethurst P, Newcombe J, Troakes C, et al. In vitro prion-like behaviour of TDP-43 in ALS. Neurobiol Dis. 2016;96:236-247.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kitamura A, Yuno S, Muto H, Kinjo M. Different aggregation states of a nuclear localization signal-tagged 25-kD a C-terminal fragment of TAR RNA/DNA-binding protein 43 kDa. Genes Cells. 2017;22:521-534.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pillai M, Jha SK. The folding and aggregation energy landscapes of tethered RRM domains of human TDP-43 are coupled via a metastable molten globule-like oligomer. Biochemistry. 2018;58:608-620.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prasad A, Sivalingam V, Bharathi V, Girdhar A, Patel BK. The amyloidogenicity of a C-terminal region of TDP-43 implicated in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis can be affected by anions, acetylation and homodimerization. Biochimie. 2018;150:76-87.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asakawa K, Handa H, Kawakami K. Optogenetic modulation of TDP-43 oligomerization accelerates ALS-related pathologies in the spinal motor neurons. Nat Commun. 2020;11:1004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mann JR, Gleixner AM, Mauna JC, et al. RNA binding antagonizes neurotoxic phase transitions of TDP-43. Neuron. 2019;102:321-338.e8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montalbano M, McAllen S, Cascio FL, et al. TDP-43 and tau oligomers in Alzheimer's disease, amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, and frontotemporal dementia. Neurobiol Dis. 2020;146:105130.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shih Y-H, Tu L-H, Chang T-Y, et al. TDP-43 interacts with amyloid-&#x3b2;, inhibits fibrillization, and worsens pathology in a model of Alzheimer's disease. Nat Commun. 2020;11:1-17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smethurst P, Risse E, Tyzack GE, et al. Distinct responses of neurons and astrocytes to TDP-43 proteinopathy in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain. 2020;143:430-440.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pirie E, Oh C-k, Zhang X, et al. S-nitrosylated TDP-43 triggers aggregation, cell-to-cell spread, and neurotoxicity in hiPSCs and in vivo models of ALS/FTD. Proc Natl Acad Sci. 2021;118(118):e2021368118.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwong LK, Uryu K, Trojanowski JQ, Lee VM. TDP-43 proteinopathies: Neurodegenerative protein misfolding diseases without amyloidosis. Neurosignals. 2008;16:41-51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cairns NJ, Neumann M, Bigio EH, et al. TDP-43 in familial and sporadic frontotemporal lobar degeneration with ubiquitin inclusions. Am J Pathol. 2007;171:227-240.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao W, Beers DR, Bell S, et al. TDP-43 activates microglia through NF-kappaB and NLRP3 inflammasome. Exp Neurol. 2015;273:24-35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leal-Lasarte MM, Franco JM, Labrador-Garrido A, Pozo D, Roodveldt C. Extracellular TDP-43 aggregates target MAPK/MAK/MRK overlapping kinase (MOK) and trigger caspase-3/IL-18 signaling in microglia. FASEB J. 2017;31:2797-2816.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen HJ, Topp SD, Hui HS, et al. RRM adjacent TARDBP mutations disrupt RNA binding and enhance TDP-43 proteinopathy. Brain. 2019;142:3753-3770.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babinchak WM, Surewicz WK. Liquid-liquid phase separation and its mechanistic role in pathological protein aggregation. J Mol Biol. 2020;432:1910-1925.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simonian N, Coyle J. Oxidative stress in neurodegenerative diseases. Annu Rev Pharmacol Toxicol. 1996;36:83-106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liguori I, Russo G, Curcio F, et al. Oxidative stress, aging, and diseases. Clin Interv Aging. 2018;13:757-772.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang C-k, Chiang M-h, Toh EK-W, Chang C-F, Huang T-h. Molecular mechanism of oxidation-induced TDP-43 RRM1 aggregation and loss of function. FEBS Lett. 2013;587:575-582.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rohn TT. Caspase-cleaved TAR DNA-binding protein-43 is a major pathological finding in Alzheimer's disease. Brain Res. 2008;1228:189-198.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tremblay C, St-Amour I, Schneider J, Bennett DA, Calon F. Accumulation of transactive response DNA binding protein 43 in mild cognitive impairment and Alzheimer disease. J Neuropathol Exp Neurol. 2011;70:788-798.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakashima-Yasuda H, Uryu K, Robinson J, et al. Co-morbidity of TDP-43 proteinopathy in Lewy body related diseases. Acta Neuropathol. 2007;114:221-229.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwab C, Arai T, Hasegawa M, Yu S, McGeer PL. Colocalization of transactivation-responsive DNA-binding protein 43 and huntingtin in inclusions of Huntington disease. J Neuropathol Exp Neurol. 2008;67:1159-1165.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Josephs KA, Murray ME, Whitwell JL, et al. Staging TDP-43 pathology in Alzheimer's disease. Acta Neuropathol. 2014;127:441-450.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guerrero-Munoz MJ, Castillo-Carranza DL, Krishnamurthy S, et al. Amyloid-beta oligomers as a template for secondary amyloidosis in Alzheimer's disease. Neurobiol Dis. 2014;71:14-23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alexander GC, Emerson S, Kesselheim AS. Evaluation of aducanumab for Alzheimer disease: Scientific evidence and regulatory review involving efficacy, safety, and futility. JAMA. 2021;325:1717-1718.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>