<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35260846</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>28</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-0048</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>23</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Nature reviews. Neuroscience</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Nat Rev Neurosci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Modelling amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in rodents.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>231</StartPage><EndPage>251</EndPage><MedlinePgn>231-251</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41583-022-00564-x</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The efficient study of human disease requires the proper tools, one of the most crucial of which is an accurate animal model that faithfully recapitulates the human condition. The study of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) is no exception. Although the majority of ALS cases are considered sporadic, most animal models of this disease rely on genetic mutations identified in familial cases. Over the past decade, the number of genes associated with ALS has risen dramatically and, with each new genetic variant, there is a drive to develop associated animal models. Rodent models are of particular importance as they allow for the study of ALS in the context of a living mammal with a comparable CNS. Such models not only help to verify the pathogenicity of novel mutations but also provide critical insight into disease mechanisms and are crucial for the testing of new therapeutics. In this Review, we aim to summarize the full spectrum of ALS rodent models developed to date.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022. Springer Nature Limited.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Todd</LastName><ForeName>Tiffany W</ForeName><Initials>TW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience, Mayo Clinic Jacksonville, Jacksonville, FL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Petrucelli</LastName><ForeName>Leonard</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2959-129X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience, Mayo Clinic Jacksonville, Jacksonville, FL, USA. petrucelli.leonard@mayo.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Nat Rev Neurosci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100962781</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-003X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004195" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Models, Animal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009154" MajorTopicYN="N">Mutation</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012377" MajorTopicYN="N">Rodentia</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35260846</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41583-022-00564-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41583-022-00564-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Cook, C. &amp; Petrucelli, L. Genetic convergence brings clarity to the enigmatic red line in ALS. Neuron 101, 1057&#x2013;1069 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30897357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosen, D. R. et al. Mutations in Cu/Zn superoxide dismutase gene are associated with familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nature 362, 59&#x2013;62 (1993).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8446170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gurney, M. E. et al. Motor neuron degeneration in mice that express a human Cu,Zn superoxide dismutase mutation. Science 264, 1772&#x2013;1775 (1994). This report documents the first genetic mouse model of ALS: a transgenic model of SOD1-G93A that remains popular to date.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8209258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gurney, M. E., Fleck, T. J., Himes, C. S. &amp; Hall, E. D. Riluzole preserves motor function in a transgenic model of familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology 50, 62&#x2013;66 (1998).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9443458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ito, H. et al. Treatment with edaravone, initiated at symptom onset, slows motor decline and decreases SOD1 deposition in ALS mice. Exp. Neurol. 213, 448&#x2013;455 (2008).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18718468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong, P. C. et al. An adverse property of a familial ALS-linked SOD1 mutation causes motor neuron disease characterized by vacuolar degeneration of mitochondria. Neuron 14, 1105&#x2013;1116 (1995).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7605627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruijn, L. I. et al. ALS-linked SOD1 mutant G85R mediates damage to astrocytes and promotes rapidly progressive disease with SOD1-containing inclusions. Neuron 18, 327&#x2013;338 (1997).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9052802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ripps, M. E., Huntley, G. W., Hof, P. R., Morrison, J. H. &amp; Gordon, J. W. Transgenic mice expressing an altered murine superoxide dismutase gene provide an animal model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Proc. Natl Acad. Sci. USA 92, 689&#x2013;693 (1995).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7846037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">42685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jonsson, P. A. et al. Motor neuron disease in mice expressing the wild type-like D90A mutant superoxide dismutase-1. J. Neuropathol. Exp. Neurol. 65, 1126&#x2013;1136 (2006).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17146286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang-Hong, R. et al. Neuroprotective effect of oxidized galectin-1 in a transgenic mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Exp. Neurol. 194, 203&#x2013;211 (2005).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15899257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joyce, P. I. et al. A novel SOD1-ALS mutation separates central and peripheral effects of mutant SOD1 toxicity. Hum. Mol. Genet. 24, 1883&#x2013;1897 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25468678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muller, F. L. et al. Absence of CuZn superoxide dismutase leads to elevated oxidative stress and acceleration of age-dependent skeletal muscle atrophy. Free Radic. Biol. Med. 40, 1993&#x2013;2004 (2006).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16716900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fischer, L. R., Li, Y., Asress, S. A., Jones, D. P. &amp; Glass, J. D. Absence of SOD1 leads to oxidative stress in peripheral nerve and causes a progressive distal motor axonopathy. Exp. Neurol. 233, 163&#x2013;171 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21963651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Philips, T. &amp; Rothstein, J. D. Rodent models of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Curr. Protoc. Pharmacol. 69, 5.67.1&#x2013;5.67.21 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trist, B. G., Hilton, J. B., Hare, D. J., Crouch, P. J. &amp; Double, K. L. Superoxide dismutase 1 in health and disease: how a frontline antioxidant becomes neurotoxic. Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. 60, 9215&#x2013;9246 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kato, S., Saito, M., Hirano, A. &amp; Ohama, E. Recent advances in research on neuropathological aspects of familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with superoxide dismutase 1 gene mutations: neuronal Lewy body-like hyaline inclusions and astrocytic hyaline inclusions. Histol. Histopathol. 14, 973&#x2013;989 (1999).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10425565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shibata, N., Asayama, K., Hirano, A. &amp; Kobayashi, M. Immunohistochemical study on superoxide dismutases in spinal cords from autopsied patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Dev. Neurosci. 18, 492&#x2013;498 (1996).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8940623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wicks, P. et al. SOD1 and cognitive dysfunction in familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J. Neurol. 256, 234&#x2013;241 (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19252762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katz, J. S., Katzberg, H. D., Woolley, S. C., Marklund, S. L. &amp; Andersen, P. M. Combined fulminant frontotemporal dementia and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis associated with an I113T SOD1 mutation. Amyotroph. Lateral Scler. 13, 567&#x2013;569 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22670877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martinelli, I. et al. A novel p.N66T mutation in exon 3 of the SOD1 gene: report of two families of ALS patients with early cognitive impairment. Amyotroph. Lateral Scler. Frontotemporal Degener. 21, 296&#x2013;300 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32248719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakamura, M. et al. A truncating SOD1 mutation, p.Gly141X, is associated with clinical and pathologic heterogeneity, including frontotemporal lobar degeneration. Acta Neuropathol. 130, 145&#x2013;157 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25917047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5039014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rothstein, J. D. Current hypotheses for the underlying biology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann. Neurol. 65 (Suppl. 1), S3&#x2013;S9 (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19191304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geser, F., Martinez-Lage, M., Kwong, L. K., Lee, V. M. &amp; Trojanowski, J. Q. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, frontotemporal dementia and beyond: the TDP-43 diseases. J. Neurol. 256, 1205&#x2013;1214 (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19271105</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2790321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Da Cruz, S. et al. Misfolded SOD1 is not a primary component of sporadic ALS. Acta Neuropathol. 134, 97&#x2013;111 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28247063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5472502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neumann, M. et al. Ubiquitinated TDP-43 in frontotemporal lobar degeneration and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Science 314, 130&#x2013;133 (2006).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17023659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackenzie, I. R. et al. Pathological TDP-43 distinguishes sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis from amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with SOD1 mutations. Ann. Neurol. 61, 427&#x2013;434 (2007).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17469116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arai, T. et al. TDP-43 is a component of ubiquitin-positive tau-negative inclusions in frontotemporal lobar degeneration and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Biochem. Biophys. Res. Commun. 351, 602&#x2013;611 (2006).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17084815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vance, C. et al. Mutations in FUS, an RNA processing protein, cause familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis type 6. Science 323, 1208&#x2013;1211 (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19251628</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4516382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng, H. X. et al. FUS-immunoreactive inclusions are a common feature in sporadic and non-SOD1 familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann. Neurol. 67, 739&#x2013;748 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20517935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4376270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tyzack, G. E. et al. Widespread FUS mislocalization is a molecular hallmark of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain 142, 2572&#x2013;2580 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31368485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6735815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ikenaka, K. et al. Characteristic Features of FUS inclusions in spinal motor neurons of sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J. Neuropathol. Exp. Neurol. 79, 370&#x2013;377 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32142134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sreedharan, J. et al. TDP-43 mutations in familial and sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Science 319, 1668&#x2013;1672 (2008).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18309045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7116650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kabashi, E. et al. TARDBP mutations in individuals with sporadic and familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat. Genet. 40, 572&#x2013;574 (2008).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18372902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rutherford, N. J. et al. Novel mutations in TARDBP (TDP-43) in patients with familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. PLoS Genet. 4, e1000193 (2008).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18802454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2527686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwiatkowski, T. J. Jr. et al. Mutations in the FUS/TLS gene on chromosome 16 cause familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Science 323, 1205&#x2013;1208 (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19251627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Couthouis, J. et al. A yeast functional screen predicts new candidate ALS disease genes. Proc. Natl Acad. Sci. USA 108, 20881&#x2013;20890 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22065782</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3248518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conicella, A. E., Zerze, G. H., Mittal, J. &amp; Fawzi, N. L. ALS mutations disrupt phase separation mediated by alpha-helical structure in the TDP-43 low-complexity C-terminal domain. Structure 24, 1537&#x2013;1549 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27545621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5014597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwon, I. et al. Phosphorylation-regulated binding of RNA polymerase II to fibrous polymers of low-complexity domains. Cell 155, 1049&#x2013;1060 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24267890</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4010232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwon, I. et al. Poly-dipeptides encoded by the C9orf72 repeats bind nucleoli, impede RNA biogenesis, and kill cells. Science 345, 1139&#x2013;1145 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25081482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4459787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han, T. W. et al. Cell-free formation of RNA granules: bound RNAs identify features and components of cellular assemblies. Cell 149, 768&#x2013;779 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22579282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kato, M. et al. Cell-free formation of RNA granules: low complexity sequence domains form dynamic fibers within hydrogels. Cell 149, 753&#x2013;767 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22579281</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6347373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davidson, Y. et al. Ubiquitinated pathological lesions in frontotemporal lobar degeneration contain the TAR DNA-binding protein, TDP-43. Acta Neuropathol. 113, 521&#x2013;533 (2007).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17219193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neumann, M. et al. Phosphorylation of S409/410 of TDP-43 is a consistent feature in all sporadic and familial forms of TDP-43 proteinopathies. Acta Neuropathol. 117, 137&#x2013;149 (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19125255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2693625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wils, H. et al. TDP-43 transgenic mice develop spastic paralysis and neuronal inclusions characteristic of ALS and frontotemporal lobar degeneration. Proc. Natl Acad. Sci. USA 107, 3858&#x2013;3863 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20133711</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2840518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stallings, N. R., Puttaparthi, K., Luther, C. M., Burns, D. K. &amp; Elliott, J. L. Progressive motor weakness in transgenic mice expressing human TDP-43. Neurobiol. Dis. 40, 404&#x2013;414 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20621187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, Y. F. et al. Wild-type human TDP-43 expression causes TDP-43 phosphorylation, mitochondrial aggregation, motor deficits, and early mortality in transgenic mice. J. Neurosci. 30, 10851&#x2013;10859 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20702714</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3056148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsuiji, H. et al. TDP-43 accelerates age-dependent degeneration of interneurons. Sci. Rep. 7, 14972 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29097807</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5668320</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, D. B. et al. Expansive gene transfer in the rat CNS rapidly produces amyotrophic lateral sclerosis relevant sequelae when TDP-43 is overexpressed. Mol. Ther. 18, 2064&#x2013;2074 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20877346</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2997590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson, K. L., Dayton, R. D., Deverman, B. E. &amp; Klein, R. L. Better targeting, better efficiency for wide-scale neuronal transduction with the synapsin promoter and AAV-PHP.B. Front. Mol. Neurosci. 9, 116 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27867348</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5095393</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Igaz, L. M. et al. Dysregulation of the ALS-associated gene TDP-43 leads to neuronal death and degeneration in mice. J. Clin. Invest. 121, 726&#x2013;738 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21206091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3026736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sasaguri, H. et al. The extreme N-terminus of TDP-43 mediates the cytoplasmic aggregation of TDP-43 and associated toxicity in vivo. Brain Res. 1647, 57&#x2013;64 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27155453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5003772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walker, A. K. et al. Functional recovery in new mouse models of ALS/FTLD after clearance of pathological cytoplasmic TDP-43. Acta Neuropathol. 130, 643&#x2013;660 (2015). Unfortunately, most TDP43 mouse models fail to recapitulate the expected cytoplasmic inclusions; the authors of this report, and a previous study, overcame this hurdle by engineering mice to express TDP43 with a mutant nuclear localization sequence.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26197969</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5127391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishino, K. et al. Mice deficient in the C-terminal domain of TAR DNA-binding protein 43 develop age-dependent motor dysfunction associated with impaired Notch1-Akt signaling pathway. Acta Neuropathol. Commun. 7, 118 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31345270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6657153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sugai, A. et al. Non-genetically modified models exhibit TARDBP mRNA increase due to perturbed TDP-43 autoregulation. Neurobiol. Dis. 130, 104534 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31310801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer, B. C. et al. Loss of murine TDP-43 disrupts motor function and plays an essential role in embryogenesis. Acta Neuropathol. 119, 409&#x2013;419 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20198480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2880609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, L. S., Cheng, W. C. &amp; Shen, C. K. Targeted depletion of TDP-43 expression in the spinal cord motor neurons leads to the development of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-like phenotypes in mice. J. Biol. Chem. 287, 27335&#x2013;27344 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22718760</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3431639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, L. S. et al. Transcriptomopathies of pre- and post-symptomatic frontotemporal dementia-like mice with TDP-43 depletion in forebrain neurons. Acta Neuropathol. Commun. 7, 50 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30922385</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6440020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, C. et al. Partial loss of TDP-43 function causes phenotypes of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Proc. Natl Acad. Sci. USA 111, E1121&#x2013;E1129 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24616503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3970502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paolicelli, R. C. et al. TDP-43 depletion in microglia promotes amyloid clearance but also induces synapse loss. Neuron 95, 297&#x2013;308.e6 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28669544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5519492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koza, P. et al. Neuronal TDP-43 depletion affects activity-dependent plasticity. Neurobiol. Dis. 130, 104499 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31176717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wegorzewska, I., Bell, S., Cairns, N. J., Miller, T. M. &amp; Baloh, R. H. TDP-43 mutant transgenic mice develop features of ALS and frontotemporal lobar degeneration. Proc. Natl Acad. Sci. USA 106, 18809&#x2013;18814 (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19833869</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2762420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo, Y. et al. HO-1 induction in motor cortex and intestinal dysfunction in TDP-43 A315T transgenic mice. Brain Res. 1460, 88&#x2013;95 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22578468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esmaeili, M. A., Panahi, M., Yadav, S., Hennings, L. &amp; Kiaei, M. Premature death of TDP-43 (A315T) transgenic mice due to gastrointestinal complications prior to development of full neurological symptoms of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Int. J. Exp. Pathol. 94, 56&#x2013;64 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23317354</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3575874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hatzipetros, T. et al. C57BL/6J congenic Prp-TDP43A315T mice develop progressive neurodegeneration in the myenteric plexus of the colon without exhibiting key features of ALS. Brain Res. 1584, 59&#x2013;72 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24141148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herdewyn, S. et al. Prevention of intestinal obstruction reveals progressive neurodegeneration in mutant TDP-43 (A315T) mice. Mol. Neurodegener. 9, 24 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24938805</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4088917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, S. et al. Riluzole exhibits no therapeutic efficacy on a transgenic rat model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Curr. Neurovasc Res. 17, 275&#x2013;285 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32271694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon, D. et al. Single-copy expression of an amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-linked TDP-43 mutation (M337V) in BAC transgenic mice leads to altered stress granule dynamics and progressive motor dysfunction. Neurobiol. Dis. 121, 148&#x2013;162 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30290270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, S. L. et al. A robust TDP-43 knock-in mouse model of ALS. Acta Neuropathol. Commun. 8, 3 (2020). While most knock-in models of Tdp43 only show ALS-like phenotypes at advanced ages, this model saw phenotypes as early as 6 months of age.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31964415</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6975031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watanabe, S. et al. ALS-linked TDP-43(M337V) knock-in mice exhibit splicing deregulation without neurodegeneration. Mol. Brain 13, 8 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31959210</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6971932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebstein, S. Y., Yagudayeva, I. &amp; Shneider, N. A. Mutant TDP-43 causes early-stage dose-dependent motor neuron degeneration in a TARDBP knockin mouse model of ALS. Cell Rep. 26, 364&#x2013;373.e4 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30625319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muller, H. P. et al. Longitudinal diffusion tensor magnetic resonance imaging analysis at the cohort level reveals disturbed cortical and callosal microstructure with spared corticospinal tract in the TDP-43 (G298S) ALS mouse model. Transl. Neurodegener. 8, 27 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31485326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6716821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>White, M. A. et al. TDP-43 gains function due to perturbed autoregulation in a Tardbp knock-in mouse model of ALS-FTD. Nat. Neurosci. 21, 552&#x2013;563 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29556029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5884423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fratta, P. et al. Mice with endogenous TDP-43 mutations exhibit gain of splicing function and characteristics of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. EMBO J. 37, e98684 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29764981</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5983119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Birsa, N., Bentham, M. P. &amp; Fratta, P. Cytoplasmic functions of TDP-43 and FUS and their role in ALS. Semin. Cell Dev. Biol. 99, 193&#x2013;201 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31132467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishigaki, S. &amp; Sobue, G. Importance of Functional Loss of FUS in FTLD/ALS. Front. Mol. Biosci. 5, 44 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29774215</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5943504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, C., Ding, X., Akram, N., Xue, S. &amp; Luo, S. Z. Fused in sarcoma: properties, self-assembly and correlation with neurodegenerative diseases. Molecules 24, 1622 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6514960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dormann, D. et al. ALS-associated fused in sarcoma (FUS) mutations disrupt transportin-mediated nuclear import. EMBO J. 29, 2841&#x2013;2857 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20606625</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2924641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel, A. et al. A liquid-to-solid phase transition of the ALS protein FUS accelerated by disease mutation. Cell 162, 1066&#x2013;1077 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26317470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murakami, T. et al. ALS/FTD mutation-induced phase transition of FUS liquid droplets and reversible hydrogels into irreversible hydrogels impairs RNP granule function. Neuron 88, 678&#x2013;690 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26526393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4660210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratti, A. &amp; Buratti, E. Physiological functions and pathobiology of TDP-43 and FUS/TLS proteins. J. Neurochem. 138, 95&#x2013;111 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27015757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olszewska, D. A., Lonergan, R., Fallon, E. M. &amp; Lynch, T. Genetics of frontotemporal dementia. Curr. Neurol. Neurosci. Rep. 16, 107 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27878525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackenzie, I. R. et al. Nomenclature and nosology for neuropathologic subtypes of frontotemporal lobar degeneration: an update. Acta Neuropathol. 119, 1&#x2013;4 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19924424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Snowden, J. S. et al. The most common type of FTLD-FUS (aFTLD-U) is associated with a distinct clinical form of frontotemporal dementia but is not related to mutations in the FUS gene. Acta Neuropathol. 122, 99&#x2013;110 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21424531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabatelli, M. et al. Mutations in the 3&#x2019; untranslated region of FUS causing FUS overexpression are associated with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Hum. Mol. Genet. 22, 4748&#x2013;4755 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23847048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dini Modigliani, S., Morlando, M., Errichelli, L., Sabatelli, M. &amp; Bozzoni, I. An ALS-associated mutation in the FUS 3&#x2019;-UTR disrupts a microRNA-FUS regulatory circuitry. Nat. Commun. 5, 4335 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25004804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell, J. C. et al. Overexpression of human wild-type FUS causes progressive motor neuron degeneration in an age- and dose-dependent fashion. Acta Neuropathol. 125, 273&#x2013;288 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22961620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ling, S. C. et al. Overriding FUS autoregulation in mice triggers gain-of-toxic dysfunctions in RNA metabolism and autophagy-lysosome axis. eLife 8, e40811 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30747709</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6389288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, C. et al. FUS transgenic rats develop the phenotypes of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal lobar degeneration. PLoS Genet. 7, e1002011 (2011). Using rats as a model system, this group documents the first rodent model to express an ALS-associated FUS mutation, FUS-R521C.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21408206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3048370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuroda, M. et al. Male sterility and enhanced radiation sensitivity in TLS(-/-) mice. EMBO J. 19, 453&#x2013;462 (2000).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10654943</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">305582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hicks, G. G. et al. Fus deficiency in mice results in defective B-lymphocyte development and activation, high levels of chromosomal instability and perinatal death. Nat. Genet. 24, 175&#x2013;179 (2000).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10655065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scekic-Zahirovic, J. et al. Toxic gain of function from mutant FUS protein is crucial to trigger cell autonomous motor neuron loss. EMBO J. 35, 1077&#x2013;1097 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26951610</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4868956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kino, Y. et al. FUS/TLS deficiency causes behavioral and pathological abnormalities distinct from amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathol. Commun. 3, 24 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25907258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4408580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yokoi, S. et al. 3&#x2019;UTR length-dependent control of SynGAP isoform alpha2 mRNA by FUS and ELAV-like proteins promotes dendritic spine maturation and cognitive function. Cell Rep. 20, 3071&#x2013;3084 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28954225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Udagawa, T. et al. FUS regulates AMPA receptor function and FTLD/ALS-associated behaviour via GluA1 mRNA stabilization. Nat. Commun. 6, 7098 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25968143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishigaki, S. et al. Altered Tau isoform ratio caused by loss of FUS and SFPQ function leads to FTLD-like phenotypes. Cell Rep. 18, 1118&#x2013;1131 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28147269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma, A. et al. ALS-associated mutant FUS induces selective motor neuron degeneration through toxic gain of function. Nat. Commun. 7, 10465 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26842965</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4742863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiu, H. et al. ALS-associated mutation FUS-R521C causes DNA damage and RNA splicing defects. J. Clin. Invest. 124, 981&#x2013;999 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24509083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3938263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Erauskin, J. et al. ALS/FTD-linked mutation in FUS suppresses intra-axonal protein synthesis and drives disease without nuclear loss-of-function of FUS. Neuron 100, 816&#x2013;830.e7 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30344044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6277851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, X. et al. In vivo stress granule misprocessing evidenced in a FUS knock-in ALS mouse model. Brain 143, 1350&#x2013;1367 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32358598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sephton, C. F. et al. Activity-dependent FUS dysregulation disrupts synaptic homeostasis. Proc. Natl Acad. Sci. USA 111, E4769&#x2013;E4778 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25324524</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4226112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shiihashi, G. et al. Dendritic homeostasis disruption in a novel frontotemporal dementia mouse model expressing cytoplasmic fused in sarcoma. EBioMedicine 24, 102&#x2013;115 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28928015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5652009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shiihashi, G. et al. Mislocated FUS is sufficient for gain-of-toxic-function amyotrophic lateral sclerosis phenotypes in mice. Brain 139, 2380&#x2013;2394 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27368346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Picchiarelli, G. et al. FUS-mediated regulation of acetylcholine receptor transcription at neuromuscular junctions is compromised in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat. Neurosci. 22, 1793&#x2013;1805 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31591561</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6858880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scekic-Zahirovic, J. et al. Motor neuron intrinsic and extrinsic mechanisms contribute to the pathogenesis of FUS-associated amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathol. 133, 887&#x2013;906 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28243725</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5427169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verbeeck, C. et al. Expression of fused in sarcoma mutations in mice recapitulates the neuropathology of FUS proteinopathies and provides insight into disease pathogenesis. Mol. Neurodegener. 7, 53 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23046583</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3519790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devoy, A. et al. Humanized mutant FUS drives progressive motor neuron degeneration without aggregation in &#x2018;FUSDelta14&#x2019; knockin mice. Brain 140, 2797&#x2013;2805 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29053787</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5841203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeJesus-Hernandez, M. et al. De novo truncating FUS gene mutation as a cause of sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Hum. Mutat. 31, E1377&#x2013;E1389 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20232451</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2922682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chesi, A. et al. Exome sequencing to identify de novo mutations in sporadic ALS trios. Nat. Neurosci. 16, 851&#x2013;855 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23708140</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3709464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Staahl, B. T. et al. Kinetic analysis of npBAF to nBAF switching reveals exchange of SS18 with CREST and integration with neural developmental pathways. J. Neurosci. 33, 10348&#x2013;10361 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23785148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3685834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park, S. et al. Calcium-responsive transactivator (CREST) toxicity is rescued by loss of PBP1/ATXN2 function in a novel yeast proteinopathy model and in transgenic flies. PLoS Genet. 15, e1008308 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31390360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6699716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kukharsky, M. S. et al. Calcium-responsive transactivator (CREST) protein shares a set of structural and functional traits with other proteins associated with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Mol. Neurodegener. 10, 20 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25888396</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4428507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng, C. et al. Loss of CREST leads to neuroinflammatory responses and ALS-like motor defects in mice. Transl. Neurodegener. 8, 13 (2019). The authors developed the main mouse models of CREST-related ALS by generating both a mutant transgenic model and a knockout; their study argues that this disease arises from a loss of CREST function.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30976389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6444434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aizawa, H. et al. Dendrite development regulated by CREST, a calcium-regulated transcriptional activator. Science 303, 197&#x2013;202 (2004).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14716005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson, J. O. et al. Mutations in the Matrin 3 gene cause familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat. Neurosci. 17, 664&#x2013;666 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24686783</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4000579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coelho, M. B. et al. Nuclear matrix protein Matrin3 regulates alternative splicing and forms overlapping regulatory networks with PTB. EMBO J. 34, 653&#x2013;668 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25599992</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4365034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banerjee, A., Vest, K. E., Pavlath, G. K. &amp; Corbett, A. H. Nuclear poly(A) binding protein 1 (PABPN1) and Matrin3 interact in muscle cells and regulate RNA processing. Nucleic Acids Res. 45, 10706&#x2013;10725 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28977530</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5737383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallego-Iradi, M. C. et al. N-terminal sequences in matrin 3 mediate phase separation into droplet-like structures that recruit TDP43 variants lacking RNA binding elements. Lab. Invest. 99, 1030&#x2013;1040 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31019288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6857798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tada, M. et al. Matrin 3 is a component of neuronal cytoplasmic inclusions of motor neurons in sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Am. J. Pathol. 188, 507&#x2013;514 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29128563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quintero-Rivera, F. et al. MATR3 disruption in human and mouse associated with bicuspid aortic valve, aortic coarctation and patent ductus arteriosus. Hum. Mol. Genet. 24, 2375&#x2013;2389 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25574029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4380077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moloney, C. et al. Analysis of spinal and muscle pathology in transgenic mice overexpressing wild-type and ALS-linked mutant MATR3. Acta Neuropathol. Commun. 6, 137 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30563574</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6299607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, X. et al. A mutant MATR3 mouse model to explain multisystem proteinopathy. J. Pathol. 249, 182&#x2013;192 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31056746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barp, A. et al. The first French case of MATR3-related distal myopathy: clinical, radiological and histopathological characterization. Rev. Neurol. 174, 752&#x2013;755 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29628183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feit, H. et al. Vocal cord and pharyngeal weakness with autosomal dominant distal myopathy: clinical description and gene localization to 5q31. Am. J. Hum. Genet. 63, 1732&#x2013;1742 (1998).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9837826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">1377645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muller, T. J. et al. Phenotype of matrin-3-related distal myopathy in 16 German patients. Ann. Neurol. 76, 669&#x2013;680 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25154462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palmio, J. et al. Re-evaluation of the phenotype caused by the common MATR3 p.Ser85Cys mutation in a new family. J. Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatry 87, 448&#x2013;450 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25952333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamashita, S. et al. Clinicopathological features of the first Asian family having vocal cord and pharyngeal weakness with distal myopathy due to a MATR3 mutation. Neuropathol. Appl. Neurobiol. 41, 391&#x2013;398 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25185957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Senderek, J. et al. Autosomal-dominant distal myopathy associated with a recurrent missense mutation in the gene encoding the nuclear matrix protein, matrin 3. Am. J. Hum. Genet. 84, 511&#x2013;518 (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19344878</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2667977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kao, C. S. et al. Selective neuronal degeneration in MATR3 S85C knock-in mouse model of early-stage ALS. Nat. Commun. 11, 5304 (2020). While previous models of mutant MATR3 showed more myopathic changes, this recent knock-in model shows phenotypes more akin to ALS.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33082323</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7576598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chance, P. F. et al. Linkage of the gene for an autosomal dominant form of juvenile amyotrophic lateral sclerosis to chromosome 9q34. Am. J. Hum. Genet. 62, 633&#x2013;640 (1998).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9497266</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">1376963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, Y. Z. et al. DNA/RNA helicase gene mutations in a form of juvenile amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS4). Am. J. Hum. Genet. 74, 1128&#x2013;1135 (2004).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15106121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">1182077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bennett, C. L. &amp; La Spada, A. R. Senataxin, a novel helicase at the interface of RNA transcriptome regulation and neurobiology: from normal function to pathological roles in motor neuron disease and cerebellar degeneration. Adv. Neurobiol. 20, 265&#x2013;281 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29916023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bennett, C. L. et al. Senataxin mutations elicit motor neuron degeneration phenotypes and yield TDP-43 mislocalization in ALS4 mice and human patients. Acta Neuropathol. 136, 425&#x2013;443 (2018). This report describes the first mouse models of ALS4: a transgenic model of SETX-R2136H and a knock-in model of SETX-L389S1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29725819</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6098723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreira, M. C. &amp; Koenig, M. Ataxia with Oculomotor Apraxia Type 2 (eds Adam, M. P. et al.) (GeneReviews, 2004).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Narain, P. et al. Identification and characterization of novel and rare susceptible variants in Indian amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. Neurogenetics 20, 197&#x2013;208 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31432357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rabin, B. A. et al. Autosomal dominant juvenile amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain 122, 1539&#x2013;1550 (1999).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10430837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halawani, D. &amp; Latterich, M. p97: the cell&#x2019;s molecular purgatory? Mol. Cell 22, 713&#x2013;717 (2006).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16793541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamanaka, K., Sasagawa, Y. &amp; Ogura, T. Recent advances in p97/VCP/Cdc48 cellular functions. Biochim. Biophys. Acta 1823, 130&#x2013;137 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21781992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watts, G. D. et al. Inclusion body myopathy associated with Paget disease of bone and frontotemporal dementia is caused by mutant valosin-containing protein. Nat. Genet. 36, 377&#x2013;381 (2004).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15034582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson, J. O. et al. Exome sequencing reveals VCP mutations as a cause of familial ALS. Neuron 68, 857&#x2013;864 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21145000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3032425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeJesus-Hernandez, M. et al. Novel p.Ile151Val mutation in VCP in a patient of African American descent with sporadic ALS. Neurology 77, 1102&#x2013;1103 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21880997</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3174069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koppers, M. et al. VCP mutations in familial and sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurobiol. Aging 33, 837.e7&#x2013;837.e13 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tiloca, C. et al. Mutational analysis of VCP gene in familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurobiol. Aging 33, 630.e1&#x2013;630.e2 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abramzon, Y. et al. Valosin-containing protein (VCP) mutations in sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurobiol. Aging 33, 2231.e1&#x2013;2231.e6 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirano, M. et al. VCP gene analyses in Japanese patients with sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis identify a new mutation. Neurobiol. Aging 36, 1604.e1&#x2013;1604.e6 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Badadani, M. et al. VCP associated inclusion body myopathy and paget disease of bone knock-in mouse model exhibits tissue pathology typical of human disease. PLoS ONE5, e13183 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20957154</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2950155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian, A. et al. A progressive translational mouse model of human valosin-containing protein disease: the VCP(R155H/+) mouse. Muscle Nerve 47, 260&#x2013;270 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23169451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin, H. Z. et al. Slow development of ALS-like spinal cord pathology in mutant valosin-containing protein gene knock-in mice. Cell Death Dis. 3, e374 (2012). Mouse models of VCP have primarily been studied in relation to IBMPFD; this report reveals that these mouse models also show ALS-like pathology with age.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22898872</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3434652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian, A. et al. The homozygote VCP(R<sup>155</sup>H/R<sup>155</sup>H) mouse model exhibits accelerated human VCP-associated disease pathology. PLoS ONE 7, e46308 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23029473</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3460820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng, H. X. et al. Mutations in UBQLN2 cause dominant X-linked juvenile and adult-onset ALS and ALS/dementia. Nature 477, 211&#x2013;215 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21857683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3169705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ko, H. S., Uehara, T., Tsuruma, K. &amp; Nomura, Y. Ubiquilin interacts with ubiquitylated proteins and proteasome through its ubiquitin-associated and ubiquitin-like domains. FEBS Lett. 566, 110&#x2013;114 (2004).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15147878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hjerpe, R. et al. UBQLN2 mediates autophagy-independent protein aggregate clearance by the proteasome. Cell 166, 935&#x2013;949 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27477512</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5003816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorrie, G. H. et al. Dendritic spinopathy in transgenic mice expressing ALS/dementia-linked mutant UBQLN2. Proc. Natl Acad. Sci. USA 111, 14524&#x2013;14529 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25246588</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4209984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radzicki, D., Liu, E., Deng, H. X., Siddique, T. &amp; Martina, M. Early impairment of synaptic and intrinsic excitability in mice expressing ALS/dementia-linked mutant UBQLN2. Front. Cell Neurosci. 10, 216 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27703430</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5028382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceballos-Diaz, C. et al. Viral expression of ALS-linked ubiquilin-2 mutants causes inclusion pathology and behavioral deficits in mice. Mol. Neurodegener. 10, 25 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26152284</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4495639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le, N. T. et al. Motor neuron disease, TDP-43 pathology, and memory deficits in mice expressing ALS-FTD-linked UBQLN2 mutations. Proc. Natl Acad. Sci. USA 113, E7580&#x2013;E7589 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27834214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5127348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, Q. et al. Pathogenic Ubqln2 gains toxic properties to induce neuron death. Acta Neuropathol. 129, 417&#x2013;428 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25388785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, B., Wu, Q., Zhou, H., Huang, C. &amp; Xia, X. G. Increased Ubqln2 expression causes neuron death in transgenic rats. J. Neurochem. 139, 285&#x2013;293 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27456931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5117623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, T., Huang, B., Shi, X., Gao, L. &amp; Huang, C. Mutant UBQLN2(P497H) in motor neurons leads to ALS-like phenotypes and defective autophagy in rats. Acta Neuropathol. Commun. 6, 122 (2018). Using a conditional rat model of UBQLN2-P497H, the authors of this study found that the motor neuron degeneration they observe is cell-autonomous.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30409191</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6225656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toth, R. P. &amp; Atkin, J. D. Dysfunction of optineurin in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and glaucoma. Front. Immunol. 9, 1017 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29875767</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5974248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maruyama, H. et al. Mutations of optineurin in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nature 465, 223&#x2013;226 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20428114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Markovinovic, A. et al. Optineurin in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: multifunctional adaptor protein at the crossroads of different neuroprotective mechanisms. Prog. Neurobiol. 154, 1&#x2013;20 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28456633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minegishi, Y., Nakayama, M., Iejima, D., Kawase, K. &amp; Iwata, T. Significance of optineurin mutations in glaucoma and other diseases. Prog. Retin. Eye Res. 55, 149&#x2013;181 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27693724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pottier, C. et al. Identification of compound heterozygous variants in OPTN in an ALS-FTD patient from the CReATe consortium: a case report. Amyotroph. Lateral Scler. Frontotemporal Degener. 19, 469&#x2013;471 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29558868</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6116528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tumer, Z. et al. Novel heterozygous nonsense mutation of the OPTN gene segregating in a Danish family with ALS. Neurobiol. Aging 33, 208.e1&#x2013;208.e5 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weishaupt, J. H. et al. A novel optineurin truncating mutation and three glaucoma-associated missense variants in patients with familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in Germany. Neurobiol. Aging 34, 1516.e9&#x2013;1516.e15 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldstein, O. et al. OPTN 691_692insAG is a founder mutation causing recessive ALS and increased risk in heterozygotes. Neurology 86, 446&#x2013;453 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26740678</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4773945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cirulli, E. T. et al. Exome sequencing in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis identifies risk genes and pathways. Science 347, 1436&#x2013;1441 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25700176</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4437632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Z. et al. ALS-associated E478G mutation in human OPTN (Optineurin) promotes inflammation and induces neuronal cell death. Front. Immunol. 9, 2647 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30519240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6251386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ito, Y. et al. RIPK1 mediates axonal degeneration by promoting inflammation and necroptosis in ALS. Science 353, 603&#x2013;608 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27493188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5444917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korac, J. et al. Ubiquitin-independent function of optineurin in autophagic clearance of protein aggregates. J. Cell Sci. 126, 580&#x2013;592 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23178947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paulus, J. D. &amp; Link, B. A. Loss of optineurin in vivo results in elevated cell death and alters axonal trafficking dynamics. PLoS ONE 9, e109922 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25329564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4199637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gleason, C. E., Ordureau, A., Gourlay, R., Arthur, J. S. C. &amp; Cohen, P. Polyubiquitin binding to optineurin is required for optimal activation of TANK-binding kinase 1 and production of interferon beta. J. Biol. Chem. 286, 35663&#x2013;35674 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21862579</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3195586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munitic, I. et al. Optineurin insufficiency impairs IRF3 but not NF-kappaB activation in immune cells. J. Immunol. 191, 6231&#x2013;6240 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24244017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurashige, T. et al. Optineurin defects cause TDP43-pathology with autophagic vacuolar formation. Neurobiol. Dis. 148, 105215 (2021). This recent Optn-knockout model showed TDP43 proteinopathy, supporting the hypothesis that ALS pathology could arise from a loss of optineurin function.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33296728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freischmidt, A. et al. Haploinsufficiency of TBK1 causes familial ALS and fronto-temporal dementia. Nat. Neurosci. 18, 631&#x2013;636 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25803835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmad, L., Zhang, S. Y., Casanova, J. L. &amp; Sancho-Shimizu, V. Human TBK1: a gatekeeper of neuroinflammation. Trends Mol. Med. 22, 511&#x2013;527 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27211305</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4890605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsai, P. C. et al. Mutational analysis of TBK1 in Taiwanese patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurobiol. Aging 40, 191.e11&#x2013;191.e16 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pozzi, L. et al. TBK1 mutations in Italian patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: genetic and functional characterisation. J. Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatry 88, 869&#x2013;875 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28822984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, F. et al. Structural insights into the interaction and disease mechanism of neurodegenerative disease-associated optineurin and TBK1 proteins. Nat. Commun. 7, 12708 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27620379</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5027247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye, J. et al. Effects of ALS-associated TANK binding kinase 1 mutations on protein-protein interactions and kinase activity. Proc. Natl Acad. Sci. USA 116, 24517&#x2013;24526 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31748271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6900539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Majo, M. et al. ALS-associated missense and nonsense TBK1 mutations can both cause loss of kinase function. Neurobiol. Aging 71, 266.e1&#x2013;266.e10 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minegishi, Y. et al. Enhanced optineurin E50K-TBK1 interaction evokes protein insolubility and initiates familial primary open-angle glaucoma. Hum. Mol. Genet. 22, 3559&#x2013;3567 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23669351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonnard, M. et al. Deficiency of T2K leads to apoptotic liver degeneration and impaired NF-kappaB-dependent gene transcription. EMBO J. 19, 4976&#x2013;4985 (2000).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10990461</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">314216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brenner, D. et al. Heterozygous Tbk1 loss has opposing effects in early and late stages of ALS in mice. J. Exp. Med. 216, 267&#x2013;278 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30635357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6363427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, D. et al. TBK1 suppresses RIPK1-driven apoptosis and inflammation during development and in aging. Cell 174, 1477&#x2013;1491.e19 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30146158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6128749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruno, C. et al. Haploinsufficiency of TANK-binding kinase 1 prepones age-associated neuroinflammatory changes without causing motor neuron degeneration in aged mice. Brain Commun. 2, fcaa133 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33005894</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7519725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duan, W. et al. Deletion of Tbk1 disrupts autophagy and reproduces behavioral and locomotor symptoms of FTD-ALS in mice. Aging 11, 2457&#x2013;2476 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31039129</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6519994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerbino, V. et al. The loss of TBK1 kinase activity in motor neurons or in all cell types differentially impacts ALS disease progression in SOD1 mice. Neuron 106, 789&#x2013;805.e5 (2020). This interesting study not only introduced the first mouse models to express ALS-associated mutations in TBK1 but also found that loss of TBK1 activity can have differential effects on ALS progression due to its varying roles in different cell types.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32220666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui, R., Tuo, M., Li, P. &amp; Zhou, C. Association between TBK1 mutations and risk of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis/frontotemporal dementia spectrum: a meta-analysis. Neurol. Sci. 39, 811&#x2013;820 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29349657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pottier, C. et al. Whole-genome sequencing reveals important role for TBK1 and OPTN mutations in frontotemporal lobar degeneration without motor neuron disease. Acta Neuropathol. 130, 77&#x2013;92 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25943890</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4470809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lattante, S. et al. Coexistence of variants in TBK1 and in other ALS-related genes elucidates an oligogenic model of pathogenesis in sporadic ALS. Neurobiol. Aging 84, 239.e9&#x2013;239.e14 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sieverding, K. et al. Hemizygous deletion of Tbk1 worsens neuromuscular junction pathology in TDP-43(G298S) transgenic mice. Exp. Neurol. 335, 113496 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33038415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geng, J. et al. Regulation of RIPK1 activation by TAK1-mediated phosphorylation dictates apoptosis and necroptosis. Nat. Commun. 8, 359 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28842570</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5572456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fecto, F. et al. SQSTM1 mutations in familial and sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Arch. Neurol. 68, 1440&#x2013;1446 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22084127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yilmaz, R. et al. SQSTM1/p62 variants in 486 patients with familial ALS from Germany and Sweden. Neurobiol. Aging 87, 139.e9&#x2013;139.e15 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rubino, E. et al. SQSTM1 mutations in frontotemporal lobar degeneration and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology 79, 1556&#x2013;1562 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22972638</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3655323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirano, M. et al. Mutations in the gene encoding p62 in Japanese patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology 80, 458&#x2013;463 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23303844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, Y. et al. SQSTM1 mutations in Han Chinese populations with sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurobiol. Aging 35, 726.e7&#x2013;726.e9 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, Y. et al. Six SQSTM1 mutations in a Chinese amyotrophic lateral sclerosis cohort. Amyotroph. Lateral Scler. Frontotemporal Degener. 16, 378&#x2013;384 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25708934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun, L. et al. Identification of a novel hemizygous SQSTM1 nonsense mutation in atypical behavioral variant frontotemporal dementia. Front. Aging Neurosci. 10, 26 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29467647</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5808128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dols-Icardo, O. et al. Analysis of known amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal dementia genes reveals a substantial genetic burden in patients manifesting both diseases not carrying the C9orf72 expansion mutation. J. Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatry 89, 162&#x2013;168 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28889094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borghero, G. et al. TBK1 is associated with ALS and ALS-FTD in Sardinian patients. Neurobiol. Aging 43, 180.e1&#x2013;180.e5 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mizuno, Y. et al. Immunoreactivities of p62, an ubiqutin-binding protein, in the spinal anterior horn cells of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J. Neurol. Sci. 249, 13&#x2013;18 (2006).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16820172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>King, A., Maekawa, S., Bodi, I., Troakes, C. &amp; Al-Sarraj, S. Ubiquitinated, p62 immunopositive cerebellar cortical neuronal inclusions are evident across the spectrum of TDP-43 proteinopathies but are only rarely additionally immunopositive for phosphorylation-dependent TDP-43. Neuropathology 31, 239&#x2013;249 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21118398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rea, S. L., Majcher, V., Searle, M. S. &amp; Layfield, R. SQSTM1 mutations &#x2014; bridging Paget disease of bone and ALS/FTLD. Exp. Cell Res. 325, 27&#x2013;37 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24486447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teyssou, E. et al. Mutations in SQSTM1 encoding p62 in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: genetics and neuropathology. Acta Neuropathol. 125, 511&#x2013;522 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23417734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwok, C. T., Morris, A. &amp; de Belleroche, J. S. Sequestosome-1 (SQSTM1) sequence variants in ALS cases in the UK: prevalence and coexistence of SQSTM1 mutations in ALS kindred with PDB. Eur. J. Hum. Genet. 22, 492&#x2013;496 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23942205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le Ber, I. et al. SQSTM1 mutations in French patients with frontotemporal dementia or frontotemporal dementia with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. JAMA Neurol. 70, 1403&#x2013;1410 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24042580</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4199096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daroszewska, A. et al. A point mutation in the ubiquitin-associated domain of SQSMT1 is sufficient to cause a Paget&#x2019;s disease-like disorder in mice. Hum. Mol. Genet. 20, 2734&#x2013;2744 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21515589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramesh Babu, J. et al. Genetic inactivation of p62 leads to accumulation of hyperphosphorylated tau and neurodegeneration. J. Neurochem. 106, 107&#x2013;120 (2008).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18346206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishimura, A. L. et al. A novel locus for late onset amyotrophic lateral sclerosis/motor neurone disease variant at 20q13. J. Med. Genet. 41, 315&#x2013;320 (2004).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15060112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">1735732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishimura, A. L. et al. A mutation in the vesicle-trafficking protein VAPB causes late-onset spinal muscular atrophy and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Am. J. Hum. Genet. 75, 822&#x2013;831 (2004).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15372378</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">1182111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamemura, K. &amp; Chihara, T. Multiple functions of the ER-resident VAP and its extracellular role in neural development and disease. J. Biochem. 165, 391&#x2013;400 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30726905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi, J., Lua, S., Tong, J. S. &amp; Song, J. Elimination of the native structure and solubility of the hVAPB MSP domain by the Pro56Ser mutation that causes amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Biochemistry 49, 3887&#x2013;3897 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20377183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakamichi, S., Yamanaka, K., Suzuki, M., Watanabe, T. &amp; Kagiwada, S. Human VAPA and the yeast VAP Scs2p with an altered proline distribution can phenocopy amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-associated VAPB(P56S). Biochem. Biophys. Res. Commun. 404, 605&#x2013;609 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21144830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, S., Leal, S. S., Ben Halevy, D., Gomes, C. M. &amp; Lev, S. Structural requirements for VAP-B oligomerization and their implication in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-associated VAP-B(P56S) neurotoxicity. J. Biol. Chem. 285, 13839&#x2013;13849 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20207736</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2859547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papiani, G. et al. Restructured endoplasmic reticulum generated by mutant amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-linked VAPB is cleared by the proteasome. J. Cell Sci. 125, 3601&#x2013;3611 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22611258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fasana, E. et al. A VAPB mutant linked to amyotrophic lateral sclerosis generates a novel form of organized smooth endoplasmic reticulum. FASEB J. 24, 1419&#x2013;1430 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20008544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tudor, E. L. et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis mutant vesicle-associated membrane protein-associated protein-B transgenic mice develop TAR-DNA-binding protein-43 pathology. Neuroscience 167, 774&#x2013;785 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20188146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiu, L. et al. Widespread aggregation of mutant VAPB associated with ALS does not cause motor neuron degeneration or modulate mutant SOD1 aggregation and toxicity in mice. Mol. Neurodegener. 8, 1 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23281774</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3538568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuijpers, M. et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS)-associated VAPB-P56S inclusions represent an ER quality control compartment. Acta Neuropathol. Commun. 1, 24 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24252306</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3893532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aliaga, L. et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-related VAPB P56S mutation differentially affects the function and survival of corticospinal and spinal motor neurons. Hum. Mol. Genet. 22, 4293&#x2013;4305 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23771029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3792689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cadoni, M. P. L. et al. VAPB ER-aggregates, a possible new biomarker in ALS pathology. Cells 9, 164 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7017080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitne-Neto, M. et al. Downregulation of VAPB expression in motor neurons derived from induced pluripotent stem cells of ALS8 patients. Hum. Mol. Genet. 20, 3642&#x2013;3652 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21685205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3159551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kabashi, E. et al. Investigating the contribution of VAPB/ALS8 loss of function in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Hum. Mol. Genet. 22, 2350&#x2013;2360 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23446633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larroquette, F. et al. Vapb/Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis 8 knock-in mice display slowly progressive motor behavior defects accompanying ER stress and autophagic response. Hum. Mol. Genet. 24, 6515&#x2013;6529 (2015). The VAPB-P56S knock-in model described in this report is arguably the best model of VAPB-related ALS8 as it shows evidence of neurogenic atrophy and motor impairment, probably arising from a loss of VAPB activity at the ER.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26362257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4614709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boillee, S., Peschanski, M. &amp; Junier, M. P. The wobbler mouse: a neurodegeneration jigsaw puzzle. Mol. Neurobiol. 28, 65&#x2013;106 (2003).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14514986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmitt-John, T. et al. Mutation of Vps54 causes motor neuron disease and defective spermiogenesis in the wobbler mouse. Nat. Genet. 37, 1213&#x2013;1215 (2005). This paper identifies the gene mutated in wobbler mice as Vps54, connecting this classic ALS model to other models with defects in endolysosomal trafficking.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16244655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palmisano, R. et al. Endosomal accumulation of APP in wobbler motor neurons reflects impaired vesicle trafficking: implications for human motor neuron disease. BMC Neurosci. 12, 24 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21385376</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3058068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hentati, A. et al. Linkage of recessive familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis to chromosome 2q33-q35. Nat. Genet. 7, 425&#x2013;428 (1994).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7920663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hosler, B. A. et al. Refined mapping and characterization of the recessive familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis locus (ALS2) on chromosome 2q33. Neurogenetics 2, 34&#x2013;42 (1998).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9933298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hadano, S. et al. A gene encoding a putative GTPase regulator is mutated in familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis 2. Nat. Genet. 29, 166&#x2013;173 (2001).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11586298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, Y. et al. The gene encoding alsin, a protein with three guanine-nucleotide exchange factor domains, is mutated in a form of recessive amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat. Genet. 29, 160&#x2013;165 (2001).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11586297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Topp, J. D., Gray, N. W., Gerard, R. D. &amp; Horazdovsky, B. F. Alsin is a Rab5 and Rac1 guanine nucleotide exchange factor. J. Biol. Chem. 279, 24612&#x2013;24623 (2004).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15033976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hadano, S. et al. Mice deficient in the Rab5 guanine nucleotide exchange factor ALS2/alsin exhibit age-dependent neurological deficits and altered endosome trafficking. Hum. Mol. Genet. 15, 233&#x2013;250 (2006).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16321985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devon, R. S. et al. Als2-deficient mice exhibit disturbances in endosome trafficking associated with motor behavioral abnormalities. Proc. Natl Acad. Sci. USA 103, 9595&#x2013;9600 (2006).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16769894</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">1480452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Otomo, A. et al. ALS2, a novel guanine nucleotide exchange factor for the small GTPase Rab5, is implicated in endosomal dynamics. Hum. Mol. Genet. 12, 1671&#x2013;1687 (2003).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12837691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai, H. et al. ALS2/alsin knockout mice and motor neuron diseases. Neurodegener. Dis. 5, 359&#x2013;366 (2008).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18714162</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2556598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamanaka, K. et al. Unstable mutants in the peripheral endosomal membrane component ALS2 cause early-onset motor neuron disease. Proc. Natl Acad. Sci. USA 100, 16041&#x2013;16046 (2003).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14668431</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">307689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sato, K. et al. Altered oligomeric states in pathogenic ALS2 variants associated with juvenile motor neuron diseases cause loss of ALS2-mediated endosomal function. J. Biol. Chem. 293, 17135&#x2013;17153 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30224357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6222102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Otomo, A., Kunita, R., Suzuki-Utsunomiya, K., Ikeda, J. E. &amp; Hadano, S. Defective relocalization of ALS2/alsin missense mutants to Rac1-induced macropinosomes accounts for loss of their cellular function and leads to disturbed amphisome formation. FEBS Lett. 585, 730&#x2013;736 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21300063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panzeri, C. et al. The first ALS2 missense mutation associated with JPLS reveals new aspects of alsin biological function. Brain 129, 1710&#x2013;1719 (2006).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16670179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai, H. et al. Loss of ALS2 function is insufficient to trigger motor neuron degeneration in knock-out mice but predisposes neurons to oxidative stress. J. Neurosci. 25, 7567&#x2013;7574 (2005).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16107644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2364727</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamanaka, K., Miller, T. M., McAlonis-Downes, M., Chun, S. J. &amp; Cleveland, D. W. Progressive spinal axonal degeneration and slowness in ALS2-deficient mice. Ann. Neurol. 60, 95&#x2013;104 (2006). This paper describes one of multiple Als2 knockout mice that have been developed over the years but also points out that the reason these models show only mild phenotypes may be due to intrinsic differences in the architecture of mouse and human upper motor neurons.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16802286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Julien, J. P. &amp; Kriz, J. Transgenic mouse models of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Biochim. Biophys. Acta 1762, 1013&#x2013;1024 (2006).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16675207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gros-Louis, F. et al. Als2 mRNA splicing variants detected in KO mice rescue severe motor dysfunction phenotype in Als2 knock-down zebrafish. Hum. Mol. Genet. 17, 2691&#x2013;2702 (2008).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18558633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hadano, S. et al. Genetic background and gender effects on gross phenotypes in congenic lines of ALS2/alsin-deficient mice. Neurosci. Res. 68, 131&#x2013;136 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20558214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng, H. X. et al. Distal axonopathy in an alsin-deficient mouse model. Hum. Mol. Genet. 16, 2911&#x2013;2920 (2007).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17855450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gautam, M. et al. Absence of alsin function leads to corticospinal motor neuron vulnerability via novel disease mechanisms. Hum. Mol. Genet. 25, 1074&#x2013;1087 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26755825</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4764190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chow, C. Y. et al. Mutation of FIG4 causes neurodegeneration in the pale tremor mouse and patients with CMT4J. Nature 448, 68&#x2013;72 (2007). This paper links a spontaneous mouse mutant called the &#x2018;pale tremor&#x2019; mice to mutations in FIG4 and neurodegenerative disease; the phenotypes seen in this mouse would later inspire the same group to link this gene to ALS.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17572665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2271033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kunita, R. et al. Homo-oligomerization of ALS2 through its unique carboxyl-terminal regions is essential for the ALS2-associated Rab5 guanine nucleotide exchange activity and its regulatory function on endosome trafficking. J. Biol. Chem. 279, 38626&#x2013;38635 (2004).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15247254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skibinski, G. et al. Mutations in the endosomal ESCRTIII-complex subunit CHMP2B in frontotemporal dementia. Nat. Genet. 37, 806&#x2013;808 (2005).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16041373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferguson, C. J. et al. Neuronal expression of Fig4 is both necessary and sufficient to prevent spongiform neurodegeneration. Hum. Mol. Genet. 21, 3525&#x2013;3534 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22581779</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3406753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chow, C. Y. et al. Deleterious variants of FIG4, a phosphoinositide phosphatase, in patients with ALS. Am. J. Hum. Genet. 84, 85&#x2013;88 (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19118816</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2668033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lenk, G. M. et al. Pathogenic mechanism of the FIG4 mutation responsible for Charcot-Marie-Tooth disease CMT4J. PLoS Genet. 7, e1002104 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21655088</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3107197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orlacchio, A. et al. SPATACSIN mutations cause autosomal recessive juvenile amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain 133, 591&#x2013;598 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20110243</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2822627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Denora, P. S. et al. Motor neuron degeneration in spastic paraplegia 11 mimics amyotrophic lateral sclerosis lesions. Brain 139, 1723&#x2013;1734 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27016404</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5839621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daoud, H. et al. Exome sequencing reveals SPG11 mutations causing juvenile ALS. Neurobiol. Aging 33, 839.e5&#x2013;839.e9 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang, J., Lee, S. &amp; Blackstone, C. Spastic paraplegia proteins spastizin and spatacsin mediate autophagic lysosome reformation. J. Clin. Invest. 124, 5249&#x2013;5262 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25365221</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4348974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varga, R. E. et al. In vivo evidence for lysosome depletion and impaired autophagic clearance in hereditary spastic paraplegia type SPG11. PLoS Genet. 11, e1005454 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26284655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4540459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boutry, M. et al. Loss of spatacsin impairs cholesterol trafficking and calcium homeostasis. Commun. Biol. 2, 380 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31637311</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6797781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boutry, M. et al. Inhibition of lysosome membrane recycling causes accumulation of gangliosides that contribute to neurodegeneration. Cell Rep. 23, 3813&#x2013;3826 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29949766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Branchu, J. et al. Loss of spatacsin function alters lysosomal lipid clearance leading to upper and lower motor neuron degeneration. Neurobiol. Dis. 102, 21&#x2013;37 (2017). Of the different Spg11-knockout models generated, this model showed phenotypes reminiscent of both HSP and ALS.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28237315</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5391847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, C. H. et al. Mutations in the profilin 1 gene cause familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nature 488, 499&#x2013;503 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22801503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3575525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alkam, D., Feldman, E. Z., Singh, A. &amp; Kiaei, M. Profilin1 biology and its mutation, actin(g) in disease. Cell Mol. Life Sci. 74, 967&#x2013;981 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27669692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boopathy, S. et al. Structural basis for mutation-induced destabilization of profilin 1 in ALS. Proc. Natl Acad. Sci. USA 112, 7984&#x2013;7989 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26056300</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4491777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nekouei, M. et al. Changes in biophysical characteristics of PFN1 due to mutation causing amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Metab. Brain Dis. 33, 1975&#x2013;1984 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30203378</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6230493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiaei, M. et al. ALS-causing mutations in profilin-1 alter its conformational dynamics: a computational approach to explain propensity for aggregation. Sci. Rep. 8, 13102 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30166578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6117255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith, B. N. et al. Novel mutations support a role for Profilin 1 in the pathogenesis of ALS. Neurobiol. Aging 36, 1602.e17&#x2013;1602.e27 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanaka, Y. &amp; Hasegawa, M. Profilin 1 mutants form aggregates that induce accumulation of prion-like TDP-43. Prion 10, 283&#x2013;289 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27432186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5082967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Del Poggetto, E. et al. Stability of an aggregation-prone partially folded state of human profilin-1 correlates with aggregation propensity. J. Biol. Chem. 293, 10303&#x2013;10313 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29760185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6028969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fil, D. et al. Mutant Profilin1 transgenic mice recapitulate cardinal features of motor neuron disease. Hum. Mol. Genet. 26, 686&#x2013;701 (2017). While not the first transgenic mutant PFN1 model to show ALS-like phenotypes, this model also reported TDP43 proteinopathy and argued that these phenotypes arise via a gain-of-function mechanism.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28040732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, C. et al. Mutant PFN1 causes ALS phenotypes and progressive motor neuron degeneration in mice by a gain of toxicity. Proc. Natl Acad. Sci. USA 113, E6209&#x2013;E6218 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27681617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5068285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brettle, M. et al. Developmental expression of mutant PFN1 in motor neurons impacts neuronal growth and motor performance of young and adult mice. Front. Mol. Neurosci. 12, 231 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31611772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6776973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tovar, Y. R. L. B., Zepeda, A. &amp; Tapia, R. Vascular endothelial growth factor prevents paralysis and motoneuron death in a rat model of excitotoxic spinal cord neurodegeneration. J. Neuropathol. Exp. Neurol. 66, 913&#x2013;922 (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Saif, A., Al-Mohanna, F. &amp; Bohlega, S. A mutation in sigma-1 receptor causes juvenile amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann. Neurol. 70, 913&#x2013;919 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21842496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, H. J. et al. Mutations in UBQLN2 and SIGMAR1 genes are rare in Korean patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurobiol. Aging 35, 1957.e7&#x2013;1957.e8 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ullah, M. I. et al. In silico analysis of SIGMAR1 variant (rs4879809) segregating in a consanguineous Pakistani family showing amyotrophic lateral sclerosis without frontotemporal lobar dementia. Neurogenetics 16, 299&#x2013;306 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26205306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayashi, T. &amp; Su, T. P. Sigma-1 receptor chaperones at the ER-mitochondrion interface regulate Ca<sup>2+</sup> signaling and cell survival. Cell 131, 596&#x2013;610 (2007).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17981125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tagashira, H., Shinoda, Y., Shioda, N. &amp; Fukunaga, K. Methyl pyruvate rescues mitochondrial damage caused by SIGMAR1 mutation related to amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Biochim. Biophys. Acta 1840, 3320&#x2013;3334 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25175561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dreser, A. et al. The ALS-linked E102Q mutation in Sigma receptor-1 leads to ER stress-mediated defects in protein homeostasis and dysregulation of RNA-binding proteins. Cell Death Differ. 24, 1655&#x2013;1671 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28622300</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5596426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prause, J. et al. Altered localization, abnormal modification and loss of function of Sigma receptor-1 in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Hum. Mol. Genet. 22, 1581&#x2013;1600 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23314020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryskamp, D. A., Korban, S., Zhemkov, V., Kraskovskaya, N. &amp; Bezprozvanny, I. Neuronal Sigma-1 receptors: signaling functions and protective roles in neurodegenerative diseases. Front. Neurosci. 13, 862 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31551669</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6736580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weng, T. Y., Tsai, S. A. &amp; Su, T. P. Roles of sigma-1 receptors on mitochondrial functions relevant to neurodegenerative diseases. J. Biomed. Sci. 24, 74 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28917260</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5603014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernard-Marissal, N., Medard, J. J., Azzedine, H. &amp; Chrast, R. Dysfunction in endoplasmic reticulum-mitochondria crosstalk underlies SIGMAR1 loss of function mediated motor neuron degeneration. Brain 138, 875&#x2013;890 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25678561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Penas, C. et al. Sigma receptor agonist 2-(4-morpholinethyl)1 phenylcyclohexanecarboxylate (Pre084) increases GDNF and BiP expression and promotes neuroprotection after root avulsion injury. J. Neurotrauma 28, 831&#x2013;840 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21332255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goyagi, T. et al. Potent sigma 1-receptor ligand 4-phenyl-1-(4-phenylbutyl) piperidine provides ischemic neuroprotection without altering dopamine accumulation in vivo in rats. Anesth. Analg. 96, 532&#x2013;538 (2003).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12538208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guzman-Lenis, M. S., Navarro, X. &amp; Casas, C. Selective sigma receptor agonist 2-(4-morpholinethyl)1-phenylcyclohexanecarboxylate (PRE084) promotes neuroprotection and neurite elongation through protein kinase C (PKC) signaling on motoneurons. Neuroscience 162, 31&#x2013;38 (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19345724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mancuso, R. et al. Sigma-1R agonist improves motor function and motoneuron survival in ALS mice. Neurotherapeutics 9, 814&#x2013;826 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22935988</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3480575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peviani, M. et al. Neuroprotective effects of the Sigma-1 receptor (S1R) agonist PRE-084, in a mouse model of motor neuron disease not linked to SOD1 mutation. Neurobiol. Dis. 62, 218&#x2013;232 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24141020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ono, Y. et al. SA4503, a sigma-1 receptor agonist, suppresses motor neuron damage in in vitro and in vivo amyotrophic lateral sclerosis models. Neurosci. Lett. 559, 174&#x2013;178 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24334165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ionescu, A. et al. Targeting the sigma-1 receptor via pridopidine ameliorates central features of ALS pathology in a SOD1(G93A) model. Cell Death Dis. 10, 210 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30824685</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6397200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mavlyutov, T. A., Epstein, M. L., Andersen, K. A., Ziskind-Conhaim, L. &amp; Ruoho, A. E. The sigma-1 receptor is enriched in postsynaptic sites of C-terminals in mouse motoneurons: an anatomical and behavioral study. Neuroscience 167, 247&#x2013;255 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20167253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabino, V., Cottone, P., Parylak, S. L., Steardo, L. &amp; Zorrilla, E. P. Sigma-1 receptor knockout mice display a depressive-like phenotype. Behav. Brain Res. 198, 472&#x2013;476 (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19100292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chevallier, N., Keller, E. &amp; Maurice, T. Behavioural phenotyping of knockout mice for the sigma-1 (&#x3c3;1) chaperone protein revealed gender-related anxiety, depressive-like and memory alterations. J. Psychopharmacol. 25, 960&#x2013;975 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21555330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mavlyutov, T. A. et al. Lack of sigma-1 receptor exacerbates ALS progression in mice. Neuroscience 240, 129&#x2013;134 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23458708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watanabe, S. et al. Mitochondria-associated membrane collapse is a common pathomechanism in SIGMAR1- and SOD1-linked ALS. EMBO Mol. Med. 8, 1421&#x2013;1437 (2016). While a previous study had shown that knocking out Sigmar1 in an SOD1 mouse model could impact disease-related phenotypes, this study found that it may accelerate disease onset by impacting ER-mitochondrial connections at the MAM &#x2014; connecting this gene to other reports of MAM collapse in ALS.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27821430</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5167132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stoica, R. et al. ER-mitochondria associations are regulated by the VAPB-PTPIP51 interaction and are disrupted by ALS/FTD-associated TDP-43. Nat. Commun. 5, 3996 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24893131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakai, S., Watanabe, S., Komine, O., Sobue, A. &amp; Yamanaka, K. Novel reporters of mitochondria-associated membranes (MAM), MAMtrackers, demonstrate MAM disruption as a common pathological feature in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. FASEB J. 35, e21688 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34143516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell, J. et al. Familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis is associated with a mutation in D-amino acid oxidase. Proc. Natl Acad. Sci. USA 107, 7556&#x2013;7561 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20368421</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2867752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Padhi, A. K. &amp; Hazra, S. Insights into the role of d-amino acid oxidase mutations in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J. Cell Biochem. https://doi.org/10.1002/jcb.27529 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jcb.27529</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30206963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sasabe, J. et al. D-serine is a key determinant of glutamate toxicity in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. EMBO J. 26, 4149&#x2013;4159 (2007).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17762863</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2230675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, S. &amp; Barger, S. W. Induction of serine racemase by inflammatory stimuli is dependent on AP-1. Ann. NY Acad. Sci. 1035, 133&#x2013;146 (2004).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15681805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paul, P., Murphy, T., Oseni, Z., Sivalokanathan, S. &amp; de Belleroche, J. S. Pathogenic effects of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-linked mutation in D-amino acid oxidase are mediated by D-serine. Neurobiol. Aging 35, 876&#x2013;885 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24138986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sasabe, J., Suzuki, M., Imanishi, N. &amp; Aiso, S. Activity of D-amino acid oxidase is widespread in the human central nervous system. Front. Synaptic Neurosci. 6, 14 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24959138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4050652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almond, S. L. et al. Behavioral and biochemical characterization of a mutant mouse strain lacking D-amino acid oxidase activity and its implications for schizophrenia. Mol. Cell Neurosci. 32, 324&#x2013;334 (2006).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16843004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sasabe, J. et al. D-amino acid oxidase controls motoneuron degeneration through D-serine. Proc. Natl Acad. Sci. USA 109, 627&#x2013;632 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22203986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kondori, N. R. et al. Focus on the role of d-serine and d-amino acid oxidase in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis/motor neuron disease (ALS). Front. Mol. Biosci. 5, 8 (2018). This article reports the only model to express a known ALS-associated mutation in DAO; other studies have relied on a spontaneous mouse mutation in this gene that also imparts a loss of function.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29487852</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5816792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeJesus-Hernandez, M. et al. Expanded GGGGCC hexanucleotide repeat in noncoding region of C9ORF72 causes chromosome 9p-linked FTD and ALS. Neuron 72, 245&#x2013;256 (2011). While not a mouse modelling paper, this is the first report, together with Renton et al. (2011), to associate the hexanucleotide repeat expansion in C9ORF72 to ALS/FTD &#x2014; a major leap forward in the field of ALS research.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21944778</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3202986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renton, A. E. et al. A hexanucleotide repeat expansion in C9ORF72 is the cause of chromosome 9p21-linked ALS-FTD. Neuron 72, 257&#x2013;268 (2011). Together with DeJesus-Hernandez et al. (2011), the authors linked a repeat expansion in C9ORF72 to ALS and FTD &#x2014; this would later prove to be the most common known genetic lesion to cause both diseases.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21944779</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3200438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Majounie, E. et al. Frequency of the C9orf72 hexanucleotide repeat expansion in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal dementia: a cross-sectional study. Lancet Neurol. 11, 323&#x2013;330 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22406228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3322422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belzil, V. V. et al. Reduced C9orf72 gene expression in c9FTD/ALS is caused by histone trimethylation, an epigenetic event detectable in blood. Acta Neuropathol. 126, 895&#x2013;905 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24166615</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3830740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gijselinck, I. et al. A C9orf72 promoter repeat expansion in a Flanders-Belgian cohort with disorders of the frontotemporal lobar degeneration-amyotrophic lateral sclerosis spectrum: a gene identification study. Lancet Neurol. 11, 54&#x2013;65 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22154785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ciura, S. et al. Loss of function of C9orf72 causes motor deficits in a zebrafish model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann. Neurol. 74, 180&#x2013;187 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23720273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fratta, P. et al. Homozygosity for the C9orf72 GGGGCC repeat expansion in frontotemporal dementia. Acta Neuropathol. 126, 401&#x2013;409 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23818065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3753468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong, W. et al. Knock in of a hexanucleotide repeat expansion in the C9orf72 gene induces ALS in rats. Animal Model. Exp. Med. 3, 237&#x2013;244 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33024945</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7529333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lagier-Tourenne, C. et al. Targeted degradation of sense and antisense C9orf72 RNA foci as therapy for ALS and frontotemporal degeneration. Proc. Natl Acad. Sci. USA 110, E4530&#x2013;E4539 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24170860</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3839752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koppers, M. et al. C9orf72 ablation in mice does not cause motor neuron degeneration or motor deficits. Ann. Neurol. 78, 426&#x2013;438 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26044557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4744979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Rourke, J. G. et al. C9orf72 is required for proper macrophage and microglial function in mice. Science 351, 1324&#x2013;1329 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26989253</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5120541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atanasio, A. et al. C9orf72 ablation causes immune dysregulation characterized by leukocyte expansion, autoantibody production, and glomerulonephropathy in mice. Sci. Rep. 6, 23204 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26979938</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4793236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang, J. et al. Gain of toxicity from ALS/FTD-linked repeat expansions in C9ORF72 is alleviated by antisense oligonucleotides targeting GGGGCC-containing RNAs. Neuron 90, 535&#x2013;550 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27112497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4860075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burberry, A. et al. Loss-of-function mutations in the C9ORF72 mouse ortholog cause fatal autoimmune disease. Sci. Transl Med. 8, 347ra393 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ugolino, J. et al. Loss of C9orf72 enhances autophagic activity via deregulated mTOR and TFEB Signaling. PLoS Genet. 12, e1006443 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27875531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5119725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burberry, A. et al. C9orf72 suppresses systemic and neural inflammation induced by gut bacteria. Nature 582, 89&#x2013;94 (2020). In an elegant example of determination in research, this study solved the riddle about why different C9orf72-knockout models showed varying phenotypes: loss of C9orf72 impacts innate immunity in mice, making them sensitive to changes in their gut microbiome.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32483373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7416879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shao, Q. et al. C9orf72 deficiency promotes motor deficits of a C9ALS/FTD mouse model in a dose-dependent manner. Acta Neuropathol. Commun. 7, 32 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30832726</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6398253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu, Q. et al. Reduced C9ORF72 function exacerbates gain of toxicity from ALS/FTD-causing repeat expansion in C9orf72. Nat. Neurosci. 23, 615&#x2013;624 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32284607</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7384305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Todd, T. W. &amp; Petrucelli, L. Insights into the pathogenic mechanisms of Chromosome 9 open reading frame 72 (C9orf72) repeat expansions. J. Neurochem. 138, 145&#x2013;162 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27016280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zu, T. et al. RAN proteins and RNA foci from antisense transcripts in C9ORF72 ALS and frontotemporal dementia. Proc. Natl Acad. Sci. USA 110, E4968&#x2013;E4977 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24248382</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3870665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mizielinska, S. et al. C9orf72 frontotemporal lobar degeneration is characterised by frequent neuronal sense and antisense RNA foci. Acta Neuropathol. 126, 845&#x2013;857 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24170096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3830745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooper-Knock, J. et al. Antisense RNA foci in the motor neurons of C9ORF72-ALS patients are associated with TDP-43 proteinopathy. Acta Neuropathol. 130, 63&#x2013;75 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25943887</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4468790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ash, P. E. et al. Unconventional translation of C9ORF72 GGGGCC expansion generates insoluble polypeptides specific to c9FTD/ALS. Neuron 77, 639&#x2013;646 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23415312</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3593233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mori, K. et al. The C9orf72 GGGGCC repeat is translated into aggregating dipeptide-repeat proteins in FTLD/ALS. Science 339, 1335&#x2013;1338 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23393093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gendron, T. F. et al. Antisense transcripts of the expanded C9ORF72 hexanucleotide repeat form nuclear RNA foci and undergo repeat-associated non-ATG translation in c9FTD/ALS. Acta Neuropathol. 126, 829&#x2013;844 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24129584</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3830741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davidson, Y. S. et al. Brain distribution of dipeptide repeat proteins in frontotemporal lobar degeneration and motor neurone disease associated with expansions in C9ORF72. Acta Neuropathol. Commun. 2, 70 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24950788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4229740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackenzie, I. R. et al. Dipeptide repeat protein pathology in C9ORF72 mutation cases: clinico-pathological correlations. Acta Neuropathol. 126, 859&#x2013;879 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24096617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edbauer, D. &amp; Haass, C. An amyloid-like cascade hypothesis for C9orf72 ALS/FTD. Curr. Opin. Neurobiol. 36, 99&#x2013;106 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26555807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baborie, A. et al. Accumulation of dipeptide repeat proteins predates that of TDP-43 in frontotemporal lobar degeneration associated with hexanucleotide repeat expansions in C9ORF72 gene. Neuropathol. Appl. Neurobiol. 41, 601&#x2013;612 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25185840</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4934135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chew, J. et al. Neurodegeneration. C9ORF72 repeat expansions in mice cause TDP-43 pathology, neuronal loss, and behavioral deficits. Science 348, 1151&#x2013;1154 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25977373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4692360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chew, J. et al. Aberrant deposition of stress granule-resident proteins linked to C9orf72-associated TDP-43 proteinopathy. Mol. Neurodegener. 14, 9 (2019). Our laboratory previously developed a viral 66-repeat model of c9FTD/ALS and found that it recapitulated features of the human disease &#x2014; this report is a step forward, where we expressed an even longer 149-repeat construct, saw more robust ALS-like features and linked defects in stress granule dynamics to pTDP43 pathology.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30767771</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6377782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herranz-Martin, S. et al. Viral delivery of C9orf72 hexanucleotide repeat expansions in mice leads to repeat-length-dependent neuropathology and behavioural deficits. Dis. Model. Mech. 10, 859&#x2013;868 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28550099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5536911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riemslagh, F. W. et al. Inducible expression of human C9ORF72 36x G4C2 hexanucleotide repeats is sufficient to cause RAN translation and rapid muscular atrophy in mice. Dis. Model. Mech. 14, dmm044842 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7903916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Rourke, J. G. et al. C9orf72 BAC transgenic mice display typical pathologic features of ALS/FTD. Neuron 88, 892&#x2013;901 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26637796</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4672384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peters, O. M. et al. Human C9ORF72 hexanucleotide expansion reproduces RNA foci and dipeptide repeat proteins but not neurodegeneration in BAC transgenic mice. Neuron 88, 902&#x2013;909 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26637797</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4828340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi, Y. et al. Haploinsufficiency leads to neurodegeneration in C9ORF72 ALS/FTD human induced motor neurons. Nat. Med. 24, 313&#x2013;325 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29400714</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6112156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Y. et al. C9orf72 BAC mouse model with motor deficits and neurodegenerative features of ALS/FTD. Neuron 90, 521&#x2013;534 (2016). While multiple groups have developed BAC models of c9FTD/ALS, this paper documents the only one to show ALS-like motor deficits and degeneration.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27112499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pattamatta, A. et al. Repeat length increases disease penetrance and severity in C9orf72 ALS/FTD BAC transgenic mice. Hum. Mol. Genet. 29, 3900&#x2013;3918 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33378537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mordes, D. A. et al. Absence of survival and motor deficits in 500 repeat C9ORF72 BAC mice. Neuron 108, 775&#x2013;783.e4 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33022228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen, L. et al. Survival and motor phenotypes in FVB C9-500 ALS/FTD BAC transgenic mice reproduced by multiple labs. Neuron 108, 784&#x2013;796.e3 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33022226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8281452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Y. J. et al. Poly(GR) impairs protein translation and stress granule dynamics in C9orf72-associated frontotemporal dementia and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat. Med. 24, 1136&#x2013;1142 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29942091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6520050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook, C. N. et al. C9orf72 poly(GR) aggregation induces TDP-43 proteinopathy. Sci. Transl Med. 12, eabb3774 (2020). We and others have developed mouse models that express only poly(GR) but, in this study, we found that expression of a 200-repeat poly(GR) could induce the formation of TDP43 inclusions, linking this DPR to the development of TDP43 proteinopathy in c9FTD/ALS.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32878979</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7989020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi, S. Y. et al. C9ORF72-ALS/FTD-associated poly(GR) binds Atp5a1 and compromises mitochondrial function in vivo. Nat. Neurosci. 22, 851&#x2013;862 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31086314</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6800116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Y. J. et al. Heterochromatin anomalies and double-stranded RNA accumulation underlie C9orf72 poly(PR) toxicity. Science 363, eaav2606 (2019). This mouse model, like others, demonstrates the potent toxicity of poly(PR) in vivo and also links this toxicity to defects in heterochromatin and double-stranded RNA accumulation.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30765536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6524780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hao, Z. et al. Motor dysfunction and neurodegeneration in a C9orf72 mouse line expressing poly-PR. Nat. Commun. 10, 2906 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31266945</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6606620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>LaClair, K. D. et al. Congenic expression of poly-GA but not poly-PR in mice triggers selective neuron loss and interferon responses found in C9orf72 ALS. Acta Neuropathol. 140, 121&#x2013;142 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32562018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7360660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Y. J. et al. C9ORF72 poly(GA) aggregates sequester and impair HR23 and nucleocytoplasmic transport proteins. Nat. Neurosci. 19, 668&#x2013;677 (2016). Poly(GA) aggregates are the most abundant DPR pathology observed in c9FTD/ALS, but this DPR often appears to be only mildly toxic in lower model organisms &#x2014; this study verified that poly(GA) could induce toxicity in rodents, possibly by sequestering HR23 and nucleocytoplasmic transport factors.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26998601</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5138863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schludi, M. H. et al. Spinal poly-GA inclusions in a C9orf72 mouse model trigger motor deficits and inflammation without neuron loss. Acta Neuropathol. 134, 241&#x2013;254 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28409281</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5508040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khosravi, B. et al. Cell-to-cell transmission of C9orf72 poly-(Gly-Ala) triggers key features of ALS/FTD. EMBO J. 39, e102811 (2020). This paper found that poly(GA) could be transferred between cells and, in this way, it induced TDP43 pathology and other defects in neighbouring cells; inhibiting this transmission with anti-poly(GA) antibodies proved beneficial.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32175624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7156967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Todd, T. W. et al. Hexanucleotide repeat expansions in c9FTD/ALS and SCA36 confer selective patterns of neurodegeneration in vivo. Cell Rep. 31, 107616 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32375043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7480900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hawrot, J., Imhof, S. &amp; Wainger, B. J. Modeling cell-autonomous motor neuron phenotypes in ALS using iPSCs. Neurobiol. Dis. 134, 104680 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31759135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burkhardt, M. F. et al. A cellular model for sporadic ALS using patient-derived induced pluripotent stem cells. Mol. Cell Neurosci. 56, 355&#x2013;364 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23891805</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4772428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujimori, K. et al. Modeling sporadic ALS in iPSC-derived motor neurons identifies a potential therapeutic agent. Nat. Med. 24, 1579&#x2013;1589 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30127392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geser, F., Lee, V. M. &amp; Trojanowski, J. Q. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal lobar degeneration: a spectrum of TDP-43 proteinopathies. Neuropathology 30, 103&#x2013;112 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20102519</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3131978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Zee, J. et al. CHMP2B C-truncating mutations in frontotemporal lobar degeneration are associated with an aberrant endosomal phenotype in vitro. Hum. Mol. Genet. 17, 313&#x2013;322 (2008).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17956895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parkinson, N. et al. ALS phenotypes with mutations in CHMP2B (charged multivesicular body protein 2B). Neurology 67, 1074&#x2013;1077 (2006).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16807408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cox, L. E. et al. Mutations in CHMP2B in lower motor neuron predominant amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). PLoS ONE 5, e9872 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20352044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2844426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Blitterswijk, M. et al. Genetic overlap between apparently sporadic motor neuron diseases. PLoS ONE 7, e48983 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23155438</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3498376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Narain, P. et al. Targeted next-generation sequencing reveals novel and rare variants in Indian patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurobiol. Aging 71, 265.e9&#x2013;265.e14 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrari, R. et al. Novel missense mutation in charged multivesicular body protein 2B in a patient with frontotemporal dementia. Alzheimer Dis. Assoc. Disord. 24, 397&#x2013;401 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20592581</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2974047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghanim, M. et al. CHMP2B mutations are rare in French families with frontotemporal lobar degeneration. J. Neurol. 257, 2032&#x2013;2036 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20625756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piper, R. C. &amp; Luzio, J. P. Late endosomes: sorting and partitioning in multivesicular bodies. Traffic 2, 612&#x2013;621 (2001).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11555415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Y. et al. Patient iPSC-derived neurons for disease modeling of frontotemporal dementia with mutation in CHMP2B. Stem Cell Rep. 8, 648&#x2013;658 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han, J. H., Ryu, H. H., Jun, M. H., Jang, D. J. &amp; Lee, J. A. The functional analysis of the CHMP2B missense mutation associated with neurodegenerative diseases in the endo-lysosomal pathway. Biochem. Biophys. Res. Commun. 421, 544&#x2013;549 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22521643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blair, I. P. et al. CHMP2B mutations are not a common cause of familial or sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J. Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatry 79, 849&#x2013;850 (2008).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18270236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isaacs, A. M., Johannsen, P., Holm, I. &amp; Nielsen, J. E., FReJA Consortium. Frontotemporal dementia caused by CHMP2B mutations. Curr. Alzheimer Res. 8, 246&#x2013;251 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21222599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3182073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, J. A., Beigneux, A., Ahmad, S. T., Young, S. G. &amp; Gao, F. B. ESCRT-III dysfunction causes autophagosome accumulation and neurodegeneration. Curr. Biol. 17, 1561&#x2013;1567 (2007).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17683935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghazi-Noori, S. et al. Progressive neuronal inclusion formation and axonal degeneration in CHMP2B mutant transgenic mice. Brain 135, 819&#x2013;832 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22366797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clayton, E. L. et al. Early microgliosis precedes neuronal loss and behavioural impairment in mice with a frontotemporal dementia-causing CHMP2B mutation. Hum. Mol. Genet. 26, 873&#x2013;887 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28093491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5409096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gascon, E. et al. Alterations in microRNA-124 and AMPA receptors contribute to social behavioral deficits in frontotemporal dementia. Nat. Med. 20, 1444&#x2013;1451 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25401692</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4257887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vernay, A. et al. A transgenic mouse expressing CHMP2Bintron5 mutant in neurons develops histological and behavioural features of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal dementia. Hum. Mol. Genet. 25, 3341&#x2013;3360 (2016). Mutations in CHMP2B are often associated with FTD, but this transgenic mouse model also saw evidence of ALS-like phenotypes.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27329763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bannwarth, S. et al. A mitochondrial origin for frontotemporal dementia and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis through CHCHD10 involvement. Brain 137, 2329&#x2013;2345 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24934289</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4107737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Genin, E. C. et al. Loss of MICOS complex integrity and mitochondrial damage, but not TDP-43 mitochondrial localisation, are likely associated with severity of CHCHD10-related diseases. Neurobiol. Dis. 119, 159&#x2013;171 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30092269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7015038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ait-El-Mkadem Saadi, S. et al. CHCHD10-Related Disorders (eds Adam, M. P. et al.) (GeneReviews, 2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Rheenen, W., Diekstra, F. P., van den Berg, L. H. &amp; Veldink, J. H. Are CHCHD10 mutations indeed associated with familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis? Brain 137, e313 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25348631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Project MinE ALS Sequencing Consortium. CHCHD10 variants in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: where is the evidence? Ann. Neurol. 84, 110&#x2013;116 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6553489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burstein, S. R. et al. In vitro and in vivo studies of the ALS-FTLD protein CHCHD10 reveal novel mitochondrial topology and protein interactions. Hum. Mol. Genet. 27, 160&#x2013;177 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29112723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson, C. J. et al. ALS/FTD mutant CHCHD10 mice reveal a tissue-specific toxic gain-of-function and mitochondrial stress response. Acta Neuropathol. 138, 103&#x2013;121 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30877432</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6571048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Genin, E. C. et al. Mitochondrial defect in muscle precedes neuromuscular junction degeneration and motor neuron death in CHCHD10(S59L/+) mouse. Acta Neuropathol. 138, 123&#x2013;145 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30874923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan, E. B. et al. Early death of ALS-linked CHCHD10-R15L transgenic mice with central nervous system, skeletal muscle, and cardiac pathology. iScience 24, 102061 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33659869</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7890413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao, Y. et al. Loss of mitochondrial protein CHCHD10 in skeletal muscle causes neuromuscular junction impairment. Hum. Mol. Genet. 29, 1784&#x2013;1796 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31261376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hideyama, T. et al. Induced loss of ADAR2 engenders slow death of motor neurons from Q/R site-unedited GluR2. J. Neurosci. 30, 11917&#x2013;11925 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20826656</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6633551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beaulieu, J. M., Nguyen, M. D. &amp; Julien, J. P. Late onset of motor neurons in mice overexpressing wild-type peripherin. J. Cell Biol. 147, 531&#x2013;544 (1999).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15132161</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2151189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beaulieu, J. M., Jacomy, H. &amp; Julien, J. P. Formation of intermediate filament protein aggregates with disparate effects in two transgenic mouse models lacking the neurofilament light subunit. J. Neurosci. 20, 5321&#x2013;5328 (2000).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10884316</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6772336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ash, P. E. A. et al. Heavy metal neurotoxicants induce ALS-linked TDP-43 pathology. Toxicol. Sci. 167, 105&#x2013;115 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30371865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maya, S., Prakash, T. &amp; Goli, D. Evaluation of neuroprotective effects of wedelolactone and gallic acid on aluminium-induced neurodegeneration: relevance to sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Eur. J. Pharmacol. 835, 41&#x2013;51 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30075221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nampoothiri, M. et al. Modulatory role of simvastatin against aluminium chloride-induced behavioural and biochemical changes in rats. Behav. Neurol. 2015, 210169 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25802481</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4329790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaw, C. A. &amp; Petrik, M. S. Aluminum hydroxide injections lead to motor deficits and motor neuron degeneration. J. Inorg. Biochem. 103, 1555&#x2013;1562 (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19740540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2819810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Munck, E. et al. beta-N-methylamino-l-alanine causes neurological and pathological phenotypes mimicking amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS): the first step towards an experimental model for sporadic ALS. Env. Toxicol. Pharmacol. 36, 243&#x2013;255 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin, H. Z. et al. Intrathecal infusion of BMAA induces selective motor neuron damage and astrogliosis in the ventral horn of the spinal cord. Exp. Neurol. 261, 1&#x2013;9 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24918341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Munck, E. et al. Morphometric and neurochemical alterations found in l-BMAA treated rats. Env. Toxicol. Pharmacol. 39, 1232&#x2013;1245 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian, K. W., Jiang, H., Wang, B. B., Zhang, F. &amp; Han, S. Intravenous injection of l-BMAA induces a rat model with comprehensive characteristics of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis/Parkinson-dementia complex. Toxicol. Res. 5, 79&#x2013;96 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott, L. L. &amp; Downing, T. G. A single neonatal exposure to BMAA in a rat model produces neuropathology consistent with neurodegenerative diseases. Toxins 10, 22 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5793109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papapetropoulos, S. Is there a role for naturally occurring cyanobacterial toxins in neurodegeneration? The beta-N-methylamino-L-alanine (BMAA) paradigm. Neurochem. Int. 50, 998&#x2013;1003 (2007).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17296249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mishra, P. S. et al. Transmission of ALS pathogenesis by the cerebrospinal fluid. Acta Neuropathol. Commun. 8, 65 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32381112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7206749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muchnik, S., Losavio, A. &amp; De Lorenzo, S. Effect of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis serum on calcium channels related to spontaneous acetylcholine release. Clin. Neurophysiol. 113, 1066&#x2013;1071 (2002).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12088701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Obal, I. et al. Experimental motor neuron disease induced in mice with long-term repeated intraperitoneal injections of serum from ALS patients. Int. J. Mol. Sci. 20, 2573 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6566871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shanmukha, S., Narayanappa, G., Nalini, A., Alladi, P. A. &amp; Raju, T. R. Sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (SALS) - skeletal muscle response to cerebrospinal fluid from SALS patients in a rat model. Dis. Model Mech. 11, dmm031997 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29666144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5963857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ikebe, S. et al. Increase of deleted mitochondrial DNA in the striatum in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease and senescence. Biochem. Biophys. Res. Commun. 170, 1044&#x2013;1048 (1990).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2390073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sankaranarayani, R., Nalini, A., Rao Laxmi, T. &amp; Raju, T. R. Altered neuronal activities in the motor cortex with impaired motor performance in adult rats observed after infusion of cerebrospinal fluid from amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. Behav. Brain Res. 206, 109&#x2013;119 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19747511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>