<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35289393</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-0290</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>119</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Biotechnology and bioengineering</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Biotechnol Bioeng</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Tissue-engineered in vitro modeling of the impact of Schwann cells in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1938</StartPage><EndPage>1948</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1938-1948</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/bit.28083</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis (ALS) is a devastating neurodegenerative disease affecting upper and lower motor neurons (MNs). To investigate whether Schwann cells could be involved in the disease pathogenesis, we developed a tissue-engineered three-dimensional (3D)&#xa0;in vitro model that combined MNs cocultured with astrocytes and microglia seeded on top of a collagen sponge populated with epineurium fibroblasts to enable 3D axonal migration. C2C12 myoblasts were seeded underneath the sponge in the presence or absence of Schwann cells. To reproduce an ALS cellular microenvironment, MNs, astrocytes, and microglia were extracted from SOD1<sup>G93A</sup> mice recapitulating many aspects of the human disease. This 3D ALS in vitro model was compared with a 3D control made of cells isolated from SOD1<sup>WT</sup> mice. We showed that normal Schwann cells strongly enhanced MN axonal migration in the 3D control model but had no effect in the ALS model. However, ALS-derived Schwann cells isolated from SOD1<sup>G93A</sup> mice failed to significantly improve axonal migration in both models. These results suggest that a cell therapy using healthy Schwann cells may not be effective in promoting axonal regeneration in ALS. In addition, this 3D ALS model could be used to study the impact of other cell types on ALS by various combinations of normal and diseased cells.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Louit</LastName><ForeName>Aur&#xe9;lie</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>LOEX, Centre de recherche du CHU de Qu&#xe9;bec-Universit&#xe9; Laval, Qu&#xe9;bec City, Qu&#xe9;bec, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Beaudet</LastName><ForeName>Marie-Jos&#xe9;e</ForeName><Initials>MJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>LOEX, Centre de recherche du CHU de Qu&#xe9;bec-Universit&#xe9; Laval, Qu&#xe9;bec City, Qu&#xe9;bec, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gros-Louis</LastName><ForeName>Fran&#xe7;ois</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>LOEX, Centre de recherche du CHU de Qu&#xe9;bec-Universit&#xe9; Laval, Qu&#xe9;bec City, Qu&#xe9;bec, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgery, Faculty of Medicine, Universit&#xe9; Laval, Quebec City, Quebec, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Berthod</LastName><ForeName>Fran&#xe7;ois</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3580-0297</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>LOEX, Centre de recherche du CHU de Qu&#xe9;bec-Universit&#xe9; Laval, Qu&#xe9;bec City, Qu&#xe9;bec, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgery, Faculty of Medicine, Universit&#xe9; Laval, Quebec City, Quebec, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Biotechnol Bioeng</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7502021</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0006-3592</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 1.15.1.1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D013482">Superoxide Dismutase</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 1.15.1.1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000072105">Superoxide Dismutase-1</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004195" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Models, Animal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051379" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019636" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neurodegenerative Diseases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012583" MajorTopicYN="N">Schwann Cells</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013482" MajorTopicYN="N">Superoxide Dismutase</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000072105" MajorTopicYN="N">Superoxide Dismutase-1</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">astrocytes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">axonal migration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">microglia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">motor neurons</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neurites</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35289393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/bit.28083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Arbour, D., Tremblay, E., Martineau, E., Julien, J. P., &amp; Robitaille, R. (2015). Early and persistent abnormal decoding by glial cells at the neuromuscular junction in an ALS model. Journal of Neuroscience, 35(2), 688-706. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.1379-14.2015</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arbour, D., Vande Velde, C., &amp; Robitaille, R. (2017). New perspectives on amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: The role of glial cells at the neuromuscular junction. Journal of Physiology, 595(3), 647-661. https://doi.org/10.1113/JP270213</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beaudet, M. J., Yang, Q., Cadau, S., Blais, M., Bellenfant, S., Gros-Louis, F., &amp; Berthod, F. (2015). High yield extraction of pure spinal motor neurons, astrocytes and microglia from single embryo and adult mouse spinal cord. Scientific Reports, 5, 16763. https://doi.org/10.1038/srep16763</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berthod, F., Germain, L., Guignard, R., Lethias, C., Garrone, R., Damour, O., &amp; Auger, F. A. (1997). Differential expression of collagen XII and XIV in human skin and in reconstructed skin. Journal of Investigative Dermatology, 108, 737-742.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berthod, F., Germain, L., Tremblay, N., &amp; Auger, F. A. (2006). Extracellular matrix deposition by fibroblasts is necessary to promote capillary-like tube formation in vitro. Journal of Cellular Physiology, 207(2), 491-498.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berthod, F., &amp; Gros-Louis, F. (2012). In vivo and in vitro models to study amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. In M. Maurer (Ed.), Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (pp. 81-124). InTech.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berthod, F., Hayek, D., Damour, O., &amp; Collombel, C. (1993). Collagen synthesis by fibroblasts cultured within a collagen sponge. Biomaterials, 14, 749-754.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berthod, F., Saintigny, G., Chretien, F., Hayek, D., Collombel, C., &amp; Damour, O. (1994). Optimization of thickness, pore size and mechanical properties of a biomaterial designed for deep burn coverage. Clinical Materials, 15(4), 259-265. https://doi.org/10.1016/0267-6605(94)90055-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blais, M., Grenier, M., &amp; Berthod, F. (2009). Improvement of nerve regeneration in tissue-engineered skin enriched with Schwann cells. Journal of Investigative Dermatology, 129(12), 2895-2900. https://doi.org/10.1038/jid.2009.159</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boillee, S., Vande Velde, C., &amp; Cleveland, D. W. (2006). ALS: A disease of motor neurons and their nonneuronal neighbors. Neuron, 52(1), 39-59. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2006.09.018</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bolivar, S., Navarro, X., &amp; Udina, E. (2020). Schwann cell role in selectivity of nerve regeneration. Cells, 9(9), 2131. https://doi.org/10.3390/cells9092131</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bucchia, M., Merwin, S. J., Re, D. B., &amp; Kariya, S. (2018). Limitations and challenges in modeling diseases involving spinal motor neuron degeneration in vitro. Frontiers in Cellular Neuroscience, 12, 61. https://doi.org/10.3389/fncel.2018.00061</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chandrasekaran, A., Avci, H. X., Leist, M., Kobolak, J., &amp; Dinnyes, A. (2016). Astrocyte differentiation of human pluripotent stem cells: New tools for neurological disorder research. Frontiers in Cellular Neuroscience, 10, 215. https://doi.org/10.3389/fncel.2016.00215</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, J., Ren, S., Duscher, D., Kang, Y., Liu, Y., Wang, C., &amp; Chen, Z. (2019). Exosomes from human adipose-derived stem cells promote sciatic nerve regeneration via optimizing Schwann cell function. Journal of Cellular Physiology, 234(12), 23097-23110. https://doi.org/10.1002/jcp.28873</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, K., Northington, F. J., &amp; Martin, L. J. (2010). Inducible nitric oxide synthase is present in motor neuron mitochondria and Schwann cells and contributes to disease mechanisms in ALS mice. Brain Structure and Function, 214(2-3), 219-234. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00429-009-0226-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, S. W., Hung, Y. S., Fuh, J. L., Chen, N. J., Chu, Y. S., Chen, S. C., &amp; Wong, Y. H. (2021). Efficient conversion of human induced pluripotent stem cells into microglia by defined transcription factors. Stem Cell Reports, 16(5), 1363-1380. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.stemcr.2021.03.010</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ching, R. C., Wiberg, M., &amp; Kingham, P. J. (2018). Schwann cell-like differentiated adipose stem cells promote neurite outgrowth via secreted exosomes and RNA transfer. Stem Cell Research &amp; Therapy, 9(1), 266. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13287-018-1017-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chio, A., Logroscino, G., Traynor, B. J., Collins, J., Simeone, J. C., Goldstein, L. A., &amp; White, L. A. (2013). Global epidemiology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A systematic review of the published literature. Neuroepidemiology, 41(2), 118-130. https://doi.org/10.1159/000351153</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clement, A. M., Nguyen, M. D., Roberts, E. A., Garcia, M. L., Boillee, S., Rule, M., &amp; Cleveland, D. W. (2003). Wild-type nonneuronal cells extend survival of SOD1 mutant motor neurons in ALS mice. Science, 302(5642), 113-117. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.1086071</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng, B., Lv, W., Duan, W., Liu, Y., Li, Z., Ma, Y., &amp; Li, C. (2018). Progressive degeneration and inhibition of peripheral nerve regeneration in the SOD1-G93A mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Cellular Physiology and Biochemistry, 46(6), 2358-2372. https://doi.org/10.1159/000489627</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dumont, N. A., Bentzinger, C. F., Sincennes, M. C., &amp; Rudnicki, M. A. (2015). Satellite cells and skeletal muscle regeneration. Comprehensive Physiology, 5(3), 1027-1059. https://doi.org/10.1002/cphy.c140068</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faye, P. A., Vedrenne, N., Miressi, F., Rassat, M., Romanenko, S., Richard, L., &amp; Lia, A. S. (2020). Optimized protocol to generate spinal motor neuron cells from induced pluripotent stem cells from Charcot Marie Tooth patients. Brain Sciences, 10(7), 407. https://doi.org/10.3390/brainsci10070407</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filipi, T., Hermanova, Z., Tureckova, J., Vanatko, O., &amp; Anderova, A. M. (2020). Glial cells-The strategic targets in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis treatment. Journal of Clinical Medicine, 9(1), 261. https://doi.org/10.3390/jcm9010261</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghasemi, M., &amp; Brown, R. H. Jr. (2018). Genetics of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Cold Spring Harbor Perspectives in Medicine, 8(5), a024125. https://doi.org/10.1101/cshperspect.a024125</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gingras, M., Beaulieu, M. M., Gagnon, V., Durham, H. D., &amp; Berthod, F. (2008). In vitro study of axonal migration and myelination of motor neurons in a three-dimensional tissue-engineered model. Glia, 56(3), 354-364.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gingras, M., Bergeron, J., Dery, J., Durham, H. D., &amp; Berthod, F. (2003). In vitro development of a tissue-engineered model of peripheral nerve regeneration to study neurite growth. FASEB Journal, 17(14), 2124-2126.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gurney, M. E., Pu, H., Chiu, A. Y., Dal Canto, M. C., Polchow, C. Y., Alexander, D. D., Caliendo, J., Hentati, A., Kwon, Y. W., Deng, H. X., Chen, W., Zhai, P., Sufit, R. L., &amp; Siddique, T. (1994). Motor neuron degeneration in mice that express a human Cu, Zn superoxide dismutase mutation. Science, 264(5166), 1772-1775. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.8209258</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hyung, S., Im, S. K., Lee, B. Y., Shin, J., Park, J. C., Lee, C., &amp; Hur, E. M. (2019). Dedifferentiated Schwann cells secrete progranulin that enhances the survival and axon growth of motor neurons. Glia, 67(2), 360-375. https://doi.org/10.1002/glia.23547</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaur, S. J., McKeown, S. R., &amp; Rashid, S. (2016). Mutant SOD1 mediated pathogenesis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Gene, 577(2), 109-118. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.gene.2015.11.049</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiernan, M. C., Vucic, S., Cheah, B. C., Turner, M. R., Eisen, A., Hardiman, O., &amp; Zoing, M. C. (2011). Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet, 377(9769), 942-955. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0140-6736(10)61156-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lino, M. M., Schneider, C., &amp; Caroni, P. (2002). Accumulation of SOD1 mutants in postnatal motoneurons does not cause motoneuron pathology or motoneuron disease. Journal of Neuroscience, 22(12), 4825-4832.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lobsiger, C. S., Boillee, S., McAlonis-Downes, M., Khan, A. M., Feltri, M. L., Yamanaka, K., &amp; Cleveland, D. W. (2009). Schwann cells expressing dismutase active mutant SOD1 unexpectedly slow disease progression in ALS mice. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 106(11), 4465-4470. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.0813339106</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marshall, K. L., &amp; Farah, M. H. (2021). Axonal regeneration and sprouting as a potential therapeutic target for nervous system disorders. Neural Regeneration Research, 16(10), 1901-1910. https://doi.org/10.4103/1673-5374.308077</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martineau, E., Arbour, D., Vallee, J., &amp; Robitaille, R. (2020). Properties of glial cell at the neuromuscular junction are incompatible with synaptic repair in the SOD1(G37R) ALS mouse model. Journal of Neuroscience, 40(40), 7759-7777. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.1748-18.2020</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mejzini, R., Flynn, L. L., Pitout, I. L., Fletcher, S., Wilton, S. D., &amp; Akkari, P. A. (2019). ALS genetics, mechanisms, and therapeutics: Where are we now? Frontiers in Neuroscience, 13, 1310. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnins.2019.01310</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakamura, T., Yokoyama, U., Kanaya, T., Ueno, T., Yoda, T., Ishibe, A., Hidaka, Y., Umemura, M., Takayama, T., Kaneko, M., Miyagawa, S., Sawa, Y., Endo, I., &amp; Ishikawa, Y. (2021). Multilayered human skeletal muscle myoblast sheets promote the healing process after colonic anastomosis in rats. Cell Transplantation, 30, 1-15. https://doi.org/10.1177/09636897211009559</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakamura-Shindo, K., Sakai, K., Shimizu, A., Ishida, C., &amp; Yamada, M. (2020). Accumulation of phosphorylated TDP-43 in the cytoplasm of Schwann cells in a case of sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuropathology, 40(6), 606-610. https://doi.org/10.1111/neup.12673</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nizzardo, M., Simone, C., Falcone, M., Locatelli, F., Riboldi, G., Comi, G. P., &amp; Corti, S. (2010). Human motor neuron generation from embryonic stem cells and induced pluripotent stem cells. Cellular and Molecular Life Sciences, 67(22), 3837-3847. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00018-010-0463-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osaki, T., Shin, Y., Sivathanu, V., Campisi, M., &amp; Kamm, R. D. (2018). In vitro microfluidic models for neurodegenerative disorders. Advanced Healthcare Materials, 7(2), 1700489. https://doi.org/10.1002/adhm.201700489</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pramatarova, A., Laganiere, J., Roussel, J., Brisebois, K., &amp; Rouleau, G. A. (2001). Neuron-specific expression of mutant superoxide dismutase 1 in transgenic mice does not lead to motor impairment. Journal of Neuroscience, 21(10), 3369-3374.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renton, A. E., Chio, A., &amp; Traynor, B. J. (2014). State of play in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis genetics. Nature Neuroscience, 17(1), 17-23. https://doi.org/10.1038/nn.3584</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roy, V., Magne, B., Vaillancourt-Audet, M., Blais, M., Chabaud, S., Grammond, E., Piquet, L. Fradette, J., Laverdi&#xe8;re, I., Moulin V. J., Landreville, S., Germain, L.,Auger, F. A., Gros-Louis F., &amp; Bolduc, S. (2020). Human organ-specific 3D cancer models produced by the stromal self-assembly method of tissue engineering for the study of solid tumors. BioMed Research International, 2020, 6051210. https://doi.org/10.1155/2020/6051210</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sohn, E. J., Nam, Y. K., &amp; Park, H. T. (2021). Involvement of the miR-363-5p/P2RX4 Axis in regulating Schwann cell phenotype after nerve injury. International Journal of Molecular Sciences, 22(21), 11601. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms222111601</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Springer, M. L., Rando, T. A., &amp; Blau, H. M. (2001). Gene delivery to muscle. Current Protocols in Human Genetics, 31(1), 13.14.11-13.14.19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trias, E., Kovacs, M., King, P. H., Si, Y., Kwon, Y., Varela, V., &amp; Barbeito, L. (2020). Schwann cells orchestrate peripheral nerve inflammation through the expression of CSF1, IL-34, and SCF in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Glia, 68(6), 1165-1181. https://doi.org/10.1002/glia.23768</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner, B. J., Ackerley, S., Davies, K. E., &amp; Talbot, K. (2010). Dismutase-competent SOD1 mutant accumulation in myelinating Schwann cells is not detrimental to normal or transgenic ALS model mice. Human Molecular Genetics, 19(5), 815-824. https://doi.org/10.1093/hmg/ddp550</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, L., Pytel, P., Feltri, M. L., Wrabetz, L., &amp; Roos, R. P. (2012). Selective knockdown of mutant SOD1 in Schwann cells ameliorates disease in G85R mutant SOD1 transgenic mice. Neurobiology of Disease, 48(1), 52-57. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nbd.2012.05.014</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warita, H., Itoyama, Y., &amp; Abe, K. (1999). Selective impairment of fast anterograde axonal transport in the peripheral nerves of asymptomatic transgenic mice with a G93A mutant SOD1 gene. Brain Research, 819(1-2), 120-131. https://doi.org/10.1016/s0006-8993(98)01351-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, B., Tu, P., Abtahian, F., Trojanowski, J. Q., &amp; Lee, V. M. (1997). Neurofilaments and orthograde transport are reduced in ventral root axons of transgenic mice that express human SOD1 with a G93A mutation. Journal of Cell Biology, 139(5), 1307-1315. https://doi.org/10.1083/jcb.139.5.1307</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>