<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">35289213</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>10</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1535-3699</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>247</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Experimental biology and medicine (Maywood, N.J.)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Exp Biol Med (Maywood)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Longitudinal intronic RNA-Seq analysis of Parkinson's disease patients reveals disease-specific nascent transcription.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>945</StartPage><EndPage>957</EndPage><MedlinePgn>945-957</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/15353702221081027</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Transcriptomic studies usually focus on either gene or exon-based annotations, and only limited experiments have reported changes in reads mapping to introns. The analysis of intronic reads allows the detection of nascent transcription that is not influenced by steady-state RNA levels and provides information on actively transcribed genes. Here, we describe substantial intronic transcriptional changes in Parkinson's disease (PD) patients compared to healthy controls (CO) at two different timepoints; at the time of diagnosis (BL) and three years later (V08). We used blood RNA-Seq data from the Parkinson's Progression Markers Initiative (PPMI) cohort and identified significantly changed transcription of intronic reads only in PD patients during this follow-up period. In CO subjects, only nine transcripts demonstrated differentially expressed introns between visits. However, in PD patients, 4873 transcripts had differentially expressed introns at visit V08 compared to BL, many of them in genes previously associated with neurodegenerative diseases, such as <i>LRRK2</i>, <i>C9orf72</i>, <i>LGALS3</i>, <i>KANSL1AS1</i>, and <i>ALS2</i>. In addition, at the time of diagnosis (BL visit), we identified 836 transcripts (e.g. <i>SNCA</i>, <i>DNAJC19</i>, <i>PRRG4</i>) and at visit V08, 2184 transcripts (e.g. <i>PINK1</i>, <i>GBA</i>, <i>ALS2</i>, <i>PLEKHM1</i>) with differential intronic expression specific to PD patients. In contrast, reads mapping to exonic regions demonstrated little variation indicating highly specific changes only in intronic transcription. Our study demonstrated that PD is characterized by substantial changes in the nascent transcription, and description of these changes could help to understand the molecular pathology underpinning this disease.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Koks</LastName><ForeName>Sulev</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6087-6643</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Perron Institute for Neurological and Translational Science, Perth, WA 6009, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Molecular Medicine and Innovative Therapeutics, Murdoch University, Perth, WA 6150, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pfaff</LastName><ForeName>Abigail L</ForeName><Initials>AL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Perron Institute for Neurological and Translational Science, Perth, WA 6009, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Molecular Medicine and Innovative Therapeutics, Murdoch University, Perth, WA 6150, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bubb</LastName><ForeName>Vivien J</ForeName><Initials>VJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2763-7004</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics, Institute of Systems, Molecular and Integrative Biology, University of Liverpool, Liverpool L69 3BX, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Quinn</LastName><ForeName>John P</ForeName><Initials>JP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics, Institute of Systems, Molecular and Integrative Biology, University of Liverpool, Liverpool L69 3BX, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Exp Biol Med (Maywood)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100973463</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1535-3699</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>63231-63-0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D012313">RNA</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><SupplMeshList><SupplMeshName Type="Disease" UI="C565957">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis 2, Juvenile</SupplMeshName></SupplMeshList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007438" MajorTopicYN="N">Introns</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008137" MajorTopicYN="N">Longitudinal Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010300" MajorTopicYN="Y">Parkinson Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012313" MajorTopicYN="Y">RNA</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000081246" MajorTopicYN="N">RNA-Seq</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017423" MajorTopicYN="N">Sequence Analysis, RNA</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014158" MajorTopicYN="N">Transcription, Genetic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PPMI</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Parkinson&#x2019;s disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">RNA-Seq</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">blood transcriptome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">introns</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nascent RNA</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nascent transcript</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">transcriptome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">whole transcriptome analysis</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement><b>Declaration of Conflicting Interests:</b> The author(s) declared no potential conflicts of interest with respect to the research, authorship, and/or publication of this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35289213</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9189572</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/15353702221081027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ameur A, Zaghlool A, Halvardson J, Wetterbom A, Gyllensten U, Cavelier L, Feuk L. Total RNA sequencing reveals nascent transcription and widespread co-transcriptional splicing in the human brain. Nat Struct Mol Biol 2011;18:1435&#x2013;40</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22056773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaidatzis D, Burger L, Florescu M, Stadler MB. Analysis of intronic and exonic reads in RNA-seq data characterizes transcriptional and post-transcriptional regulation. Nat Biotechnol 2015;33:722&#x2013;9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26098447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wissink EM, Vihervaara A, Tippens ND, Lis JT. Nascent RNA analyses: tracking transcription and its regulation. Nat Rev Genet 2019;20:705&#x2013;23</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6858503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31399713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Core LJ, Waterfall JJ, Lis JT. Nascent RNA sequencing reveals widespread pausing and divergent initiation at human promoters. Science 2008;322:1845&#x2013;8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2833333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19056941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hendriks GJ, Gaidatzis D, Aeschimann F, Gro&#xdf;hans H. Extensive oscillatory gene expression during C. elegans larval development. Mol Cell 2014;53:380&#x2013;92</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24440504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khodor YL, Rodriguez J, Abruzzi KC, Tang CH, Marr MT, 2nd, Rosbash M. Nascent-seq indicates widespread cotranscriptional pre-mRNA splicing in Drosophila. Genes Dev 2011;25:2502&#x2013;12</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3243060</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22156210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gray JM, Harmin DA, Boswell SA, Cloonan N, Mullen TE, Ling JJ, Miller N, Kuersten S, Ma YC, McCarroll SA, Grimmond SM, Springer M. SnapShot-Seq: a method for extracting genome-wide, in vivo mRNA dynamics from a single total RNA sample. PLoS ONE 2014;9:e89673</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3935918</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24586954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iwaki H, Blauwendraat C, Leonard HL, Kim JJ, Liu G, Maple-Gr&#xf8;dem J, Corvol JC, Pihlstr&#xf8;m L, van Nimwegen M, Hutten SJ, Nguyen KH, Rick J, Eberly S, Faghri F, Auinger P, Scott KM, Wijeyekoon R, Van Deerlin VM, Hernandez DG, Gibbs JR, International Parkinson&#x2019;s Disease Genomics Consortium, Chitrala KN, Day-Williams AG, Brice A, Alves G, Noyce AJ, Tysnes OB, Evans JR, Breen DP, Estrada K, Wegel CE, Danjou F, Simon DK, Andreassen O, Ravina B, Toft M, Heutink P, Bloem BR, Weintraub D, Barker RA, Williams-Gray CH, van de Warrenburg BP, Van Hilten JJ, Scherzer CR, Singleton AB, Nalls MA. Genomewide association study of Parkinson&#x2019;s disease clinical biomarkers in 12 longitudinal patients&#x2019; cohorts. Mov Disord 2019;34:1839&#x2013;50</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7017876</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31505070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bandres-Ciga S, Ahmed S, Sabir MS, Blauwendraat C, Adarmes-G&#xf3;mez AD, Bernal-Bernal I, Bonilla-Toribio M, Buiza-Rueda D, Carrillo F, Carri&#xf3;n-Claro M, G&#xf3;mez-Garre P, Jes&#xfa;s S, Labrador-Espinosa MA, Macias D, M&#xe9;ndez-Del-Barrio C, Peri&#xf1;&#xe1;n-Tocino T, Tejera-Parrado C, Vargas-Gonz&#xe1;lez L, Diez-Fairen M, Alvarez I, Tartari JP, Buongiorno M, Aguilar M, Gorostidi A, Bergareche JA, Mondragon E, Vinagre-Aragon A, Croitoru I, Ruiz-Mart&#xed;nez J, Dols-Icardo O, Kulisevsky J, Mar&#xed;n-Lahoz J, Pagonabarraga J, Pascual-Sedano B, Ezquerra M, C&#xe1;mara A, Compta Y, Fern&#xe1;ndez M, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Santiago R, Mu&#xf1;oz E, Tolosa E, Valldeoriola F, Gonzalez-Aramburu I, Sanchez Rodriguez A, Sierra M, Men&#xe9;ndez-Gonz&#xe1;lez M, Blazquez M, Garcia C, Suarez-San Martin E, Garc&#xed;a-Ruiz P, Mart&#xed;nez-Castrillo JC, Vela-Desojo L, Ruz C, Barrero FJ, Escamilla-Sevilla F, M&#xed;nguez-Castellanos A, Cerdan D, Tabernero C, Gomez Heredia MJ, Perez Errazquin F, Romero-Acebal M, Feliz C, Lopez-Sendon JL, Mata M, Mart&#xed;nez Torres I, Kim JJ, Dalgard CL, Brooks J, Saez-Atienzar S, Gibbs JR, Jorda R, Botia JA, Bonet-Ponce L, Morrison KE, Clarke C, Tan M, Morris H, Edsall C, Hernandez D, Simon-Sanchez J, Nalls MA, Scholz SW, Jimenez-Escrig A, Duarte J, Vives F, Duran R, Hoenicka J, Alvarez V, Infante J, Marti MJ, Clarim&#xf3;n J, L&#xf3;pez de, Munain A, Pastor P, Mir P, Singleton A. The genetic architecture of Parkinson disease in Spain: characterizing population-specific risk, differential haplotype structures, and providing etiologic insight. Mov Disord 2019;34:1851&#x2013;63</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8393828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31660654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalls MA, Blauwendraat C, Vallerga CL, Heilbron K, Bandres-Ciga S, Chang D, Tan M, Kia DA, Noyce AJ, Xue A, Bras J, Young E, von Coelln R, Sim&#xf3;n-S&#xe1;nchez J, Schulte C, Sharma M, Krohn L, Pihlstr&#xf8;m L, Siitonen A, Iwaki H, Leonard H, Faghri F, Gibbs JR, Hernandez DG, Scholz SW, Botia JA, Martinez M, Corvol JC, Lesage S, Jankovic J, Shulman LM, Sutherland M, Tienari P, Majamaa K, Toft M, Andreassen OA, Bangale T, Brice A, Yang J, Gan-Or Z, Gasser T, Heutink P, Shulman JM, Wood NW, Hinds DA, Hardy JA, Morris HR, Gratten J, Visscher PM, Graham RR, Singleton AB. Identification of novel risk loci, causal insights, and heritable risk for Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: a meta-analysis of genome-wide association studies. Lancet Neurol 2019;18:1091&#x2013;102</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8422160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31701892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Billingsley KJ, Barbosa IA, Bandres-Ciga S, Quinn JP, Bubb VJ, Deshpande C, Botia JA, Reynolds RH, Zhang D, Simpson MA, Blauwendraat C, Gan-Or Z, Gibbs JR, Nalls MA, Singleton A, International Parkinson&#x2019;s Disease Genomics C, Ryten M, Koks S. Mitochondria function associated genes contribute to Parkinson&#x2019;s Disease risk and later age at onset. NPJ Parkinsons Dis 2019;5:8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6531455</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31123700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurvits L, Lattekivi F, Reimann E, Kadastik-Eerme L, Kasterpalu KM, Koks S, Taba P, Planken A. Transcriptomic profiles in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Exp Biol Med 2021;246:584&#x2013;95</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7934142</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33148011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller-Nedebock AC, van der Westhuizen FH, K&#xf5;ks S, Bardien S. Nuclear genes associated with mitochondrial DNA processes as contributors to Parkinson&#x2019;s disease risk. Mov Disord 2021;36:815&#x2013;31</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33513296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pfaff AL, Bubb VJ, Quinn JP, Koks S. An increased burden of highly active retrotransposition competent L1s is associated with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease risk and progression in the PPMI cohort. Int J Mol Sci 2020;21:6562</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7554759</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32911699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guelfi S, D&#x2019;Sa K, Bot&#xed;a JA, Vandrovcova J, Reynolds RH, Zhang D, Trabzuni D, Collado-Torres L, Thomason A, Quijada Leyton P, Gagliano Taliun SA, Nalls MA, Small KS, Smith C, Ramasamy A, Hardy J, Weale ME, Ryten M. Regulatory sites for splicing in human basal ganglia are enriched for disease-relevant information. Nat Commun 2020;11:1041.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7042265</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32098967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reynolds RH, Bot&#xed;a J, Nalls MA, Hardy J, Gagliano Taliun SA, Ryten M. Moving beyond neurons: the role of cell type-specific gene regulation in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease heritability. NPJ Parkinsons Dis 2019;5:6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6470136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31016231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurvits L, Reimann E, Kadastik-Eerme L, Truu L, Kingo K, Erm T, K&#xf5;ks S, Taba P, Planken A. Serum amyloid alpha is downregulated in peripheral tissues of Parkinson&#x2019;s disease patients. Front Neurosci 2019;13:13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6361740</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30760975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Planken A, Kurvits L, Reimann E, Kadastik-Eerme L, Kingo K, K&#xf5;ks S, Taba P. Looking beyond the brain to improve the pathogenic understanding of Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: implications of whole transcriptome profiling of Patients&#x2019; skin. BMC Neurol 2017;17:6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5223462</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28068941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dobin A, Davis CA, Schlesinger F, Drenkow J, Zaleski C, Jha S, Batut P, Chaisson M, Gingeras TR. STAR: ultrafast universal RNA-seq aligner. Bioinformatics 2013;29:15&#x2013;21</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3530905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23104886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawrence M, Huber W, Pag&#xe8;s H, Aboyoun P, Carlson M, Gentleman R, Morgan MT, Carey VJ. Software for computing and annotating genomic ranges. Plos Comput Biol 2013;9:e1003118</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3738458</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23950696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malsam J, Satoh A, Pelletier L, Warren G. Golgin tethers define subpopulations of COPI vesicles. Science 2005;307:1095&#x2013;8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15718469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franco-Iborra S, Cuadros T, Parent A, Romero-Gimenez J, Vila M, Perier C. Defective mitochondrial protein import contributes to complex I-induced mitochondrial dysfunction and neurodegeneration in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Cell Death Dis 2018;9:1122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6221944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30405116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davey KM, Parboosingh JS, McLeod DR, Chan A, Casey R, Ferreira P, Snyder FF, Bridge PJ, Bernier FP. Mutation of DNAJC19, a human homologue of yeast inner mitochondrial membrane co-chaperones, causes DCMA syndrome, a novel autosomal recessive Barth syndrome-like condition. J Med Genet 2006;43:385&#x2013;93</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2564511</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16055927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heinemeyer T, Stemmet M, Bardien S, Neethling A. Underappreciated roles of the translocase of the outer and inner mitochondrial membrane protein complexes in human disease. DNA Cell Biol 2019;38:23&#x2013;40</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30481057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Napoli E, Song G, Panoutsopoulos A, Riyadh MA, Kaushik G, Halmai J, Levenson R, Zarbalis KS, Giulivi C. Beyond autophagy: a novel role for autism-linked Wdfy3 in brain mitophagy. Sci Rep 2018;8:11348.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6063930</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30054502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao S, Zhang X, Zou SC, Zhu Y, Li B, Kuang WP, Guo Y, Li XS, Li L, Wang XY. A transcriptome-wide association study identifies susceptibility genes for Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. NPJ Parkinsons Dis 2021;7:79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8429416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34504106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conesa A, Madrigal P, Tarazona S, Gomez-Cabrero D, Cervera A, McPherson A, Szcze&#x15b;niak MW, Gaffney DJ, Elo LL, Zhang X, Mortazavi A. A survey of best practices for RNA-seq data analysis. Genome Biol 2016;17:13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4728800</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26813401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Falchetti M, Prediger RD, Zanotto-Filho A. Classification algorithms applied to blood-based transcriptome meta-analysis to predict idiopathic Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Comput Biol Med 2020;124:103925.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32889300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bray NL, Pimentel H, Melsted P, Pachter L. Near-optimal probabilistic RNA-seq quantification. Nat Biotechnol 2016;34:525&#x2013;7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27043002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patro R, Duggal G, Love MI, Irizarry RA, Kingsford C. Salmon provides fast and bias-aware quantification of transcript expression. Nat Methods 2017;14:417&#x2013;9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5600148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28263959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xf5;ks S, Overall RW, Ivask M, Soomets U, Guha M, Vasar E, Fernandes C, Schalkwyk LC. Silencing of the WFS1 gene in HEK cells induces pathways related to neurodegeneration and mitochondrial damage. Physiol Genomics 2013;45:182&#x2013;90</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23321269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filimonenko M, Isakson P, Finley KD, Anderson M, Jeong H, Melia TJ, Bartlett BJ, Myers KM, Birkeland HC, Lamark T, Krainc D, Brech A, Stenmark H, Simonsen A, Yamamoto A. The selective macroautophagic degradation of aggregated proteins requires the PI3P-binding protein Alfy. Mol Cell 2010;38:265&#x2013;79</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2867245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20417604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fox LM, Kim K, Johnson CW, Chen S, Croce KR, Victor MB, Eenjes E, Bosco JR, Randolph LK, Dragatsis I, Dragich JM, Yoo AS, Yamamoto A. Huntington&#x2019;s disease pathogenesis is modified in vivo by Alfy/Wdfy3 and selective macroautophagy. Neuron 2020;105:813&#x2013;216</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7060123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31899071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamamoto A, Simonsen A. Alfy-dependent elimination of aggregated proteins by macroautophagy: can there be too much of a good thing. Autophagy 2011;7:346&#x2013;50</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3060415</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21150266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reinhart EF, Litt NA, Katzenell S, Pellegrini M, Yamamoto A, Ragusa MJ. A highly conserved glutamic acid in ALFY inhibits membrane binding to aid in aggregate clearance. Traffic 2021;22:23&#x2013;37</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7902475</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33225481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aneichyk T, Hendriks WT, Yadav R, Shin D, Gao D, Vaine CA, Collins RL, Domingo A, Currall B, Stortchevoi A, Multhaupt-Buell T, Penney EB, Cruz L, Dhakal J, Brand H, Hanscom C, Antolik C, Dy M, Ragavendran A, Underwood J, Cantsilieris S, Munson KM, Eichler EE, Acu&#xf1;a P, Go C, Jamora RDG, Rosales RL, Church DM, Williams SR, Garcia S, Klein C, M&#xfc;ller U, Wilhelmsen KC, Timmers HTM, Sapir Y, Wainger BJ, Henderson D, Ito N, Weisenfeld N, Jaffe D, Sharma N, Breakefield XO, Ozelius LJ, Bragg DC, Talkowski ME. Dissecting the Causal Mechanism of X-Linked Dystonia-Parkinsonism by Integrating Genome and Transcriptome Assembly. Cell 2018;172:897.e&#x2013;909.e21</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5831509</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29474918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>