<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35353910</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-4598</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>65</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Muscle &amp; nerve</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Muscle Nerve</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Ten years of riluzole use in a tertiary ALS clinic.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>659</StartPage><EndPage>666</EndPage><MedlinePgn>659-666</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/mus.27541</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION/AIMS">Riluzole is a glutamate inhibitor approved for the treatment of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). There are scant data on factors associated with riluzole initiation and adherence. The goal of this study was to describe the use of riluzole at the Penn State Hershey Medical Center (PSHMC) ALS clinic.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">A retrospective medical record review of ALS patients seen at the PSHMC from January 2007 to December 2016. A timeline of riluzole use was established for each patient. Factors contributing to dose changes or discontinuations were recorded. Riluzole adherence was assessed using the proportion of days covered (PDC) calculated by the patient-reported length of riluzole use divided by total time from prescription to death/censor. Multivariable analysis was performed to evaluate the association of demography and clinical course with adherence.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Seven hundred twenty-three records were screened, with 508 (307 men, 201 women) meeting the criteria for inclusion. The median duration of riluzole use was 435 (range, 0-3773) days. The median PDC for the group was 64%. Those with higher initial overall function and slower rate of decline were more likely to have a larger PDC. No trends in patients' demographics, riluzole use, and tracheostomy-free survival were found over time.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION">A high rate of riluzole initiation and adherence was found in this sample. The most common reasons for dose modification were related to adverse effects, yet social-, economic-, and patient-related factors were also common. The characteristics of riluzole prescription and use have remained relatively unchanged in a single tertiary ALS center over the past 10&#x2009;years.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Geronimo</LastName><ForeName>Andrew</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7754-3754</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, Penn State College of Medicine, Hershey, Pennsylvania.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Albertson</LastName><ForeName>Richard M</ForeName><Initials>RM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, Michigan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Noto</LastName><ForeName>James</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Commonwealth Health Physician Network, Plains, Pennsylvania.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Simmons</LastName><ForeName>Zachary</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8574-5332</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departments of Neurology, Penn State College of Medicine, Hershey, Pennsylvania.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Humanities, Penn State College of Medicine, Hershey, Pennsylvania.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>UL1 TR000127</GrantID><Acronym>TR</Acronym><Agency>NCATS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>UL1 TR002014</GrantID><Acronym>TR</Acronym><Agency>NCATS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Muscle Nerve</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7803146</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0148-639X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D018696">Neuroprotective Agents</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>7LJ087RS6F</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D019782">Riluzole</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018696" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neuroprotective Agents</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019782" MajorTopicYN="N">Riluzole</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014139" MajorTopicYN="N">Tracheostomy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">adherence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">management</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">outcome measure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">riluzole</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35353910</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS1793885</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9275511</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.27541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Miller RG, Jackson CE, Kasarskis EJ, et al. Practice Parameter update: The care of the patient with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Multidisciplinary care, symptom management, and cognitive/behavioral impairment (an evidence-based review): Report of the Quality Standards Subcommittee of the American Academy of Neurology. Neurology. 2009;73(15):1227&#x2013;1233.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2764728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19822873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller RG, Jackson CE, Kasarskis EJ, et al. Practice parameter update: The care of the patient with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Drug, nutritional, and respiratory therapies (an evidence-based review): Report of the quality standards subcommittee of the American academy of neurology. Neurology. 2009;73(15):1218&#x2013;1226.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2764727</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19822872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Traynor BJ, Alexander M, Corr B, Frost E, Hardiman O. Effect of a multidisciplinary amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) clinic on ALS survival: a population based study, 1996&#x2013;2000. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2003;74: 1258&#x2013;1261.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1738639</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12933930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aridegbe T, Kandler R, Walters JS, Walsh T, Shaw PJ, McDermott CJ. The natural history of motor neuron disease: Assessing the impact of specialist care Amyotrophic Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2013;14:13&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22642305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rooney J, Byrne S, Heverin M, Tobin K, Dick A, Donaghy C, Hardiman O. A multidisciplinary clinic approach improves survival in ALS: a comparative study of ALS in Ireland and Northern Ireland. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2015;86:496&#x2013;501.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25550416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Den Berg JP, Kalmijn S, Lindeman E, et al. Multidisciplinary ALS care improves quality of life in patients with ALS. Neurology. 2005;65:1264&#x2013;1267.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16247055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bensimon G, Lacomblez L, Meininger V. A controlled trial of riluzole in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. New England Journal of Medicine. 1994;330(9):585&#x2013;591.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8302340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abe K, Aoki M, Tsuji S, et al. Safety and efficacy of edaravone in well defined patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. The Lancet Neurology. 2017;16(7):505&#x2013;512.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28522181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller RG, Mitchell JD, Lyon M, Moore DH. Riluzole for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS)/motor neuron disease (MND). Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews. 2007;(1).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17253460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang T, al Khleifat A, Meurgey JH, et al. Stage at which riluzole treatment prolongs survival in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a retrospective analysis of data from a dose-ranging study. The Lancet Neurology. 2018;17(5):416&#x2013;422.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5899963</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29525492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lacomblez L, Bensimon G, Leigh PN, Guillet P, Meninger V, et al. Dose-ranging study of riluzole in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet. 1996;347:1425&#x2013;1431.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8676624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrews JA, Jackson CE, Heiman-Patterson TD, Bettica P, Brooks BR, Pioro EP. Real-world evidence of riluzole effectiveness in treating amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis and Frontotemporal Degeneration. 2020;21(7&#x2013;8):509&#x2013;518.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32573277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandriori J, Malerba SA, Beghi E, et al. Riluzole and other prognostic factors in ALS: a population-based registry study in Italy. J Neurol 2018;265:817&#x2013;827.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29404735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cramer JA, Roy A, Burrell A, et al. Medication compliance and persistence: Terminology and definitions. Value in Health. 2008;11(1):44&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18237359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osterberg L, Blaschke T. Adherence to Medication. New England Journal of Medicine. 2005;353(5):487&#x2013;497.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16079372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho PM, Bryson CL, Rumsfeld JS. Medication Adherence. Circulation. 2009;119(23):3028&#x2013;3035.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19528344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabat&#xe9; E, editor. Adherence to long-term therapies: evidence for action. Geneva, Switzerland: World Health Organization; 2003. 211 p.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Introna A, D&#x2019;Errico E, Modugno B, et al. Adherence to riluzole in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: An observational study. Neuropsychiatric Disease and Treatment. 2018;14:193&#x2013;203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5757977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29379292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Par&#xf3;la A, da Silva Mousinho de Palhares Falc&#xe3;o F, Farinha H, et al. Analysis of riluzole&#x2019;s profile of use in a central hospital in Lisbon. Patient Preference and Adherence. 2018;12:2357&#x2013;2361.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6229141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30464422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, Miller RG, Swash M, and Munsat TL. El Escorial revisited: Revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis &amp; Other Motor Neuron Disorders. 2000;1(5):293&#x2013;299.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11464847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balendra R, al Khleifat A, Fang T, Al-Chalabi A. A standard operating procedure for King&#x2019;s ALS clinical staging. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis and Frontotemporal Degeneration. 2019;20(3&#x2013;4):159&#x2013;164.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6558284</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30773950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum JM, Stambler N, Malta E, Fuller C, Hilt D, Thurmond B, Nakanishi A. The ALSFRS-R: a revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. Journal of the Neurological Sciences. 1999;169(1&#x2013;2):13&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10540002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riluzole. LexiDrugs. Lexicomp Online. Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc.
Riverwoods, IL. Available at : http://online.lexi.com. Accessed April 19, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackevicius CA, Mamdani M, Tu JV. Adherence with statin therapy in elderly patients with and without acute coronary syndromes. Journal of the American Medical Association. 2002;288(4):462&#x2013;467.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12132976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ofori-Asenso R, Ilom&#xe4;ki J, Tacey M, et al. Patterns of statin use and long-term adherence and persistence among older adults with diabetes. Journal of Diabetes. 2018;10(9):699&#x2013;707.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29658177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackevicius CA, Li P, Tu JV. Prevalence, predictors, and outcomes of primary nonadherence after acute myocardial infarction. Circulation. 2008;117(8):1028&#x2013;1036.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18299512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deshpande S, Quek RGW, Forbes CA, et al. A systematic review to assess adherence and persistence with statins. Current Medical Research and Opinion. 2017;33(4):769&#x2013;778.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28076703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ofori-Asenso R, Jakhu A, Zomer E, et al. Adherence and Persistence among Statin Users Aged 65 Years and Over: A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis. Journals of Gerontology - Series A Biological Sciences and Medical Sciences. 2018;73(6):813&#x2013;819.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28958039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coleman CI, Limone B, Sobieraj DM, Lee S, Roberts MS, Kaur R, Alam T. Dosing frequency and medication adherence in chronic disease. J Manag Care Pharm. 2012;18(7):527&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22971206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Srivastava K, Arora A, Kataria A, Cappelleri JC, Sadosky A, Peterson AM. Impact of reducing dosing frequency on adherence to oral therapies: a literature review and meta-analysis. Patient Preference and Adherence. 2013;7:419&#x2013;434.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3669002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23737662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horton DK, Graham S, Punjani R, et al. A spatial analysis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) cases in the United States and their proximity to multidisciplinary ALS clinics, 2013. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2018;19:126&#x2013;133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5815888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29262737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy V, Felgoise SH, Walsh SM, Simmons Z. Problem solving skills predict quality of life and psychological morbidity in ALS caregivers. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2009;10:147&#x2013;153.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18618351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hecht MJ, Graesel E, Tigges S, et al. Burden of care in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Palliat Med. 2003;17:327&#x2013;333.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12822849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thakore NJ, Lapin BR, Pioro EP, et al. Stage-specific riluzole effect in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a retrospective study. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2020;21:140&#x2013;143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31450993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>