<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35395402</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>19</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1095-9572</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>255</Volume><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Jul</Month><Day>15</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>NeuroImage</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Neuroimage</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Longitudinal surface-based spatial Bayesian GLM reveals complex trajectories of motor neurodegeneration in ALS.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>119180</StartPage><MedlinePgn>119180</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.neuroimage.2022.119180</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S1053-8119(22)00305-6</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Longitudinal fMRI studies hold great promise for the study of neurodegenerative diseases, development and aging, but realizing their full potential depends on extracting accurate fMRI-based measures of brain function and organization in individual subjects over time. This is especially true for studies of rare, heterogeneous and/or rapidly progressing neurodegenerative diseases. These often involve small samples with heterogeneous functional features, making traditional group-difference analyses of limited utility. One such disease is amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS), a severe disease resulting in extreme loss of motor function and eventual death. Here, we use an advanced individualized task fMRI analysis approach to analyze a rich longitudinal dataset containing 190 hand clench fMRI scans from 16 ALS patients (78 scans) and 22 age-matched healthy controls (112 scans). Specifically, we adopt our cortical surface-based spatial Bayesian general linear model (GLM), which has high power and precision to detect activations in individual subjects, and propose a novel longitudinal extension to leverage information shared across visits. We perform all analyses in native surface space to preserve individual anatomical and functional features. Using mixed-effects models to subsequently study the relationship between size of activation and ALS disease progression, we observe for the first time an inverted U-shaped trajectory of motor activations: at relatively mild motor disability we observe enlarging activations, while at higher levels of motor disability we observe severely diminished activation, reflecting progression toward complete loss of motor function. We further observe distinct trajectories depending on clinical progression rate, with faster progressors exhibiting more extreme changes at an earlier stage of disability. These differential trajectories suggest that initial hyper-activation is likely attributable to loss of inhibitory neurons, rather than functional compensation as earlier assumed. These findings substantially advance scientific understanding of the ALS disease process. This study also provides the first real-world example of how surface-based spatial Bayesian analysis of task fMRI can further scientific understanding of neurodegenerative disease and other phenomena. The surface-based spatial Bayesian GLM is implemented in the BayesfMRI R package.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022. Published by Elsevier Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mejia</LastName><ForeName>Amanda F</ForeName><Initials>AF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Statistics, Indiana University, Bloomington, IN, USA. Electronic address: afmejia@iu.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Koppelmans</LastName><ForeName>Vincent</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, University of Utah, Salt Lake City, UT, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jelsone-Swain</LastName><ForeName>Laura</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, University of South Carolina Aiken, Aiken, SC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kalra</LastName><ForeName>Sanjay</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Neurology, Department of Medicine, University of Alberta, Edmonton, AB, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Welsh</LastName><ForeName>Robert C</ForeName><Initials>RC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, University of Utah, Salt Lake City, UT, USA; Department of Psychiatry and Biobehavioral Sciences, University of California Los Angeles, Los Angeles, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R01 EB027119</GrantID><Acronym>EB</Acronym><Agency>NIBIB NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01 NS052514</GrantID><Acronym>NS</Acronym><Agency>NINDS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01 NS082304</GrantID><Acronym>NS</Acronym><Agency>NINDS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Neuroimage</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9215515</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1053-8119</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001499" MajorTopicYN="N">Bayes Theorem</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006233" MajorTopicYN="Y">Disabled Persons</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018450" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Progression</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016014" MajorTopicYN="N">Linear Models</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008279" MajorTopicYN="N">Magnetic Resonance Imaging</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000068079" MajorTopicYN="Y">Motor Disorders</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019636" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neurodegenerative Diseases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bayesian</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">General linear model</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Longitudinal</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neurodegeneration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Statistics</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35395402</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS1813904</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9580623</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuroimage.2022.119180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S1053-8119(22)00305-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Agosta F, Valsasina P, Riva N, Copetti M, Messina MJ, Prelle A, Comi G, Filippi M, 2012. The cortical signature of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. PLoS ONE 7 (8), e42816.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3412820</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22880116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akaike H, 1998. Information Theory and an Extension of the Maximum Likelihood Principle. In: Selected papers of Hirotugu Akaike. Springer, pp. 199&#x2013;213.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avants BB, Tustison NJ, Song G, Cook PA, Klein A, Gee JC, 2011. A reproducible evaluation of ANTs similarity metric performance in brain image registration. Neuroimage 54 (3), 2033&#x2013;2044.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3065962</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20851191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bates D, M&#xe4;chler M, Bolker B, Walker S, 2015. Fitting linear mixed-effects models using lme4. J. Stat. Softw 67 (1), 1&#x2013;48. doi: 10.18637/jss.v067.i01.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18637/jss.v067.i01</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benjamini Y, Hochberg Y, 1995. Controlling the false discovery rate: a practical and powerful approach to multiple testing. J. R. Stat. Soc.: Ser. B (Stat. Methodol.) 289&#x2013;300.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bharti K, Khan M, Beaulieu C, Graham SJ, Briemberg H, Frayne R, Genge A, Korngut L, Zinman L, Kalra S, Consortium, f.t.C.A.N., 2020. Involvement of the dentate nucleus in the pathophysiology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a multi-center and multi-modal neuroimaging study. Neuroimage: Clinical 28, 102385.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7476068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32871387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blicher JU, Eskildsen SF, rmose T.G.S.x., ller A.T.M.x., Figlewski K, Near J, 2019. Short echo-time magnetic resonance spectroscopy in ALS, simultaneous quantification of glutamate and GABA at 3T. Sci. Rep 1&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6879471</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31772352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brodoehl S, Gaser C, Dahnke R, Witte OW, Klingner CM, 2020. Surface-based analysis increases the specificity of cortical activation patterns and connectivity results. Sci. Rep 10 (1), 1&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7109138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32235885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, 1994. El Escorial World Federation of Neurology criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Subcommittee on Motor Neuron Diseases/Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis of the World Federation of Neurology Research Group on Neuromuscular Diseases and the El Escorial &#x201c;Clinical limits of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis &#x201d; workshop contributors. J. Neurol. Sci 124, 96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7807156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Burgh HK, Westeneng H-J, Walhout R, van Veenhuijzen K, Tan HHG, Meier JM, Bakker LA, Hendrikse J, van Es MA, Veldink JH, Van Den Heuvel MP, van den Berg LH, 2020. Multimodal longitudinal study of structural brain involvement in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology 94 (24), e2592&#x2013;e2604.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7455328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32414878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castelnovo V, Canu E, Calderaro D, Riva N, Poletti B, Basaia S, Solca F, Silani V, Filippi M, Agosta F, 2020. Progression of brain functional connectivity and frontal cognitive dysfunction in ALS. YNICL 28, 102509.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7708866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33395998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chapman MC, Jelsone-Swain L, Johnson TD, Gruis KL, Welsh RC, 2014. Diffusion tensor MRI of the corpus callosum in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J. Magn. Reson. Imaging 39 (3), 641&#x2013;647.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3888481</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23843179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cremers HR, Wager TD, Yarkoni T, 2017. The relation between statistical power and inference in fMRI. PLoS ONE 12 (11), e0184923.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5695788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29155843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Douaud G, Filippini N, Knight S, Talbot K, Turner MR, 2011. Integration of structural and functional magnetic resonance imaging in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain 134 (Pt 12), 3470&#x2013;3479.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22075069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dubois J, Adolphs R, 2016. Building a science of individual differences from fMRI. Trends Cogn. Sci. (Regul. Ed.) 20 (6), 425&#x2013;443.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4886721</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27138646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elliott ML, Knodt AR, Ireland D, Morris ML, Poulton R, Ramrakha S, Sison ML, Moffitt TE, Caspi A, Hariri AR, 2020. What is the test-retest reliability of common task-fMRI measures? New empirical evidence and a meta-analysis. Psychological Science 31 (7), 792&#x2013;806.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7370246</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32489141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellis CM, Simmons A, Jones D, Bland J, Dawson JM, Horsfield M, Williams SC, Leigh PN, 1999. Diffusion tensor MRI assesses corticospinal tract damage in ALS. Neurology 53 (5), 1051&#x2013;1058.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10496265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eloyan A, Shou H, Shinohara RT, Sweeney EM, Nebel MB, Cuzzocreo JL, Calabresi PA, Reich DS, Lindquist MA, Crainiceanu CM, 2014. Health effects of lesion localization in multiple sclerosis: spatial registration and confounding adjustment. PLoS ONE 9 (9), e107263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4169434</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25233361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fischl B, 2012. Freesurfer. Neuroimage 62 (2), 774&#x2013;781.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3685476</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22248573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fitzhugh MC, Braden BB, Sabbagh MN, Rogalsky C, Baxter LC, 2019. Age-related atrophy and compensatory neural networks in reading comprehension. J. Int. Neuropsychol. Soc 25 (6), 569&#x2013;582.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6816336</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31030698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foerster BR, Pomper MG, Callaghan BC, Petrou M, Edden RAE, Mohamed MA, Welsh RC, Carlos RC, Barker PB, Feldman EL, 2013. An imbalance between excitatory and inhibitory neurotransmitters in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis revealed by use of 3-T proton magnetic resonance spectroscopy. JAMA Neurol. 70 (8), 1009&#x2013;1016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4382938</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23797905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friston K, Ashburner J, Kiebel S, Nichols T, Penny W.(Eds.), 2007. Statistical parametric mapping: The analysis of functional brain images. Academic Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friston K, Penny W, 2003. Posterior probability maps and spms. Neuroimage 19 (3), 1240&#x2013;1249.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12880849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon PH, Cheng B, Salachas F, Pradat P-F, Bruneteau G, Corcia P, Lacomblez L, Meininger V, 2010. Progression in ALS is not linear but is curvilinear. J. Neurol 257 (10), 1713&#x2013;1717.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20532545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gray KR, Wolz R, Heckemann RA, Aljabar P, Hammers A, Rueckert D, Alzheimer&#x2019;s Disease Neuroimaging Initiative, 2012. Multi-region analysis of longitudinal FDG-PET for the classification of Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. Neuroimage 60 (1), 221&#x2013;229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3303084</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22236449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta L, Besseling RMH, Overvliet GM, Hofman PAM, de Louw A, Vaessen MJ, Aldenkamp AP, Ulman S, Jansen JFA, Backes WH, 2010. Spatial heterogeneity analysis of brain activation in fMRI. Neuroimage: Clinical 5, 266&#x2013;276.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4141984</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25161893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holmes A, 1988. Generalisability, random effects and population inference. Neuroimage 7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jelsone-Swain LM, Fling BW, Seidler RD, Hovatter R, Gruis K, Welsh RC, 2010. Reduced interhemispheric functional connectivity in the motor cortex during rest in limb-onset amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Front. Syst. Neurosci 4, 158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3018774</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21228916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kassubek J, Muller HP, Del Tredici K, Brettschneider J, Pinkhardt EH, Lule D, Bohm S, Braak H, Ludolph AC, 2014. Diffusion tensor imaging analysis of sequential spreading of disease in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis confirms patterns of TDP-43 pathology. Brain 137 (6), 1733&#x2013;1740.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24736303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kolinger GD, V&#xe1;llez Garc&#xed;a D, Willemsen ATM, Reesink FE, de Jong BM, Dierckx RAJO, De Deyn PP, Boellaard R, 2021. Amyloid burden quantification depends on PET and MR image processing methodology. PLoS ONE 16 (3), e0248122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7935288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33667281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konrad C, Henningsen H, Bremer J, Mock B, Deppe M, Buchinger C, Turski P, Knecht S, Brooks B, 2002. Pattern of cortical reorganization in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a functional magnetic resonance imaging study. Exp. Brain Res 143 (1), 51&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11907690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konrad C, Jansen A, Henningsen H, Sommer J, Turski PA, Brooks BR, Knecht S, 2006. Subcortical reorganization in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Exp. Brain Res. Exp. Hirnforschung Exp&#xe9;rimentation c&#xe9;r&#xe9;brale 172 (3), 361&#x2013;369.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16463149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawrence E, Vegvari C, Ower A, Hadjichrysanthou C, De Wolf F, Anderson RM, 2017. A systematic review of longitudinal studies which measure Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease biomarkers. J. Alzheimers Dis 59 (4), 1359&#x2013;1379.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5611893</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28759968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee SE, Sias AC, Mandelli ML, Brown JA, Brown AB, Khazenzon AM, Vidovszky AA, Zanto TP, Karydas AM, Pribadi M, Dokuru D, Coppola G, Geschwind DH, Rademakers R, Gorno-Tempini ML, Rosen HJ, Miller BL, Seeley WW, 2017. Network degeneration and dysfunction in presymptomatic C9ORF72 expansion carriers. Neuroimage: Clinical 14, 286&#x2013;297.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5349617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28337409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu TT, Frank LR, Wong EC, Buxton RB, 2001. Detection power, estimation efficiency, and predictability in event-related fMRI. Neuroimage 13 (4), 759&#x2013;773.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11305903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lloyd CM, Richardson MP, Brooks DJ, Al-Chalabi A, Leigh PN, 2000. Extramotor involvement in ALS: PET studies with the GABA(a) ligand [(11)C]flumazenil. Brain 123 (Pt 11), 2289&#x2013;2296.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11050028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mejia AF, Nebel MB, Eloyan A, Caffo B, Lindquist MA, 2017. PCA Leverage: outlier detection for high-dimensional functional magnetic resonance imaging data. Biostatistics 18 (3), 521&#x2013;536.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5862350</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28334131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mejia AF, Yue Y, Bolin D, Lindgren F, Lindquist MA, 2020. A Bayesian general linear modeling approach to cortical surface fMRI data analysis. J. Am. Stat. Assoc 115 (530), 501&#x2013;520.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7556728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33060871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menke RAL, Abraham I, Thiel CS, Filippini N, Knight S, Talbot K, Turner MR, 2012. Fractional anisotropy in the posterior limb of the internal capsule and prognosis in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis : fractional anisotropy and ALS. Arch. Neurol 69 (11), 1493.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22910997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menke RAL, Proudfoot M, Talbot K, Turner MR, 2018. The two-year progression of structural and functional cerebral MRI in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuroimage: Clinical 17, 953&#x2013;961.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5752097</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29321969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammadi B, Kollewe K, Samii A, Krampfl K, Dengler R, M&#xfc;nte TF, 2009. Changes of resting state brain networks in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Exp. Neurol 217 (1), 147&#x2013;153.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19416664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monti MM, 2011. Statistical analysis of fMRI time-series: a critical review of the GLM approach. Front. Hum. Neurosci 5, 28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3062970</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21442013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller H-P, Turner MR, Grosskreutz J, Abrahams S, Bede P, Govind V, Prudlo J, Ludolph AC, Filippi M, Kassubek J, 2016. A large-scale multicentre cerebral diffusion tensor imaging study in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J. Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatry 87 (6), 570&#x2013;579.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26746186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mumford JA, Nichols T, 2009. Simple group fMRI modeling and inference. Neuroimage 47 (4), 1469&#x2013;1475.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2719771</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19463958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murdock BJ, Famie JP, Piecuch CE, Raue KD, Mendelson FE, Pieroni CH, Iniguez SD, Zhao L, Goutman SA, Feldman EL, 2021. Nk cells associate with als in a sex-and age-dependent manner. JCI Insight 6 (11).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8262328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33974561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noll D, 2002. Rapid MR image acquisition in the presence of background gradients. Proc. IEEE Int. Sympos. Biomed. Imag 725&#x2013;728.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noll DC, Meyer CH, Pauly JM, Nishimura DG, Macovski A, 2004. A homogeneity correction method for magnetic resonance imaging with time-varying gradients. IEEE Trans. Med. Imag 10 (4), 629&#x2013;637.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18222870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park DC, Welsh RC, Marshuetz C, Gutchess AH, Mikels J, Polk TA, Noll DC, Taylor SF, 2003. Working memory for complex scenes: age differences in frontal and hippocampal activations. J. Cogn. Neurosci 15 (8), 1122&#x2013;1134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14709231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poujois A, Schneider FC, Faillenot I, Camdessanch&#xe9; J-P, Vandenberghe N, Thomas-Ant&#xe9;rion C, Antoine J-C, 2013. Brain plasticity in the motor network is correlated with disease progression in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Hum. Brain Mapp 34 (10), 2391&#x2013;2401.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6870334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22461315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renton AE, Majounie E, Waite A, Sim&#xf3;n-S&#xe1;nchez J, Rollinson S, Gibbs JR, Schymick JC, Laaksovirta H, van Swieten JC, Myllykangas L, Kalimo H, Paetau A, Abramzon Y, Remes AM, Kaganovich A, Scholz SW, Duckworth J, Ding J, Harmer DW, Hernandez DG, Johnson JO, Mok K, Ryten M, Trabzuni D, Guerreiro RJ, Orrell RW, Neal J, Murray A, Pearson J, Jansen IE, Sondervan D, Seelaar H, Blake D, Young K, Halliwell N, Callister JB, Toulson G, Richardson A, Gerhard A, Snowden J, Mann D, Neary D, Nalls MA, Peuralinna T, Jansson L, Isoviita V-M, Kaivorinne A-L, H&#xf6;ltt&#xe4;-Vuori M, Ikonen E, Sulkava R, Benatar M, Wuu J, Chi&#xf2; A, Restagno G, Borghero G, Sabatelli M, Heckerman D, Rogaeva E, Zinman L, Rothstein JD, Sendtner M, Drepper C, Eichler EE, Alkan C, Abdullaev Z, Pack SD, Dutra A, Pak E, Hardy J, Singleton A, Williams NM, Heutink P, Pickering-Brown S, Morris HR, Tienari PJ, Traynor BJ, Consortium28, T.I., 2011. A hexanucleotide repeat expansion in C9ORF72 is the cause of chromosome 9p21-Linked ALS-FTD. Neuron 72 (2), 257&#x2013;268.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3200438</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21944779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rooney J, Burke T, Vajda A, Heverin M, Hardiman O, 2017. What does the ALSFRS-R really measure? A longitudinal and survival analysis of functional dimension subscores in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J. Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatry 88 (5), 381&#x2013;385.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27888187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld MA, Tempelmann C, Gaul C, K&#xfc;hnel GR, D&#xfc;zel E, Hopf J-M, Feistner H, Zierz S, Heinze HJ, Vielhaber S, 2005. Functional motor compensation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J. Neurol 252 (8), 944&#x2013;952.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15750701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shan ZY, Wright MJ, Thompson PM, McMahon KL, Blokland GGAM, de Zubicaray GI, Martin NG, Vinkhuyzen AAE, Reutens DC, 2013. Modeling of the hemodynamic responses in block design fMRI studies. J. Cerebral Blood Flow Metabol 34 (2), 316&#x2013;324.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3915209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24252847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stern ER, Welsh RC, Fitzgerald KD, Taylor SF, 2009. Topographic analysis of individual activation patterns in medial frontal cortex in schizophrenia. Hum. Brain Mapp 30 (7), 2146&#x2013;2156.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2700203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18819107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stoppel CM, Vielhaber S, Eckart C, Machts J, Kaufmann J, Heinze H-J, Kollewe K, Petri S, Dengler R, Hopf J-M, Schoenfeld MA, 2014. Structural and functional hallmarks of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis progression in motor-and memory-related brain regions. Neuroimage: Clinical 5, 277&#x2013;290.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4141983</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25161894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Subramaniam S, 2019. Selective neuronal death in neurodegenerative diseases: the ongoing mystery. Yale J. Biol. Med 92 (4), 695&#x2013;705.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6913821</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31866784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Telzer EH, McCormick EM, Peters S, Cosme D, Pfeifer JH, van Duijvenvoorde AC, 2018. Methodological considerations for developmental longitudinal fMRI research. Dev. Cogn. Neurosci 33, 149&#x2013;160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6345379</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29456104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trojsi F, Di Nardo F, Siciliano M, Caiazzo G, Femiano C, Passaniti C, Ricciardi D, Russo A, Bisecco A, Esposito S, Monsurr&#xf2; MR, Cirillo M, Santangelo G, Esposito F, Tedeschi G, 2020. Frontotemporal degeneration in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS): a longitudinal MRI one-year study. CNS Spectr. 1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32089134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner MR, Hardiman PO, Benatar M, Brooks BR, Chi&#xf2; A, de Carvalho MD M, Ince PG, Lin C, Miller RG, Mitsumoto H, Nicholson G, Ravits J, Shaw PJ, Swash M, Talbot K, Traynor BJ, van den Berg LH, Veldink JH, Vucic S, Kiernan MC, 2013. Controversies and priorities in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet Neurol. 12 (3), 310&#x2013;322.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4565161</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23415570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner MR, Kiernan MC, Leigh PN, Talbot K, 2009. Biomarkers in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet Neurol. 8 (1), 94&#x2013;109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19081518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner MR, Modo M, 2010. Advances in the application of MRI to amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Expert Opin. Med. Diagn 4 (6), 483&#x2013;496.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3080036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21516259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verstraete E, Van Den Heuvel MP, Veldink JH, Blanken N, Mandl RC, Hulshoff Pol HE, van den Berg LH, 2010. Motor network degeneration in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a structural and functional connectivity study. PLoS ONE 2012 (10), e13664.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2965124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21060689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woo C-W, Chang LJ, Lindquist MA, Wager TD, 2017. Building better biomarkers: brain models in translational neuroimaging. Nat. Neurosci 20 (3), 365.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5988350</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28230847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woolrich MW, Jbabdi S, Patenaude B, Chappell M, Makni S, Behrens T, Beckmann C, Jenkinson M, Smith SM, 2009. Bayesian analysis of neuroimaging data in FSL. Neuroimage 45 (1), S173&#x2013;S186.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19059349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Worsley KJ, Friston KJ, 1995. Analysis of fMRI time-series revisited - again. Neuroimage 2 (3), 173&#x2013;181.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9343600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zanette G, Tamburin S, Manganotti P, Refatti N, Forgione A, Rizzuto N, 2002. Different mechanisms contribute to motor cortex hyperexcitability in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin. Neurophysiol 113 (11), 1688&#x2013;1697.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12417221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>