<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35419115</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1875-8584</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>2022</Volume><PubDate><Year>2022</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Behavioural neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Behav Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Classification of Myopathy and Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Electromyograms Using Bat Algorithm and Deep Neural Networks.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>3517872</StartPage><MedlinePgn>3517872</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">3517872</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1155/2022/3517872</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Electromyograms (EMG) are a recorded galvanic action of nerves and muscles which assists in diagnosing the disorders associated with muscles and nerves. The efficient discrimination of abnormal EMG signals, myopathy and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, engage crucial role in automatic diagnostic assistance tools, since EMG signals are nonstationary signals. Hence, for computer-aided identification of abnormalities, extraction of features, selection of superlative feature subset, and developing an efficient classifier are indispensable. Initially, time domain and Wigner-Ville transformed time-frequency features were extracted from abnormal EMG signals for experiments. The selection of substantial characteristics from time and time-frequency features was performed using bat algorithm. Extensively, deep neural network classifier is modelled for selected feature subset using bat algorithm from extracted time and time-frequency features. The performance of deep neural network exerting selected features from bat algorithm was compared with conventional artificial neural network. Results demonstrate that the deep neural network modelled with layers 2 and 3 (neurons = 2 and 4) using time domain features is efficient in classifying the abnormalities of EMG signals with an accuracy, sensitivity, and specificity of 100% and also exhibited finer performance. Correspondingly, the developed conventional single layer artificial neural network (neurons = 7) with time domain features has shown an accuracy of 83.3%, sensitivity of 100%, and specificity of 71.42%. The work materializes the significance of conventional and deep neural network using time and time-frequency features in diagnosing the abnormal signals exists in neuromuscular system using efficient classification.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022 A. Bakiya et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bakiya</LastName><ForeName>A</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electronics and Communication Engineering, Vel Tech Rangarajan Dr. Sagunthala R&amp;D Institute of Science and Technology, Chennai 600062, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Anitha</LastName><ForeName>A</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>PG Department of Computer Science, Dwaraka Doss Goverdhan Doss Vaishnav College, Chennai-600106, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sridevi</LastName><ForeName>T</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>PG and Research Department of MCA, Dwaraka Doss Goverdhan Doss Vaishnav College, Chennai-600106, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kamalanand</LastName><ForeName>K</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4381-7630</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Instrumentation Engineering, MIT Campus, Anna University, Chennai-600044, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Behav Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8914585</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0953-4180</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000465" MajorTopicYN="N">Algorithms</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004576" MajorTopicYN="N">Electromyography</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009135" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscular Diseases</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016571" MajorTopicYN="N">Neural Networks, Computer</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors have no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35419115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9001138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2022/3517872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Reed S. M., Bayly W. M., Sellon D. C. Equine Internal Medicine-E-Book . Elsevier Health Sciences; 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blottner D., Salanova M., Blottner D., Salanova M. In The Neuro Muscular System: From Earth to Space Life Science . Springer International Publishing; 2015. Skeletal Muscle; pp. 9&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-3-319-12298-4_2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Artameeyanant P., Sultornsanee S., Chamnongthai K., Higuchi K. Classification of electromyogram using vertical visibility algorithm with support vector machine. In Asia-Pacific Signal and Information Processing Association, 2014 Annual Summit and Conference (APSIPA); 2014; Siem Reap, Cambodia. pp. 1&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/APSIPA.2014.7041820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Preston D. C., Shapiro B. E. Clinical-Electrophysiologic Correlations. Elsevier Health Sciences . Elsevier Health Sciences; 2013. Electromyography and neuromuscular disorders E-book.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rowland L. P., Shneider N. A. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. New England Journal of Medicine . 2001;344(22):1688&#x2013;1700. doi: 10.1056/NEJM200105313442207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJM200105313442207</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11386269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenway M. J., Andersen P. M., Russ C., et al. ANG mutations segregate with familial and 'sporadic' amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nature Genetics . 2006;38(4):411&#x2013;413. doi: 10.1038/ng1742.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ng1742</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16501576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadikoglu F., Kavalcioglu C., Dagman B. Electromyogram (EMG) signal detection, classification of EMG signals and diagnosis of neuropathy muscle disease. Procedia Computer Science . 2017;120:422&#x2013;429. doi: 10.1016/j.procs.2017.11.259.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.procs.2017.11.259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duque C. J. G., Mu&#xf1;oz L. D., Mej&#xed;a J. G., Trejos E. D. Discrete Wavelet Transform and K-Nn Classification in EMG Signals for Diagnosis of Neuromuscular Disorders. In Image, Signal Processing and Artificial Vision (STSIVA); 2014; Armenia, Colombia. pp. 1&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/STSIVA.2014.7010171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phinyomark A., Phukpattaranont P., Limsakul C. Feature reduction and selection for EMG signal classification. Expert Systems with Applications . 2012;39(8):7420&#x2013;7431. doi: 10.1016/j.eswa.2012.01.102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eswa.2012.01.102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nazmi N., Abdul Rahman M., Yamamoto S. I., Ahmad S., Zamzuri H., Mazlan S. A review of classification techniques of EMG signals during isotonic and isometric contractions. Sensors . 2016;16(8):p. 1304. doi: 10.3390/s16081304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s16081304</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5017469</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27548165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geethanjali P., Mohan Y. K., Sen J. Time domain feature extraction and classification of EEG data for brain computer interface. In 2012 9th International Conference on Fuzzy Systems and Knowledge Discovery; 2012; Chongqing, China. pp. 1136&#x2013;1139.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/FSKD.2012.6234336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oskoei M. A., Hu H. Myoelectric control systems--a survey. Biomedical Signal Processing and Control . 2007;2(4):275&#x2013;294. doi: 10.1016/j.bspc.2007.07.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bspc.2007.07.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vasanthi S. M., Jayasree T. Performance evaluation of pattern recognition networks using electromyography signal and time-domain features for the classification of hand gestures. Proceedings of the Institution of Mechanical Engineers, Part H: Journal of Engineering in Medicine . 2020;234(6):639&#x2013;648. doi: 10.1177/0954411920912119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0954411920912119</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32202473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma R. R., Kumar M., Pachori R. B. Biomedical and Clinical Engineering for Healthcare Advancement . IGI Global; 2020. Classification of EMG signals using eigenvalue decomposition-based time-frequency representation; pp. 118&#x2013;196.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4018/978-1-7998-0326-3.ch006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torres-Castillo J. R., L&#xf3;pez-L&#xf3;pez C. O., Padilla-Casta&#xf1;eda M. A. Neuromuscular disorders detection through time-frequency analysis and classification of multi-muscular EMG signals using Hilbert-Huang transform. Biomedical Signal Processing and Control . 2022;71, article 103037 doi: 10.1016/j.bspc.2021.103037.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bspc.2021.103037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhattacharjee D., Singh M. Time-Domain Feature and Ensemble Model Based Classification of EMG Signals for Hand Gesture Recognition . 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee K. H., Min J. Y., Byun S. Electromyogram-based classification of hand and finger gestures using artificial neural networks. Sensors . 2022;22(1):p. 225. doi: 10.3390/s22010225.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s22010225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8749583</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35009768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ullah A., Ali S., Khan I., Khan M. A., Faizullah S. Intelligent Systems and Applications . Springer, Cham; 2021. Effect of analysis window and feature selection on classification of hand movements using EMG signal.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-3-030-55190-2_30</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ambikapathy B., Kirshnamurthy K., Venkatesan R. Assessment of electromyograms using genetic algorithm and artificial neural networks. Evolutionary Intelligence . 2021;14(2):261&#x2013;271. doi: 10.1007/s12065-018-0174-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12065-018-0174-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ambikapathy B., Krishnamurthy K. Analysis of electromyograms recorded using invasive and noninvasive electrodes: a study based on entropy and Lyapunov exponents estimated using artificial neural networks. Journal of Ambient Intelligence and Humanized Computing . 2018:1&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1007/s12652-018-0811-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12652-018-0811-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hinton G., Deng L., Yu D., et al. Deep neural networks for acoustic modeling in speech recognition. IEEE Signal Processing Magazine . 2012;29(6):82&#x2013;97. doi: 10.1109/MSP.2012.2205597.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/MSP.2012.2205597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brunetti A., Buongiorno D., Trotta G. F., Bevilacqua V. Computer vision and deep learning techniques for pedestrian detection and tracking: a survey. Neurocomputing . 2018;300:17&#x2013;33. doi: 10.1016/j.neucom.2018.01.092.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neucom.2018.01.092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nikolic M.  
Signals EMG Decomposition, Findings and Firing Pattern Analysis in Controls and Patients with Myopathy and Amytrophic Lateral Sclerosis
. Faculty of Health Science, University of Copenhagen; 2001. Detailed Analysis of Clinical Electromyography. 
 http://www.emglab.net
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oskoei M. A., Hu H. Support vector machine-based classification scheme for myoelectric control applied to upper limb. IEEE Transactions on Biomedical Engineering . 2008;55(8):1956&#x2013;1965. doi: 10.1109/TBME.2008.919734.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TBME.2008.919734</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18632358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Subasi A. Classification of EMG signals using combined features and soft computing techniques. Applied Soft Computing . 2012;12(8):2188&#x2013;2198. doi: 10.1016/j.asoc.2012.03.035.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.asoc.2012.03.035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies M. R., Reisman S. S. Time frequency analysis of the electromyogram during fatigue. In Proceedings of 1994 20th Annual Northeast Bioengineering Conference; 1994; Springfield, MA, USA. pp. 93&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/NEBC.1994.305165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Too J., Abdullah A. R., Mohd Saad N., Tee W. EMG feature selection and classification using a Pbest-guide binary particle swarm optimization. Computation . 2019;7(1):p. 12. doi: 10.3390/computation7010012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/computation7010012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dragoman D. Applications of the Wigner distribution function in signal processing. EURASIP Journal on Advances in Signal Processing . 2005;2005(10) doi: 10.1155/ASP.2005.1520.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/ASP.2005.1520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qian S., Chen D. Decomposition of the Wigner-Ville distribution and time-frequency distribution series. IEEE Transactions on Signal Processing . 1994;42(10):2836&#x2013;2842. doi: 10.1109/78.324750.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/78.324750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Debnath L., Shah F. A. In Wavelet Transforms and their Applications . Boston, MA: Birkh&#xe4;user; 2015. The Wigner&#x2013;Ville distribution and time&#x2013;frequency signal analysis.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anitha A., Bakiya A. In Handbook of Machine Learning for Computational Optimization . CRC Press; Analysis of EMG signals using extreme learning machine with nature inspired feature selection techniques.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1201/9781003138020-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang X. S. Nature Inspired Cooperative Strategies for Optimization (NICSO 2010) Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg; 2010. A new metaheuristic bat-inspired algorithm; pp. 65&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-3-642-12538-6_6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakiya A., Kamalanand K., Rajinikanth V. Automated diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis using electromyograms and firefly algorithm based neural networks with fractional position update. Physical and Engineering Sciences in Medicine . 2021;44(4):1095&#x2013;1105. doi: 10.1007/s13246-021-01046-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13246-021-01046-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34398392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wulsin D. F., Gupta J. R., Mani R., Blanco J. A., Litt B. Modeling electroencephalography waveforms with semi-supervised deep belief nets: fast classification and anomaly measurement. Journal of Neural Engineerig . 2011;8(3, article 36015) doi: 10.1088/1741-2560/8/3/036015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1741-2560/8/3/036015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3193936</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21525569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner J. T., Page A., Mohsenin T., Oates T. In 2014 AAAI Spring Symposium Series . Symposium series; 2014. Deep belief networks used on high resolution multichannel electroencephalography data for seizure detection.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Y., He L. Deep learning in the EEG diagnosis of Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. In Asian Conference on Computer Vision; 2014; Springer, Cham.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jirayucharoensak S., Pan-Ngum S., Israsena P. EEG-based emotion recognition using deep learning network with principal component based covariate shift adaptation. The Scientific World Journal . 2014;2014:10. doi: 10.1155/2014/627892.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2014/627892</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4165739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25258728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakiya A., Kamalanand K., Rajinikanth V., Nayak R. S., Kadry S. Deep neural network assisted diagnosis of time-frequency transformed electromyograms. Multimedia Tools and Applications. . 2020;79(15-16):11051&#x2013;11067. doi: 10.1007/s11042-018-6561-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11042-018-6561-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barcel&#xf3; M. A., Povedano M., V&#xe1;zquez-Costa J. F., Franquet &#xc1;., Solans M., Saez M. Estimation of the prevalence and incidence of motor neuron diseases in two Spanish regions: Catalonia and Valencia. Scientific Reports . 2021;11(1):1&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7973725</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33737526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute of Neurological Disorders and Strokes Fact sheet.  2022,  https://www.ninds.nih.gov/Disorders/Patient-Caregiver-Education/Fact-Sheets/Amyotrophic-Lateral-Sclerosis-ALS-Fact-Sheet.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>