<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35426195</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>18</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1468-1331</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>29</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Dynamic Bayesian networks for stratification of disease progression in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2201</StartPage><EndPage>2210</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2201-2210</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/ene.15357</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND PURPOSE">Progression rate is quite variable in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS); thus, tools for profiling disease progression are essential for timely interventions. The objective was to apply dynamic Bayesian networks (DBNs) to establish the influence of clinical and demographic variables on disease progression rate.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">In all, 664 ALS patients from our database were included stratified into slow (SP), average (AP) and fast (FP) progressors, according to the Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Functional Rating Scale Revised (ALSFRS-R) rate of decay. The sdtDBN framework was used, a machine learning model which learnt optimal DBNs with both static (gender, age at onset, onset region, body mass index, disease duration at entry, familial history, revised El Escorial criteria and C9orf72) and dynamic (ALSFRS-R scores and sub-scores, forced vital capacity, maximum inspiratory pressure, maximum expiratory pressure and phrenic amplitude) variables.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Disease duration and body mass index at diagnosis are the foremost influences amongst static variables. Disease duration is the variable that better discriminates the three groups. Maximum expiratory pressure is the respiratory test with prevalent influence on all groups. ALSFRS score has a higher influence on FP, but lower on AP and SP. The bulbar sub-score has considerable influence on FP but limited on SP. Limb function has a more decisive influence on AP and SP. The respiratory sub-score has little influence in all groups. ALSFRS-R questions 1 (speech) and 9 (climbing stairs) are the most influential in FP and SP, respectively.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">The sdtDBN analysis identified five variables, easily obtained during clinical evaluation, which are the most influential for each progression group. This insightful information may help to improve prognosis and care.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022 European Academy of Neurology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gromicho</LastName><ForeName>Marta</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2111-4579</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Instituto de Medicina Molecular, Faculdade de Medicina, Universidade de Lisboa, Lisbon, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Le&#xe3;o</LastName><ForeName>Tiago</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Instituto Superior T&#xe9;cnico, Universidade de Lisboa, Lisbon, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oliveira Santos</LastName><ForeName>Miguel</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8290-0410</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Instituto de Medicina Molecular, Faculdade de Medicina, Universidade de Lisboa, Lisbon, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosciences and Mental Health, Centro Hospitalar Universit&#xe1;rio de Lisboa-Norte, Lisbon, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pinto</LastName><ForeName>Susana</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Instituto de Medicina Molecular, Faculdade de Medicina, Universidade de Lisboa, Lisbon, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Carvalho</LastName><ForeName>Alexandra M</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Instituto de Telecomunica&#xe7;&#xf5;es and Lisbon ELLIS Unit (LUMLIS), Instituto Superior T&#xe9;cnico, Universidade de Lisboa, Lisbon, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Madeira</LastName><ForeName>Sara C</ForeName><Initials>SC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>LASIGE, Faculdade de Ci&#xea;ncias, Universidade de Lisboa, Lisbon, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>De Carvalho</LastName><ForeName>Mamede</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7556-0158</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Instituto de Medicina Molecular, Faculdade de Medicina, Universidade de Lisboa, Lisbon, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosciences and Mental Health, Centro Hospitalar Universit&#xe1;rio de Lisboa-Norte, Lisbon, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9506311</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1351-5101</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><SupplMeshList><SupplMeshName Type="Disease" UI="C531617">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis 1</SupplMeshName></SupplMeshList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001499" MajorTopicYN="N">Bayes Theorem</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018450" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Progression</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014797" MajorTopicYN="N">Vital Capacity</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dynamic Bayesian networks</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">progression</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">stratification</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35426195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ene.15357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Longinetti E, Fang F. Epidemiology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Curr Opin Neurol. 2019;32(5):771-776. http://journals.lww.com/00019052-201910000-00018</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Swash M. Can selection of rapidly progressing patients shorten clinical trials in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis? Arch Neurol. 2006;63:557-560.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shoesmith CL, Findlater K, Rowe A, Strong MJ. Prognosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with respiratory onset. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2007;78(6):629-631. doi:10.1136/jnnp.2006.103564</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2; A, Logroscino G, Hardiman O, et al. Prognostic factors in ALS: a critical review. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2009;10(5-6):310-323. doi:10.3109/17482960802566824</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spencer KR, Foster ZW, Rauf NA, et al. Neuropathological profile of long-duration amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in military veterans. Brain Pathol. 2020;30(6):1028-1040. doi:10.1111/bpa.12876</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chipika RH, Finegan E, Li Hi Shing S, Hardiman O, Bede P. Tracking a fast-moving disease: longitudinal markers, monitoring, and clinical trial endpoints in ALS. Front Neurol. 2019;10:1-18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu L, He B, Zhang Y, et al. Prognostic models for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a systematic review. J Neurol. 2021;268(9):3361-3370. doi:10.1007/s00415-021-10508-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westeneng H-J, Debray TPA, Visser AE, et al. Prognosis for patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: development and validation of a personalised prediction model. Lancet Neurol. 2018;17(5):423-433. https://linkinghub.elsevier.com/retrieve/pii/S1474442218300899</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon PH, Cheung YK, Kimura F. Progression rate of ALSFRS-R at time of diagnosis predicts survival time in ALS. Neurology. 2006;67(7):1314-1315. doi:10.1212/01.wnl.0000243807.14293.07</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kimura F, Fujimura C, Ishida S, et al. Progression rate of ALSFRS-R at time of diagnosis predicts survival time in ALS. Neurology. 2006;66(2):265-267.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pires S, Gromicho M, Pinto S, Carvalho M, Madeira SC. Predicting non-invasive ventilation in ALS patients using stratified disease progression groups. 2018 IEEE International Conference on Data Mining Workshops (ICDMW). IEEE; 2018: 748-757. https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/8637368/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pfohl SR, Kim RB, Coan GS, Mitchell CS. Unraveling the complexity of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis survival prediction. Front Neuroinform. 2018;12:36. http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/29962944%0Ahttp://www.pubmedcentral.nih.gov/articlerender.fcgi?artid=PMC6010549%0Ahttps://www.frontiersin.org/article/10.3389/fninf.2018.00036/full</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koller D, Friedma N. Probabilistic Graphical Models: Principles and Techniques. MIT Press; 2009: 1272.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russell S, Norvig P, Davis E. Artificial Intelligence: A Modern Approach, 3rd edition. Prentice Hall; 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carvalho AM. Scoring Functions for Learning Bayesian Networks. INESC-ID; 2009: 46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le&#xe3;o T, Madeira SC, Gromicho M, de Carvalho M, Carvalho AM. Learning dynamic Bayesian networks from time-dependent and time-independent data: unraveling disease progression in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Biomed Inform. 2021;117:103730. https://linkinghub.elsevier.com/retrieve/pii/S1532046421000599</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zandon&#xe0; A, Vasta R, Chi&#xf2; A, Di Camillo B. A dynamic Bayesian network model for the simulation of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis progression. BMC Bioinformatics. 2019;20(S4):118. https://bmcbioinformatics.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12859-019-2692-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahangaran M, Jahed-Motlagh MR, Minaei-Bidgoli B. A novel method for predicting the progression rate of ALS disease based on automatic generation of probabilistic causal chains. Artif Intell Med. 2020;107:101879. https://linkinghub.elsevier.com/retrieve/pii/S0933365719310152</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum JM, Stambler N, Malta E, et al. The ALSFRS-R: a revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. J Neurol Sci. 1999;169(1-2):13-21. https://linkinghub.elsevier.com/retrieve/pii/S0022510X99002105</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinto S, De Carvalho M. The R of ALSFRS-R: does it really mirror functional respiratory involvement in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis? Amyotroph Lateral Scler Front Degener. 2015;16(1-2):120-123. doi:10.3109/21678421.2014.952641</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franchignoni F, Mora G, Giordano A, Volanti P, Chi&#xf2; A. Evidence of multidimensionality in the ALSFRS-R scale: a critical appraisal on its measurement properties using Rasch analysis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2013;84(12):1340-1345.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Witten IH, Frank E, Hall MA, Pal CJ. Data Mining: Practical Machine Learning Tools and Techniques. Morgan Kaufmann Publishers Inc.; 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grollemund V, Pradat P, Querin G, et al. Machine learning in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: achievements, pitfalls, and future directions. Front Neurosci. 2019;13:1-28. https://www.frontiersin.org/article/10.3389/fnins.2019.00135/full</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karanevich AG, Statland JM, Gajewski BJ, He J. Using an onset-anchored Bayesian hierarchical model to improve predictions for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis disease progression. BMC Med Res Methodol. 2018;18(1):19. https://bmcmedresmethodol.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12874-018-0479-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kueffner R, Zach N, Bronfeld M, et al. Stratification of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients: a crowdsourcing approach. Sci Rep. 2019;9(1):1-14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miltenberger-Miltenyi G, Concei&#xe7;&#xe3;o VA, Gromicho M, et al. C9orf72 expansion is associated with accelerated decline of respiratory function and decreased survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2019;90(1):118-120.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rooney J, Murray D, Campion A, et al. The C9orf72 expansion is associated with accelerated respiratory function decline in a large amyotrophic lateral sclerosis cohort. HRB Open Res. 2019;2:23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moglia C, Calvo A, Grassano M, et al. Early weight loss in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: outcome relevance and clinical correlates in a population-based cohort. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2019;90(6):666-673. http://jnnp.bmj.com/content/90/6/666.abstract</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimizu T, Nakayama Y, Matsuda C, et al. Prognostic significance of body weight variation after diagnosis in ALS: a single-centre prospective cohort study. J Neurol. 2019;266(6):1412-1420. doi:10.1007/s00415-019-09276-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pirola A, De Mattia E, Lizio A, et al. The prognostic value of spirometric tests in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. Clin Neurol Neurosurg. 2019;184:105456.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinto S, Pinto A, de Carvalho M. Phrenic nerve studies predict survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Neurophysiol. 2012;123(12):2454-2459. doi:10.1016/j.clinph.2012.05.012</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calvo A, Moglia C, Lunetta C, et al. Factors predicting survival in ALS: a multicenter Italian study. J Neurol. 2017;264(1):54-63. http://link.springer.com/10.1007/s00415-016-8313-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dorst J, Chen L, Rosenbohm A, et al. Prognostic factors in ALS: a comparison between Germany and China. J Neurol. 2019;266(6):1516-1525. doi:10.1007/s00415-019-09290-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kjaeldgaard A-L, Pilely K, Olsen KS, et al. Prediction of survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a nationwide, Danish cohort study. BMC Neurol. 2021;21:164. https://bmcneurol.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12883-021-02187-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Creemers H, Grupstra H, Nollet F, van den Berg LH, Beelen A. Prognostic factors for the course of functional status of patients with ALS: a systematic review. J Neurol. 2015;262(6):1407-1423. doi:10.1007/s00415-014-7564-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ong M, Tan PF, Holbrook JD. Predicting functional decline and survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. PLoS One. 2017;12(4):e0174925. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0174925</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watanabe H, Atsuta N, Nakamura R, et al. Factors affecting longitudinal functional decline and survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Front Degener. 2015;16(3-4):230-236.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandrioli J, Biguzzi S, Guidi C, et al. Heterogeneity in ALSFRS-R decline and survival: a population-based study in Italy. Neurol Sci. 2015;36(12):2243-2252.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schito P, Ceccardi G, Calvo A, et al. Clinical features and outcomes of the flail arm and flail leg and pure lower motor neuron MND variants: a multicentre Italian study. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2020;91(9):1001-1003. doi:10.1136/jnnp-2020-323542</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wijesekera LC, Mathers S, Galtrey C, et al. Natural history and clinical features of the flail arm and flail leg ALS variants. Neurology. 2009;72(12):1087-1094.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rooney J, Burke T, Vajda A, Heverin M, Hardiman O. What does the ALSFRS-R really measure? A longitudinal and survival analysis of functional dimension subscores in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2016;88(5):381-385. http://jnnp.bmj.com/content/early/2016/11/25/jnnp-2016-314661.abstract</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakker LA, Schr&#xf6;der CD, van Es MA, Westers P, Visser-Meily JMA, van den Berg LH. Assessment of the factorial validity and reliability of the ALSFRS-R: a revision of its measurement model. J Neurol. 2017;264(7):1413-1420.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinto S, Gromicho M, de Carvalho M. Sialorrhoea and reversals in ALS functional rating scale. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2017;88(2):187-188. doi:10.1136/jnnp-2016-313614</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robison R, DiBiase L, Ashley A, et al. Swallowing safety and efficiency impairment profiles in individuals with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Dysphagia. 2022;37(3):644-654. doi:10.1007/s00455-021-10315-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chahin N, Klein C, Mandrekar J, Sorenson E. Natural history of spinal-bulbar muscular atrophy. Neurology. 2008;70(21):1967-1971.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon J, Lerner B. Insights into amyotrophic lateral sclerosis from a machine learning perspective. J Clin Med. 2019;8(10):1578. https://www.mdpi.com/2077-0383/8/10/1578</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elamin M, Bede P, Byrne S, et al. Cognitive changes predict functional decline in ALS: a population-based longitudinal study. Neurology. 2013;80(17):1590-1597. doi:10.1212/WNL.0b013e31828f18ac</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gromicho M, Figueiral M, Uysal H, et al. Spreading in ALS: the relative impact of upper and lower motor neuron involvement. Ann Clin Transl Neurol. 2020;7(7):1181-1192. doi:10.1002/acn3.51098</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blasco H, Patin F, Descat A, et al. A pharmaco-metabolomics approach in a clinical trial of ALS: identification of predictive markers of progression. PLoS One. 2018;13(6):e0198116. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0198116</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grollemund V, Le CG, Secchi-Buhour M-S, Delbot F, Pradat-Peyre J-F, Bede P. Development and validation of a 1-year survival prognosis estimation model for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis using manifold learning algorithm UMAP. Sci Rep. 2020;10(1):13378. doi:10.1038/s41598-020-70125-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bede P, Murad A, Lope J, et al. Phenotypic categorisation of individual subjects with motor neuron disease based on radiological disease burden patterns: a machine-learning approach. J Neurol Sci. 2022;432:120079. doi:10.1016/j.jns.2021.120079</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>