<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35445401</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1873-3468</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>596</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>FEBS letters</Title><ISOAbbreviation>FEBS Lett</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Valosin-containing protein regulates the stability of fused in sarcoma granules in cells by changing ATP concentrations.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1412</StartPage><EndPage>1423</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1412-1423</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/1873-3468.14353</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Fused in sarcoma (FUS), a DNA/RNA-binding protein, undergoes liquid-liquid phase separation to form granules in cells. Aberrant FUS granulation is associated with neurodegenerative diseases, including amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal lobar degeneration. We found that FUS granules contain a multifunctional AAA ATPase, valosin-containing protein (VCP), which is known as a key regulator of protein degradation. FUS granule stability depends on ATP concentrations in cells. VCP ATPase changes the FUS granule stability time-dependently by consuming ATP to reduce its concentrations in the granules: VCPs in de&#x2009;novo FUS granules stabilize the granules, while long-lasting VCP colocalization destabilizes the granules. The proteolysis-promoting function of VCP may subsequently dissolve the unstabilized granules. We propose that VCP colocalized to the FUS granules acts as a timer to limit the residence time of the granules in cells.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022 Federation of European Biochemical Societies.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yasuda</LastName><ForeName>Kyota</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mathematical and Life Sciences, Graduate School of Integrated Sciences for Life, Hiroshima University, Higashi-Hiroshima, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Center for the Mathematics on Chromatin Live Dynamics (RcMcD), Hiroshima University, Higashi-Hiroshima, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Watanabe</LastName><ForeName>Tomonobu M</ForeName><Initials>TM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory for Comprehensive Bioimaging, RIKEN Center for Biosystems Dynamics Research (BDR), Kobe, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Stem Cell Biology, Research Institute for Radiation Biology and Medicine, Hiroshima University, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kang</LastName><ForeName>Myeong-Gyun</ForeName><Initials>MG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, School of Biological Sciences, Seoul National University, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Seo</LastName><ForeName>Jeong Kon</ForeName><Initials>JK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>UNIST Central Research Facilities (UCRF), Ulsan National Institute of Science and Technology (UNIST), Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rhee</LastName><ForeName>Hyun-Woo</ForeName><Initials>HW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, School of Biological Sciences, Seoul National University, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tate</LastName><ForeName>Shin-Ichi</ForeName><Initials>SI</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5556-7712</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mathematical and Life Sciences, Graduate School of Integrated Sciences for Life, Hiroshima University, Higashi-Hiroshima, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Center for the Mathematics on Chromatin Live Dynamics (RcMcD), Hiroshima University, Higashi-Hiroshima, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>FEBS Lett</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0155157</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0014-5793</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D034702">RNA-Binding Protein FUS</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>8L70Q75FXE</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000255">Adenosine Triphosphate</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 3.6.4.6</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000074405">Valosin Containing Protein</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000255" MajorTopicYN="N">Adenosine Triphosphate</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057174" MajorTopicYN="Y">Frontotemporal Lobar Degeneration</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D034702" MajorTopicYN="N">RNA-Binding Protein FUS</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012509" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sarcoma</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000074405" MajorTopicYN="N">Valosin Containing Protein</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ALS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ATP</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">FUS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">VCP</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">liquid-liquid phase separation</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35445401</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/1873-3468.14353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Crozat A, &#xc5;man P, Mandahl N, Ron D. Fusion of CHOP to a novel RNA-binding protein in human myxoid liposarcoma. Nature. 1993;363:640-4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee BJ, Cansizoglu AE, S&#xfc;el KE, Louis TH, Zhang Z, Chook YM. Rules for nuclear localization sequence recognition by karyopherin&#x3b2;2. Cell. 2006;126:543-58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackenzie IRA, Neumann M. Fused in sarcoma neuropathology in neurodegenerative disease. Cold Spring Harb Perspect Med. 2017;7:a024299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iko Y, Kodama TS, Kasai N, Oyama T, Morita EH, Muto T, et&#x2009;al. Domain architectures and characterization of an RNA-binding protein, TLS. J Biol Chem. 2004;279:44834-40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel A, Lee H, Jawerth L, Maharana S, Jahnel M, Hein M, et&#x2009;al. A liquid-to-solid phase transition of the ALS protein FUS accelerated by disease mutation. Cell. 2015;162:1066-77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen C, Ding X, Akram N, Xue S, Luo S-Z. Fused in sarcoma: properties, self-assembly and correlation with neurodegenerative diseases. Molecules. 2019;24:1622.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verdile V, De Paola E, Paronetto MP. Aberrant phase transitions: side effects and novel therapeutic strategies in human disease. Front Genet. 10:173.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calabretta S, Richard S. Emerging roles of disordered sequences in RNA-binding proteins. Trends Biochem Sci. 2015;40:662-72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watts G, Thomasova D, Ramdeen SK, Fulchiero EC, Mehta SG, Drachman DA, et&#x2009;al. Novel VCP mutations in inclusion body myopathy associated with Paget disease of bone and frontotemporal dementia. Clin Genet. 2007;72:420-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson JO, Mandrioli J, Benatar M, Abramzon Y, Van Deerlin VM, Trojanowski JQ, et&#x2009;al. Exome sequencing reveals VCP mutations as a cause of familial ALS. Neuron. 2010;68:857-64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun X, Qiu H. Valosin-containing protein, a calcium-associated ATPase protein, in endoplasmic reticulum and mitochondrial function and its implications for diseases. Int J Mol Sci. 2020;21:3842.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stolz A, Hilt W, Buchberger A, Wolf DH. Cdc48: a power machine in protein degradation. Trends Biochem Sci. 2011;36:515-23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai R-M, Chen E, Longo DL, Gorbea CM, Li C-CH. Involvement of valosin-containing protein, an ATPase co-purified with I&#x3ba;B&#x3b1; and 26 S proteasome, in ubiquitin-proteasome-mediated degradation of I&#x3ba;B&#x3b1;. J Biol Chem. 1998;273:3562-73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai RM, Li C-CH. Valosin-containing protein is a multi-ubiquitin chain-targeting factor required in ubiquitin-proteasome degradation. Nat Cell Biol. 2001;3:740-4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia D, Tang WK, Ye Y. Structure and function of the AAA+ ATPase p97/Cdc48p. Gene. 2016;583:64-77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tyzack GE, Luisier R, Taha DM, Neeves J, Modic M, Mitchell JS, et&#x2009;al. Widespread FUS mislocalization is a molecular hallmark of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain. 2019;142:2572-80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu G, Byrd A, Warner AN, Pei F, Basha E, Buchanan A, et&#x2009;al. Cdc48/VCP and endocytosis regulate TDP-43 and FUS toxicity and turnover. Mol Cell Biol. 2020;40:e00256-19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ju J-S, Fuentealba RA, Miller SE, Jackson E, Piwnica-Worms D, Baloh RH, et&#x2009;al. Valosin-containing protein (VCP) is required for autophagy and is disrupted in VCP disease. J Cell Biol. 2009;187:875-88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang T, Jiang X, Chen G, Xu J. Interaction of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis/frontotemporal lobar degeneration-associated fused-in-sarcoma with proteins involved in metabolic and protein degradation pathways. Neurobiol Aging. 2015;36:527-35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang J, Lim L, Song J. ATP enhances at low concentrations but dissolves at high concentrations liquid-liquid phase separation (LLPS) of ALS/FTD-causing FUS. Biochem Biophys Res Comm. 2018;504:545-51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel A, Malinovska L, Saha S, Wang J, Alberti S, Krishnan Y, et&#x2009;al. ATP as a biological hydrotrope. Science. 2017;356:753-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshida T, Kakizuka A, Imamura H. BTeam, a novel BRET-based biosensor for the accurate quantification of ATP concentration within living cells. Sci Rep. 2016;6:39618.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasuda K, Zhang H, Loiselle D, Haystead T, Macara IG, Mili S. The RNA-binding protein Fus directs translation of localized mRNAs in APC-RNP granules. J Cell Biol. 2013;203:737-46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasuda K, Clatterbuck-Soper SF, Jackrel ME, Shorter J, Mili S. FUS inclusions disrupt RNA localization by sequestering kinesin-1 and inhibiting microtubule detyrosination. J Cell Biol. 2017;216:1015-34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kotera I, Iwasaki T, Imamura H, Noji H, Nagai T. Reversible dimerization of Aequorea victoria fluorescent proteins increases the dynamic range of FRET-based indicators. ACS Chem Biol. 2010;5:215-22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morikawa TJ, Fujita H, Kitamura A, Horio T, Yamamoto J, Kinjo M, et&#x2009;al. Dependence of fluorescent protein brightness on protein concentration in solution and enhancement of it. Sci Rep. 2016;6:22342.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goehring NW, Chowdhury D, Hyman AA, Grill SW. FRAP analysis of membrane-associated proteins: lateral diffusion and membrane-cytoplasmic exchange. Biophys J. 2010;99:2443-52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mishra PK, Yoo CM, Hong E, Rhee HW. Photo-crosslinking: an emerging chemical tool for investigating molecular networks in live cells. ChemBioChem. 2020;21:924-32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Axelrod D, Koppel DE, Schlessinger J, Elson E, Webb WW. Mobility measurement by analysis of fluorescence photobleaching recovery kinetics. Biophys J. 1976;16:1055-69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer H, Bug M, Bremer S. Emerging functions of the VCP/p97 AAA-ATPase in the ubiquitin system. Nat Cell Biol. 2012;14:117-23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang N, Shen Y, Fei X, Sheng K, Sun P, Qiu Y, et&#x2009;al. Valosin-containing protein regulates the proteasome-mediated degradation of DNA-PKcs in glioma cells. Cell Death Dis. 2013;4:e647.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jain S, Wheeler J, Walters R, Agrawal A, Barsic A, Parker R. ATPase-modulated stress granules contain a diverse proteome and substructure. Cell. 2016;164:487-98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niwa H, Ewens CA, Tsang C, Yeung HO, Zhang X, Freemont PS. The role of the N-domain in the ATPase activity of the mammalian AAA ATPase p97/VCP. J&#x2009;Biol Chem. 2012;287:8561-70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer H, Weihl CC. The VCP/p97 system at a glance: connecting cellular function to disease pathogenesis. J&#x2009;Cell Sci. 2014;127:3877-83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halawani D, LeBlanc AC, Rouiller I, Michnick SW, Servant MJ, Latterich M. Hereditary inclusion body myopathy-linked p97/VCP mutations in the NH2 domain and the D1 ring modulate p97/VCP ATPase activity and D2 ring conformation. Mol Cell Biol. 2009;29:4484-94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gitcho MA, Strider J, Carter D, Taylor-Reinwald L, Forman MS, Goate AM, et&#x2009;al. VCP mutations causing frontotemporal lobar degeneration disrupt localization of TDP-43 and induce cell death. J Biol Chem. 2009;284:12384-98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Imamura H, Huynh Nhat KP, Togawa H, Saito K, Iino R, Kato-Yamada Y, et&#x2009;al. Visualization of ATP levels inside single living cells with fluorescence resonance energy transfer-based genetically encoded indicators. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2009;106:15651-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Imamura T, Izumi H, Nagatani G, Ise T, Nomoto M, Iwamoto Y, et&#x2009;al. Interaction with p53 enhances binding of cisplatin-modified DNA by high mobility group 1 protein. J Biol Chem. 2001;276:7534-40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchan JR, Kolaitis R-M, Taylor JP, Parker R. Eukaryotic stress granules are cleared by autophagy and Cdc48/VCP function. Cell. 2013;153:1461-74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shiina N. Liquid- and solid-like RNA granules form through specific scaffold proteins and combine into biphasic granules. J Biol Chem. 2019;294:3532-48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwiatkowski TJ, Bosco DA, Leclerc AL, Tamrazian E, Vanderburg CR, Russ C, et&#x2009;al. Mutations in the FUS/TLS gene on chromosome 16 cause familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Science. 2009;323:1205-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nomura T, Watanabe S, Kaneko K, Yamanaka K, Nukina N, Furukawa Y. Intranuclear aggregation of mutant FUS/TLS as a molecular pathomechanism of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Biol Chem. 2014;289:1192-202.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vance C, Rogelj B, Hortob&#xe1;gyi T, De Vos KJ, Nishimura AL, Sreedharan J, et&#x2009;al. Mutations in FUS, an RNA processing protein, cause familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis type 6. Science. 2009;323:1208-11.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>