<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">35467758</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>19</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2362</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>52</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of clinical investigation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Clin Invest</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Redox profiles of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis lymphoblasts with or without known SOD1 mutations.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e13798</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e13798</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/eci.13798</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) is a fatal and rapidly progressing neurodegenerative disease that affects motor neurons. This disease is associated with oxidative stress especially in mutant superoxide dismutase 1 (mutSOD1) patients. However, less is known for the most prevalent sporadic ALS form, due to a lack of disease models. Here, we studied oxidative stress profiles in lymphoblasts from ALS patients with mutSOD1 or unknown (undSOD1) mutations.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">mutSOD1 and undSOD1 lymphoblasts, as well as sex/age-matched controls (3/group) were obtained from Coriell and divided into 46&#xa0;years-old-men (C1), 46&#xa0;years-old-women (C2) or 26/27&#xa0;years-old-men (C3) cohorts. Growth curves were performed, and several parameters associated with redox homeostasis were evaluated, including SOD activity and expression, general oxidative stress levels, lipid peroxidation, response to oxidative stimulus, glutathione redox cycle, catalase expression, and activity, and Nrf2 transcripts. Pooled (all cohorts) and paired (intra-cohort) statistical analyses were performed, followed by clustering and principal component analyses (PCA).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Although a high heterogeneity among lymphoblast redox profiles was found between cohorts, clustering analysis based on 7 parameters with high chi-square ranking (total SOD activity, oxidative stress levels, catalase transcripts, SOD1 protein levels, metabolic response to mM concentrations of tert-butyl hydroperoxide, glutathione reductase activity, and Nrf2 transcript levels) provided a perfect cluster segregation between samples from healthy controls and ALS (undSOD1 and mutSOD1), also visualized in the PCA.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Our results show distinct redox signatures in lymphoblasts from mutSOD1, undSOD1 and healthy controls that can be used as therapeutic targets for ALS drug development.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022 Stichting European Society for Clinical Investigation Journal Foundation. Published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cunha-Oliveira</LastName><ForeName>Teresa</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7382-0339</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>CNC-Center for Neuroscience and Cell Biology, CIBB - Centre for Innovative Biomedicine and Biotechnology, University of Coimbra, Coimbra, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Silva</LastName><ForeName>Daniela Franco</ForeName><Initials>DF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>CNC-Center for Neuroscience and Cell Biology, CIBB - Centre for Innovative Biomedicine and Biotechnology, University of Coimbra, Coimbra, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Segura</LastName><ForeName>Luis</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Santa Casa de S&#xe3;o Paulo School of Medical Science, Physiological Sciences, S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Baldeiras</LastName><ForeName>In&#xea;s</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>CNC-Center for Neuroscience and Cell Biology, CIBB - Centre for Innovative Biomedicine and Biotechnology, University of Coimbra, Coimbra, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>FMUC - Faculty of Medicine, University of Coimbra, Coimbra, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Marques</LastName><ForeName>Ricardo</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4749-7523</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>CNC-Center for Neuroscience and Cell Biology, CIBB - Centre for Innovative Biomedicine and Biotechnology, University of Coimbra, Coimbra, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health School of the Polytechnic Institute of Guarda, Guarda, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rosenstock</LastName><ForeName>Tatiana</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacology, University of S&#xe3;o Paulo, S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sygnature Discovery, In vitro Neuroscience, Nottingham, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oliveira</LastName><ForeName>Paulo J</ForeName><Initials>PJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5201-9948</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>CNC-Center for Neuroscience and Cell Biology, CIBB - Centre for Innovative Biomedicine and Biotechnology, University of Coimbra, Coimbra, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Silva</LastName><ForeName>Filomena S G</ForeName><Initials>FSG</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7143-8905</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>CNC-Center for Neuroscience and Cell Biology, CIBB - Centre for Innovative Biomedicine and Biotechnology, University of Coimbra, Coimbra, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mitotag Lda, Cantanhede, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>POCI-01-0145-FEDER-029297</GrantID><Agency>Fundo Regional para a Ci&#xea;ncia e Tecnologia</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>POCI-01-0145-FEDER-029391</GrantID><Agency>Fundo Regional para a Ci&#xea;ncia e Tecnologia</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>DL57/2016/CP1448/CT0016</GrantID><Agency>Funda&#xe7;&#xe3;o para a Ci&#xea;ncia e a Tecnologia</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>LA/P/0058/2020</GrantID><Agency>Funda&#xe7;&#xe3;o para a Ci&#xea;ncia e a Tecnologia</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>PTDC/BTM-ORG/0055/2021</GrantID><Agency>Funda&#xe7;&#xe3;o para a Ci&#xea;ncia e a Tecnologia</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>PTDC/BTM-SAL/29297/2017</GrantID><Agency>Funda&#xe7;&#xe3;o para a Ci&#xea;ncia e a Tecnologia</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>PTDC/MED-FAR/29391/2017</GrantID><Agency>Funda&#xe7;&#xe3;o para a Ci&#xea;ncia e a Tecnologia</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>UIDB/04539/2020</GrantID><Agency>Funda&#xe7;&#xe3;o para a Ci&#xea;ncia e a Tecnologia</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>UIDP/04539/2020</GrantID><Agency>Funda&#xe7;&#xe3;o para a Ci&#xea;ncia e a Tecnologia</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Clin Invest</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0245331</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0014-2972</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D051267">NF-E2-Related Factor 2</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C000606290">SOD1 protein, human</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 1.11.1.6</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D002374">Catalase</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 1.15.1.1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000072105">Superoxide Dismutase-1</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002374" MajorTopicYN="N">Catalase</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009154" MajorTopicYN="N">Mutation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051267" MajorTopicYN="N">NF-E2-Related Factor 2</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010084" MajorTopicYN="N">Oxidation-Reduction</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000072105" MajorTopicYN="Y">Superoxide Dismutase-1</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mitochondria</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">oxidative stress</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">superoxide dismutase 1</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35467758</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/eci.13798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Abu-Hamad S, Kahn J, Leyton-Jaimes MF, Rosenblatt J, Israelson A. Misfolded SOD1 accumulation and mitochondrial association contribute to the selective vulnerability of motor neurons in familial ALS: correlation to human disease. ACS Chem Neurosci. 2017;8(10):2225-2234.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walczak J, Debska-Vielhaber G, Vielhaber S, et al. Distinction of sporadic and familial forms of ALS based on mitochondrial characteristics. FASEB J. 2019;33(3):4388-4403.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benjaminsen E, Alstadhaug KB, Gulsvik M, Baloch FK, Odeh F. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in Nordland county, Norway, 2000-2015: prevalence, incidence, and clinical features. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2018;19(7-8):522-527.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins CM, Jung C, Ding H, Xu Z. Mutant Cu, Zn superoxide dismutase that causes motoneuron degeneration is present in mitochondria in the CNS. J Neurosci. 2002;22(6):RC215.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fogarty MJ, Noakes PG, Bellingham MC. Motor cortex layer V pyramidal neurons exhibit dendritic regression, spine loss, and increased synaptic excitation in the presymptomatic hSOD1(G93A) mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurosci. 2015;35(2):643-647.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cunha-Oliveira T, Montezinho L, Mendes C, et al. Oxidative stress in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: pathophysiology and opportunities for pharmacological intervention. Oxid Med Cell Longev. 2020;2020:5021694.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCombe PA, Henderson RD. Effects of gender in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Gend Med. 2010;7(6):557-570.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrews JA, Jackson CE, Heiman-Patterson TD, Bettica P, Brooks BR, Pioro EP. Real-world evidence of riluzole effectiveness in treating amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2020;21(7-8):509-518.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Group WGOBOTEAS. Safety and efficacy of edaravone in well defined patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Lancet Neurol. 2017;16(7):505-512.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshino H, Kimura A. Investigation of the therapeutic effects of edaravone, a free radical scavenger, on amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (Phase II study). Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2006;7(4):241-245.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Group WGOBOTEAS. Exploratory double-blind, parallel-group placebo-controlled extension study of edaravone (MCI-186) in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2017;18(sup1):20-31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zarei S, Carr K, Reiley L, et al. A comprehensive review of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Surg Neurol Int. 2015;6:171.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrew AS, Bradley WG, Peipert D, et al. Risk factors for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a regional United States case-control study. Muscle Nerve. 2021;63(1):52-59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ingre C, Roos PM, Piehl F, Kamel F, Fang F. Risk factors for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Epidemiol. 2015;7:181-193.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang MD, Little J, Gomes J, Cashman NR, Krewski D. Identification of risk factors associated with onset and progression of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis using systematic review and meta-analysis. Neurotoxicology. 2017;61:101-130.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malek AM, Barchowsky A, Bowser R, et al. Environmental and occupational risk factors for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a case-control study. Neurodegener Dis. 2014;14(1):31-38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brito MD, da Silva GFG, Tilieri EM, Araujo BG, Calio ML, Rosenstock TR. Metabolic alteration and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis outcome: a systematic review. Front Neurol. 2019;10:1205.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Chalabi A, Hardiman O. The epidemiology of ALS: a conspiracy of genes, environment and time. Nat Rev Neurol. 2013;9(11):617-628.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu B, Pamphlett R. Environmental insults: critical triggers for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Transl Neurodegener. 2017;6:15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mejzini R, Flynn LL, Pitout IL, Fletcher S, Wilton SD, Akkari PA. ALS genetics, mechanisms, and therapeutics: where are we now? Front Neurosci. 2019;13:1310.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosen DR, Siddique T, Patterson D, et al. Mutations in Cu/Zn superoxide dismutase gene are associated with familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nature. 1993;362(6415):59-62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henden L, Twine NA, Szul P, et al. Identity by descent analysis identifies founder events and links SOD1 familial and sporadic ALS cases. NPJ Genom Med. 2020;5:32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pickles S, Semmler S, Broom HR, et al. ALS-linked misfolded SOD1 species have divergent impacts on mitochondria. Acta Neuropathol Commun. 2016;4(1):43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tokuda E, Takei YI, Ohara S, Fujiwara N, Hozumi I, Furukawa Y. Wild-type Cu/Zn-superoxide dismutase is misfolded in cerebrospinal fluid of sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Mol Neurodegener. 2019;14(1):42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones CT, Swingler RJ, Simpson SA, Brock DJ. Superoxide dismutase mutations in an unselected cohort of Scottish amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. J Med Genet. 1995;32(4):290-292.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gamez J, Corbera-Bellalta M, Nogales G, et al. Mutational analysis of the Cu/Zn superoxide dismutase gene in a Catalan ALS population: should all sporadic ALS cases also be screened for SOD1? J Neurol Sci. 2006;247(1):21-28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corrado L, D'Alfonso S, Bergamaschi L, et al. SOD1 gene mutations in Italian patients with sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). Neuromuscul Disord. 2006;16(11):800-804.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chio A, Traynor BJ, Lombardo F, et al. Prevalence of SOD1 mutations in the Italian ALS population. Neurology. 2008;70(7):533-537.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith EF, Shaw PJ, De Vos KJ. The role of mitochondria in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurosci Lett. 2019;710:132933.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Zundert B, Peuscher MH, Hynynen M, et al. Neonatal neuronal circuitry shows hyperexcitable disturbance in a mouse model of the adult-onset neurodegenerative disease amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurosci. 2008;28(43):10864-10874.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rojas F, Gonzalez D, Cortes N, et al. Reactive oxygen species trigger motoneuron death in non-cell-autonomous models of ALS through activation of c-Abl signaling. Front Cell Neurosci. 2015;9:203.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Araujo BG, Souza ESLF, de Barros Torresi JL, et al. Decreased mitochondrial function, biogenesis, and degradation in peripheral blood mononuclear cells from amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients as a potential tool for biomarker research. Mol Neurobiol. 2020;57(12):5084-5102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calingasan NY, Chen J, Kiaei M, Beal MF. Beta-amyloid 42 accumulation in the lumbar spinal cord motor neurons of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. Neurobiol Dis. 2005;19(1-2):340-347.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrante RJ, Browne SE, Shinobu LA, et al. Evidence of increased oxidative damage in both sporadic and familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurochem. 1997;69(5):2064-2074.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaw PJ, Ince PG, Falkous G, Mantle D. Oxidative damage to protein in sporadic motor neuron disease spinal cord. Ann Neurol. 1995;38(4):691-695.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shibata N, Nagai R, Uchida K, et al. Morphological evidence for lipid peroxidation and protein glycoxidation in spinal cords from sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. Brain Res. 2001;917(1):97-104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fitzmaurice PS, Shaw IC, Kleiner HE, et al. Evidence for DNA damage in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 1996;19(6):797-798.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ihara Y, Nobukuni K, Takata H, Hayabara T. Oxidative stress and metal content in blood and cerebrospinal fluid of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients with and without a Cu, Zn-superoxide dismutase mutation. Neurol Res. 2005;27(1):105-108.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simpson EP, Henry YK, Henkel JS, Smith RG, Appel SH. Increased lipid peroxidation in sera of ALS patients: a potential biomarker of disease burden. Neurology. 2004;62(10):1758-1765.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith RG, Henry YK, Mattson MP, Appel SH. Presence of 4-hydroxynonenal in cerebrospinal fluid of patients with sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol. 1998;44(4):696-699.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tohgi H, Abe T, Yamazaki K, Murata T, Ishizaki E, Isobe C. Remarkable increase in cerebrospinal fluid 3-nitrotyrosine in patients with sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol. 1999;46(1):129-131.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weishaupt JH, Bartels C, Polking E, et al. Reduced oxidative damage in ALS by high-dose enteral melatonin treatment. J Pineal Res. 2006;41(4):313-323.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blasco H, Garcon G, Patin F, et al. Panel of oxidative stress and inflammatory biomarkers in ALS: a pilot study. Can J Neurol Sci. 2017;44(1):90-95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>LoGerfo A, Chico L, Borgia L, et al. Lack of association between nuclear factor erythroid-derived 2-like 2 promoter gene polymorphisms and oxidative stress biomarkers in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. Oxid Med Cell Longev. 2014;2014:432626.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitsumoto H, Santella RM, Liu X, et al. Oxidative stress biomarkers in sporadic ALS. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2008;9(3):177-183.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mattiazzi M, D'Aurelio M, Gajewski CD, et al. Mutated human SOD1 causes dysfunction of oxidative phosphorylation in mitochondria of transgenic mice. J Biol Chem. 2002;277(33):29626-29633.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Q, Spencer NY, Pantazis NJ, Engelhardt JF. Alsin and SOD1(G93A) proteins regulate endosomal reactive oxygen species production by glial cells and proinflammatory pathways responsible for neurotoxicity. J Biol Chem. 2011;286(46):40151-40162.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pehar M, Beeson G, Beeson CC, Johnson JA, Vargas MR. Mitochondria-targeted catalase reverts the neurotoxicity of hSOD1G(9)(3)A astrocytes without extending the survival of ALS-linked mutant hSOD1 mice. PLoS One. 2014;9(7):e103438.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saccon RA, Bunton-Stasyshyn RK, Fisher EM, Fratta P. Is SOD1 loss of function involved in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis? Brain. 2013;136(Pt 8):2342-2358.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reddi AR, Culotta VC. SOD1 integrates signals from oxygen and glucose to repress respiration. Cell. 2013;152(1-2):224-235.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D'Amico E, Factor-Litvak P, Santella RM, Mitsumoto H. Clinical perspective on oxidative stress in sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Free Radic Biol Med. 2013;65:509-527.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pansarasa O, Bordoni M, Diamanti L, Sproviero D, Gagliardi S, Cereda C. SOD1 in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: "ambivalent" behavior connected to the disease. Int J Mol Sci. 2018;19(5):1345.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simera I, Moher D, Hoey J, Schulz KF, Altman DG. A catalogue of reporting guidelines for health research. Eur J Clin Invest. 2010;40(1):35-53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith PK, Krohn RI, Hermanson GT, et al. Measurement of protein using bicinchoninic acid. Anal Biochem. 1985;150(1):76-85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bradford MM. A rapid and sensitive method for the quantitation of microgram quantities of protein utilizing the principle of protein-dye binding. Anal Biochem. 1976;72:248-254.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romero-Calvo I, Ocon B, Martinez-Moya P, et al. Reversible ponceau staining as a loading control alternative to actin in Western blots. Anal Biochem. 2010;401(2):318-320.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eruslanov E, Kusmartsev S. Identification of ROS using oxidized DCFDA and flow-cytometry. Methods Mol Biol. 2010;594:57-72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Espinosa-Diez C, Miguel V, Mennerich D, et al. Antioxidant responses and cellular adjustments to oxidative stress. Redox Biol. 2015;6:183-197.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freitas M, Baldeiras I, Proenca T, Alves V, Mota-Pinto A, Sarmento-Ribeiro A. Oxidative stress adaptation in aggressive prostate cancer may be counteracted by the reduction of glutathione reductase. FEBS Open Bio. 2012;2:119-128.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahman I, Kode A, Biswas SK. Assay for quantitative determination of glutathione and glutathione disulfide levels using enzymatic recycling method. Nat Protoc. 2006;1(6):3159-3165.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goncalves AC, Alves R, Baldeiras I, et al. Oxidative stress parameters can predict the response to erythropoiesis-stimulating agents in myelodysplastic syndrome patients. Front Cell Dev Biol. 2021;9:701328.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dem&#x161;ar J, Curk T, Erjavec A, et al. Orange: data mining toolbox in. Python. 2013;14(1):2349-2353.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waskom M. Seaborn: statistical data visualization. J Open Source Softw. 2021;6(60):3021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maniatis S, Aijo T, Vickovic S, et al. Spatiotemporal dynamics of molecular pathology in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Science. 2019;364(6435):89-93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Therrien M, Dion PA, Rouleau GA. ALS: recent developments from genetics studies. Curr Neurol Neurosci Rep. 2016;16(6):59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goyal NA, Berry JD, Windebank A, et al. Addressing heterogeneity in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis CLINICAL TRIALS. Muscle Nerve. 2020;62(2):156-166.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katz JS, Barohn RJ, Dimachkie MM, Mitsumoto H. The dilemma of the clinical trialist in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: the hurdles to finding a cure. Neurol Clin. 2015;33(4):937-947.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masson JJR, Ostrowski M, Duette G, et al. The multiparametric analysis of mitochondrial dynamics in T cells from cryopreserved peripheral blood mononuclear cells (PBMCs). Methods Mol Biol. 2020;2184:215-224.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cunha-Oliveira T, Carvalho M, Sard&#xe3;o V, et al. Integrative profiling of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis lymphoblasts identifies unique metabolic and mitochondrial disease fingerprints. Res Sq. 2021. doi:10.21203/rs.3.rs-1196454/v1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naia L, Ferreira IL, Cunha-Oliveira T, et al. Activation of IGF-1 and insulin signaling pathways ameliorate mitochondrial function and energy metabolism in Huntington's Disease human lymphoblasts. Mol Neurobiol. 2015;51(1):331-348.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panov A, Obertone T, Bennett-Desmelik J, Greenamyre JT. Ca(2+)-dependent permeability transition and complex I activity in lymphoblast mitochondria from normal individuals and patients with Huntington's or Alzheimer's disease. Ann N Y Acad Sci. 1999;893:365-368.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Annesley SJ, Lay ST, De Piazza SW, et al. Immortalized Parkinson's disease lymphocytes have enhanced mitochondrial respiratory activity. Dis Model Mech. 2016;9(11):1295-1305.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guareschi S, Cova E, Cereda C, et al. An over-oxidized form of superoxide dismutase found in sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with bulbar onset shares a toxic mechanism with mutant SOD1. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2012;109(13):5074-5079.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lastres-Becker I, Porras G, Arribas-Blazquez M, et al. Molecular alterations in sporadic and SOD1-ALS immortalized lymphocytes: towards a personalized therapy. Int J Mol Sci. 2021;22(6):3007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Said Ahmed M, Hung WY, Zu JS, Hockberger P, Siddique T. Increased reactive oxygen species in familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with mutations in SOD1. J Neurol Sci. 2000;176(2):88-94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ihara Y, Mori A, Hayabara T, et al. Superoxide dismutase and free radicals in sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: relationship to clinical data. J Neurol Sci. 1995;134(1-2):51-56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niebroj-Dobosz I, Dziewulska D, Kwiecinski H. Oxidative damage to proteins in the spinal cord in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). Folia Neuropathol. 2004;42(3):151-156.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowling AC, Schulz JB, Brown RH Jr, Beal MF. Superoxide dismutase activity, oxidative damage, and mitochondrial energy metabolism in familial and sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurochem. 1993;61(6):2322-2325.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedersen WA, Fu W, Keller JN, et al. Protein modification by the lipid peroxidation product 4-hydroxynonenal in the spinal cords of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. Ann Neurol. 1998;44(5):819-824.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beal MF, Ferrante RJ, Browne SE, Matthews RT, Kowall NW, Brown RH Jr. Increased 3-nitrotyrosine in both sporadic and familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol. 1997;42(4):644-654.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abe K, Pan LH, Watanabe M, Kato T, Itoyama Y. Induction of nitrotyrosine-like immunoreactivity in the lower motor neuron of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurosci Lett. 1995;199(2):152-154.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abe K, Pan LH, Watanabe M, Konno H, Kato T, Itoyama Y. Upregulation of protein-tyrosine nitration in the anterior horn cells of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurol Res. 1997;19(2):124-128.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babu GN, Kumar A, Chandra R, et al. Oxidant-antioxidant imbalance in the erythrocytes of sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients correlates with the progression of disease. Neurochem Int. 2008;52(6):1284-1289.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cova E, Bongioanni P, Cereda C, et al. Time course of oxidant markers and antioxidant defenses in subgroups of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. Neurochem Int. 2010;56(5):687-693.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huai J, Zhang Z. Structural properties and interaction partners of familial ALS-associated SOD1 mutants. Front Neurol. 2019;10:527.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yim MB, Kang JH, Yim HS, Kwak HS, Chock PB, Stadtman ER. A gain-of-function of an amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-associated Cu, Zn-superoxide dismutase mutant: an enhancement of free radical formation due to a decrease in Km for hydrogen peroxide. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 1996;93(12):5709-5714.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borchelt DR, Lee MK, Slunt HS, et al. Superoxide dismutase 1 with mutations linked to familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis possesses significant activity. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 1994;91(17):8292-8296.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kokic AN, Stevic Z, Stojanovic S, et al. Biotransformation of nitric oxide in the cerebrospinal fluid of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. Redox Rep. 2005;10(5):265-270.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratovitski T, Corson LB, Strain J, et al. Variation in the biochemical/biophysical properties of mutant superoxide dismutase 1 enzymes and the rate of disease progression in familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis kindreds. Hum Mol Genet. 1999;8(8):1451-1460.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reaume A, Elliott J, Hoffman E, et al. Motor neurons in Cu/Zn Superoxide dismutase-deficient mice develop normally but exhibit enhanced cell death after axonal injury. Nat Genet. 1996;13:43-47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pickles S, Destroismaisons L, Peyrard SL, et al. Mitochondrial damage revealed by immunoselection for ALS-linked misfolded SOD1. Hum Mol Genet. 2013;22(19):3947-3959.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferri A, Cozzolino M, Crosio C, et al. Familial ALS-superoxide dismutases associate with mitochondria and shift their redox potentials. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2006;103(37):13860-13865.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi L, Ke Y, Luo C, Gozal D, Liu R. Depletion of reduced glutathione enhances motor neuron degeneration in vitro and in vivo. Neuroscience. 2007;144(3):991-1003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vargas MR, Johnson DA, Johnson JA. Decreased glutathione accelerates neurological deficit and mitochondrial pathology in familial ALS-linked hSOD1(G93A) mice model. Neurobiology of Disease. 2011;43(3):543-551.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Przedborski S, Donaldson DM, Murphy PL, et al. Blood superoxide dismutase, catalase and glutathione peroxidase activities in familial and sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurodegeneration. 1996;5(1):57-64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Golenia A, Leskiewicz M, Regulska M, et al. Catalase activity in blood fractions of patients with sporadic ALS. Pharmacol Rep. 2014;66(4):704-707.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alsuntangled G, Richard B. ALSUntangled 55: vitamin E (alpha-tocopherol). Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2021;22(1-2):154-160.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Bustos F, Jimenez-Jimenez FJ, Molina JA, et al. Cerebrospinal fluid levels of alpha-tocopherol in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neural Transm. 1998;105(6-7):703-708.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milani P, Ambrosi G, Gammoh O, Blandini F, Cereda C. SOD1 and DJ-1 converge at Nrf2 pathway: a clue for antioxidant therapeutic potential in neurodegeneration. Oxid Med Cell Longev. 2013;2013:836760.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milani P, Gagliardi S, Cova E, Cereda C. SOD1 transcriptional and posttranscriptional regulation and its potential implications in ALS. Neurol Res Int. 2011;2011:458427.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirby J, Halligan E, Baptista MJ, et al. Mutant SOD1 alters the motor neuronal transcriptome: implications for familial ALS. Brain. 2005;128(Pt 7):1686-1706.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raghunath A, Sundarraj K, Nagarajan R, et al. Antioxidant response elements: discovery, classes, regulation and potential applications. Redox Biol. 2018;17:297-314.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraft AD, Resch JM, Johnson DA, Johnson JA. Activation of the Nrf2-ARE pathway in muscle and spinal cord during ALS-like pathology in mice expressing mutant SOD1. Exp Neurol. 2007;207(1):107-117.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuadrado A. Brain-protective mechanisms of transcription factor NRF2: toward a common strategy for neurodegenerative diseases. Annu Rev Pharmacol Toxicol. 2022;62:255-277.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>La Rosa P, Petrillo S, Turchi R, et al. The Nrf2 induction prevents ferroptosis in Friedreich's Ataxia. Redox Biol. 2021;38:101791.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>