<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35470471</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>12</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1440-1746</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>37</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of gastroenterology and hepatology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Gastroenterol Hepatol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Percutaneous endoscopic gastrostomy using the introducer method with ultra-slim endoscopy in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients with respiratory compromise: A safe technique.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1367</StartPage><EndPage>1372</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1367-1372</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/jgh.15870</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND AIM" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Percutaneous endoscopic gastrostomy (PEG) placement is recommended in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS), but the procedure is considered high risk. In this study, we aimed to compare the outcome of ALS patients with and without PEG. The success of the procedure and complications of PEG insertion were also explored.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Patients with ALS who met the criteria for enteral feeding support were consecutively recruited. Patients who consented had PEG insertion using the modified technique of introducer method with transoral ultra-slim endoscopy.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 64 patients were recruited, of which 36 (56%) patients consented to PEG. The median age of all patients was 65&#xa0;years and 59% were male. There was no difference in demographic and clinical characteristics between patients who agreed to a PEG and those who did not. The mortality rate at 6 and 12&#xa0;months was lower in the PEG cohort compared with non-PEG, but this was not statistically significant (6&#xa0;months: 28.6% vs 32.2%, P&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.561; 12&#xa0;months: 38.9% vs 50.0%, P&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.374). Amongst the PEG cohort, 61% were stratified high risk and 31% moderate risk. Thirty-one percent of them required long-term home noninvasive ventilation. All patients (100%) underwent successful PEG insertion at single attempt using the modified approach. The complications reported over a period of 6&#xa0;months were infected PEG site (17%), dislodged gastrostomy tube (14%), and minor bleeding (8%).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">In ALS patients with moderate to high risk of PEG insertion, the introducer technique utilizing ultra-slim endoscopy guidance was well tolerated and safe.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022 Journal of Gastroenterology and Hepatology Foundation and John Wiley &amp; Sons Australia, Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chuah</LastName><ForeName>Kee Huat</ForeName><Initials>KH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9811-7546</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Gastroenterology and Hepatology Unit, Department of Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, University of Malaya, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yim</LastName><ForeName>Carolyn Chue Wai</ForeName><Initials>CCW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anaesthesiology, Faculty of Medicine, University of Malaya, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abdul Aziz</LastName><ForeName>Nur Adilah</ForeName><Initials>NA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurology Unit, Department of Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, University of Malaya, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Loh</LastName><ForeName>Ee Chin</ForeName><Initials>EC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Palliative Care Unit, Department of Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, University of Malaya, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Capelle</LastName><ForeName>David Paul</ForeName><Initials>DP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Palliative Care Unit, Department of Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, University of Malaya, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shahrizaila</LastName><ForeName>Nortina</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurology Unit, Department of Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, University of Malaya, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Leow</LastName><ForeName>Alex Hwong Ruey</ForeName><Initials>AHR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Gastroenterology and Hepatology Unit, Department of Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, University of Malaya, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Australia</Country><MedlineTA>J Gastroenterol Hepatol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8607909</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0815-9319</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016099" MajorTopicYN="N">Endoscopy, Gastrointestinal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004750" MajorTopicYN="N">Enteral Nutrition</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005774" MajorTopicYN="Y">Gastrostomy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">adverse events</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">enteral feeding tube</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">gastroscopy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">motor neuron disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nasal endoscopy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">slim endoscopy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">survival</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">&#x201c;push&#x201d; PEG</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35470471</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jgh.15870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Miller RG, Jackson CE, Kasarskis EJ et al. Practice parameter update: the care of the patient with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: drug, nutritional, and respiratory therapies (an evidence-based review). Neurology 2009; 73: 1218-1226. https://doi.org/10.1212/WNL.0b013e3181bc0141</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen PM, Abrahams S, Borasio GD et al. EFNS guidelines on the clinical management of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (MALS)-revised report of an EFNS task force. Eur. J. Neurol. 2012; 19: 360-375. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1468-1331.2011.03501.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ProGas Study Group. Gastrostomy in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ProGas): a prospective cohort study. The Lancet Neurology. 2015; 14: 702-709. https://doi.org/10.1016/S1474-4422(15)00104-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahnemai-Azar AA, Rahnemaiazar AA, Naghshizadian R, Kurtz A, Farkas DT. Percutaneous endoscopic gastrostomy: indications, technique, complications and management. World J. Gastroenterol. 2014; 20: 7739-7751. https://doi.org/10.3748/wjg.v20.i24.7739</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdul Aziz NA, Toh TH, Goh KJ et al. Natural history and clinical features of ALS in Malaysia. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis &amp; Frontotemporal Degeneration 2021; 22: 108-116. https://doi.org/10.1080/21678421.2020.1832121</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen PM, Kuzma-Kozakiewicz M, Keller J et al. Therapeutic decisions in ALS patients: cross-cultural differences and clinical implications. J. Neurol. 2018; 265: 1600-1606. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00415-018-8861-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson AG, Blackwell V, Marsden R et al. A risk stratifying tool to facilitate safe late-stage percutaneous endoscopic gastrostomy in ALS. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis &amp; Frontotemporal Degeneration 2017; 18: 243-248. https://doi.org/10.1080/21678421.2016.1274330</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas K, Schrager J, Neel R, Brook L. Percutaneous endoscopic gastrostomy tube placement in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a case series with a multidisciplinary, team-based approach. Ann. Gastroenterol. 2020; 33: 480-484. https://doi.org/10.20524/aog.2020.0517</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toh Yoon EW, Yoneda K, Nakamura S, Nishihara K. Percutaneous endoscopic gastrostomy (PEG) using a novel large-caliber introducer technique kit: a retrospective analysis. Endoscopy International Open 2016; 4: E990-E996. https://doi.org/10.1055/s-0042-112587</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, Miller RG, Swash M, Munsat TL. El Escorial revisited: revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis and Other Motor Neuron Disorders: Official Publication of the World Federation of Neurology, Research Group on Motor Neuron Diseases 2000; 1: 293-299. https://doi.org/10.1080/146608200300079536</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Dengler R, Eisen A et al. Electrodiagnostic criteria for diagnosis of ALS. Clinical Neurophysiology: Official Journal of the International Federation of Clinical Neurophysiology 2008; 119: 497-503. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.clinph.2007.09.143</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bond L, Ganguly P, Khamankar N, Mallet N, Bowen G, Green B, Mitchell CS. A comprehensive examination of percutaneous endoscopic gastrostomy and its association with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patient outcomes. Brain Sci. 2019; 9. https://doi.org/10.3390/brainsci9090223</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui F, Sun L, Xiong J, Li J, Zhao Y, Huang X. Therapeutic effects of percutaneous endoscopic gastrostomy on survival in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a meta-analysis. PLoS ONE 2018; 13: e0192243. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0192243</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanson LC, Garrett JM, Lewis C, Phifer N, Jackman A, Carey TS. Physicians' expectations of benefit from tube feeding. J. Palliat. Med. 2008; 11: 1130-1134. https://doi.org/10.1089/jpm.2008.0033</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carb&#xf3; Perseguer J, Madej&#xf3;n Seiz A, Romero Portales M, Mart&#xed;nez Hern&#xe1;ndez J, Mora Pardina JS, Garc&#xed;a-Samaniego J. Percutaneous endoscopic gastrostomy in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: mortality and complications. Neurologia (Barcelona, Spain) 2019; 34: 582-588. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nrl.2018.01.003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang B, Shi X. Percutaneous endoscopic gastrostomy versus fluoroscopic gastrostomy in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) sufferers with nutritional impairment: a meta-analysis of current studies. Oncotarget 2017; 8: 102244-102253. https://doi.org/10.18632/oncotarget.22288</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sato Y, Goshi S, Kawauchi Y et al. Safety of unsedated PEG placement using transoral ultrathin endoscopy in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nutr. Neurosci. 2017; 20: 71-75. https://doi.org/10.1179/1476830514Y.0000000161</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCulloch A, Roy O, Massey D, Hedges R, Skerratt S, Wilson N, Woodward J. Nasal unsedated seated percutaneous endoscopic gastrostomy (nuPEG): a safe and effective technique for percutaneous endoscopic gastrostomy placement in high-risk candidates. Frontline Gastroenterol. 2018; 9: 105-109. https://doi.org/10.1136/flgastro-2017-100894</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ust&#xfc;nda&#x11f; Y, Sarita&#x15f; U, Ponchon T. Unsedated small caliber esophagogastroduodenoscopy: can we trust this technique? The Turkish Journal of Gastroenterology: The Official Journal of Turkish Society of Gastroenterology 2011; 22: 237-242.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sami SS, Subramanian V, Ortiz-Fern&#xe1;ndez-Sordo J et al. Performance characteristics of unsedated ultrathin video endoscopy in the assessment of the upper GI tract: systematic review and meta-analysis. Gastrointest. Endosc. 2015; 82: 782-792. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.gie.2015.07.016</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trevisani L, Cifal&#xe0; V, Sartori S, Gilli G, Matarese G, Abbasciano V. Unsedated ultrathin upper endoscopy is better than conventional endoscopy in routine outpatient gastroenterology practice: a randomized trial. World J. Gastroenterol. 2007; 13: 906-911. https://doi.org/10.3748/wjg.v13.i6.906</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>