<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35483133</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>19</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2213-1582</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>34</Volume><PubDate><Year>2022</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>NeuroImage. Clinical</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Neuroimage Clin</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Early and progressive dysfunction revealed by in vivo neurite imaging in the rNLS8 TDP-43 mouse model of ALS.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>103016</StartPage><MedlinePgn>103016</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">103016</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.nicl.2022.103016</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S2213-1582(22)00081-X</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) is characterized by transactive response DNA-binding protein 43 (TDP-43) pathology, progressive loss of motor neurons and muscle dysfunction. Symptom onset can be insidious and diagnosis challenging. Conventional neuroimaging is used to exclude ALS mimics, however more advanced neuroimaging techniques may facilitate an earlier diagnosis. Here, we investigate the potential for neurite orientation dispersion and density imaging and diffusion tensor imaging (DTI) to detect microstructural changes in an experimental model of ALS with neuronal doxycycline (Dox)-suppressible overexpression of human TDP-43 (hTDP-43). In vivo diffusion-weighted imaging (DWI) was acquired 1- and 3- weeks following the initiation of hTDP-43 expression (post-Dox) to investigate whether neurite density imaging (NDI) and orientation dispersion imaging (ODI) are affected early in this preclinical model of ALS and if so, how these metrics compare to those derived from the diffusion tensor. Tract-based spatial statistics at 1-week post-Dox, i.e. very early in the disease stage, demonstrated increased NDI in TDP-43 mice but no change in ODI or DTI metrics. At 3-weeks post-Dox, a reduced pattern of increased NDI was observed along with widespread increases in ODI, and decreased fractional anisotropy (FA), apparent diffusion coefficient (ADC) and axial diffusivity (AD). A hypothesis driven analysis of the bilateral corticospinal tracts demonstrated that at 1-week post-Dox, ODI was significantly increased caudally but decreased in the motor cortex of TDP-43 mice. Decreased cortical ODI had normalized by 3-weeks post-Dox and only significant increases were observed. A similar, but inverse pattern in FA was also observed. Together, these results suggest a non-monotonic relationship between DWI metrics and pathophysiological progression with TDP-43 mice exhibiting significantly altered diffusion metrics consistent with early inflammation followed by progressive axonal degeneration. Importantly, significant group-wise changes were observed in the earliest stages of disease when subtle pathology may be more elusive to traditional structural imaging techniques.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022 The Author(s). Published by Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zamani</LastName><ForeName>Akram</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience, Central Clinical School, Monash University, Melbourne, VIC 3004, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Walker</LastName><ForeName>Adam K</ForeName><Initials>AK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Queensland Brain Institute, The University of Queensland, QLD 4072, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rollo</LastName><ForeName>Ben</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience, Central Clinical School, Monash University, Melbourne, VIC 3004, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ayers</LastName><ForeName>Katie L</ForeName><Initials>KL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Murdoch Children's Research Institute, The Royal Children's Hospital, Parkville, VIC 3052, Australia; Department of Pediatrics, The University of Melbourne, Parkville, VIC 3052, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Farah</LastName><ForeName>Raysha</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience, Central Clinical School, Monash University, Melbourne, VIC 3004, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>O'Brien</LastName><ForeName>Terence J</ForeName><Initials>TJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience, Central Clinical School, Monash University, Melbourne, VIC 3004, Australia; Department of Medicine, The Royal Melbourne Hospital, The University of Melbourne, Parkville, VIC 3052, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wright</LastName><ForeName>David K</ForeName><Initials>DK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience, Central Clinical School, Monash University, Melbourne, VIC 3004, Australia. Electronic address: david.wright@monash.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Neuroimage Clin</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101597070</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2213-1582</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D004268">DNA-Binding Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C578077">TDP-43 protein, mouse</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004268" MajorTopicYN="N">DNA-Binding Proteins</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D038524" MajorTopicYN="N">Diffusion Magnetic Resonance Imaging</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D056324" MajorTopicYN="Y">Diffusion Tensor Imaging</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051379" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016501" MajorTopicYN="N">Neurites</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">DTI</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">MRI</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Motor neurone disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">NODDI</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neurodegeneration</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35483133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9125783</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nicl.2022.103016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2213-1582(22)00081-X</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Andersson J.L.R., Sotiropoulos S.N. An integrated approach to correction for off-resonance effects and subject movement in diffusion MR imaging. Neuroimage. 2016;125:1063&#x2013;1078.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4692656</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26481672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Broad R.J., Gabel M.C., Dowell N.G., Schwartzman D.J., Seth A.K., Zhang H., Alexander D.C., Cercignani M., Leigh P.N. Neurite orientation and dispersion density imaging (NODDI) detects cortical and corticospinal tract degeneration in ALS. J. Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatry. 2019;90:404&#x2013;411.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6581155</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30361295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks B.R., Miller R.G., Swash M., Munsat T.L., World Federation of Neurology Research Group on Motor Neuron, D El Escorial revisited: revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph. Lateral Scler. Other Motor Neuron Disord. 2000;1:293&#x2013;299.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11464847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Budde M.D., Janes L., Gold E., Turtzo L.C., Frank J.A. The contribution of gliosis to diffusion tensor anisotropy and tractography following traumatic brain injury: validation in the rat using Fourier analysis of stained tissue sections. Brain. 2011;134:2248&#x2013;2260.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3155707</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21764818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardenas-Blanco A., Machts J., Acosta-Cabronero J., Kaufmann J., Abdulla S., Kollewe K., Petri S., Schreiber S., Heinze H.J., Dengler R., Vielhaber S., Nestor P.J. Structural and diffusion imaging versus clinical assessment to monitor amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuroimage Clin. 2016;11:408&#x2013;414.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4827722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27104135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chio A. ISIS Survey: an international study on the diagnostic process and its implications in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J. Neurol. 1999;246(Suppl 3):III1-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10631652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2; A., Pagani M., Agosta F., Calvo A., Cistaro A., Filippi M. Neuroimaging in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: insights into structural and functional changes. Lancet Neurol. 2014;13:1228&#x2013;1240.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25453462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colgan N., Siow B., O'Callaghan J.M., Harrison I.F., Wells J.A., Holmes H.E., Isail O., Richardson S., Alexander D.C., Collins E.C., Fisher E.M., Johnson R., Schwarz A.J., Ahmed Z., O'Neill M.J., Murray T.K., Zhang H., Lythgoe M.F. Application of neurite orientation dispersion and density imaging (NODDI) to a tau pathology model of Alzheimer's disease. Neuroimage. 2016;125:739&#x2013;744.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4692518</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26505297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colon-Perez L.M., Ibanez K.R., Suarez M., Torroella K., Acuna K., Ofori E., Levites Y., Vaillancourt D.E., Golde T.E., Chakrabarty P., Febo M. Neurite orientation dispersion and density imaging reveals white matter and hippocampal microstructure changes produced by Interleukin-6 in the TgCRND8 mouse model of amyloidosis. Neuroimage. 2019;202</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6894485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31472250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebstein S.Y., Yagudayeva I., Shneider N.A. Mutant TDP-43 causes early-stage dose-dependent motor neuron degeneration in a TARDBP knockin mouse model of ALS. Cell Rep. 2019;26(364&#x2013;373):e364.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30625319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gatto R.G., Mustafi S.M., Amin M.Y., Mareci T.H., Wu Y.C., Magin R.L. Neurite orientation dispersion and density imaging can detect presymptomatic axonal degeneration in the spinal cord of ALS mice. Funct. Neurol. 2018;33:155&#x2013;163.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7212765</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30457969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gatto R.G., Amin M., Finkielsztein A., Weissmann C., Barrett T., Lamoutte C., Uchitel O., Sumagin R., Mareci T.H., Magin R.L. Unveiling early cortical and subcortical neuronal degeneration in ALS mice by ultra-high field diffusion MRI. Amyotroph. Lateral Scler. Frontotemporal Degener. 2019;20:549&#x2013;561.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31159586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hobbs N.Z., Cole J.H., Farmer R.E., Rees E.M., Crawford H.E., Malone I.B., Roos R.A., Sprengelmeyer R., Durr A., Landwehrmeyer B., Scahill R.I., Tabrizi S.J., Frost C. Evaluation of multi-modal, multi-site neuroimaging measures in Huntington's disease: baseline results from the PADDINGTON study. Neuroimage Clin. 2012;2:204&#x2013;211.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3777685</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24179770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jack C.R., Jr., Barnes J., Bernstein M.A., Borowski B.J., Brewer J., Clegg S., Dale A.M., Carmichael O., Ching C., DeCarli C., Desikan R.S., Fennema-Notestine C., Fjell A.M., Fletcher E., Fox N.C., Gunter J., Gutman B.A., Holland D., Hua X., Insel P., Kantarci K., Killiany R.J., Krueger G., Leung K.K., Mackin S., Aillard P., Malone I.B., Mattsson N., McEvoy L., Modat M., Mueller S., Nosheny R., Ourselin S., Schuff N., Senjem M.L., Simonson A., Thompson P.M., Rettmann D., Vemuri P., Walhovd K., Zhao Y., Zuk S., Weiner M. Magnetic resonance imaging in Alzheimer's Disease Neuroimaging Initiative 2. Alzheimers Dement. 2015;11:740&#x2013;756.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4523217</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26194310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamagata K., Andica C., Kato A., Saito Y., Uchida W., Hatano T., Lukies M., Ogawa T., Takeshige-Amano H., Akashi T., Hagiwara A., Fujita S., Aoki S. Diffusion magnetic resonance imaging-based biomarkers for neurodegenerative diseases. Int. J. Mol. Sci. 2021;22</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8155849</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34069159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamiya K., Hori M., Aoki S. NODDI in clinical research. J. Neurosci. Methods. 2020;346</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32814118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanayama S., Kuhara S., Satoh K. In vivo rapid magnetic field measurement and shimming using single scan differential phase mapping. Magn. Reson. Med. 1996;36:637&#x2013;642.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8892219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kassubek J., Muller H.P. Advanced neuroimaging approaches in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: refining the clinical diagnosis. Expert Rev. Neurother. 2020;20:237&#x2013;249.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31937156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiernan M.C., Vucic S., Cheah B.C., Turner M.R., Eisen A., Hardiman O., Burrell J.R., Zoing M.C. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet. 2011;377:942&#x2013;955.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21296405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller H.P., Turner M.R., Grosskreutz J., Abrahams S., Bede P., Govind V., Prudlo J., Ludolph A.C., Filippi M., Kassubek J., Neuroimaging Society in, A.L.S.D.T.I.S.G A large-scale multicentre cerebral diffusion tensor imaging study in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J. Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatry. 2016;87:570&#x2013;579.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26746186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller H.P., Brenner D., Roselli F., Wiesner D., Abaei A., Gorges M., Danzer K.M., Ludolph A.C., Tsao W., Wong P.C., Rasche V., Weishaupt J.H., Kassubek J. Longitudinal diffusion tensor magnetic resonance imaging analysis at the cohort level reveals disturbed cortical and callosal microstructure with spared corticospinal tract in the TDP-43 (G298S) ALS mouse model. Transl. Neurodegener. 2019;8:27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6716821</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31485326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palese F., Sartori A., Logroscino G., Pisa F.E. Predictors of diagnostic delay in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a cohort study based on administrative and electronic medical records data. Amyotroph. Lateral Scler. Frontotemporal Degener. 2019;20:176&#x2013;185.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30656971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raffelt D.A., Smith R.E., Ridgway G.R., Tournier J.D., Vaughan D.N., Rose S., Henderson R., Connelly A. Connectivity-based fixel enhancement: whole-brain statistical analysis of diffusion MRI measures in the presence of crossing fibres. Neuroimage. 2015;117:40&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4528070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26004503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raffelt D., Tournier J.D., Rose S., Ridgway G.R., Henderson R., Crozier S., Salvado O., Connelly A. Apparent Fibre Density: a novel measure for the analysis of diffusion-weighted magnetic resonance images. Neuroimage. 2012;59:3976&#x2013;3994.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22036682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richards D., Morren J.A., Pioro E.P. Time to diagnosis and factors affecting diagnostic delay in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J. Neurol. Sci. 2020;417</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32763509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sach M., Winkler G., Glauche V., Liepert J., Heimbach B., Koch M.A., Buchel C., Weiller C. Diffusion tensor MRI of early upper motor neuron involvement in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain. 2004;127:340&#x2013;350.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14607785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slattery C.F., Zhang J., Paterson R.W., Foulkes A.J.M., Carton A., Macpherson K., Mancini L., Thomas D.L., Modat M., Toussaint N., Cash D.M., Thornton J.S., Henley S.M.D., Crutch S.J., Alexander D.C., Ourselin S., Fox N.C., Zhang H., Schott J.M. ApoE influences regional white-matter axonal density loss in Alzheimer's disease. Neurobiol. Aging. 2017;57:8&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5538347</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28578156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith S.M., Nichols T.E. Threshold-free cluster enhancement: addressing problems of smoothing, threshold dependence and localisation in cluster inference. Neuroimage. 2009;44:83&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18501637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith S.M., Jenkinson M., Johansen-Berg H., Rueckert D., Nichols T.E., Mackay C.E., Watkins K.E., Ciccarelli O., Cader M.Z., Matthews P.M., Behrens T.E. Tract-based spatial statistics: voxelwise analysis of multi-subject diffusion data. Neuroimage. 2006;31:1487&#x2013;1505.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16624579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Todd T.W., Petrucelli L. Modelling amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in rodents. Nat. Rev. Neurosci. 2022;23:231&#x2013;251.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35260846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tournier J.D., Smith R., Raffelt D., Tabbara R., Dhollander T., Pietsch M., Christiaens D., Jeurissen B., Yeh C.H., Connelly A. MRtrix3: A fast, flexible and open software framework for medical image processing and visualisation. Neuroimage. 2019;202</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31473352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsitkanou S., Della Gatta P.A., Abbott G., Wallace M.A., Lindsay A., Gerlinger-Romero F., Walker A.K., Foletta V.C., Russell A.P. miR-23a suppression accelerates functional decline in the rNLS8 mouse model of TDP-43 proteinopathy. Neurobiol. Dis. 2022;162</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34774794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Underwood C.K., Kurniawan N.D., Butler T.J., Cowin G.J., Wallace R.H. Non-invasive diffusion tensor imaging detects white matter degeneration in the spinal cord of a mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuroimage. 2011;55:455&#x2013;461.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21185943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vogt N.M., Hunt J.F.V., Adluru N., Ma Y., Van Hulle C.A., Iii D.C.D., Kecskemeti S.R., Chin N.A., Carlsson C.M., Asthana S., Johnson S.C., Kollmorgen G., Batrla R., Wild N., Buck K., Zetterberg H., Alexander A.L., Blennow K., Bendlin B.B. Interaction of amyloid and tau on cortical microstructure in cognitively unimpaired adults. Alzheimers Dement. 2021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8589921</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33984184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walker A.K., Spiller K.J., Ge G., Zheng A., Xu Y., Zhou M., Tripathy K., Kwong L.K., Trojanowski J.Q., Lee V.M. Functional recovery in new mouse models of ALS/FTLD after clearance of pathological cytoplasmic TDP-43. Acta Neuropathol. 2015;130:643&#x2013;660.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5127391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26197969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wen J., Zhang H., Alexander D.C., Durrleman S., Routier A., Rinaldi D., Houot M., Couratier P., Hannequin D., Pasquier F., Zhang J., Colliot O., Le Ber I., Bertrand A., Predict to Prevent Frontotemporal Lobar, D., Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Study, G Neurite density is reduced in the presymptomatic phase of C9orf72 disease. J. Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatry. 2019;90:387&#x2013;394.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30355607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wright A.L., Della Gatta P.A., Le S., Berning B.A., Mehta P., Jacobs K.R., Gul H., San Gil R., Hedl T.J., Riddell W.R., Watson O., Keating S.S., Venturato J., Chung R.S., Atkin J.D., Lee A., Shi B., Blizzard C.A., Morsch M., Walker A.K. Riluzole does not ameliorate disease caused by cytoplasmic TDP-43 in a mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Eur. J. Neurosci. 2021;54:6237&#x2013;6255.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34390052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wright D.K., Johnston L.A., Kershaw J., Ordidge R., O'Brien T.J., Shultz S.R. Changes in apparent fiber density and track-weighted imaging metrics in white matter following experimental traumatic brain injury. J. Neurotrauma. 2017;34:2109&#x2013;2118.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28152648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wright D.K., Liu S., van der Poel C., McDonald S.J., Brady R.D., Taylor L., Yang L., Gardner A.J., Ordidge R., O'Brien T.J., Johnston L.A., Shultz S.R. Traumatic brain injury results in cellular, structural and functional changes resembling motor neuron disease. Cereb. Cortex. 2017;27:4503&#x2013;4515.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27566977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wright D.K., Gardner A.J., Wojtowicz M., Iverson G.L., O'Brien T.J., Shultz S.R., Stanwell P. White matter abnormalities in retired professional rugby league players with a history of concussion. J. Neurotrauma. 2021;38:983&#x2013;988.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32245344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wright D.K., Symons G.F., O'Brien W.T., McDonald S.J., Zamani A., Major B., Chen Z., Costello D., Brady R.D., Sun M., Law M., O'Brien T.J., Mychasiuk R., Shultz S.R. Diffusion imaging reveals sex differences in the white matter following sports-related concussion. Cereb. Cortex. 2021;31:4411&#x2013;4419.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33860291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zamani A., O'Brien T.J., Kershaw J., Johnston L.A., Semple B.D., Wright D.K. White matter changes following experimental pediatric traumatic brain injury: an advanced diffusion-weighted imaging investigation. Brain Imaging Behav. 2021;15:2766&#x2013;2774.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33411159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zamani A., Walker A.K., Rollo B., Ayers K.L., Farah R., O'Brien T.J., Wright D.K. Impaired glymphatic function in the early stages of disease in a TDP-43 mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Transl. Neurodegener. 2022;11:17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8922788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35287738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H., Schneider T., Wheeler-Kingshott C.A., Alexander D.C. NODDI: practical in vivo neurite orientation dispersion and density imaging of the human brain. Neuroimage. 2012;61:1000&#x2013;1016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22484410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>