<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35503446</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0386-300X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>76</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Acta medica Okayama</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Acta Med Okayama</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Capsaicin May Improve Swallowing Impairment in Patients with Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis: A Randomized Controlled Trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>179</StartPage><EndPage>186</EndPage><MedlinePgn>179-186</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.18926/AMO/63412</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Patients with neurodegenerative diseases are at an increased risk of dysphagia and aspiration pneumonia. In this study, we examined whether ingestion of capsaicin prior to swallowing changes the temporal dynamics of swallowing in such patients. In a crossover, randomized controlled trial, 29 patients with neurodegenerative diseases were given a soluble wafer containing 1.5 &#x3bc;g capsaicin or an identical placebo 20 min prior to testing. For evaluation with video fluoroscopy (VF), patients consumed a barium-containing liquid plus thickening material. The durations of the latency, elevating and recovery periods of the hyoid were assessed from VF. Overall, no significant differences were observed in the duration of each period between capsaicin and placebo treatments. However, reductions in the latency and elevating periods were positively correlated with baseline durations. In subgroup analyses, that correlation was observed in patents with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) but not in patients with Parkinson's disease. The consumption of wafer paper containing capsaicin before the intake of food may be effective in patients with dysphagia related with certain neurodegenerative diseases, particularly ALS patients. Further studies will be needed to validate this finding.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Higashi</LastName><ForeName>Tomoko</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dental Anesthesiology and Special Care Dentistry, Okayama University Graduate School of Medicine, Dentistry and Pharmaceutical Sciences.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Murata</LastName><ForeName>Naomichi</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Center for Special Needs Dentistry, Okayama University Hospital.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fujimoto</LastName><ForeName>Maki</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dental Anesthesiology and Special Care Dentistry, Okayama University Graduate School of Medicine, Dentistry and Pharmaceutical Sciences.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Miyake</LastName><ForeName>Saki</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Center for Dental Anesthesiology, Okayama University Hospital.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Egusa</LastName><ForeName>Masahiko</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Center for Special Needs Dentistry, Okayama University Hospital.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Higuchi</LastName><ForeName>Hitoshi</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Center for Dental Anesthesiology, Okayama University Hospital.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maeda</LastName><ForeName>Shigeru</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Center for Dental Anesthesiology, Okayama University Hospital.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dental Anesthesiology and Orofacial Pain Management, Graduate School of Medical and Dental Sciences.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Miyawaki</LastName><ForeName>Takuya</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dental Anesthesiology and Special Care Dentistry, Okayama University Graduate School of Medicine, Dentistry and Pharmaceutical Sciences.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Japan</Country><MedlineTA>Acta Med Okayama</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0417611</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0386-300X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>S07O44R1ZM</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D002211">Capsaicin</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002211" MajorTopicYN="N">Capsaicin</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003679" MajorTopicYN="N">Deglutition</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003680" MajorTopicYN="Y">Deglutition Disorders</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005471" MajorTopicYN="N">Fluoroscopy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Parkinson disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">deglutition disorder</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fluoroscopy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neurodegenerative diseases</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>No potential conflict of interest relevant to this article was reported.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35503446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18926/AMO/63412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Onesti E, Schettino I, Gori MC, Frasca V, Ceccanti M, Cambieri C, Ruoppolo G and Inghilleri M: Dysphagia in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis: Impact on Patient Behavior, Diet Adaptation, and Riluzole Management. Front Neurol (2017) 8: 94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karam C, Scelsa SN and MacGowan DJL: The clinical course of progressive bulbar palsy. Amyotroph Lateral Scler (2010) 11: 364- 368.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suttrup I and Warnecke T: Dysphagia in Parkinson&#x2bc;s Disease. Dysphagia (2016) 31: 24-32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalf JG, de Swart BJM, Bloem BR and Munneke M: Prevalence of oropharyngeal dysphagia in Parkinson&#x2bc;s disease: A meta-analysis. Parkinsonism Relat Disord (2012) 18: 311-315.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee HH, Seo HG, Kim K, Lee SH, Lee WH, Oh B-M, Lee WW, Kim Y, Kim A, Kim HJ, Jeon B and Han TR: Characteristics of</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Early Oropharyngeal Dysphagia in Patients with Multiple System Atrophy. Neurodegener Dis (2018) 18: 84-90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark HM, Stierwalt JAG, Tosakulwong N, Botha H, Ali F, Whitwell JL and Josephs KA: Dysphagia in Progressive Supranuclear Palsy. Dysphagia (2020) 35: 667-676.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iglesias C, Sangari S, El Mendili M-M, Benali H, Marchand- Pauvert V and Pradat P-F: Electrophysiological and spinal imaging evidences for sensory dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. BMJ open (2015) 5: e007659.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pugdahl K, Fuglsang-Frederiksen A, de Carvalho M, Johnsen B, Fawcett PRW, Labarre-Vila A, Liguori R, Nix WA and Schofield IS: Generalised sensory system abnormalities in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a European multicentre study. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry (2007) 78: 746-749.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mochizuki Y, Mizutani T, Warabi Y, Shimizu T and Isozaki E: The somatosensory cortex in multiple system atrophy. J Neurosurg Sci (2008) 271: 174-179.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mu L, Sobotka S, Chen J, Su H, Sanders I, Nyirenda T, Adler, Charles H, Shill HA, Caviness JN, Samanta JE, Sue LI and Beach TG: Parkinson Disease Affects Peripheral Sensory Nerves in the Pharynx. J Neuropathol Exp Neurol (2013) 72: 614-623.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebihara T, Sekizawa K, Nakazawa H and Sasaki H: Capsaicin and swallowing reflex. Lancet (1993) 341: 432.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebihara T, Takahashi H, Ebihara S, Okazaki T, Sasaki T, Watando A, Nemoto M and Sasaki H: Capsaicin Troche for Swallowing Dysfunction in Older People. J Am Geriatrics Soc (2005) 53: 824-828.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomsen N, Ortega O, Rofes L, Arreola V, Martin A, Mundet L and Clav&#xe9; P: Acute and subacute effects of oropharyngeal sensory stimulation with TRPV1 agonists in older patients with oropharyngeal dysphagia: a biomechanical and neurophysiological randomized pilot study. Therap Adv Gastroenterol (2019) 12: 1-13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jinnouchi O, Ohnishi H, Kondo E, Kawata I, Bando H, Okamoto H, Azuma T, Sato G, Kitamura Y, Abe K and Takeda N: Aural stimulation with capsaicin prevented pneumonia in dementia patients. Auris Nasus Larynx (2019) 47: 154-157.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakato R, Manabe N, Shimizu S, Hanayama K, Shiotani A, Hata J and Haruma K: Effects of Capsaicin on Older Patients with Oropharyngeal Dysphagia: A Double-Blind, Placebo-Controlled, Crossover Study. Digestion (2017) 95: 210-220.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burgos R, Bret&#xf3;n I, Cereda E, Desport JC, Dziewas R, Genton L, Gomes, Filomena J&#xe9;sus P, Leischker A, Muscaritoli M, Poulia KA, Preiser JC, Van der Marck M, Wirth R, Singer P and Bischoff SC: ESPEN guideline clinical nutrition in neurology. Clin Nutr (2018) 37: 354-396.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goto T, Murata N, Arioka T, Kanda Y, Kobayashi Y, Mori T, Miyawaki T and Egusa M: Accelerating effect in swallowing reflex by Taking Capcisine Film. J Jpn Soc Dysphagia Rehab (2013) 17: 209-216.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horiguchi S and Suzuki Y: Screening tests in evaluating swallowing function. Jpn Med Assoc J (2011) 54: 31-34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallace E, Guiu Hernandez E, Ang A, Hiew S and Macrae P: A systematic review of methods of citric acid cough reflex testing. Pulmonary Pharmacol Ther (2019) 58: 101827.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magara J, Hayashi H, Kanda C, Hori K, Taniguchi H, Ono K and Inoue M: Spatial and temporal relationship between swallowrelated hyoid movement and bolus propulsion during swallowing. J Jpn Soc Stomatognathic Function (2013) 20: 22-32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dodds W, Taylor A, Stewart E, Kern M, Logemann J and Cook I: Tipper and dipper types of oral swallows. Am J Roentgenol (1989) 153: 1197-1199.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rofes L, Arreola V, Mukherjee R and Clav&#xe9; P: Sensitivity and specificity of the Eating Assessment Tool and the Volume-Viscosity Swallow Test for clinical evaluation of oropharyngeal dysphagia. Neurogastroenterol Motil (2014) 26: 1256-1265.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kendall KA and Leonard RJ: Hyoid Movement During Swallowing in Older Patients With Dysphagia. Arch Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg (2001) 127: 1224-1229.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rofes L, Arreola V, Martin A and Clav&#xe9; P: Natural capsaicinoids improve swallow response in older patients with oropharyngeal dysphagia. Gut (2013) 62: 1280-1287.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szolcs&#xe1;nyi J: Forty years in capsaicin research for sensory pharmacology and physiology. Neuropeptides (2004) 38: 377-384.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okano H, Koike S, Bamba H, Toyoda K, Uno T and Hisa Y: Participation of TRPV1 and TRPV2 in the rat laryngeal sensory innervation. Neurosci Lett (2006) 400: 35-38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang H-B, Inoue A, Iwasa M, Hide I and Nakata Y: Substance P release evoked by capsaicin or potassium from rat cultured dorsal root ganglion neurons is conversely modulated with bradykinin. J Neurochem (2006) 97: 1412-1418.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sivarao D and Goyal RK: Functional anatomy and physiology of the upper esophageal sphincter. Am J Med (2000) 108: 27-37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vijayakumar UG, Milla V, Cynthia Stafford MY, Bjourson AJ, Duddy W and Duguez SM-R: A Systematic Review of Suggested Molecular Strata, Biomarkers and Their Tissue Sources in ALS. Front Neurol (2019) 10: 1-17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawai S, Tsukuda M, Mochimatsu I, Enomoto H, Kagesato Y, Hirose H, Kuroiwa Y and Suzuki Y: A Study of the Early Stage of Dysphagia in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. Dysphagia (2003) 18: 1-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steele CM and Miller AJ: Sensory Input Pathways and Mechanisms in Swallowing: A Review. Dysphagia (2010) 25: 323-333.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rofes L, Ortega O, Vilardell N, Mundet L and Clav&#xe9; P: Spatiotemporal characteristics of the pharyngeal event-related potential in healthy subjects and older patients with oropharyngeal dysfunction. Neurogastroenterol Motil (2017) 29: e12916.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cabib C, Ortega O, Vilardell N, Mundet L, Clav&#xe9; P and Rofes L: Chronic post-stroke oropharyngeal dysphagia is associated with impaired cortical activation to pharyngeal sensory inputs. Eur J Neurol (2017) 24: 1355-1362.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clav&#xe9; P and Shaker R: Dysphagia: current reality and scope of the problem. Nat Rev Gastroenterol Hepatol (2015) 12: 259-270.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tiago R, Pontes P and Brasil OC do: Age-Related Changes in Human Laryngeal Nerves. Otolaryngology&#x2012;Head and Neck Surgery (2007) 136: 747-751.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaneoka A, Pisegna JM, Inokuchi H, Ueha R, Goto T, Nito T, Stepp CE, LaValley MP, Haga N and Langmore SE: Relationship Between Laryngeal Sensory Deficits, Aspiration, and Pneumonia in Patients with Dysphagia. Dysphagia (2018) 33: 192-199.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>