<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35549000</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1948-7193</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>13</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Jun</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>ACS chemical neuroscience</Title><ISOAbbreviation>ACS Chem Neurosci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Sequestration of TDP-43<sup>216-414</sup> Aggregates by Cytoplasmic Expression of the proSAAS Chaperone.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1651</StartPage><EndPage>1665</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1651-1665</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1021/acschemneuro.2c00156</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>As neurons age, protein homeostasis becomes less efficient, resulting in misfolding and aggregation. Chaperone proteins perform vital functions in the maintenance of cellular proteostasis, and chaperone-based therapies that promote sequestration of toxic aggregates may prove useful in blocking the development of neurodegenerative disease. We previously demonstrated that proSAAS, a small secreted neuronal protein, exhibits potent chaperone activity against protein aggregation in vitro and blocks the cytotoxic effects of amyloid and synuclein oligomers in cell culture systems. We now examine whether cytoplasmic expression of proSAAS results in interactions with protein aggregates in this cellular compartment. We report that expression of proSAAS within the cytoplasm generates dense, membraneless 2 &#x3bc;m proSAAS spheres which progressively fuse to form larger spheres, suggesting liquid droplet-like properties. ProSAAS spheres selectively accumulate a C-terminally truncated fluorescently tagged form of TDP-43, initiating its cellular redistribution; these TDP-43-containing spheres also exhibit dynamic fusion. Efficient encapsulation of TDP-43 into proSAAS spheres is driven by its C-terminal prion-like domain; spheres must be formed for sequestration to occur. Three proSAAS sequences, a predicted coiled-coil, a conserved region (residues 158-169), and the positively charged sequence 181-185, are all required for proSAAS to form spheres able to encapsulate TDP-43 aggregates. Substitution of lysines for arginines in the 181-185 sequence results in nuclear translocation of proSAAS and encapsulation of nuclear-localized TDP-43<sup>216-414</sup>. As a functional output, we demonstrate that proSAAS expression results in cytoprotection against full-length TDP-43 toxicity in yeast. We conclude that proSAAS can act as a functional holdase for TDP-43 via this phase-separation property, representing a cytoprotectant whose unusual biochemical properties can potentially be exploited in the design of therapeutic molecules.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Peinado</LastName><ForeName>Juan R</ForeName><Initials>JR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anatomy and Neurobiology, University of Maryland School of Medicine, University of Maryland, Baltimore, Maryland 21201, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chaplot</LastName><ForeName>Kriti</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anatomy and Neurobiology, University of Maryland School of Medicine, University of Maryland, Baltimore, Maryland 21201, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jarvela</LastName><ForeName>Timothy S</ForeName><Initials>TS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anatomy and Neurobiology, University of Maryland School of Medicine, University of Maryland, Baltimore, Maryland 21201, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Barbieri</LastName><ForeName>Edward M</ForeName><Initials>EM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biochemistry and Biophysics, Perelman School of Medicine, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania 19104, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shorter</LastName><ForeName>James</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5269-8533</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biochemistry and Biophysics, Perelman School of Medicine, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania 19104, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lindberg</LastName><ForeName>Iris</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1188-170X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anatomy and Neurobiology, University of Maryland School of Medicine, University of Maryland, Baltimore, Maryland 21201, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R01 AG062222</GrantID><Acronym>AG</Acronym><Agency>NIA NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>ACS Chem Neurosci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101525337</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1948-7193</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D004268">DNA-Binding Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D018832">Molecular Chaperones</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D066329">Protein Aggregates</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003593" MajorTopicYN="N">Cytoplasm</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004268" MajorTopicYN="N">DNA-Binding Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018832" MajorTopicYN="N">Molecular Chaperones</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019636" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neurodegenerative Diseases</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D066329" MajorTopicYN="N">Protein Aggregates</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ALS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">FTD</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PCSK1N</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">TDP-43</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chaperone</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">liquid&#x2212;liquid phase separation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neurodegeneration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">proSAAS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">proteostasis</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement><b>Conflicts of Interest:</b> None.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35549000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS1850929</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9731516</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acschemneuro.2c00156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Valastyan JS; Lindquist S, Mechanisms of protein-folding diseases at a glance. Dis Model Mech 2014, 7 (1), 9&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3882043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24396149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klaips CL; Jayaraj GG; Hartl FU, Pathways of cellular proteostasis in aging and disease. J Cell Biol 2018, 217 (1), 51&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5748993</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29127110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayala YM; Zago P; D&#x2019;Ambrogio A; Xu YF; Petrucelli L; Buratti E; Baralle FE, Structural determinants of the cellular localization and shuttling of TDP-43. J Cell Sci 2008, 121 (Pt 22), 3778&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18957508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neumann M; Sampathu DM; Kwong LK; Truax AC; Micsenyi MC; Chou TT; Bruce J; Schuck T; Grossman M; Clark CM; McCluskey LF; Miller BL; Masliah E; Mackenzie IR; Feldman H; Feiden W; Kretzschmar HA; Trojanowski JQ; Lee VM, Ubiquitinated TDP-43 in frontotemporal lobar degeneration and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Science 2006, 314 (5796), 130&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17023659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Boer EMJ; Orie VK; Williams T; Baker MR; De Oliveira HM; Polvikoski T; Silsby M; Menon P; van den Bos M; Halliday GM; van den Berg LH; Van Den Bosch L; van Damme P; Kiernan MC; van Es MA; Vucic S, TDP-43 proteinopathies: a new wave of neurodegenerative diseases. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2020, 92 (1), 86&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7803890</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33177049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gasset-Rosa F; Lu S; Yu H; Chen C; Melamed Z; Guo L; Shorter J; Da Cruz S; Cleveland DW, Cytoplasmic TDP-43 De-mixing Independent of Stress Granules Drives Inhibition of Nuclear Import, Loss of Nuclear TDP-43, and Cell Death. Neuron 2019, 102 (2), 339&#x2013;357.e7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6548321</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30853299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gomes E; Shorter J, The molecular language of membraneless organelles. J Biol Chem 2019, 294 (18), 7115&#x2013;7127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6509512</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30045872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartl FU, Protein Misfolding Diseases. Annu Rev Biochem 2017, 86, 21&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28441058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bobori C; Theocharopoulou G; Vlamos P, Molecular Chaperones in Neurodegenerative Diseases: A Short Review. Adv Exp Med Biol 2017, 987, 219&#x2013;231.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28971461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiti F; Dobson CM, Protein Misfolding, Amyloid Formation, and Human Disease: A Summary of Progress Over the Last Decade. Annu Rev Biochem 2017, 86, 27&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28498720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balchin D; Hayer-Hartl M; Hartl FU, In vivo aspects of protein folding and quality control. Science 2016, 353 (6294), aac4354.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27365453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Webster JM; Darling AL; Uversky VN; Blair LJ, Small Heat Shock Proteins, Big Impact on Protein Aggregation in Neurodegenerative Disease. Frontiers in pharmacology 2019, 10, 1047.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6759932</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31619995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whiten DR; Cox D; Horrocks MH; Taylor CG; De S; Flagmeier P; Tosatto L; Kumita JR; Ecroyd H; Dobson CM; Klenerman D; Wilson MR, Single-Molecule Characterization of the Interactions between Extracellular Chaperones and Toxic alpha-Synuclein Oligomers. Cell Rep 2018, 23 (12), 3492&#x2013;3500.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6024880</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29924993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foster EM; Dangla-Valls A; Lovestone S; Ribe EM; Buckley NJ, Clusterin in Alzheimer&#x2019;s Disease: Mechanisms, Genetics, and Lessons From Other Pathologies. Frontiers in neuroscience 2019, 13, 164.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6403191</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30872998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoshino A; Helwig M; Razaei S; Berridge C; Eriksen J; Lindberg I, A novel function for proSAAS as an amyloid anti-aggregant in Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. J Neurochem 2014, 128 (3), 419&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3946950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24102330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jarvela TS; Lam HA; Helwig M; Lorenzen N; Otzen DE; McLean PJ; Maidment NT; Lindberg I, The neural chaperone proSAAS blocks alpha-synuclein fibrillation and neurotoxicity. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 2016, 113 (32), E4708&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4987805</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27457957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kikuchi K; Arawaka S; Koyama S; Kimura H; Ren CH; Wada M; Kawanami T; Kurita K; Daimon M; Kawakatsu S; Kadoya T; Goto K; Kato T, An N-terminal fragment of ProSAAS (a granin-like neuroendocrine peptide precursor) is associated with tau inclusions in Pick&#x2019;s disease. Biochem Biophys Res Commun 2003, 308 (3), 646&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12914799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wada M; Ren CH; Koyama S; Arawaka S; Kawakatsu S; Kimura H; Nagasawa H; Kawanami T; Kurita K; Daimon M; Hirano A; Kato T, A human granin-like neuroendocrine peptide precursor (proSAAS) immunoreactivity in tau inclusions of Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease and parkinsonism-dementia complex on Guam. Neurosci Lett 2004, 356 (1), 49&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14746899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davidsson P; Sjogren M; Andreasen N; Lindbjer M; Nilsson CL; Westman-Brinkmalm A; Blennow K, Studies of the pathophysiological mechanisms in frontotemporal dementia by proteome analysis of CSF proteins. Brain Res Mol Brain Res 2002, 109 (1&#x2013;2), 128&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12531522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdi F; Quinn JF; Jankovic J; McIntosh M; Leverenz JB; Peskind E; Nixon R; Nutt J; Chung K; Zabetian C; Samii A; Lin M; Hattan S; Pan C; Wang Y; Jin J; Zhu D; Li GJ; Liu Y; Waichunas D; Montine TJ; Zhang J, Detection of biomarkers with a multiplex quantitative proteomic platform in cerebrospinal fluid of patients with neurodegenerative disorders. J Alzheimers Dis 2006, 9 (3), 293&#x2013;348.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16914840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jahn H; Wittke S; Zurbig P; Raedler TJ; Arlt S; Kellmann M; Mullen W; Eichenlaub M; Mischak H; Wiedemann K, Peptide fingerprinting of Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease in cerebrospinal fluid: identification and prospective evaluation of new synaptic biomarkers. PLoS One 2011, 6 (10), e26540.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3202544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22046305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finehout EJ; Franck Z; Choe LH; Relkin N; Lee KH, Cerebrospinal fluid proteomic biomarkers for Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. Ann Neurol 2007, 61 (2), 120&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17167789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J; Cunningham R; Zetterberg H; Asthana S; Carlsson C; Okonkwo O; Li L, Label-free quantitative comparison of cerebrospinal fluid glycoproteins and endogenous peptides in subjects with Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease, mild cognitive impairment, and healthy individuals. Proteomics. Clinical applications 2016, 10 (12), 1225&#x2013;1241.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27863112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi YS; Hou S; Choe LH; Lee KH, Targeted human cerebrospinal fluid proteomics for the validation of multiple Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease biomarker candidates. J Chromatogr B Analyt Technol Biomed Life Sci 2013, 930, 129&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3710693</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23735279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spellman DS; Wildsmith KR; Honigberg LA; Tuefferd M; Baker D; Raghavan N; Nairn AC; Croteau P; Schirm M; Allard R; Lamontagne J; Chelsky D; Hoffmann S; Potter WZ, Development and evaluation of a multiplexed mass spectrometry based assay for measuring candidate peptide biomarkers in Alzheimer&#x2019;s Disease Neuroimaging Initiative (ADNI) CSF. Proteomics. Clinical applications 2015, 9 (7&#x2013;8), 715&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4739636</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25676562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holtta M; Minthon L; Hansson O; Holmen-Larsson J; Pike I; Ward M; Kuhn K; Ruetschi U; Zetterberg H; Blennow K; Gobom J, An integrated workflow for multiplex CSF proteomics and peptidomics-identification of candidate cerebrospinal fluid biomarkers of Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. J Proteome Res 2015, 14 (2), 654&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25490617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khoonsari PE; Shevchenko G; Herman S; Remnest&#xe5;l J; Giedraitis V; Brundin R; Degerman Gunnarsson M; Kilander L; Zetterberg H; Nilsson P; Lannfelt L; Ingelsson M; Kultima K, Improved Differential Diagnosis of Alzheimer&#x2019;s Disease by Integrating ELISA and Mass Spectrometry-Based Cerebrospinal Fluid Biomarkers. J Alzheimers Dis 2019, 67 (2), 639&#x2013;651.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6398544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30614806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Steenoven I; Koel-Simmelink MJA; Vergouw LJM; Tijms BM; Piersma SR; Pham TV; Bridel C; Ferri GL; Cocco C; Noli B; Worley PF; Xiao MF; Xu D; Oeckl P; Otto M; van der Flier WM; de Jong FJ; Jimenez CR; Lemstra AW; Teunissen CE, Identification of novel cerebrospinal fluid biomarker candidates for dementia with Lewy bodies: a proteomic approach. Mol Neurodegener 2020, 15 (1), 36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7301448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32552841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathys H; Davila-Velderrain J; Peng Z; Gao F; Mohammadi S; Young JZ; Menon M; He L; Abdurrob F; Jiang X; Martorell AJ; Ransohoff RM; Hafler BP; Bennett DA; Kellis M; Tsai LH, Single-cell transcriptomic analysis of Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. Nature 2019, 570 (7761), 332&#x2013;337.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6865822</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31042697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#xf6;rrbaum AR; Alvarez-Castelao B; Nassim-Assir B; Langer JD; Schuman EM, Proteome dynamics during homeostatic scaling in cultured neurons. Elife 2020, 9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7117909</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32238265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang C; Tan W; Whittle C; Qiu L; Cao L; Akbarian S; Xu Z, The C-terminal TDP-43 fragments have a high aggregation propensity and harm neurons by a dominant-negative mechanism. PLoS One 2010, 5 (12), e15878.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3013128</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21209826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Narain Y; Wyttenbach A; Rankin J; Furlong RA; Rubinsztein DC, A molecular investigation of true dominance in Huntington&#x2019;s disease. Journal of medical genetics 1999, 36 (10), 739&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1734229</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10528852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoover BR; Reed MN; Su J; Penrod RD; Kotilinek LA; Grant MK; Pitstick R; Carlson GA; Lanier LM; Yuan LL; Ashe KH; Liao D, Tau mislocalization to dendritic spines mediates synaptic dysfunction independently of neurodegeneration. Neuron 2010, 68 (6), 1067&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3026458</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21172610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furlong RA; Narain Y; Rankin J; Wyttenbach A; Rubinsztein DC, Alpha-synuclein overexpression promotes aggregation of mutant huntingtin. Biochem J 2000, 346 Pt 3, 577&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1220887</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10698681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Porta S; Xu Y; Restrepo CR; Kwong LK; Zhang B; Brown HJ; Lee EB; Trojanowski JQ; Lee VM, Patient-derived frontotemporal lobar degeneration brain extracts induce formation and spreading of TDP-43 pathology in vivo. Nat Commun 2018, 9 (1), 4220.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6181940</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30310141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jarnot P; Ziemska-Legiecka J; Dobson L; Merski M; Mier P; Andrade-Navarro MA; Hancock JM; Doszt&#xe1;nyi Z; Paladin L; Necci M; Piovesan D; Tosatto SCE; Promponas VJ; Grynberg M; Gruca A, PlaToLoCo: the first web meta-server for visualization and annotation of low complexity regions in proteins. Nucleic Acids Res 2020, 48 (W1), W77&#x2013;w84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7319588</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32421769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang A; Conicella AE; Schmidt HB; Martin EW; Rhoads SN; Reeb AN; Nourse A; Ramirez Montero D; Ryan VH; Rohatgi R; Shewmaker F; Naik MT; Mittag T; Ayala YM; Fawzi NL, A single N-terminal phosphomimic disrupts TDP-43 polymerization, phase separation, and RNA splicing. Embo j 2018, 37 (5).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5830921</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29438978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mann JR; Gleixner AM; Mauna JC; Gomes E; DeChellis-Marks MR; Needham PG; Copley KE; Hurtle B; Portz B; Pyles NJ; Guo L; Calder CB; Wills ZP; Pandey UB; Kofler JK; Brodsky JL; Thathiah A; Shorter J; Donnelly CJ, RNA Binding Antagonizes Neurotoxic Phase Transitions of TDP-43. Neuron 2019, 102 (2), 321&#x2013;338.e8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6472983</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30826182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaplot K; Jarvela TS; Lindberg I, Secreted Chaperones in Neurodegeneration. Frontiers in aging neuroscience 2020, 12, 268.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7481362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33192447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Becker LA; Huang B; Bieri G; Ma R; Knowles DA; Jafar-Nejad P; Messing J; Kim HJ; Soriano A; Auburger G; Pulst SM; Taylor JP; Rigo F; Gitler AD, Therapeutic reduction of ataxin-2 extends lifespan and reduces pathology in TDP-43 mice. Nature 2017, 544 (7650), 367&#x2013;371.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5642042</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28405022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suk TR; Rousseaux MWC, The role of TDP-43 mislocalization in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Mol Neurodegener 2020, 15 (1), 45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7429473</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32799899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banani SF; Lee HO; Hyman AA; Rosen MK, Biomolecular condensates: organizers of cellular biochemistry. Nat Rev Mol Cell Biol 2017, 18 (5), 285&#x2013;298.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7434221</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28225081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alberti S; Halfmann R; King O; Kapila A; Lindquist S, A systematic survey identifies prions and illuminates sequence features of prionogenic proteins. Cell 2009, 137 (1), 146&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2683788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19345193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kudo H; Liu J; Jansen EJ; Ozawa A; Panula P; Martens GJ; Lindberg I, Identification of proSAAS homologs in lower vertebrates: conservation of hydrophobic helices and convertase-inhibiting sequences. Endocrinology 2009, 150 (3), 1393&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2654743</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18948394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolozin B; Ivanov P, Stress granules and neurodegeneration. Nat Rev Neurosci 2019, 20 (11), 649&#x2013;666.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6986315</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31582840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prasad A; Bharathi V; Sivalingam V; Girdhar A; Patel BK, Molecular Mechanisms of TDP-43 Misfolding and Pathology in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. Front Mol Neurosci 2019, 12, 25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6382748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30837838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eck RJ; Kraemer BC; Liachko NF, Regulation of TDP-43 phosphorylation in aging and disease. Geroscience 2021, 43 (4), 1605&#x2013;1614.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8492835</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34032984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt HB; Barreau A; Rohatgi R, Phase separation-deficient TDP43 remains functional in splicing. Nat Commun 2019, 10 (1), 4890.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6814767</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31653829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson BS; Snead D; Lee JJ; McCaffery JM; Shorter J; Gitler AD, TDP-43 is intrinsically aggregation-prone, and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-linked mutations accelerate aggregation and increase toxicity. J Biol Chem 2009, 284 (30), 20329&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2740458</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19465477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li HR; Chiang WC; Chou PC; Wang WJ; Huang JR, TAR DNA-binding protein 43 (TDP-43) liquid-liquid phase separation is mediated by just a few aromatic residues. J Biol Chem 2018, 293 (16), 6090&#x2013;6098.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5912450</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29511089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt HB; Rohatgi R, In Vivo Formation of Vacuolated Multi-phase Compartments Lacking Membranes. Cell Rep 2016, 16 (5), 1228&#x2013;1236.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4972689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27452472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu H; Lu S; Gasior K; Singh D; Vazquez-Sanchez S; Tapia O; Toprani D; Beccari MS; Yates JR 3rd; Da Cruz S; Newby JM; Lafarga M; Gladfelter AS; Villa E; Cleveland DW, HSP70 chaperones RNA-free TDP-43 into anisotropic intranuclear liquid spherical shells. Science 2021, 371 (6529).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8286096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33335017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reinkemeier CD; Lemke EA, Synthetic biomolecular condensates to engineer eukaryotic cells. Curr Opin Chem Biol 2021, 64, 174&#x2013;181.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34600419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lasker K; Boeynaems S; Lam V; Stainton E; Jacquemyn M; Daelemans D; Villa E; Holehouse AS; Gitler AD; Shapiro L, A modular platform for engineering function of natural and synthetic biomolecular condensates. bioRxiv 2021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9512792</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36163138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boeynaems S; Dorone Y; Marian A; Shabardina V; Huang G; Kim G; Sanyal A; &#x15e;en N-E; Docampo R; Ruiz-Trillo I; Lasker K; Auburger G; Kabashi E; Gitler AD, Poly(A)-binding protein is an ataxin-2 chaperone that emulsifies biomolecular condensates. bioRxiv 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshikawa M; Yoshii T; Ikuta M; Tsukiji S, Synthetic Protein Condensates That Inducibly Recruit and Release Protein Activity in Living Cells. J Am Chem Soc 2021, 143 (17), 6434&#x2013;6446.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33890764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boyd JD; Lee P; Feiler MS; Zauur N; Liu M; Concannon J; Ebata A; Wolozin B; Glicksman MA, A high-content screen identifies novel compounds that inhibit stress-induced TDP-43 cellular aggregation and associated cytotoxicity. J Biomol Screen 2014, 19 (1), 44&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3913261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24019256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackrel ME; Shorter J, Potentiated Hsp104 variants suppress toxicity of diverse neurodegenerative disease-linked proteins. Disease Models &amp; Mechanisms 2014, 7, 1175&#x2013;1184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4174528</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25062688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elden AC; Kim HJ; Hart MP; Chen-Plotkin AS; Johnson BS; Fang X; Armakola M; Geser F; Greene R; Lu MM; Padmanabhan A; Clay-Falcone D; McCluskey L; Elman L; Juhr D; Gruber PJ; Rub U; Auburger G; Trojanowski JQ; Lee VM; Van Deerlin VM; Bonini NM; Gitler AD, Ataxin-2 intermediate-length polyglutamine expansions are associated with increased risk for ALS. Nature 2010, 466 (7310), 1069&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2965417</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20740007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peggion C; Massimino ML; Stella R; Bortolotto R; Agostini J; Maldi A; Sartori G; Tonello F; Bertoli A; Lopreiato R, Nucleolin Rescues TDP-43 Toxicity in Yeast and Human Cell Models. Front Cell Neurosci 2021, 15, 625665.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8072491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33912014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frost NA; Shroff H; Kong H; Betzig E; Blanpied TA, Single-molecule discrimination of discrete perisynaptic and distributed sites of actin filament assembly within dendritic spines. Neuron 2010, 67 (1), 86&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2904347</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20624594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fischer JW; Busa VF; Shao Y; Leung AKL, Structure-Mediated RNA Decay by UPF1 and G3BP1. Mol Cell 2020, 78 (1), 70&#x2013;84.e6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8055448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32017897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thayer JA; Awad O; Hegdekar N; Sarkar C; Tesfay H; Burt C; Zeng X; Feldman RA; Lipinski MM, The PARK10 gene USP24 is a negative regulator of autophagy and ULK1 protein stability. Autophagy 2020, 16 (1), 140&#x2013;153.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6984603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30957634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schindelin J; Arganda-Carreras I; Frise E; Kaynig V; Longair M; Pietzsch T; Preibisch S; Rueden C; Saalfeld S; Schmid B; Tinevez JY; White DJ; Hartenstein V; Eliceiri K; Tomancak P; Cardona A, Fiji: an open-source platform for biological-image analysis. Nat Methods 2012, 9 (7), 676&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3855844</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22743772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ollion J; Cochennec J; Loll F; Escude C; Boudier T, TANGO: a generic tool for high-throughput 3D image analysis for studying nuclear organization. Bioinformatics 2013, 29 (14), 1840&#x2013;1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3702251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23681123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jumper J; Evans R; Pritzel A; Green T; Figurnov M; Ronneberger O; Tunyasuvunakool K; Bates R; &#x17d;&#xed;dek A; Potapenko A; Bridgland A; Meyer C; Kohl SAA; Ballard AJ; Cowie A; Romera-Paredes B; Nikolov S; Jain R; Adler J; Back T; Petersen S; Reiman D; Clancy E; Zielinski M; Steinegger M; Pacholska M; Berghammer T; Bodenstein S; Silver D; Vinyals O; Senior AW; Kavukcuoglu K; Kohli P; Hassabis D, Highly accurate protein structure prediction with AlphaFold. Nature 2021, 596 (7873), 583&#x2013;589.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8371605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34265844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varadi M; Anyango S; Deshpande M; Nair S; Natassia C; Yordanova G; Yuan D; Stroe O; Wood G; Laydon A; &#x17d;&#xed;dek A; Green T; Tunyasuvunakool K; Petersen S; Jumper J; Clancy E; Green R; Vora A; Lutfi M; Figurnov M; Cowie A; Hobbs N; Kohli P; Kleywegt G; Birney E; Hassabis D; Velankar S, AlphaFold Protein Structure Database: massively expanding the structural coverage of protein-sequence space with high-accuracy models. Nucleic Acids Res 2022, 50 (D1), D439&#x2013;d444.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8728224</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34791371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ludwiczak J; Winski A; Szczepaniak K; Alva V; Dunin-Horkawicz S, DeepCoil-a fast and accurate prediction of coiled-coil domains in protein sequences. Bioinformatics 2019, 35 (16), 2790&#x2013;2795.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30601942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>