<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35579450</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>22</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1531-8257</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>37</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Movement disorders : official journal of the Movement Disorder Society</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Mov Disord</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Can We Treat Neurodegenerative Proteinopathies by Enhancing Protein Degradation?</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1346</StartPage><EndPage>1359</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1346-1359</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/mds.29058</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Neurodegenerative proteinopathies are defined as a class of neurodegenerative disorders, with either genetic or sporadic age-related onset, characterized by the pathological accumulation of aggregated protein deposits. These mainly include Alzheimer's disease (AD), Parkinson's disease (PD), amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS), Huntington's disease (HD) as well as frontotemporal lobar degeneration (FTLD). The deposition of abnormal protein aggregates in the brain of patients affected by these disorders is thought to play a causative role in neuronal loss and disease progression. On that account, the idea of improving the clearance of pathological protein aggregates has taken hold as a potential therapeutic strategy. Among the possible approaches to pursue for reducing disease protein accumulation, there is the stimulation of the main protein degradation machineries of eukaryotic cells: the ubiquitin proteasomal system (UPS) and autophagy lysosomal pathway (ALP). Of note, several clinical trials testing the efficacy of either UPS- or ALP-active compounds are currently ongoing. Here, we discuss the main gaps and controversies emerging from experimental studies and clinical trials assessing the therapeutic efficacy of modulators of either the UPS or ALP in neurodegenerative proteinopathies, to gather whether they may constitute a real gateway from these disorders. &#xa9; 2022 International Parkinson and Movement Disorder Society.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022 International Parkinson and Movement Disorder Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Engelender</LastName><ForeName>Simone</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biochemistry, The B. Rappaport Faculty of Medicine and Institute of Medical Research, Technion-Israel Institute of Technology, Haifa, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stefanis</LastName><ForeName>Leonidas</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biomedical Research Foundation of the Academy of Athens, Athens, Greece.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>First Department of Neurology, National and Kapodistrian University of Athens Medical School, Athens, Greece.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oddo</LastName><ForeName>Salvatore</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemical, Biological, Pharmaceutical, and Environmental Sciences, University of Messina, Messina, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bellucci</LastName><ForeName>Arianna</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9581-1919</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Molecular and Translational Medicine, University of Brescia, Brescia, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Mov Disord</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8610688</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0885-3185</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D066329">Protein Aggregates</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D011506">Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D025801">Ubiquitin</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057174" MajorTopicYN="Y">Frontotemporal Lobar Degeneration</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D066329" MajorTopicYN="N">Protein Aggregates</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011506" MajorTopicYN="N">Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D059748" MajorTopicYN="N">Proteolysis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D025801" MajorTopicYN="N">Ubiquitin</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">autophagy lysosomal pathway</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neurodegenerative proteinopathies</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pathological protein aggregates</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic strategies</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ubiquitin proteasomal system</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35579450</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mds.29058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Kovaks GG. Molecular pathology of neurodegenerative diseases: principles and practice. J Clin Pathol 2019;72:725-735.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Root J, Merino P, Nuckols A, Johnson M, Kukar T. Lysosome dysfunction as a cause of neurodegenerative diseases: lessons from frontotemporal dementia and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurobiol Dis 2021;154:105360</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jucker M, Walker LC. Propagation and spread of pathogenic protein assemblies in neurodegenerative diseases. Nat Neurosci 2018;21:1341-1349.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henderson MX, Henrich MT, Geibl FF, Oertel WH, Brundin P, Surmeier DJ. The role of connectivity and neuronal phenotype in determining the pattern of &#x3b1;-synuclein pathology in Parkinson's disease. Neurobiol Dis 2022;10:168</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Engelender S, Isacson O. The threshold theory for Parkinson's disease. Trends Neurosci 2017;40:4-14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Espay A. Movement disorders research in 2021: cracking the paradigm. Lancet Neurol 2022;21:10-11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parkkinen L, O'Sullivan SS, Collins C, et al. Disentangling the relationship between lewy bodies and nigral neuronal loss in Parkinson's disease. J Parkinsons Dis 2011;1:277-286.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke RE, Dauer WT, Vonsattel JPG. A critical evaluation of the Braak staging scheme for Parkinson's disease. Ann Neurol 2008;64:485-491.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchman AS, Yu L, Wilson RS, et al. Progressive parkinsonism in older adults is related to the burden of mixed brain pathologies. Neurology 2019;92:e1821-e1830.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Espay AJ, Sturchio A, Schneiderb LS, Ezzatc K. Soluble amyloid-&#x3b2; consumption in Alzheimer's disease. J Alzheimers Dis 2021;82:1403-1415.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alexander GC, Emerson S, Kesselheim AS. Evaluation of Aducanumab for Alzheimer disease: scientific evidence and regulatory review involving efficacy, safety, and futility. JAMA 2019;325:1717-1718.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ciechanover A, Brundin P. The ubiquitin proteasome system in neurodegenerative diseases: sometimes the chicken, sometimes the egg. Neuron 2003;40:427-446.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McFarthing K, Rafaloff G, Baptista MAS, Wyse RK, Stott SRW. Parkinson's disease drug therapies in the clinical trial pipeline: 2020. J Parkinsons Dis 2020;10:757-774.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva-Islas CA, Maldonado PD. Canonical and non-canonical mechanisms of Nrf2 activation. Pharmacol Res 2018;134:92-99.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skibinski G, Hwang V, Ando DM, et al. Nrf2 mitigates LRRK2- and &#x3b1;-synuclein-induced neurodegeneration by modulating proteostasis. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 2017;114:1165-1170.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lastres-Becker I, Ulusoy A, Innamorato NG, et al. &#x3b1;-Synuclein expression and Nrf2 deficiency cooperate to aggravate protein aggregation, neuronal death and inflammation in early-stage Parkinson's disease. Hum Mol Genet 2012;21:3173-3192.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rojo AI, Pajares M, Rada P, et al. NRF2 deficiency replicates transcriptomic changes in Alzheimer's patients and worsens APP and TAU pathology. Redox Biol 2017;13:444-451.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ram&#xed;rez-Garza SL, Laveriano-Santos EP, Marhuenda-Mu&#xf1;oz M, et al. Health effects of resveratrol: results from human intervention trials. Nutrients 2018;10:1892</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boselli M, Lee BH, Robert J, et al. An inhibitor of the proteasomal deubiquitinating enzyme USP14 induces tau elimination in cultured neurons. J Biol Chem 2017;292:19209-19225.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian T, McLean JW, Wilson JA, Wilson SM. Examination of genetic and pharmacological tools to study the proteasomal deubiquitinating enzyme ubiquitin-specific protease 14 in the nervous system. J Neurochem 2021;156:309-323.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lokireddy S, Kukushkin NK, Goldberg AL. cAMP-induced phosphorylation of 26S proteasomes on Rpn6/PSMD11 enhances their activity and the degradation of misfolded proteins. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 2015;112:E7176-E7185.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myeku N, Clelland CL, Emrani S, et al. Tau-driven 26S proteasome impairment and cognitive dysfunction can be prevented early in disease by activating cAMP-PKA signaling. Nat Med 2016;22:46-53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanders O, Rajagopal L. Phosphodiesterase inhibitors for Alzheimer's disease: a systematic review of clinical trials and epidemiology with a mechanistic Rationale. J Alzheimers Dis Rep 2020;4:185-215.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boland B, Yu WH, Corti O, et al. Promoting the clearance of neurotoxic proteins in neurodegenerative disorders of ageing. Nat Rev Drug Discov 2018;17:660-688.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rott R, Szargel R, Shani V, et al. SUMOylation and ubiquitination reciprocally regulate &#x3b1;-synuclein degradation and pathological aggregation. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 2017;114:13176-13181.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vicente Miranda H, Szego EM, Oliveira LMA, et al. Glycation potentiates &#x3b1;-synuclein-associated neurodegeneration in synucleinopathies. Brain 2017;140:1399-1419.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo HB, Xia YY, Shu XJ, et al. Sumoylation at K340 inhibits tau degradation through regulating its phosphorylation and ubiquitination. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA 2017;111:16586-16591.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stefanis L, Emmanouilidou E, Pantazopoulou M, Kirik D, Vekrellis K, Tofaris GK. How is alpha-synuclein cleared from the cell? J Neurochem 2019;150:577-590.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xilouri M, Stefanis L. Chaperone mediated autophagy to the rescue: a new-fangled target for the treatment of neurodegenerative diseases. Mol Cell Neurosci 2015;66(Pt A):29-36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Querfurth H, Lee HK. Mammalian/mechanistic target of rapamycin (mTOR) complexes in neurodegeneration. Mol Neurodegener 2021;16:44</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alvarez-Erviti L, Rodriguez-Oroz MC, Cooper JM, et al. Chaperone-mediated autophagy markers in Parkinson disease brains. Arch Neurol 2010;67:1464-1472.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy KE, Gysbers AM, Abbott SK, et al. Lysosomal-associated membrane protein 2 isoforms are differentially affected in early Parkinson's disease. Mov Disord 2015;30:1639-1647.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crews L, Spencer B, Desplats P, et al. Selective molecular alterations in the autophagy pathway in patients with Lewy body disease and in models of alpha-synucleinopathy. PLoS One 2010;5:e9313</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bj&#xf8;rk&#xf8;y G, Lamark T, Brech A, et al. p62/SQSTM1 forms protein aggregates degraded by autophagy and has a protective effect on huntingtin-induced cell death. J Cell Biol 2005;171:603-614.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ravikumar B, Vacher C, Berger Z, et al. Inhibition of mTOR induces autophagy and reduces toxicity of polyglutamine expansions in fly and mouse models of Huntington disease. Nat Genet 2004;36:585-595.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spilman P, Podlutskaya N, Hart MJ, et al. Inhibition of mTOR by rapamycin abolishes cognitive deficits and reduces amyloid-beta levels in a mouse model of Alzheimer's disease. PLoS One 2010;5:e9979</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Staats KA, Hernandez S, Sch&#xf6;nefeldt S, et al. Rapamycin increases survival in ALS mice lacking mature lymphocytes. Mol Neurodegener 2013;8:31</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Eijk RPA, Jones AJ, Sproviero W, et al. Meta-analysis of pharmacogenetic interactions in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis clinical trials. Neurology 2017;89:1915-1922.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simuni T, Fiske B, Merchant K, et al. Efficacy of Nilotinib in patients with moderately advanced Parkinson disease: a randomized clinical trial. Parkinson study group NILO-PD investigators and collaborators. JAMA Neurol 2021;78:312-320.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pagan FL, Hebron ML, Wilmarth B, et al. Nilotinib effects on safety, tolerability, and potential biomarkers in Parkinson disease: a phase 2 randomized clinical trial. JAMA Neurol 2020;77:309-317.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner RS, Hebron ML, Lawler A, et al. Nilotinib effects on safety, tolerability, and biomarkers in Alzheimer's disease. Ann Neurol 2020;88:183-194.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egan MF, Kost J, Voss T, et al. Randomized trial of Verubecestat for prodromal Alzheimer's disease. N Engl J Med 2019;380:1408-1420.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sur C, Kost J, Scott D, et al. BACE inhibition causes rapid, regional, and non-progressive volume reduction in Alzheimer's disease brain. Brain 2020;143:3816-3826.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zempel H, Luedtke J, Kumar Y, et al. Amyloid-&#x3b2; oligomers induce synaptic damage via tau-dependent microtubule severing by TTLL6 and spastin. EMBO J 2013;32:2920-2937.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jadhav S, Cubinkova V, Zimova I, et al. Tau-mediated synaptic damage in Alzheimer's disease. Transl Neurosci 2015;6:214-226.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellucci A, Mercuri NB, Venneri A, Faustini G, et al. Parkinson's disease: from synaptic loss to connectome dysfunction. Neuropathol Appl Neurobiol 2016;42:77-94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schulz-Schaeffer W. The synaptic pathology of alpha-synuclein aggregation in dementia with Lewy bodies, Parkinson's disease and Parkinson's disease dementia. Acta Neuropatol 2010;120:131-143.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kramer ML, Schulz-Schaeffer WJ. Presynaptic &#x3b1;-Synuclein aggregates, not Lewy bodies, cause neurodegeneration in dementia with Lewy bodies. J Neurosci 2007;27:1405-1410.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andica C, Kamagata K, Hatano T, et al. Neurite orientation dispersion and density imaging of the nigrostriatal pathway in Parkinson's disease: retrograde degeneration observed by tract-profile analysis. Parkinsonism Relat Disord 2018;51:55-60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cal&#xf3; L, Hidari E, Wegrzynowicz M, Dalley JW, et al. CSP&#x3b1; reduces aggregates and rescues striatal dopamine release in &#x3b1;-synuclein transgenic mice. Brain 2021;144:1661-1669.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faustini G, Longhena F, Masato A, et al. Synapsin III gene silencing redeems alpha-synuclein trasgenic mice from Parkinson's disease-like phenotype. Mol Ther 2022;30:1465-1483.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang J-H, Irwin DJ, Chen-Plotkin AS, et al. Association of cerebrospinal fluid &#x3b2;-amyloid 1-42, T-tau, P-tau181, and &#x3b1;-synuclein levels with clinical features of drug-naive patients with early Parkinson disease. JAMA Neurol 2013;70:1277-1287.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hall S, Surova Y, &#xd6;hrfelt A, et al. Longitudinal measurements of cerebrospinal fluid biomarkers in Parkinson's disease. Mov Disord 2016;31:898-905.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Majbour NK, Abdi IY, Dakna M, et al. Cerebrospinal &#x3b1;-Synuclein oligomers reflect disease motor severity in DeNoPa longitudinal cohort. Mov Disord 2021;36:2048-2056.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stuedl A, Kunadt M, Kruse N, et al. Induction of &#x3b1;-synuclein aggregate formation by CSF exosomes from patients with Parkinson's disease and dementia with Lewy bodies. Brain 2016;139:481-494.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ngolab J, Trihn I, Rockenstein E, et al. Brain-derived exosomes from dementia with Lewy bodies propagate &#x3b1;-synuclein pathology. Acta Neuropathol Comm 2017;5:46</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Rusinek H, Butler T, et al. Decreased CSF clearance and increased brain amyloid in Alzheimer's disease. Fluids Barriers CNS 2022;19:21</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parnetti L, Chiasserini D, Bellomo G, et al. Cerebrospinal fluid tau/&#x3b1;-synuclein ratio in Parkinson's disease and degenerative dementias. Mov Disord 2011;26:1428-1435.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leuzy A, Cullen NC, Mattsson-Carlgren N, Hansson O. Current advances in plasma and cerebrospinal fluid biomarkers in Alzheimer's disease. Curr Opin Neurol 2021;34:266-274.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abu-Rumeileh S, Mometto N, Bartoletti-Stella A, et al. Cerebrospinal fluid biomarkers in patients with frontotemporal dementia Spectrum: a single-center study. J Alzheimers Dis 2018;66:551-563.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pilotto A, Imarisio A, Conforti F, et al. Plasma NfL, clinical subtypes and motor progression in Parkinson's disease. Parkinsonism Relat Disord 2021;87:41-47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pilotto A, Imarisio A, Carrarini C, et al. Plasma Neurofilament light chain predicts cognitive progression in prodromal and clinical dementia with Lewy bodies. J Alzheimers Dis 2021;82:913-919.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark C, Lewczuk P, Kornhuber J, et al. Plasma neurofilament light and phosphorylated tau 181 as biomarkers of Alzheimer's disease pathology and clinical disease progression. Alzheimers Res Ther 2021;13:65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Constantinescu R, Rosengren L, Eriksson B, Blennow K, Axelsson M. Cerebrospinal fluid neurofilament light and tau protein as mortality biomarkers in parkinsonism. Clin Neurol Neurosurg 2018;174:174-179.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Araki W, Hattori K, Kanemaru K, et al. Re-evaluation of soluble APP-&#x3b1; and APP-&#x3b2; in cerebrospinal fluid as potential biomarkers for early diagnosis of dementia disorders. Biomark Res 2017;5:28</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davidsson P, Bogdanovic N, Lannfelt L, Blennow K. Reduced expression of amyloid precursor protein, presenilin-1 and rab3a in cortical brain regions in Alzheimer's disease. Dement Geriatr Cogn Dis 2001;12:243-250.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ransohof R. How neuroinflammation contributes to neurodegeneration. Science 2016;353:777-783.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim Y, Lee JS. Jo YH rapamycin increases the incidence of neuropsychiatric illness in kidney transplant patients through the suppression of neural stem cells. Transl Psychiatry 2020;18:156</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchman AS, Yu L, Wilson RS, Schneider JA, Bennett DA. Association of brain pathology with the progression of frailty in older adults. Neurology 2013;80:2055-2061.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Pablo-Fern&#xe1;ndez E, Lees AJ, Holton JH, Warner TT. Prognosis and neuropathologic correlation of clinical subtypes of Parkinson disease. JAMA Neurol 2019;76:470-479.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pickrell AM, Huang CH, Kennedy SR, et al. Endogenous Parkin preserves dopaminergic substantia Nigral neurons following mitochondrial DNA mutagenic stress. Neuron 2015;87:371-381.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poulopoulos M, Levy OA, Alcalay RN. The neuropathology of genetic Parkinson's disease. Mov Dis 2012;27:831-842.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shapira A. Glucocerebrosidase and Parkinson disease: recent advances. Mol Cell Neurosci 2015;66:37-42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balestrino R, Schapira A. Glucocerebrosidase and Parkinson disease: molecular, clinical, and therapeutic implications. Neuroscientist 2018;24:540-559.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong K, Sidransky E, Verma A, et al. Neuropathology provides clues to the pathophysiology of Gaucher disease. Mol Genet Metab 2004;82:192-207.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi JH, Stubblefield B, Cookson MR, Goldin E, Velayati A, Tayebi N, Sidransky E. Aggregation of &#x3b1;-synuclein in brain samples from subjects with glucocerebrosidase mutations. Mol Genet Metab 2011;104:185-188.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cullen V, Sardi SP S, Ng J, et al. Acid &#x3b2;-glucosidase mutants linked to Gaucher disease, Parkinson disease, and Lewy body dementia alter &#x3b1;-synuclein processing. Ann Neurol 2011;69:940-953.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sch&#xf6;ndorf DC, Aureli M, McAllister FE, et al. iPSC-derived neurons from GBA1-associated Parkinson's disease patients show autophagic defects and impaired calcium homeostasis. Nat Comm 2014;5:4028</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du TT, Wang L, Duan CL, et al. GBA deficiency promotes SNCA/&#x3b1;-synuclein accumulation through autophagic inhibition by inactivated PPP2A. Autophagy 2011;11:18031820</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ron I, Rapaport D. Horowitz M interaction between parkin and mutant glucocerebrosidase variants: a possible link between Parkinson disease and Gaucher disease. Hum Mol Genet 2010;19:3771-3781.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lerche S, Isabel Wurster I, Roeben B, et al. Parkinson's disease: Glucocerebrosidase 1 mutation severity is associated with CSF alpha-Synuclein profiles. Mov. Dis. 2020;35:495-499.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gegg ME, Menozzi E, Schapira A. Glucocerebrosidase-associated Parkinson disease: pathogenic mechanisms and potential drug treatments. Neurobiol Dis 2022;166:105663</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson SA, Bhattacharyya B, Rachel RA, et al. Synaptic defects in ataxia mice result from a mutation in Usp14, encoding a ubiquitin-specific protease. Nat Genet 2002;32:420-425.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marshall AG, Watson JA, Hallengren JJ, et al. Genetic background alters the severity and onset of neuromuscular disease caused by the loss of ubiquitin-specific protease 14 (Usp14). Plos One 2013;8:e84042</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avgerinos KI, Ferrucci L, Kapogiannis D. Effects of monoclonal antibodies against amyloid-&#x3b2; on clinical and biomarker outcomes and adverse event risks: a systematic review and meta-analysis of phase III RCTs in Alzheimer's disease. Ageing Res Rev 2021;68:101339</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwon D. Failure of genetic therapies for Huntington's devastates community. Nature 2021;593:180</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai Q, Genesan D. Regulation of neuronal autophagy and the implications in neurodegenerative diseases. Neurobiol Dis 2022;162:105582</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>