<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35598461</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>24</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2213-1582</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>35</Volume><PubDate><Year>2022</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>NeuroImage. Clinical</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Neuroimage Clin</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Motor imagery in amyotrophic lateral Sclerosis: An fMRI study of postural control.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>103051</StartPage><MedlinePgn>103051</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">103051</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.nicl.2022.103051</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S2213-1582(22)00116-4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">The functional reorganization of brain networks sustaining gait is poorly characterized in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) despite ample evidence of progressive disconnection between brain regions. The main objective of this fMRI study is to assess gait imagery-specific networks in ALS patients using dynamic causal modeling (DCM) complemented by parametric empirical Bayes (PEB) framework.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHOD">Seventeen lower motor neuron predominant (LMNp) ALS patients, fourteen upper motor neuron predominant (UMNp) ALS patients and fourteen healthy controls participated in this study. Each subject performed a dual motor imagery task: normal and precision gait. The Movement Imagery Questionnaire (MIQ-rs) and imagery time (IT) were used to evaluate gait imagery in each participant. In a neurobiological computational model, the circuits involved in imagined gait and postural control were investigated by modelling the relationship between normal/precision gait and connection strengths.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Behavioral results showed significant increase in IT in UMNp patients compared to healthy controls (P<sub>corrected</sub>&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;0.05) and LMNp (P<sub>corrected</sub>&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;0.05). During precision gait, healthy controls activate the model's circuits involved in the imagined gait and postural control. In UMNp, decreased connectivity (inhibition) from basal ganglia (BG) to supplementary motor area (SMA) and from SMA to posterior parietal cortex (PPC) is observed. Contrary to healthy controls, DCM detects no cerebellar-PPC connectivity in neither UMNp nor LMNp ALS. During precision gait, bilateral connectivity (excitability) between SMA and BG is observed in the LMNp group contrary to UMNp and healthy controls.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Our findings demonstrate the utility of implementing both DCM and PEB to characterize connectivity patterns in specific patient phenotypes. Our approach enables the identification of specific circuits involved in postural deficits, and our findings suggest a putative excitatory-inhibitory imbalance. More broadly, our data demonstrate how clinical manifestations are underpinned by network-specific disconnection phenomena in ALS.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022 The Author(s). Published by Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abidi</LastName><ForeName>Malek</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>LINP2 Laboratory, UPL, Paris Nanterre University, France; COMUE Paris Lumi&#xe8;res University, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pradat</LastName><ForeName>Pierre-Francois</ForeName><Initials>PF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Piti&#xe9;-Salp&#xea;tri&#xe8;re University Hospital, Paris, France; Biomedical Imaging Laboratory, Sorbonne University, CNRS, INSERM, Paris, France; Biomedical Sciences Research Institute, Northern Ireland Centre for Stratified Medicine, Ulster University, Londonderry, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Termoz</LastName><ForeName>Nicolas</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>LINP2 Laboratory, UPL, Paris Nanterre University, France; COMUE Paris Lumi&#xe8;res University, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Couillandre</LastName><ForeName>Annabelle</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>LINP2 Laboratory, UPL, Paris Nanterre University, France; Universit&#xe9; Paris-Saclay,CIAMS, Orsay, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bede</LastName><ForeName>Peter</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Piti&#xe9;-Salp&#xea;tri&#xe8;re University Hospital, Paris, France; Biomedical Imaging Laboratory, Sorbonne University, CNRS, INSERM, Paris, France; Computational Neuroimaging Group, Trinity College Dublin, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>de Marco</LastName><ForeName>Giovanni</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>LINP2 Laboratory, UPL, Paris Nanterre University, France; COMUE Paris Lumi&#xe8;res University, France. Electronic address: demarco.giovanni@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Neuroimage Clin</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101597070</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2213-1582</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001499" MajorTopicYN="N">Bayes Theorem</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008279" MajorTopicYN="N">Magnetic Resonance Imaging</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009044" MajorTopicYN="Y">Motor Cortex</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004856" MajorTopicYN="N">Postural Balance</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ALS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Connectivity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">DCM</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Motor imagery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neuroimaging</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fMRI</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35598461</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9127212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nicl.2022.103051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2213-1582(22)00116-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abidi M., Marco G., Couillandre A., Feron M., Mseddi E., Termoz N., Querin G., Pradat P.-F., Bede P. Adaptive functional reorganization in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: coexisting degenerative and compensatory changes. Eur. J. Neurol. 2020;27(1):121&#x2013;128.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31310452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abidi M., Marco G., Grami F., Termoz N., Couillandre A., Querin G., Bede P., Pradat P.-F. Neural correlates of motor imagery of gait in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J. Magn. Resonance Imaging. 2021;53(1):223&#x2013;233.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32896088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assal F., Schwartz S., Vuilleumier P. Moving with or without will: functional neural correlates of alien hand syndrome. Ann. Neurol. 2007;62(3):301&#x2013;306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17638304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakker M., De Lange F.P., Helmich R.C., Scheeringa R., Bloem B.R., Toni I. Cerebral correlates of motor imagery of normal and precision gait. NeuroImage. 2008;41(3):998&#x2013;1010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18455930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bede P., Chipika R.H., Christidi F., Hengeveld J.C., Karavasilis E., Argyropoulos G.D., Lope J., Li Hi Shing S., Velonakis G., Dupuis L., Doherty M.A., Vajda A., McLaughlin R.L., Hardiman O. Genotype-associated cerebellar profiles in ALS: focal cerebellar pathology and cerebro-cerebellar connectivity alterations. J. Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatry. 2021;92(11):1197&#x2013;1205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8522463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34168085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bede P., Chipika R.H., Finegan E., Li Hi Shing S., Doherty M.A., Hengeveld J.C., Vajda A., Hutchinson S., Donaghy C., McLaughlin R.L., Hardiman O. Brainstem pathology in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and primary lateral sclerosis: a longitudinal neuroimaging study. NeuroImage: Clinical. 2019;24:102054.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6849418</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31711033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bede P., Omer T., Finegan E., Chipika R.H., Iyer P.M., Doherty M.A., Vajda A., Pender N., McLaughlin R.L., Hutchinson S., Hardiman O. Connectivity-based characterisation of subcortical grey matter pathology in frontotemporal dementia and ALS: a multimodal neuroimaging study. Brain Imaging Behav. 2018;12(6):1696&#x2013;1707.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29423814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belkhiria C., Driss T., Habas C., Jaafar H., Guillevin R., de Marco G. Exploration and identification of cortico-cerebellar-brainstem closed loop during a motivational-motor task: an fMRI study. Cerebellum. 2017;16(2):326&#x2013;339.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27271710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blakemore S.-J., Oakley D.A., Frith C.D. Delusions of alien control in the normal brain. Neuropsychologia. 2003;41(8):1058&#x2013;1067.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12667541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bostan A.C., Dum R.P., Strick P.L. The basal ganglia communicate with the cerebellum. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA. 2010;107(18):8452&#x2013;8456.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2889518</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20404184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks B.R., Miller R.G., Swash M., Munsat T.L. El Escorial revisited: revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. 2000;1(5):293&#x2013;299.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11464847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke T., Pinto-Grau M., Lonergan K., Elamin M., Bede P., Costello E., Hardiman O., Pender N., Cereda C. Measurement of social cognition in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a population based study. PLoS One. 2016;11(8):e0160850.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4996502</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27556398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caeyenberghs K., Leemans A., De Decker C., Heitger M., Drijkoningen D., Linden C.V., Sunaert S., Swinnen S.P. Brain connectivity and postural control in young traumatic brain injury patients: a diffusion MRI based network analysis. NeuroImage: Clinical. 2012;1(1):106&#x2013;115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3757722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24179743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cavanna, A.E., Trimble, M.R. (2006). The precuneus: a review of its functional anatomy and behavioural correlates. Brain https://doi.org/10.1093/brain/awl004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16399806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christidi F., Karavasilis E., Rentzos M., Velonakis G., Zouvelou V., Xirou S., Argyropoulos G., Papatriantafyllou I., Pantolewn V., Ferentinos P., Kelekis N., Seimenis I., Evdokimidis I., Bede P. Hippocampal pathology in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: selective vulnerability of subfields and their associated projections. Neurobiol. Aging. 2019;84:178&#x2013;188.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31629116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desmurget M., Reilly K.T., Richard N., Szathmari A., Mottolese C., Sirigu A. Movement intention after parietal cortex stimulation in humans. Science. 2009;324(5928):811&#x2013;813.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19423830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feron M., Couillandre A., Mseddi E., Termoz N., Abidi M., Bardinet E., Delgadillo D., Lenglet T., Querin G., Welter M.-L., Le Forestier N., Salachas F., Bruneteau G., del Mar Amador M., Debs R., Lacomblez L., Meininger V., P&#xe9;l&#xe9;grini-Issac M., Bede P., Pradat P.-F., de Marco G. Extrapyramidal deficits in ALS: a combined biomechanical and neuroimaging study. J. Neurol. 2018;265(9):2125&#x2013;2136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29995291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friston K.J., Buechel C., Fink G.R., Morris J., Rolls E., Dolan R.J. Psychophysiological and modulatory interactions in neuroimaging. NeuroImage. 1997;6(3):218&#x2013;229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9344826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friston K.J., Harrison L., Penny W. Dynamic causal modelling. NeuroImage. 2003;19(4):1273&#x2013;1302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12948688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friston K.J., Li B., Daunizeau J., Stephan K.E. Network discovery with DCM. NeuroImage. 2011;56(3):1202&#x2013;1221.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3094760</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21182971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friston K.J., Litvak V., Oswal A., Razi A., Stephan K.E., van Wijk B.C.M., Ziegler G., Zeidman P. Bayesian model reduction and empirical Bayes for group (DCM) studies. NeuroImage. 2016;128:413&#x2013;431.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4767224</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26569570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goel R., Nakagome S., Rao N., Paloski W.H., Contreras-Vidal J.L., Parikh P.J. Fronto-parietal brain areas contribute to the online control of posture during a continuous balance task. Neuroscience. 2019;413:135&#x2013;153.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31200107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hinton D.C., Thiel A., Soucy J.-P., Bouyer L., Paquette C. Adjusting gait step-by-step: brain activation during split-belt treadmill walking. NeuroImage. 2019;202:116095.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31430533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jahn K., Deutschl&#xe4;nder A., Stephan T., Kalla R., Wiesmann M., Strupp M., Brandt T. Imaging human supraspinal locomotor centers in brainstem and cerebellum. NeuroImage. 2008;39(2):786&#x2013;792.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18029199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeannerod M. Mental imagery in the motor context. Neuropsychologia. 1995;33(11):1419&#x2013;1432.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8584178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeannerod, Marc. (2001). Neural simulation of action: a unifying mechanism for motor cognition. NeuroImage https://doi.org/10.1006/nimg.2001.0832.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11373140</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>la Foug&#xe8;re C., Zwergal A., Rominger A., F&#xf6;rster S., Fesl G., Dieterich M., Brandt T., Strupp M., Bartenstein P., Jahn K. Real versus imagined locomotion: a [18F]-FDG PET-fMRI comparison. NeuroImage. 2010;50(4):1589&#x2013;1598.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20034578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lul&#xe9; D., Diekmann V., Kassubek J., Kurt A., Birbaumer N., Ludolph A.C., Kraft E. Cortical plasticity in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: motor imagery and function. Neurorehabilitation Neural Repair. 2007;21(6):518&#x2013;526.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17476000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maidan I., Rosenberg-Katz K., Jacob Y., Giladi N., Deutsch J.E., Hausdorff J.M., Mirelman A. Altered brain activation in complex walking conditions in patients with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Parkinsonism Relat. Disord. 2016;25:91&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26861167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malouin F., Richards C.L., Jackson P.L., Dumas F., Doyon J. Brain activations during motor imagery of locomotor-related tasks: a PET study. Hum. Brain Mapp. 2003;19(1):47&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6872050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12731103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manto M., Huisman T.A.G.M. The cerebellum from the fetus to the elderly: history, advances, and future challenges. Handb. Clin. Neurol. 2018 doi: 10.1016/B978-0-444-64189-2.00027-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/B978-0-444-64189-2.00027-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29891075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martino G., Ivanenko Y.P., Serrao M., Ranavolo A., d'Avella A., Draicchio F., Conte C., Casali C., Lacquaniti F. Locomotor patterns in cerebellar ataxia. J. Neurophysiol. 2014;112(11):2810&#x2013;2821.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25185815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsumura M., Nambu A., Yamaji Y., Watanabe K., Imai H., Inase M., Tokuno H., Takada M. Organization of somatic motor inputs from the frontal lobe to the pedunculopontine tegmental nucleus in the macaque monkey. Neuroscience. 2000;98(1):97&#x2013;110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10858616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meier J.M., Burgh H.K., Nitert A.D., Bede P., Lange S.C., Hardiman O., Berg L.H., Heuvel M.P. Connectome-based propagation model in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann. Neurol. 2020;87(5):725&#x2013;738.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7186838</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32072667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Middleton F.A., Strick P.L. Basal ganglia and cerebellar loops: motor and cognitive circuits. Brain Res. Rev. 2000 doi: 10.1016/S0165-0173(99)00040-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0165-0173(99)00040-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10719151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mori F., Nakajima K. Cortical control in locomotion. Brain Nerve. 2010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21068450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Musienko P.E., Zelenin P.V., Lyalka V.F., Gerasimenko Y.P., Orlovsky G.N., Deliagina T.G. Spinal and supraspinal control of the direction of stepping during locomotion. J. Neurosci. 2012;32(48):17442&#x2013;17453.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3521535</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23197735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pool E.-M., Rehme A.K., Fink G.R., Eickhoff S.B., Grefkes C. Network dynamics engaged in the modulation of motor behavior in healthy subjects. NeuroImage. 2013;82:68&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23747288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pradat P.-F., Bruneteau G., Munerati E., Salachas F., Le Forestier N., Lacomblez L., Lenglet T., Meininger V. Extrapyramidal stiffness in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Mov. Disord. 2009;24(14):2143&#x2013;2148.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19735090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proudfoot M., Bede P., Turner M.R. Imaging cerebral activity in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Front. Neurol. 2019 doi: 10.3389/fneur.2018.01148.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fneur.2018.01148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6332509</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30671016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quinn C., Edmundson C., Dahodwala N., Elman L. Reliable and efficient scale to assess upper motor neuron disease burden in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 2020;61(4):508&#x2013;511.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31743477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rowe J.B., Hughes L.E., Barker R.A., Owen A.M. Dynamic causal modelling of effective connectivity from fMRI: are results reproducible and sensitive to Parkinson&#x2019;s disease and its treatment? NeuroImage. 2010;52(3):1015&#x2013;1026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3021391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20056151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaikh A.G., Meng H., Angelaki D.E. Multiple reference frames for motion in the primate cerebellum. J. Neurosci. 2004 doi: 10.1523/JNEUROSCI.0109-04.2004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1523/JNEUROSCI.0109-04.2004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6729386</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15140919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simon N.G., Lin C.-Y., Lee M., Howells J., Vucic S., Burke D., Kiernan M.C. Segmental motoneuronal dysfunction is a feature of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2015;126(4):828&#x2013;836.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25220597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takakusaki K. Functional neuroanatomy for posture and gait control. J. Mov. Disord. 2017;10(1):1&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5288669</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28122432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takakusaki K., Tomita N., Yano M. Substrates for normal gait and pathophysiology of gait disturbances with respect to the basal ganglia dysfunction. J. Neurol. 2008;255(S4):19&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18821082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tessitore A., Esposito F., Monsurr&#xf2; M.R., Graziano S., Panza D., Russo A., Migliaccio R., Conforti F.L., Morrone R., Quattrone A., Di Salle F., Tedeschi G. Subcortical motor plasticity in patients with sporadic ALS: an fMRI study. Brain Res. Bull. 2006;69(5):489&#x2013;494.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16647577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tjernstr&#xf6;m F., Fransson P.-A., Patel M., Magnusson M. Postural control and adaptation are influenced by preceding postural challenges. Exp. Brain Res. 2010;202(3):613&#x2013;621.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20101395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tu S., Menke R.A.L., Talbot K., Kiernan M.C., Turner M.R. Regional thalamic MRI as a marker of widespread cortical pathology and progressive frontotemporal involvement in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J. Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatry. 2018;89(12):1250&#x2013;1258.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30049750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Visser J.E., Bloem B.R. Role of the basal ganglia in balance control. Neural Plasticity. 2005;12(2-3):161&#x2013;174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2565457</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16097484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yanagihara D., Udo M. Climbing fiber responses in cerebellar vermal Purkinje cells during perturbed locomotion in decerebrate cats. Neurosci. Res. 1994;19(2):245&#x2013;248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8008254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeidman P., Jafarian A., Seghier M.L., Litvak V., Cagnan H., Price C.J., Friston K.J. A guide to group effective connectivity analysis, part 2: second level analysis with PEB. NeuroImage. 2019;200:12&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6711451</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31226492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>