<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35597032</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>24</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2213-1582</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>35</Volume><PubDate><Year>2022</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>NeuroImage. Clinical</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Neuroimage Clin</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Graph theory network analysis provides brain MRI evidence of a partial continuum of neurodegeneration in patients with UMN-predominant ALS and ALS-FTD.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>103037</StartPage><MedlinePgn>103037</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">103037</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.nicl.2022.103037</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S2213-1582(22)00102-4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">Our routine clinical neuroimaging showed hyperintense signal along the corticospinal tract only in some but not all patients with upper motor neuron (UMN)-predominant ALS. ALS patients with CST hyperintensity (ALS-CST+) and those without CST hyperintensity (ALS-CST-) present with nearly identical clinical UMN-predominant symptoms. Some previous studies have suggested that ALS patients with frontotemporal dementia (FTD) are on a continuum with ALS patients without FTD, while others have not. We aimed to determine whether: (a) ALS-CST+, ALS-CST-, and ALS-FTD patients show differential sites of predominant neurodegeneration occurring primarily cortically in the perikaryon or subcortically in the white matter (WM), or (b) UMN-predominant ALS is on a continuum with ALS-FTD.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Exploratory whole brain grey matter (GM) voxel-based morphometry and WM network analysis using graph theory approach were performed. In this exploratory study, MRI data from 58 ALS patients (ALS-FTD, n&#xa0;=&#xa0;15; ALS-CST+, n&#xa0;=&#xa0;19; ALS-CST-, n&#xa0;=&#xa0;24) and 14 neurological controls were obtained.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Significant differences in degree measures (evaluating WM networks) were observed between ALS patients and controls in frontal, motor, extra-motor, subcortical, and cerebellar regions. GM atrophy was observed only in the ALS-FTD subgroup and not in the other ALS subgroups.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">Although WM network disruption by the ALS disease process showed different patterns between ALS-CST+, ALS-CST-, and ALS-FTD subgroups, there were some overlaps, particularly in prefrontal regions and between ALS-CST+&#xa0;and ALS-FTD patients. Our preliminary findings suggest a partial continuum of, at least, WM degeneration between these subgroups with predominance of cortical pathology ("neuronopathy") in ALS-FTD patients and subcortical WM pathology ("axonopathy") in ALS-CST+&#xa0;and ALS-CST- patients.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022 The Authors. Published by Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rajagopalan</LastName><ForeName>Venkateswaran</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical and Electronics Engineering, Birla Institute of Technology and Science Pilani, Hyderabad Campus, Hyderabad 500078, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pioro</LastName><ForeName>Erik P</ForeName><Initials>EP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neuromuscular Center, Department of Neurology, Neurological Institute, United States; Department of Neurosciences, Lerner Research Institute, Cleveland Clinic, Cleveland, OH 44195, United States; Neuromuscular Division, The Ken &amp; Ruth Davee Department of Neurology, Northwestern University Feinberg School of Medicine, Chicago, IL 60611, United States. Electronic address: erik.pioro@northwestern.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Neuroimage Clin</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101597070</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2213-1582</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Frontotemporal Dementia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D066128" MajorTopicYN="N">Gray Matter</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008279" MajorTopicYN="N">Magnetic Resonance Imaging</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009046" MajorTopicYN="N">Motor Neurons</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D059906" MajorTopicYN="N">Neuroimaging</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ALS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ALS-FTD</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Brain network</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Grey matter</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">White matter</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35597032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9123271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nicl.2022.103037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2213-1582(22)00102-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abe K., Fujimura H., Kobayashi Y., Fujita N., Yanagihara T. Degeneration of the pyramidal tracts in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. A premortem and postmortem magnetic resonance imaging study. J. Neuroimaging. 1997;7(4):208&#x2013;212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9344001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abe O., Yamada H., Masutani Y., Aoki S., Kunimatsu A., Yamasue H., Fukuda R., Kasai K., Hayashi N., Masumoto T., Mori H., Soma T., Ohtomo K. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: diffusion tensor tractography and voxel-based analysis. NMR Biomed. 2004;17(6):411&#x2013;416.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15386625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abrahams S., Goldstein L.H., Suckling J., Ng V., Simmons A., Chitnis X., Atkins L., Williams S.C.R., Leigh P.N. Frontotemporal white matter changes in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J. Neurol. 2005;252(3):321&#x2013;331.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15739047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alexander A.L., Lee J.E., Lazar M., Field A.S. Diffusion tensor imaging of the brain. Neurotherapeutics. 2007;4(3):316&#x2013;329.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2041910</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17599699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashburner J. Computational anatomy with the SPM software. Magn. Reson. Imaging. 2009;27(8):1163&#x2013;1174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19249168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks B.R., Miller R.G., Swash M., Munsat T.L. El Escorial revisited: revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph. Lateral Scler. Other Motor Neuron Disord. 2000;1(5):293&#x2013;299.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11464847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang J.L., Lomen-Hoerth C., Murphy J., Henry R.G., Kramer J.H., Miller B.L., Gorno-Tempini M.L. A voxel-based morphometry study of patterns of brain atrophy in ALS and ALS/FTLD. Neurology. 2005;65(1):75&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16009889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dimond D., Ishaque A., Chenji S., Mah D., Chen Z., Seres P., Beaulieu C., Kalra S. White matter structural network abnormalities underlie executive dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Hum. Brain Mapp. 2017;38(3):1249&#x2013;1268.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6866969</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27796080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellis C.M., Simmons A., Jones D.K., Bland J., Dawson J.M., Horsfield M.A., Williams S.C.R., Leigh P.N. Diffusion tensor MRI assesses corticospinal tract damage in ALS. Neurology. 1999;53(5):1051.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10496265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filippini N., Douaud G., Mackay C.E., Knight S., Talbot K., Turner M.R. Corpus callosum involvement is a consistent feature of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology. 2010;75(18):1645&#x2013;1652.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2974368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21041787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham J.M., Papadakis N., Evans J., Widjaja E., Romanowski C.A.J., Paley M.N.J., Wallis L.I., Wilkinson I.D., Shaw P.J., Griffiths P.D. Diffusion tensor imaging for the assessment of upper motor neuron integrity in ALS. Neurology. 2004;63(11):2111&#x2013;2119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15596758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hosseini S.M.H., Hoeft F., Kesler S.R., Lambiotte R. GAT: a graph-theoretical analysis toolbox for analyzing between-group differences in large-scale structural and functional brain networks. PLoS ONE. 2012;7(7):e40709.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3396592</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22808240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacob S., Finsterbusch J., Weishaupt J.H., Khorram-Sefat D., Frahm J., Ehrenreich H. Diffusion tensor imaging for long-term follow-up of corticospinal tract degeneration in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuroradiology. 2003;45(9):598&#x2013;600.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12904924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kassubek J., Unrath A., Huppertz H.-J., Lul&#xe9; D., Ethofer T., Sperfeld A.-D., Ludolph A.C. Global brain atrophy and corticospinal tract alterations in ALS, as investigated by voxel-based morphometry of 3-D MRI. Amyotroph. Lateral Scler. Other Motor Neuron Disord. 2005;6(4):213&#x2013;220.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16319024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leemans A, Jeurissen B, Sijbers J, Jones D, editors. ExploreDTI: A graphical toolbox for processing, analyzing, and visualizing diffusion MR data. Proceedings of the 17th Scientific Meeting, International Society for Magnetic Resonance in Medicine; 2009; Honolulu.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lillo P., Mioshi E., Burrell J.R., Kiernan M.C., Hodges J.R., Hornberger M., Stamatakis E.A. Grey and white matter changes across the amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-frontotemporal dementia continuum. PLoS One. 2012;7(8):e43993.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3430626</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22952843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lul&#xe9; D.E., Aho-&#xd6;zhan H.E.A., V&#xe1;zquez C., Weiland U., Weishaupt J.H., Otto M., Anderl-Straub S., Semler E., Uttner I., Ludolph A.C. Story of the ALS-FTD continuum retold: rather two distinct entities. J. Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatry. 2019;90(5):586&#x2013;589.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30257969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matte G.P., Pioro E.P. Clinical features and natural history in ALS patients with upper motor neuron abnormalities on conventional brain MRI. Neurology. 2010;74(Suppl 2):A216.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mezzapesa D.M., Ceccarelli A., Dicuonzo F., Carella A., De Caro M.F., Lopez M., et al. Whole-brain and regional brain atrophy in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. AJNR Am. J. Neuroradiol. 2007;28(2):255&#x2013;259.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7977419</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17296989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitsumoto H., Chad D.A., Pioro E.P. F.A. Davis Company; Philadelphia: 1998. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neary D., Snowden J.S., Gustafson L., Passant U., Stuss D., Black S., Freedman M., Kertesz A., Robert P.H., Albert M., Boone K., Miller B.L., Cummings J., Benson D.F. Frontotemporal lobar degeneration: a consensus on clinical diagnostic criteria. Neurology. 1998;51(6):1546&#x2013;1554.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9855500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neumann M., Sampathu D.M., Kwong L.K., Truax A.C., Micsenyi M.C., Chou T.T., Bruce J., Schuck T., Grossman M., Clark C.M., McCluskey L.F., Miller B.L., Masliah E., Mackenzie I.R., Feldman H., Feiden W., Kretzschmar H.A., Trojanowski J.Q., Lee V.-Y. Ubiquitinated TDP-43 in frontotemporal lobar degeneration and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Science. 2006;314(5796):130&#x2013;133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17023659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Omer T., Finegan E., Hutchinson S., Doherty M., Vajda A., McLaughlin R.L., Pender N., Hardiman O., Bede P. Neuroimaging patterns along the ALS-FTD spectrum: a multiparametric imaging study. Amyotroph. Lateral Scler. Frontotemporal Degener. 2017;18(7-8):611&#x2013;623.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28562080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajagopalan V., Liu Z., Allexandre D., Zhang L., Wang X.-F., Pioro E.P., Yue G.H., Le W. Brain white matter shape changes in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS): a fractal dimension study. PLoS ONE. 2013;8(9):e73614.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3767806</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24040000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajagopalan V., Pioro E.P. Distinct patterns of cortical atrophy in ALS patients with or without dementia: An MRI VBM study. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. Frontotemporal Degener. 2014;15(3&#x2013;4):216&#x2013;225.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24555884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajagopalan V., Pioro E.P. Differential involvement of corticospinal tract fibers in ALS phenotypes: A diffusion tensor tractography and imaging study. Neuroimage Clin. 2017;14:574&#x2013;579.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5349615</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28337412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajagopalan V., Yue G.H., Pioro E.P. Brain white matter diffusion tensor metrics from clinical 1.5T MRI distinguish between ALS phenotypes. J. Neurol. 2013;260(10):2532&#x2013;2540.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23864396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rascovsky K., Hodges J.R., Knopman D., Mendez M.F., Kramer J.H., Neuhaus J., et al. Sensitivity of revised diagnostic criteria for the behavioural variant of frontotemporal dementia. Brain. 2011;134(Pt 9):2456&#x2013;2477.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3170532</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21810890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rubinov M., Sporns O. Complex network measures of brain connectivity: uses and interpretations. NeuroImage. 2010;52(3):1059&#x2013;1069.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19819337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sach M., Winkler G., Glauche V., Liepert J., Heimbach B., Koch M.A., et al. Diffusion tensor MRI of early upper motor neuron involvement in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain. 2004;127(Pt 2):340&#x2013;350.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14607785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sage C.A., Peeters R.R., Gorner A., Robberecht W., Sunaert S. Quantitative diffusion tensor imaging in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuroimage. 2007;34(2):486&#x2013;499.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17097892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schimrigk S.K., Bellenberg B., Schluter M., Stieltjes B., Drescher R., Rexilius J., et al. Diffusion tensor imaging-based fractional anisotropy quantification in the corticospinal tract of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis using a probabilistic mixture model. AJNR Am. J. Neuroradiol. 2007;28(4):724&#x2013;730.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7977339</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17416829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strong, M.J., 2001. The Evidence for ALS as a Multisystems Disorder of Limited Phenotypic Expression Canadian Journal of Neurological Sciences. 28:285-98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11766772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang M., Chen X., Zhou Q., Liu B., Liu Y., Liu S., et al. Quantitative assessment of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with diffusion tensor imaging in 3.0T magnetic resonance. Int. J. Clin. Exp. Med. 2015;8(5):8295&#x2013;8303.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4509358</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26221413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner M.R., Hammers A., Allsop J., Al&#x2010;chalabi A., Shaw C.E., Brooks D.J., Nigel Leigh P., Andersen P.M. Volumetric cortical loss in sporadic and familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph. Lateral. Scler. 2007;8(6):343&#x2013;347.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18033592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tzourio-Mazoyer N., Landeau B., Papathanassiou D., Crivello F., Etard O., Delcroix N., Mazoyer B., Joliot M. Automated anatomical labeling of activations in SPM using a macroscopic anatomical parcellation of the MNI MRI single-subject brain. NeuroImage. 2002;15(1):273&#x2013;289.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11771995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verstraete E., Veldink J.H., Mandl R.C.W., van den Berg L.H., van den Heuvel M.P., He Y. Impaired structural motor connectome in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. PLoS ONE. 2011;6(9):e24239.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3166305</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21912680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>