<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35607838</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-4598</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>66</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Muscle &amp; nerve</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Muscle Nerve</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis mimics.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>240</StartPage><EndPage>252</EndPage><MedlinePgn>240-252</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/mus.27567</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) is the most common adult-onset motor neuron disorder characterized by progressive degeneration of cortical, bulbar, and spinal motor neurons. When a patient presents with a progressive upper and/or lower motor syndrome, clinicians must pay particular attention to any atypical features in the history and/or clinical examination suggesting an alternate diagnosis, as up to 10% percent of patients initially diagnosed with ALS have a mimic of ALS. ALS is a clinical diagnosis and requires the exclusion of other disorders that may have similar presentations but a more favorable prognosis or an effective therapy. Because there is currently no specific diagnostic biomarker that is sensitive or specific for ALS, understanding the spectrum of clinical presentations of ALS and its mimics is paramount. While true mimics of ALS are rare, the clinician must correctly identify these disorders to avoid the misdiagnosis of ALS and to initiate effective treatment where available.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022 by the American Association of Neuromuscular &amp; Electrodiagnostic Medicine, Inc. All rights reserved. This article has been contributed to by U.S. Government employees and their work is in the public domain in the USA.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kwan</LastName><ForeName>Justin</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Institute of Neurological Disorders and Stroke, National Institutes of Health, Bethesda, Maryland, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vullaganti</LastName><ForeName>Mithila</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Tufts Medical Center, Tuft University School of Medicine, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052060">Research Support, N.I.H., Intramural</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Muscle Nerve</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7803146</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0148-639X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016472" MajorTopicYN="Y">Motor Neuron Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009046" MajorTopicYN="N">Motor Neurons</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011379" MajorTopicYN="N">Prognosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013577" MajorTopicYN="N">Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">differential diagnosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lower motor neuron disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mimic</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">motor neuron disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">upper motor neuron disease</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35607838</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.27567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Hardiman O, Al-Chalabi A, Chio A, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat Rev Dis Primers. 2017;3:17071.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, Miller RG, Swash M, Munsat TL. El Escorial revisited: revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord. 2000;1(5):293-299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa J, Swash M, de Carvalho M. Awaji criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis:a systematic review. Arch Neurol. 2012;69(11):1410-1416.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swinnen B, Robberecht W. The phenotypic variability of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat Rev Neurol. 2014;10(11):661-670.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davenport RJ, Swingler RJ, Chancellor AM, Warlow CP. Avoiding false positive diagnoses of motor neuron disease: lessons from the Scottish Motor Neuron Disease Register. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 1996;60(2):147-151.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Traynor BJ, Codd MB, Corr B, Forde C, Frost E, Hardiman O. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis mimic syndromes: a population-based study. Arch Neurol. 2000;57(1):109-113.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Visser J, van den Berg-Vos RM, Franssen H, et al. Mimic syndromes in sporadic cases of progressive spinal muscular atrophy. Neurology. 2002;58(11):1593-1596.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaudhuri KR, Crump S, al-Sarraj S, Anderson V, Cavanagh J, Leigh PN. The validation of El Escorial criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a clinicopathological study. J Neurol Sci. 1995;129(Suppl):11-12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Traynor BJ, Codd MB, Corr B, Forde C, Frost E, Hardiman OM. Clinical features of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis according to the El Escorial and Airlie House diagnostic criteria: a population-based study. Arch Neurol. 2000;57(8):1171-1176.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Engelen M, Kemp S, de Visser M, et al. X-linked adrenoleukodystrophy (X-ALD): clinical presentation and guidelines for diagnosis, follow-up and management. Orphanet J Rare Dis. 2012;7:51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dastagir A, Healy BC, Chua AS, et al. Brain and spinal cord MRI lesions in primary progressive vs. relapsing-remitting multiple sclerosis. eNeurologicalSci. 2018;12:42-46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antel J, Antel S, Caramanos Z, Arnold DL, Kuhlmann T. Primary progressive multiple sclerosis: part of the MS disease spectrum or separate disease entity? Acta Neuropathol. 2012;123(5):627-638.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bangham CR, Araujo A, Yamano Y, Taylor GP. HTLV-1-associated myelopathy/tropical spastic paraparesis. Nat Rev Dis Primers. 2015;1:15012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boelmans K, Kaufmann J, Bodammer N, Heinze HJ, Niehaus L. Corticospinal tract atrophy in corticobasal degeneration. Arch Neurol. 2006;63(3):462-463.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leis AA, Stokic DS. Neuromuscular manifestations of west nile virus infection. Front Neurol. 2012;3:37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehndiratta MM, Mehndiratta P, Pande R. Poliomyelitis: historical facts, epidemiology, and current challenges in eradication. Neurohospitalist. 2014;4(4):223-229.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sawlani K, Katirji B. Peripheral nerve hyperexcitability syndromes. Continuum (Minneap Minn). 2017;23(5, Peripheral Nerve and Motor Neuron Disorders):1437-1450.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shillito P, Molenaar PC, Vincent A, et al. Acquired neuromyotonia: evidence for autoantibodies directed against K+ channels of peripheral nerves. Ann Neurol. 1995;38(5):714-722.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evoli A, Tonali PA, Padua L, et al. Clinical correlates with anti-MuSK antibodies in generalized seronegative myasthenia gravis. Brain. 2003;126(Pt 10):2304-2311.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simon NG, Reddel SW, Kiernan MC, Layzer R. Muscle-specific kinase antibodies: a novel cause of peripheral nerve hyperexcitability? Muscle Nerve. 2013;48(5):819-823.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furuta N, Ishizawa K, Shibata M, et al. Anti-MuSK antibody-positive myasthenia gravis mimicking amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Intern Med. 2015;54(19):2497-2501.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S, Tian D, Chong PS, Cudkowicz ME, Hedley-Whyte ET, Cros D. Facial onset sensory and motor neuronopathy (FOSMN syndrome): a novel syndrome in neurology. Brain. 2006;129(Pt 12):3384-3390.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glenn SA, Ross MA. Delayed radiation-induced bulbar palsy mimicking ALS. Muscle Nerve. 2000;23(5):814-817.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowen LN, Tyagi R, Li W, et al. HIV-associated motor neuron disease: HERV-K activation and response to antiretroviral therapy. Neurology. 2016;87(17):1756-1762.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Leo S, Lee SY, Braverman LE. Hyperthyroidism. Lancet. 2016;388(10047):906-918.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hakeem H, Uz Zaman M, Khan S. Hypoparathyroidism: a rare mimic of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 2017;55(3):437-439.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goswami R, Bhatia M, Goyal R, Kochupillai N. Reversible peripheral neuropathy in idiopathic hypoparathyroidism. Acta Neurol Scand. 2002;105(2):128-131.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lebouteux MV, Franques J, Guillevin R, et al. Revisiting the spectrum of lower motor neuron diseases with snake eyes appearance on magnetic resonance imaging. Eur J Neurol. 2014;21(9):1233-1241.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thurnher MM, Post MJ, Jinkins JR. MRI of infections and neoplasms of the spine and spinal cord in 55 patients with AIDS. Neuroradiology. 2000;42(8):551-563.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liblau R, Chiras J, Orssaud C, Dormont D, Duclos H, Gentilini M. Spinal infarction in the anterior spinal territory with possible relation with bilharziasis. Rev Neurol (Paris). 1991;147(8-9):605-608.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berg D, M&#xfc;llges W, Koltzenburg M, Bendszus M, Reiners K. Man-in-the-barrel syndrome caused by cervical spinal cord infarction. Acta Neurol Scand. 1998;97(6):417-419.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pullicino P. Bilateral distal upper limb amyotrophy and watershed infarcts from vertebral dissection. Stroke. 1994;25(9):1870-1872.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xe4;mann PG, Himmerich H, Merl T, Er&#xf6;s C, M&#xfc;ller MB, Tonn JC, Buchwald B Cervicothoracic intradural arachnoid cyst misdiagnosed as motor neuron disease. Case Rep Med 2010;2010:261657.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmalbach S, Petri S, G&#xf6;tz F, Dengler R, Krampfl K. Anterior cysts of the spine: a difficult differential diagnosis to amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol. 2008;255(11):1662-1669.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kendall BE, Logue V. Spinal epidural angiomatous malformations draining into intrathecal veins. Neuroradiology. 1977;13(4):181-189.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jellema K, Tijssen CC, van Gijn J. Spinal dural arteriovenous fistulas: a congestive myelopathy that initially mimics a peripheral nerve disorder. Brain. 2006;129(Pt 12):3150-3164.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schaat TJ, Salzman KL, Stevens EA. Sacral origin of a spinal dural arteriovenous fistula: case report and review. Spine (Phila Pa 1976). 2002;27(8):893-897.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reinges MH, Thron A, Mull M, Huffmann BC, Gilsbach JM. Dural arteriovenous fistulae at the foramen magnum. J Neurol. 2001;248(3):197-203.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Motebejane MS, Choi IS. Foramen magnum dural arteriovenous fistulas: clinical presentations and treatment outcomes, a case-series of 12 patients. Oper Neurosurg (Hagerstown). 2018;15(3):262-269.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ll&#xe1;cer JL, Suay G, Piquer J, Vazquez V. Dural arteriovenous fistula at the foramen magnum: report of a case and clinical-anatomical review. Neurocirugia (Astur). 2016;27(4):199-203.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorelov D, Respicio G. Diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis overturned. Clinical Advisor. 2007. wwwclinicaladvisorcom/home/features/clinical-challenge/diagnosis-of-amyotrophic-lateral-sclerosis-overturned/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hedera P. Hereditary spastic paraplegia overview. In: Adams MP, ed. GeneReviews. Seattle, Washington: University of Washington; 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fink JK. Hereditary spastic paraplegia: clinico-pathologic features and emerging molecular mechanisms. Acta Neuropathol. 2013;126(3):307-328.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fink JK. Hereditary spastic paraplegia: clinical principles and genetic advances. Semin Neurol. 2014;34(3):293-305.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fink JK, Heiman-Patterson T, Bird T, et al. Hereditary spastic paraplegia: advances in genetic research. Hereditary Spastic Paraplegia Working group. Neurology. 1996;46(6):1507-1514.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel H, Hart PE, Warner TT, et al. The Silver syndrome variant of hereditary spastic paraplegia maps to chromosome 11q12-q14, with evidence for genetic heterogeneity within this subtype. Am J Hum Genet. 2001;69(1):209-215.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filosto M, Piccinelli SC, Palmieri I, et al. A Novel mutation in the stalk domain of KIF5A causes a slowly progressive atypical motor syndrome. J Clin Med. 2018;8(1):17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicolas A, Kenna KP, Renton AE, et al. Genome-wide analyses identify KIF5A as a novel ALS gene. Neuron. 2018;97(6):1268-1283.e1266.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams TL. Motor neurone disease: diagnostic pitfalls. Clin Med (Lond). 2013;13(1):97-100.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haverkamp LJ, Appel V, Appel SH. Natural history of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in a database population. Validation of a scoring system and a model for survival prediction. Brain. 1995;118(Pt 3):707-719.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weindling SM, Wood CP, Hoxworth JM. Hypoglossal canal lesions: distinctive imaging features and simple diagnostic algorithm. AJR Am J Roentgenol. 2017;209(5):1119-1127.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phukan J, Pender NP, Hardiman O. Cognitive impairment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet Neurol. 2007;6(11):994-1003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Segers K, Kadhim H, Colson C, Duttmann R, Glibert G. Adult polyglucosan body disease masquerading as &#x201c;ALS with dementia of the Alzheimer type&#x201d;: an exceptional phenotype in a rare pathology. Alzheimer Dis Assoc Disord. 2012;26(1):96-99.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hellmann MA, Kakhlon O, Landau EH, et al. Frequent misdiagnosis of adult polyglucosan body disease. J Neurol. 2015;262(10):2346-2351.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jellinger K, Anzil AP, Seemann D, Bernheimer H. Adult GM2 gangliosidosis masquerading as slowly progressive muscular atrophy: motor neuron disease phenotype. Clin Neuropathol. 1982;1(1):31-44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scarpelli M, Tomelleri G, Bertolasi L, Salviati A. Natural history of motor neuron disease in adult onset GM2-gangliosidosis: a case report with 25&#x2009;years of follow-up. Mol Genet Metab Rep. 2014;1:269-272.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breiden B, Sandhoff K. Mechanism of secondary ganglioside and lipid accumulation in lysosomal disease. Int J Mol Sci. 2020;21(7):2566.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferreira CR, Gahl WA. Lysosomal storage diseases. Transl Sci Rare Dis. 2017;2(1-2):1-71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jamrozik Z, Lugowska A, Go&#x142;&#x119;biowski M, Kr&#xf3;licki L, M&#x105;czewska J, Ku&#x17a;ma-Kozakiewicz M. Late onset GM2 gangliosidosis mimicking spinal muscular atrophy. Gene. 2013;527(2):679-682.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson WG, Wigger HJ, Karp HR, Glaubiger LM, Rowland LP. Juvenile spinal muscular atrophy: a new hexosaminidase deficiency phenotype. Ann Neurol. 1982;11(1):11-16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karni A, Navon R, Sadeh M. Hexosaminidase A deficiency manifesting as spinal muscular atrophy of late onset. Ann Neurol. 1988;24(3):451-453.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belsh JM, Johnson WG, Wu PM, Schwarz KO. Pure ALS phenotype in a patient with hexosaminidase A deficiency (adult Tay-Sachs disease). Eighth International Symposium on ALS/MND, 1997.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yaffe MG, Kaback M, Goldberg NJ, et al. An amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-like syndrome with hexosaminidase A deficiency: a new type of GM2 gangliosidosis. Neurology. 1979;29:S611.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masingue M, Dufour L, Lenglet T, et al. Natural history of adult patients with GM2 gangliosidosis. Ann Neurol. 2020;87(4):609-617.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitsumoto H, Sliman RJ, Schafer IA, et al. Motor neuron disease and adult hexosaminidase A deficiency in two families: evidence for multisystem degeneration. Ann Neurol. 1985;17(4):378-385.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gertz MA, Dispenzieri A. Systemic amyloidosis recognition, prognosis, and therapy: a systematic review. JAMA. 2020;324(1):79-89.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cappellari M, Cavallaro T, Ferrarini M, et al. Variable presentations of TTR-related familial amyloid polyneuropathy in seventeen patients. J Peripher Nerv Syst. 2011;16(2):119-129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riboldi G, Del Bo R, Ranieri M, et al. Tyr78Phe transthyretin mutation with predominant motor neuropathy as the initial presentation. Case Rep Neurol. 2011;3(1):62-68.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goyal NA, Mozaffar T. Tongue atrophy and fasciculations in transthyretin familial amyloid neuropathy: an ALS mimicker. Neurol Genet. 2015;1(2):e18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lozeron P, Lacroix C, Theaudin M, et al. An amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-like syndrome revealing an amyloid polyneuropathy associated with a novel transthyretin mutation. Amyloid. 2013;20(3):188-192.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reed DM, Kurland LT. Muscle fasciculations in a healthy population. Arch Neurol. 1963;9:363-367.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filippakis A, Jara J, Ventura N, et al. A prospective study of benign fasciculation syndrome and anxiety. Muscle Nerve. 2018;58(6):852-854.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blexrud MD, Windebank AJ, Daube JR. Long-term follow-up of 121 patients with benign fasciculations. Ann Neurol. 1993;34(4):622-625.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simon NG, Kiernan MC. Fasciculation anxiety syndrome in clinicians. J Neurol. 2013;260(7):1743-1747.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amato AA, Russell JA. Chapter 10: Disorders of motor nerve hyperactivity. Neuromuscular Disorders. 2nd ed. New York: McGraw-Hill Education Medical; 2016:193-211.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh V, Gibson J, McLean B, Boggild M, Silver N, White R. Fasciculations and cramps: how benign? Report of four cases progressing to ALS. J Neurol. 2011;258(4):573-578.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fleet WS, Watson RT. From benign fasciculations and cramps to motor neuron disease. Neurology. 1986;36(7):997-998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okuda B, Kodama N, Tachibana H, Sugita M. Motor neuron disease following generalized fasciculations and cramps. J Neurol Sci. 1997;150(2):129-131.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>La Spada AR, Wilson EM, Lubahn DB, Harding AE, Fischbeck KH. Androgen receptor gene mutations in X-linked spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Nature. 1991;352(6330):77-79.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atsuta N, Watanabe H, Ito M, et al. Natural history of spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy (SBMA): a study of 223 Japanese patients. Brain. 2006;129(Pt 6):1446-1455.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>La Spada AR, Roling DB, Harding AE, et al. Meiotic stability and genotype-phenotype correlation of the trinucleotide repeat in X-linked spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Nat Genet. 1992;2(4):301-304.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhodes LE, Freeman BK, Auh S, et al. Clinical features of spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Brain. 2009;132(Pt 12):3242-3251.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sperfeld AD, Karitzky J, Brummer D, et al. X-linked bulbospinal neuronopathy: Kennedy disease. Arch Neurol. 2002;59(12):1921-1926.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Statland JM, Barohn RJ, McVey AL, Katz JS, Dimachkie MM. Patterns of weakness, classification of motor neuron disease, and clinical diagnosis of sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurol Clin. 2015;33(4):735-748.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grunseich C, Fischbeck KH. Spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Neurol Clin. 2015;33(4):847-854.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanajima R, Terao Y, Nakatani-Enomoto S, et al. Postural tremor in X-linked spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Mov Disord. 2009;24(14):2063-2069.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grunseich C, Rinaldi C, Fischbeck KH. Spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy: pathogenesis and clinical management. Oral Dis. 2014;20(1):6-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sobue G, Hashizume Y, Mukai E, Hirayama M, Mitsuma T, Takahashi A. X-linked recessive bulbospinal neuronopathy. A clinicopathological study. Brain. 1989;112(Pt 1):209-232.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hama T, Hirayama M, Hara T, et al. Discrimination of spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy from amyotrophic lateral sclerosis using sensory nerve action potentials. Muscle Nerve. 2012;45(2):169-174.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roth G, Rohr J, Magistris MR, Ochsner F. Motor neuropathy with proximal multifocal persistent conduction block, fasciculations and myokymia. Evolution to tetraplegia. Eur Neurol. 1986;25(6):416-423.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katz JS, Wolfe GI, Bryan WW, Jackson CE, Amato AA, Barohn RJ. Electrophysiologic findings in multifocal motor neuropathy. Neurology. 1997;48(3):700-707.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pestronk A, Cornblath DR, Ilyas AA, et al. A treatable multifocal motor neuropathy with antibodies to GM1 ganglioside. Ann Neurol. 1988;24(1):73-78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azulay JP, Blin O, Pouget J, et al. Intravenous immunoglobulin treatment in patients with motor neuron syndromes associated with anti-GM1 antibodies: a double-blind, placebo-controlled study. Neurology. 1994;44(3 Pt 1):429-432.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van den Berg LH, Kerkhoff H, Oey PL, et al. Treatment of multifocal motor neuropathy with high dose intravenous immunoglobulins: a double blind, placebo controlled study. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 1995;59(3):248-252.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Federico P, Zochodne DW, Hahn AF, Brown WF, Feasby TE. Multifocal motor neuropathy improved by IVIg: randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled study. Neurology. 2000;55(9):1256-1262.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xe9;ger JM, Chassande B, Musset L, Meininger V, Bouche P, Baumann N. Intravenous immunoglobulin therapy in multifocal motor neuropathy: a double-blind, placebo-controlled study. Brain. 2001;124(Pt 1):145-153.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hahn AF, Beydoun SR, Lawson V, et al. A controlled trial of intravenous immunoglobulin in multifocal motor neuropathy. J Peripher Nerv Syst. 2013;18(4):321-330.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Misbah SA, Baumann A, Fazio R, et al. A smooth transition protocol for patients with multifocal motor neuropathy going from intravenous to subcutaneous immunoglobulin therapy: an open-label proof-of-concept study. J Peripher Nerv Syst. 2011;16(2):92-97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S, Black KR, Chong PS, Cros D. Multifocal motor neuropathy: decrease in conduction blocks and reinnervation with long-term IVIg. Neurology. 2004;63(7):1264-1269.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van den Berg-Vos RM, Franssen H, Wokke JH, Van den Berg LH. Multifocal motor neuropathy: long-term clinical and electrophysiological assessment of intravenous immunoglobulin maintenance treatment. Brain. 2002;125(Pt 8):1875-1886.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nobile-Orazio E. Multifocal motor neuropathy. J Neuroimmunol. 2001;115(1-2):4-18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ivanovski T, Miralles F. Differential weakness of finger extensor muscles: a clinical pattern of multifocal motor neuropathy. Muscle Nerve. 2017;55(3):433-437.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cats EA, Jacobs BC, Yuki N, et al. Multifocal motor neuropathy: association of anti-GM1 IgM antibodies with clinical features. Neurology. 2010;75(22):1961-1967.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vlam L, van der Pol WL, Cats EA, et al. Multifocal motor neuropathy: diagnosis, pathogenesis and treatment strategies. Nat Rev Neurol. 2011;8(1):48-58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Schaik IN, Bossuyt PM, Brand A, Vermeulen M. Diagnostic value of GM1 antibodies in motor neuron disorders and neuropathies: a meta-analysis. Neurology. 1995;45(8):1570-1577.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor BV, Gross L, Windebank AJ. The sensitivity and specificity of anti-GM1 antibody testing. Neurology. 1996;47(4):951-955.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nobile-Orazio E, Gallia F, Terenghi F, Allaria S, Giannotta C, Carpo M. How useful are anti-neural IgM antibodies in the diagnosis of chronic immune-mediated neuropathies? J Neurol Sci. 2008;266(1-2):156-163.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kollewe K, Wurster U, Sinzenich T, et al. Anti-ganglioside antibodies in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis revisited. PLoS One. 2015;10(4):e0125339.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nodera H, Izumi Y, Takamatsu N, Kaji R. Cervical root sonography to differentiate multifocal motor neuropathy from ALS. J Med Investig. 2016;63(1-2):104-107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loewenbr&#xfc;ck KF, Liesenberg J, Dittrich M, et al. Nerve ultrasound in the differentiation of multifocal motor neuropathy (MMN) and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with predominant lower motor neuron disease (ALS/LMND). J Neurol. 2016;263(1):35-44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grimm A, D&#xe9;card BF, Athanasopoulou I, Schweikert K, Sinnreich M, Axer H. Nerve ultrasound for differentiation between amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and multifocal motor neuropathy. J Neurol. 2015;262(4):870-880.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lefebvre S, B&#xfc;rglen L, Reboullet S, et al. Identification and characterization of a spinal muscular atrophy-determining gene. Cell. 1995;80(1):155-165.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zapletalov&#xe1; E, Hedvic&#xe1;kov&#xe1; P, Koz&#xe1;k L, et al. Analysis of point mutations in the SMN1 gene in SMA patients bearing a single SMN1 copy. Neuromuscul Disord. 2007;17(6):476-481.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lunn MR, Wang CH. Spinal muscular atrophy. Lancet. 2008;371(9630):2120-2133.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Groen EJN, Talbot K, Gillingwater TH. Advances in therapy for spinal muscular atrophy: promises and challenges. Nat Rev Neurol. 2018;14(4):214-224.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lorson CL, Hahnen E, Androphy EJ, Wirth B. A single nucleotide in the SMN gene regulates splicing and is responsible for spinal muscular atrophy. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 1999;96(11):6307-6311.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gavrilov DK, Shi X, Das K, Gilliam TC, Wang CH. Differential SMN2 expression associated with SMA severity. Nat Genet. 1998;20(3):230-231.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wadman RI, Stam M, Gijzen M, et al. Association of motor milestones, SMN2 copy and outcome in spinal muscular atrophy types 0-4. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2017;88(4):365-367.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tizzano EF, Finkel RS. Spinal muscular atrophy: a changing phenotype beyond the clinical trials. Neuromuscul Disord. 2017;27(10):883-889.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zerres K, Rudnik-Sch&#xf6;neborn S, Forrest E, Lusakowska A, Borkowska J, Hausmanowa-Petrusewicz I. A collaborative study on the natural history of childhood and juvenile onset proximal spinal muscular atrophy (type II and III SMA): 569 patients. J Neurol Sci. 1997;146(1):67-72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zerres K, Rudnik-Sch&#xf6;neborn S. Natural history in proximal spinal muscular atrophy. Clinical analysis of 445 patients and suggestions for a modification of existing classifications. Arch Neurol. 1995;52(5):518-523.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnold WD, Kassar D, Kissel JT. Spinal muscular atrophy: diagnosis and management in a new therapeutic era. Muscle Nerve. 2015;51(2):157-167.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ionasescu V, Christensen J, Hart M. Intestinal pseudo-obstruction in adult spinal muscular atrophy. Muscle Nerve. 1994;17(8):946-948.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dubowitz V. Chaos in classification of the spinal muscular atrophies of childhood. Neuromuscul Disord. 1991;1(2):77-80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kolb SJ, Kissel JT. Spinal muscular atrophy. Neurol Clin. 2015;33(4):831-846.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mercuri E, Finkel RS, Muntoni F, et al. Diagnosis and management of spinal muscular atrophy: part 1: recommendations for diagnosis, rehabilitation, orthopedic and nutritional care. Neuromuscul Disord. 2018;28(2):103-115.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finkel RS, Mercuri E, Darras BT, et al. Nusinersen versus sham control in infantile-onset spinal muscular atrophy. N Engl J Med. 2017;377(18):1723-1732.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendell JR, Al-Zaidy S, Shell R, et al. Single-dose gene-replacement therapy for spinal muscular atrophy. N Engl J Med. 2017;377(18):1713-1722.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peeters K, Chamova T, Jordanova A. Clinical and genetic diversity of SMN1-negative proximal spinal muscular atrophies. Brain. 2014;137(Pt 11):2879-2896.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dabby R, Lange DJ, Trojaborg W, et al. Inclusion body myositis mimicking motor neuron disease. Arch Neurol. 2001;58(8):1253-1256.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenberg SA. Inclusion body myositis: clinical features and pathogenesis. Nat Rev Rheumatol. 2019;15(5):257-272.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griggs RC, Askanas V, DiMauro S, et al. Inclusion body myositis and myopathies. Ann Neurol. 1995;38(5):705-713.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lotz BP, Engel AG, Nishino H, Stevens JC, Litchy WJ. Inclusion body myositis. Observations in 40 patients. Brain. 1989;112(Pt 3):727-747.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eisen A, Berry K, Gibson G. Inclusion body myositis (IBM): myopathy or neuropathy? Neurology. 1983;33(9):1109-1114.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joy JL, Oh SJ, Baysal AI. Electrophysiological spectrum of inclusion body myositis. Muscle Nerve. 1990;13(10):949-951.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paganoni S, Macklin EA, Lee A, et al. Diagnostic timelines and delays in diagnosing amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2014;15(5-6):453-456.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Felice KJ, Relva GM, Conway SR. Further observations on forearm flexor weakness in inclusion body myositis. Muscle Nerve. 1998;21(5):659-661.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips BA, Cala LA, Thickbroom GW, Melsom A, Zilko PJ, Mastaglia FL. Patterns of muscle involvement in inclusion body myositis: clinical and magnetic resonance imaging study. Muscle Nerve. 2001;24(11):1526-1534.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frasquet M, Rojas-Garc&#xed;a R, Argente-Escrig H, et al. Distal hereditary motor neuropathies: mutation spectrum and genotype-phenotype correlation. Eur J Neurol. 2021;28(4):1334-1343.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossor AM, Kalmar B, Greensmith L, Reilly MM. The distal hereditary motor neuropathies. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2012;83(1):6-14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanemann CO, Ludolph AC. Hereditary motor neuropathies and motor neuron diseases: which is which. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord. 2002;3(4):186-189.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Irobi J, Dierick I, Jordanova A, Claeys KG, De Jonghe P, Timmerman V. Unraveling the genetics of distal hereditary motor neuronopathies. NeuroMolecular Med. 2006;8(1-2):131-146.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cho HJ, Sung DH, Ki CS. Identification of de novo BSCL2 Ser90Leu mutation in a Korean family with Silver syndrome and distal hereditary motor neuropathy. Muscle Nerve. 2007;36(3):384-386.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dierick I, Baets J, Irobi J, et al. Relative contribution of mutations in genes for autosomal dominant distal hereditary motor neuropathies: a genotype-phenotype correlation study. Brain. 2008;131(Pt 5):1217-1227.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bunschoten C, Jacobs BC, Van den Bergh PYK, Cornblath DR, van Doorn PA. Progress in diagnosis and treatment of chronic inflammatory demyelinating polyradiculoneuropathy. Lancet Neurol. 2019;18(8):784-794.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van den Bergh PY, Hadden RD, Bouche P, et al. European Federation of Neurological Societies/Peripheral Nerve Society guideline on management of chronic inflammatory demyelinating polyradiculoneuropathy: report of a joint task force of the European Federation of Neurological Societies and the Peripheral Nerve Society-first revision. Eur J Neurol. 2010;17(3):356-363.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viala K, Maisonobe T, Stojkovic T, et al. A current view of the diagnosis, clinical variants, response to treatment and prognosis of chronic inflammatory demyelinating polyradiculoneuropathy. J Peripher Nerv Syst. 2010;15(1):50-56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doneddu PE, Cocito D, Manganelli F, et al. Atypical CIDP: diagnostic criteria, progression and treatment response. Data from the Italian CIDP Database. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2019;90(2):125-132.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarulli AW, Raynor EM. Lumbosacral radiculopathy. Neurol Clin. 2007;25(2):387-405.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siller S, Kasem R, Witt TN, Tonn JC, Zausinger S. Painless motor radiculopathy of the cervical spine: clinical and radiological characteristics and long-term outcomes after operative decompression. J Neurosurg Spine. 2018;28(6):621-629.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robles LA. Metachronous bilateral painless foot drop secondary to spinal stenosis: case report. Cureus. 2018;10(3):e2276.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lipetz JS, Misra N, Silber JS. Resolution of pronounced painless weakness arising from radiculopathy and disk extrusion. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2005;84(7):528-537.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frymoyer JW, Moskowitz RW. Spinal degeneration: pathogenesis and medical management. In: Frymoyer JW, ed. The Adult Spine Principles and Practice. 1st ed. New York: Raven Press; 1991:611-634.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friberg S, Hirsch C. Anatomical and clinical studies on lumbar disc degeneration. Acta Orthop Scand. 1949;19(2):222-242. illust.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schultz A, Andersson G, Ortengren R, Haderspeck K, Nachemson A. Loads on the lumbar spine. Validation of a biomechanical analysis by measurements of intradiscal pressures and myoelectric signals. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 1982;64(5):713-720.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoss RE, Corbin KB, Maccarty CS, Love JG. Significance of symptoms and signs in localization of involved root in cervical disk protrusion. Neurology. 1957;7(10):673-683.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radhakrishnan K, Litchy WJ, O&#x2032;Fallon WM, Kurland LT. Epidemiology of cervical radiculopathy. A population-based study from Rochester, Minnesota, 1976 through 1990. Brain. 1994;117(Pt 2):325-335.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>