<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35653913</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>24</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2213-1582</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>35</Volume><PubDate><Year>2022</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>NeuroImage. Clinical</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Neuroimage Clin</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Segmental alterations of the corpus callosum in motor neuron disease: A DTI and texture analysis in 575 patients.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>103061</StartPage><MedlinePgn>103061</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">103061</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.nicl.2022.103061</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S2213-1582(22)00126-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION">Within the core neuroimaging signature of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS), the corpus callosum (CC) is increasingly recognized as a consistent feature. The aim of this study was to investigate the sensitivity and specificity of the microstructural segmental CC morphology, assessed by diffusion tensor imaging (DTI) and high-resolution T1-weighted (T1w) imaging, in a large cohort of ALS patients including different clinical phenotypes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">In a single-centre study, 575 patients with ALS (classical phenotype, N &#xa0;=&#xa0;432; restricted phenotypes primary lateral sclerosis (PLS) N&#xa0;=&#xa0;55, flail arm syndrome (FAS) N&#xa0;=&#xa0;45, progressive bulbar palsy (PBP) N&#xa0;=&#xa0;22, lower motor neuron disease (LMND) N&#xa0;=&#xa0;21) and 112 healthy controls underwent multiparametric MRI, i.e. volume-rendering T1w scans and DTI. Tract-based fractional anisotropy statistics (TFAS) was applied to callosal tracts of CC areas I-V, identified from DTI data (tract-of-interest (TOI) analysis), and texture analysis was applied to T1w data. In order to further specify the callosal alterations, a support vector machine (SVM) algorithm was used to discriminate between motor neuron disease patients and controls.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">The analysis of white matter integrity revealed predominantly FA reductions for tracts of the callosal areas I, II, and III (with highest reductions in callosal area III) for all ALS patients and separately for each phenotype when compared to controls; texture analysis demonstrated significant alterations of the parameters entropy and homogeneity for ALS patients and all phenotypes for the CC areas I, II, and III (with again highest reductions in callosal area III) compared to controls. With SVM applied on multiparametric callosal parameters of area III, a separation of all ALS patients including phenotypes from controls with 72% sensitivity and 73% specificity was achieved. These results for callosal area III parameters could be improved by an SVM of six multiparametric callosal parameters of areas I, II, and III, achieving a separation of all ALS patients including phenotypes from controls with 84% sensitivity and 85% specificity.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION">The multiparametric MRI texture and DTI analysis demonstrated substantial alterations of the frontal and central CC with most significant alterations in callosal area III (motor segment) in ALS and separately in all investigated phenotypes (PLS, FAS, PBP, LMND) in comparison to controls, while no significant differences were observed between ALS and its phenotypes. The combination of the texture and the DTI parameters in an unbiased SVM-based approach might contribute as a neuroimaging marker for the assessment of the CC in ALS, including subtypes.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022 The Author(s). Published by Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>M&#xfc;nch</LastName><ForeName>Maximilian</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of Ulm, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>M&#xfc;ller</LastName><ForeName>Hans-Peter</ForeName><Initials>HP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of Ulm, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Behler</LastName><ForeName>Anna</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of Ulm, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ludolph</LastName><ForeName>Albert C</ForeName><Initials>AC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of Ulm, Germany; German Center for Neurodegenerative Diseases (DZNE), Ulm, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kassubek</LastName><ForeName>Jan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of Ulm, Germany; German Center for Neurodegenerative Diseases (DZNE), Ulm, Germany. Electronic address: jan.kassubek@uni-ulm.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Neuroimage Clin</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101597070</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2213-1582</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016880" MajorTopicYN="N">Anisotropy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003337" MajorTopicYN="N">Corpus Callosum</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D056324" MajorTopicYN="N">Diffusion Tensor Imaging</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016472" MajorTopicYN="Y">Motor Neuron Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Diffusion-weighted imaging</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Magnetic resonance imaging</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Motor neuron disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neurodegenerative disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Support vector machine</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35653913</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9163839</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nicl.2022.103061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2213-1582(22)00126-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Agosta F., Galantucci S., Riva N., Chi&#xf2; A., Messina S., Iannaccone S., Calvo A., Silani V., Copetti M., Falini A., Comi G., Filippi M. Intrahemispheric and interhemispheric structural network abnormalities in PLS and ALS. Hum. Brain Mapp. 2014;35:1710&#x2013;1722.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6869498</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23633431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agosta F., Pagani E., Petrolini M., Caputo D., Perini M., Prelle A., Salvi F., Filippi M. Assessment of white matter tract damage in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a diffusion tensor MR imaging tractography study. AJNR Am. J. Neuroradiol. 2010;31:1457&#x2013;1461.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7966122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20395382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agosta F., Spinelli E.G., Filippi M. Neuroimaging in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: current and emerging uses. Expert Rev. Neurother. 2018;18:395&#x2013;406.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29630421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xe2;rlescu L.A., M&#xfc;ller H.P., Uttner I., Ludolph A.C., Punkhardt E.H., Huppertz H.J., Kassubek J. Segmental alterations of the corpus callosum in progressive supranuclear palsy: A multiparametric magnetic resonance imaging study. Front. Aging Neurosci. 2021;13</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8640496</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34867268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bede P., Omer T., Finegan E., Chipika R.H., Iyer P.M., Doherty M.A., Vajda A., Pender N., McLaughlin R.L., Hutchinson S., Hardiman O. Connectivity-based characterisation of subcortical grey matter pathology in frontotemporal dementia and ALS: a multimodal neuroimaging study. Brain Imaging Behav. 2018;12:1696&#x2013;1707.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29423814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bede P., Siah W.F., McKenna M.C., Shing L.H., S. Consideration of C9orf72-associated ALS-FTD as a neurodevel-opmental disorder: insights from neuroimaging. J. Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatry. 2020;91:1138.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32855286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bede, P., Murad, A., Lope, J., Li Hi Shing, S., Finegan, E., Chipika, R.H., Hardiman, O., Chang, K.M. 2022A. Phenotypic categorisation of individual subjects with motor neuron disease based on radiological disease burden patterns: A machine-learning approach. J Neurol Sci. 432, 120079.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34875472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bede P., Murad A., Hardiman O. Pathological neural networks and artificial neural networks in ALS: diagnostic classification based on pathognomonic neuroimaging features. J. Neurol. 2022;269(5):2440&#x2013;2452.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9021106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34585269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behler A., Kassubek J., M&#xfc;ller H.P. Age-related alterations in DTI metrics in the human brain-consequences for age correction. Front. Aging Neurosci. 2021;13</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8239142</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34211389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks B.R., Miller R.G., Swash M., Munsat T.L. El Escorial revisited: Revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amytroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord. 2000;1:293&#x2013;299.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11464847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardenas A.M., Sarlls J.E., Kwan J.Y., Bageac D., Gala Z.S., Danielian L.E., Ray-Chaudhury A., Wang H.W., Miller K.L., Foxley S., Jbabdi S., Welsh R.C., Floeter M.K. Pathology of callosal damage in ALS: an ex-vivo, 7 T diffusion tensor MRI study. Neuroimage Clin. 2017;15:200&#x2013;208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5429246</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28529876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum J.M., Stambler N., Malta E., Fuller C., Hilt D., Thurmond B., Nakanishi A. The ALSFRS-R: a revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. BDNF ALS study group (phase III) J. Neurol. Sci. 1999;169:13&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10540002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chapman M.C., Jelsone-Swain L., Johnson T.D., Gruis K.L., Welsh R.C. Diffusion tensor MRI of the corpus callosum in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J. Magn. Reson. Imaging. 2014;39:641&#x2013;647.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3888481</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23843179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, H.J., Zhan, C., Cai, L.M., Lin, J.H., Zhou, M.X., Zou, Z.Y., Yao, X.F., Lin, Y.J. 2021. White matter microstructural impairments in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A mean apparent propagator MRI study. Neuroimage Clin. 32, 102863.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8551695</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34700102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng L., Tang X., Luo C., Liu D., Zhang Y., Zhang J. Fiber-specific white matter reductions in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuroimage Clin. 2020;28</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7724379</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33396003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2; A., Calvo A., Moglia C., Mazzini L., Mora G., PARALS study group. Phenotypic heterogeneity of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a population based study. J. Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatry. 2011;82:740&#x2013;746.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21402743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2; A., Pagani M., Agosta F., Calvo A., Cistaro A., Filippi M. Neuroimaging in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: insights into structural and functional changes. Lancet Neurol. 2014;13:1228&#x2013;1240.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25453462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Vries B.S., Rustemeijer L.M.M., Bakker L.A., Schr&#xf6;der C.D., Veldink J.H., van den Berg L.H., Nijboer T.C.W., van Es M.A. Cognitive and behavioural changes in PLS and PMA: challenging the concept of restricted phenotypes. J. Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatry. 2019;90:141&#x2013;147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30076267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filippini N., Douaud G., Mackay C.E., Knight S., Talbot K., Turner M.R. Corpus callosum involvement is a consistent feature of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology. 2010;75:1645&#x2013;1652.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2974368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21041787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filippi, M., Agosta, F., Grosskreutz, J., Benatar, M., Kassubek, J., Verstraete, E., Turner, M.R.; Neuroimaging Society in ALS (NiSALS). 2015. Progress towards a neuroimaging biomarker for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet Neurol. 14, 786-788.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26194923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foerster B.R., Welsh R.C., Feldman E.L. 25 years of neuroimaging in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat Rev Neurol. 2013;9:513&#x2013;524.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4182931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23917850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finegan E., Chipika R.H., Shing S.L.H., Hardiman O., Bede P. Primary lateral sclerosis: a distinct entity or part of the ALS spectrum? Amyotroph Lateral Scler. Frontotemporal Degener. 2019;20:133&#x2013;145.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30654671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grollemund V., Pradat P.F., Querin G., Delbot F., Le Chat G., Pradat-Peyre J.F., Bede P. Machine learning in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: achievements, pitfalls, and future directions. Front. Neurosci. 2019;13:135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6403867</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30872992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hofer S., Frahm J. Topography of the human corpus callosum revisited &#x2013; comprehensive fiber tractography using diffusion tensor magnetic resonance imaging. Neuroimage. 2006;32:989&#x2013;994.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16854598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xfc;bers A., Hildebrandt V., Petri S., Kollewe K., Hermann A., Storch A., Hanisch F., Zierz S., Rosenbohm A., Ludolph A.C., Dorst J. Clinical features and differential diagnosis of flail arm syndrome. J. Neurol. 2016;263:390&#x2013;395.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26705123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalra S., M&#xfc;ller H.P., Ishaque A., Zinman L., Korngut L., Genge A., Beaulieu C., Frayne R., Graham S.J., Kassubek J. A prospective harmonized multicenter DTI study of cerebral white matter degeneration in ALS. Neurology. 2020;95:e943&#x2013;e952.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7668555</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32646955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kassubek J., Ludolph A.C., M&#xfc;ller H.P. Neuroimaging of motor neuron diseases. Ther Adv Neurol Disord. 2012;5:119&#x2013;127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3302203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22435076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kassubek J., M&#xfc;ller H.P., Del Tredici K., Lul&#xe9; D., Gorges M., Braak H., Ludolph A.C. Imaging the pathoanatomy of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in vivo: targeting a propagation-based biological marker. J. Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatry. 2018;89:374&#x2013;381.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5869447</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29101254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kassubek J., M&#xfc;ller H.P. Advanced neuroimaging approaches in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: refining the clinical diagnosis. Expert Rev. Neurother. 2020;20:237&#x2013;249.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31937156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kassubek J., M&#xfc;ller H.P., Del Tredici K., Brettschneider J., Pinkhardt E.H., Lul&#xe9; D., B&#xf6;hm S., Braak H., Ludolph A.C. Diffusion tensor imaging analysis of sequential spreading of disease in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis confirms patterns of TDP-43 pathology. Brain. 2014;137:1733&#x2013;1740.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24736303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kocar T.D., Behler A., Ludolph A.C., M&#xfc;ller H.P., Kassubek J. Multiparametric microstructural MRI and machine learning classification yields high diagnostic accuracy in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: proof of concept. Front. Neurol. 2021;12</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8637840</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34867726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le Bihan D., Mangin J.F., Poupon C., Clark C.A., Pappata S., Molko N., Chabriat H. Diffusion tensor imaging: concepts and applications. J. Magn. Reson. Imaging. 2001;13:534&#x2013;546.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11276097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ludolph, A., Drory, V., Hardiman, O., Nakano, I., Ravits, J., Robberecht, W., Shefner, J; WFN Research Group On ALS/MND. 2015. A revision of the El Escorial criteria - 2015. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. Frontotemporal Degener. 29, 1&#x2013;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26121170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandrekar J.N. Receiver operating characteristic curve in diagnostic test assessment. J Thorac Oncol. 2010;5:1315&#x2013;1316.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20736804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menke R.A.L., Proudfoot M., Talbot K., Turner M.R. The two-year progression of structural and functional cerebral MRI in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuroimage Clin. 2017;17:953&#x2013;961.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5752097</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29321969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller, H.P., Lul&#xe9;, D., Roselli, F., Behler, A., Ludolph, A.C., Kassubek J. 2021. Segmental involvement of the corpus callosum in C9orf72-associated ALS: a tract of interest-based DTI study. Ther Adv Chronic Dis. 12, 20406223211002969.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7989124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33815737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller, H.P., Turner, M.R., Grosskreutz, J., Abrahams, S., Bede, P., Govind, V., Prudlo, J., Ludolph, A.C., Filippi, M., Kassubek, J.; Neuroimaging Society in ALS (NiSALS) DTI Study Group. 2016. A large-scale multicentre cerebral diffusion tensor imaging study in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 87, 570&#x2013;579.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26746186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller, H.P., Dreyhaupt, J., Roselli, F., Schlecht, M., Ludolph, A.C., Huppertz, H.J., Kassubek, J. 2020. Focal alterations of the callosal area III in primary lateral sclerosis: an MRI planimetry and texture analysis. Neuroimage Clin. 26, 102223.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7049663</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32114375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller H.P., Unrath A., Ludolph A.C., Kassubek J. Preservation of diffusion tensor properties during spatial normalisation by use of tensor imaging and fibre tracking on a normal brain database. Phys. Med. Biol. 2007;52:N99&#x2013;N.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17327646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller H.P., Unrath A., Sperfeld A.D., Ludolph A.C., Riecker A., Kassubek J. Diffusion tensor imaging and tractwise fractional anisotropy statistics: quantitative analysis in white matter pathology. Biomed. Eng. Online. 2007;6:42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2186341</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17996104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogura A., Kawabata K., Watanabe H., Choy S.W., Bagarinao E., Kato T., Imai K., Masuda M., Ohdake R., Hara K., Nakamura R., Atsuta N., Nakamura T., Katsuno M., Sobue G. Fiber-specific white matter analysis reflects upper motor neuron impairment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Eur. J. Neurol. 2022;29:432&#x2013;440.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34632672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenbohm A., M&#xfc;ller H.-P., H&#xfc;bers A., Ludolph A.C., Kassubek J. Corticoefferent pathways in pure lower motor neuron disease: a diffusion tensor imaging study. J. Neurol. 2016;263(12):2430&#x2013;2437.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27624123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenbohm A., Del Tredici K., Braak H., Huppertz H.-J., Ludolph A.C., M&#xfc;ller H.-P., Kassubek J. Involvement of cortico-efferent tracts in flail arm syndrome: a tract-of-interest-based DTI study. J. Neurol. 2022;269(5):2619&#x2013;2626.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9021061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34676447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosskopf J., M&#xfc;ller H.P., Dreyhaupt J., Goreges M., Ludolph A.C., Kassubek J. Ex post facto assessment of diffusion tensor imaging metrics from different MRI protocols: preparing for multicentre studies in ALS. Amyotroph. Lateral Scler. Frontotemporal Degener. 2015;16:92&#x2013;101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25574564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song S.-K., Sun S.-W., Ramsbottom M.J., Chang C., Russell J., Cross A.H. Dysmyelination revealed through MRI as increased radial (but unchanged axial) diffusion of water. Neuroimage. 2002;17:1429&#x2013;1436.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12414282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spinelli E.G., Riva N., Rancoita P.M.V., Schito P., Doretti A., Poletti B., Di Serio C., Silani V., Filippi M., Agosta F. Structural MRI outcomes and predictors of disease progression in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuroimage Clin. 2020;27</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7327879</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32593977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steinwart I., Christmann A. Springer; New York: 2008. Support Vector Machines; p. 602.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stockman G., Shapiro L.G. Computer Vision. rentice Hall PTR Upper Saddle River; NJ, USA: 2001. Chapter 7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swinnen B., Robberecht W. The phenotypic variability of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat Rev Neurol. 2014;10:661&#x2013;670.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25311585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thome J., Steinbach R., Grosskreutz J., Durstewitz D., Koppe G. Classification of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis by brain volume, connectivity, and network dynamics. Hum. Brain Mapp. 2022;43:681&#x2013;699.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8720197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34655259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tu S., Wang C., Menke R.A.L., Talbot K., Barnett M., Kiernan M.C., Turner M.R. Regional callosal integrity and bilaterality of limb weakness in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2020;21:396&#x2013;402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32106716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner M.R., Verstraete E. What does imaging reveal about the pathology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis? Curr Neurol Neurosci Rep. 2015;15:45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4443002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26008817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Unrath A., M&#xfc;ller H.P., Riecker A., Ludolph A.C., Sperfeld A.D., Kassubek J. Whole brain-based analysis of regional white matter tract alterations in rare motor neuron diseases by diffusion tensor imaging. Hum. Brain Mapp. 2010;31:1727&#x2013;1740.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6871219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20336652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van den Berg-Vos R.M., Visser J., Franssen H., de Visser M., de Jong J.M.B.V., Kalmijn S., Wokke J.H.J., Van den Berg L.H. Sporadic lower motor neuron disease with adult onset: classification of subtypes. Brain. 2003;126(5):1036&#x2013;1047.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12690044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Es M.A., Hardiman O., Chio A., Al-Chalabi A., Pasterkamp R.J., Veldink J.H., van den Berg L.H. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet. 2017;390:2084.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28552366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verstraete, E., van den Heuvel, M.P., Veldink, J.H., Blanken, N., Mandl, R.C., Hulshoff Pol, H.E., van den Berg, L.H. 2010. Motor network degeneration in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a structural and functional connectivity study. PLoS One. 5, e13664.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2965124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21060689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wijesekera L.C., Mathers S., Talman P., Galtrey C., Parkinson M.H., Ganesalingam J., Willey E., Ampong M.A., Ellis C.M., Shaw C.E., Al-Chalabi A., Leigh P.N. Natural history and clinical features of the flail arm and flail leg ALS variants. Neurology. 2009;72:1087&#x2013;1094.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2821838</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19307543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang F., Chen G., He M., Dai J., Shang H., Gong Q., Jia Z. Altered white matter microarchitecture in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A voxel-based meta-analysis of diffusion tensor imaging. Neuroimage Clin. 2018;19:122&#x2013;129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6051469</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30035009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>