<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35680039</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1878-1519</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>304</Volume><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Respiratory physiology &amp; neurobiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Respir Physiol Neurobiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Exploring inspiratory occlusion metrics to assess respiratory drive in patients under acute intermittent hypoxia.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>103922</StartPage><MedlinePgn>103922</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.resp.2022.103922</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S1569-9048(22)00081-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Patients living with Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis (ALS) experience respiratory weakness and, eventually, failure due to inspiratory motor neuron degeneration. Routine pulmonary function tests (e.g., maximum inspiratory pressure (MIP)) are used to assess disease progression and ventilatory compromise. However, these tests are poor discriminators between respiratory drive and voluntary respiratory function at rest. To better understand ALS disease progression, we can look into compensatory strategies and how patients consciously react to the occlusion and the effort produced to meet the ventilatory challenge of the occlusion. This ventilatory challenge, especially beyond the P<sub>0.1</sub> (200&#xa0;ms and 300&#xa0;ms), provides information regarding the patient's ability to recruit additional respiratory muscles as a compensatory strategy. Utilizing a standard P<sub>0.1</sub> protocol to assess respiratory drive, we extend the occlusion time analysis to 200&#xa0;ms and 300&#xa0;ms (Detected Occlusion Response (DOR)) in order to capture compensatory respiratory mechanics. Furthermore, we followed an Acute Intermittent Hypoxia (AIH) protocol known to increase phrenic nerve discharge to evaluate the compensatory strategies. Inspiratory pressure, the rate of change in pressure, and pressure generation normalized to MIP were measured at 100&#xa0;ms, 200&#xa0;ms, and 300&#xa0;ms after an occlusion. Airway occlusions were performed three times during the experiment (i.e., baseline, 30 and 60&#xa0;minutes post-AIH). Results indicated that while AIH did not elicit change in the P<sub>0.1</sub> or MIP, the DOR increased for ALS patients. These results support the expected therapeutic role of AIH and indicate the potential of the DOR as a metric to detect compensatory changes.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022. Published by Elsevier B.V.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rodrigues</LastName><ForeName>Victoria R</ForeName><Initials>VR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Florida, Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering, US; University of Florida, Human Informatics and Predictive Performance Optimization (HIPPO) Lab, US. Electronic address: victoria.ribeiro@ufl.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Olsen</LastName><ForeName>Wendy L</ForeName><Initials>WL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Florida, Human Informatics and Predictive Performance Optimization (HIPPO) Lab, US; University of Florida, Breathing Research and Therapeutics Center, Department of Physiological Sciences, US. Electronic address: olsenwendy@ufl.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sajjadi</LastName><ForeName>Elaheh</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Florida, Department of Physical Therapy, US. Electronic address: elasajjadi1@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Smith</LastName><ForeName>Barbara K</ForeName><Initials>BK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Florida, Department of Physical Therapy, US; University of Florida, Breathing Research and Therapeutics Center, Department of Physiological Sciences, US. Electronic address: bksmith@phhp.ufl.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Napoli</LastName><ForeName>Nicholas J</ForeName><Initials>NJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Florida, Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering, US; University of Florida, Human Informatics and Predictive Performance Optimization (HIPPO) Lab, US; University of Florida, Breathing Research and Therapeutics Center, Department of Physiological Sciences, US. Electronic address: n.napoli@ufl.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>L30 HL159818</GrantID><Acronym>HL</Acronym><Agency>NHLBI NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>T32 HL134621</GrantID><Acronym>HL</Acronym><Agency>NHLBI NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>UL1 TR001427</GrantID><Acronym>TR</Acronym><Agency>NCATS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Respir Physiol Neurobiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101140022</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1569-9048</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018450" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Progression</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000860" MajorTopicYN="N">Hypoxia</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010791" MajorTopicYN="N">Phrenic Nerve</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012132" MajorTopicYN="N">Respiratory Muscles</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Acute intermittent hypoxia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Inspiratory pressure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Occlusion pressure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">P(0.1)</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35680039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS1849973</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9749200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.resp.2022.103922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S1569-9048(22)00081-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Baker-Herman TL, Fuller DD, Bavis RW, Zabka AG, Golder FJ, Doperalski NJ, Johnson RA, Watters JJ, Mitchell GS, 2003. BDNF is necessary and sufficient for spinal respiratory plasticity following intermittent hypoxia. Nat. Neurosci 7 (1), 48&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14699417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baydur A, 1991. Respiratory muscle strength and control of ventilation in patients with neuromuscular disease. Chest 99 (2), 330&#x2013;338.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1989791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bourke S, Shaw P, Gibson G, 2001. Respiratory function vs sleep-disordered breathing as predictors of QOL in ALS. Neurology 57 (11), 2040&#x2013;2044.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11739823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bourke SC, Bullock RE, Williams TL, Shaw PJ, Gibson GJ, 2003. Noninvasive ventilation in ALS: indications and effect on quality of life. Neurology 61 (2), 171&#x2013;177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12874394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheah BC, Boland RA, Brodaty NE, Zoing MC, Jeffery SE, McKenzie DK, Kiernan MC, 2009. INSPIRATIonAL &#x2013; INSPIRAtory muscle training in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. myotroph. Lateral Scler. 10 (5&#x2013;6), 384&#x2013;392.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19922129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faraway J, 2016. Extending the Linear Model with R: Generalized Linear, Mixed Effects and Nonparametric Regression Models. CRC Press Taylor &amp; Francis Group,, Boca Raton.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Golub G, 1965. Numerical methods for solving linear least squares problems, umer. Math 7 (3), 206&#x2013;216.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>I&#x142;&#x17c;ecka J, Stelmasiak Z, Balicka G, 2003. Respiratory function in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurol. Sci 24 (4), 288&#x2013;289.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14658052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiernan MC, Vucic S, Cheah BC, Turner MR, Eisen A, Hardiman O, Burrell JR, Zoing MC, 2011. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, lancet 377 (9769), 942&#x2013;955.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21296405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lahrmann H, Wild M, Zdrahal F, Grisold W, 2003. Expiratory muscle weakness and assisted cough in ALS. myotroph. Lateral Scler. Other Mot. Neuron Disord 4 (1), 49&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12745619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lange DJ, Lechtzin N, Davey C, David W, Heiman-Patterson T, Gelinas D, Becker B, Mitsumoto HM, The HFCWO Study Group, 2006. chest wall oscillation in ALS: An exploratory randomized, controlled trial. Neurology 67 (6), 991&#x2013;997.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17000967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laveneziana P, Albuquerque A, Aliverti A, Babb T, Barreiro E, Dres M, Dub&#xe9; B-P, Fauroux B, Gea J, Guenette JA, Hudson AL, Kabitz H-J, Laghi F, Langer D, Luo Y-M, Neder JA, O&#x2019;Donnell D, Polkey MI, Rabinovich RA, Rossi A, Series F, Similowski T, Spengler C, Vogiatzis I, Verges S, 2019. ERS statement on respiratory muscle testing at rest and during exercise. Eur. Respir. J 53 (6), 1801214.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30956204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lechtzin N, Rothstein J, Clawson L, Diette GB, Wiener CM, 2002. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: evaluation and treatment of respiratory impairment. Amyotroph. Lateral Scler. Other Mot. Neuron Disord 3 (1), 5&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12061943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Napoli NJ, Kotoriy ME, Barnhardt W, Young JS, Barnes LE, Addressing bias from non-random missing attributes in health data. IEEE EMBS Intern. Conf. on Biomedical and Health Informatics, 265&#x2013;268, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Napoli NJ, Rodrigues VR, Davenport PW, 2022. Characterizing and modeling breathing dynamics: Flow rate, rhythm, period, and frequency. Front. Physiol 12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8899297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35264974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nichols NL, Gowing G, Satriotomo I, Nashold LJ, Dale EA, Suzuki M, Avalos P, Mulcrone PL, McHugh J, Svendsen CN, et al., 2013. Intermittent hypoxia and stem cell implants preserve breathing capacity in a rodent model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Am. J. Respir. Crit. Care Med 187 (5), 535&#x2013;542.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3733409</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23220913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nichols NL, Satriotomo I, Harrigan DJ, Mitchell GS, 2015. Acute intermittent hypoxia induced phrenic long-term facilitation despite increased sod1 expression in a rat model of als. Exp. Neurol 273, 138&#x2013;150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4644466</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26287750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olsen W, Morris K, Bolser D, 2021. Proposed mechanisms of opioid-induced respiratory suppression mediated by actions at excitatory synapses within the inspiratory network: Results from a neuromechanical computational model of the respiratory control system. FASEB J. 35 (S1).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinto S, Swash M, Carvalho M.De, 2021. Mouth occlusion pressure at 100ms (p0.1) as a respiratory biomarker in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph. Lateral Scler. Front. Degener 22 (1&#x2013;2), 53&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32955378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sajjadi E, Seven YB, Ehrbar JG, Wymer JP, Mitchell GS, Smith BK, 2022. Acute intermittent hypoxia and respiratory muscle recruitment in people with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a preliminary study. Exp. Neurol 347, 113890.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9488543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34624328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seven YB, Mitchell GS, 2019. Mechanisms of compensatory plasticity for respiratory motor neuron death. Respir. Physiol. Neurobiol 265, 32&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6579668</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30625378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seven YB, Nichols NL, Kelly MN, Hobson OR, Satriotomo I, Mitchell GS, 2018. Compensatory plasticity in diaphragm and intercostal muscle utilization in a rat model of ALS. Exp. Neurol 299, 148&#x2013;156.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5951687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29056361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh D, Verma R, Garg RK, Singh MK, Shukla R, Verma S, 2011. Assessment of respiratory functions by spirometry and phrenic nerve studies in patients of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J. Neurol. Sci 306 (1&#x2013;2), 76&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21496826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sutor T, Cavka K, Vose AK, Welch JF, Davenport P, Fuller DD, Mitchell GS, Fox EJ, 2021. Single-session effects of acute intermittent hypoxia on breathing function after human spinal cord injury. Exp. Neurol, 113735.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8616729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33951477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vitacca M, Clini E, Facchetti D, Pagani M, Poloni M, Porta R, Ambrosino N, 1997. Breathing pattern and respiratory mechanics in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Eur. Respir. J 10 (7), 1614&#x2013;1621.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9230256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitelaw WA and Derenne JP, Airway occlusion pressure. 74(4), 1475&#x2013;1483, Apr. 1993.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8514660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitelaw WA, Derenne J-P, Milic-Emili J, 1975. Occlusion pressure as a measure of respiratory center output cm conscious man. Respir. Physiol 23 (2), 181&#x2013;199.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1144940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zinman L, Cudkowicz M, 2011. Emerging targets and treatments in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet Neurol. 10 (5), 481&#x2013;490.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21511200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>