<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35707959</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1938-3673</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>112</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of leukocyte biology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Leukoc Biol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>In silico design of a TLR4-mediating multiepitope chimeric vaccine against amyotrophic lateral sclerosis via advanced immunoinformatics.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1191</StartPage><EndPage>1207</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1191-1207</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/JLB.6MA0721-376RR</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) is the most prevalent motor neuron disorder worldwide. In ALS, progressing disease can result from misfolding and aggregation of superoxide dismutase-1 (SOD1) or TAR DNA-binding protein 43&#xa0;kDa (TDP43). An efficient immunotherapy for ALS should spare intact SOD1 while eliminating its dysfunctional variant. We utilized advanced immunoinformatics to suggest a potential vaccine candidate against ALS by proposing a model of dynamic TLR4 mediation and induction of a specific Th2-biased shift against mutant SOD1, TDP43, and TRAF6, a protein that specifically interacts with dysfunctional SOD1. SOD1, TDP43, and TRAF6 were retrieved in FASTA. Immune Epitopes Database and CTLpred suggested T/B-cell epitopes from disease-specific regions of selected antigens. A TLR4-mediating adjuvant, RS01, was used. Sequences were assembled via suitable linkers. Tertiary structure of the protein was calculated. Refined protein structure and physicochemical features of the 3D structure were verified in silico. Differential immune induction was assessed via C-ImmSim. GROningen MAchine for Chemical Simulation was used to assess evolution of the docked vaccine-TLR4 complex in blood. Our protein showed high structural quality and was nonallergenic and immune inducing. Also, the vaccine-TLR4 complex stability was verified by RMSD, RMSF, gyration, and visual analyses of the molecular dynamic trajectory. Contact residues in the vaccine-TLR4 complex showed favorable binding energies. Immune stimulation analyses of the proposed candidate demonstrated a sustained memory cell response and a strong adaptive immune reaction. We proposed a potential vaccine candidate against ALS and verified its physicochemical and immune inducing features. Future studies should assess this vaccine in animal studies.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9;2022 Society for Leukocyte Biology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saleki</LastName><ForeName>Kiarash</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Student Research Committee, Babol University of Medical Sciences, Babol, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>USERN Office, Babol University of Medical Sciences, Babol, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mohamadi</LastName><ForeName>Mohamad Hosein</ForeName><Initials>MH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Student Research Committee, Sabzevar University of Medical Sciences, Sabzevar, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Banazadeh</LastName><ForeName>Mohamad</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pharmaceutical Sciences and Cosmetic Products Research Center, Kerman University of Medical Sciences, Kerman, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alijanizadeh</LastName><ForeName>Parsa</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Student Research Committee, Babol University of Medical Sciences, Babol, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>USERN Office, Babol University of Medical Sciences, Babol, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Javanmehr</LastName><ForeName>Nima</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Student Research Committee, Babol University of Medical Sciences, Babol, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>USERN Office, Babol University of Medical Sciences, Babol, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pourahmad</LastName><ForeName>Ramtin</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, Tehran University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nouri</LastName><ForeName>Hamid Reza</ForeName><Initials>HR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>USERN Office, Babol University of Medical Sciences, Babol, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Immunoregulation Research Center, Health Research Institute, Babol University of Medical Sciences, Babol, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Leukoc Biol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8405628</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0741-5400</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 1.15.1.1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000072105">Superoxide Dismutase-1</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D051197">Toll-Like Receptor 4</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D018985">Epitopes, B-Lymphocyte</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D048029">TNF Receptor-Associated Factor 6</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 1.15.1.1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D013482">Superoxide Dismutase</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D004268">DNA-Binding Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D014612">Vaccines</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D018984">Epitopes, T-Lymphocyte</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000072105" MajorTopicYN="N">Superoxide Dismutase-1</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051197" MajorTopicYN="N">Toll-Like Receptor 4</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018985" MajorTopicYN="N">Epitopes, B-Lymphocyte</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D048029" MajorTopicYN="N">TNF Receptor-Associated Factor 6</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013482" MajorTopicYN="N">Superoxide Dismutase</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004268" MajorTopicYN="N">DNA-Binding Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014612" MajorTopicYN="Y">Vaccines</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018984" MajorTopicYN="N">Epitopes, T-Lymphocyte</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">computational biology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neurodegeneration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neuroimmunology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">reverse vaccinology
</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35707959</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/JLB.6MA0721-376RR</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Simon NG, Huynh W, Vucic S, Talbot K, Kiernan MC. Motor neuron disease: current management and future prospects. Intern Med J. 2015;45:1005-13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longinetti E, Fang F. Epidemiology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: an update of recent literature. Curr Opin Neurol. 2019;32:771-776.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Bos MAJ, Geevasinga N, Higashihara M, Menon P, Vucic S. Pathophysiology and diagnosis of ALS: insights from advances in neurophysiological techniques. Int J Mol Sci. 2019;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Chalabi A, Calvo A, Chio A, et&#xa0;al. Analysis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis as a multistep process: a population-based modelling study. Lancet Neurol. 2014;13:1108-1113.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuo J, Siddique T, Fu R, Heckman C. Increased persistent Na+ current and its effect on excitability in motoneurones cultured from mutant SOD1 mice. J Physiol. 2005;563:843-854.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang W, Zhang L, Liang B, et&#xa0;al. Hyperactive somatostatin interneurons contribute to excitotoxicity in neurodegenerative disorders. Nat Neurosci. 2016;19:557-559.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geloso MC, Corvino V, Marchese E, Serrano A, Michetti F, D'Ambrosi N. The dual role of microglia in ALS: mechanisms and therapeutic approaches. Front Aging Neurosci. 2017;9:242.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao W, Beers DR, Appel SH. Immune-mediated mechanisms in the pathoprogression of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neuroimmune Pharmacol. 2013;8:888-899.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao B, Marciniuk K, Gibbs E, Yousefi M, Napper S, Cashman NR. Therapeutic vaccines for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis directed against disease specific epitopes of superoxide dismutase 1. Vaccine. 2019;37:4920-4927.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Semmler S, Gagn&#xe9; M, Garg P, et&#xa0;al. TNF receptor-associated factor 6 interacts with ALS-linked misfolded superoxide dismutase 1 and promotes aggregation. J Biol Chem. 2020;295:3808-3825.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rasoulinejad SA, Karkhah A, Paniri A, Saleki K, Pirzadeh M, Nouri HR. Contribution of inflammasome complex in inflammatory-related eye disorders and its implications for anti-inflammasome therapy. Immunopharmacol Immunotoxicol. 2020;42:400-407.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johann S, Heitzer M, Kanagaratnam M, et&#xa0;al. NLRP3 inflammasome is expressed by astrocytes in the SOD1 mouse model of ALS and in human sporadic ALS patients. Glia. 2015;63:2260-2273.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rostamtabar M, Esmaeilzadeh S, Tourani M, et&#xa0;al. Pathophysiological roles of chronic low-grade inflammation mediators in polycystic ovary syndrome. J Cell Physiol. 2021;236:824-838.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Urushitani M, Tamaki Y, Hikiami R, Minamiyama S. [Immunotherapy against misfolded proteins in ALS]. Brain Nerve. 2019;71:1289-1301.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee JY, Lee JD, Phipps S, Noakes PG, Woodruff TM. Absence of toll-like receptor 4 (TLR4) extends survival in the hSOD1 G93A mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neuroinflamm. 2015;12:90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Netea MG, Van der Meer JW, Sutmuller RP, Adema GJ, Kullberg BJ. From the Th1/Th2 paradigm towards a Toll-like receptor/T-helper bias. Antimicrob Agents Chemother. 2005;49:3991-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grasselli C, Ferrari D, Zalfa C, et&#xa0;al. Toll-like receptor 4 modulation influences human neural stem cell proliferation and differentiation. Cell Death Dis. 2018;9:280.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rappuoli R. Reverse vaccinology. Curr Opin Microbiol. 2000;3:445-450.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Der Spoel D, Lindahl E, Hess B, Groenhof G, Mark AE, Berendsen HJ. GROMACS: fast, flexible, and free. J Comput Chem. 2005;26:1701-1718.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castiglione F, Duca K, Jarrah A, Laubenbacher R, Hochberg D, Thorley-Lawson D. Simulating epstein-barr virus infection with c-immsim. Bioinformatics. 2007;23:1371-1377.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahmani A, Baee M, Saleki K, Moradi S, Nouri HR. Applying high throughput and comprehensive immunoinformatics approaches to design a trivalent subunit vaccine for induction of immune response against emerging human coronaviruses SARS-CoV, MERS-CoV and SARS-CoV-2. J Biomol Struct Dynam. 2021:1-17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munson P, Liu Y, Bratt D, et&#xa0;al. Therapeutic conserved elements (CE) DNA vaccine induces strong T-cell responses against highly conserved viral sequences during simian-human immunodeficiency virus infection. Hum Vaccin Immunother. 2018;14:1820-1831.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenbaum J, Sidney J, Chung J, Brander C, Peters B, Sette A. Functional classification of class II human leukocyte antigen (HLA) molecules reveals seven different supertypes and a surprising degree of repertoire sharing across supertypes. Immunogenetics. 2011;63:325-35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shanmugam A, Rajoria S, George AL, Mittelman A, Suriano R, Tiwari RK. Synthetic Toll like receptor-4 (TLR-4) agonist peptides as a novel class of adjuvants. PLoS One. 2012;7:e30839.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doytchinova IA, Flower DR. VaxiJen: a server for prediction of protective antigens, tumour antigens and subunit vaccines. BMC Bioinformatics. 2007;8:4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacRaild CA, Seow J, Das SC, Norton RS. Disordered epitopes as peptide vaccines. Pept Sci (Hoboken). 2018;110:e24067.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larsen JEP, Lund O, Nielsen M. Improved method for predicting linear B-cell epitopes. Immunome Res. 2006;2:1-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu T, Wang Y, Luo X, et&#xa0;al. Enhancing protein stability with extended disulfide bonds. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2016;113:5910-5915.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan Y, Tao H, He J, Huang S-Y. The HDOCK server for integrated protein-protein docking. Nat Protoc. 2020;15:1829-1852.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mallik B, Morikis D. Applications of molecular dynamics simulations in immunology: a useful computational method in aiding vaccine design. Curr Proteom. 2006;3:259-270.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wodi AP, Ault K, Hunter P, McNally V, Szilagyi PG, Bernstein H. Advisory committee on immunization practices recommended immunization schedule for children and adolescents aged 18 years or younger-United States, 2021. Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2021;70:189.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>CDC (2021) Child and adolescents immunization schedule.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saleki K, Yaribash S, Banazadeh M, et&#xa0;al. Interferon therapy in patients with SARS, MERS, and COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis of clinical studies. Eur J Pharmacol. 2021;906:174248.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saleki K, Banazadeh M, Miri NS, Azadmehr A. Triangle of cytokine storm, central nervous system involvement, and viral infection in COVID-19: the role of sFasL and neuropilin-1. Rev Neurosci. 2022;33:147-160.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahmani A, Saleki K, Javanmehr N, Khodaparast J, Saadat P, Nouri HR. Mesenchymal stem cell-derived extracellular vesicle-based therapies protect against coupled degeneration of the central nervous and vascular systems in stroke. Ageing Res Rev. 2020;62:101106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saleki K, Banazadeh M, Saghazadeh A, Rezaei N. The involvement of the central nervous system in patients with COVID-19. Rev Neurosci. 2020;31:453-456.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marciniuk K, Taschuk R, Napper S. Evidence for prion-like mechanisms in several neurodegenerative diseases: potential implications for immunotherapy. Clin Dev Immunol. 2013;2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li L, Napper S, Cashman NR. Immunotherapy for prion diseases: opportunities and obstacles. Immunotherapy. 2010;2:269-282.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ido A, Fukuyama H, Urushitani M. Protein misdirection inside and outside motor neurons in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS): a possible clue for therapeutic strategies. Int J Mol Sci. 2011;12:6980-7003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Southwell AL, Patterson PH. Antibody therapy in neurodegenerative disease. Rev Neurosci. 2010;21:273-288.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panza F, Solfrizzi V, Imbimbo BP, Tortelli R, Santamato A, Logroscino G. Amyloid-based immunotherapy for Alzheimer's disease in the time of prevention trials: the way forward. Expert Rev Clin Immunol. 2014;10:405-419.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barrera-Ocampo A, Lopera F. Amyloid-beta immunotherapy: the hope for Alzheimer disease? Colombia M&#xe9;dica. 2016;47:203-212.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panza F, Logroscino G, Imbimbo BP, Solfrizzi V. Is there still any hope for amyloid-based immunotherapy for Alzheimer's disease? Curr Opin Psychiatry. 2014;27:128-137.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orgogozo J-M, Gilman S, Dartigues J-F, et&#xa0;al. Subacute meningoencephalitis in a subset of patients with AD after A&#x3b2;42 immunization. Neurology. 2003;61:46-54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilman S, Koller M, Black R, et&#xa0;al. Clinical effects of A&#x3b2; immunization (AN1792) in patients with AD in an interrupted trial. Neurology. 2005;64:1553-1562.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sevigny J, Chiao P, Bussi&#xe8;re T, et&#xa0;al. The antibody aducanumab reduces A&#x3b2; plaques in Alzheimer's disease. Nature. 2016;537:50-56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pereira GRC, Vieira BdAA, De Mesquita JF. Comprehensive in silico analysis and molecular dynamics of the superoxide dismutase 1 (SOD1) variants related to amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. PLoS One. 2021;16:e0247841.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee JY, Lee JD, Phipps S, Noakes PG, Woodruff TM. Absence of toll-like receptor 4 (TLR4) extends survival in the hSOD1G93A mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neuroinflamm. 2015;12:90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grasselli C, Ferrari D, Zalfa C, et&#xa0;al. Toll-like receptor 4 modulation influences human neural stem cell proliferation and differentiation. Cell Death Dis. 2018;9:280.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Molnar KS, Karabacak NM, Johnson JL, et&#xa0;al. A common property of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-associated variants: destabilization of the copper/zinc superoxide dismutase electrostatic loop. J Biol Chem. 2009;284:30965-30973.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>