<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35707968</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-4598</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>66</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Muscle &amp; nerve</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Muscle Nerve</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>National prescription patterns of antidepressants among patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: An analysis of the Korean National Health Insurance database.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>312</StartPage><EndPage>318</EndPage><MedlinePgn>312-318</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/mus.27663</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION/AIMS">The current status of antidepressant use in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS), such as the prevalence and factors associated with it, has not been systematically investigated. We aimed to analyze the prevalence and patterns of antidepressant prescriptions in patients with ALS and depression, and to identify factors associated with antidepressant prescriptions after the diagnosis of ALS.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">The data of patients with ALS and the prescription of antidepressants were retrieved from the Korean National Health Insurance claims data. A multivariate logistic regression model was used to identify factors associated with antidepressant prescriptions.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">In total, 533 of 2955 patients had depressive disorders, and 426 were prescribed antidepressants. Selective serotonin reuptake inhibitors and tricyclic antidepressants were the most frequently prescribed drugs. Adjusted odds ratios (ORs) were 1.379 for the prescription of antidepressants in females. For various age groups, compared with those aged 80&#x2009;years and older, adjusted ORs were 1.889 for those in their 70s, 2.319 for those in their 60s, 2.872 for those in their 50s, 2.854 for those in their 40s, and 3.363 for those under 40&#x2009;years of age. Adjusted ORs were 1.662 for patients with a history of a psychiatric disorder and 1.861 for those with a history of psychiatric pharmacotherapy (all P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;.05).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION">Most patients with ALS who had depression received antidepressant prescriptions. In young females with a previous psychiatric disorder or pharmacotherapy, an in-depth evaluation for a depressive disorder should be performed.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Park</LastName><ForeName>C Hyung Keun</ForeName><Initials>CHK</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2568-1426</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Asan Medical Center, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Choi</LastName><ForeName>Seok-Jin</ForeName><Initials>SJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6444-977X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Seoul National University Hospital, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biomedical Research Institute, Seoul, National University Hospital, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biomedical Research Institute, Inha, University Hospital, Incheon, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Ye-Jee</ForeName><Initials>YJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Epidemiology and Biostatistics, Asan Medical Center, University of Ulsan College of Medicine, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hong</LastName><ForeName>Yoon-Ho</ForeName><Initials>YH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Seoul Metropolitan Government Seoul National University Boramae Medical Center, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sung</LastName><ForeName>Jung-Joon</ForeName><Initials>JJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7525-5313</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Seoul National University Hospital, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wide River Institute of Immunology, Seoul National University, Hongcheon, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neuroscience Research Institute, Seoul, National University College of Medicine, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Muscle Nerve</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7803146</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0148-639X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000928">Antidepressive Agents</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000139" MajorTopicYN="N">chemically induced</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000928" MajorTopicYN="N">Antidepressive Agents</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009313" MajorTopicYN="N">National Health Programs</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055656" MajorTopicYN="N">Prescriptions</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D056910" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Republic of Korea</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">antidepressants</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anxiety</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anxiolytics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">depression</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35707968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.27663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Roos E, Mariosa D, Ingre C, et al. Depression in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology. 2016;86:2271-2277.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner MR, Goldacre R, Talbot K, et al. Psychiatric disorders prior to amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol. 2016;80:935-938.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zucchi E, Ticozzi N, Mandrioli J. Psychiatric symptoms in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: beyond a motor neuron disorder. Front Neurosci. 2019;13:175.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gill D, Hatcher S. Antidepressants for depression in medical illness. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2000;(4):CD001312.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pisa FE, Logroscino G, Casetta A, et al. The use of antidepressant medication before and after the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a population-based cohort study. Neuroepidemiology. 2015;44:91-98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mann JJ. The medical management of depression. N Engl J Med. 2005;353:1819-1834.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. International Statistical Classification of Diseases and Related Health Problems, 10th Revision, Clinical Modification. https://icd.who.int/browse10/2019/en. Accessed December 15, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Law Information Center. Enforcement Decree of the National Health Insurance Act. https://www.law.go.kr/LSW/eng/engLsSc.do?menuId=2&amp;section=lawNm&amp;query=%EA%B5%AD%EB%AF%BC%EA%B1%B4%EA%B0%95%EB%B3%B4%ED%97%98%EB%B2%95&amp;x=0&amp;y=0#liBgcolor0. Accessed December 15, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cunningham R, Sarfati D, Peterson D, et al. Premature mortality in adults using New Zealand psychiatric services. N Z Med J. 2014;127:31-41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gasse C, Danielsen AA, Pedersen MG, et al. Positive predictive value of a register-based algorithm using the Danish National Registries to identify suicidal events. Pharmacoepidemiol Drug Saf. 2018;27:1131-1138.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo Y, Kataoka Y, Ostinelli EG, et al. National prescription patterns of antidepressants in the treatment of adults with major depression in the US between 1996 and 2015: a population representative survey based analysis. Front Psych. 2020;11:35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marcus SC, Olfson M. National trends in the treatment for depression from 1998 to 2007. Arch Gen Psychiatry. 2010;67:1265-1273.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen P, Kales HC, Weintraub D, et al. Antidepressant treatment of veterans with Parkinson's disease and depression: analysis of a national sample. J Geriatr Psychiatry Neurol. 2007;20:161-165.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park J-I, Oh K-Y, Chung Y-C. Psychiatry in Korea. Asian J Psychiatry. 2013;6:186-190.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bauer M, Monz BU, Montejo AL, et al. Prescribing patterns of antidepressants in Europe: results from the factors influencing depression endpoints research (FINDER) study. Eur Psychiatry. 2008;23:66-73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chee KY, Tripathi A, Avasthi A, et al. International study on antidepressant prescription pattern at 40 major psychiatric institutions and hospitals in Asia: a 10-year comparison study. Asia Pac Psychiatry. 2015;7:366-374.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fornasari D. Pharmacotherapy for neuropathic pain: a review. Pain Ther. 2017;6(Suppl 1):25-33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banfi P, Ticozzi N, Lax A, et al. A review of options for treating sialorrhea in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Respir Care. 2015;60:446-454.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2; A, Mora G, Lauria G. Pain in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet Neurol. 2017;16:144-157.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stone CA, O'Leary N. Systematic review of the effectiveness of botulinum toxin or radiotherapy for sialorrhea in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Pain Symptom Manage. 2009;37:246-258.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S-M, Han C, Bahk W-M, et al. Addressing the side effects of contemporary antidepressant drugs: a comprehensive review. Chonnam Med J. 2018;54:101-112.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karsten J, Hagenauw LA, Kamphuis J, et al. Low doses of mirtazapine or quetiapine for transient insomnia: a randomised, double-blind, cross-over, placebo-controlled trial. J Psychopharmacol. 2017;31:327-337.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alam A, Voronovich Z, Carley JA. A review of therapeutic uses of mirtazapine in psychiatric and medical conditions. Prim Care Companion CNS Disord. 2013;15:PCC.13r01525.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feighner JP. Overview of antidepressants currently used to treat anxiety disorders. J Clin Psychiatry. 1999;60:18-22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siciliano M, Trojano L, Trojsi F, et al. Assessing anxiety and its correlates in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: the state-trait anxiety inventory. Muscle Nerve. 2019;60:47-55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wicks P, Abrahams S, Masi D, et al. Prevalence of depression in a 12-month consecutive sample of patients with ALS. Eur J Neurol. 2007;14:993-1001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rabkin J, Albert S, Del Bene M, et al. Prevalence of depressive disorders and change over time in late-stage ALS. Neurology. 2005;65:62-67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qutub K, Lacomis D, Albert SM, et al. Life factors affecting depression and burden in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis caregivers. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemp Degener. 2014;15:292-297.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui F, Zhu W, Zhou Z, et al. Frequency and risk factor analysis of cognitive and anxiety-depressive disorders in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis/motor neuron disease. Neuropsychiatr Dis Treat. 2015;11:2847-2854.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grant BF, Goldstein RB, Chou SP, et al. Sociodemographic and psychopathologic predictors of first incidence of DSM-IV substance use, mood and anxiety disorders: results from the wave 2 National Epidemiologic Survey on alcohol and related conditions. Mol Psychiatry. 2009;14:1051-1066.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grant BF, Harford TC. Comorbidity between DSM-IV alcohol use disorders and major depression: results of a national survey. Drug Alcohol Depend. 1995;39:197-206.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoevers R, Beekman A, Deeg D, et al. Risk factors for depression in later life; results of a prospective community based study (AMSTEL). J Affect Disord. 2000;59:127-137.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furukawa T, Streiner D, Young L. Antidepressant plus benzodiazepine for major depression. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2000;(2):CD001026.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Londborg PD, Smith WT, Glaudin V, et al. Short-term cotherapy with clonazepam and fluoxetine: anxiety, sleep disturbance and core symptoms of depression. J Affect Disord. 2000;61:73-79.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fava M, Rush AJ, Alpert JE, et al. Difference in treatment outcome in outpatients with anxious versus nonanxious depression: a STAR*D report. Am J Psychiatry. 2008;165:342-351.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katz C, Yaseen ZS, Mojtabai R, et al. Panic as an independent risk factor for suicide attempt in depressive illness: findings from the National Epidemiological Survey on alcohol and related conditions (NESARC). J Clin Psychiatry. 2011;72:1628-1635.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dawood S, Poole N, Fung R, et al. Neurologists' detection and recognition of mental disorder in a tertiary in-patient neurological unit. B J Psych Bull. 2018;42:19-23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asnis GM, Thomas M, Henderson MA. Pharmacotherapy treatment options for insomnia: a primer for clinicians. Int J Mol Sci. 2016;17:50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borasio GD, Shaw PJ, Hardiman O, Ludolph AC, Sales Luis ML, Silani V. Standards of palliative care for patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: results of a European survey. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord. 2001;2:159-164.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen PM, Abrahams S, Borasio GD, et al. EFNS guidelines on the clinical management of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (MALS)---revised report of an EFNS task force. Eur J Neurol. 2012;19:360-375.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bae JS, Hong Y-H, Baek W, et al. Current status of the diagnosis and management of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in Korea: a multi-center cross-sectional study. J Clin Neurol. 2012;8:293-300.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>