<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35708508</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>09</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1468-1331</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>29</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Detection of changes in synaptic density in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients using <sup>18</sup> F-SynVesT-1 positron emission tomography.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2934</StartPage><EndPage>2943</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2934-2943</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/ene.15451</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND PURPOSE">Synaptic loss is well established as the major correlate of characteristic and consistent pathology in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). We aimed to assess the possible discriminant diagnostic value of <sup>18</sup> F-SynVesT-1 positron emission tomography (PET) as a marker of ALS pathology and investigate whether specific synaptic density signatures are present in ALS with different subtypes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Twenty-one patients with ALS and 25 healthy controls (HCs) were recruited. All participants underwent <sup>18</sup> F-SynVesT-1-PET. Synaptic density between ALS and HCs and between different ALS subgroups were compared. Correlation between synaptic density and clinical features in ALS was also analyzed.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Low uptake distribution was found in the group comprising 21 ALS patients as compared with HCs in the right temporal lobe and the bilateral inferior frontal gyrus, anterior cingulate, and hippocampus-insula region. We also found low uptake in the bilateral superior temporal gyrus, hippocampus-insula, anterior cingulate, and left inferior frontal gyrus in ALS patients with cognitive impairment compared to HCs. Furthermore, compared to spinal onset ALS, bulbar onset ALS showed low uptake in the bilateral cingulate gyrus and high uptake in the bilateral superior temporal gyrus and left occipital lobe. No significant result was found in correlation analysis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">This approach may provide a direct measure of synaptic density, and it therefore might represent a potentially useful biomarker for ALS diagnosis, as well as for estimating the cognitive decline and site of onset in ALS. <sup>18</sup> F-SynVesT-1-PET is presently not justified as a routine investigation to detect evidence of brain dysfunction leading to progression in ALS.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022 European Academy of Neurology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tang</LastName><ForeName>Yongxiang</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nuclear Medicine, Xiangya Hospital, Central South University, Changsha, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Pan</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Xiangya Hospital, Central South University, Changsha, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Wanzhen</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Xiangya Hospital, Central South University, Changsha, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Zhen</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Xiangya Hospital, Central South University, Changsha, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Ming</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nuclear Medicine, Xiangya Hospital, Central South University, Changsha, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Jian</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nuclear Medicine, Xiangya Hospital, Central South University, Changsha, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yuan</LastName><ForeName>Yanchun</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Xiangya Hospital, Central South University, Changsha, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fang</LastName><ForeName>Liangjuan</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Xiangya Hospital, Central South University, Changsha, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Mengli</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Third Xiangya Hospital, Central South University, Changsha, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shen</LastName><ForeName>Lu</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Xiangya Hospital, Central South University, Changsha, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Clinical Research Center for Geriatric Diseases, Xiangya Hospital, Central South University, Changsha, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Hunan Province in Neurodegenerative Disorders, Central South University, Changsha, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Medical Genetics, School of Life Sciences, Central South University, Changsha, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Yiyun</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>PET Center, Department of Radiology and Biomedical Imaging, Yale University School of Medicine, New Haven, Connecticut, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tang</LastName><ForeName>Beisha</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Xiangya Hospital, Central South University, Changsha, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Clinical Research Center for Geriatric Diseases, Xiangya Hospital, Central South University, Changsha, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Hunan Province in Neurodegenerative Disorders, Central South University, Changsha, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Medical Genetics, School of Life Sciences, Central South University, Changsha, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Junling</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5117-5204</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Xiangya Hospital, Central South University, Changsha, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Clinical Research Center for Geriatric Diseases, Xiangya Hospital, Central South University, Changsha, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Hunan Province in Neurodegenerative Disorders, Central South University, Changsha, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Medical Genetics, School of Life Sciences, Central South University, Changsha, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Engineering Research Center of Hunan Province in Cognitive Impairment Disorders, Central South University, Changsha, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hunan International Scientific and Technological Cooperation Base of Neurodegenerative and Neurogenetic Diseases, Changsha, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hu</LastName><ForeName>Shuo</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nuclear Medicine, Xiangya Hospital, Central South University, Changsha, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Clinical Research Center for Geriatric Diseases, Xiangya Hospital, Central South University, Changsha, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Biological Nanotechnology of National Health Commission, Xiangya Hospital, Central South University, Changsha, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9506311</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1351-5101</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001921" MajorTopicYN="N">Brain</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002540" MajorTopicYN="N">Cerebral Cortex</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D060825" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cognitive Dysfunction</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008279" MajorTopicYN="N">Magnetic Resonance Imaging</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D049268" MajorTopicYN="N">Positron-Emission Tomography</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017397" MajorTopicYN="N">Prefrontal Cortex</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">18F-SynVesT-1</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">positron emission tomography</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">synaptic density</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35708508</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ene.15451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Brown RH, Al-Chalabi A. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. N Engl J Med. 2017;377:162-172.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huisman MH, de Jong SW, van Doormaal PT, et al. Population based epidemiology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis using capture-recapture methodology. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2011;82:1165-1170.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longinetti E, Fang F. Epidemiology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: an update of recent literature. Curr Opin Neurol. 2019;32:771-776.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wittie M, Nelson LM, Usher S, Ward K, Benatar M. Utility of capture-recapture methodology to assess completeness of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis case ascertainment. Neuroepidemiology. 2013;40:133-141.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, Miller RG, Swash M, Munsat TL. El Escorial revisited: revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord. 2000;1:293-299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pasinetti GM, Ungar LH, Lange DJ, et al. Identification of potential CSF biomarkers in ALS. Neurology. 2006;66:1218-1222.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henstridge CM, Sideris DI, Carroll E, et al. Synapse loss in the prefrontal cortex is associated with cognitive decline in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathol. 2018;135:213-226.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y, Pattamatta A, Zu T, et al. C9orf72 BAC mouse model with motor deficits and neurodegenerative features of ALS/FTD. Neuron. 2016;90:521-534.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fogarty MJ, Mu EW, Noakes PG, Lavidis NA, Bellingham MC. Marked changes in dendritic structure and spine density precede significant neuronal death in vulnerable cortical pyramidal neuron populations in the SOD1(G93A) mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathol Commun. 2016;4:77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorrie GH, Fecto F, Radzicki D, et al. Dendritic spinopathy in transgenic mice expressing ALS/dementia-linked mutant UBQLN2. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2014;111:14524-14529.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fogarty MJ, Mu EWH, Lavidis NA, Noakes PG, Bellingham MC. Motor areas show altered dendritic structure in an amyotrophic lateral sclerosis mouse model. Front Neurosci. 2017;11:609.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bajjalieh SM, Frantz GD, Weimann JM, McConnell SK, Scheller RH. Differential expression of synaptic vesicle protein 2 (SV2) isoforms. J Neurosci. 1994;14:5223-5235.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen MK, Mecca AP, Naganawa M, et al. Assessing synaptic density in Alzheimer disease with synaptic vesicle glycoprotein 2A positron emission tomographic imaging. JAMA Neurol. 2018;75:1215-1224.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matuskey D, Tinaz S, Wilcox KC, et al. Synaptic changes in Parkinson disease assessed with in vivo imaging. Ann Neurol. 2020;87:329-338.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li S, Cai Z, Wu X, et al. Synthesis and in vivo evaluation of a novel PET radiotracer for imaging of synaptic vesicle glycoprotein 2A (SV2A) in nonhuman primates. ACS Chem Nerosci. 2019;10:1544-1554.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naganawa M, Li S, Nabulsi N, et al. First-in-human evaluation of (18)F-SynVesT-1, a radioligand for PET imaging of synaptic vesicle glycoprotein 2A. J Nucl Med. 2021;62:561-567.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang Y, Yu J, Zhou M, et al. Cortical abnormalities of synaptic vesicle protein 2A in focal cortical dysplasia type II identified in vivo with (18)F-SynVesT-1 positron emission tomography imaging. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging. 2022;49:3482-3491.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang Y, Yu J, Zhou M, Chen C, Hu S. 18F-SynVesT-1 PET in focal cortical dysplasia type II with thickening cortex. Clin Nucl Med. 2022;47:741-743.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ludolph A, Drory V, Hardiman O, et al. A revision of the El Escorial criteria - 2015. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2015;16:291-292.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abrahams S, Newton J, Niven E, Foley J, Bak TH. Screening for cognition and behaviour changes in ALS. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2014;15:9-14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye S, Ji Y, Li C, He J, Liu X, Fan D. The Edinburgh cognitive and behavioural ALS screen in a Chinese amyotrophic lateral sclerosis population. PLoS One. 2016;11:e0155496.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceccanti M, Pozzilli V, Cambieri C, et al. Creatine kinase and progression rate in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Cell. 2020;9:1174.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang Y, Liao G, Li J, et al. FDG-PET profiles of extratemporal metabolism as a predictor of surgical failure in temporal lobe epilepsy. Front Med (Lausanne). 2020;7:605002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H, Wu P, Ziegler SI, et al. Data-driven identification of intensity normalization region based on longitudinal coherency of (18)F-FDG metabolism in the healthy brain. Neuroimage. 2017;146:589-599.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Gonzalez FJ, Silva-Rodriguez J, Paredes-Pacheco J, et al. Intensity normalization methods in brain FDG-PET quantification. Neuroimage. 2020;222:117229.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finnema SJ, Toyonaga T, Detyniecki K, et al. Reduced synaptic vesicle protein 2A binding in temporal lobe epilepsy: a [(11) C]UCB-J positron emission tomography study. Epilepsia. 2020;61:2183-2193.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mecca AP, Chen MK, O'Dell RS, et al. In vivo measurement of widespread synaptic loss in Alzheimer's disease with SV2A PET. Alzheimers Dement. 2020;16:974-982.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holland N, Jones PS, Savulich G, et al. Synaptic loss in primary tauopathies revealed by [(11) C]UCB-J positron emission tomography. Mov Disord. 2020;35:1834-1842.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canosa A, Pagani M, Cistaro A, et al. 18F-FDG-PET correlates of cognitive impairment in ALS. Neurology. 2016;86:44-49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeong Y, Park KC, Cho SS, et al. Pattern of glucose hypometabolism in frontotemporal dementia with motor neuron disease. Neurology. 2005;64:734-736.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mioshi E, Lillo P, Yew B, et al. Cortical atrophy in ALS is critically associated with neuropsychiatric and cognitive changes. Neurology. 2013;80:1117-1123.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cistaro A, Valentini MC, Chio A, et al. Brain hypermetabolism in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a FDG PET study in ALS of spinal and bulbar onset. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging. 2012;39:251-259.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pagani M, Chio A, Valentini MC, et al. Functional pattern of brain FDG-PET in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology. 2014;83:1067-1074.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bede P, Elamin M, Byrne S, et al. Basal ganglia involvement in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology. 2013;81:2107-2115.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brettschneider J, Libon DJ, Toledo JB, et al. Microglial activation and TDP-43 pathology correlate with executive dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathol. 2012;123:395-407.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takeda T, Uchihara T, Arai N, Mizutani T, Iwata M. Progression of hippocampal degeneration in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with or without memory impairment: distinction from Alzheimer disease. Acta Neuropathol. 2009;117:35-44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phukan J, Elamin M, Bede P, et al. The syndrome of cognitive impairment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a population-based study. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2012;83:102-108.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yokoi S, Udagawa T, Fujioka Y, et al. 3'UTR length-dependent control of SynGAP isoform &#x3b1;2 mRNA by FUS and ELAV-like proteins promotes dendritic spine maturation and cognitive function. Cell Rep. 2017;20:3071-3084.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdulla S, Machts J, Kaufmann J, et al. Hippocampal degeneration in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurobiol Aging. 2014;35:2639-2645.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner MR, Rabiner EA, Hammers A, et al. [11C]-WAY100635 PET demonstrates marked 5-HT1A receptor changes in sporadic ALS. Brain. 2005;128:896-905.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chou SM, Norris FH. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: lower motor neuron disease spreading to upper motor neurons. Muscle Nerve. 1993;16:864-869.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sala A, Iaccarino L, Fania P, et al. Testing the diagnostic accuracy of [18F]FDG-PET in discriminating spinal- and bulbar-onset amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging. 2019;46:1117-1131.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>