<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35759769</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>22</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1532-3145</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>46</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><MedlineDate>2022 Nov-Dec 01</MedlineDate></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of computer assisted tomography</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Comput Assist Tomogr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Cauda Equina Atrophy in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis on Routine Lumbar Magnetic Resonance Imaging.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>991</StartPage><EndPage>996</EndPage><MedlinePgn>991-996</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/RCT.0000000000001349</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The aim of the study was to evaluate the cross-sectional area of the cauda equina in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) on routine lumbar magnetic resonance imaging and investigate the diagnostic accuracy in comparison with age- and sex-matched non-ALS controls.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This retrospective study included 15 ALS patients and 15 age- and sex-matched non-ALS controls. Two independent neuroradiologists measured and compared the total cross-sectional area of the cauda equina of ALS patients and the non-ALS controls at the level of the L3 and L4 using axial T2-weighted images. The cutoff value, sensitivity, specificity, and area under the curve were measured. The interobserver reproducibility of the 2 independently obtained measurements was evaluated.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The total cross-sectional area of the cauda equina in the ALS group was significantly smaller than that in the non-ALS group (L3: median, 66.73 vs 90.19 mm 2 , P &lt; 0.001; L4: median, 52.9 vs 67.63 mm 2 , P &lt; 0.001). The cutoff values at L3 and L4 were 76.95 and 61.04 mm 2 with a sensitivity and specificity of 1 and 0.87 and 0.8 and 0.87, respectively. The area under the curve at L3 and L4 were high at 0.96 and 0.94, respectively. The interobserver reproducibility was 0.88 at L3 and 0.89 at L4.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The ALS patients showed significant atrophy of the cauda equina compared with non-ALS patients.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Matsushima</LastName><ForeName>Satoshi</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9940-5205</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Departments of Radiology.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Omoto</LastName><ForeName>Shusaku</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurology, The Jikei University School of Medicine, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shimizu</LastName><ForeName>Tetsuya</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Departments of Radiology.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Baba</LastName><ForeName>Akira</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Departments of Radiology.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ojiri</LastName><ForeName>Hiroya</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Departments of Radiology.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Comput Assist Tomogr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7703942</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0363-8715</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002420" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cauda Equina</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015203" MajorTopicYN="N">Reproducibility of Results</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008279" MajorTopicYN="N">Magnetic Resonance Imaging</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001284" MajorTopicYN="N">Atrophy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35759769</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/RCT.0000000000001349</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00004728-990000000-00057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Geevasinga N, Menon P, Scherman DB, et al. Diagnostic criteria in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a multicenter prospective study. Neurology . 2016;87:684&#x2013;690.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnsen B, Pugdahl K, Fuglsang-Frederiksen A, et al. Diagnostic criteria for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a multicentre study of inter-rater variation and sensitivity. Clin Neurophysiol . 2019;130:307&#x2013;314.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner MR, Grosskreutz J, Kassubek J, et al. Towards a neuroimaging biomarker for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet Neurol . 2011;10:400&#x2013;403.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filippi M, Agosta F, Grosskreutz J, et al. Progress towards a neuroimaging biomarker for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet Neurol . 2015;14:786&#x2013;788.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheung G, Gawel MJ, Cooper PW, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: correlation of clinical and MR imaging findings. Radiology . 1995;194:263&#x2013;270.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L, Ulug AM, Zimmerman RD, et al. The diagnostic utility of FLAIR imaging in clinically verified amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Magn Reson Imaging . 2003;17:521&#x2013;527.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adachi Y, Sato N, Saito Y, et al. Usefulness of SWI for the detection of iron in the motor cortex in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neuroimaging . 2015;25:443&#x2013;451.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakamura-Shindo K, Sakai K, Shimizu A, et al. Accumulation of phosphorylated TDP-43 in the cytoplasm of Schwann cells in a case of sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuropathology . 2020;40:606&#x2013;610.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young NP, Laughlin RS, Sorenson EJ. Gadolinium enhancement of the lumbar roots in a case of ALS. Amyotroph Lateral Scler . 2010;11:207&#x2013;209.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luigetti M, Cianfoni A, Conte A, et al. Gadolinium enhancement of the lumbar leptomeninges and roots in a case of ALS. Amyotroph Lateral Scler . 2010;11:412&#x2013;413.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyata M, Kakeda S, Hashimoto T, et al. Facial nerve atrophy in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: evaluation with fast imaging employing steady-state acquisition (FIESTA). J Magn Reson Imaging . 2020;51:757&#x2013;766.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerevini S, Agosta F, Riva N, et al. MR imaging of brachial plexus and limb-girdle muscles in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Radiology . 2016;279:553&#x2013;561.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Staff NP, Amrami KK, Howe BM. Magnetic resonance imaging abnormalities of peripheral nerve and muscle are common in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and share features with multifocal motor neuropathy. Muscle Nerve . 2015;52:137&#x2013;139.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kronlage M, Knop KC, Schwarz D, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis versus multifocal motor neuropathy: utility of MR neurography. Radiology . 2019;292:149&#x2013;156.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nodera H, Takamatsu N, Shimatani Y, et al. Thinning of cervical nerve roots and peripheral nerves in ALS as measured by sonography. Clin Neurophysiol . 2014;125:1906&#x2013;1911.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schreiber S, Abdulla S, Debska-Vielhaber G, et al. Peripheral nerve ultrasound in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis phenotypes. Muscle Nerve . 2015;51:669&#x2013;675.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cowin GJ, Butler TJ, Kurniawan ND, et al. Magnetic resonance microimaging of the spinal cord in the SOD1 mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis detects motor nerve root degeneration. Neuroimage . 2011;58:69&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans MC, Couch Y, Sibson N, et al. Inflammation and neurovascular changes in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Mol Cell Neurosci . 2013;53:34&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>