<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35760064</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>19</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1421-9972</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>75</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Folia phoniatrica et logopaedica : official organ of the International Association of Logopedics and Phoniatrics (IALP)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Folia Phoniatr Logop</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Tongue and Lip Acceleration as a Measure of Speech Decline in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>23</StartPage><EndPage>34</EndPage><MedlinePgn>23-34</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1159/000525514</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE">The goal of this study was to examine the efficacy of acceleration-based articulatory measures in characterizing the decline in speech motor control due to amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHOD">Electromagnetic articulography was used to record tongue and lip movements during the production of 20 phrases. Data were collected from 50 individuals diagnosed with ALS. Articulatory kinematic variability was measured using the spatiotemporal index of both instantaneous acceleration and speed signals. Linear regression models were used to analyze the relationship between variability measures and intelligible speaking rate (a clinical measure of disease progression). A machine learning algorithm (support vector regression, SVR) was used to assess whether acceleration or speed features (e.g., mean, median, maximum) showed better performance at predicting speech severity in patients with ALS.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">As intelligible speaking rate declined, the variability of acceleration of tongue and lip movement patterns significantly increased (p &lt; 0.001). The variability of speed and vertical displacement did not significantly predict speech performance measures. Additionally, based on R2 and root mean square error (RMSE) values, the SVR model was able to predict speech severity more accurately from acceleration features (R2 = 0.601, RMSE = 38.453) and displacement features (R2 = 0.218, RMSE = 52.700) than from speed features (R2 = 0.554, RMSE = 40.772).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">Results from these models highlight differences in speech motor control in participants with ALS. The variability in acceleration of tongue and lip movements increases as speech performance declines, potentially reflecting physiological deviations due to the progression of ALS. Our findings suggest that acceleration is a more sensitive indicator of speech deterioration due to ALS than displacement and speed and may contribute to improved algorithm designs for monitoring disease progression from speech signals.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022 S. Karger AG, Basel.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Teplansky</LastName><ForeName>Kristin J</ForeName><Initials>KJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Speech, Language, and Hearing Sciences, University of Texas, Austin, Texas, USA, kristin.teplansky@austin.utexas.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wisler</LastName><ForeName>Alan</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mathematics and Statistics, Utah State University, Logan, Utah, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Green</LastName><ForeName>Jordan R</ForeName><Initials>JR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Communication Sciences and Disorders, MGH Institute of Health Professions, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Speech and Hearing Bioscience and Technology Program, Harvard University, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Campbell</LastName><ForeName>Thomas</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Callier Center for Communication Disorders, University of Texas at Dallas, Dallas, Texas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Heitzman</LastName><ForeName>Daragh</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MDA/ALS Clinic, Texas Neurology, Dallas, Texas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Austin</LastName><ForeName>Sara G</ForeName><Initials>SG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurology, Dell Medical School, University of Texas, Austin, Texas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Jun</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Speech, Language, and Hearing Sciences, University of Texas, Austin, Texas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurology, Dell Medical School, University of Texas, Austin, Texas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R01 DC013547</GrantID><Acronym>DC</Acronym><Agency>NIDCD NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01 DC016621</GrantID><Acronym>DC</Acronym><Agency>NIDCD NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R03 DC013990</GrantID><Acronym>DC</Acronym><Agency>NIDCD NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Folia Phoniatr Logop</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9422792</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1021-7762</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013060" MajorTopicYN="Y">Speech</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008046" MajorTopicYN="N">Lip</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007568" MajorTopicYN="N">Jaw</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013068" MajorTopicYN="N">Speech Production Measurement</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014059" MajorTopicYN="N">Tongue</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001696" MajorTopicYN="N">Biomechanical Phenomena</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018450" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Progression</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013065" MajorTopicYN="N">Speech Intelligibility</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dysarthria</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Speech kinematics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Speech motor control</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Support vector machine</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict of Interest Statement. The authors have no conflicts of interest to declare.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35760064</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS1822195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9792632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000525514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">000525514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Kiernan MC, Vucic S, Cheah BC, Turner MR, Eisen A, Hardiman O, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. The Lancet. 2011. Mar;377(9769):942&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21296405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green JR, Yunusova Y, Kuruvilla MS, Wang J, Pattee GL, Synhorst L, et al. Bulbar and speech motor assessment in ALS: Challenges and future directions. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis and Frontotemporal Degeneration. 2013;14(7&#x2013;8):494&#x2013;500.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3833808</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23898888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meininger V Getting the diagnosis right: beyond El Escorial. Journal of Neurology. 1999;246(S3):III10&#x2013;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10631654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Kothalkar PV, Cao B, Heitzman D. Towards automatic detection of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis from speech acoustic and articulatory samples. In: Interspeech. 2016. p. 1195&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Kothalkar PV, Kim M, Yunusova Y, Campbell TF, Heitzman D, et al. Predicting intelligible speaking rate of individuals with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis from a small number of speech acoustic and articulatory samples. Workshop Speech Language Processing Assistive Technology. 2016;91&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5800530</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29423454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wisler A, Teplansky K, Green J, Yunusova Y, Campbell T, Heitzman D, et al. Speech-based estimation of bulbar progression in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. In: Proceedings of the Eighth Workshop on Speech and Language Processing for Assistive Technologies. Minneapolis: Association for Computational Linguistics; 2019. p. 24&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Es MA, Hardiman O, Chio A, Al-Chalabi A, Pasterkamp RJ, Veldink JH, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. The Lancet. 2017;390(10107):2084&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28552366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matharan M, Mathis S, Bonabaud S, Carla L, Soulages A, Le Masson G. Minimizing the diagnostic delay in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: The role of nonneurologist practitioners. Neurology Research International. 2020. May 11;2020:1&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7238340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32455015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner MR, Scaber J, Goodfellow JA, Lord ME, Marsden R, Talbot K. The diagnostic pathway and prognosis in bulbar-onset amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Journal of the Neurological Sciences. 2010;294(1&#x2013;2):81&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20452624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum JM, Stambler N, Malta E, Fuller C, Hilt D, Thurmond B, et al. The ALSFRS-R: a revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. Journal of the Neurological Sciences. 1999. Oct;169(1&#x2013;2):13&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10540002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yorkston KM, Beukelman DR. Communication efficiency of dysarthric speakers as measured by sentence intelligibility and speaking rate. Journal of Speech and Hearing Disorders. 1981;46(3):296&#x2013;301.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7278175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenfield DB, Viswanath N, Herbrich KE, Nudelman HB. Evaluation of the speech motor control system in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Journal of Voice. 1991. Jan;5(3):224&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allison KM, Yunusova Y, Campbell TF, Wang J, Berry JD, Green JR. The diagnostic utility of patient-report and speech-language pathologists&#x2019; ratings for detecting the early onset of bulbar symptoms due to ALS. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis and Frontotemporal Degeneration. 2017. Jul 3;18(5&#x2013;6):358&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5530595</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28355886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yunusova Y, Weismer G, Westbury JR, Lindstrom MJ. Articulatory movements during vowels in speakers with dysarthria and healthy controls. Journal of Speech, Language, and Hearing Research. 2008. Jun;51(3):596&#x2013;611.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18506038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langmore SE, Lehman ME. Physiologic deficits in the orofacial system underlying dysarthria in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Journal of Speech, Language, and Hearing Research. 1994. Feb;37(1):28&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8170127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shellikeri S, Green JR, Kulkarni M, Rong P, Martino R, Zinman L, et al. Speech movement measures as markers of bulbar disease in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Journal of Speech, Language, and Hearing Research. 2016. Oct;59(5):887&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5345561</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27679842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mefferd AS, Green JR, Pattee G. A novel fixed-target task to determine articulatory speed constraints in persons with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Journal of Communication Disorders. 2012;45(1):35&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3251716</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22000045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuruvilla-Dugdale M, Chuquilin-Arista M. An investigation of clear speech effects on articulatory kinematics in talkers with ALS. Clinical Linguistics &amp; Phonetics. 2017. Oct 3;31(10):725&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28494172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuruvilla-Dugdale M, Mefferd A. Spatiotemporal movement variability in ALS: Speaking rate effects on tongue, lower lip, and jaw motor control. Journal of Communication Disorders. 2017. May;67(May):22&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5514846</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28528293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mefferd AS, Pattee GL, Green JR. Speaking rate effects on articulatory pattern consistency in talkers with mild ALS. Clinical Linguistics &amp; Phonetics. 2014. Nov 11;28(11):799&#x2013;811.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4675322</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24724615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith A, Kleinow J. Kinematic correlates of speaking rate changes in stuttering and normally fluent adults. Journal of Speech, Language, and Hearing Research. 2000. Apr;43(2):521&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10757701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith A, Goffman L, Zelaznik Howard N, Ying G, McGillem C. Spatiotemporal stability and patterning of speech movement sequences. Experimental Brain Research. 1995. Jun;104(3):493&#x2013;501.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7589300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mefferd AS. Associations between tongue movement pattern consistency and formant movement pattern consistency in response to speech behavioral modifications. The Journal of the Acoustical Society of America. 2016;140(5):3728&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5392073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27908069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith A, Johnson M, McGillem C, Goffman L. On the assessment of stability and patterning of speech movements. Journal of Speech, Language, and Hearing Research. 2000. Feb;43(1):277&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10668669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McHenry MA. The effect of pacing strategies on the variability of speech movement sequences in dysarthria. Journal of Speech, Language, and Hearing Research. 2003;46(3):702&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14696996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finsterer J, Fuglsang-Frederiksen A, Mamoli B. Needle EMG of the tongue: motor unit action potential versus peak ratio analysis in limb and bulbar onset amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Journal of Neurology, Neurosurgery &amp; Psychiatry. 1997. Aug 1;63(2):175&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2169683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9285455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cha CH, Patten BM. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Abnormalities of the tongue on magnetic resonance imaging. Annals of Neurology. 1989. May;25(5):468&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2774487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DePaul R, Abbs JH, Caligiuri M, Gracco VL, Brooks BR. Hypoglossal, trigeminal, and facial motoneuron involvement in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology. 1988. Feb 1;38(2):281&#x2013;281.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3340294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DePaul R, Brooks BR. Multiple orofacial indices in ayotrophic lateral sclerosis. Journal of Speech, Language, and Hearing Research. 1993. Dec;36(6):1158&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8114482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weikamp JG, Schelhaas HJ, Hendriks JCM, de Swart BJM, Geurts ACH. Prognostic value of decreased tongue strength on survival time in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Journal of Neurology. 2012. Nov 24;259(11):2360&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3484270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22527240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shellikeri S, Yunusova Y, Green JR, Pattee GL, Berry JD, Rutkove SB, et al. Electrical impedance myography in the evaluation of the tongue musculature in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle &amp; Nerve. 2015. Oct;52(4):584&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4499330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25580728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pizzorni N, Ginocchio D, Bianchi F, Feroldi S, Vedrodyova M, Mora G, et al. Association between maximum tongue pressure and swallowing safety and efficacy in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurogastroenterology &amp; Motility. 2020. Aug 26;32(8):1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32337820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newton I Isaac Newton&#x2019;s philosophiae naturalis principia mathematica. 3rd ed. Koyr&#xe9; A, Cohen IB, editors. Cambridge, Mass: Harvard University Press; 1726.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nelson WL, Perkell JS, Westbury JR. Mandible movements during increasingly rapid articulations of single syllables: Preliminary observations. J Acoust Soc Am. 1984. Mar;75(3):945&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6707325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nelson WL. Physical principles for economies of skilled movements. Biol Cybern. 1983. Feb;46(2):135&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6838914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bandini A, Green JR, Wang J, Campbell TF, Zinman L, Yunusova Y. Kinematic features of jaw and lips distinguish symptomatic from presymptomatic stages of bulbar decline in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Journal of Speech, Language, and Hearing Research. 2018. May 17;61(5):1118&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6195078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29800359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bandini A, Green JR, Zinman L, Yunusova Y. Classification of bulbar ALS from kinematic features of the jaw and lips: Towards computer-mediated assessment. In: Interspeech 2017. ISCA: ISCA; 2017. p. 1819&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>An K, Kim M, Teplansky K, Green J, Campbell T, Yunusova Y, et al. Automatic early detection of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis from intelligible speech using convolutional neural networks. In: Interspeech 2018. ISCA: ISCA; 2018. p. 1913&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cummins N, Scherer S, Krajewski J, Schnieder S, Epps J, Quatieri TF. A review of depression and suicide risk assessment using speech analysis. Speech Communication. 2015. Jul;71:10&#x2013;49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quatieri TF, Malyska N. Vocal-source biomarkers for depression: A link to psychomotor activity. In: Interspeech. 2012. p. 1058&#x2013;61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Camilo V&#xe1;squez Correa J, Rafael Orozdco Arroyave J, David Arias-Londo&#xf1;o J, Francisco Vargas Bonilla J, N&#xf6;th E. New computer aided device for real time analysis of speech of people with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Revista Facultad De Ingenieria-universidad De Antioquia. 2014;72:87&#x2013;103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Falcone M, Yadav N, Poellabauer C, Flynn P. Using isolated vowel sounds for classification of mild traumatic brain injury. In: 2013 IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech and Signal Processing. IEEE; 2013. p. 7577&#x2013;81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hahm S, Wang J. Parkinson&#x2019;s condition estimation using speech acoustic and inversely mapped articulatory data. In: Interspeech. 2015. p. 513&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsanas A, Little MA, McSharry PE, Spielman J, Ramig LO. Novel speech signal processing algorithms for high-accuracy classification of Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. IEEE Transactions on Biomedical Engineering. 2012. May;59(5):1264&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22249592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yorkston KM, Beukelman DR, Hakel M, Dorsey M. Sentence intelligibility test for windows. Lincoln, NE; 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stipancic KL, Palmer KM, Rowe HP, Yunusova Y, Berry JD, Green JR. &#x201c;You say severe, I say mild&#x201d;: Toward an empirical classification of dysarthria severity. J Speech Lang Hear Res. 2021. Dec 13;64(12):4718&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9150682</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34762814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berry JJ. Accuracy of the NDI wave speech research system. Journal of Speech, Language, and Hearing Research. 2011;54:1295&#x2013;301.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21498575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Samal A, Rong P, Green JR. An optimal set of flesh points on tongue and lips for speech-movement classification. J Speech Lang Hear Res. 2016. Feb;59(1):15&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4867928</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26564030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green JR, Wang J, Wilson DL. SMASH&#x202f;: A tool for articulatory data processing and analysis. In: Interspeech. Lyon; 2013. p. 1331&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cortes C, Vapnik V. Support-vector networks. Machine Learning. 1995;20:273&#x2013;97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basak D, Pal S, Patranabis DC. Support Vector Regression. Neural Information Processing. 2007;11(10):203&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Witten IH, Frank E, Hall MA. Data mining: practical machine learning tools and techniques. 3rd ed. Burlington, MA: Morgan Kaufmann; 2011. 629 p. (Morgan Kaufmann series in data management systems).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gardner J, Brooks C. Statistical approaches to the model comparison task in learning analytics. :14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kleinow J, Smith A, Ramig LO. Speech Motor Stability in IPD. Journal of Speech, Language, and Hearing Research. 2001. Oct;44(5):1041&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11708525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chu SY, Barlow SM, Lee J, Wang J. Effects of utterance rate and length on the spatiotemporal index in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. International Journal of Speech-Language Pathology. 2020;22(2):141&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31213093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Kothalkar PV, Kim M, Bandini A, Cao B, Yunusova Y, et al. Automatic prediction of intelligible speaking rate for individuals with ALS from speech acoustic and articulatory samples. International Journal of Speech-Language Pathology. 2018. Oct 16;20(6):669&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6506394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30409057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eshghi M, Stipancic KL, Mefferd A, Rong P, Berry JD, Yunusova Y, et al. Assessing oromotor capacity in ALS: The effect of a fixed-target task on lip biomechanics. Front Neurol. 2019. Dec 5;10:1288.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6906194</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31866935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wisler A, Goffman L, Zhang L, Wang J. Influences of methodological decisions on assessing the spatiotemporal stability of speech movement sequences. J Speech Lang Hear Res. 2022. Feb 9;65(2):538&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9132147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35077649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kleinow J, Smith A, Ramig LO. Speech motor stability in IPD: Effects of rate and loudness manipulations. J Speech Lang Hear Res. 2001. Oct;44(5):1041&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11708525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green JR, Moore CA, Reilly KJ. The sequential development of jaw and lip control for speech. J Speech Lang Hear Res. 2002. Feb;45(1):66&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2890215</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14748639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith A, Goffman L, Zelaznik HN, Ying G, McGillem C. Spatiotemporal stability and patterning of speech movement sequences. Exp Brain Res [Internet]. 1995. Jun [cited 2021 Oct 12];104(3). Available from: 10.1007/BF00231983</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF00231983</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7589300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hausdorff JM, Lertratanakul A, Cudkowicz ME, Peterson AL, Kaliton D, Goldberger ALRYL, et al. Dynamic markers of altered gait rhythm in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Journal of Applied Physiology. 2000;88(6):2045&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10846017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jette DU, Slavin MD, Andres PL, Munsat TL. The relationship of lower-limb muscle force to walking ability in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Physical Therapy. 1999. Jul 1;79(7):672&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10416576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Netsell R, Daniel B, Celesia GG. Acceleration and weakness in parkinsonian dysarthria. Journal of Speech and Hearing Disorders. 1975;40(2):170&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">189132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wisler A, Teplansky K, Green JR, Austin SG, Wang J. Can machines learn continuous measures of speech severity from ordinal training labels? In: 33rd International Conference of the Florida Artifcial Intelligence Research Society (FLAIRS). 2020. p. 550&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>