<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35770772</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>01</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1555-3892</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>31</Volume><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Season>Jan-Dec</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cell transplantation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cell Transplant</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Therapeutic Potential of Astrocyte Transplantation.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>9636897221105499</StartPage><MedlinePgn>9636897221105499</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">09636897221105499</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/09636897221105499</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Cell transplantation is an attractive treatment strategy for a variety of brain disorders, as it promises to replenish lost functions and rejuvenate the brain. In particular, transplantation of astrocytes has come into light recently as a therapy for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS); moreover, grafting of astrocytes also showed positive results in models of other conditions ranging from neurodegenerative diseases of older age to traumatic injury and stroke. Despite clear differences in etiology, disorders such as ALS, Parkinson's, Alzheimer's, and Huntington's diseases, as well as traumatic injury and stroke, converge on a number of underlying astrocytic abnormalities, which include inflammatory changes, mitochondrial damage, calcium signaling disturbance, hemichannel opening, and loss of glutamate transporters. In this review, we examine these convergent pathways leading to astrocyte dysfunction, and explore the existing evidence for a therapeutic potential of transplantation of healthy astrocytes in various models. Existing literature presents a wide variety of methods to generate astrocytes, or relevant precursor cells, for subsequent transplantation, while described outcomes of this type of treatment also differ between studies. We take technical differences between methodologies into account to understand the variability of therapeutic benefits, or lack thereof, at a deeper level. We conclude by discussing some key requirements of an astrocyte graft that would be most suitable for clinical applications.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hastings</LastName><ForeName>Nataly</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5376-339X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Neurosciences, University of Cambridge, Cambridge, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wellcome-MRC Cambridge Stem Cell Institute, University of Cambridge, Cambridge, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kuan</LastName><ForeName>Wei-Li</ForeName><Initials>WL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Neurosciences, University of Cambridge, Cambridge, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Osborne</LastName><ForeName>Andrew</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Neurosciences, University of Cambridge, Cambridge, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kotter</LastName><ForeName>Mark R N</ForeName><Initials>MRN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Neurosciences, University of Cambridge, Cambridge, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wellcome-MRC Cambridge Stem Cell Institute, University of Cambridge, Cambridge, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>MR/S005528/1</GrantID><Acronym>MRC_</Acronym><Agency>Medical Research Council</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>CS-2015-15-023</GrantID><Acronym>DH_</Acronym><Agency>Department of Health</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cell Transplant</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9208854</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0963-6897</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001253" MajorTopicYN="N">Astrocytes</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006816" MajorTopicYN="Y">Huntington Disease</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019636" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neurodegenerative Diseases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020521" MajorTopicYN="Y">Stroke</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">astrocyte</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">brain</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">injury</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neurodegeneration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">spinal cord</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">transplantation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement><b>Declaration of Conflicting Interests:</b> The author(s) declared no potential conflicts of interest with respect to the research, authorship, and/or publication of this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35770772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9251977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/09636897221105499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Freed CR, Greene PE, Breeze RE, Tsai WY, DuMouchel W, Kao R, Dillon S, Winfield H, Culver S, Trojanowski JQ, Eidelberg D, et al.. Transplantation of embryonic dopamine neurons for severe Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. N Engl J Med. 2001;344(10):710&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11236774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wernig M, Zhao J-P, Pruszak J, Hedlund E, Fu D, Soldner F, Broccoli V, Constantine-Paton M, Isacson O, Jaenisch R. Neurons derived from reprogrammed fibroblasts functionally integrate into the fetal brain and improve symptoms of rats with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Proc Natl Acad Sci. 2008;105(15): 5856&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2311361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18391196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barker RA, Barrett J, Mason SL, Bj&#xf6;rklund A. Fetal dopaminergic transplantation trials and the future of neural grafting in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Lancet Neurol. 2013;12(1):85&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23237903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans JR, Mason SL, Barker RA. Current status of clinical trials of neural transplantation in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Prog Brain Res. 2012;200:169&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23195419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barker R, Drouin-Ouellet J, Parmar M. Cell-based therapies for Parkinson disease-past insights and future potential. Nat Rev Neurol. 2015;11(9):492&#x2013;503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26240036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu L, Yan J, Chen D, Welsh AM, Hazel T, Johe K, Hatfield G, Koliatsos VE. Human neural stem cell grafts ameliorate motor neuron disease in SOD-1 transgenic rats. Transplantation. 2006;82(7):865&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17038899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu L, Ryugo DK, Pongstaporn T, Johe K, Koliatsos VE. Human neural stem cell grafts in the spinal cord of SOD1 transgenic rats: differentiation and structural integration into the segmental motor circuitry. J Comp Neurol. 2009;514(4):297&#x2013;309.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2727711</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19326469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goul&#xe3;o M, Ghosh B, Urban MW, Sahu M, Mercogliano C, Charsar BA, Komaravolu S, Block CG, Smith GM, Wright MC, Lepore AC. Astrocyte progenitor transplantation promotes regeneration of bulbospinal respiratory axons, recovery of diaphragm function, and a reduced macrophage response following cervical spinal cord injury. Glia. 2019;67(3):452&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6355351</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30548313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Southwell DG, Froemke RC, Alvarez-Buylla A, Stryker MP, Gandhi SP. Cortical plasticity induced by inhibitory neuron transplantation. Science. 2010;327(5969):1145&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3164148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20185728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis MF, Figueroa Velez DX, Guevarra RP, Yang MC, Habeeb M, Carathedathu MC, Gandhi SP. Inhibitory neuron transplantation into adult visual cortex creates a new critical period that rescues impaired vision. Neuron. 2015;86(4):1055&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4441572</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25937171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Curtis E, Martin JR, Gabel B, Sidhu N, Rzesiewicz TK, Mandeville R, Van Gorp S, Leerink M, Tadokoro T, Marsala S, Jamieson C, et al.. A first-in-human, phase I study of neural stem cell transplantation for chronic spinal cord injury. Cell Stem Cell. 2018;22(6):941&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29859175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhasin A, Srivastava MV, Mohanty S, Bhatia R, Kumaran SS, Bose S. Stem cell therapy: a clinical trial of stroke. Clin Neurol Neurosurg. 2013;115(7):1003&#x2013;1008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23183251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barker RA, Parmar M, Kirkeby A, Bj&#xf6;rklund A, Thompson L, Brundin P. Are stem cell-based therapies for Parkinson&#x2019;s disease ready for the clinic in 2016? J Parkinsons Dis. 2016;6(1):57&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4927930</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27003785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez R, Garitaonandia I, Crain A, Poustovoitov M, Abramihina T, Noskov A, Jiang C, Morey R, Laurent LC, Elsworth JD, Snyder EY, et al.. Proof of concept studies exploring the safety and functional activity of human parthenogenetic-derived neural stem cells for the treatment of Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Cell Transplant. 2015;24(4):681&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25839189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guan Y, Zou H, Chen X, Zhao C, Wang J, Cai Y, Chan P, Chen L, Zhang YA. Ischemia, immunosuppression, and SSEA-1-negative cells all contribute to tumors resulting from mouse embryonic stem cell-derived neural progenitor transplantation. J Neurosci Res. 2014;92(1):74&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24123213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pustavoitau A, Bhardwaj A, Stevens R. Neurological complications of transplantation. J Intensive Care Med. 2011;26(4): 209&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21764765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuga N, Sasaki T, Takahara Y, Matsuki N, Ikegaya Y. Large-scale calcium waves traveling through astrocytic networks in vivo. J Neurosci. 2011;31(7):2607&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6623677</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21325528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winship IR, Plaa N, Murphy TH. Rapid astrocyte calcium signals correlate with neuronal activity and onset of the hemodynamic response in vivo. J Neurosci. 2007;27(23):6268&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6672142</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17554000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szab&#xf3; Z, H&#xe9;ja L, Szalay G, K&#xe9;kesi O, F&#xfc;redi A, Szeb&#xe9;nyi K, Dobolyi &#xc1;, Orb&#xe1;n TI, Kolacsek O, Tompa T, Miskolczy Z, et al.. Extensive astrocyte synchronization advances neuronal coupling in slow wave activity in vivo. Sci Rep. 2017;7(1): 6018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5519671</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28729692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henneberger C, Papouin T, Oliet SHR, Rusakov DA. Long-term potentiation depends on release of d-serine from astrocytes. Nature. 2010;463(7278):232&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2807667</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20075918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dall&#xe9;rac G, Chever O, Rouach N. How do astrocytes shape synaptic transmission? Insights from electrophysiology. Front Cell Neurosci. 2013;7:159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3787198</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24101894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lutz SE, Zhao Y, Gulinello M, Lee SC, Raine CS, Brosnan CF. Deletion of astrocyte connexins 43 and 30 leads to a dysmyelinating phenotype and hippocampal CA1 vacuolation. J Neurosci. 2009;29(24):7743&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2737812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19535586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dutta DJ, Woo DH, Lee PR, Pajevic S, Bukalo O, Huffman WC, Wake H, Basser PJ, SheikhBahaei S, Lazarevic V, Smith JC, et al.. Regulation of myelin structure and conduction velocity by perinodal astrocytes. Proc Natl Acad Sci. 2018; 115(46):11832&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6243273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30373833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bohlen CJ, Bennett FC, Tucker AF, Collins HY, Mulinyawe SB, Barres BA. Diverse requirements for microglial survival, specification, and function revealed by defined-medium cultures. Neuron. 2017;94(4):759&#x2013;773.e8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5523817</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28521131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bozoyan L, Khlghatyan J, Saghatelyan A. Astrocytes control the development of the migration-promoting vasculature scaffold in the postnatal brain via VEGF signaling. J Neurosci. 2012;32(5):1687&#x2013;704.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6703370</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22302810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oberheim NA, Takano T, Han X, He W, Lin JHC, Wang F, Xu Q, Wyatt JD, Pilcher W, Ojemann JG, Ransom BR, et al.. Uniquely hominid features of adult human astrocytes. J Neurosci. 2009;29(10):3276&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2819812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19279265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oberheim NA, Wang X, Goldman S, Nedergaard M. Astrocytic complexity distinguishes the human brain. Trends Neurosci. 2006;29(10):547&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16938356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michelucci A, Bithell A, Burney MJ, Johnston CE, Wong KY, Teng SW, Desai J, Gumbleton N, Anderson G, Stanton LW, Williams BP, et al.. The neurogenic potential of astrocytes is regulated by inflammatory signals. Mol Neurobiol. 2016;53(6):3724&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4937102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26138449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zamboni M, Llorens-Bobadilla E, Magnusson JP, Fris&#xe9;n J. A Widespread neurogenic potential of neocortical astrocytes is induced by injury. Cell Stem Cell. 2020;27(4):605&#x2013;17.e5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7534841</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32758425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russo FB, Freitas BC, Pignatari GC, Fernandes IR, Sebat J, Muotri AR, Beltr&#xe3;o-Braga PCB. Modeling the interplay between neurons and astrocytes in autism using human induced pluripotent stem cells. Biol Psychiatry. 2018;83(7):569&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29129319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mizuno GO, Wang Y, Shi G, Wang Y, Sun J, Papadopoulos S, Broussard GJ, Unger EK, Deng W, Weick J, Bhattacharyya A, et al.. Aberrant calcium signaling in astrocytes inhibits neuronal excitability in a human down syndrome stem cell model. Cell Rep. 2018;24(2):355&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6631348</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29996097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skripuletz T, Hackstette D, Bauer K, Gudi V, Pul R, Voss E, Berger K, Kipp M, Baumg&#xe4;rtner W, Stangel M. Astrocytes regulate myelin clearance through recruitment of microglia during cuprizone-induced demyelination. Brain. 2013;136(1):147&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23266461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Correale J, Farez MF. The role of astrocytes in multiple sclerosis progression. Front Neurol. 2015;6:180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4539519</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26347709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams MR, Hampton T, Pearce RKB, Hirsch SR, Ansorge O, Thom M, Maier M. Astrocyte decrease in the subgenual cingulate and callosal genu in schizophrenia. Eur Arch Psychiatry Clin Neurosci. 2013;263(1):41&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22660922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim R, Healey KL, Sepulveda-Orengo MT, Reissner KJ. Astroglial correlates of neuropsychiatric disease: from astrocytopathy to astrogliosis. Prog Neuro-Psychopharmacology Biol Psychiatry. 2018;87(Pt A):126&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5889368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28989099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>David J, Gormley S, McIntosh AL, Kebede V, Thuery G, Varidaki A, Coffey ET, Harkin A. L-alpha-amino adipic acid provokes depression-like behaviour and a stress related increase in dendritic spine density in the pre-limbic cortex and hippocampus in rodents. Behav Brain Res. 2019;362:90&#x2013;102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30639510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eti&#xe9;vant A, Oosterhof C, B&#xe9;try C, Abrial E, Novo-Perez M, Rovera R, Scarna H, Devader C, Mazella J, Wegener G, S&#xe1;nchez C, et al.. Astroglial control of the antidepressant-like effects of prefrontal cortex deep brain stimulation. EBioMedicine. 2015;2(8):898&#x2013;908.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4563138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26425697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lima A, Sardinha VM, Oliveira AF, Reis M, Mota C, Silva MA, Marques F, Cerqueira JJ, Pinto L, Sousa N, Oliveira JF. Astrocyte pathology in the prefrontal cortex impairs the cognitive function of rats. Mol Psychiatry. 2014;19(7):834&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24419043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui W, Allen ND, Skynner M, Gusterson B, Clark AJ. Inducible ablation of astrocytes shows that these cells are required for neuronal survival in the adult brain. Glia. 2001; 34(4):272&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11360300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schreiner B, Romanelli E, Liberski P, Ingold-Heppner B, Sobottka-Brillout B, Hartwig T, Chandrasekar V, Johannssen H, Zeilhofer HU, Aguzzi A, Heppner F, et al.. Astrocyte depletion impairs redox homeostasis and triggers neuronal loss in the adult CNS. Cell Rep. 2015;12(9):1377&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26299968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang YF, Cauley RK, Chang JD, Rao VV. L-&#x3b1;-aminoadipate inhibits kynurenate synthesis in rat brain hippocampus and tissue culture. Neurochem Res. 1997;22(7):825&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9232635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu X, Taylor AMW, Nagai J, Golshani P, Evans CJ, Coppola G, Khakh BS. Reducing Astrocyte calcium signaling in vivo alters striatal microcircuits and causes repetitive behavior. Neuron. 2018;99(6):1170&#x2013;87.e9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6450394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30174118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adamsky A, Kol A, Kreisel T, Doron A, Ozeri-Engelhard N, Melcer T, Refaeli R, Horn H, Regev L, Groysman M, London M, et al.. Astrocytic activation generates de novo neuronal potentiation and memory enhancement. Cell. 2018;174:59&#x2013;71.e14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29804835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pereira MF, Amaral IM, Lopes C, Leit&#xe3;o C, Madeira D, Lopes JP, Gon&#xe7;alves FQ, Canas PM, Cunha RA, Agostinho P. l-&#x3b1;-aminoadipate causes astrocyte pathology with negative impact on mouse hippocampal synaptic plasticity and memory. FASEB J. 2021;35(8):e21726.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34196433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>J&#xe4;kel S, Dimou L. Glial cells and their function in the adult brain: a journey through the history of their ablation. Front Cell Neurosci. 2017;11:24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5303749</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28243193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Neill E, Chiara Goisis R, Haverty R, Harkin A. L-alpha-aminoadipic acid restricts dopaminergic neurodegeneration and motor deficits in an inflammatory model of Parkinson&#x2019;s disease in male rats. J Neurosci Res. 2019;97(7):804&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30924171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madadi S, Pasbakhsh P, Tahmasebi F, Mortezaee K, Khanehzad M, Boroujeni FB, Noorzehi G, Kashani IR. Astrocyte ablation induced by La-aminoadipate (L-AAA) potentiates remyelination in a cuprizone demyelinating mouse model. Metab Brain Dis. 2019;34(2):593&#x2013;603.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30652255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jang SE, Qiu L, Chan LL, Tan EK, Zeng L. Current status of stem cell-derived therapies for Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: from cell assessment and imaging modalities to clinical trials. Front Neurosci. 2020;14:558532.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7596695</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33177975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayashi Y, Lin HT, Lee CC, Tsai KJ. Effects of neural stem cell transplantation in Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease models. J Biomed Sci. 2020;27(1):1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6986162</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31987051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bazarek S, Johnston BR, Sten M, Mandeville R, Eggan K, Wainger BJ, Brown JM. Spinal motor neuron transplantation to enhance nerve reconstruction strategies: towards a cell therapy. Exp Neurol. 2022;353:114054.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35341748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fischer I, Dulin JN, Lane MA. Transplanting neural progenitor cells to restore connectivity after spinal cord injury. Nat Rev Neurosci. 2020;21(7):366&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8384139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32518349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baloh RH, Glass JD, Svendsen CN. Stem cell transplantation for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Curr Opin Neurol. 2018;31(5):655&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30080719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izrael M, Slutsky SG, Revel M. Rising stars: astrocytes as a therapeutic target for ALS disease. Front Neurosci. 2020;14:824.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7399224</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32848579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Man JHK, Groenink L, Caiazzo M. Cell reprogramming approaches in gene- and cell-based therapies for Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. J Control Release. 2018;286:114&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30026082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu S, Schackel T, Weidner N, Puttagunta R. Biomaterial-supported cell transplantation treatments for spinal cord injury: challenges and perspectives. Front Cell Neurosci. 2018;11:430.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5768640</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29375316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu AK, Gong Z, He YZ, Xia KS, Tao HM. Comprehensive therapeutics targeting the corticospinal tract following spinal cord injury. J Zhejiang Univ Sci B. 2019;20(3):205&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6421122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30829009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grochowski C, Radzikowska E, Maciejewski R. Neural stem cell therapy&#x2014;brief review. Clin Neurol Neurosurg. 2018;173:8&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30053745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghosh HS. Adult neurogenesis and the promise of adult neural stem cells. J Exp Neurosci. 2019;13:1179069519856876.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6600486</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31285654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang GL, Zhu ZH, Wang YZ. Neural stem cell transplantation therapy for brain ischemic stroke: review and perspectives. World J Stem Cells. 2019;11(10):817&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6828598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31692854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martins-Macedo J, Lepore AC, Domingues HS, Salgado AJ, Gomes ED, Pinto L. Glial restricted precursor cells in central nervous system disorders: current applications and future perspectives. Glia. 2021;69(3):513&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7857417</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33052610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldman SA, Mariani JN, Madsen PM. Glial progenitor cell-based repair of the dysmyelinated brain: progression to the clinic. Semin Cell Dev Biol. 2021;116:62&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8254822</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33414060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serrenho I, Rosado M, Dinis A, Cardoso CM, Gr&#xe3;os M, Manadas B, Baltazar G. Stem cell therapy for neonatal hypoxic-ischemic encephalopathy: a systematic review of preclinical studies. Int J Mol Sci. 2021;22(6):3142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8003344</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33808671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Y, Wang S, Song X, Yuan J, Qi D, Gu X, Yin MY, Han Z, Zhu Y, Liu Z, Zhang Y, et al.. Glial cell-based vascular mechanisms and transplantation therapies in brain vessel and neurodegenerative diseases. Front Cell Neurosci. 2021;15: 627682.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8032950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33841101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Albert K, Niskanen J, K&#xe4;lv&#xe4;l&#xe4; S, Lehtonen &#x160;. Utilising induced pluripotent stem cells in neurodegenerative disease research: focus on glia. Int J Mol Sci. 2021;22(9):4334.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8122303</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33919317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baez-Jurado E, Hidalgo-Lanussa O, Barrera-Bail&#xf3;n B, Sahebkar A, Ashraf GM, Echeverria V, Barreto GE. Secretome of mesenchymal stem cells and its potential protective effects on brain pathologies. Mol Neurobiol. 2019;56(10):6902&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30941733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Das M, Mayilsamy K, Mohapatra SS, Mohapatra S. Mesenchymal stem cell therapy for the treatment of traumatic brain injury: progress and prospects. Rev Neurosci. 2019;30(8):839&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31203262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L, Dong Z-F, Zhang J-Y. Immunomodulatory role of mesenchymal stem cells in Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. Life Sci. 2020;246:117405.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32035129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lv B, Zhang X, Yuan J, Chen Y, Ding H, Cao X, Huang A. Biomaterial-supported MSC transplantation enhances cell-cell communication for spinal cord injury. Stem Cell Res Ther. 2021;12(1):36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7791771</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33413653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hatakeyama M, Ninomiya I, Otsu Y, Omae K, Kimura Y, Onodera O, Fukushima M, Shimohata T, Kanazawa M. Cell therapies under clinical trials and polarized cell therapies in pre-clinical studies to treat ischemic stroke and neurological diseases: a literature review. Int J Mol Sci. 2020;21(17):1&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7503631</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32867222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mariani JN, Zou L, Goldman SA. Human glial chimeric mice to define the role of glial pathology in human disease. Methods Mol Biol. 2019;1936:311&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6700730</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30820907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lepore AC, Rauck B, Dejea C, Pardo AC, Rao MS, Rothstein JD, Maragakis NJ. Focal transplantation-based astrocyte replacement is neuroprotective in a model of motor neuron disease. Nat Neurosci. 2008;11(11):1294&#x2013;301.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2656686</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18931666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lepore AC, O&#x2019;Donnell J, Kim AS, Williams T, Tuteja A, Rao MS, Kelley LL, Campanelli JT, Maragakis NJ. Human glial-restricted progenitor transplantation into cervical spinal cord of the SOD1 G93A mouse model of ALS. PLoS ONE. 2011;6(10):e25968.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3187829</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21998733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kondo T, Funayama M, Tsukita K, Hotta A, Yasuda A, Nori S, Kaneko S, Nakamura M, Takahashi R, Okano H, Yamanaka S, et al.. Focal transplantation of human iPSC-derived glial-rich neural progenitors improves lifespan of ALS mice. Stem Cell Rep. 2014;3(2):242&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4175543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25254338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izrael M, Slutsky SG, Admoni T, Cohen L, Granit A, Hasson A, Itskovitz-Eldor J, Krush Paker L, Kuperstein G, Lavon N, Yehezkel Ionescu S, et al.. Safety and efficacy of human embryonic stem cell-derived astrocytes following intrathecal transplantation in SOD1 G93A and NSG animal models. Stem Cell Res. Ther. 2018;9(1):152.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5989413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29871694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renton AE, Chi&#xf2; A, Traynor BJ. State of play in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis genetics. Nat Neurosci. 2014;17(1):17&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4544832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24369373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathis S, Goizet C, Soulages A, Vallat JM, Masson GL. Genetics of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a review. J Neurol Sci. 2019;399:217&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30870681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calvo AC, Manzano R, Mendon&#xe7;a DMF, Mu&#xf1;oz MJ, Zaragoza P, Osta R. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a focus on disease progression. Biomed Res Int. 2014;2014:925101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4137497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25157374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Chalabi A, Jones A, Troakes C, King A, Al-Sarraj S, Van Den Berg LH. The genetics and neuropathology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathol. 2012;124(3):339&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22903397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor JP, Brown RH, Cleveland DW. Decoding ALS: from genes to mechanism. Nature. 2016;539(7628):197&#x2013;206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5585017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27830784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papadeas ST, Kraig SE, O&#x2019;Banion C, Lepore AC, Maragakis NJ. Astrocytes carrying the superoxide dismutase 1 (SOD1G93A) mutation induce wild-type motor neuron degeneration in vivo. Proc Natl Acad Sci. 2011;108(43):17803&#x2013;808.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3203804</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21969586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qian K, Huang H, Peterson A, Hu B, Maragakis NJ, Ming G-L, Chen H, Zhang SC. Sporadic ALS astrocytes induce neuronal degeneration in vivo. Stem Cell Reports. 2017;8(4):843&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5390239</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28366455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen H, Qian K, Chen W, Hu B, Blackbourn LW, Du Z, Ma L, Liu H, Knobel KM, Ayala M, Zhang SC. Human-derived neural progenitors functionally replace astrocytes in adult mice. J Clin Invest. 2015;125(3):1033&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4362241</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25642771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L, Gutmann DH, Roos RP. Astrocyte loss of mutant SOD1 delays ALS disease onset and progression in G85R transgenic mice. Hum Mol Genet. 2011;20(2):286&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20962037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dirren E, Aebischer J, Rochat C, Towne C, Schneider BL, Aebischer P. SOD1 silencing in motoneurons or glia rescues neuromuscular function in ALS mice. Ann Clin Transl Neurol. 2015;2(2):167&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4338957</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25750921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gong YH, Parsadanian AS, Andreeva A, Snider WD, Elliott JL. Restricted expression of G86R Cu/Zn superoxide dismutase in astrocytes results in astrocytosis but does not cause motoneuron degeneration. J Neurosci. 2000;20(2):660&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6772423</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10632595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stephenson DT, Stephenson DT, Wright S. Reactive astrogliosis is widespread in the subcortical white matter of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis brain. J Neuropathol Exp Neurol. 1991;50(3):263&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2022968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schiffer D, Cordera S, Cavalla P, Migheli A. Reactive astrogliosis of the spinal cord in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Sci. 1996;139:27&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8899654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vargas MR, Johnson JA. Astrogliosis in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: role and therapeutic potential of astrocytes. Neurotherapeutics. 2010;7(4):471&#x2013;781.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2967019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20880509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schiffer D, Fiano V. Astrogliosis in ALS: possible interpretations according to pathogenetic hypotheses. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Mot. Neuron Disord. 2004;5(1):22&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15204020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wegorzewska I, Bell S, Cairns NJ, Miller TM, Baloh RH. TDP-43 mutant transgenic mice develop features of ALS and frontotemporal lobar degeneration. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2009;106(44):18809&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2762420</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19833869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossi D, Brambilla L, Valori CF, Roncoroni C, Crugnola A, Yokota T, Bredesen DE, Volterra A. Focal degeneration of astrocytes in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Cell Death Differ. 2008;15(11):1691&#x2013;700.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18617894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trias E, D&#xed;az-Amarilla P, Olivera-Bravo S, Isasi E, Drechsel DA, Lopez N, Bradford CS, Ireton KE, Beckman JS, Barbeito L. Phenotypic transition of microglia into astrocyte-like cells associated with disease onset in a model of inherited ALS. Front Cell Neurosci. 2013;7:274.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3871969</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24399933</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trias E, Ibarburu S, Barreto-N&#xfa;&#xf1;ez R, Barbeito L. Significance of aberrant glial cell phenotypes in pathophysiology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurosci Lett. 2017;636:27&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27473942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almer G, Vukosavic S, Romero N, Przedborski S. Inducible nitric oxide synthase up-regulation in a transgenic mouse model of familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurochem. 1999;72(6):2415&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10349851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin LJ, Liu Z, Chen K, Price AC, Yan P, Swaby JA, Golden WC. Motor neuron degeneration in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis mutant superoxide dismutase-1 transgenic mice: mechanisms of mitochondriopathy and cell death. J Comp Neurol. 2007;500(1):20&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17099894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hensley K, Mhatre M, Mou S, Pye QN, Stewart C, West M, Williamson KS. On the relation of oxidative stress to neuroinflammation: lessons learned from the G93A-SOD1 mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Antioxidants Redox Signal. 2006;8(11&#x2013;12):2075&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17034351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Birger A, Ben-Dor I, Ottolenghi M, Turetsky T, Gil Y, Sweetat S, Perez L, Belzer V, Casden N, Steiner D, Izrael M, et al.. Human iPSC-derived astrocytes from ALS patients with mutated C9ORF72 show increased oxidative stress and neurotoxicity. EBioMedicine. 2019;50:274&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6921360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31787569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anneser JMH, Cookson MR, Ince PG, Shaw PJ, Borasio GD. Glial cells of the spinal cord and subcortical white matter up-regulate neuronal nitric oxide synthase in sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Exp Neurol. 2001;171(2): 418&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11573993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rojas F, Cortes N, Abarzua S, Dyrda A, van Zundert B. Astrocytes expressing mutant SOD1 and TDP43 trigger motoneuron death that is mediated via sodium channels and nitroxidative stress. Front Cell Neurosci. 2014;8:24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3916762</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24570655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dringen R, Hirrlinger J. Glutathione pathways in the brain. Biol Chem. 2003;384(4):505&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12751781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y, Vartiainen NE, Ying W, Chan PH, Koistinaho J, Swanson RA. Astrocytes protect neurons from nitric oxide toxicity by a glutathione-dependent mechanism. J Neurochem. 2001;77(6):1601&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11413243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cassina P, Cassina A, Pehar M, Castellanos R, Gandelman M, De Le&#xf3;n A, Robinson KM, Mason RP, Beckman JS, Barbeito L, Radi R. Mitochondrial dysfunction in SOD1G93A-bearing astrocytes promotes motor neuron degeneration: prevention by mitochondrial-targeted antioxidants. J Neurosci. 2008; 28(16):4115&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3844766</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18417691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harlan BA, Pehar M, Sharma DR, Beeson G, Beeson CC, Vargas MR. Enhancing NAD+ salvage pathway reverts the toxicity of primary astrocytes expressing amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-linked mutant superoxide dismutase 1 (SOD1). J Biol Chem. 2016;291(20):10836&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4865928</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27002158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pehar M, Cassina P, Vargas MR, Castellanos R, Viera L, Beckman JS, Est&#xe9;vez AG, Barbeito L. Astrocytic production of nerve growth factor in motor neuron apoptosis: implications for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurochem. 2004;89(2):464&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15056289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin DT, Wu J, Holstein D, Upadhyay G, Rourk W, Muller E, Lechleiter JD. Ca2+ signaling, mitochondria and sensitivity to oxidative stress in aging astrocytes. Neurobiol Aging. 2007;28(1):99&#x2013;111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16359757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boitier E, Rea R, Duchen MR. Mitochondria exert a negative feedback on the propagation of intracellular Ca2+ waves in rat cortical astrocytes. J Cell Biol. 1999;145(4):795&#x2013;808.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2133193</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10330407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Decuypere JP, Monaco G, Missiaen L, De Smedt H, Parys JB, Bultynck G. IP(3) receptors, mitochondria, and Ca2+ signaling: implications for aging. J Aging Res. 2011;2011:920178.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3056293</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21423550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agarwal A, Wu PH, Hughes EG, Fukaya M, Tischfield MA, Langseth AJ, Wirtz D, Bergles DE. Transient opening of the mitochondrial permeability transition pore induces microdomain calcium transients in astrocyte processes. Neuron. 2017;93(3):587&#x2013;605.e7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5308886</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28132831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawamata H, Ng SK, Diaz N, Burstein S, Morel L, Osgood A, Sider B, Higashimori H, Haydon PG, Manfredi G, Yang Y. Abnormal intracellular calcium signaling and SNARE dependent exocytosis contributes to SOD1G93A astrocyte- mediated toxicity in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurosci. 2014;34(6):2331&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3913875</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24501372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norante RP, Peggion C, Rossi D, Martorana F, De Mario A, Lia A, Massimino ML, Bertoli A. ALS-associated SOD1(G93A) decreases SERCA pump levels and increases store-operated Ca2+ entry in primary spinal cord astrocytes from a transgenic mouse model. Int J Mol Sci. 2019;20(20):5151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6829245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31627428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aras R, Barron AM, Pike CJ. Caspase activation contributes to astrogliosis. Brain Res. 2012;1450:102&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3319728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22436850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varcianna A, Myszczynska MA, Castelli LM, O&#x2019;Neill B, Kim Y, Talbot J, Nyberg S, Nyamali I, Heath PR, Stopford MJ, Hautbergue GM, et al.. Micro-RNAs secreted through astrocyte-derived extracellular vesicles cause neuronal network degeneration in C9orf72 ALS. EBioMedicine. 2019;40:626&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6413467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30711519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bezzi P, Gundersen V, Galbete JL, Seifert G, Steinh&#xe4;user C, Pilati E, Volterra A. Astrocytes contain a vesicular compartment that is competent for regulated exocytosis of glutamate. Nat Neurosci. 2004;7(6):613&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15156145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hensley K, Abdel-Moaty H, Hunter J, Mhatre M, Mhou S, Nguyen K, Potapova T, Pye QN, Qi M, Rice H, Stewart C, et al.. Primary glia expressing the G93A-SOD1 mutation present a neuroinflammatory phenotype and provide a cellular system for studies of glial inflammation. J Neuroinflammation. 2006;3:2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1360663</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16436205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haidet-Phillips AM, Hester ME, Miranda CJ, Meyer K, Braun L, Frakes A, Song S, Likhite S, Murtha MJ, Foust KD, Rao M, et al.. Astrocytes from familial and sporadic ALS patients are toxic to motor neurons. Nat Biotechnol. 2011;29(9):824&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3170425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21832997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tripathi P, Rodriguez-Muela N, Klim JR, de Boer AS, Agrawal S, Sandoe J, Lopes CS, Ogliari KS, Williams LA, Shear M, Rubin LL, et al.. Reactive astrocytes promote ALS-like degeneration and intracellular protein aggregation in human motor neurons by disrupting autophagy through TGF-&#x3b2;1. Stem Cell Rep. 2017;9(2):667&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5549875</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28712846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howland DS, Liu J, She Y, Goad B, Maragakis NJ, Kim B, Erickson J, Kulik J, DeVito L, Psaltis G, DeGennaro LJ, et al.. Focal loss of the glutamate transporter EAAT2 in a transgenic rat model of SOD1 mutant-mediated amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2002;99(3):1604&#x2013;609.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC122237</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11818550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tong J, Huang C, Bi F, Wu Q, Huang B, Liu X, Li F, Zhou H, Xia XG. Expression of ALS-linked TDP-43 mutant in astrocytes causes non-cell-autonomous motor neuron death in rats. EMBO J. 2013;32(13):1917&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3981181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23714777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenblum LT, Shamamandri-Markandaiah S, Ghosh B, Foran E, Lepore AC, Pasinelli P, Trotti D. Mutation of the caspase-3 cleavage site in the astroglial glutamate transporter EAAT2 delays disease progression and extends lifespan in the SOD1-G93A mouse model of ALS. Exp Neurol. 2017;292:145&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5433801</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28342750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aebischer J, Cassina P, Otsmane B, Moumen A, Seilhean D, Meininger V, Barbeito L, Pettmann B, Raoul C. IFN&#x3b3; triggers a LIGHT-dependent selective death of motoneurons contributing to the non-cell-autonomous effects of mutant SOD1. Cell Death Differ. 2011;18(5):754&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3131923</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21072055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raoul C, Est&#xe9;vez AG, Nishimune H, Cleveland DW, DeLapeyri&#xe8;re O, Henderson CE, Haase G, Pettmann B. Motoneuron death triggered by a specific pathway downstream of Fas: potentiation by ALS-linked SOD1 mutations. Neuron. 2002;35(6):1067&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12354397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petri S, Kiaei M, Wille E, Calingasan NY, Flint Beal M. Loss of Fas ligand-function improves survival in G93A-transgenic ALS mice. J Neurol Sci. 2006;251(1&#x2013;2):44&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17049562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gandelman M, Levy M, Cassina P, Barbeito L, Beckman JS. P2X7 receptor-induced death of motor neurons by a peroxynitrite/FAS-dependent pathway. J Neurochem. 2013;126(3): 382&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3716845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23646980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vargas MR, Pehar M, Cassina P, Est&#xe9;vez AG, Beckman JS, Barbeito L. Stimulation of nerve growth factor expression in astrocytes by peroxynitrite. In Vivo (Brooklyn). 2004;18(3): 269&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15341182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deinhardt K, Chao MV. Trk receptors. Handb Exp Pharmacol. 2014;220:103&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24668471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller FD, Kaplan DR. Life and death decisions: a biological role for the p75 neurotrophin receptor. Cell Death Differ. 1998;5(5):343&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10200482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer BR, Yoon SO, Carter BD. The biological functions and signaling mechanisms of the p75 neurotrophin receptor. Handb Exp Pharmacol. 2014;220:121&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24668472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lowry KS, Murray SS, McLean CA, Talman P, Mathers S, Lopes EC, Cheema SS. A potential role for the p75 low-affinity neurotrophin receptor in spinal motor neuron degeneration in murine and human amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Mot Neuron Disord. 2001;2(3):127&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11771768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Copray JCVM, Jaarsma D, K&#xfc;st BM, Bruggeman RWG, Mantingh I, Brouwer N, Boddeke HWGM. Expression of the low affinity neurotrophin receptor p75 in spinal motoneurons in a transgenic mouse model for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuroscience. 2003;116(3):685&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12573711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith KS, Rush RA, Rogers ML. Characterization and changes in neurotrophin receptor p75N-expressing motor neurons in SOD1(G93A)G1H mice. J Comp Neurol. 2015;523(16):2476.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26382029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schapira a H, Cooper JM, Dexter D, Jenner P, Clark JB, Marsden CD. Mitochondrial complex I deficiency in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Lancet. 1989;1(8649):1269.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2566813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parihar MS, Parihar A, Fujita M, Hashimoto M, Ghafourifar P. Mitochondrial association of alpha-synuclein causes oxidative stress. Cell Mol Life Sci. 2008;65(7&#x2013;8):1272&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18322646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schapira AH. Mitochondria in the aetiology and pathogenesis of Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Lancet Neurol. 2008;7(1):97&#x2013;109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18093566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calvo A, Chi&#xf2; A, Pagani M, Cammarosano S, Dematteis F, Moglia C, Solero L, Manera U, Martone T, Brunetti M, Balma M, et al.. Parkinsonian traits in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS): a prospective population-based study. J Neurol. 2019;266(7):1633&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30949819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuzuhara S, Kokubo Y. Atypical Parkinsonism of Japan: amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-parkinsonism-dementia complex of the Kii peninsula of Japan (Muro disease): an update. Mov Disord. 2005;20(Suppl 12): S108&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16092099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Lau LM, Breteler MM. Epidemiology of Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Lancet Neurol. 2006;5(6):525&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16713924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tysnes OB, Storstein A. Epidemiology of Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. J Neural Transm. 2017;124(8):901&#x2013;905.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28150045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Obeso JA, Stamelou M, Goetz CG, Poewe W, Lang AE, Weintraub D, Burn D, Halliday GM, Bezard E, Przedborski S, Lehericy S, et al.. Past, present, and future of Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: a special essay on the 200th Anniversary of the Shaking Palsy. Mov Disord. 2017;32(9):1264&#x2013;310.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5685546</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28887905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Br&#xfc;ck D, Wenning GK, Stefanova N, Fellner L. Glia and alpha-synuclein in neurodegeneration: a complex interaction. Neurobiol Dis. 2016;85:262&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4730552</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25766679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azizi SA. Parkinson&#x2019;s Disease. In: Koob GF, Le Moal M, Thompson RF, eds. Encyclopedia of Behavioral Neuroscience. 1st ed. Elsevier Science; 2010:24&#x2013;28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalia LV, Lang AE. Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Lancet. 2015;386(9996):896&#x2013;912.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25904081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martinez-Martin P, Rodriguez-Blazquez C, Kurtis MM, Chaudhuri KR. The impact of non-motor symptoms on health-related quality of life of patients with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Mov Disord. 2011;26(3):399&#x2013;406.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21264941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lebouvier T, Chaumette T, Paillusson S, Duyckaerts C, Bruley Des Varannes S, Neunlist M, Derkinderen P. The second brain and Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Eur J Neurosci. 2009;30(5):735&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19712093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devos D, Lebouvier T, Lardeux B, Biraud M, Rouaud T, Pouclet H, Coron E, Bruley des Varannes S, Naveilhan P, Nguyen JM, Neunlist M, et al.. Colonic inflammation in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Neurobiol Dis. 2013;50:42&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23017648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clairembault T, Leclair-Visonneau L, Neunlist M, Derkinderen P. Enteric glial cells: new players in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease? Mov Disord. 2015;30(4):494&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25100667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braak H, Braak E. Pathoanatomy of Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. J Neurol. 2000;247(Suppl 2): II3&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10991663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braak H, Del Tredici K, R&#xfc;b U, De Vos RAI, Jansen Steur ENH, Braak E. Staging of brain pathology related to sporadic Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Neurobiol Aging. 2003;24(2):197&#x2013;211.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12498954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braak H, Sastre M, Del Tredici K. Development of &#x3b1;-synuclein immunoreactive astrocytes in the forebrain parallels stages of intraneuronal pathology in sporadic Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Acta Neuropathol. 2007;114(3):231&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17576580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tawfik VL, Chang SY, Hitti FL, Roberts DW, Leiter JC, Jovanovic S, Lee KH. Deep brain stimulation results in local glutamate and adenosine release: investigation into the role of astrocytes. Neurosurgery. 2010;67(2):367&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2919357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20644423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bahat-Stroomza M, Barhum Y, Levy YS, Karpov O, Bulvik S, Melamed E, Offen D. Induction of adult human bone marrow mesenchymal stromal cells into functional astrocyte-like cells: potential for restorative treatment in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. J Mol Neurosci. 2009;39(1&#x2013;2):199&#x2013;210.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19127447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proschel C, Stripay JL, Shih CH, Munger JC, Noble MD. Delayed transplantation of precursor cell-derived astrocytes provides multiple benefits in a rat model of Parkinsons. EMBO Mol Med. 2014;6(4):504&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3992077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24477866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song JJ, Oh SM, Kwon OC, Wulansari N, Lee HS, Chang MY, Lee E, Sun W, Lee SE, Chang S, An H, et al.. Cografting astrocytes improves cell therapeutic outcomes in a Parkinson&#x2019;s disease model. J Clin Invest. 2018;128(1):463&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5749514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29227284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tornatore C, Baker-Cairns B, Yadid G, Hamilton R, Meyers K, Atwood W, Cummins A, Tanner V, Major E. Expression of tyrosine hydroxylase in an immortalized human fetal astrocyte cell line; in vitro characterization and engraftment into the rodent striatum. Cell Transplant. 1996;5(2):145&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8689028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu XL, Long CX, Sun L, Xie C, Lin X, Cai H. Astrocytic expression of Parkinson&#x2019;s disease-related A53T alpha-synuclein causes neurodegeneration in mice. Mol Brain. 2010;3:12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2873589</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20409326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>di Domenico A, Carola G, Calatayud C, Pons-Espinal M, Mu&#xf1;oz JP, Richaud-Patin Y, Fernandez-Carasa I, Gut M, Faella A, Parameswaran J, Soriano J, et al.. Patient-specific iPSC-derived astrocytes contribute to non-cell-autonomous neurodegeneration in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Stem Cell Rep. 2019;12(2):213&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6372974</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30639209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ji KA, Eu MY, Kang SH, Gwag BJ, Jou I, Joe EH. Differential neutrophil infiltration contributes to regional differences in brain inflammation in the substantia nigra pars compacta and cortex. Glia. 2008;56(10):1039&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18381656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asanuma M, Miyazaki I, Diaz-Corrales FJ, Kimoto N, Kikkawa Y, Takeshima M, Miyoshi K, Murata M. Neuroprotective effects of zonisamide target astrocyte. Ann Neurol. 2010;67(2):239&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20225289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isooka N, Miyazaki I, Kikuoka R, Wada K, Nakayama E, Shin K, Yamamoto D, Kitamura Y, Asanuma M. Dopaminergic neuroprotective effects of rotigotine via 5-HT1A receptors: possibly involvement of metallothionein expression in astrocytes. Neurochem Int. 2020;132:104608.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31765686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramos-Gonzalez P, Mato S, Chara JC, Verkhratsky A, Matute C, Cavaliere F. Astrocytic atrophy as a pathological feature of Parkinson&#x2019;s disease with LRRK2 mutation. NPJ Park Dis. 2021;7(1):31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8009947</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33785762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee HJ, Kim C, Lee SJ. Alpha-synuclein stimulation of astrocytes: potential role for neuroinflammation and neuroprotection. Oxid Med Cell Longev. 2010;3(4):283&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2952089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20972375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee HJ, Suk JE, Patrick C, Bae EJ, Cho JH, Rho S, Hwang D, Masliah E, Lee SJ. Direct transfer of &#x3b1;-synuclein from neuron to astroglia causes inflammatory responses in synucleinopathies. J Biol Chem. 2010;285(12):9262&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2838344</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20071342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sorrentino ZA, Giasson BI, Chakrabarty P. &#x3b1;-Synuclein and astrocytes: tracing the pathways from homeostasis to neurodegeneration in Lewy body disease. Acta Neuropathol. 2019; 138(1):1&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6571045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30798354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cavaliere F, Cerf L, Dehay B, Ramos-Gonzalez P, De Giorgi F, Bourdenx M, Bessede A, Obeso JA, Matute C, Ichas F, Bezard E. In vitro &#x3b1;-synuclein neurotoxicity and spreading among neurons and astrocytes using Lewy body extracts from Parkinson disease brains. Neurobiol Dis. 2017;103:101&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28411117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fellner L, Irschick R, Schanda K, Reindl M, Klimaschewski L, Poewe W, Wenning GK, Stefanova N. Toll-like receptor 4 is required for &#x3b1;-synuclein dependent activation of microglia and astroglia. Glia. 2013;61(3):349&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3568908</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23108585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aflaki E, Stubblefield BK, McGlinchey RP, McMahon B, Ory DS, Sidransky E. A characterization of Gaucher iPS-derived astrocytes: potential implications for Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Neurobiol Dis. 2020;134:104647.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6980699</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31669751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gan L, Vargas MR, Johnson DA, Johnson JA. Astrocyte-specific overexpression of Nrf2 delays motor pathology and synuclein aggregation throughout the CNS in the alpha-synuclein mutant (A53T) mouse model. J Neurosci. 2012;32(49): 17775&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3539799</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23223297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alvarez-Erviti L, Seow Y, Schapira AH, Gardiner C, Sargent IL, Wood MJA, Cooper JM. Lysosomal dysfunction increases exosome-mediated alpha-synuclein release and transmission. Neurobiol Dis. 2011;42(3):360&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3107939</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21303699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braidy N, Gai WP, Xu YH, Sachdev P, Guillemin GJ, Jiang XM, Ballard JWO, Horan MP, Fang ZM, Chong BH, Chan DKY. Uptake and mitochondrial dysfunction of alpha-synuclein in human astrocytes, cortical neurons and fibroblasts. Transl Neurodegener. 2013;2(1):20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3853407</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24093918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erustes AG, Stefani FY, Terashima JY, Stilhano RS, Monteforte PT, da Silva Pereira GJ, Han SW, Calgarotto AK, Hsu Y, Te Ureshino RP, Bincoletto C, et al.. Overexpression of &#x3b1;-synuclein in an astrocyte cell line promotes autophagy inhibition and apoptosis. J Neurosci Res. 2018;96(1):160&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28573674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu M, Qin L, Wang L, Tan J, Zhang H, Tang J, Shen X, Tan L, Wang C. Alpha-synuclein induces apoptosis of astrocytes by causing dysfunction of the endoplasmic reticulum-Golgi compartment. Mol Med Rep. 2018;18(1):322&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6059687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29749529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stefanova N, Klimaschewski L, Poewe W, Wenning GK, Reindl M. Glial cell death induced by overexpression of alpha-synuclein. J Neurosci Res. 2001;65(5):432&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11536327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#xed;az EF, Labra VC, Alvear TF, Mellado LA, Inostroza CA, Oyarz&#xfa;n JE, Salgado N, Quintanilla RA, Orellana JA. Connexin 43 hemichannels and pannexin-1 channels contribute to the &#x3b1;-synuclein-induced dysfunction and death of astrocytes. Glia. 2019;67(8):1598&#x2013;619.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31033038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barodia SK, McMeekin LJ, Creed RB, Quinones EK, Cowell RM, Goldberg MS. PINK1 phosphorylates ubiquitin predominantly in astrocytes. NPJ Park Dis. 2019;5:29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6906478</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31840043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi I, Kim J, Jeong H-K, Kim B, Jou I, Park M, Chen L, Kang U-J, Zhuang X, Joe E-H. PINK1 deficiency attenuates astrocyte proliferation through mitochondrial dysfunction, reduced AKT and increased p38 MAPK activation, and downregulation of EGFR. Glia. 2013;61(5):800&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3657120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23440919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larsen NJ, Ambrosi G, Mullett SJ, Berman SB, Hinkle DA. DJ-1 knock-down impairs astrocyte mitochondrial function. Neuroscience. 2011;196:251&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3490195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21907265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y, Hu J, Wu J, Zhu C, Hui Y, Han Y, Huang Z, Ellsworth K, Fan W. &#x3b1;7 nicotinic acetylcholine receptor-mediated neuroprotection against dopaminergic neuron loss in an MPTP mouse model via inhibition of astrocyte activation. J Neuroinflammation. 2012;9:98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3416733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22624500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Episcopo F, Tirolo C, Testa N, Caniglia S, Morale M, Marchetti B. Reactive astrocytes are key players in nigrostriatal dopaminergic neurorepair in the MPTP mouse model of Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: focus on endogenous neurorestoration. Curr Aging Sci. 2013;6(1):45&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23895521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goswami P, Gupta S, Joshi N, Sharma S, Singh S. Astrocyte activation and neurotoxicity: a study in different rat brain regions and in rat C6 astroglial cells. Environ Toxicol Pharmacol. 2015;40(1):122&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26113375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X, Sullivan KA, Madl JE, Legare M, Tjalkens RB. Manganese-induced neurotoxicity: the role of astroglial-derived nitric oxide in striatal interneuron degeneration. Toxicol Sci. 2006;91(2):521&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16551646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Exil V, Ping L, Yu Y, Chakraborty S, Caito SW, Wells KS, Karki P, Lee E, Aschner M. Activation of MAPK and FoxO by Manganese (Mn) in rat neonatal primary astrocyte cultures. PLoS ONE. 2014;9(5):e94753.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4008430</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24787138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charron G, Doudnikoff E, Canron MH, Li Q, V&#xe9;ga C, Marais S, Baufreton J, Vital A, Oliet SHR, Bezard E. Astrocytosis in Parkinsonism: considering tripartite striatal synapses in physiopathology? Front Aging Neurosci. 2014;6:258.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4174038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25309435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y, Zeng X, Hui Y, Zhu C, Wu J, Taylor DH, Ji J, Fan W, Huang Z, Hu J. Activation of &#x3b1;7 nicotinic acetylcholine receptors protects astrocytes against oxidative stress-induced apoptosis: implications for Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Neuropharmacology. 2015;91:87&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25486621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindholm D, M&#xe4;kel&#xe4; J, Di Liberto V, Mud&#xf2; G, Belluardo N, Eriksson O, Saarma M. Current disease modifying approaches to treat Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Cell Mol Life Sci. 2016;73(7):1365&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26616211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishii T, Warabi E, Mann GE. Circadian control of BDNF-mediated Nrf2 activation in astrocytes protects dopaminergic neurons from ferroptosis. Free Radic Biol Med. 2019;133: 169&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30189266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voutilainen MH, B&#xe4;ck S, P&#xf6;rsti E, Toppinen L, Lindgren L, Lindholm P, Per&#xe4;nen J, Saarma M, Tuominen RK. Mesencephalic astrocyte-derived neurotrophic factor is neurorestorative in rat model of Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. J Neurosci. 2009;29(30):9651&#x2013;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6666534</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19641128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Booth HDE, Hirst WD, Wade-Martins R. The role of astrocyte dysfunction in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease pathogenesis. Trends Neurosci. 2017;40(6):358&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5462417</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28527591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrejack J, Mathur S. What people with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease want. J Parkinsons Dis. 2020;10:S5&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7592662</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32651334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braak H, Braak E. Staging of Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease-related neurofibrillary changes. Neurobiol Aging. 1995;16(3):271&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7566337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braak H, Braak E. Evolution of the neuropathology of Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. Acta Neurol Scand. 1996;165:3&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8740983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar A, Singh A, Ekavali. A review on Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease pathophysiology and its management: an update. Pharmacol Rep. 2015;67(2):195&#x2013;203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25712639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neary D, Snowden J, Mann D. Frontotemporal dementia. Lancet Neurol. 2005;4(11):771&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16239184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spillantini MG, Goedert M. Tau pathology and neurodegeneration. Lancet Neurol. 2013;12(6):609&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23684085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Irwin DJ, Hurtig HI. The contribution of tau, amyloid-beta and alpha-synuclein pathology to dementia in Lewy body disorders. J Alzheimer&#x2019;s Dis Park. 2018;8(4):444.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6248323</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30473927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Compta Y, Parkkinen L, O&#x2019;Sullivan SS, Vandrovcova J, Holton JL, Collins C, Lashley T, Kallis C, Williams DR, De Silva R, Lees AJ, et al.. Lewy- and Alzheimer-type pathologies in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease dementia: which is more important? Brain. 2011;134(Pt 5):1493&#x2013;505.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4194668</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21596773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinton LK, Blurton-Jones M, Myczek K, Trojanowski JQ, LaFerla FM. Synergistic interactions between A&#x3b2;, tau, and &#x3b1;-synuclein: acceleration of neuropathology and cognitive decline. J Neurosci. 2010;30(21):7281&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3308018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20505094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marsh SE, Blurton-Jones M. Examining the mechanisms that link &#x3b2;-amyloid and &#x3b1;-synuclein pathologies. Alzheimer&#x2019;s Res Ther. 2012;4(2):11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4054672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22546279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ballard C, Gauthier S, Corbett A, Brayne C, Aarsland D, Jones E. Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. Lancet. 2011;377(9770):1019&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21371747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiu C, Kivipelto M, Von Strauss E. Epidemiology of Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease: occurrence, determinants, and strategies toward intervention. Dialogues Clin Neurosci. 2009;11(2): 111&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3181909</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19585947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masters CL, Bateman R, Blennow K, Rowe CC, Sperling RA, Cummings JL. Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. Nat Rev Dis Prim. 2015;1:15056.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27188934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Cauwenberghe C, Van Broeckhoven C, Sleegers K. The genetic landscape of Alzheimer disease: clinical implications and perspectives. Genet Med. 2016;18(5):421&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4857183</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26312828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gatz M, Reynolds CA, Fratiglioni L, Johansson B, Mortimer JA, Berg S, Fiske A, Pedersen NL. Role of genes and environments for explaining Alzheimer disease. Arch Gen Psychiatry. 2006;63(2):168&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16461860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riedel BC, Thompson PM, Brinton RD. Age, APOE and sex: triad of risk of Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. J Steroid Biochem Mol Biol. 2016;160:134&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4905558</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26969397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun Y, Wu S, Bu G, Onifade MK, Patel SN, LaDu MJ, Fagan AM, Holtzman DM. Glial fibrillary acidic protein-apolipoprotein E (apoE) transgenic mice: astrocyte-specific expression and differing biological effects of astrocyte- secreted apoE3 and apoE4 lipoproteins. J Neurosci. 1998;18(9):3261&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6792658</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9547235</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yiannopoulou KG, Papageorgiou SG. Current and future treatments for Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. Ther Adv Neurol Disord. 2013;6(1):19&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3526946</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23277790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esposito G, Sarnelli G, Capoccia E, Cirillo C, Pesce M, Lu J, Cal&#xec; G, Cuomo R, Steardo L. Autologous transplantation of intestine-isolated glia cells improves neuropathology and restores cognitive deficits in &#x3b2; amyloid-induced neurodegeneration. Sci Rep. 2016;6:22605.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4778118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26940982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hampton DW, Webber DJ, Bilican B, Goedert M, Spillantini MG, Chandran S. Cell-mediated neuroprotection in a mouse model of human tauopathy. J Neurosci. 2010;30(30):9973&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6633376</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20668182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osborn LM, Kamphuis W, Wadman WJ, Hol EM. Astrogliosis: an integral player in the pathogenesis of Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. Prog Neurobiol. 2016;144:121&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26797041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeh CY, Vadhwana B, Verkhratsky A, Rodr&#xed;guez JJ. Early astrocytic atrophy in the entorhinal cortex of a triple transgenic animal model of Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. ASN Neuro. 2011;3(5):271&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3243908</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22103264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olabarria M, Noristani HN, Verkhratsky A, Rodr&#xed;guez JJ. Concomitant astroglial atrophy and astrogliosis in a triple transgenic animal model of Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. Glia. 2010;58(7):831&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20140958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsu ET, Gangolli M, Su S, Holleran L, Stein TD, Alvarez VE, McKee AC, Schmidt RE, Brody DL. Astrocytic degeneration in chronic traumatic encephalopathy. Acta Neuropathol. 2018;136(6):955&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30194648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orre M, Kamphuis W, Osborn LM, Jansen AHP, Kooijman L, Bossers K, Hol EM. Isolation of glia from Alzheimer&#x2019;s mice reveals inflammation and dysfunction. Neurobiol Aging. 2014;35(12):2746&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25002035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qi L, Cui EH, Ji CM, Zhang XB, Wang ZA, Sun YZ, Xu JC, Zhai XF, Chen ZJ, Li J, Zheng JY, et al.. Specific knockdown of hippocampal astroglial EphB2 improves synaptic function via inhibition of D-serine secretion in APP/PS1 mice. Am J Transl Res. 2019;11(2):1073&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6413293</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30899407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serrano-Pozo A, Mielke ML, G&#xf3;mez-Isla T, Betensky RA, Growdon JH, Frosch MP, Hyman BT. Reactive glia not only associates with plaques but also parallels tangles in Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. Am J Pathol. 2011;179(3):1373&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3157187</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21777559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceyz&#xe9;riat K, Ben Haim L, Denizot A, Pommier D, Matos M, Guillemaud O, Palomares MA, Abjean L, Petit F, Gipchtein P, Gaillard MC, et al.. Modulation of astrocyte reactivity improves functional deficits in mouse models of Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. Acta Neuropathol Commun. 2018;6(1):104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6190663</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30322407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beauquis J, Vinuesa A, Pomilio C, Pav&#xed;a P, Galv&#xe1;n V, Saravia F. Neuronal and glial alterations, increased anxiety, and cognitive impairment before hippocampal amyloid deposition in PDAPP mice, model of Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. Hippocampus. 2014;24(3):257&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24132937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao J, O&#x2019;Connor T, Vassar R. The contribution of activated astrocytes to A&#x3b2; production: implications for Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease pathogenesis. J Neuroinflammation. 2011;8:150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3216000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22047170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ro&#xdf;ner S, Lange-Dohna C, Zeitschel U, Perez-Polo JR. Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease &#x3b2;-secretase BACE1 is not a neuron-specific enzyme. J Neurochem. 2005;92(2):226&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15663471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dom&#xed;nguez-Prieto M, Velasco A, Tabernero A, Medina JM. Endocytosis and transcytosis of amyloid-&#x3b2; peptides by astrocytes: a possible mechanism for amyloid-&#x3b2; clearance in Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. J Alzheimer&#x2019;s Dis. 2018;65(4):1109&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30103329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhong L, Wang Z, Wang D, Wang Z, Martens YA, Wu L, Xu Y, Wang K, Li J, Huang R, Can D, et al.. Amyloid-beta modulates microglial responses by binding to the triggering receptor expressed on myeloid cells 2 (TREM2). Mol Neurodegener. 2018;13(1):15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5870375</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29587871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mu&#xf1;oz Y, Paula-Lima AC, N&#xfa;&#xf1;ez MT. Reactive oxygen species released from astrocytes treated with amyloid beta oligomers elicit neuronal calcium signals that decrease phospho-Ser727-STAT3 nuclear content. Free Radic Biol Med. 2018;117:132&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29309895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hallmann AL, Ara&#xfa;zo-Bravo MJ, Mavrommatis L, Ehrlich M, R&#xf6;pke A, Brockhaus J, Missler M, Sterneckert J, Sch&#xf6;ler HR, Kuhlmann T, Zaehres H, et al.. Astrocyte pathology in a human neural stem cell model of frontotemporal dementia caused by mutant TAU protein. Sci Rep. 2017;7:42991.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5335603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28256506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sekar S, McDonald J, Cuyugan L, Aldrich J, Kurdoglu A, Adkins J, Serrano G, Beach TG, Craig DW, Valla J, Reiman EM, et al.. Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease is associated with altered expression of genes involved in immune response and mitochondrial processes in astrocytes. Neurobiol Aging. 2015;36(2):583&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4315763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25448601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li MZ, Zheng LJ, Shen J, Li XY, Zhang Q, Bai X, Wang QS, Ji JG. SIRT1 facilitates amyloid beta peptide degradation by upregulating lysosome number in primary astrocytes. Neural Regen Res. 2018;13(11):2005&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6183050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30233076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prasad H, Rao R. Amyloid clearance defect in ApoE4 astrocytes is reversed by epigenetic correction of endosomal pH. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2018;115(28):E6640&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6048470</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29946028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kimura N, Takahashi M, Tashiro T, Terao K. Amyloid &#x3b2; up-regulates brain-derived neurotrophic factor production from astrocytes: rescue from amyloid &#x3b2;-related neuritic degeneration. J Neurosci Res. 2006;84(4):782&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16862545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuan WL, Kasis A, Yuan Y, Mason SL, Lazar AS, Barker RA, Goncalves J. Modelling the natural history of Huntington&#x2019;s disease progression. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2015;86(10):1143&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25515501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waldvogel HJ, Kim EH, Tippett LJ, Vonsattel JPG, Faull RLM. The neuropathology of Huntington&#x2019;s disease. Curr Top Behav Neurosci. 2015;22:33&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25300927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris KL, Kuan WL, Mason SL, Barker RA. Antidopaminergic treatment is associated with reduced chorea and irritability but impaired cognition in Huntington&#x2019;s disease (Enroll-HD). J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2020;91:622&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7279191</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32229581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wyant KJ, Ridder AJ, Dayalu P. Huntington&#x2019;s disease&#x2014;update on treatments. Curr Neurol Neurosci Rep. 2017;17(4):33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28324302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carroll JB, Bates GP, Steffan J, Saft C, Tabrizi SJ. Treating the whole body in Huntington&#x2019;s disease. Lancet Neurol. 2015;14(11):1135&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26466780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shin JY, Fang ZH, Yu ZX, Wang CE, Li SH, Li XJ. Expression of mutant huntingtin in glial cells contributes to neuronal excitotoxicity. J Cell Biol. 2005;171(6):1001&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2171327</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16365166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tydlacka S, Wang CE, Wang X, Li S, Li XJ. Differential activities of the ubiquitin-proteasome system in neurons versus glia may account for the preferential accumulation of misfolded proteins in neurons. J Neurosci. 2008;28(49):13285&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2662777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19052220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang CE, Tydlacka S, Orr AL, Yang SH, Graham RK, Hayden MR, Li S, Chan AWS, Li XJ. Accumulation of N-terminal mutant huntingtin in mouse and monkey models implicated as a pathogenic mechanism in Huntington&#x2019;s disease. Hum Mol Genet. 2008;17(17):2738&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2733806</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18558632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bradford J, Shin JY, Roberts M, Wang CE, Li XJ, Li S. Expression of mutant huntingtin in mouse brain astrocytes causes age-dependent neurological symptoms. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2009;106(52):22480&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2799722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20018729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juopperi TA, Kim WR, Chiang CH, Yu H, Margolis RL, Ross CA, Ming GL, Song H. Astrocytes generated from patient induced pluripotent stem cells recapitulate features of Huntington&#x2019;s disease patient cells. Mol Brain. 2012;5:17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3506453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22613578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osipovitch M, Asenjo Martinez A, Mariani JN, Cornwell A, Dhaliwal S, Zou L, Chandler-Militello D, Wang S, Li X, Benraiss SJ, Agate R, et al.. Human ESC-derived chimeric mouse models of Huntington&#x2019;s disease reveal cell-intrinsic defects in glial progenitor cell differentiation. Cell Stem Cell. 2019;24(1):107&#x2013;122.e7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6700734</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30554964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wood TE, Barry J, Yang Z, Cepeda C, Levine MS, Gray M. Mutant huntingtin reduction in astrocytes slows disease progression in the BACHD conditional Huntington&#x2019;s disease mouse model. Hum Mol Genet. 2019;28(3):487&#x2013;500.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6337698</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30312396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benraiss A, Wang S, Herrlinger S, Li X, Chandler-Militello D, Mauceri J, Burm HB, Toner M, Osipovitch M, Jim Xu Q, Ding F, et al.. Human glia can both induce and rescue aspects of disease phenotype in Huntington disease. Nat Commun. 2016;7:11758.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4899632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27273432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tong X, Ao Y, Faas GC, Nwaobi SE, Xu J, Haustein MD, Anderson MA, Mody I, Olsen ML, Sofroniew MV, Khakh BS. Astrocyte Kir4.1 ion channel deficits contribute to neuronal dysfunction in Huntington&#x2019;s disease model mice. Nat Neurosci. 2014;17(5):694&#x2013;703.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4064471</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24686787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang R, Diaz-Castro B, Looger LL, Khakh BS. Dysfunctional calcium and glutamate signaling in striatal astrocytes from Huntington&#x2019;s disease model mice. J Neurosci. 2016;36(12): 3453&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4804005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27013675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Estrada-S&#xe1;nchez AM, Montiel T, Segovia J, Massieu L. Glutamate toxicity in the striatum of the R6/2 Huntington&#x2019;s disease transgenic mice is age-dependent and correlates with decreased levels of glutamate transporters. Neurobiol Dis. 2009;34(1):78&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19168136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li&#xe9;vens JC, Woodman B, Mahal A, Spasic-Boscovic O, Samuel D, Kerkerian-Le Goff L, Bates GP. Impaired glutamate uptake in the R6 Huntington&#x2019;s disease transgenic mice. Neurobiol Dis. 2001;8(5):807&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11592850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faideau M, Kim J, Cormier K, Gilmore R, Welch M, Auregan G, Dufour N, Guillermier M, Brouillet E, Hantraye P, D&#xe9;Glon N, et al.. In vivo expression of polyglutamine-expanded huntingtin by mouse striatal astrocytes impairs glutamate transport: a correlation with Huntington&#x2019;s disease subjects. Hum Mol Genet. 2010;19(15):3053&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2901144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20494921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen LL, Wu JC, Wang LH, Wang J, Qin ZH, Difiglia M, Lin F. Rapamycin prevents the mutant huntingtin-suppressed GLT-1 expression in cultured astrocytes. Acta Pharmacol Sin. 2012;33(3):385&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4077128</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22266730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsiao HY, Chen YC, Chen HM, Tu PH, Chern Y. A critical role of astrocyte-mediated nuclear factor-&#x3ba;B-dependent inflammation in Huntington&#x2019;s disease. Hum Mol Genet. 2013;22(9):1826&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23372043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haim L, Ben Ceyz&#xe9;riat K, Sauvage MAC, de Aubry F, Auregan G, Guillermier M, Ruiz M, Petit F, Houitte D, Faivre E, Vandesquille M, et al.. The JAK/STAT3 pathway is a common inducer of astrocyte reactivity in Alzheimer&#x2019;s and Huntington&#x2019;s diseases. J Neurosci. 2015;35(6):2817&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6605603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25673868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abjean L, Haim L, Ben Sauvage MAC, H&#xe9;rard A-S, Derbois C, Petit F, Gipstein P, Guillermier M, Gaudin M, Bernier S, Dufour N, et al.. A42 Reactive astrocytes promote proteostasis in huntington&#x2019;s disease. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2018;89:A15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khakh BS, Beaumont V, Cachope R, Munoz-Sanjuan I, Goldman SA, Grantyn R. Unravelling and exploiting astrocyte dysfunction in Huntington&#x2019;s disease. Trends Neurosci. 2017;40(7):422&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5706770</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28578789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steele AD, Jackson WS, King OD, Lindquist S. The power of automated high-resolution behavior analysis revealed by its application to mouse models of Huntington&#x2019;s and prion diseases. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2007;104(6):1983&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1794260</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17261803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliveira JMA. Mitochondrial bioenergetics and dynamics in Huntington&#x2019;s disease: tripartite synapses and selective striatal degeneration. J Bioenerg Biomembr. 2010;42(3):227&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20454921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wright DJ, Renoir T, Smith ZM, Frazier AE, Francis PS, Thorburn DR, McGee SL, Hannan AJ, Gray LJ. N-Acetylcysteine improves mitochondrial function and ameliorates behavioral deficits in the R6/1 mouse model of Huntington&#x2019;s disease. Transl Psychiatry. 2015;5(1):e492.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4312826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25562842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diaz-Castro B, Gangwani MR, Yu X, Coppola G, Khakh BS. Astrocyte molecular signatures in Huntington&#x2019;s disease. Sci Transl Med. 2019;11(514):eaaw8546.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31619545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Dalahmah O, Sosunov AA, Shaik A, Ofori K, Liu Y, Vonsattel JP, Adorjan I, Menon V, Goldman JE. Single-nucleus RNA-seq identifies Huntington disease astrocyte states. Acta Neuropathol Commun. 2020;8(1):19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7029580</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32070434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wyndaele M, Wyndaele JJ. Incidence, prevalence and epidemiology of spinal cord injury: what learns a worldwide literature survey? Spinal Cord. 2006;44(9):523&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16389270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh A, Tetreault L, Kalsi-Ryan S, Nouri A, Fehlings MG. Global prevalence and incidence of traumatic spinal cord injury. Clin Epidemiol. 2014;6:309&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4179833</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25278785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Badhiwala JH, Wilson JR, Fehlings MG. Global burden of traumatic brain and spinal cord injury. Lancet Neurol. 2019;18(1):24&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30497967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu J, Stoica BA, Luo T, Sabirzhanov B, Zhao Z, Guanciale K, Nayar SK, Foss CA, Pomper MG, Faden AI. Isolated spinal cord contusion in rats induces chronic brain neuroinflammation, neurodegeneration, and cognitive impairment: involvement of cell cycle activation. Cell Cycle. 2014;13(15): 2446&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4128888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25483194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu J, Zhao Z, Sabirzhanov B, Stoica BA, Kumar A, Luo T, Skovira J, Faden AI. Spinal cord injury causes brain inflammation associated with cognitive and affective changes: role of cell cycle pathways. J Neurosci. 2014;34(33):10989&#x2013;1006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4131014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25122899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies JE, Huang C, Proschel C, Noble M, Mayer-Proschel M, Davies SJA. Astrocytes derived from glial-restricted precursors promote spinal cord repair. J Biol. 2006;5(3):7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1561531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16643674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies JE, Pr&#xf6;schel C, Zhang N, Noble M, Mayer-Pr&#xf6;schel M, Davies SJA. Transplanted astrocytes derived from BMP- or CNTF-treated glial-restricted precursors have opposite effects on recovery and allodynia after spinal cord injury. J Biol. 2008;19(7):24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2776404</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18803859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies SJA, Shih C-HH, Noble M, Mayer-Proschel M, Davies JE, Proschel C. Transplantation of Specific human astrocytes promotes functional recovery after spinal cord injury. PLoS ONE. 2011;6(3):e17328.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3047562</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21407803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chu T, Zhou H, Li F, Wang T, Lu L, Feng S. Astrocyte transplantation for spinal cord injury: current status and perspective. Brain Res Bull. 2014;107:18&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24878447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kliot M, Smith GM, Siegal JD, Silver J. Astrocyte-polymer implants promote regeneration of dorsal root fibers into the adult mammalian spinal cord. Exp Neurol. 1990;109(1):57&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1694141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernstein JJ, Goldberg WJ. Grafted fetal astrocyte migration can prevent host neuronal atrophy: comparison of astrocytes from cultures and whole piece donors. Restor Neurol Neurosci. 1991;2(4):261&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21551612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang JJ, Chuah MI, Yew DTW, Leung PC, Tsang DSC. Effects of astrocyte implantation into the hemisected adult rat spinal cord. Neuroscience. 1995;65(4):973&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7617172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olby NJ, Blakemore WF. Reconstruction of the glial environment of a photochemically induced lesion in the rat spinal cord by transplantation of mixed glial cells. J Neurocytol. 1996;25(8):481&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8899569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joosten EAJ, Veldhuis WB, Hamers FPT. Collagen containing neonatal astrocytes stimulates regrowth of injured fibers and promotes modest locomotor recovery after spinal cord injury. J Neurosci Res. 2004;77(1):127&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15197746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pencalet P, Serguera C, Corti O, Privat A, Mallet J, Gim&#xe9;nez Y, Ribotta M. Integration of genetically modified adult astrocytes into the lesioned rat spinal cord. J Neurosci Res. 2006;83(1):61&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16294335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayashi K, Hashimoto M, Koda M, Naito AT, Murata A, Okawa A, Takahashi K, Yamazaki M. Increase of sensitivity to mechanical stimulus after transplantation of murine induced pluripotent stem cell-derived astrocytes in a rat spinal cord injury model: laboratory investigation. J Neurosurg Spine. 2011;15(6):582&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21854127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin Y, Neuhuber B, Singh A, Bouyer J, Lepore A, Bonner J, Himes T, Campanelli JT, Fischer I. Transplantation of human glial restricted progenitors and derived astrocytes into a contusion model of spinal cord injury. J Neurotrauma. 2011;28(4):579&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3070147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21222572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haas C, Neuhuber B, Yamagami T, Rao M, Fischer I. Phenotypic analysis of astrocytes derived from glial restricted precursors and their impact on axon regeneration. Exp Neurol. 2012;233(2):717&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3272137</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22101004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan C, Zheng Y, Cheng X, Qi X, Bu P, Luo X, Kim DH, Cao Q. Transplantation of D15A-expressing glial-restricted-precursor-derived astrocytes improves anatomical and locomotor recovery after spinal cord injury. Int J Biol Sci. 2013;9(1):78&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3535536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23289019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haas C, Fischer I. Human astrocytes derived from glial restricted progenitors support regeneration of the injured spinal cord. J Neurotrauma. 2013;30(12):1035&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3689933</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23635322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu L, Li JJ, Chen L, Zhang H, Yuan L, Davies SJA. Combined transplantation of GDAs(BMP) and hr-decorin in spinal cord contusion repair. Neural Regen Res. 2013;8(24):2236&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4146032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25206533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shih CH, Lacagnina M, Leuer-Bisciotti K, Pr&#xf6;schel C. Astroglial-derived periostin promotes axonal regeneration after spinal cord injury. J Neurosci. 2014;34(7):2438&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6802751</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24523534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi W, Huang CJ, Xu XD, Jin GH, Huang RQ, Huang JF, Chen YN, Ju SQ, Wang Y, Shi YW, Qin JB, et al.. Transplantation of RADA16-BDNF peptide scaffold with human umbilical cord mesenchymal stem cells forced with CXCR4 and activated astrocytes for repair of traumatic brain injury. Acta Biomater. 2016;45:247&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27592818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Becerra GD, Tatko LM, Pak ES, Murashov AK, Hoane MR. Transplantation of GABAergic neurons but not astrocytes induces recovery of sensorimotor function in the traumatically injured brain. Behav Brain Res. 2007;179(1):118&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1880895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17324477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quan FS, Chen J, Zhong Y, Ren WZ. Comparative effect of immature neuronal or glial cell transplantation on motor functional recovery following experimental traumatic brain injury in rats. Exp Ther Med. 2016;12(3):1671&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4998226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27602084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson MA, Burda JE, Ren Y, Ao Y, O&#x2019;Shea TM, Kawaguchi R, Coppola G, Khakh BS, Deming TJ, Sofroniew MV. Astrocyte scar formation aids central nervous system axon regeneration. Nature. 2016;532(7598):195&#x2013;200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5243141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27027288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>White RE, Jakeman LB. Don&#x2019;t fence me in: harnessing the beneficial roles of astrocytes for spinal cord repair. Restor Neurol Neurosci. 2008;26(2&#x2013;3):197&#x2013;214.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2825119</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18820411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerschensteiner M, Schwab ME, Lichtman JW, Misgeld T. In vivo imaging of axonal degeneration and regeneration in the injured spinal cord. Nat Med. 2005;11(5):572&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15821747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Becerra JL, Puckett WR, Hiester ED, Quencer RM, Marcillo AE, Post MJD, Bunge RP. MR-pathologic comparisons of wallerian degeneration in spinal cord injury. Am J Neuroradiol. 1995;16(1):125&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8337709</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7900580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coleman MP, Perry VH. Axon pathology in neurological disease: a neglected therapeutic target. Trends Neurosci. 2002;25(10):532&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12220882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu J, Zhang G, Rodemer W, Jin LQ, Shifman M, Selzer ME. The role of RhoA in retrograde neuronal death and axon regeneration after spinal cord injury. Neurobiol Dis. 2017;98:25&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5219843</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27888137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodemer W, Selzer ME. Role of axon resealing in retrograde neuronal death and regeneration after spinal cord injury. Neural Regen Res. 2019;14(3):399&#x2013;404.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6334596</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30539805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishibashi T, Dakin KA, Stevens B, Lee PR, Kozlov SV, Stewart CL, Fields RD. Astrocytes promote myelination in response to electrical impulses. Neuron. 2006;49(6):823&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1474838</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16543131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kotter MR, Li W-W, Zhao C, Franklin RJM. Myelin impairs CNS remyelination by inhibiting oligodendrocyte precursor cell differentiation. J Neurosci. 2006;26(1):328&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6674302</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16399703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldshmit Y, McLenachan S, Turnley A. Roles of Eph receptors and ephrins in the normal and damaged adult CNS. Brain Res Rev. 2006;52(2):327&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16774788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng W, Cotrina ML, Han X, Yu H, Bekar L, Blum L, Takano T, Tian GF, Goldman SA, Nedergaard M. Systemic administration of an antagonist of the ATP-sensitive receptor P2X7 improves recovery after spinal cord injury. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2009;106(30):12489&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2718350</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19666625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park E, Velumian AA, Fehlings MG. The role of excitotoxicity in secondary mechanisms of spinal cord injury: a review with an emphasis on the implications for white matter degeneration. J Neurotrauma. 2004;21(6):754&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15253803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bains M, Hall ED. Antioxidant therapies in traumatic brain and spinal cord injury. Biochim Biophys Acta. 2012;1822(5): 675&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4134010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22080976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krencik R, Weick JP, Liu Y, Zhang ZJ, Zhang SC. Specification of transplantable astroglial subtypes from human pluripotent stem cells. Nat Biotechnol. 2011;29(6):528&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3111840</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21602806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rolls A, Shechter R, London A, Segev Y, Jacob-Hirsch J, Amariglio N, Rechavi G, Schwartz M. Two faces of chondroitin sulfate proteoglycan in spinal cord repair: a role in microglia/macrophage activation. PLoS Med. 2008;5(8):e171.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2517615</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18715114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rolls A, Shechter R, Schwartz M. The bright side of the glial scar in CNS repair. Nat Rev Neurosci. 2009;10(3):235&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19229242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flynn RWV, MacWalter RSM, Doney ASF. The cost of cerebral ischaemia. Neuropharmacology. 2008;55(3):250&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18573263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xe9;jot Y, Bailly H, Durier J, Giroud M. Epidemiology of stroke in Europe and trends for the 21st century. Press Med. 2016;45(12, Pt 2):e391&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27816343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Appelros P, Stegmayr B, Ter&#xe9;nt A. Sex differences in stroke epidemiology: a systematic review. Stroke. 2009;40(4):1082&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19211488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smajlovi&#x107; D. Strokes in young adults: epidemiology and prevention. Vasc Health Risk Manag. 2015;11:157&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4348138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25750539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Donnell MJ, Denis X, Liu L, Zhang H, Chin SL, Rao-Melacini P, Rangarajan S, Islam S, Pais P, McQueen MJ, Mondo C, et al.. Risk factors for ischaemic and intracerebral haemorrhagic stroke in 22 countries (the INTERSTROKE study): a case-control study. Lancet. 2010;376(9735):112&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20561675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai Q, Chen Z, Song P, Wu L, Wang L, Deng G, Liu B, Chen Q. Co-transplantation of hippocampal neural stem cells and astrocytes and microvascular endothelial cells improve the memory in ischemic stroke rat. Int J Clin Exp Med. 2015;8(8):13109&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4612918</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26550233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Becerra-Calixto A, Cardona-G&#xf3;mez GP. Neuroprotection induced by transplanted CDK5 knockdown astrocytes in global cerebral ischemic rats. Mol Neurobiol. 2017;54(9):6681&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27744570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Becerra-Calixto A, Posada-Duque R, Cardona-G&#xf3;mez GP. Recovery of neurovascular unit integrity by CDK5-KD astrocyte transplantation in a global cerebral ischemia model. Mol Neurobiol. 2018;55(11):8563&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29564811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su SC, Tsai L-H. Cyclin-dependent kinases in brain development and disease. Annu Rev Cell Dev Biol. 2011;27:465&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21740229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer DA, Torres-Altoro MI, Tan Z, Tozzi A, Filippo M, Di DiNapoli V, Plattner F, Kansy JW, Benkovic SA, Huber JD, Miller DB, et al.. Ischemic stroke injury is mediated by aberrant Cdk5. J Neurosci. 2014;34(24):8259&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4051977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24920629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butenko O, Dzamba D, Benesova J, Honsa P, Benfenati V, Rusnakova V, Ferroni S, Anderova M. The increased activity of TRPV4 channel in the astrocytes of the adult rat hippocampus after cerebral hypoxia/ischemia. PLoS ONE. 2012;7(6):e39959.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3384594</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22761937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zanotti S, Charles A. Extracellular calcium sensing by glial cells: low extracellular calcium induces intracellular calcium release and intercellular signaling. J Neurochem. 1997;69(2):594&#x2013;602.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9231716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanaka M, Kawahara K, Kosugi T, Yamada T, Mioka T. Changes in the spontaneous calcium oscillations for the development of the preconditioning-induced ischemic tolerance in neuron/astrocyte co-culture. Neurochem Res. 2007;32(6):988&#x2013;1001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17401678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y, Mancuso J, Zhao Z, Li X, Cheng J, Roman G, Wong STC. Vasodilation by in vivo activation of astrocyte endfeet via two-photon calcium uncaging as a strategy to prevent brain ischemia. J Biomed Opt. 2013;18(12):126012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3865896</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24343443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gunnarson E, Song Y, Kowalewski JM, Brismar H, Brines M, Cerami A, Andersson U, Zelenina M, Aperia A. Erythropoietin modulation of astrocyte water permeability as a component of neuroprotection. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2009;106(5):1602&#x2013;607.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2629445</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19164545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vanzulli I, Butt AM. mGluR5 protect astrocytes from ischemic damage in postnatal CNS white matter. Cell Calcium. 2015;58(5):423&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4634333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26189008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashpole NM, Chawla AR, Martin MP, Brustovetskys T, Brustovetskys N, Hudmon A. Loss of calcium/calmodulin-dependent protein kinase II activity in cortical astrocytes decreases glutamate uptake and induces neurotoxic release of ATP. J Biol Chem. 2013;288(20):14599&#x2013;611.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3656312</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23543737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krebs C, Fernandes HB, Sheldon C, Raymond LA, Baimbridge KG. Functional NMDA receptor subtype 2B is expressed in astrocytes after ischemia in vivo and anoxia in vitro. J Neurosci. 2003;23(8):3364&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6742326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12716944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dugan LL, Kim-Han JS. Astrocyte mitochondria in in vitro models of ischemia. J Bioenerg Biomembr. 2004;36(4):317&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15377865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bambrick L, Kristian T, Fiskum G. Astrocyte mitochondrial mechanisms of ischemic brain injury and neuroprotection. Neurochem Res. 2004;29(3):601&#x2013;608.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15038607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nahirney PC, Reeson P, Brown CE. Ultrastructural analysis of blood-brain barrier breakdown in the peri-infarct zone in young adult and aged mice. J Cereb Blood Flow Metab. 2016;36(2):413&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4759675</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26661190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ouyang Y-B, Xu L, Liu S, Giffard RG. Role of astrocytes in delayed neuronal death: GLT-1 and its novel regulation by MicroRNAs. Adv Neurobiol. 2014;11:171&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4283583</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25236729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ouyang Y-B, Voloboueva LA, Xu L, Giffard RG. Selective dysfunction of hippocampal CA1 astrocytes contributes to delayed neuronal damage after transient forebrain ischemia. J Neurosci. 2007;27(16):4253&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3140959</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17442809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zvalova D, Cordier J, Mesnil M, Junier MP, Chneiweiss H. p38/SAPK2 controls gap junction closure in astrocytes. Glia. 2004;46(3):323&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15048855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao Q, Katakowski M, Chen X, Li Y, Chopp M. Human marrow stromal cells enhance connexin43 gap junction intercellular communication in cultured astrocytes. Cell Transplant. 2005;14(2&#x2013;3):109&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15881420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y, Wang L, Zhang L, Chen B, Yang L, Li X, Li Y, Yu H. Inhibition of connexin 43 hemichannels alleviates cerebral ischemia/reperfusion injury via the TLR4 signaling pathway. Front Cell Neurosci. 2018;12:372.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6199357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30386214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma D, Feng L, Cheng Y, Xin M, You J, Yin X, Hao Y, Cui L, Feng J. Astrocytic gap junction inhibition by carbenoxolone enhances the protective effects of ischemic preconditioning following cerebral ischemia. J Neuroinflammation. 2018;15(1):198.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6034345</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29976213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin X, Feng L, Ma D, Yin P, Wang X, Hou S, Hao Y, Zhang J, Xin M, Feng J. Roles of astrocytic connexin-43, hemichannels, and gap junctions in oxygen-glucose deprivation/reperfusion injury induced neuroinflammation and the possible regulatory mechanisms of salvianolic acid B and carbenoxolone. J Neuroinflammation. 2018;15(1):97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5872583</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29587860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giffard RG, Swanson RA. Ischemia-induced programmed cell death in astrocytes. Glia. 2005;50(4):299&#x2013;306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15846803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swanson R, Ying W, Kauppinen T. Astrocyte influences on ischemic neuronal death. Curr Mol Med. 2004;4(2):193&#x2013;205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15032713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsushita T, Masaki K, Suzuki S, Matsuoka T, Yonekawa T, Wu XM, Tabira T, Iwaki T, Kira JI. Astrocytopathy in neuromyelitis optica, multiple sclerosis and Bal&#xf3;&#x2019;s disease. Clin Neurol. 2011;51(11):898&#x2013;900.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22277409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chalazonitis A, Rao M. Enteric nervous system manifestations of neurodegenerative disease. Brain Res. 2018;1693(Pt B): 207&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6003851</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29360466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batiuk MY, Martirosyan A, Wahis J, de Vin F, Marneffe C, Kusserow C, Koeppen J, Viana JF, Oliveira JF, Voet T, Ponting CP, et al.. Identification of region-specific astrocyte subtypes at single cell resolution. Nat Commun. 2020;11(1):1220.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7058027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32139688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morel L, Chiang MSR, Higashimori H, Shoneye T, Iyer LK, Yelick J, Tai A, Yang Y. Molecular and functional properties of regional astrocytes in the adult brain. J Neurosci. 2017; 37(36):8706&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5588463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28821665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bradley RA, Shireman J, McFalls C, Choi J, Canfield SG, Dong Y, Liu K, Lisota B, Jones JR, Petersen A, Bhattacharyya A, et al.. Regionally specified human pluripotent stem cell-derived astrocytes exhibit different molecular signatures and functional properties. Development. 2019;146(13):dev170910.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6633609</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31189664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Molofsky AV, Kelley KW, Tsai H-H, Redmond SA, Chang SM, Madireddy L, Chan JR, Baranzini SE, Ullian EM, Rowitch DH. Astrocyte-encoded positional cues maintain sensorimotor circuit integrity. Nature. 2014;509(7499):189&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4057936</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24776795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsai HH, Li H, Fuentealba LC, Molofsky AV, Taveira-Marques R, Zhuang H, Tenney A, Murnen AT, Fancy SP, Merkle F, Kessaris N, Alvarez-Buylla A, et al.. Regional astrocyte allocation regulates CNS synaptogenesis and repair. Science. 2012;337(6092):358&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4059181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22745251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee SH, Kim WT, Cornell-Bell AH, Sontheimer H. Astrocytes exhibit regional specificity in gap-junction coupling. Glia. 1994;11(4):315&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7960035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schreyer DJ, Jones EG. Growth of corticospinal axons on prosthetic substrates introduced into the spinal cord of neonatal rats. Brain Res. 1987;432(2):291&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3676843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qian J, Bull MS, Levitt P. Target-derived astroglia regulate axonal outgrowth in a region-specific manner. Dev Biol. 1992;149(2):278&#x2013;294.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1730385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keirstead HS, Nistor G, Bernal G, Totoiu M, Cloutier F, Sharp K, Steward O. Human embryonic stem cell-derived oligodendrocyte progenitor cell transplants remyelinate and restore locomotion after spinal cord injury. J Neurosci. 2005;25(19):4694&#x2013;705.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6724772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15888645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Namekawa M, Takiyama Y, Aoki Y, Takayashiki N, Sakoe K, Shimazaki H, Taguchi T, Tanaka Y, Nishizawa M, Saito K, Matsubara Y, et al.. Identification of GFAP gene mutation in hereditary adult-onset Alexander&#x2019;s disease. Ann Neurol. 2002;52(6):779&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12447932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han X, Chen M, Wang F, Windrem M, Wang S, Shanz S, Xu Q, Oberheim NA, Bekar L, Betstadt S, Silva AJ, et al.. Forebrain engraftment by human glial progenitor cells enhances synaptic plasticity and learning in adult mice. Cell Stem Cell. 2013;12(3):342&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3700554</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23472873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeanson T, Pondaven A, Ezan P, Mouthon F, Charv&#xe9;riat M, Giaume C. Antidepressants impact connexin 43 channel functions in astrocytes. Front Cell Neurosci. 2016;9:495.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4703821</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26778961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Windrem MS, Osipovitch M, Liu Z, Bates J, Chandler-Militello D, Zou L, Munir J, Schanz S, McCoy K, Miller RH, Wang S, et al.. Human iPSC glial mouse chimeras reveal glial contributions to schizophrenia. Cell Stem Cell. 2017;21(2):195&#x2013;208.e6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5576346</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28736215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Das MM, Avalos P, Suezaki P, Godoy M, Garcia L, Chang CD, Vit JP, Shelley B, Gowing G, Svendsen CN. Human neural progenitors differentiate into astrocytes and protect motor neurons in aging rats. Exp Neurol. 2016;280:41&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27032721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kriz J, Nguyen MD, Julien JP. Minocycline slows disease progression in a mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurobiol Dis. 2002;10(3):268&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12270689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drachman DB, Frank K, Dykes-Hoberg M, Teismann P, Almer G, Przedborski S, Rothstein JD. Cyclooxygenase 2 inhibition protects motor neurons and prolongs survival in a transgenic mouse model of ALS. Ann Neurol. 2002;52(6):771&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12447931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>