<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35775096</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>04</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1440-1789</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>42</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Neuropathology : official journal of the Japanese Society of Neuropathology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Neuropathology</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>An autopsy case of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with striatonigral and pallidoluysian degeneration and cat's-eye-shaped neuronal nuclear inclusions.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>329</StartPage><EndPage>338</EndPage><MedlinePgn>329-338</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/neup.12843</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>We report the case of a Japanese woman with sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) of 28&#x2009;months' duration who died at the age of 66&#x2009;years. Postmortem examination revealed moderate loss of neurons and phosphorylated TDP-43 (p-TDP-43)-immunoreactive neuronal and glial cytoplasmic inclusions in the upper and lower motor neurons. Additionally, marked neuronal loss was observed in the neostriatum, globus pallidum, subthalamic nucleus, and substantia nigra. p-TDP-43-immunoreactive inclusions were frequently found in these areas. Neuronal loss and TDP-43 pathology in the motor, striatonigral, and pallidoluysian systems were predominant on the right side. Moreover, p-TDP-43-immunoreactive cat's-eye-shaped neuronal nuclear inclusions (NNIs) were observed in the affected lesions. NNIs in the striatonigral system were also positive for valosin-containing protein (VCP). We diagnosed the patient as having ALS with striatonigral and pallidoluysian degeneration. Patients with ALS rarely experience pallido-nigro-luysian degeneration. To our best knowledge, only one case of ALS combined with striatonigral and pallidoluysian degeneration has been reported. Neuronal loss in the striatonigral and/or pallidoluysian systems has also been reported in patients with ALS with multisystem degeneration accompanied by long-term use of an artificial respirator. Based on these findings, a possibility of an extremely rare subtype of ALS demonstrating selective loss of neurons in the striatonigral and pallidoluysian systems exists; another possibility is that this type could be an early stage or forme fruste of ALS with multisystem degeneration. Although VCP-positive cat's-eye-shaped NNIs have been reported in spinocerebellar ataxia type-2 cases, our case report presents VCP-positive NNIs in a patient with ALS for the first time.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022 Japanese Society of Neuropathology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kon</LastName><ForeName>Tomoya</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6072-3954</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Institute of Brain Science, Hirosaki University Graduate School of Medicine, Hirosaki, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mori</LastName><ForeName>Fumiaki</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuropathology, Institute of Brain Science, Hirosaki University Graduate School of Medicine, Hirosaki, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kinoshita</LastName><ForeName>Iku</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Institute of Brain Science, Hirosaki University Graduate School of Medicine, Hirosaki, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nakamura</LastName><ForeName>Takashi</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Institute of Brain Science, Hirosaki University Graduate School of Medicine, Hirosaki, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nishijima</LastName><ForeName>Haruo</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Institute of Brain Science, Hirosaki University Graduate School of Medicine, Hirosaki, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Suzuki</LastName><ForeName>Chieko</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Institute of Brain Science, Hirosaki University Graduate School of Medicine, Hirosaki, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Goto</LastName><ForeName>Shintaro</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathology and Bioscience, Hirosaki University Graduate School of Medicine, Hirosaki, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kijima</LastName><ForeName>Hiroshi</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathology and Bioscience, Hirosaki University Graduate School of Medicine, Hirosaki, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tomiyama</LastName><ForeName>Masahiko</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Institute of Brain Science, Hirosaki University Graduate School of Medicine, Hirosaki, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wakabayashi</LastName><ForeName>Koichi</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3756-7209</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuropathology, Institute of Brain Science, Hirosaki University Graduate School of Medicine, Hirosaki, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>20K16592</GrantID><Agency>Japan Society for the Promotion of Science</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><Agency>JSPS</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Australia</Country><MedlineTA>Neuropathology</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9606526</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0919-6544</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D004268">DNA-Binding Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001344" MajorTopicYN="N">Autopsy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004268" MajorTopicYN="N">DNA-Binding Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D045586" MajorTopicYN="N">Intranuclear Inclusion Bodies</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009046" MajorTopicYN="N">Motor Neurons</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">TDP-43</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neuronal nuclear inclusion</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pallidonigroluysian degeneration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">valosin-containing protein</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>50</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35775096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/neup.12843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Neumann M, Sampathu DM, Kwong LK et al. Ubiquitinated TDP-43 in frontotemporal lobar degeneration and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Science 2006; 314: 130-133.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arai T, Hasegawa M, Akiyama H et al. TDP-43 is a component of ubiquitin-positive tau-negative inclusions in frontotemporal lobar degeneration and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Biochem Biophys Res Commun 2006; 351: 602-611.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ito J, Shimizu H, Ohta K et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with pallidonigroluysian degeneration: A clinicopathological study. Ann Neurol 2020; 87: 302-312.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piao YS, Wakabayashi K, Kakita A et al. Neuropathology with clinical correlations of sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: 102 autopsy cases examined between 1962 and 2000. Brain Pathol 2003; 13: 10-22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gray F, Eizenbaum JF, Gherardi R, Degos JD, Poirier J. Luyso-pallido-nigral atrophy and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathol 1985; 66: 78-82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gray F, De Baecque C, Serdaru M, Escourolle R. Pallido-luyso-nigral atrophy and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathol 1981; 7: 348-351.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasegawa K, Kowa H, Yagishita S. Extrapyramidal system involvement in motor neuron disease. J Neurol Sci 1992; 108: 137-148.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergmann M, Kuchelmeister K, Migheli A, Schiffer D, Gullotta F. Motor neuron disease with pallido-luysio-nigral atrophy. Acta Neuropathol 1993; 86: 105-108.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kato S, Oda M, Murahashi M, Suda N. Motor neuron disease with involvement of the pallido-luysio-nigral system and mesencephalic tegmentum. Neuropathology 1995; 14: 241-244.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hashimoto T, Matsubara S, Mochizuki Y, Tsuji S, Mizutani T, Oyanagi K. Forme fruste or incipient form of widespread-type amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, or motor neuron disease with pallido-nigro-luysian atrophy? An autopsy case report. Neuropathology 2008; 28: 309-316.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uchino A, Ogino M, Takahashi-Fujigasaki J et al. Pathological and immunoblot analysis of phosphorylated TDP-43 in sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with pallido-nigro-luysian degeneration. Neuropathology 2018; 38: 171-178.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miki Y, Mori F, Nunomura J et al. Sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with pallido-nigro-luysian degeneration: A TDP-43 immunohistochemical study. Neuropathology 2010; 30: 149-153.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudo S, Fukutani Y, Matsubara R et al. Motor neuron disease with dementia combined with degeneration of striatonigral and pallidoluysian systems. Acta Neuropathol 2002; 103: 521-525.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishihira Y, Tan CF, Toyoshima Y et al. Sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Widespread multisystem degeneration with TDP-43 pathology in a patient after long-term survival on a respirator. Neuropathology 2009; 29: 689-696.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayashi K, Mochizuki Y, Takeuchi R et al. Clinicopathological characteristics of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis resulting in a totally locked-in state (communication stage V). Acta Neuropathol Commun 2016; 4: 107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geevasinga N, Loy CT, Menon P et al. Awaji criteria improves the diagnostic sensitivity in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A systematic review using individual patient data. Clin Neurophysiol 2016; 127: 2684-2691.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braak H, Alafuzoff I, Arzberger T, Kretzschmar H, Del Tredici K. Staging of Alzheimer disease-associated neurofibrillary pathology using paraffin sections and immunocytochemistry. Acta Neuropathol 2006; 112: 389-404.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brettschneider J, Del Tredici K, Toledo JB et al. Stages of pTDP-43 pathology in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol 2013; 74: 20-38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braak H, Brettschneider J, Ludolph AC, Lee VM, Trojanowski JQ, Del Tredici K. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-A model of corticofugal axonal spread. Nat Rev Neurol 2013; 9: 708-714.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quartarone A, Cacciola A, Milardi D et al. New insights into cortico-basal-cerebellar connectome: Clinical and physiological considerations. Brain 2020; 143: 396-406.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackenzie IR, Feldman H. Neuronal intranuclear inclusions distinguish familial FTD-MND type from sporadic cases. Acta Neuropathol 2003; 105: 543-548.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackenzie IR, Neumann M, Baborie A et al. A harmonized classification system for FTLD-TDP pathology. Acta Neuropathol 2011; 122: 111-113.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee EB, Porta S, Michael Baer G et al. Expansion of the classification of FTLD-TDP: Distinct pathology associated with rapidly progressive frontotemporal degeneration. Acta Neuropathol 2017; 134: 65-78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsubara T, Izumi Y, Oda M et al. An autopsy report of a familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis case carrying VCP Arg487His mutation with a unique TDP-43 proteinopathy. Neuropathology 2021; 41: 118-126.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seilhean D, Takahashi J, El Hachimi KH et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with neuronal intranuclear protein inclusions. Acta Neuropathol 2004; 108: 81-87.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kakita A, Oyanagi K, Nagai H, Takahashi H. Eosinophilic intranuclear inclusions in the hippocampal pyramidal neurons of a patient with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathol 1997; 93: 532-536.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin WL, Dickson DW. Ultrastructural localization of TDP-43 in filamentous neuronal inclusions in various neurodegenerative diseases. Acta Neuropathol 2008; 116: 205-213.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson MA, Klickstein JA, Khanna R et al. Molecular and clinical insights into neurodegeneration and myopathy linked to multisystem proteinopathy-1 (MSP-1). Neurobiol Dis 2021; 2022: 105722.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayaki T, Ito H, Fukushima H et al. Immunoreactivity of valosin-containing protein in sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and in a case of its novel mutant. Acta Neuropathol Commun 2014; 2: 172.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishikawa H, Yasui K, Oketa Y, Suzuki M, Ono S. Increased expression of valosin-containing protein in the skin of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Clin Neurosci 2012; 19: 522-526.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mori F, Tanji K, Toyoshima Y et al. Valosin-containing protein immunoreactivity in tauopathies, synucleinopathies, polyglutamine diseases and intranuclear inclusion body disease. Neuropathology 2013; 33: 637-644.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirabayashi M, Inoue K, Tanaka K et al. VCP/p97 in abnormal protein aggregates, cytoplasmic vacuoles, and cell death, phenotypes relevant to neurodegeneration. Cell Death Differ 2001; 8: 977-984.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koike M, Fukushi J, Ichinohe Y et al. Valosin-containing protein (VCP) in novel feedback machinery between abnormal protein accumulation and transcriptional suppression. J Biol Chem 2010; 285: 21736-21749.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mori F, Toyoshima Y, Tanji K, Kakita A, Takahashi H, Wakabayashi K. FUS colocalizes with polyglutamine, but not with TDP-43 in neuronal intranuclear inclusions in spinocerebellar ataxia type 2. Neuropathol Appl Neurobiol 2014; 40: 351-355.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Sarraj S, King A, Troakes C et al. p62 positive, TDP-43 negative, neuronal cytoplasmic and intranuclear inclusions in the cerebellum and hippocampus define the pathology of C9orf72-linked FTLD and MND/ALS. Acta Neuropathol 2011; 122: 691-702.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer H, Weihl CC. The VCP/p97 system at a glance: Connecting cellular function to disease pathogenesis. J Cell Sci 2014; 127: 3877-3883.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>