<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35808978</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1468-1331</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>29</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Predictive parameters of early respiratory decline in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>3170</StartPage><EndPage>3176</EndPage><MedlinePgn>3170-3176</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/ene.15486</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND PURPOSE">Respiratory insufficiency is a common symptom during the course of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). The diagnostic workup may be challenging and includes a wide array of diagnostic measures. In this study, the aim was to analyze the relationship between hypercapnia-associated symptoms, blood gas parameters and pulmonary function tests.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">In total, 109 patients (56 women, 53 men, 62.4&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;11.9&#x2009;years) with definite, possible or probable ALS according to El Escorial criteria were included. All patients received either arterial blood gas analysis, nocturnal capnometry or both. Pulmonary function was assessed by spirometry and peak cough flow. Clinical symptoms potentially indicating hypercapnia were assessed using 17 dichotomous (yes/no) items.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Of 109 ALS patients, 40 had hypercapnia. The highest accuracy and specificity for predicting hypercapnia was observed for dyspnea at rest (Youden's index 17%, 95% confidence interval [CI] 2%-34%; sensitivity 23%, 95% CI 9%-38%; specificity 95%, 95% CI 88%-100%). Daytime fatigue yielded the highest sensitivity of 58% (95% CI 40%-76%). Logistic regression for all assessed symptoms combined yielded an area under the receiver operating charteristic curve of 0.8 (95% CI 0.7-0.9). Compared to the clinical symptoms, forced vital capacity and peak cough flow showed higher sensitivity (70% and 87%, respectively) but lacked specificity (33% and 20%).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">Evaluation of the presence of hypercapnic symptoms can be utilized to predict incipient respiratory insufficiency and should complement pulmonary function tests. Further studies are needed to validate specific questionnaires in this regard. No single hypercapnia-associated symptom or pulmonary function test on its own seems sufficient to safely predict hypercapnia.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022 The Authors. European Journal of Neurology published by John Wiley &amp;amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of European Academy of Neurology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Michels</LastName><ForeName>Sebastian</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9265-9034</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of Ulm, Ulm, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Widmann</LastName><ForeName>Paul</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of Ulm, Ulm, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rapp</LastName><ForeName>Daniel</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of Ulm, Ulm, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Willkomm</LastName><ForeName>Frank</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of Ulm, Ulm, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ludolph</LastName><ForeName>Albert C</ForeName><Initials>AC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of Ulm, Ulm, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>German Center of Neurodegenerative Diseases (DZNE), Ulm, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dorst</LastName><ForeName>Johannes</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6352-0909</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of Ulm, Ulm, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>German Center of Neurodegenerative Diseases (DZNE), Ulm, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9506311</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1351-5101</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003371" MajorTopicYN="N">Cough</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006935" MajorTopicYN="N">Hypercapnia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012129" MajorTopicYN="N">Respiratory Function Tests</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012131" MajorTopicYN="Y">Respiratory Insufficiency</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hypercapnia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">respiratory function</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35808978</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ene.15486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>van Es MA, Hardiman O, Chio A, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet. 2017;390(10107):2084-2098.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dorst J, Behrendt G, Ludolph AC. Non-invasive ventilation and hypercapnia-associated symptoms in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neurol Scand. 2019;139(2):128-134.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butz M, Wollinsky KH, Wiedemuth-Catrinescu U, et al. Longitudinal effects of noninvasive positive-pressure ventilation in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2003;82(8):597-604.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen PM, Abrahams S, Borasio GD, et al. EFNS guidelines on the clinical management of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (MALS)-revised report of an EFNS task force. Eur J Neurol. 2012;19(3):360-375.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ringel SP, Murphy JR, Alderson MK, et al. The natural history of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology. 1993;43(7):1316.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dorst J, Ludolph AC. Non-invasive ventilation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ther Adv Neurol Disord. 2019;12:175628641985704.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bourke SC, Tomlinson M, Williams TL, Bullock RE, Shaw PJ, Gibson GJ. Effects of non-invasive ventilation on survival and quality of life in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a randomised controlled trial. Lancet Neurol. 2006;5:140-147.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ackrivo J, Hsu JY, Hansen-Flaschen J, Elman L, Kawut SM. Noninvasive ventilation use is associated with better survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Am Thorac Soc. 2021;18(3):486-494.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tilanus TBM, Groothuis JT, TenBroek-Pastoor JMC, et al. The predictive value of respiratory function tests for non-invasive ventilation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Respir Res. 2017;18(1):144.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mellies U, Goebel C. Optimum insufflation capacity and peak cough flow in neuromuscular disorders. Ann Am Thorac Soc. 2014;11(10):1560-1568.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lechtzin N, Cudkowicz ME, de Carvalho M, et al. Respiratory measures in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2018;19:321-330.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardiman O. Management of respiratory symptoms in ALS. J Neurol. 2011;258:359-365.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinto S, Pinto A, De Carvalho M. Do bulbar-onset amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients have an earlier respiratory involvement than spinal-onset amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients? Eura Medicophys. 2007;43(4):505-509.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manera U, Torrieri MC, Moglia C, et al. The role of arterial blood gas analysis (ABG) in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis respiratory monitoring. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2020;91:999-1000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boentert M, Brenscheidt I, Glatz C, Young P. Effects of non-invasive ventilation on objective sleep and nocturnal respiration in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol. 2015;262(9):2073-2082.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim SM, Park KS, Nam H, et al. Capnography for assessing nocturnal hypoventilation and predicting compliance with subsequent noninvasive ventilation in patients with ALS. PLoS One. 2011;6(3):e17893.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atalaia A, De Carvalho M, Evangelista T, Pinto A. Sleep characteristics of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in patients with preserved diaphragmatic function. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2007;8(2):101-105.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, Miller RG, Swash M, Munsat TL. El Escorial revisited: revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2000;1(5):293-299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barreiro TJ, Perillo I. An approach to interpreting spirometry. Am Fam Physician. 2004;69:1107-1114.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boentert M, Glatz C, Helmle C, Okegwo A, Young P. Prevalence of sleep apnoea and capnographic detection of nocturnal hypoventilation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2018;89(4):418-424.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dougan CF, Connell CO, Thornton E, Young CA. Development of a patient-specific dyspnoea questionnaire in motor neurone disease (MND): the MND Dyspnoea Rating Scale (MDRS). J Neurol Sci. 2000;180(1-2):86-93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vogt S, Schreiber S, Kollewe K, et al. Dyspnea in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: the dyspnea-ALS-scale (DALS-15) essentially contributes to the diagnosis of respiratory impairment. Respir Med. 2019;154:116-121.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Just N, Bautin N, Danel-Brunaud V, Debroucker V, Matran R, Perez T. The Borg dyspnoea score: a relevant clinical marker of inspiratory muscle weakness in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Eur Respir J. 2010;35(2):353-360.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller RG, Jackson CE, Kasarskis EJ, et al. Practice parameter update: the care of the patient with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: drug, nutritional, and respiratory therapies (an evidence-based review): report of the quality standards subcommittee of the American Academy of Neurology. Neurology. 2009;73(15):1218-1226.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>