<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">35833745</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1538-9766</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>45</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><MedlineDate>2022 Jul-Aug 01</MedlineDate></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Gastroenterology nursing : the official journal of the Society of Gastroenterology Nurses and Associates</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Gastroenterol Nurs</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Exploring Gastrostomy Care-Related Information Needs in Patients With Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis and Their Families.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>231</StartPage><EndPage>237</EndPage><MedlinePgn>231-237</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/SGA.0000000000000651</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The aim of this study was to explore gastrostomy care-related information needs in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) patients and their families. This was a quantitative content analysis. Data were collected from a major online patient community in Korea by analyzing posted free texts. A total of 173 posted free texts from January 2010 to July 2020 from the "question and answer" bulletin board were analyzed. Questions were mostly asked by the adult children of patients, and the most frequent question period was "after hospital discharge." The commonly mentioned topics related to gastrostomy and G-tube complications. Patients with ALS and their families have a high requirement for gastrostomy care and enteral feeding information. These findings indicate that there is a need to support decision-making for gastrostomy in hospitals and to provide information about G-tube care and enteral nutrition after leaving the hospital. This information and coaching/support for patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and their families currently appears to be obtained mainly through online patient communities. Both hospital and home care nurses could play a greater role in providing this information.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022 Society of Gastroenterology Nurses and Associates.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chu</LastName><ForeName>Hyeon Sik</ForeName><Initials>HS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hyeon Sik Chu, MSN, RN, is Doctoral Student, College of Nursing, Hanyang University, Seoul, South Korea; ALS/MND Clinic, Hanyang University Seoul Hospital, Seoul, South Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Young Ran Tak, PhD, RN, is Professor, College of Nursing, Hanyang University, Seoul, South Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tak</LastName><ForeName>Young Ran</ForeName><Initials>YR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hyeon Sik Chu, MSN, RN, is Doctoral Student, College of Nursing, Hanyang University, Seoul, South Korea; ALS/MND Clinic, Hanyang University Seoul Hospital, Seoul, South Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Young Ran Tak, PhD, RN, is Professor, College of Nursing, Hanyang University, Seoul, South Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Gastroenterol Nurs</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8915377</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1042-895X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004750" MajorTopicYN="N">Enteral Nutrition</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005774" MajorTopicYN="Y">Gastrostomy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D056910" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Republic of Korea</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D032721" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult Children</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35833745</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/SGA.0000000000000651</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00001610-202207000-00003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bartlett Y. K., Coulson N. S. (2011). An investigation into the empowerment effects of using online support groups and how this affects health professional/patient communication. Patient Education and Counseling, 83(1), 113&#x2013;119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bassola B., Lusignani M. (2017). Self-care in people with motor neuron disease: An integrative review. Journal of Neuroscience Nursing, 49(5), 311&#x2013;317.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown R. H., Al-Chalabi A. (2017). Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. New England Journal of Medicine, 377(2), 162&#x2013;172.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chu H. S., Oh J. (2020). Information needs and preferences of family caregivers of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Journal of Neuroscience Nursing, 52(5), 207&#x2013;213.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dollard K., Dunn S. (2004). Development and evaluation of an innovative community-based PEG support service. Gastroenterology Nursing, 27(4), 156&#x2013;162.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>EFNS Task Force on Diagnosis and Management of Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis; Andersen P. M., Abrahams S., Borasio G. D., de Carvalho M., Chio A., Weber M. (2012). EFNS guidelines on the clinical management of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (MALS)&#x2013;revised report of an EFNS task force. European Journal of Neurology, 19(3), 360&#x2013;375.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Estacio E. V., Whittle R., Protheroe J. (2019). The digital divide: Examining socio-demographic factors associated with health literacy, access and use of internet to seek health information. Journal of Health Psychology, 24(12), 1668&#x2013;1675.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griffiths J., Lewis D. (2002). Guidelines for the oral care of patients who are dependent, dysphagic or critically ill. Journal of Disability and Oral Health, 3(1), 30&#x2013;33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gye V., Mortensen M. B. (2018). Nurse-assisted percutaneous endoscopic gastrostomy tube placement is a safe procedure in adult patients. Gastroenterology Nursing, 41(3), 219&#x2013;222.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hogden A., Greenfield D., Nugus P., Kiernan M. C. (2015). Development of a model to guide decision making in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis multidisciplinary care. Health Expectations, 18(5), 1769&#x2013;1782.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hucl T., Spicak J. (2016). Complications of percutaneous endoscopic gastrostomy. Best Practice &amp; Research Clinical Gastroenterology, 30(5), 769&#x2013;781.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jun K. Y., Park J., Oh K. W., Kim E. M., Bae J. S., Kim I., Kim S. H. (2019). Epidemiology of ALS in Korea using nationwide big data. Journal of Neurology, Neurosurgery &amp; Psychiatry, 90(4), 395&#x2013;403.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klek S., Szybinski P., Sierzega M., Szczepanek K., Sumlet M., Kupiec M., Kulig J. (2011). Commercial enteral formulas and nutrition support teams improve the outcome of home enteral tube feeding. Journal of Parenteral and Enteral Nutrition, 35(3), 380&#x2013;385.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muoki D. C. (2020). Decisional conflict in percutaneous gastrostomy tube placement in adults: An integrative review of the literature. Gastroenterology Nursing, 43(5), 355&#x2013;362.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh J., Kim J. A. (2017). Information-seeking behavior and information needs in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Analyzing an online patient community. Computers, Informatics, Nursing, 35(7), 345&#x2013;351.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ProGas Study Group. (2015). Gastrostomy in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ProGas): A prospective cohort study. The Lancet Neurology, 14(7), 702&#x2013;709.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarkar P., Cole A., Scolding N. J., Rice C. M. (2017). Percutaneous endoscopic gastrostomy tube insertion in neurodegenerative disease: A retrospective study and literature review. Clinical Endoscopy, 50(3), 270&#x2013;278.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seo Y. J., Lee M. K. (2019). Performance and impediments to patient and family education among home health care nurses. Journal of Korean Academic Society of Home Health Care Nursing, 26(3), 329&#x2013;340.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sezer R. E., Ozdemir Koken Z., Senol Celik S. (2020). Home percutaneous endoscopic gastrostomy feeding: Difficulties and needs of caregivers, qualitative study. Journal of Parenteral and Enteral Nutrition, 44(3), 525&#x2013;533.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simmers P. (2019). Development of a new nurse navigator program. Journal of Oncology Navigation &amp; Survivorship, 10(11).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stavroulakis T., Baird W. O., Baxter S. K., Walsh T., Shaw P. J., McDermott C. J. (2014). Factors influencing decision-making in relation to timing of gastrostomy insertion in patients with motor neurone disease. BMJ Supportive &amp; Palliative Care, 4(1), 57&#x2013;63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stavroulakis T., Baird W. O., Baxter S. K., Walsh T., Shaw P. J., McDermott C. J. (2016). The impact of gastrostomy in motor neurone disease: Challenges and benefits from a patient and carer perspective. BMJ Supportive &amp; Palliative Care, 6(1), 52&#x2013;59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suluhan D., Yildiz D., Surer I., Fidanci Eren B., Balamtekin N. (2020). Effect of gastrostomy tube feeding education on parents of children with gastrostomy. Nutrition in Clinical Practice. Advance online publication. doi:10.1002/ncp.10586</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tay C. M., Howe J., Borromeo G. L. (2014). Oral health and dental treatment needs of people with motor neurone disease. Australian Dental Journal, 59(3), 309&#x2013;313.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Es M. A., Hardiman O., Chio A., Al-Chalabi A., Pasterkamp R. J., Veldink J. H., Van den Berg L. H. (2017). Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. The Lancet, 390(10107), 2084&#x2013;2098.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoo E. K., Suh M. J. (2000). A study on the perception of the importance and performance of patient education of the clinical nurses. The Journal of Korean Academic Society of Nursing Education, 6(2):287&#x2013;302.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu P., Shen J., Xu M. (2020). Study on the evolution of information sharing strategy for users of online patient community. Personal and Ubiquitous Computing, doi:10.1007/s00779-020-01464-6</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>