<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35908282</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>31</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1600-0854</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>23</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Traffic (Copenhagen, Denmark)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Traffic</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Defective axonal transport of endo-lysosomes and dense core vesicles in a Drosophila model of C9-ALS/FTD.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>430</StartPage><EndPage>441</EndPage><MedlinePgn>430-441</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/tra.12861</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>A GGGGCC (G<sub>4</sub> C<sub>2</sub> ) repeat expansion in the C9orf72 gene is the most common genetic cause of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) and frontotemporal dementia (FTD). Although disruptions in axonal transport are implicated in the pathogenesis of multiple neurodegenerative diseases, the underlying mechanisms causing these defects remain unclear. Here, we performed live imaging of Drosophila motor neurons expressing expanded G<sub>4</sub> C<sub>2</sub> repeats in third-instar larvae and investigated the axonal transport of multiple organelles in vivo. Expression of expanded G<sub>4</sub> C<sub>2</sub> repeats causes an increase in static axonal lysosomes, while it impairs trafficking of late endosomes (LEs) and dense core vesicles (DCVs). Surprisingly, however, axonal transport of mitochondria is unaffected in motor axons expressing expanded G<sub>4</sub> C<sub>2</sub> repeats. Thus, our data indicate that expanded G<sub>4</sub> C<sub>2</sub> repeat expression differentially impacts axonal transport of vesicular organelles and mitochondria in Drosophila models of C9orf72-associated ALS/FTD.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022 John Wiley &amp; Sons A/S. Published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sung</LastName><ForeName>Hyun</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3451-1442</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, School of Medicine, Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, Maryland, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Solomon H. Snyder Department of Neuroscience, School of Medicine, Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, Maryland, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lloyd</LastName><ForeName>Thomas E</ForeName><Initials>TE</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4756-3700</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, School of Medicine, Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, Maryland, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Solomon H. Snyder Department of Neuroscience, School of Medicine, Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, Maryland, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Acronym>NH</Acronym><Agency>NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01 NS094239</GrantID><Acronym>NS</Acronym><Agency>NINDS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Traffic</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100939340</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1398-9219</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000073885">C9orf72 Protein</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001370" MajorTopicYN="N">Axonal Transport</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000073885" MajorTopicYN="N">C9orf72 Protein</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D042622" MajorTopicYN="N">DNA Repeat Expansion</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000088482" MajorTopicYN="N">Dense Core Vesicles</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004330" MajorTopicYN="N">Drosophila</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Frontotemporal Dementia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008247" MajorTopicYN="N">Lysosomes</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">C9-ALS/FTD</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">axonal transport</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dense core vesicle</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">drosophila</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">endo-lysosome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mitochondria</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">motor neuron</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35908282</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/tra.12861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Kiernan MC, Vucic S, Cheah BC, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. The Lancet. 2011;377:942-955. doi:10.1016/S0140-6736(10)61156-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor JP, Brown RH, Cleveland DW. Decoding ALS: from genes to mechanism. Nature. 2016;539:197-206. doi:10.1038/nature20413</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greaves CV, Rohrer JD. An update on genetic frontotemporal dementia. J Neurol. 2019;266:2075-2086. doi:10.1007/s00415-019-09363-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ling SC, Polymenidou M, Cleveland DW. Converging mechanisms in als and FTD: disrupted RNA and protein homeostasis. Neuron. 2013;79:416-438. doi:10.1016/j.neuron.2013.07.033</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abramzon YA, Fratta P, Traynor BJ, Chia R. The overlapping genetics of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal dementia. Front Neurosci. 2020;14:1-10. doi:10.3389/fnins.2020.00042</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeJesus-Hernandez M, Mackenzie IR, Boeve BF, et al. Expanded GGGGCC Hexanucleotide repeat in noncoding region of C9ORF72 causes chromosome 9p-linked FTD and ALS. Neuron. 2011;72:245-256. doi:10.1016/j.neuron.2011.09.011</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renton AE, Majounie E, Waite A, et al. A hexanucleotide repeat expansion in C9ORF72 is the cause of chromosome 9p21-linked ALS-FTD. Neuron. 2011;72:257-268. doi:10.1016/j.neuron.2011.09.010</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu W, Xu J. C9orf72 dipeptide repeats cause selective neurodegeneration and cell-autonomous excitotoxicity in drosophila glutamatergic neurons. J Neurosci. 2018;38:7741-7752. doi:10.1523/JNEUROSCI.0908-18.2018</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mizielinska S, Gr&#xf6;nke S, Niccoli T, et al. C9orf72 repeat expansions cause neurodegeneration in drosophila through arginine-rich proteins. Science. 2014;345:1192-1194. doi:10.1126/science.1256800</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Vos KJ, Hafezparast M. Neurobiology of axonal transport defects in motor neuron diseases: opportunities for translational research? Neurobiol Dis. 2017;105:283-299. doi:10.1016/j.nbd.2017.02.004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo W, Stoklund Dittlau K, Van Den Bosch L. Axonal transport defects and neurodegeneration: molecular mechanisms and therapeutic implications. Semin Cell Dev Biol. 2020;99:133-150. doi:10.1016/j.semcdb.2019.07.010</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maday S, Twelvetrees AE, Moughamian AJ, Holzbaur ELF. Axonal transport: cargo-specific mechanisms of motility and regulation. Neuron. 2014;84:292-309. doi:10.1016/j.neuron.2014.10.019</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guedes-Dias P, Holzbaur ELF. Axonal transport: driving synaptic function. Science. 2019;366:1-13. doi:10.1126/science.aaw9997</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sleigh JN, Rossor AM, Fellows AD, Tosolini AP, Schiavo G. Axonal transport and neurological disease. Nat Rev Neurol. 2019;15:691-703. doi:10.1038/s41582-019-0257-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Vos KJ, Grierson AJ, Ackerley S, Miller CCJ. Role of axonal transport in neurodegenerative diseases. Annu Rev Neurosci. 2008;31:151-173. doi:10.1146/annurev.neuro.31.061307.090711</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burton PR, Paige JL. Polarity of axoplasmic microtubules in the olfactory nerve of the frog. Proc Natl Acad Sci. 1981;78:3269-3273. doi:10.1073/pnas.78.5.3269</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rao AN, Baas PW. Polarity sorting of microtubules in the axon. Trends Neurosci. 2018;41:77-88. doi:10.1016/j.tins.2017.11.002</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirokawa N, Sato-Yoshitake R, Yoshida T, Kawashima T. Brain dynein (MAP1C) localizes on both anterogradely and retrogradely transported membranous organelles in vivo. J Cell Biol. 1990;111:1027-1037. doi:10.1083/jcb.111.3.1027</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirokawa N, Sato-Yoshitake R, Kobayashi N, Pfister KK, Bloom GS, Brady ST. Kinesin associates with anterogradely transported membranous organelles in vivo. J Cell Biol. 1991;114:295-302. doi:10.1083/jcb.114.2.295</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirokawa N, Niwa S, Tanaka Y. Molecular motors in neurons: transport mechanisms and roles in brain function, development, and disease. Neuron. 2010;68:610-638. doi:10.1016/j.neuron.2010.09.039</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirokawa N, Takemura R. Molecular motors and mechanisms of directional transport in neurons. Nat Rev Neurosci. 2005;6:201-214. doi:10.1038/nrn1624</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith BN, Ticozzi N, Fallini C, et al. Exome-wide rare variant analysis identifies TUBA4A mutations associated with familial ALS. Neuron. 2014;84:324-331. doi:10.1016/j.neuron.2014.09.027</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P&#xe9;rez-Brangul&#xed; F, Mishra HK, Prots I, et al. Dysfunction of spatacsin leads to axonal pathology in SPG11-linked hereditary spastic paraplegia. Hum Mol Genet. 2014;23:4859-4874. doi:10.1093/hmg/ddu200</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taes I, Timmers M, Hersmus N, et al. Hdac6 deletion delays disease progression in the sod1g93a mouse model of als. Hum Mol Genet. 2013;22:1783-1790. doi:10.1093/hmg/ddt028</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fazal R, Boeynaems S, Swijsen A, et al. HDAC6 inhibition restores TDP-43 pathology and axonal transport defects in human motor neurons with TARDBP mutations. EMBO J. 2021;40:e106177. doi:10.15252/embj.2020106177</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Majid T, Ali YO, Venkitaramani DV, Jang MK, Lu HC, Pautler RG. In vivo axonal transport deficits in a mouse model of fronto-temporal dementia. NeuroImage Clin. 2014;4:711-717. doi:10.1016/j.nicl.2014.02.005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brenner D, Yilmaz R, M&#xfc;ller K, et al. Hot-spot KIF5A mutations cause familial ALS. Brain. 2018;141:688-697. doi:10.1093/brain/awx370</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicolas A, Kenna K, Renton AE, et al. Genome-wide analyses identify KIF5A as a novel ALS gene. Neuron. 2018;97:1268-1283.e6. doi:10.1016/j.neuron.2018.02.027</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saez-Atienzar S, Dalgard CL, Ding J, et al. Identification of a pathogenic intronic KIF5A mutation in an ALS-FTD kindred. Neurology. 2020;95:1015-1018. doi:10.1212/WNL.0000000000011064</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;nch C, Sedlmeier R, Meyer T, et al. Point mutations of the p150 subunit of dynactin (DCTN1) gene ALS. Neurology. 2004;63:724-726. doi:10.1212/01.WNL.0000134608.83927.B1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;nch C, Rosenbohm A, Sperfeld AD, et al. Heterozygous R1101K mutation of the DCTN1 gene in a family with ALS and FTD. Ann Neurol. 2005;58:777-780. doi:10.1002/ana.20631</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lloyd TE, Machamer J, O'Hara K, et al. The p150 glued CAP-Gly domain regulates initiation of retrograde transport at synaptic termini. Neuron. 2012;74:344-360. doi:10.1016/j.neuron.2012.02.026</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moughamian AJ, Holzbaur ELF. Dynactin is required for transport initiation from the distal axon. Neuron. 2012;74:331-343. doi:10.1016/j.neuron.2012.02.025</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williamson TL, Cleveland DW. Slowing of axonal transport is a very early event in the toxicity of ALS-linked SOD1 mutants to motor neurons. Nat Neurosci. 1999;2:50-56. doi:10.1038/4553</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bilsland LG, Sahai E, Kelly G, Golding M, Greensmith L, Schiavo G. Deficits in axonal transport precede ALS symptoms in vivo. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2010;107:20523-20528. doi:10.1073/pnas.1006869107</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Vos KJ, Chapman AL, Tennant ME, et al. Familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-linked SOD1 mutants perturb fast axonal transport to reduce axonal mitochondria content. Hum Mol Genet. 2007;16:2720-2728. doi:10.1093/hmg/ddm226</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magran&#xe9; J, Hervias I, Henning MS, Damiano M, Kawamata H, Manfredi G. Mutant SOD1 in neuronal mitochondria causes toxicity and mitochondrial dynamics abnormalities. Hum Mol Genet. 2009;18:4552-4564. doi:10.1093/hmg/ddp421</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang W, Li L, Lin WL, et al. The ALS disease-associated mutant TDP-43 impairs mitochondrial dynamics and function in motor neurons. Hum Mol Genet. 2013;22:4706-4719. doi:10.1093/hmg/ddt319</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magran&#xe9; J, Cortez C, Gan WB, Manfredi G. Abnormal mitochondrial transport and morphology are common pathological denominators in SOD1 and TDP43 ALS mouse models. Hum Mol Genet. 2014;23:1413-1424. doi:10.1093/hmg/ddt528</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moller A, Bauer CS, Cohen RN, Webster CP, De Vos KJ. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-associated mutant SOD1 inhibits anterograde axonal transport of mitochondria by reducing Miro1 levels. Hum Mol Genet. 2017;26:4668-4679. doi:10.1093/hmg/ddx348</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fumagalli L, Young FL, Boeynaems S, et al. C9orf72-derived arginine-containing dipeptide repeats associate with axonal transport machinery and impede microtubule-based motility. Sci Adv. 2021;7:1-20. doi:10.1126/SCIADV.ABG3013</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baldwin KR, Godena VK, Hewitt VL, Whitworth AJ. Axonal transport defects are a common phenotype in drosophila models of ALS. Hum Mol Genet. 2016;25:ddw105-dd2392. doi:10.1093/hmg/ddw105</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beckers J, Tharkeshwar AK, Van Damme P. C9orf72 ALS-FTD: recent evidence for dysregulation of the autophagy-lysosome pathway at multiple levels. Autophagy. 2021;17:3306-3322. doi:10.1080/15548627.2021.1872189</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hollenbeck PJ. Products of endocytosis and autophagy are retrieved from axons by regulated retrograde organelle transport. J Cell Biol. 1993;121:305-315. doi:10.1083/jcb.121.2.305</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Overly CC, Lee KD, Berthiaume E, Hollenbeck PJ. Quantitative measurement of intraorganelle pH in the endosomal-lysosomal pathway in neurons by using ratiometric imaging with pyranine. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 1995;92:3156-3160. doi:10.1073/pnas.92.8.3156</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferguson SM. Axonal transport and maturation of lysosomes. Curr Opin Neurobiol. 2018;51:45-51. doi:10.1016/j.conb.2018.02.020</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maday S, Wallace KE, Holzbaur ELF. Autophagosomes initiate distally and mature during transport toward the cell soma in primary neurons. J Cell Biol. 2012;196:407-417. doi:10.1083/jcb.201106120</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maday S, Holzbaur ELF. Autophagosome biogenesis in primary neurons follows an ordered and spatially regulated pathway. Dev Cell. 2014;30:71-85. doi:10.1016/j.devcel.2014.06.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cunningham KM, Maulding K, Ruan K, et al. Tfeb/mitf links impaired nuclear import to autophagolysosomal dysfunction in c9-als. Elife. 2020;9:1-35. doi:10.7554/ELIFE.59419</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parkinson-Lawrence EJ, Shandala T, Prodoehl M, Plew R, Borlace GN, Brooks DA. Lysosomal storage disease: revealing lysosomal function and physiology. Phys Ther. 2010;25:102-115. doi:10.1152/physiol.00041.2009</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sasaki S. Autophagy in spinal cord motor neurons in sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neuropathol Exp Neurol. 2011;70:349-359. doi:10.1097/NEN.0b013e3182160690</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sung H, Tandarich LC, Nguyen K, Hollenbeck PJ. Compartmentalized regulation of Parkin-mediated mitochondrial quality control in the drosophila nervous system in vivo. J Neurosci. 2016;36:7375-7391. doi:10.1523/JNEUROSCI.0633-16.2016</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu Z, Poidevin M, Li X, et al. Expanded GGGGCC repeat RNA associated with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal dementia causes neurodegeneration. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2013;110:7778-7783. doi:10.1073/pnas.1219643110</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amick J, Ferguson SM. C9orf72: at the intersection of lysosome cell biology and neurodegenerative disease. Traffic. 2017;18:267-276. doi:10.1111/tra.12477</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Root J, Merino P, Nuckols A, Johnson M, Kukar T. Lysosome dysfunction as a cause of neurodegenerative diseases: lessons from frontotemporal dementia and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurobiol Dis. 2021;154:105360. doi:10.1016/j.nbd.2021.105360</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang K, Donnelly CJ, Haeusler AR, et al. The C9orf72 repeat expansion disrupts nucleocytoplasmic transport. Nature. 2015;525:56-61. doi:10.1038/nature14973</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stavoe AKH, Holzbaur ELF. Autophagy in neurons. Annu Rev Cell Dev Biol. 2019;35:477-500. doi:10.1146/annurev-cellbio-100818-125242</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papadopoulos C, Meyer H. Detection and clearance of damaged lysosomes by the Endo-lysosomal damage response and lysophagy. Curr Biol. 2017;27:R1330-R1341. doi:10.1016/j.cub.2017.11.012</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papadopoulos C, Kravic B, Meyer H. Repair or lysophagy: dealing with damaged lysosomes. J Mol Biol. 2020;432:231-239. doi:10.1016/j.jmb.2019.08.010</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vukoja A, Rey U, Petzoldt AG, et al. Presynaptic biogenesis requires axonal transport of lysosome-related vesicles. Neuron. 2018;99:1216-1232.e7. doi:10.1016/j.neuron.2018.08.004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toyoshima I, Sugawara M, Kato K, et al. Kinesin and cytoplasmic dynein in spinal spheroids with motor neuron disease. J Neurol Sci. 1998;159:38-44. doi:10.1016/S0022-510X(98)00137-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galvin JE, Uryu K, Lee VMY, Trojanowski JQ. Axon pathology in Parkinson's disease and Lewy body dementia hippocampus contains &#x3b1;-, &#x3b2;-, and &#x3b3;-synuclein. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 1999;96:13450-13455. doi:10.1073/pnas.96.23.13450</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>LaMonte BH, Wallace KE, Holloway BA, et al. Disruption of dynein/dynactin inhibits axonal transport in motor neurons causing late-onset progressive degeneration. Neuron. 2002;34:715-727. doi:10.1016/S0896-6273(02)00696-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cabukusta B, Neefjes J. Mechanisms of lysosomal positioning and movement. Traffic. 2018;19:761-769. doi:10.1111/tra.12587</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakamura S, Yoshimori T. New insights into autophagosome-lysosome fusion. J Cell Sci. 2017;130:1209-1216. doi:10.1242/jcs.196352</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suzuki SW, Emr SD. Membrane protein recycling from the vacuole/lysosome membrane. J Cell Biol. 2018;217:1623-1632. doi:10.1083/jcb.201709162</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cantalupo G, Alifano P, Roberti V, Bruni CB, Bucci C. Rab-interacting lysosomal protein (RILP): the Rab7 effector required for transport to lysosomes. EMBO J. 2001;20:683-693. doi:10.1093/emboj/20.4.683</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jordens I, Fernandez-Borja M, Marsman M, et al. The Rab7 effector protein RILP controls lysosomal transport by inducing the recruitment of dynein-dynactin motors. Curr Biol. 2001;11:1680-1685. doi:10.1016/S0960-9822(01)00531-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johansson M, Rocha N, Zwart W, et al. Activation of endosomal dynein motors by stepwise assembly of Rab7-RILP-p150Glued, ORP1L, and the receptor &#x3b2;III spectrin. J Cell Biol. 2007;176:459-471. doi:10.1083/jcb.200606077</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rao S, Lang C, Levitan ES, Deitcher DL. Fast track: visualization of neuropeptide expression, transport, and exocytosis in Drosophila melanogaster. J Neurobiol. 2001;49:159-172. doi:10.1002/neu.1072</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim A, Rechtsteiner A, Saxton WM. Two kinesins drive anterograde neuropeptide transport. Mol Biol Cell. 2017;28:3542-3553. doi:10.1091/mbc.E16-12-0820</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lund VK, Lycas MD, Schack A, Andersen RC, Gether U, Kjaerulff O. Rab2 drives axonal transport of dense core vesicles and lysosomal organelles. Cell Rep. 2021;35:108973. doi:10.1016/j.celrep.2021.108973</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rocha N, Kuijl C, Van Der Kant R, et al. Cholesterol sensor ORP1L contacts the ER protein VAP to control Rab7-RILP-p150Glued and late endosome positioning. J Cell Biol. 2009;185:1209-1225. doi:10.1083/jcb.200811005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pankiv S, Alemu EA, Brech A, et al. FYCO1 is a Rab7 effector that binds to LC3 and PI3P to mediate microtubule plus end - directed vesicle transport. J Cell Biol. 2010;188:253-269. doi:10.1083/jcb.200907015</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedman JR, DiBenedetto JR, West M, Rowland AA, Voeltz GK. Endoplasmic reticulum-endosome contact increases as endosomes traffic and mature. Mol Biol Cell. 2013;24:1030-1040. doi:10.1091/mbc.E12-10-0733</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakashima A, Bin CS, Kusabiraki T, et al. Endoplasmic reticulum stress disrupts lysosomal homeostasis and induces blockade of autophagic flux in human trophoblasts. Sci Rep. 2019;9:11466. doi:10.1038/s41598-019-47607-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X, Chow CY, Sahenk Z, Shy ME, Meisler MH, Li J. Mutation of FIG4 causes a rapidly progressive, asymmetric neuronal degeneration. Brain. 2008;131:1990-2001. doi:10.1093/brain/awn114</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stagi M, Klein ZA, Gould TJ, Bewersdorf J, Strittmatter SM. Lysosome size, motility and stress response regulated by fronto-temporal dementia modifier TMEM106B. Mol Cell Neurosci. 2014;61:226-240. doi:10.1016/j.mcn.2014.07.006</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, Rydzewski N, Hider A, et al. A molecular mechanism to regulate lysosome motility for lysosome positioning and tubulation. Nat Cell Biol. 2016;18:404-417. doi:10.1038/ncb3324</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zigdon H, Meshcheriakova A, Farfel-Becker T, Volpert G, Sabanay H, Futerman AH. Altered lysosome distribution is an early neuropathological event in neurological forms of Gaucher disease. FEBS Lett. 2017;591:774-783. doi:10.1002/1873-3468.12591</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bandyopadhyay D, Cyphersmith A, Zapata JA, Kim YJ, Payne CK. Lysosome transport as a function of lysosome diameter. PLoS One. 2014;9:e86847. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0086847</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casterton RL, Hunt RJ, Fanto M. Pathomechanism heterogeneity in the amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal dementia disease spectrum: providing focus through the lens of autophagy. J Mol Biol. 2020;432:2692-2713. doi:10.1016/j.jmb.2020.02.018</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao YC, Fernandopulle MS, Wang G, et al. RNA granules hitchhike on lysosomes for long-distance transport, using annexin A11 as a molecular tether. Cell. 2019;179:147-164.e20. doi:10.1016/j.cell.2019.08.050</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Urwin H, Authier A, Nielsen JE, et al. Disruption of endocytic trafficking in frontotemporal dementia with CHMP2B mutations. Hum Mol Genet. 2010;19:2228-2238. doi:10.1093/hmg/ddq100</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim F, Hern&#xe1;ndez F, Lucas JJ, G&#xf3;mez-Ramos P, Mor&#xe1;n MA, &#xc1;vila J. FTDP-17 mutations in tau transgenic mice provoke lysosomal abnormalities and tau filaments in forebrain. Mol Cell Neurosci. 2001;18:702-714. doi:10.1006/mcne.2001.1051</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brand AH, Perrimon N. Targeted gene expression as a means of altering cell fates and generating dominant phenotypes. Development. 1993;118:401-415. doi:10.1242/dev.118.2.401</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Louie K, Russo GJ, Salkoff DB, Wellington A, Zinsmaier KE. Effects of imaging conditions on mitochondrial transport and length in larval motor axons of drosophila. Comp Biochem Physiol A Mol Integr Physiol. 2008;151:159-172. doi:10.1016/j.cbpa.2008.06.023</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devireddy S, Sung H, Liao PC, Garland-Kuntz E, Hollenbeck PJ. Analysis of mitochondrial traffic in drosophila. Methods Enzymol. 2014;547;131-150. doi:10.1016/B978-0-12-801415-8.00008-4</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>