<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35942673</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>08</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1473-6551</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>35</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Current opinion in neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Curr Opin Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Update on genetics of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>672</StartPage><EndPage>677</EndPage><MedlinePgn>672-677</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/WCO.0000000000001093</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE OF REVIEW">ALS genetics are highly dynamic and of great interest for the ALS research community. Each year, by using ever-growing datasets and cutting-edge methodology, an array of novel ALS-associated genes and downstream pathomechanisms are discovered. The increasing plenty and complexity of insights warrants regular summary by-reviews.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RECENT FINDINGS">Most recent disease gene discoveries constitute the candidate and risk genes SPTLC1 , KANK1 , CAV1 , HTT , and WDR7 , as well as seven novel risk loci. Cell type and functional enrichment analyses enlighten the genetic basis of selective motor neuron vulnerability in ALS demonstrating high expression of ALS-associated genes in cortical motor neurons and highlight the pathogenic significance of cell-autonomous processes. Major pathomechanistic insights have been gained regarding known ALS genes/proteins, specifically C9orf72 , TDP43, ANXA11 , and KIF5A . The first ASO-based gene-specific therapy trials in familial forms of ALS have yielded equivocal results stressing the re-evaluation of pathomechanisms linked to SOD1 and C9orf72 mutations.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUMMARY">The genetic and molecular basis of ALS is increasingly examined on single-cell resolution. In the past 2 years, the understanding of the downstream mechanisms of several ALS genes and TDP-43 proteinopathy has been considerably extended. These insights will result in novel gene specific therapy approaches for sporadic ALS and genetic subtypes.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brenner</LastName><ForeName>David</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurology Department, Ulm University, Ulm, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Freischmidt</LastName><ForeName>Axel</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Curr Opin Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9319162</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1350-7540</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D048868">Adaptor Proteins, Signal Transducing</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000073885">C9orf72 Protein</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D003598">Cytoskeletal Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C467739">KANK1 protein, human</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C500506">KIF5A protein, human</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C409880">WDR7 protein, human</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 3.6.4.4</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D016547">Kinesins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D048868" MajorTopicYN="N">Adaptor Proteins, Signal Transducing</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000073885" MajorTopicYN="N">C9orf72 Protein</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003598" MajorTopicYN="N">Cytoskeletal Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016547" MajorTopicYN="N">Kinesins</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009046" MajorTopicYN="N">Motor Neurons</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009154" MajorTopicYN="N">Mutation</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35942673</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/WCO.0000000000001093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00019052-202210000-00018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Shepheard SR, Parker MD, Cooper-Knock J, et al. Project MINE Consortium, Project MinE. Original research: value of systematic genetic screening of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2021; 92:510.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Chalabi A, Fang F, Hanby MF, et al. Rijsdijk F: an estimate of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis heritability using twin data. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2010; 81:1324&#x2013;1326.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gregory J, Fagegaltier D, Phatnani HP. Harms MB. Genetics of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Curr Genet Med Rep 2020; 43:538&#x2013;549.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohassel P, Donkervoort S, Lone MA, et al. Childhood amyotrophic lateral sclerosis caused by excess sphingolipid synthesis. Nat Med 2021; 27:1197&#x2013;1204.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson JO, Chia R, Miller DE, et al. Association of variants in the SPTLC1 gene with juvenile amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. JAMA Neurol 2021; 78:1236&#x2013;1248.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dewan R, Chia R, Ding J, et al. Pathogenic Huntingtin Repeat Expansions in Patients with Frontotemporal Dementia and Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. Neuron 2021; 109:448.e4&#x2013;460.e4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas Q, Coarelli G, Heinzmann A, et al. Questioning the causality of HTT CAG-repeat expansions in FTD/ALS. Neuron 2021; 109:1945&#x2013;1946.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooper-Knock J, Zhang S, Kenna KP, et al. Rare variant burden analysis within enhancers identifies CAV1 as an ALS risk gene. Cell Rep 2020; 33:108456.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saez-Atienzar S, Bandres-Ciga S, Langston RG, et al. Genetic analysis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis identifies contributing pathways and cell types. Sci Adv 2021; 7:eabd9036.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Rheenen W, van der Spek RAA, Bakker MK, et al. Common and rare variant association analyses in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis identify 15 risk loci with distinct genetic architectures and neuron-specific biology. Nat Genet 2021 5312 2021; 53:1636&#x2013;1648.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakamura R, Misawa K, Tohnai G, et al. A multiethnic meta-analysis identifies novel genes, including ACSL5, associated with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Commun Biol 2020; 3:526.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang S, Cooper-Knock J, Weimer AK, et al. Genome-wide identification of the genetic basis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuron 2022; 110:992.e11&#x2013;1008.e11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Course MM, Gudsnuk K, Smukowski SN, et al. Evolution of a human-specific tandem repeat associated with ALS. Am J Hum Genet 2020; 107:445&#x2013;460.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iacoangeli A, Lin T, Al Khleifat A, et al. Genome-wide meta-analysis finds the ACSL5-ZDHHC6 locus is associated with ALS and links weight loss to the disease genetics. Cell Rep 2020; 33:108323.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Limone F, Mordes D, Couto A, et al. Single-nucleus sequencing reveals enriched expression of genetic risk factors sensitises motor neurons to degeneration in ALS. bioRxiv 2021; 452054.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Megat S, Mora N, Sanogo J, et al. Loss of nucleoporin Nup50 is a risk factor for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. medRxiv 2021; 21262299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eitan C, Siany A, Barkan E, et al. Whole-genome sequencing reveals that variants in the interlukin 18 receptor accessory protein 3&#x2032;UTR protect against ALS. Nat Neurosci 2022 254 2022; 25:433&#x2013;445.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lall D, Lorenzini I, Mota TA, et al. C9orf72 deficiency promotes microglial-mediated synaptic loss in aging and amyloid accumulation. Neuron 2021; 109:2275&#x2013;2291e8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCauley ME, O&#x2019;Rourke JG, Y&#xe1;&#xf1;ez A, et al. C9orf72 in myeloid cells suppresses STING-induced inflammation. Nature 2020; 585:96&#x2013;101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>LaClair KD, Zhou Q, Michaelsen M, et al. Congenic expression of poly-GA but not poly-PR in mice triggers selective neuron loss and interferon responses found in C9orf72 ALS. Acta Neuropathol 2020; 140:121&#x2013;142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook CN, Wu Y, Odeh HM, et al. C9orf72 poly (GR) aggregation induces TDP-43 proteinopathy. Sci Transl Med 2020; 12:eabb3774.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu CH, Davidson S, Harapas CR, et al. TDP-43 triggers mitochondrial DNA release via mPTP to activate cGAS/STING in ALS. Cell 2020; 183:636.e18&#x2013;649.e18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bo&#x17e;i&#x10d; J, Motaln H, Jane&#x17e; AP, et al. Interactome screening of C9orf72 dipeptide repeats reveals VCP sequestration and functional impairment by polyGA. Brain 2021; 145:684&#x2013;699.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang K, Wang A, Zhong K, et al. UBQLN2-HSP70 axis reduces poly-Gly-Ala aggregates and alleviates behavioral defects in the C9ORF72 animal model. Neuron 2021; 109:1949.e6&#x2013;1962.e6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maor-Nof M, Shipony Z, Lopez-Gonzalez R, et al. p53 is a central regulator driving neurodegeneration caused by C9orf72 poly (PR). Cell 2021; 184:689.e20&#x2013;708.e20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ling JP, Pletnikova O, Troncoso JC. Wong PC: TDP-43 repression of nonconserved cryptic exons is compromised in ALS-FTD. Science 2015; 349:650&#x2013;655.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma XR, Prudencio M, Koike Y, et al. TDP-43 represses cryptic exon inclusion in the FTD&#x2013;ALS gene UNC13A. Nature 2022; 603:124.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melamed Z, L&#xf3;pez-Erauskin J, Baughn MW, et al. Premature polyadenylation-mediated loss of stathmin-2 is a hallmark of TDP-43-dependent neurodegeneration. Nat Neurosci 2019; 22:180&#x2013;190.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guerra San Juan I, Nash LA, Smith KS, et al. Loss of mouse Stmn2 function causes motor neuropathy. Neuron 2022; 110:1671.e6&#x2013;1688.e6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krus KL, Strickland A, Yamada Y, et al. DiAntonio A: Loss of Stathmin-2, a hallmark of TDP-43-associated ALS, causes motor neuropathy. Cell Rep 2022; 39:111001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korobeynikov VA, Lyashchenko AK, Blanco-Redondo B, et al. Antisense oligonucleotide silencing of FUS expression as a therapeutic approach in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat Med 2022; 28:104&#x2013;116.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baskoylu SN, Chapkis N, Unsal B, Hart AC. Disrupted autophagy and neuronal dysfunction in C. elegans knockin models of FUS amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Cell Rep 2022; 38:110195.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H, Qi W, Zou C, et al. NEK1-mediated retromer trafficking promotes blood-brain barrier integrity by regulating glucose metabolism and RIPK1 activation. Nat Commun 2021; 12:4826.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richard P, Feng S, Tsai YL, et al. SETX (senataxin), the helicase mutated in AOA2 and ALS4, functions in autophagy regulation. Autophagy 2021; 17:1&#x2013;18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baron DM, Fenton AR, Saez-Atienzar S, et al. ALS-associated KIF5A mutations abolish autoinhibition resulting in a toxic gain of function. Cell Rep 2022; 39:110598.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nahm M, Lim SM, Kim YE, et al. ANXA11 mutations in ALS cause dysregulation of calcium homeostasis and stress granule dynamics. Sci Transl Med 2020; 12:eaax3993.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al Khleifat A, Iacoangeli A, van Vugt JJFA, et al. Structural variation analysis of 6,500 whole genome sequences in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. NPJ Genomic Med 2022; 7:8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lule DE, M&#xfc;ller HP, Finsel J, et al. Deficits in verbal fluency in presymptomatic C9orf72 mutation gene carriers-a developmental disorder. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2020; 91:1195&#x2013;1200.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gossink F, Dols A, Stek ML, et al. Pijnenburg YAL: early life involvement in C9orf72 repeat expansion carriers. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2022; 93:93&#x2013;100.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saez-Atienzar S, Dalgard CL, Ding J, et al. Identification of a pathogenic intronic KIF5A mutation in an ALS-FTD kindred. Neurology 2020; 95:1015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biogen announces topline results from the Tofersen Phase 3 Study and its Open-Label Extension in SOD1-ALS | Biogen. 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ezer S, Daana M, Park JH, et al. Infantile SOD1 deficiency syndrome caused by a homozygous SOD1 variant with absence of enzyme activity. Brain 2021; 145:872&#x2013;878.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park JH, Elpers C, Reunert J, et al. SOD1 deficiency: a novel syndrome distinct from amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain 2019; 142:2230&#x2013;2237.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen PM, Nordstr&#xf6;m U, Tsiakas K, et al. Phenotype in an infant with SOD1 homozygous truncating mutation. N Engl J Med 2019; 381:486&#x2013;488.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biogen and Ionis announce Topline Phase 1 Study results of investigational drug in C9orf72 amyotrophic lateral sclerosis | Biogen. 2021.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>