<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35942672</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>08</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1473-6551</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>35</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Current opinion in neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Curr Opin Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Clinical studies in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>686</StartPage><EndPage>692</EndPage><MedlinePgn>686-692</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/WCO.0000000000001099</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE OF REVIEW">The purpose of this review is to discuss the most important recent clinical studies in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS), including their impact on clinical practice, their methodology, and open questions to be addressed in the future.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RECENT FINDINGS">This article focuses on studies, which provided either a positive primary endpoint or positive post hoc analysis, including edaravone, sodium phenylbutyrate-taurursodiol, rasagiline, tofersen, and high-caloric, fat-rich nutrition. It also covers recent developments in the design of clinical ALS studies with regard to inclusion criteria, stratification factors, and outcome parameters.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUMMARY">Recent clinical studies have indicated various substances to be considered for treatment of ALS. Edaravone has been approved by the US Food and Drug Association (FDA) but not by the European Medicines Agency (EMA), and further studies testing oral formulations are currently conducted. A follow-up study with sodium phenylbutyrate-taurursodiol is ongoing, while follow-up studies for rasagiline and high-caloric, fat-rich nutrition are planned. A phase III study with tofersen was negative but nevertheless yielded promising results. Important developments regarding the design of clinical ALS studies include the implementation of neurofilament light chain (NfL) levels as a standard outcome parameter and the consideration of progression rate for therapeutic response and stratification.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dorst</LastName><ForeName>Johannes</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of Ulm, Ulm, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Genge</LastName><ForeName>Angela</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Montreal Neurological Institute-Hospital, Montreal, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Curr Opin Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9319162</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1350-7540</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>S798V6YJRP</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000077553">Edaravone</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000077553" MajorTopicYN="N">Edaravone</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005500" MajorTopicYN="N">Follow-Up Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008137" MajorTopicYN="N">Longitudinal Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35942672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/WCO.0000000000001099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00019052-202210000-00020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bensimon G, Lacomblez L, Meininger V. A controlled trial of riluzole in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. ALS/Riluzole Study Group. N Engl J Med 1994; 330:585&#x2013;591.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katz JS, Rothstein JD, Cudkowicz ME, et al. A phase 1 study of GDC-0134, a dual leucine zipper kinase inhibitor, in ALS. Ann Clin Transl Neurol 2022; 9:50&#x2013;66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cudkowicz ME, Lindborg SR, Goyal NA, et al. A randomized placebo-controlled phase 3 study of mesenchymal stem cells induced to secrete high levels of neurotrophic factors in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve 2022; 65:291&#x2013;302.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S, Henderson RD, Mathers S, et al. TEALS study group. Safety and efficacy of dimethyl fumarate in ALS: randomised controlled study. Ann Clin Transl Neurol 2021; 8:1991&#x2013;1999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aizawa H, Kato H, Oba K, et al. Randomized phase 2 study of perampanel for sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol 2022; 269:885&#x2013;896.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milligan C, Atassi N, Babu S, et al. Tocilizumab is safe and tolerable and reduces C-reactive protein concentrations in the plasma and cerebrospinal fluid of ALS patients. Muscle Nerve 2021; 64:309&#x2013;320.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dalla Bella E, Bersano E, Antonini G, et al. The unfolded protein response in amyotrophic later sclerosis: results of a phase 2 trial. Brain 2021; 144:2635&#x2013;2647.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shefner JM, Andrews JA, Genge A, et al. A Phase 2, Double-Blind, Randomized, Dose-Ranging Trial Of Reldesemtiv In Patients With ALS. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2021; 22:287&#x2013;299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Camu W, Mickunas M, Veyrune JL, et al. Repeated 5-day cycles of low dose aldesleukin in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (IMODALS): a phase 2a randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. EBioMedicine 2020; 59:7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Es MA, Van Eijk RPA, Bunte TM, Van Den Berg LH. A placebo-controlled trial to investigate the safety and efficacy of Penicillin G/Hydrocortisone in patients with ALS (PHALS trial). Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2020; 21:584&#x2013;592.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ito H, Wate R, Zhang J, et al. Treatment with edaravone, initiated at symptom onset, slows motor decline and decreases SOD1 deposition in ALS mice. Exp Neurol 2008; 213:448&#x2013;455.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abe K, Itoyama Y, Sobue G, et al. Edaravone ALS Study Group. Confirmatory double-blind, parallel-group, placebo-controlled study of efficacy and safety of edaravone (MCI-186) in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2014; 15:610&#x2013;617.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>EdavaroneStudyGroup. Safety and efficacy of edaravone in well defined patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Lancet Neurol 2017; 15:30115&#x2013;30121.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lunetta C, Moglia C, Lizio A, et al. EDARAVALS Study Group. The Italian multicenter experience with edaravone in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol 2020; 267:3258&#x2013;3267.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Witzel S, Maier A, Steinbach R, et al. German Motor Neuron Disease Network (MND-NET). Safety and effectiveness of long-term intravenous administration of edaravone for treatment of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. JAMA Neurol 2022; 79:121&#x2013;130.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Del Signore SJ, Amante DJ, Kim J, et al. Combined riluzole and sodium phenylbutyrate therapy in transgenic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis mice. Amyotroph Lateral Scler 2009; 10:85&#x2013;94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cudkowicz ME, Andres PL, Macdonald SA, et al. Northeast ALS and National VA ALS Research Consortiums. Phase 2 study of sodium phenylbutyrate in ALS. Amyotroph Lateral Scler 2009; 10:99&#x2013;106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang F, Pariante CM, Borsini A. From dried bear bile to molecular investigation: a systematic review of the effect of bile acids on cell apoptosis, oxidative stress and inflammation in the brain, across preclinical models of neurological, neurodegenerative and neuropsychiatric disorders. Brain Behav Immun 2022; 99:132&#x2013;146.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elia AE, Lalli S, Monsurr&#xf2; MR, et al. Tauroursodeoxycholic acid in the treatment of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Eur J Neurol 2016; 23:45&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paganoni S, Macklin EA, Hendrix S, et al. Trial of sodium phenylbutyrate-taurursodiol for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. New Engl J Med 2020; 383:919&#x2013;930.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rascol O, Fitzer-Attas CJ, Hauser R, et al. A double-blind, delayed-start trial of rasagiline in Parkinson's disease (the ADAGIO study): prespecified and posthoc analyses of the need for additional therapies, changes in UPDRS scores, and nonmotor outcomes. Lancet Neurol 2011; 10:415&#x2013;423.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kostic V, Gurney ME, Deng HX, et al. Midbrain dopaminergic neuronal degeneration in a transgenic mouse model of familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol 1997; 41:497&#x2013;504.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dentel C, Palamiuc L, Henriques A, et al. Degeneration of serotonergic neurons in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a link to spasticity. Brain 2013; 136 (Pt 2):483&#x2013;493.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abu-Raya S, Blaugrund E, Trembovler V, et al. Rasagiline, a monoamine oxidase-B inhibitor, protects NGF-differentiated PC12 cells against oxygen-glucose deprivation. J Neurosci Res 1999; 58:456&#x2013;463.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waibel S, Reuter A, Malessa S, et al. Rasagiline alone and in combination with riluzole prolongs survival in an ALS mouse model. J Neurol 2004; 251:1080&#x2013;1084.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ludolph AC, Schuster J, Dorst J, et al. RAS-ALS Study Group. Safety and efficacy of rasagiline as an add-on therapy to riluzole in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a randomised, double-blind, parallel-group, placebo-controlled, phase 2 trial. Lancet Neurol 2018; 18:30176&#x2013;30185.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Statland JM, Moore D, Wang Y, et al. Rasagiline Investigators of the Muscle Study Group and Western ALS Consortium. Rasagiline for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a randomized, controlled trial. Muscle Nerve 2019; 59:201&#x2013;207.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finkel RS, Mercuri E, Darras BT, et al. ENDEAR Study Group. Nusinersen versus sham control in infantile-onset spinal muscular atrophy. New Engl J Med 2017; 377:1723&#x2013;1732.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winer L, Srinivasan D, Chun S, et al. SOD1 in cerebral spinal fluid as a pharmacodynamic marker for antisense oligonucleotide therapy. JAMA Neurol 2013; 70:201&#x2013;207.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith RA, Miller TM, Yamanaka K, et al. Antisense oligonucleotide therapy for neurodegenerative disease. J Clin Invest 2006; 116:2290&#x2013;2296.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller T, Cudkowicz M, Shaw PJ, et al. Phase 1-2 Trial of Antisense Oligonucleotide Tofersen for SOD1 ALS. New Engl J Med 2020; 383:109&#x2013;119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller T, Cudkowicz M. Results from the Phase 3 VALOR study and its open-label extension: evaluating the clinical efficacy and safety of tofersen in adults with ALS and confirmed SOD1 mutation. American Neurological Association Annual Meeting. 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desport JC, Preux PM, Truong TC, et al. Nutritional status is a prognostic factor for survival in ALS patients. Neurology 1999; 53:1059&#x2013;1063.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dupuis L, Oudart H, Rene F, et al. Evidence for defective energy homeostasis in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: benefit of a high-energy diet in a transgenic mouse model. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 2004; 101:11159&#x2013;11164.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dupuis L, Corcia P, Fergani A, et al. Dyslipidemia is a protective factor in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology 2008; 70:1004&#x2013;1009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wills AM, Hubbard J, Macklin EA, et al. MDA Clinical Research Network. Lancet 2014; 383:2065&#x2013;2072.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ludolph AC, Dorst J, Dreyhaupt J, et al. LIPCAL-ALS Study Group. Effect of high-caloric nutrition on survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol 2019; 17:25661.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dorst J, Schuster J, Dreyhaupt J, et al. Effect of high-caloric nutrition on serum neurofilament light chain levels in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2020; 91:1007&#x2013;1009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dorst J, Doenz J, Kandler K, et al. Fat-rich versus carbohydrate-rich nutrition in ALS: a randomised controlled study. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2022; 93:298&#x2013;302.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wainger BJ, Macklin EA, Vucic S, et al. Effect of ezogabine on cortical and spinal motor neuron excitability in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA Neurol 2021; 78:186&#x2013;196.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Eijk RPA, de Jongh AD, Nikolakopoulos S, et al. An old friend who has overstayed their welcome: the ALSFRS-R total score as primary endpoint for ALS clinical trials. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2021; 22:300&#x2013;307.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fournier CN, Bedlack R, Quinn C, et al. Development and validation of the Rasch-Built Overall Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Disability Scale (ROADS). JAMA Neurol 2019; 77:480&#x2013;488.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>