<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35946801</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>08</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1473-6551</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>35</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Current opinion in neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Curr Opin Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The challenge of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis descriptive epidemiology: to estimate low incidence rates across complex phenotypes in different geographic areas.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>678</StartPage><EndPage>685</EndPage><MedlinePgn>678-685</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/WCO.0000000000001097</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE OF REVIEW">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) is a rare progressive neurodegenerative disease of motor neurons with a fatal outcome. The rareness of the disease and the rapidly fatal course are the main challenges for the ALS epidemiological research. The understanding of ALS has clearly advanced in the recent years both in the genetics and in the leading pathways of disease determinants. Epidemiological research has played a primary role in these discoveries.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RECENT FINDINGS">Epidemiological studies have shown a variation of incidence, mortality and prevalence of ALS between geographical areas and different populations, supporting the notion that genetic factors, linked to populations' ancestries, along with environmental and lifestyle factors, play a significant role in the occurrence of the disease. The burden of motor neuron diseases is increasing and currently more relevant in high-income countries but increasing at the highest rate in low and middle-income countries. The ALS phenotype is not restricted to motor functions. C9orf72 repeat expansion seems to present a recognizable phenotype characterized by earlier disease onset, the presence of cognitive and behavioural impairment.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUMMARY">Population-based disease registries have played a major role in developing new knowledge on ALS, in characterizing genotype-phenotype correlations, in discovering new genetic modifiers and finally in planning research and health services, considering the high cost of motor neuron disease care. Epidemiological research based on multicentre international collaboration is essential to provide new data on ALS, especially in some regions of the world with poor data.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022 The Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Logroscino</LastName><ForeName>Giancarlo</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Neurodegenerative Diseases and the Aging Brain, Department of Clinical Research in Neurology, University of Bari 'Aldo Moro', "Pia Fondazione Cardinale G. Panico", Tricase, Lecce.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Basic Medicine, Neuroscience, and Sense Organs, University of Bari 'Aldo Moro', Bari, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Urso</LastName><ForeName>Daniele</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Neurodegenerative Diseases and the Aging Brain, Department of Clinical Research in Neurology, University of Bari 'Aldo Moro', "Pia Fondazione Cardinale G. Panico", Tricase, Lecce.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosciences, King's College London, Institute of Psychiatry, Psychology and Neuroscience, De Crespigny Park, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tortelli</LastName><ForeName>Rosanna</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neuroscience and Rare Diseases Discovery and Translational Area, Roche Pharma Research and Early Development, F. Hoffmann-La Roche Ltd., Basel, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Curr Opin Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9319162</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1350-7540</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015994" MajorTopicYN="N">Incidence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016472" MajorTopicYN="Y">Motor Neuron Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019636" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neurodegenerative Diseases</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010641" MajorTopicYN="N">Phenotype</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>
<i>R.T. is a full employee of F. Hoffmann-La Roche Ltd.</i>
</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35946801</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9593328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/WCO.0000000000001097</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00019052-202210000-00019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>
European Union. Regulation (EC) N&#xb0;141/2000 of the European Parliament and of the Council of 16 December 1999 on orphan medicinal products. 2000. [Accessed on 14 April 2022]. http://eurlex.europa.eu/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=OJ:L:2000:018:0001:0005:EN:PDF
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>TRICARE; rare diseases definition. Final rule. Fed Regist 2010; 75:47458.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20690233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardiman O, van den Berg LH, Kiernan MC. Clinical diagnosis and management of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat Rev Neurol 2011; 7:639&#x2013;649.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21989247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodwell C, Aym&#xe9; S. Rare disease policies to improve care for patients in Europe. Biochim Biophys Acta 2015; 1852:2329&#x2013;2335.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25725454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Scottish Motor Neuron Disease Register: a prospective study of adult onset motor neuron disease in Scotland. Methodology, demography and clinical features of incident cases in 1989. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 1992; 55:536&#x2013;541.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC489161</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1640227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell JD, Gibson HN, Gatrell A. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in Lancashire and South Cumbria, England, 1976&#x2013;1986: a geographical study. Arch Neurol 1990; 47:875&#x2013;880.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2375694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Traynor BJ, Codd MB, Corr B, et al. . Incidence and prevalence of ALS in Ireland, 1995&#x2013;1997: a population-based study. Neurology 1999; 52:504&#x2013;509.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10025778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Incidence of ALS in Italy: evidence for a uniform frequency in Western countries. Neurology 2001; 56:239&#x2013;244.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11160962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beghi E, Millul A, Micheli A, et al. . Incidence of ALS in Lombardy, Italy. Neurology 2007; 68:141&#x2013;145.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17210896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Logroscino G, Beghi E, Zoccolella S, et al. . Incidence of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in southern Italy: a population based study. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2005; 76:1094&#x2013;1098.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1739746</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16024886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Logroscino G, Traynor BJ, Hardiman O, et al. . Incidence of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in Europe. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2010; 81:385&#x2013;390.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2850819</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19710046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Logroscino G, Kurth T, Piccininni M. The reconstructed cohort design: a method to study rare neurodegenerative diseases in population-based settings. Neuroepidemiology 2020; 54:114&#x2013;122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31910416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Logroscino G, Piccininni M, Binetti G, et al. . Incidence of frontotemporal lobar degeneration in Italy. The Salento-Brescia Registry study 2019; 92:e2355&#x2013;e2363.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30979859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borroni B, Graff C, Hardiman O, et al. . FRONTIERS. FRONTotemporal dementia Incidence European Research Study-FRONTIERS: Rationale and design. Alzheimers Dement 2022; 18:498&#x2013;506.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9291221</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34338439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Preux PM, Druet-Cabanac M, Couratier P, et al. . Estimation of the amyotrophic lateral sclerosis incidence by capture-recapture method in the Limousin region of France. J Clin Epidemiol 2000; 53:1025&#x2013;1029.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11027935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nanan DJ, White F. Capture-recapture: reconnaissance of a demographic technique in epidemiology. Chronic Dis Can 1997; 18:144&#x2013;148.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9445362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marin B, Hamidou B, Couratier P, et al. . Population-based epidemiology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) in an ageing Europe: the French register of ALS in Limousin (FRALim register). Eur J Neurol 2014; 21:1292&#x2013;1300. e78&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24909935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huisman MHB, de Jong SW, van Doormaal PTC, et al. . Population based epidemiology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis using capture&#x2013;recapture methodology. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2011; 2011:244939.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21622937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uenal H, Rosenbohm A, Kufeldt J, et al. . Incidence and geographical variation of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) in Southern Germany &#x2013; completeness of the ALS Registry Swabia. PLoS One 2014; 9:e93932.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3983245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24722455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cronin S, Hardiman O, Traynor BJ. Ethnic variation in the incidence of ALS: a systematic review. Neurology 2007; 68:1002&#x2013;1007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17389304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marin B, Boum&#xe9;diene F, Logroscino G, et al. . Variation in worldwide incidence of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a meta-analysis. Int J Epidemiol 2017; 46:57&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5407171</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27185810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plato CC, Garruto RM, Galasko D, et al. . Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and parkinsonism-dementia complex of Guam: changing incidence rates during the past 60&#x200a;years. Am J Epidemiol 2003; 157:149&#x2013;157.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12522022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kokubo Y. The current state of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis/parkinsonism-dementia complex in the Kii Peninsula, Japan, 2019. Brain Nerve 2019; 71:1236&#x2013;1244.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31722309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johansen M, Svenstrup K, Joensen P, et al. . High incidence of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in the Faroe Islands 2010&#x2013;2020. Ann Clin Transl Neurol 2022; 9:227&#x2013;231.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8862418</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35048555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feigin VL, Nichols E, Alam T, et al. . Global, regional, and national burden of neurological disorders, 1990&#x2013;2016: a systematic analysis for the Global Burden of Disease Study 2016. Lancet Neurol 2019; 18:459&#x2013;480.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6459001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30879893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaldivar T, Gutierrez J, Lara G, et al. . Reduced frequency of ALS in an ethnically mixed population: a population-based mortality study. Neurology 2009; 72:1640&#x2013;1645.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19433736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardiman O, Heverin M, Rooney J, et al. . The Latin American Epidemiology Network for ALS (Laenals). Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2022; 23:372&#x2013;377.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35060421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burrell JR, Halliday GM, Kril JJ, et al. . The frontotemporal dementia-motor neuron disease continuum. Lancet 2016; 388:919&#x2013;931.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26987909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Chalabi A, Hardiman O. The epidemiology of ALS: a conspiracy of genes, environment and time. Nat Rev Neurol 2013; 9:617&#x2013;628.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24126629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neary D, Snowden JS, Mann DM, et al. . Frontal lobe dementia and motor neuron disease. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 1990; 53:23&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1014093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2303828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vance C, Al-Chalabi A, Ruddy D, et al. . Familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with frontotemporal dementia is linked to a locus on chromosome 9p13.2&#x2013;21.3. Brain 2006; 129:868&#x2013;876.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16495328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeJesus-Hernandez M, Mackenzie IR, Boeve BF, et al. . Expanded GGGGCC hexanucleotide repeat in noncoding region of C9ORF72 causes chromosome 9p-linked FTD and ALS. Neuron 2011; 72:245&#x2013;256.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3202986</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21944778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strong MJ, Abrahams S, Goldstein LH, et al. . Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis - frontotemporal spectrum disorder (ALS-FTSD): revised diagnostic criteria. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2017; 18:153&#x2013;174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7409990</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28054827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strong MJ, Grace GM, Freedman M, et al. . Consensus criteria for the diagnosis of frontotemporal cognitive and behavioural syndromes in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler 2009; 10:131&#x2013;146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19462523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2; A, Moglia C, Canosa A, et al. . Cognitive impairment across ALS clinical stages in a population-based cohort. Neurology 2019; 93:e984&#x2013;e994.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6745732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31409738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montuschi A, Iazzolino B, Calvo A, et al. . Cognitive correlates in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a population-based study in Italy. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2015; 86:168&#x2013;173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24769471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elamin M, Bede P, Byrne S, et al. . Cognitive changes predict functional decline in ALS: a population-based longitudinal study. Neurology 2013; 80:1590&#x2013;1597.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23553481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phukan J, Elamin M, Bede P, et al. . The syndrome of cognitive impairment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a population-based study. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2012; 83:102&#x2013;108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21836033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner MR, Goldacre R, Talbot K, Goldacre MJ. Psychiatric disorders prior to amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol 2016; 80:935&#x2013;938.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5215396</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27761925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longinetti E, Mariosa D, Larsson H, et al. . Neurodegenerative and psychiatric diseases among families with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology 2017; 89:578&#x2013;585.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5562958</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28701495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byrne S, Heverin M, Elamin M, et al. . Aggregation of neurologic and neuropsychiatric disease in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis kindreds: a population-based case&#x2013;control cohort study of familial and sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol 2013; 74:699&#x2013;708.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23836460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Brien M, Burke T, Heverin M, et al. . Clustering of neuropsychiatric disease in first-degree and second-degree relatives of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. JAMA Neurol 2017; 74:1425&#x2013;1430.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5822189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29049464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silverman HE, Goldman JS, Huey ED. Links between the C9orf72 repeat expansion and psychiatric symptoms. Curr Neurol Neurosci Rep 2019; 19:93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31773397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devenney EM, Ahmed RM, Halliday G, et al. . Psychiatric disorders in C9orf72 kindreds: study of 1,414 family members. Neurology 2018; 91:e1498&#x2013;e1507.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30258023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosen DR, Siddique T, Patterson D, et al. . Mutations in Cu/Zn superoxide dismutase gene are associated with familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nature 1993; 362:59&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8446170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renton AE, Chi&#xf2; A, Traynor BJ. State of play in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis genetics. Nat Neurosci 2014; 17:17&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4544832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24369373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chia R, Chi&#xf2; A, Traynor BJ. Novel genes associated with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: diagnostic and clinical implications. Lancet Neurol 2018; 17:94&#x2013;102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5901717</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29154141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardiman O, Al-Chalabi A, Brayne C, et al. . The changing picture of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: lessons from European registers. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2017; 88:557&#x2013;563.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28285264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grassano M, Calvo A, Moglia C, et al. . Mutational analysis of known ALS genes in an Italian population-based cohort. Neurology 2021; 96:e600&#x2013;e609.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7905787</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33208543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2; A, Calvo A, Mazzini L, et al. . Extensive genetics of ALS: a population-based study in Italy. Neurology 2012; 79:1983&#x2013;1989.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3484987</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23100398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kenna KP, McLaughlin RL, Byrne S, et al. . Delineating the genetic heterogeneity of ALS using targeted high-throughput sequencing. J Med Genet 2013; 50:776&#x2013;783.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3812897</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23881933</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Majounie E, Renton AE, Mok K, et al. . Frequency of the C9orf72 hexanucleotide repeat expansion in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal dementia: a cross-sectional study. Lancet Neurol 2012; 11:323&#x2013;330.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3322422</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22406228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2; A, Brunetti M, Barberis M, et al. . The role of APOE in the occurrence of frontotemporal dementia in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. JAMA Neurol 2016; 73:425&#x2013;430.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26903389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2; A, Moglia C, Canosa A, et al. . ALS phenotype is influenced by age, sex, and genetics: a population-based study. Neurology 2020; 94:e802&#x2013;e810.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31907290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byrne S, Elamin M, Bede P, et al. . Cognitive and clinical characteristics of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis carrying a C9orf72 repeat expansion: a population-based cohort study. Lancet Neurol 2012; 11:232&#x2013;240.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3315021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22305801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westeneng HJ, van Veenhuijzen K, van der Spek RA, et al. . Associations between lifestyle and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis stratified by C9orf72 genotype: a longitudinal, population-based, case-control study. Lancet Neurol 2021; 20:373&#x2013;384.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33894192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Chalabi A, Fang F, Hanby MF, et al. . An estimate of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis heritability using twin data. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2010; 81:1324&#x2013;1326.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2988617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20861059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan M, Heverin M, McLaughlin RL, Hardiman O. Lifetime risk and heritability of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. JAMA Neurol 2019; 76:1367&#x2013;1374.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6646974</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31329211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crockford C, Newton J, Lonergan K, et al. . ALS-specific cognitive and behavior changes associated with advancing disease stage in ALS. Neurology 2018; 91:e1370&#x2013;e1380.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6177274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30209236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pliner HA, Mann DM, Traynor BJ. Searching for Grendel: origin and global spread of the C9ORF72 repeat expansion. Acta Neuropathol 2014; 127:391&#x2013;396.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4545603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24496499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paganoni S, Macklin EA, Hendrix S, et al. . Trial of sodium phenylbutyrate&#x2013;taurursodiol for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. N Engl J Med 2020; 383:919&#x2013;930.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9134321</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32877582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim G, Gautier O, Tassoni-Tsuchida E, et al. . ALS genetics: gains, losses, and implications for future therapies. Neuron 2020; 108:822&#x2013;842.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7736125</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32931756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>