<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35942674</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>08</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1473-6551</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>35</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Current opinion in neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Curr Opin Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Biomarkers for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>699</StartPage><EndPage>704</EndPage><MedlinePgn>699-704</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/WCO.0000000000001094</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE OF REVIEW">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) is an incurable, devastating neurodegenerative disease. Still, the diagnosis is mainly based on clinical symptoms, and the treatment options are strongly limited. However, the pipeline of potential treatments currently tested in clinical trials is promising. This review will discuss developments in ALS biomarker research and applications within the last 2 years and suggest future directions and needs.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RECENT FINDINGS">The diagnostic and prognostic utility of neurofilaments, a general marker for axoneuronal degeneration, has been confirmed by further studies in patients with ALS, and neurofilaments are finding their way into routine diagnostic and clinical trials. Additionally, there have been advancements in developing and implementing disease-specific biomarkers, especially in patients with a genetic variant, such as SOD1 or C9orf72 . Here, biomarkers have already been used as target markers and outcome parameters for novel treatment approaches. In addition, several novel biomarkers have shown encouraging results but should be discussed in the context of their early stage of assay and clinical establishment.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUMMARY">The first biomarkers have found their way into clinical routine in ALS. In light of an increasing pipeline of potential treatments, further progress in discovering and implementing novel and existing biomarkers is crucial.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Witzel</LastName><ForeName>Simon</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Ulm University Hospital, Oberer Eselsberg.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mayer</LastName><ForeName>Kristina</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Ulm University Hospital, Oberer Eselsberg.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oeckl</LastName><ForeName>Patrick</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Ulm University Hospital, Oberer Eselsberg.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>German Center for Neurodegenerative Diseases (DZNE), Site Ulm, Ulm, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Curr Opin Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9319162</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1350-7540</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D015415">Biomarkers</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015415" MajorTopicYN="N">Biomarkers</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019636" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neurodegenerative Diseases</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011379" MajorTopicYN="N">Prognosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35942674</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/WCO.0000000000001094</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00019052-202210000-00022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Vacchiano V, Mastrangelo A, Zenesini C, et al. Plasma and CSF neurofilament light chain in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a cross-sectional and longitudinal study. Front Aging Neurosci 2021; 13:753242.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sferruzza G, Bosco L, Falzone YM, et al. Neurofilament light chain as a biological marker for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a meta-analysis study. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2021; 23:446&#x2013;457.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dreger M, Steinbach R, Gaur N, et al. cerebrospinal fluid neurofilament light chain (NfL) predicts disease aggressiveness in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: an application of the D50 Disease Progression Model. Front Neurosci 2021; 15:651651.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behzadi A, Pujol-Calder&#xf3;n F, Tjust AE, et al. Neurofilaments can differentiate ALS subgroups and ALS from common diagnostic mimics. Sci Rep 2021; 11:22126&#x2013;22128.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halbgebauer S, Steinacker P, Verde F, et al. Comparison of CSF and serum neurofilament light and heavy chain as differential diagnostic biomarkers for ALS. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2022; 93:68&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gagliardi D, Faravelli I, Meneri M, et al. Diagnostic and prognostic value of CSF neurofilaments in a cohort of patients with motor neuron disease: a cross-sectional study. J Cell Mol Med 2021; 25:3765&#x2013;3771.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashton NJ, Janelidze S, Khleifat Aal, et al. A multicentre validation study of the diagnostic value of plasma neurofilament light. Nat Commun 2021; 12:3400.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dorst J, Schuster J, Dreyhaupt J, et al. Effect of high-caloric nutrition on serum neurofilament light chain levels in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2020; 91:1007&#x2013;1009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biogen announces topline results from the Tofersen Phase 3 Study and its open-label extension in SOD1-ALS. Available at: https://investors.biogen.com/news-releases/news-release-details/biogen-announces-topline-results-tofersen-phase-3-study-and-its , 17 October 2021[accessed 25 March 2022]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Witzel S, Frauhammer F, Steinacker P, et al. Neurofilament light and heterogeneity of disease progression in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: development and validation of a prediction model to improve interventional trials. Transl Neurodegener 2021; 10:31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen PM. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis associated with mutations in the CuZn superoxide dismutase gene. Curr Neurol Neurosci Rep 2006; 6:37&#x2013;46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saccon RA, Bunton-Stasyshyn RKA, Fisher EMC, Fratta P. Is SOD1 loss of function involved in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis? Brain 2013; 136:2342&#x2013;2358.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Souza PVS, de Rezende Pinto WBV, Farias IB, et al. Progressive spastic tetraplegia and axial hypotonia (STAHP) due to SOD1 deficiency: is it really a new entity? Orphanet J Rare Dis 2021; 16:360.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wegener AJ, Setnicka A, Schoch KM, et al. Antisense oligonucleotides extend survival and reverse decrement in muscle response in ALS models recommended citation. J Clin Invest 2018; 128:3558&#x2013;3567.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller T, Cudkowicz M, Shaw PJ, et al. Phase 1-2 trial of antisense oligonucleotide Tofersen for SOD1 ALS. New Engl J Med 2020; 383:109&#x2013;119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gertsman I, Wuu J, McAlonis-Downes M, et al. An endogenous peptide marker differentiates SOD1 stability and facilitates pharmacodynamic monitoring in SOD1 amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. JCI Insight 2019; 4:e122768.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iannitti T, Scarrott JM, Likhite S, et al. Translating SOD1 gene silencing toward the clinic: a highly efficacious, off-target-free, and biomarker-supported strategy for fALS. Mol Ther Nucleic Acids 2018; 12:75&#x2013;88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCampbell A, Cole T, Wegener AJ, et al. Antisense oligonucleotides extend survival and reverse decrement in muscle response in ALS models. J Clin Invest 2018; 128:3558&#x2013;3567.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abati E, Bresolin N, Comi G, Corti S. Silence superoxide dismutase 1 (SOD1): a promising therapeutic target for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). Expert Opin Ther Targets 2020; 24:295&#x2013;310.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fahmy N, M&#xfc;ller K, Andersen P, et al. Motor neuron disorders and neuropathies. Neuromusc Disord 2021; 31:S122&#x2013;S123.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen PM, Nordstr&#xf6;m U, Tsiakas K, et al. Phenotype in an infant with SOD1 homozygous truncating mutation 2019; 381:486&#x2013;488.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park JH, Elpers C, Reunert J, et al. SOD1 deficiency: a novel syndrome distinct from amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain 2019; 142:2230&#x2013;2237.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lehmer C, Oeckl P, Weishaupt JH, et al. Poly- GP in cerebrospinal fluid links C9orf72 -associated dipeptide repeat expression to the asymptomatic phase of ALS/FTD. EMBO Mol Med 2017; 9:859&#x2013;868.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gendron TF, Chew J, Stankowski JN, et al. Poly(GP) proteins are a useful pharmacodynamic marker for C9ORF72-associated amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Sci Transl Med 2017; 9:eaai7866.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson KM, Katona E, Glaria I, et al. Development of a sensitive trial-ready poly(GP) CSF biomarker assay for C9orf72-associated frontotemporal dementia and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2022; 93:761&#x2013;771.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dreger M, Steinbach R, Otto M, et al. Cerebrospinal fluid biomarkers of disease activity and progression in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2022; 93:422&#x2013;435.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scial&#xf2; C, Tran TH, Salzano G, et al. TDP-43 real-time quaking induced conversion reaction optimization and detection of seeding activity in CSF of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal dementia patients. Brain Commun 2020; 2:fcaa142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beyer L, G&#xfc;nther R, Koch JC, et al. TDP-43 as structure-based biomarker in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Clin Transl Neurol 2021; 8:271&#x2013;277.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gen&#xe7; B, Jara JH, Schultz MC, et al. Absence of UCHL 1 function leads to selective motor neuropathy. Ann Clin Transl Neurol 2016; 3:331&#x2013;345.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oeckl P, Weydt P, Thal DR, et al. Proteomics in cerebrospinal fluid and spinal cord suggests UCHL1, MAP2 and GPNMB as biomarkers and underpins importance of transcriptional pathways in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathol 2020; 139:119&#x2013;134.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barschke P, Oeckl P, Steinacker P, et al. German FTLD consortium. Different CSF protein profiles in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal dementia with C9orf72 hexanucleotide repeat expansion. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2020; 91:503&#x2013;511.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li R, Wang J, Xie W, et al. UCHL1 from serum and CSF is a candidate biomarker for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Clin Transl Neurol 2020; 7:1420&#x2013;1428.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu S, Wuolikainen A, Wu J, et al. Targeted multiple reaction monitoring analysis of CSF identifies UCHL1 and GPNMB as candidate biomarkers for ALS. J Mol Neurosci 2019; 69:643&#x2013;657.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanaka H, Shimazawa M, Kimura M, et al. The potential of GPNMB as novel neuroprotective factor in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Sci Rep 2012; 2:573.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Lienden M, Gaspar P, Boot R, et al. Glycoprotein non-metastatic protein B: an emerging biomarker for lysosomal dysfunction in macrophages. Int J Mol Sci 2018; 20:66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steinacker P, Feneberg E, Halbgebauer S, et al. Chitotriosidase as biomarker for early stage amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a multicenter study. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2021; 22:276&#x2013;286.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oeckl P, Weydt P, Steinacker P, et al. Different neuroinflammatory profile in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal dementia is linked to the clinical phase. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2019; 90:4&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xe5;nberg A, Skene N, Sanders F, et al. Altered perivascular fibroblast activity precedes ALS disease onset. Nat Med 2021; 27:640&#x2013;646.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saracino D, Dorgham K, Camuzat A, et al. Plasma NfL levels and longitudinal change rates in C9orf72 and GRN-associated diseases: from tailored references to clinical applications. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2021; 92:1278&#x2013;1288.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khalil M, Pirpamer L, Hofer E, et al. Serum neurofilament light levels in normal aging and their association with morphologic brain changes. Nat Commun 2020; 11:812.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akamine S, Marutani N, Kanayama D, et al. Renal function is associated with blood neurofilament light chain level in older adults. Sci Rep 2020; 10:20350.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manouchehrinia A, Piehl F, Hillert J, et al. Confounding effect of blood volume and body mass index on blood neurofilament light chain levels. Ann Clin Transl Neurol 2020; 7:139&#x2013;143.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paterson RW, Gabelle A, Lucey BP, et al. SILK studies - capturing the turnover of proteins linked to neurodegenerative diseases. Nat Rev Neurol 2019; 15:419&#x2013;427.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>