<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">35965311</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1743-0003</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>19</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>14</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of neuroengineering and rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Neuroeng Rehabil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Evaluating surface EMG control of motorized wheelchairs for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>88</StartPage><MedlinePgn>88</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">88</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12984-022-01066-8</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">This study evaluated a novel control method for patients unable to independently control powered wheelchairs. Patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis often require a wheelchair but struggle with sufficient hand dexterity required for joystick control making them a population that needs this type of control method.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">The study employed a novel control mechanism, using electromyography surface sensors applied to temporalis muscles able to measure the myoelectric voltage. Pattern and magnitude control of muscle contraction allowed for steering intention recognition and were used to manipulate their power wheelchair joystick. Four patients ages 51 to 69, two female and two male with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, conducted Wheelchair Skills Test developed by Dalhousie University and were surveyed on the experience's Clinical Global Impression of Change.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Findings showed independent steering was capable for patients without hand function and provided recommendations for improved human-machine interface. All patients demonstrated the ability to engage the system, with varying precision, for driving their wheelchair in a controlled environment.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Three patients in the pilot trial reported the highest score of clinical global impression of change, all of whom had lost independent control of their wheelchair joystick. Patient four retained impaired hand dexterity for joystick control and reported negative impression of change, comparatively. Feedback from the study will be leveraged to improve training outcomes. Trial registration Subjects provided signed informed consent according to the Declaration of Helsinki to enter the study that was approved by the Mayo Clinic Institutional Review Board in Rochester, Minnesota. The study is registered on ClinicalTrials.gov under identifier NCT04800926 as of March 14, 2021 retrospectively registered.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Manero</LastName><ForeName>Albert C</ForeName><Initials>AC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0145-7582</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Limbitless Solutions, University of Central Florida, 12703 Research Parkway, Suite 100, Orlando, USA. albert@limbitless-solutions.org.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McLinden</LastName><ForeName>Shea L</ForeName><Initials>SL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Limbitless Solutions, University of Central Florida, 12703 Research Parkway, Suite 100, Orlando, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sparkman</LastName><ForeName>John</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Limbitless Solutions, University of Central Florida, 12703 Research Parkway, Suite 100, Orlando, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oskarsson</LastName><ForeName>Bj&#xf6;rn</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ALS Center of Excellence, Mayo Clinic, 4500 San Pablo Road, Jacksonville, 32224, USA. Oskarsson.Bjorn@mayo.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT04800926</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D018848">Controlled Clinical Trial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Neuroeng Rehabil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101232233</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1743-0003</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004576" MajorTopicYN="N">Electromyography</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005246" MajorTopicYN="N">Feedback</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014910" MajorTopicYN="Y">Wheelchairs</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Electromyography</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle activation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Temporalis muscles</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Wheelchair</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no competing interests and want to disclose that the technology used for this study is awarded Patent # 10,426,370.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35965311</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9375912</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12984-022-01066-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12984-022-01066-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Oskarsson B, Gendron TF, Staff NP. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: an update for 2018. In: Mayo clinic proceedings, vol. 93. Elsevier; 2018. p. 1617&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30401437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wijesekera LC, Nigel Leigh P. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Orphanet J Rare Dis. 2009;4(1):1&#x2013;22. doi: 10.1186/1750-1172-4-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1750-1172-4-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2656493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19192301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arthur KC, Calvo A, Price TR, Geiger JT, Chio A, Traynor BJ. Projected increase in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis from 2015 to 2040. Nat Commun. 2016;7(1):1&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1038/ncomms12408.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ncomms12408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4987527</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27510634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehta P, Kaye W, Bryan L, Larson T, Copeland T, Wu J, Muravov O, Horton K. Prevalence of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-united states, 2012&#x2013;2013. Morb Mortal Wkly Rep Surveill Summ. 2016;65(8):1&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27490513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bello-Haas VD, Kloos AD, Mitsumoto H. Physical therapy for a patient through six stages of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Phys Ther. 1998;78(12):1312&#x2013;1324. doi: 10.1093/ptj/78.12.1312.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ptj/78.12.1312</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9859950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyrick A. Powered wheelchair provision for adults diagnosed with rapidly deteriorating MND. Posture and Mobility Group. 2016;2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oskarsson B, Joyce NC, De Bie E, Nicorici A, Bajcsy R, Kurillo G, Han JJ. Upper extremity 3-dimensional reachable workspace assessment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis by Kinect sensor. Muscle Nerve. 2016;53(2):234&#x2013;241. doi: 10.1002/mus.24703.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.24703</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4770889</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25965847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cowan RE, Fregly BJ, Boninger ML, Chan L, Rodgers MM, Reinkensmeyer DJ. Recent trends in assistive technology for mobility. J Neuroeng Rehabilitat. 2012;9(1):1&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1186/1743-0003-9-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1743-0003-9-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3474161</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22520500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andres PL, Slavin MD, Jette DU, Munsat TL. Lower extremity muscle strength measures in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurol Rep. 1997;21(5):184. doi: 10.1097/01253086-199721050-00067.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/01253086-199721050-00067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arts IM, Overeem S, Pillen S, Schelhaas HJ, Zwarts MJ. Muscle changes in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a longitudinal ultrasonography study. Clin Neurophysiol. 2011;122(3):623&#x2013;628. doi: 10.1016/j.clinph.2010.07.023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clinph.2010.07.023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20810308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Disselhorst-Klug C, Schmitz-Rode T, Rau G. Surface electromyography and muscle force: limits in sEMG-force relationship and new approaches for applications. Clin Biomech. 2009;24(3):225&#x2013;235. doi: 10.1016/j.clinbiomech.2008.08.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clinbiomech.2008.08.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18849097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manero A, Oskarsson B, Sparkman J, Smith PA, Dombrowski M, Peddinti M, Rodriguez A, Vila J, Jones B. Xavier electromyographic wheelchair control and virtual training. In: International conference on human&#x2013;computer interaction. Springer; 2019. p. 133&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Day S. Important factors in surface EMG measurement. Calgary: Bortec Biomedical Ltd Publishers; 2002. pp. 1&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merletti R, Parker PJ. Electromyography: physiology, engineering, and non-invasive applications. Hoboken: Wiley; 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaur A. Wheelchair control for disabled patients using EMG/EOG based human machine interface: a review. J Med Eng Technol. 2021;45(1):61&#x2013;74. doi: 10.1080/03091902.2020.1853838.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/03091902.2020.1853838</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33302770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu X, Zhang Y, Luo Y, Chen D. Robust bio-signal based control of an intelligent wheelchair. Robotics. 2013;2(4):187&#x2013;197. doi: 10.3390/robotics2040187.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/robotics2040187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moon I, Lee M, Chu J, Mun M. Wearable EMG-based HCI for electric-powered wheelchair users with motor disabilities. In: Proceedings of the 2005 IEEE international conference on robotics and automation. 2005. p. 2649&#x2013;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt ER, Pasterkamp RJ, van den Berg LH. Axon guidance proteins: novel therapeutic targets for ALS? Progr Neurobiol. 2009;88(4):286&#x2013;301. doi: 10.1016/j.pneurobio.2009.05.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pneurobio.2009.05.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19523502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruijn LI, Miller TM, Cleveland DW. Unraveling the mechanisms involved in motor neuron degeneration in ALS. Annu Rev Neurosci. 2004;27:723&#x2013;749. doi: 10.1146/annurev.neuro.27.070203.144244.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev.neuro.27.070203.144244</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15217349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lung C-W, Chen C-L, Jan Y-K, Chao L-F, Chen W-F, Liau B-Y. Activation sequence patterns of forearm muscles for driving a power wheelchair. In: International conference on applied human factors and ergonomics. Springer; 2017. p. 141.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lung C-W, Cheng T-Y, Jan Y-K, Chen H-C, Liau B-Y. Advances in physical ergonomics and human factors. Cham: Springer; 2016. Electromyographic assessments of muscle activation patterns during driving a power wheelchair; pp. 705&#x2013;711.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Felzer T, Freisleben B. Hawcos: the &#x201c;hands-free&#x201d; wheelchair control system. In: Proceedings of the fifth international ACM conference on assistive technologies. 2002. p. 127&#x2013;34 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva A, Mor&#xe8;re Y, Naves E, De&#xa0;Sa A, Soares A. Virtual electric wheelchair controlled by electromyographic signals. In: 2013 ISSNIP biosignals and biorobotics conference: biosignals and robotics for better and safer living (BRC). IEEE; 2013. p. 1&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Araujo JM, Zhang G, Hansen JPP, Puthusserypady S. Exploring eye-gaze wheelchair control. In: ACM symposium on eye tracking research and applications. 2020. p. 1&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bazrafkan S, Kar A, Costache C. Eye gaze for consumer electronics: controlling and commanding intelligent systems. IEEE Consum Electron Mag. 2015;4(4):65&#x2013;71. doi: 10.1109/MCE.2015.2464852.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/MCE.2015.2464852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puanhvuan D, Khemmachotikun S, Wechakarn P, Wijarn B, Wongsawat Y. Navigation-synchronized multimodal control wheelchair from brain to alternative assistive technologies for persons with severe disabilities. Cogn Neurodyn. 2017;11(2):117&#x2013;134. doi: 10.1007/s11571-017-9424-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11571-017-9424-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5350091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28348644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, Miller RG, Swash M, Munsat TL. El Escorial revisited: revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord. 2000;1(5):293&#x2013;299. doi: 10.1080/146608200300079536.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/146608200300079536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11464847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ALS CNTF Treatment study (ACTS) phase I&#x2013;II study group The amyotrophic lateral sclerosis functional rating scale. Assessment of activities of daily living in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Arch Neurol. 1996;53(2):41&#x2013;147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8639063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coco DL, Marchese S, La Bella V, Piccoli T, Coco AL. The amyotrophic lateral sclerosis functional rating scale predicts survival time in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients on invasive mechanical ventilation. Chest. 2007;132(1):64&#x2013;69. doi: 10.1378/chest.06-2712.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1378/chest.06-2712</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17475635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Busner J, Targum SD. The clinical global impressions scale: applying a research tool in clinical practice. Psychiatry. 2007;4(7):28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2880930</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20526405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guy W. ECDEU assessment manual for psychopharmacology. Rockville: US Department of Health, Education, and Welfare; 1976.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirby RL, Smith C, Parker K, McAllister M, Boyce J, Rushton PW, Routhier F, Best KL, Brandt A. Wheelchair skills program manual 4.0. Halifax: Dalhousie University; 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirby RL, Rushton PW, Smith C, Routhier F, Best KL, Cowan R, Giesbrecht E, Koontz A, MacKenzie D, Mortenson B, et al. Wheelchair skills program manual 5.0. Halifax: Dalhousie University; 2019.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>