<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35975358</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1600-0404</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>146</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Acta neurologica Scandinavica</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Acta Neurol Scand</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Slow vital capacity as a useful indicator of the prognosis after percutaneous endoscopic gastrostomy in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>578</StartPage><EndPage>585</EndPage><MedlinePgn>578-585</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/ane.13683</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Forced vital capacity (FVC) is recommended as a respiratory function test in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). However, in ALS associated with orofacial palsy, FVC may be an unreliable test. Slow vital capacity (SVC) is an easier and more reliable test even in cases with bulbar symptoms. However, it remains unclear whether respiratory function tests using SVC and FVC are associated with prognosis after percutaneous endoscopic gastrostomy (PEG) placement. This study aimed to confirm whether both SVC and FVC are related to prognosis after PEG placement in patients with ALS.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We conducted this retrospective observational cohort study of 69 consecutive patients diagnosed with sporadic ALS who underwent PEG placement between July 2007 and February 2020. We analyzed the association with mortality 6&#x2009;months after PEG placement and evaluated long-term prognosis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Forty-four patients met the inclusion criteria. In cases with decreased SVC (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;.01) and FVC (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;.01), a significant difference was observed in mortality 6&#x2009;months after PEG placement, with an optimal cut-off of SVC &#x2264;57.4% (sensitivity, 0.828; specificity, 0.867) and FVC &#x2264;57.3% (sensitivity, 0.828; specificity, 0.867). Multivariate analysis showed that onset age&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;65&#x2009;years (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;.05), SVC &#x2264;57.4% (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;.01), and FVC &#x2264;57.3% (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;.01) were associated with survival after PEG placement.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">SVC, like FVC, is an important prognostic factor after PEG placement in patients with ALS, and there is a possibility that evaluation using SVC can complement respiratory function testing even in cases where the evaluation of FVC is limited.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022 John Wiley &amp; Sons A/S. Published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ueno</LastName><ForeName>Tatsuya</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6212-0265</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Aomori Prefectural Central Hospital, Aomori, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Haga</LastName><ForeName>Rie</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Aomori Prefectural Central Hospital, Aomori, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Arai</LastName><ForeName>Akira</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Aomori Prefectural Central Hospital, Aomori, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tomiyama</LastName><ForeName>Masahiko</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Hirosaki University Graduate School of Medicine, Hirosaki, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D064888">Observational Study</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Denmark</Country><MedlineTA>Acta Neurol Scand</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0370336</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0001-6314</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000601" MajorTopicYN="N">surgery</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005774" MajorTopicYN="N">Gastrostomy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011379" MajorTopicYN="N">Prognosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014797" MajorTopicYN="N">Vital Capacity</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">forced vital capacity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">percutaneous endoscopic gastrostomy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">prognosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">slow vital capacity</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35975358</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ane.13683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Goutman SA. Diagnosis and clinical management of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and other motor neuron disorders. Continuum (Minneapolis, Minn). 2017;23:1332-1359.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barone M, Viggiani MT, Introna A, et al. Nutritional prognostic factors for survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients undergone percutaneous endoscopic gastrostomy placement. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2019;20:490-496.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pena MJ, Ravasco P, Machado M, et al. What is the relevance of percutaneous endoscopic gastrostomy on the survival of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis? Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2012;13:550-554.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ProGasStudyGroup. Gastrostomy in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ProGas): a prospective cohort study. Lancet Neurol. 2015;14:702-709.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bond L, Ganguly P, Khamankar N, et al. A comprehensive examination of percutaneous endoscopic gastrostomy and its association with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patient outcomes. Brain Sci. 2019;9:223.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagashima K, Furuta N, Makioka K, Fujita Y, Ikeda M, Ikeda Y. An analysis of prognostic factors after percutaneous endoscopic gastrostomy placement in Japanese patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Sci. 2017;376:202-205.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fasano A, Fini N, Ferraro D, Ferri L, Vinceti M, Mandrioli J. Percutaneous endoscopic gastrostomy, body weight loss and survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a population-based registry study. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2017;18:233-242.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bokuda K, Shimizu T, Imamura K, et al. Predictive factors for prognosis following unsedated percutaneous endoscopic gastrostomy in ALS patients. Muscle Nerve. 2016;54:277-283.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2; A, Finocchiaro E, Meineri P, Bottacchi E, Schiffer D. Safety and factors related to survival after percutaneous endoscopic gastrostomy in ALS. ALS Percutaneous Endoscopic Gastrostomy Study Group. Neurology. 1999;53:1123-1125.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasarskis EJ, Scarlata D, Hill R, Fuller C, Stambler N, Cedarbaum JM. A retrospective study of percutaneous endoscopic gastrostomy in ALS patients during the BDNF and CNTF trials. J Neurol Sci. 1999;169:118-125.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazzini L, Corr&#xe0; T, Zaccala M, Mora G, Del Piano M, Galante M. Percutaneous endoscopic gastrostomy and enteral nutrition in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol. 1995;242:695-698.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller RG, Jackson CE, Kasarskis EJ, et al. Practice parameter update: the care of the patient with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: drug, nutritional, and respiratory therapies (an evidence-based review): report of the Quality Standards Subcommittee of the American Academy of Neurology. Neurology. 2009;73:1218-1226.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen PM, Abrahams S, Borasio GD, et al. EFNS guidelines on the clinical management of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (MALS)--revised report of an EFNS task force. Eur J Neurol. 2012;19:360-375.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Swash M, Pinto S. Diaphragmatic neurophysiology and respiratory markers in ALS. Front Neurol. 2019;10:143.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheung HJ, Cheung L. Coaching patients during pulmonary function testing: a practical guide. Can J Respir Ther. 2015;51:65-68.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Epstein SK. Respiratory muscle weakness due to neuromuscular disease: clinical manifestations and evaluation. In: Post T, ed. UpToDate. Waltham, MA: UpToDate; 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinto S, de Carvalho M. Correlation between forced vital capacity and slow vital capacity for the assessment of respiratory involvement in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a prospective study. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2017;18:86-91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinto S, de Carvalho M. Comparison of slow and forced vital capacities on ability to predict survival in ALS. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2017;18:528-533.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desport J-C, Mabrouk T, Bouillet P, Perna A, Preux P-M, Couratier P. Complications and survival following radiologically and endoscopically-guided gastrostomy in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2005;6:88-93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, Miller RG, Swash M, Munsat TL. El Escorial revisited: revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord. 2000;1:293-299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishimura M, Aizawa H, Kanbe M, et al. Committee of pulmonary physiology, the Japanese Respiratory Society guidelines for pulmonary function tests: spirometry, flow-volume curve, diffusion capacity of the lung. Tokyo: Japanese Respiratory Society. 2004:20-23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burgos R, Bret&#xf3;n I, Cereda E, et al. ESPEN guideline clinical nutrition in neurology. Clin Nutr. 2018;37:354-396.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castanheira A, Swash M, De Carvalho M. Percutaneous gastrostomy in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a review. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2021;14:1-14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allen JA, Chen R, Ajroud-Driss S, et al. Gastrostomy tube placement by endoscopy versus radiologic methods in patients with ALS: a retrospective study of complications and outcome. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2013;14:308-314.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson AG, Blackwell V, Marsden R, et al. A risk stratifying tool to facilitate safe late-stage percutaneous endoscopic gastrostomy in ALS. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2017;18:243-248.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elbe P, Markus K, Valente R, Ingre C, Tsolakis AV, Vujasinovic M. Effectiveness of percutaneous endoscopic gastrostomy in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Minerva Gastroenterol Dietol. 2020;66:219-224.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spataro R, Ficano L, Piccoli F, La Bella V. Percutaneous endoscopic gastrostomy in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: effect on survival. J Neurol Sci. 2011;304:44-48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kak M, Issa NP, Roos RP, et al. Gastrostomy tube placement is safe in advanced amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurol Res. 2017;39:16-22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarfaty M, Nefussy B, Gross D, Shapira Y, Vaisman N, Drory VE. Outcome of percutaneous endoscopic gastrostomy insertion in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in relation to respiratory dysfunction. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2013;14:528-532.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forbes RB, Colville S, Swingler RJ. Frequency, timing and outcome of gastrostomy tubes for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis/motor neurone disease--a record linkage study from the Scottish Motor Neurone Disease Register. J Neurol. 2004;251:813-817.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gregory S, Siderowf A, Golaszewski AL, McCluskey L. Gastrostomy insertion in ALS patients with low vital capacity: respiratory support and survival. Neurology. 2002;58:485-487.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suzuki Y, Tamez S, Murakami A, et al. Survival of geriatric patients after percutaneous endoscopic gastrostomy in Japan. World J Gastroenterol. 2010;16:5084-5091.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atsuta N, Watanabe H, Ito M, et al. Age at onset influences on wide-ranged clinical features of sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Sci. 2009;276:163-169.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferraro PM, Cabona C, Meo G, et al. Age at symptom onset influences cortical thinning distribution and survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuroradiology. 2021;63:1481-1487.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Mantgem MRJ, van Eijk RP, van der Burgh HK, et al. Prognostic value of weight loss in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a population-based study. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2020;91:867-875.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moglia C, Calvo A, Grassano M, et al. Early weight loss in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: outcome relevance and clinical correlates in a population-based cohort. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2019;90:666-673.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ackrivo J, Hansen-Flaschen J, Jones BL, et al. Classifying patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis by changes in FVC. A group-based trajectory analysis. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2019;200:1513-1521.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>