<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35981308</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>08</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2331-2637</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>28</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>May</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The neurologist</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Neurologist</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Prognostic Value of Regular Nutritional Treatment in Patients With Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>166</StartPage><EndPage>172</EndPage><MedlinePgn>166-172</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/NRL.0000000000000460</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Malnutrition adversely affects the prognosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). The aim of this study was to evaluate the effect of regular nutrition treatment and follow-up in clinical nutrition outpatient clinic (CNOC) on survival in ALS patients.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">The study included 55 ALS patients who were admitted and followed up in CNOC. Malnutrition was diagnosed using ESPEN criteria and nutrition treatment was planned according to needs of each patient. Nutritional status was followed up by body mass index (BMI), bioelectrical impedence analysis, and serum albumin. During the follow-up, survivors and nonsurvivors were compared according to their nutrition treatment success and changes in the anthropometric and laboratory measurements.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Body weight, BMI, and fat free mass were decreased during the follow-up in both survivors and nonsurvivors ( P &lt;0.01). The decrease in the serum albumin and BMI were significantly higher in nonsurvivors ( P &lt;0.01). Mortality rate was lower in those with higher adherence to nutrition treatment ( P &lt;0.01) and patients with lower adherence to nutrition treatment showed more significant decrease in serum albumin levels ( P &lt;0.01).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">A personalized nutrition treatment combined with increased nutritional adherence in CNOC can decrease mortality in ALS patients.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Altinkaynak</LastName><ForeName>Mustafa</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7768-2746</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Istanbul Faculty of Medicine, Istanbul University, Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gok</LastName><ForeName>Gokhan Kerim</ForeName><Initials>GK</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ozmen</LastName><ForeName>Bahar</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Buyukdemir</LastName><ForeName>Serpil</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Akpinar</LastName><ForeName>Timur Selcuk</ForeName><Initials>TS</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Erten</LastName><ForeName>Sebile Nilgun</ForeName><Initials>SN</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saka</LastName><ForeName>Bulent</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Neurologist</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9503763</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1074-7931</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D012709">Serum Albumin</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011379" MajorTopicYN="N">Prognosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009752" MajorTopicYN="N">Nutritional Status</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015992" MajorTopicYN="N">Body Mass Index</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D044342" MajorTopicYN="Y">Malnutrition</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012709" MajorTopicYN="N">Serum Albumin</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000032" MajorTopicYN="N">analysis</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35981308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/NRL.0000000000000460</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00127893-202305000-00006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Kumar V, Kashav T, Hassan MI. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis: Current Therapeutic Perspectives. Pathology, Prevention and Therapeutics of Neurodegenerative Disease. Singapore: Springer; 2019:207&#x2013;224.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wijesekera LC, Leigh PN. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Orphanet J Rare Dis. 2009;4:1&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Es MA, Hardiman O, Chio A, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet. 2017;390:2084&#x2013;2098.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morgan S, Orrell RW. Pathogenesis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Br Med Bull. 2016;119:87&#x2013;98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mejzini R, Flynn LL, Pitout IL, et al. ALS genetics, mechanisms, and therapeutics: where are we now? Front Neurosci. 2019;13:1310.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quinn C, Elman L. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and other motor neuron diseases. Continuum (Minneap Minn). 2020;26:1323&#x2013;1347.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller RG, Mitchell JD, Moore DH. Riluzole for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS)/motor neuron disease (MND). Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2012;3:CD001447.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takei K, Takahashi F, Liu S, et al. Post-hoc analysis of randomised, placebo-controlled, double-blind study (MCI186-19) of edaravone (MCI-186) in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2017;18:49&#x2013;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cederholm T, Bosaeus I, Barazzoni R, et al. Diagnostic criteria for malnutrition&#x2014;an ESPEN Consensus Statement. Clin Nutr. 2015;34:335&#x2013;340.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cederholm T, Jensen GL, Correia MI, et al. GLIM criteria for the diagnosis of malnutrition&#x2013;a consensus report from the global clinical nutrition community. Clin Nutr. 2019;10:207&#x2013;217.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Genton L, Viatte V, Janssens JP, et al. Nutritional state, energy intakes and energy expenditure of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) patients. Clin Nutr. 2011;30:553&#x2013;559.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higo R, Tayama N, Nito T. Longitudinal analysis of progression of dysphagia in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Auris Nasus Larynx. 2004;31:247&#x2013;254.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenfeld J, Ellis A. Nutrition and dietary supplements in motor neuron disease. Phys Med Rehabil Clin N Am. 2008;19:573&#x2013;589.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desport JC, Preux PM, Truong CT, et al. Nutritional assessment and survival in ALS patients. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord. 2000;1:91&#x2013;96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf3;pez-G&#xf3;mez JJ, Ballesteros-Pomar MD, Torres-Torres B, et al. Malnutrition at diagnosis in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (als) and its influence on survival: using glim criteria. Clin Nutr. 2021;40:237&#x2013;244.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazzini L, Corr&#xe0; T, Zaccala M, et al. Percutaneous endoscopic gastrostomy and enteral nutrition in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol. 1995;242:695&#x2013;698.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kondrup J, Allison SP, Elia M, et al. ESPEN Guidelines for Nutrition Screening 2002. Clin Nutr. 2003;22:415&#x2013;421.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kondrup J, Rasmussen HH, Hamberg O, et al. Nutritional risk screening (NRS 2002): a new method based on an analysis of controlled clinical trials. Clin Nutr. 2003;22:321&#x2013;336.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim KM, Jang HC, Lim S. Differences among skeletal muscle mass indices derived from height-, weight-, and body mass index-adjusted models in assessing sarcopenia. Korean J Intern Med. 2016;31:643&#x2013;650.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z, Heymsfield SB, Pi-Sunyer FX, et al. Body composition analysis: cellular level modeling of body component ratios. Int J Body Compos Res. 2008;6:173&#x2013;184.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris JA, Benedict FG. A Biometric Study of Human Basal Metabolism in Man. Carnegie Institution of Washington; 1919. Publication No: 279.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volkert D, Beck AM, Cederholm T, et al. ESPEN guideline on clinical nutrition and hydration in geriatrics. Clin Nutr. 2019;38:10&#x2013;47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desport JC, Preux PM, Magy L, et al. Factors correlated with hypermetabolism in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Am J Clin Nutr. 2001;74:328&#x2013;334.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mariosa D, Kamel F, Bellocco R, et al. Association between diabetes and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in Sweden. Eur J Neurol. 2015;22:1436&#x2013;1442.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nunes G, Santos CA, Grunho M, et al. Enteral feeding through endoscopic gastrostomy in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. Nutr Hosp. 2016;33:1015&#x2013;1021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braun MM, Osecheck M, Joyce NC. Nutrition assessment and management in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Phys Med Rehabil Clin N Am. 2012;23:751&#x2013;771.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kellogg J, Bottman L, Arra EJ, et al. Nutrition management methods effective in increasing weight, survival time and functional status in ALS patients: a systematic review. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2018;19:7&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piquet MA. Nutritional approach for patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Rev Neurol (Paris). 2006;162:4S177&#x2013;4S187.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gil J, Funalot B, Verschueren A, et al. Causes of death amongst French patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a prospective study. Eur J Neurol. 2008;15:1245&#x2013;1251.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lechtzin N, Wiener CM, Clawson L, et al. Hospitalization in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: causes, costs, and outcomes. Neurology. 2001;56:753&#x2013;757.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardiman O, Van den Berg LH, Kiernan MC. Clinical diagnosis and management of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat Rev Neurol. 2011;7:639&#x2013;649.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xf6;rner S, Hendricks M, Kollewe K, et al. Weight loss, dysphagia and supplement intake in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS): impact on quality of life and therapeutic options. BMC Neurol. 2013;13:1&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallo V, Wark PA, Jenab M, et al. Prediagnostic body fat and risk of death from amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: the EPIC cohort. Neurology. 2013;80:829&#x2013;838.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sznajder J, Slefarska-Wasilewska M, K&#x142;ek S. The influence of the initial state of nutrition on the lifespan of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) during home enteral nutrition. Nutr Hosp. 2016;33:3&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almeida CS, Stanich P, Salvioni CC, et al. Assessment and nutrition education in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Arq Neuropsiquiatr. 2016;74:902&#x2013;908.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desport JC, Preux PM, Truong TC, et al. Nutritional status is a prognostic factor for survival in ALS patients. Neurology. 1999;53:1059&#x2013;1063.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>