<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35986916</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-4598</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>66</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Muscle &amp; nerve</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Muscle Nerve</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Appetite and quality of life in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A scoping review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>653</StartPage><EndPage>660</EndPage><MedlinePgn>653-660</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/mus.27694</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Loss of appetite is related to undesirable loss of weight in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) and affects up to two thirds of people with this disease. Little is known about the instruments used to measure appetite loss, its impact on quality of life (QoL), or strategies used to improve loss of appetite. In this study we aim to characterize the existing literature on the symptom of appetite loss in ALS through a systematic scoping review following the framework by Arksey and O'Malley and PRISMA guidelines. Studies assessing appetite in people with ALS (pALS) published in English and indexed on Web of Science, PubMed, and Scopus databases were included. A total of 156 full references were identified, of which 10 articles met the inclusion criteria and were eligible for data synthesis after screening. Seven unique instruments were used to assess appetite across the included studies, most commonly the Council of Nutrition Appetite Questionnaire. No studies included a subjective assessment of appetite loss. A total of 12 unique potential associated factors across five studies were identified. QoL was measured in seven studies using nine different QoL measurement tools. Few studies measure appetite in pALS and there is no consensus on the assessment tool used. Few studies evaluated the impact of appetite as a symptom on QoL. Furthermore, the heterogeneity of outcomes and risk factors of the existing data limit the clinical application of these findings. Future studies are needed to guide clinical management and interventions for people with ALS and appetite loss.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sarmet</LastName><ForeName>Max</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3029-8912</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Tertiary Referral Center of Neuromuscular Diseases, Hospital de Apoio de Bras&#xed;lia, Bras&#xed;lia, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate Department of Health Science and Technology, University of Bras&#xed;lia, Bras&#xed;lia, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kabani</LastName><ForeName>Aamna</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, Maryland, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maragakis</LastName><ForeName>Nicholas J</ForeName><Initials>NJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, Maryland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mehta</LastName><ForeName>Ambereen K</ForeName><Initials>AK</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7834-2279</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Palliative Care Program, Division of General Internal Medicine, Johns Hopkins Bayview Medical Center, Johns Hopkins University School of Medicine, Baltimore, Maryland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Muscle Nerve</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7803146</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0148-639X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001066" MajorTopicYN="N">Appetite</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011795" MajorTopicYN="N">Surveys and Questionnaires</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009752" MajorTopicYN="N">Nutritional Status</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">appetite alteration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">motor neuron disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neurodegenerative diseases</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neuromuscular diseases</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">quality of life</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35986916</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.27694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Ludolph AC, Dorst J, Dreyhaupt J, et al. Effect of high-caloric nutrition on survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol. 2020;87:206-216.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moglia C, Calvo A, Grassano M, et al. Early weight loss in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: outcome relevance and clinical correlates in a population-based cohort. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2019;90:666-673.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holm T, Maier A, Wicks P, et al. Severe loss of appetite in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients: online self-assessment study. Interact J Med Res. 2013;2:e8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagaoka U, Shimizu T, Uchihara T, Komori T, Hosoda H, Takahashi K. Decreased plasma ghrelin in male ALS patients is associated with poor prognosis. Neurosci Res. 2022;177:111-117.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Ye S, Chen L, Tang L, Fan D. Loss of appetite in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis is associated with weight loss and anxiety/depression. Sci Rep. 2021;11:9119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ngo ST, Wang H, Henderson RD, et al. Ghrelin as a treatment for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neuroendocrinol. 2021;33:e12938.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorges M, Vercruysse P, M&#xfc;ller H-P, et al. Hypothalamic atrophy is related to body mass index and age at onset in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2017;88:1033-1041.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wills A-M, Hubbard J, Macklin EA, et al. Hypercaloric enteral nutrition in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled phase 2 trial. Lancet. 2014;383:2065-2072.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mezoian T, Belt E, Garry J, et al. Loss of appetite in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis is associated with weight loss and decreased calorie consumption independent of dysphagia. Muscle Nerve. 2020;61:230-234.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Landi F, Calvani R, Tosato M, et al. Anorexia of aging: risk factors, consequences, and potential treatments. Nutrients. 2016;8:69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barajas Galindo DE, Vidal-Casariego A, Calleja-Fern&#xe1;ndez A, et al. Appetite disorders in cancer patients: impact on nutritional status and quality of life. Appetite. 2017;114:23-27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zabel R, Ash S, King N, Juffs P, Bauer J. Relationships between appetite and quality of life in hemodialysis patients. Appetite. 2012;59:194-199.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cox NJ, Morrison L, Robinson SM, Roberts HC, Ibrahim K. Older individual's perceptions of appetite, its loss, influencing factors and adaptions to poor appetite. A qualitative study. Appetite. 2021;167:105609.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bossola M, Ciciarelli C, Di Stasio E, et al. Relationship between appetite and symptoms of depression and anxiety in patients on chronic hemodialysis. J Ren Nutr. 2012;22:27-33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carrero JJ. Identification of patients with eating disorders: clinical and biochemical signs of appetite loss in dialysis patients. J Ren Nutr. 2009;19:10-15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Labarthe A, Fiquet O, Hassouna R, et al. Ghrelin-derived peptides: a link between appetite/reward, GH axis, and psychiatric disorders? Front Endocrinol. 2014;5:163.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arksey H, O'Malley L. Scoping studies: towards a methodological framework. Int J Soc Res Methodol. 2005;8:19-32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tricco AC, Lillie E, Zarin W, et al. PRISMA extension for scoping reviews (PRISMA-ScR): checklist and explanation. Ann Intern Med. 2018;169:467-473.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weber M, Goldman B, Truniger S. Tetrahydrocannabinol (THC) for cramps in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a randomised, double-blind crossover trial. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2010;81:1135-1140.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei Q, Chen X, Cao B, et al. Associations between neuropsychiatric symptoms and cognition in Chinese patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Front Degener. 2016;17:358-365.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ngo ST, Van Eijk RPA, Chachay V, et al. Loss of appetite is associated with a loss of weight and fat mass in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Front Degener. 2019;20:497-505.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anca M, Sebastian A, Cristina R, et al. Predictors of depression in Caucasian patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in Romania. Brain Sci. 2020;10:470.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coates E, Zarotti N, Williams I, et al. Patient, carer and healthcare professional perspectives on increasing calorie intake in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Chronic Illn. 2021. doi:10.1177/17423953211069090.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juliao M, Sobral MA, Calcada P, et al. &#x201c;Truly holistic?&#x201d; differences in documenting physical and psychosocial needs and hope in Portuguese palliative patients. Palliat Support Care. 2021;19:69-74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dorst J, Doenz J, Kandler K, et al. Fat-rich versus carbohydrate-rich nutrition in ALS: a randomised controlled study. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2022;93:298-302. doi:10.1136/jnnp-2021-328331.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janse van Mantgem MR, van Eijk RPA, van der Burgh HK, et al. Prognostic value of weight loss in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a population-based study. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2020;91:867-875.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steyn FJ, Ngo ST. Prognostic value of weight loss in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2020;91:813.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xf6;rner S, Hendricks M, Kollewe K, et al. Weight loss, dysphagia and supplement intake in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS): impact on quality of life and therapeutic options. BMC Neurol. 2013;13:84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>V&#xe1;zquez Medrano CR, Aho-&#xd6;zhan HEA, Weiland U, Uttner I, Ludolph AC, Lul&#xe9; D. Disease progression but not physical state per se determines mental wellbeing in ALS. J Neurol. 2020;267:3593-3601.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Doherty LJ, Hickey A, Hardiman O. Measuring life quality, physical function and psychological well-being in neurological illness. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2010;11:461-468.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson M-MG, Thomas DR, Rubenstein LZ, et al. Appetite assessment: simple appetite questionnaire predicts weight loss in community-dwelling adults and nursing home residents. Am J Clin Nutr. 2005;82:1074-1081.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribaudo JM, Cella D, Hahn EA, et al. Re-validation and shortening of the Functional Assessment of Anorexia/Cachexia Therapy (FAACT) questionnaire. Qual Life Res. 2000;9:1137-1146.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>