<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36002963</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>26</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2213-1582</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>35</Volume><PubDate><Year>2022</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>NeuroImage. Clinical</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Neuroimage Clin</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Pallidal functional connectivity changes are associated with disgust recognition in pure motor amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>103145</StartPage><MedlinePgn>103145</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">103145</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.nicl.2022.103145</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S2213-1582(22)00210-8</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>In the present study, we aimed to investigate the resting-state functional connectivity (RS-FC) of the globus pallidus (GP) in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) compared to healthy controls, and the relationship between RS-FC changes and disgust recognition. Twenty-six pure-motor ALS patients and 52 healthy controls underwent RS functional MRI and a neuropsychological assessment including the Comprehensive Affect Testing System. A seed-based RS-FC analysis was performed between the left and right GP and the rest of the brain and compared between groups. Correlations between RS-FC significant changes and subjects' performance in recognizing disgust were tested. Compared to controls, patients were significantly less able to recognize disgust. In ALS compared to controls, the seed-based analysis showed: reduced RS-FC between bilateral GP and bilateral middle and superior frontal and middle cingulate gyri, and increased RS-FC between bilateral GP and bilateral postcentral, supramarginal and superior temporal gyri and Rolandic operculum. Decreased RS-FC was further observed between left GP and left middle and inferior temporal gyri and bilateral caudate; and increased RS-FC was also shown between right GP and left lingual and fusiform gyri. In patients and controls, lower performance in recognizing disgust correlated with reduced RS-FC between left GP and left middle and inferior temporal gyri. In pure-motor ALS patients, we demonstrated altered RS-FC between GP and the rest of the brain. The reduced left pallidum-temporo-striatal RS-FC may have a role in the lower ability of patients in recognizing disgust.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022 The Authors. Published by Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Castelnovo</LastName><ForeName>Veronica</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neuroimaging Research Unit, Division of Neuroscience, IRCCS San Raffaele Scientific Institute, Milan, Italy; Vita-Salute San Raffaele University, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Canu</LastName><ForeName>Elisa</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neuroimaging Research Unit, Division of Neuroscience, IRCCS San Raffaele Scientific Institute, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Magno</LastName><ForeName>Maria Antonietta</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neuroimaging Research Unit, Division of Neuroscience, IRCCS San Raffaele Scientific Institute, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gatti</LastName><ForeName>Elena</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neuroimaging Research Unit, Division of Neuroscience, IRCCS San Raffaele Scientific Institute, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Riva</LastName><ForeName>Nilo</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurology Unit, IRCCS San Raffaele Scientific Institute, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pain</LastName><ForeName>Debora</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurorehabilitation, ICS Maugeri IRCCS, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mora</LastName><ForeName>Gabriele</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurorehabilitation, ICS Maugeri IRCCS, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Poletti</LastName><ForeName>Barbara</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology and Laboratory of Neuroscience, IRCCS Istituto Auxologico Italiano, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Silani</LastName><ForeName>Vincenzo</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology and Laboratory of Neuroscience, IRCCS Istituto Auxologico Italiano, Milan, Italy; Department of Pathophysiology and Transplantation, "Dino Ferrari" Center, Universit&#xe0; degli Studi di Milano, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Filippi</LastName><ForeName>Massimo</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neuroimaging Research Unit, Division of Neuroscience, IRCCS San Raffaele Scientific Institute, Milan, Italy; Neurology Unit, IRCCS San Raffaele Scientific Institute, Milan, Italy; Neurorehabilitation Unit, IRCCS San Raffaele Scientific Institute, Milan, Italy; Neurophysiology Service, IRCCS San Raffaele Scientific Institute, Milan, Italy; Vita-Salute San Raffaele University, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Agosta</LastName><ForeName>Federica</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neuroimaging Research Unit, Division of Neuroscience, IRCCS San Raffaele Scientific Institute, Milan, Italy; Neurology Unit, IRCCS San Raffaele Scientific Institute, Milan, Italy; Vita-Salute San Raffaele University, Milan, Italy. Electronic address: agosta.federica@hsr.it.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Neuroimage Clin</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101597070</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2213-1582</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001921" MajorTopicYN="N">Brain</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001931" MajorTopicYN="N">Brain Mapping</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000078382" MajorTopicYN="Y">Disgust</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005917" MajorTopicYN="N">Globus Pallidus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008279" MajorTopicYN="N">Magnetic Resonance Imaging</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Disgust</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Functional connectivity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pallidum</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Resting-state fMRI</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare the following financial interests/personal relationships which may be considered as potential competing interests: V. Castelnovo, M.A. Magno, S. Basaia, N. Riva, D. Pain, G. Mora, B. Poletti report no disclosures. E. Canu has received research supports from the Italian Ministry of Health. V. Silani received compensation for consulting services and/or speaking activities from AveXis, Cytokinetics and Italfarmaco; and receives or has received research supports form the Italian Ministry of Health, AriSLA (Fondazione Italiana di Ricerca per la SLA), and E- Rare Joint Transnational Call. M. Filippi is Editor-in-Chief of the <i>Journal of Neurology</i> and Associate Editor of <i>Human Brain Mapping</i>; received compensation for consulting services and/or speaking activities from Almiral, Alexion, Bayer, Biogen, Celgene, Eli Lilly, Genzyme, Merck- Serono, Novartis, Roche, Sanofi, Takeda, and Teva Pharmaceutical Industries; and receives research support from Biogen Idec, Merck-Serono, Novartis, Roche, Teva Pharmaceutical Industries, Italian Ministry of Health, Fondazione Italiana Sclerosi Multipla, and ARiSLA (Fondazione Italiana di Ricerca per la SLA). F. Agosta is Section Editor of <i>NeuroImage: Clinical</i>; received compensation for consulting services and/or speaking activities from Biogen Idec, Roche and Zambon; and receives or has received research supports from the Italian Ministry of Health, AriSLA (Fondazione Italiana di Ricerca per la SLA), Foundation Research on Alzheimer Disease and the European Research Council.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36002963</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9421543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nicl.2022.103145</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2213-1582(22)00210-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Agosta F., Spinelli E.G., Filippi M. Neuroimaging in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: current and emerging uses. Expert Rev. Neurother. 2018;18:395&#x2013;406.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29630421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aho-Ozhan H.E., Keller J., Heimrath J., Uttner I., Kassubek J., Birbaumer N., Ludolph A.C., Lule D. Perception of Emotional Facial Expressions in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis (ALS) at Behavioural and Brain Metabolic Level. PLoS ONE. 2016;11:e0164655.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5065224</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27741285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrews S.C., Staios M., Howe J., Reardon K., Fisher F. Multimodal emotion processing deficits are present in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuropsychology. 2017;31:304&#x2013;310.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28054821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basaia S., Agosta F., Cividini C., Trojsi F., Riva N., Spinelli E.G., Moglia C., Femiano C., Castelnovo V., Canu E., Falzone Y., Monsurro M.R., Falini A., Chio A., Tedeschi G., Filippi M. Structural and functional brain connectome in motor neuron diseases: A multicenter MRI study. Neurology. 2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7682834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32913015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benbrika S., Desgranges B., Eustache F., Viader F. Cognitive, Emotional and Psychological Manifestations in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis at Baseline and Overtime: A Review. Front. Neurosci. 2019;13:951.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6746914</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31551700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bora E. Meta-analysis of social cognition in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Cortex. 2017;88:1&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28002755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brettschneider J., Del Tredici K., Toledo J.B., Robinson J.L., Irwin D.J., Grossman M., Suh E., Van Deerlin V.M., Wood E.M., Baek Y., Kwong L., Lee E.B., Elman L., McCluskey L., Fang L., Feldengut S., Ludolph A.C., Lee V.M., Braak H., Trojanowski J.Q. Stages of pTDP-43 pathology in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann. Neurol. 2013;74:20&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3785076</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23686809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks, B.R., Miller, R.G., Swash, M., Munsat, T.L., World Federation of Neurology Research Group on Motor Neuron, D., 2000. El Escorial revisited: revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord 1, 293-299.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11464847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caga J., Hsieh S., Lillo P., Dudley K., Mioshi E. The Impact of Cognitive and Behavioral Symptoms on ALS Patients and Their Caregivers. Front. Neurol. 2019;10:192.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6421295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30915018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calder A.J., Keane J., Manes F., Antoun N., Young A.W. Impaired recognition and experience of disgust following brain injury. Nat. Neurosci. 2000;3:1077&#x2013;1078.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11036262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calder A.J., Beaver J.D., Davis M.H., van Ditzhuijzen J., Keane J., Lawrence A.D. Disgust sensitivity predicts the insula and pallidal response to pictures of disgusting foods. Eur. J. Neurosci. 2007;25:3422&#x2013;3428.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17553011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canu, E., Agosta, F., Tomic, A., Sarasso, E., Petrovic, I., Piramide, N., Svetel, M., Inuggi, A., N, D.M., Kostic, V.S., Filippi, M., 2020. Breakdown of the affective-cognitive network in functional dystonia. Hum Brain Mapp 41, 3059-3076.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7336141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32243055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castelnovo V., Canu E., Calderaro D., Riva N., Poletti B., Basaia S., Solca F., Silani V., Filippi M., Agosta F. Progression of brain functional connectivity and frontal cognitive dysfunction in ALS. Neuroimage Clin. 2020;28</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7708866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33395998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castelnovo V., Canu E., Magno M.A., Basaia S., Riva N., Poletti B., Silani V., Filippi M., Agosta F. Impaired recognition of disgust in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis is related to basal ganglia involvement. Neuroimage Clin. 2021;32</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8478135</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34537684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castelnovo V., Canu E., Riva N., Poletti B., Cividini C., Fontana A., Solca F., Silani V., Filippi M., Agosta F. Progression of cognitive and behavioral disturbances in motor neuron diseases assessed using standard and computer-based batteries. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2021:1&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33463386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum J.M., Stambler N., Malta E., Fuller C., Hilt D., Thurmond B., Nakanishi A. The ALSFRS-R: a revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. BDNF ALS Study Group (Phase III) J. Neurol. Sci. 1999;169:13&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10540002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cerami C., Dodich A., Canessa N., Crespi C., Iannaccone S., Corbo M., Lunetta C., Consonni M., Scola E., Falini A., Cappa S.F. Emotional empathy in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a behavioural and voxel-based morphometry study. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2014;15:21&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23586919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crespi C., Cerami C., Dodich A., Canessa N., Arpone M., Iannaccone S., Corbo M., Lunetta C., Scola E., Falini A., Cappa S.F. Microstructural white matter correlates of emotion recognition impairment in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. Cortex. 2014;53:1&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24534360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crespi C., Cerami C., Dodich A., Canessa N., Iannaccone S., Corbo M., Lunetta C., Falini A., Cappa S.F. Microstructural Correlates of Emotional Attribution Impairment in Non-Demented Patients with Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. PLoS ONE. 2016;11:e0161034.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4981464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27513746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dodich A., Cerami C., Canessa N., Crespi C., Marcone A., Arpone M., Realmuto S., Cappa S.F. Emotion recognition from facial expressions: a normative study of the Ekman 60-Faces Test in the Italian population. Neurol. Sci. 2014;35:1015&#x2013;1021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24442557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Douaud G., Filippini N., Knight S., Talbot K., Turner M.R. Integration of structural and functional magnetic resonance imaging in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain. 2011;134:3470&#x2013;3479.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22075069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekman P., F.w., Consulting Psychologists Press; Palo Alto: 1976. Pictures of facial affect.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Froming K., Levy M., Schaffer S., Ekman P. Psychology Software Inc.; 2006. The Comprehensive Affect Testing System.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fusar-Poli P., Placentino A., Carletti F., Landi P., Allen P., Surguladze S., Benedetti F., Abbamonte M., Gasparotti R., Barale F., Perez J., McGuire P., Politi P. Functional atlas of emotional faces processing: a voxel-based meta-analysis of 105 functional magnetic resonance imaging studies. J. Psychiatry Neurosci. 2009;34:418&#x2013;432.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2783433</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19949718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Girardi A., MacPherson S.E., Abrahams S. Deficits in emotional and social cognition in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuropsychology. 2011;25:53&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20919762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo C.C., Sturm V.E., Zhou J., Gennatas E.D., Trujillo A.J., Hua A.Y., Crawford R., Stables L., Kramer J.H., Rankin K., Levenson R.W., Rosen H.J., Miller B.L., Seeley W.W. Dominant hemisphere lateralization of cortical parasympathetic control as revealed by frontotemporal dementia. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 2016;113:E2430&#x2013;E2439.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4855566</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27071080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamilton M. A rating scale for depression. J. Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatry. 1960;23:56&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC495331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14399272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho C.Y., Berridge K.C. Excessive disgust caused by brain lesions or temporary inactivations: mapping hotspots of the nucleus accumbens and ventral pallidum. Eur. J. Neurosci. 2014;40:3556&#x2013;3572.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4236281</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25229197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holtmann O., Bruchmann M., Monig C., Schwindt W., Melzer N., Miltner W.H.R., Straube T. Lateralized Deficits of Disgust Processing After Insula-Basal Ganglia Damage. Front. Psychol. 2020;11:1429.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7347022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32714249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin Y.H., Young I.M., Conner A.K., Glenn C.A., Chakraborty A.R., Nix C.E., Bai M.Y., Dhanaraj V., Fonseka R.D., Hormovas J., Tanglay O., Briggs R.G., Sughrue M.E. Anatomy and White Matter Connections of the Inferior Temporal Gyrus. World Neurosurg. 2020;143:e656&#x2013;e666.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32798785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lule D., Kurt A., Jurgens R., Kassubek J., Diekmann V., Kraft E., Neumann N., Ludolph A.C., Birbaumer N., Anders S. Emotional responding in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J. Neurol. 2005;252:1517&#x2013;1524.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15977000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lule D., Diekmann V., Anders S., Kassubek J., Kubler A., Ludolph A.C., Birbaumer N. Brain responses to emotional stimuli in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) J. Neurol. 2007;254:519&#x2013;527.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17401515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martins A.P., Prado L.G.R., Lillo P., Mioshi E., Teixeira A.L., de Souza L.C. Deficits in Emotion Recognition as Markers of Frontal Behavioral Dysfunction in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. J. Neuropsychiatry Clin. Neurosci. 2019;31:165&#x2013;169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30537912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKenna M.C., Corcia P., Couratier P., Siah W.F., Pradat P.F., Bede P. Frontotemporal Pathology in Motor Neuron Disease Phenotypes: Insights From Neuroimaging. Front. Neurol. 2021;12</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8415268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34484106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh S.I., Oh K.W., Kim H.J., Park J.S., Kim S.H. Impaired Perception of Emotional Expression in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. J Clin Neurol. 2016;12:295&#x2013;300.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4960213</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27095526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palumbo F., Iazzolino B., Peotta L., Canosa A., Manera U., Grassano M., Casale F., Pellegrino G., Rizzone M.G., Vasta R., Moglia C., Chio A., Calvo A. Social cognition deficits in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A pilot cross-sectional population-based study. Eur. J. Neurol. 2022;29:2211&#x2013;2219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35524505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pessoa L. A network model of the emotional brain. Trends Cogn. Sci. 2017;21:357&#x2013;371.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5534266</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28363681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips M.L., Young A.W., Scott S.K., Calder A.J., Andrew C., Giampietro V., Williams S.C., Bullmore E.T., Brammer M., Gray J.A. Neural responses to facial and vocal expressions of fear and disgust. Proc. Biol. Sci. 1998;265:1809&#x2013;1817.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1689379</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9802236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pruim R.H.R., Mennes M., van Rooij D., Llera A., Buitelaar J.K., Beckmann C.F. ICA-AROMA: A robust ICA-based strategy for removing motion artifacts from fMRI data. Neuroimage. 2015;112:267&#x2013;277.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25770991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Royet J.P., Plailly J., Delon-Martin C., Kareken D.A., Segebarth C. fMRI of emotional responses to odors: influence of hedonic valence and judgment, handedness, and gender. Neuroimage. 2003;20:713&#x2013;728.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14568446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Savage S.A., Lillo P., Kumfor F., Kiernan M.C., Piguet O., Hodges J.R. Emotion processing deficits distinguish pure amyotrophic lateral sclerosis from frontotemporal dementia. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2014;15:39&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23889548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh-Bains M.K., Waldvogel H.J., Faull R.L. The role of the human globus pallidus in Huntington's disease. Brain Pathol. 2016;26:741&#x2013;751.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8029019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27529459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Small D.M., Gregory M.D., Mak Y.E., Gitelman D., Mesulam M.M., Parrish T. Dissociation of neural representation of intensity and affective valuation in human gustation. Neuron. 2003;39:701&#x2013;711.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12925283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith S.M., Fox P.T., Miller K.L., Glahn D.C., Fox P.M., Mackay C.E., Filippini N., Watkins K.E., Toro R., Laird A.R., Beckmann C.F. Correspondence of the brain's functional architecture during activation and rest. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 2009;106:13040&#x2013;13045.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2722273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19620724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sprengelmeyer R., Rausch M., Eysel U.T., Przuntek H. Neural structures associated with recognition of facial expressions of basic emotions. Proc. Biol. Sci. 1998;265:1927&#x2013;1931.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1689486</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9821359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strong M.J., Abrahams S., Goldstein L.H., Woolley S., McLaughlin P., Snowden J., Mioshi E., Roberts-South A., Benatar M., HortobaGyi T., Rosenfeld J., Silani V., Ince P.G., Turner M.R. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis - frontotemporal spectrum disorder (ALS-FTSD): Revised diagnostic criteria. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2017;18:153&#x2013;174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7409990</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28054827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trojsi F., Di Nardo F., Santangelo G., Siciliano M., Femiano C., Passaniti C., Caiazzo G., Fratello M., Cirillo M., Monsurro M.R., Esposito F., Tedeschi G. Resting state fMRI correlates of Theory of Mind impairment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Cortex. 2017;97:1&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29073458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wicker B., Keysers C., Plailly J., Royet J.P., Gallese V., Rizzolatti G. Both of us disgusted in My insula: the common neural basis of seeing and feeling disgust. Neuron. 2003;40:655&#x2013;664.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14642287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu J., Lyu H., Li T., Xu Z., Fu X., Jia F., Wang J., Hu Q. Delineating functional segregations of the human middle temporal gyrus with resting-state functional connectivity and coactivation patterns. Hum. Brain Mapp. 2019;40:5159&#x2013;5171.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6865466</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31423713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshimura N., Kawamura M., Masaoka Y., Homma I. The amygdala of patients with Parkinson's disease is silent in response to fearful facial expressions. Neuroscience. 2005;131:523&#x2013;534.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15708493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zimmerman E.K., Eslinger P.J., Simmons Z., Barrett A.M. Emotional perception deficits in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Cogn. Behav. Neurol. 2007;20:79&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1905862</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17558250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>