<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36003035</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>03</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1440-1789</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>43</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Neuropathology : official journal of the Japanese Society of Neuropathology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Neuropathology</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with TDP-43 abnormalities exhibiting globular glial tau inclusions in frontotemporal lobes and pallido-nigral system.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>117</StartPage><EndPage>126</EndPage><MedlinePgn>117-126</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/neup.12862</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Here we present the autopsy case of an 80-year-old woman with a 9-year history of motor neuron disease and atypical Parkinsonism. Her initial symptom was gait disturbance, and she subsequently developed limb weakness and Parkinsonism without response to levodopa. Her motor symptoms progressed to bulbar palsy, and she died of respiratory failure. Postmortem examination revealed characteristic findings of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS), including motor neuronal loss with astrogliosis, corticospinal tract degeneration, and TAR DNA-binding protein of 43&#x2009;kDa abnormalities, including nuclear loss and skein-like inclusions. In contrast, severe tau pathological changes were seen in the frontotemporal lobes and pallido-nigral system. Tau pathologies affected not only neuronal components, such as neurofibrillary tangles and neuropil threads, but also glial cells (astrocytes and oligodendrocytes). Some glial tau pathologies exhibited peculiar round accumulations, reminiscent of globular glial inclusions (GGIs) in globular glial tauopathy. This unique autopsy case demonstrates that ALS with TDP-43 could be comorbid with globular glial tau inclusions and indicates that common pathological mechanisms exist among ALS and GGI formation.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022 Japanese Society of Neuropathology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yagita</LastName><ForeName>Kaoru</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuropathology, Graduate School of Medical Sciences, Kyushu University, Fukuoka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sasagasako</LastName><ForeName>Naokazu</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Neuro-Muscular Center, National Omuta Hospital, Omuta, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Koyama</LastName><ForeName>Sachiko</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuropathology, Graduate School of Medical Sciences, Kyushu University, Fukuoka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Noguchi</LastName><ForeName>Hideko</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuropathology, Graduate School of Medical Sciences, Kyushu University, Fukuoka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Honda</LastName><ForeName>Hiroyuki</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4225-7248</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuropathology, Graduate School of Medical Sciences, Kyushu University, Fukuoka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Australia</Country><MedlineTA>Neuropathology</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9606526</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0919-6544</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D004268">DNA-Binding Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009457" MajorTopicYN="N">Neuroglia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009474" MajorTopicYN="N">Neurons</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020734" MajorTopicYN="Y">Parkinsonian Disorders</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004268" MajorTopicYN="N">DNA-Binding Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ELAVL3</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">TDP-43</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tauopathy</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36003035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/neup.12862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Neumann M, Sampathu DM, Kwong LK et al. Ubiquitinated TDP-43 in frontotemporal lobar degeneration and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Science 2006; 314: 130-133.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arai T, Hasegawa M, Akiyama H et al. TDP-43 is a component of ubiquitin-positive tau-negative inclusions in frontotemporal lobar degeneration and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Biochem Biophys Res Commun 2006; 351: 602-611.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vance C, Rogelj B, Hortob&#xe1;gyi T et al. Mutations in FUS, an RNA processing protein, cause familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis type 6. Science 2009; 323: 1208-1211.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chattopadhyay M, Valentine JS. Aggregation of copper-zinc superoxide dismutase in familial and sporadic ALS. Antioxid Redox Signal 2009; 11: 1603-1614.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oyanagi K, Tsuchiya K, Yamazaki M et al. Substantia Nigra in progressive Supranuclear palsy, Corticobasal degeneration, and parkinsonism-dementia complex of Guam: Specific pathological features. J Neuropathol Exp Neurol 2001; 60: 393-402.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuzuhara S, Kokubo Y, Sasaki R et al. Familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and parkinsonism-dementia complex of the Kii peninsula of Japan: Clinical and neuropathological study and tau analysis. Ann Neurol 2001; 49: 501-511.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Josephs KA, Katsuse O, Beccano-Kelly DA et al. Atypical progressive supranuclear palsy with corticospinal tract degeneration. J Neuropathol Exp Neurol 2006; 65: 396-405.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu YJ, Nishihira Y, Kuroda S et al. Sporadic four-repeat tauopathy with frontotemporal lobar degeneration, parkinsonism, and motor neuron disease: A distinct clinicopathological and biochemical disease entity. Acta Neuropathol 2010; 120: 21-32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed Z, Bigio EH, Budka H et al. Globular glial tauopathies (GGT): Consensus recommendations. Acta Neuropathol 2013; 126: 537-544.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shibata N, Nagai R, Uchida K et al. Morphological evidence for lipid peroxidation and protein glycoxidation in spinal cords from sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. Brain Res 2001; 917: 97-104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carr&#xec; MT, D'Ambrosi N, Cozzolino M. Pathways to mitochondrial dysfunction in ALS pathogenesis. Biochem Biophys Res Commun 2017; 483: 1187-1193.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujita Y, Mizuno Y, Takatama M et al. Anterior horn cells with abnormal TDP-43 immunoreactivities show fragmentation of the Golgi apparatus in ALS. J Neurol Sci 2008; 269: 30-34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strong MJ. The evidence for altered RNA metabolism in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). J Neurol Sci 2010; 288: 1-12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bampton A, Gittings LM, Fratta P et al. The role of hnRNPs in frontotemporal dementia and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathol 2020; 140: 599-623.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim G, Gautier O, Tassoni-Tsuchida E et al. ALS genetics: Gains, losses, and implications for future therapies. Neuron 2020; 108: 822-842.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diaz-Garcia S, Ko VI, Vazquez-Sanchez S et al. Nuclear depletion of RNA-binding protein ELAVL3 (HuC) in sporadic and familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathol 2021; 142: 985-1001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu J, Chen F, Iqbal K et al. Transactive response DNA-binding protein 43 (TDP-43) regulates alternative splicing of tau exon 10: Implications for the pathogenesis of tauopathies. J Biol Chem 2017; 292: 10600-10612.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishigaki S, Fujioka Y, Okada Y, Riku Y et al. Altered tau isoform ratio caused by loss of FUS and SFPQ function leads to FTLD-like phenotypes. Cell Rep 2017; 18: 1118-1131.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishigaki S, Riku Y, Fujioka Y et al. Aberrant interaction between FUS and SFPQ in neurons in a wide range of FTLD spectrum diseases. Brain 2020; 143: 2398-2405.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moszczynski AJ, Yang W, Hammond R et al. Threonine175, a novel pathological phosphorylation site on tau protein linked to multiple tauopathies. J Intensive Care 2017; 5: 1-14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strong MJ, Yang W, Strong WL et al. Tau protein hyperphosphorylation in sporadic ALS with cognitive impairment. Neurology 2006; 66: 1770-1771.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanaka H, Toyoshima Y, Kawakatsu S et al. Morphological characterisation of glial and neuronal tau pathology in globular glial tauopathy (types II and III). Neuropathol Appl Neurobiol 2020; 46: 344-358.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yokota O, Tsuchiya K, Oda T et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with dementia: An autopsy case showing many Bunina bodies, tau-positive neuronal and astrocytic plaque-like pathologies, and pallido-nigral degeneration. Acta Neuropathol 2006; 112: 633-645.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takeuchi R, Toyoshima Y, Tada M et al. Globular glial mixed four repeat tau and TDP-43 Proteinopathy with motor neuron disease and frontotemporal dementia. Brain Pathol 2016; 26: 82-94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behrouzi R, Liu X, Wu D et al. Pathological tau deposition in motor Neurone disease and frontotemporal lobar degeneration associated with TDP-43 proteinopathy. Acta Neuropathol Commun 2016; 4: 33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang W, Leystra-Lantz C, Strong MJ. Upregulation of GSK3&#x3b2; expression in frontal and temporal cortex in ALS with cognitive impairment (ALSci). Brain Res 2008; 1196: 131-139.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Honda H, Hamasaki H, Wakamiya T et al. Loss of hnRNPA1 in ALS spinal cord motor neurons with TDP-43-positive inclusions. Neuropathology 2015; 35: 37-43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davidson YS, Flood L, Robinson AC et al. Heterogeneous ribonuclear protein A3 (hnRNP A3) is present in dipeptide repeat protein containing inclusions in frontotemporal lobar degeneration and motor Neurone disease associated with expansions in C9orf72 gene. Acta Neuropathol Commun 2017; 5: 31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bampton A, Gatt A, Humphrey J et al. HnRNP K mislocalisation is a novel protein pathology of frontotemporal lobar degeneration and ageing and leads to cryptic splicing. Acta Neuropathol 2021; 142: 609-627.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi Y, Zhang W, Yang Y et al. Structure-based classification of tauopathies. Nature 2021; 598: 359-363.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung DEC, Carlomagno Y, Cook CN et al. Tau exhibits unique seeding properties in globular glial tauopathy. Acta Neuropathol Commun 2019; 7: 36.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>