<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">36054038</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>24</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-4598</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>66</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Muscle &amp; nerve</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Muscle Nerve</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Associations between urate levels and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis functional score with edaravone treatment: Post hoc analysis of studies MCI186-16, MCI186-17, and MCI186-19.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>583</StartPage><EndPage>592</EndPage><MedlinePgn>583-592</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/mus.27699</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION/AIMS">Edaravone in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) was analyzed in two phase 3 studies (MCI186-16 and MCI186-19). Those trials enrolled patients with Japanese ALS severity grades 1 and 2 (less severe ALS), but many patients progressed to grades 3 and 4 during the double-blind treatment period. The placebo patients who initiated edaravone treatment in the open-label periods provided an opportunity to assess the effects of edaravone in more severe ALS. This study also assessed the association between ALS Functional Rating Scale-Revised (ALSFRS-R) slope and biomarker changes after open-label edaravone initiation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Change in ALSFRS-R slope in placebo patients before and after initiating edaravone treatment was assessed using the random coefficient model. The association of ALSFRS-R change and blood marker changes was explored by the least absolute shrinkage and selection operator (LASSO) method of machine learning.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Twenty-four percent of patients (35/146) in the placebo-edaravone group showed &#x2265;25% slowing of decline in the ALSFRS-R slope. Within the 25% slower-decline group, 60% (21/35) had Japanese ALS severity grades 3 or 4 at the start of edaravone treatment. The LASSO model identified serum urate as associated with the percentage change in ALSFRS-R slope. The rate of decrease in urate was smaller in the 25% slower-decline group than in the non-25% slower-decline group during edaravone treatment.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION">This post hoc analysis indicated that ALS patients, including those with advanced ALS severity grades, may receive benefit in the group of patients whose urate levels are stable during the course of the edaravone treatment.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Takahashi</LastName><ForeName>Fumihiro</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5701-5332</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mitsubishi Tanabe Pharma Corporation, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kano</LastName><ForeName>Osamu</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Toho University Faculty of Medicine, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nagano</LastName><ForeName>Yoshito</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mitsubishi Tanabe Pharma Corporation, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yoneoka</LastName><ForeName>Takatomo</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mitsubishi Tanabe Pharma Corporation, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nelson</LastName><ForeName>Sally</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mitsubishi Tanabe Pharma America, Jersey City, New Jersey, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ushirogawa</LastName><ForeName>Yoshiteru</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mitsubishi Tanabe Pharma Corporation, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Muscle Nerve</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7803146</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0148-639X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>S798V6YJRP</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000077553">Edaravone</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D016166">Free Radical Scavengers</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>268B43MJ25</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D014527">Uric Acid</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018450" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Progression</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000077553" MajorTopicYN="Y">Edaravone</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016166" MajorTopicYN="N">Free Radical Scavengers</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014527" MajorTopicYN="Y">Uric Acid</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004311" MajorTopicYN="N">Double-Blind Method</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017326" MajorTopicYN="N">Clinical Trials, Phase III as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ALS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ALSFRS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ALSFRS-R slope</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">LASSO</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">biomarker</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">motor neuron disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">oxidative stress</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36054038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.27699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Abe K, Itoyama Y, Sobue G, et al. Confirmatory double-blind, parallel-group, placebo-controlled study of efficacy and safety of edaravone (MCI-186) in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2014;15(7-8):610-617.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Writing Group on Behalf of the Edaravone ALS 17 Study Group. Exploratory double-blind, parallel-group, placebo-controlled extension study of edaravone (MCI-186) in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2017;18(suppl 1):20-31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edaravone (MCI-186) ALS 16 Study Group. A post-hoc subgroup analysis of outcomes in the first phase III clinical study of edaravone (MCI-186) in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2017;18(suppl 1):11-19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palumbo JM, Hubble J, Apple S, et al. Post-hoc analyses of the edaravone clinical trials study 16 and study 19: a step toward more efficient clinical trial designs in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2019;20(5-6):421-431.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Writing Group; Edaravone (MCI-186) ALS 19 Study Group. Safety and efficacy of edaravone in well defined patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Lancet Neurol. 2017;16(7):505-512.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ilzecka J, Stelmasiak Z. Serum bilirubin concentration in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Neurol Neurosurg. 2003;105(4):237-240.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kano O, Tanaka K, Kanno T, Iwasaki Y, Ikeda JE. Neuronal apoptosis inhibitory protein is implicated in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis symptoms. Sci Rep. 2018;8(1):6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lunetta C, Lizio A, Maestri E, et al. Serum C-reactive protein as a prognostic biomarker in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. JAMA Neurol. 2017;74(6):660-667.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagel G, Peter RS, Rosenbohm A, et al. Adipokines, C-reactive protein and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis - results from a population- based ALS registry in Germany. Sci Rep. 2017;7(1):4374.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun J, Carrero JJ, Zagai U, et al. Blood biomarkers and prognosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Eur J Neurol. 2020;27(11):2125-2133.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Figlewicz DA, Krizus A, Martinoli MG, et al. Variants of the heavy neurofilament subunit are associated with the development of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Hum Mol Genet. 1994;3(10):1757-1761.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ikeda K, Hirayama T, Takazawa T, Kawabe K, Iwasaki Y. Relationships between disease progression and serum levels of lipid, urate, creatinine and ferritin in Japanese patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a cross-sectional study. Intern Med. 2012;51(12):1501-1508.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chio A, Calvo A, Bovio G, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis outcome measures and the role of albumin and creatinine: a population-based study. JAMA Neurol. 2014;71(9):1134-1142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo QF, Hu W, Xu LQ, Luo H, Wang N, Zhang QJ. Decreased serum creatinine levels predict short survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Clin Transl Neurol. 2021;8(2):448-455.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitsumoto H, Garofalo DC, Santella RM, et al. Plasma creatinine and oxidative stress biomarkers in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2020;21(3-4):263-272.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) (designated intractable disease 2). Japan intractable disease information center. https://www.nanbyou.or.jp/wp-content/uploads/upload_files/File/002-201704-kijyun.pdf (Japanese). Accessed July 21, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Writing Group on Behalf of the Edaravone ALS 19 Study Group. Open-label 24-week extension study of edaravone (MCI-186) in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2017;18(suppl 1):55-63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, Miller RG, Swash M, Munsat TL, World Federation of Neurology Research Group on Motor Neuron D. El escorial revisited: revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord. 2000;1(5):293-299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castrillo-Viguera C, Grasso DL, Simpson E, Shefner J, Cudkowicz ME. Clinical significance in the change of decline in ALSFRS-R. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2010;11(1-2):178-180.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han HJ, Shin HY, Choi YC, Kim SM, Kim SW. Serum uric acid level predicts the progression of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis following treatment with edaravone. Redox Rep. 2022;27(1):79-84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Writing Group on Behalf of the Edaravone ALS 18 Study Group. Exploratory double-blind, parallel-group, placebo-controlled study of edaravone (MCI-186) in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (Japan ALS severity classification: grade 3, requiring assistance for eating, excretion or ambulation). Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2017;18(suppl 1):40-48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zoccolella S, Simone IL, Capozzo R, et al. An exploratory study of serum urate levels in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol. 2011;258(2):238-243.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abraham A, Drory VE. Influence of serum uric acid levels on prognosis and survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a meta-analysis. J Neurol. 2014;261(6):1133-1138.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paganoni S, Nicholson K, Chan J, et al. Urate levels predict survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: analysis of the expanded pooled resource open-access ALS clinical trials database. Muscle Nerve. 2018;57(3):430-434.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paganoni S, Zhang M, Quiroz Zarate A, et al. Uric acid levels predict survival in men with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol. 2012;259(9):1923-1928.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang F, Zhang Q, Ke Y, et al. Serum uric acid levels in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a meta-analysis. Sci Rep. 2018;8(1):1100.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh SI, Baek S, Park JS, Piao L, Oh KW, Kim SH. Prognostic role of serum levels of uric acid in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Clin Neurol. 2015;11(4):376-382.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haji S, Sako W, Murakami N, et al. The value of serum uric acid as a prognostic biomarker in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: evidence from a meta-analysis. Clin Neurol Neurosurg. 2021;203:106566.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keizman D, Ish-Shalom M, Berliner S, et al. Low uric acid levels in serum of patients with ALS: further evidence for oxidative stress? J Neurol Sci. 2009;285(1-2):95-99.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Llull L, Amaro S, Chamorro A. Administration of uric acid in the emergency treatment of acute ischemic stroke. Curr Neurol Neurosci Rep. 2016;16(1):4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagase M, Yamamoto Y, Miyazaki Y, Yoshino H. Increased oxidative stress in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and the effect of edaravone administration. Redox Rep. 2016;21(3):104-112.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamamoto Y. Plasma marker of tissue oxidative damage and edaravone as a scavenger drug against peroxyl radicals and peroxynitrite. J Clin Biochem Nutr. 2017;60(1):49-54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicholson K, Chan J, Macklin EA, et al. Pilot trial of inosine to elevate urate levels in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Clin Transl Neurol. 2018;5(12):1522-1533.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baxmann AC, Ahmed MS, Marques NC, et al. Influence of muscle mass and physical activity on serum and urinary creatinine and serum cystatin C. Clin J Am Soc Nephrol. 2008;3(2):348-354.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon PH, Cheng B, Salachas F, et al. Progression in ALS is not linear but is curvilinear. J Neurol. 2010;257(10):1713-1717.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proudfoot M, Jones A, Talbot K, Al-Chalabi A, Turner MR. The ALSFRS as an outcome measure in therapeutic trials and its relationship to symptom onset. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2016;17(5-6):414-425.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thakore NJ, Lapin BR, Pioro EP, Pooled Resource Open-Access, ALS Clinical Trials Consortium. Trajectories of impairment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: insights from the pooled resource open-access ALS clinical trials cohort. Muscle Nerve. 2018;57(6):937-945.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>