<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">36053970</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>24</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-4598</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>66</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Muscle &amp; nerve</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Muscle Nerve</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Associations between the ALSFRS-R score and urate levels during 12&#x2009;months of edaravone treatment for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Post hoc analysis of ALSFRS-R scores in clinical studies MCI186-16, MCI186-17, and MCI186-19.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>593</StartPage><EndPage>602</EndPage><MedlinePgn>593-602</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/mus.27700</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION/AIMS">In this study we examined the relationship between urate levels at baseline and functional change measured by the Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Functional Rating Scale-Revised (ALSFRS-R) total score after edaravone treatment.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Data from the edaravone trials MCI186-16, MCI186-17, and MCI186-19 were analyzed, including the following treatment sequence groups: edaravone-edaravone (EE, n&#xa0;=&#xa0;113); edaravone-placebo (EP, n&#xa0;=&#xa0;45); and placebo-edaravone (PE, n&#xa0;=&#xa0;146). Subgroups were defined as low baseline urate (below the median value of 4.8&#xa0;mg/dL) and high baseline urate (&#x2265;4.8&#xa0;mg/dL). The differences in ALSFRS-R total score change and urate change were evaluated using the mixed model for repeated measurement for overall population, by urate-level subgroup, and by trial.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Compared with the PE group, the EE group showed a slower decline in ALSFRS-R score, regardless of the urate baseline level, and a slower decline in urate level in the higher baseline urate subgroup. Smaller changes in ALSFRS-R score and urate were observed in patients diagnosed with "probable, laboratory-supported ALS." There was a positive correlation between changes from baseline to cycle 12 in urate levels and ALSFRS-R score.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION">Edaravone treatment in ALS patients diagnosed with "definite ALS" or "probable ALS" showed slowing of disease progression, regardless of baseline urate level. In addition, because edaravone treatment was associated with a slower decline in urate level in the higher baseline urate subgroup and urate-level changes were associated with changes in ALSFRS-R score, urate level, and/or change may be one indicator in predicting disease progression after edaravone administration.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Takahashi</LastName><ForeName>Fumihiro</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5701-5332</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mitsubishi Tanabe Pharma Corporation, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kano</LastName><ForeName>Osamu</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Toho University, Faculty of Medicine, Ota-ku, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nagano</LastName><ForeName>Yoshito</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mitsubishi Tanabe Pharma Corporation, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yoneoka</LastName><ForeName>Takatomo</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mitsubishi Tanabe Pharma Corporation, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nelson</LastName><ForeName>Sally</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mitsubishi Tanabe Pharma America, Inc, Jersey City, New Jersey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ushirogawa</LastName><ForeName>Yoshiteru</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mitsubishi Tanabe Pharma Corporation, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Muscle Nerve</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7803146</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0148-639X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>S798V6YJRP</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000077553">Edaravone</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D016166">Free Radical Scavengers</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>268B43MJ25</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D014527">Uric Acid</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018450" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Progression</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000077553" MajorTopicYN="N">Edaravone</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016166" MajorTopicYN="N">Free Radical Scavengers</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014527" MajorTopicYN="N">Uric Acid</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002986" MajorTopicYN="N">Clinical Trials as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ALS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ALSFRS-R</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">biomarker</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">motor neuron disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">oxidative stress</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36053970</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.27700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Takahashi F, Kano O, Nagano Y, Yoneoka T, Nelson S, Ushirogawa Y. Associations between urate levels and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis functional score with edaravone treatment: post hoc analysis of studies MCI186-16, MCI186-17, and MCI186-19. Muscle Nerve. 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han HJ, Shin HY, Choi YC, Kim SM, Kim SW. Serum uric acid level predicts the progression of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis following treatment with edaravone. Redox Rep. 2022;27:79-84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ames BN, Cathcart R, Schwiers E, Hochstein P. Uric acid provides an antioxidant defense in humans against oxidant- and radical-caused aging and cancer: a hypothesis. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 1981;78:6858-6862.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keizman D, Ish-Shalom M, Berliner S, et al. Low uric acid levels in serum of patients with ALS: further evidence for oxidative stress? J Neurol Sci. 2009;285:95-99.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hink HU, Santanam N, Dikalov S, et al. Peroxidase properties of extracellular superoxide dismutase: role of uric acid in modulating in vivo activity. Arterioscler Thromb Vasc Biol. 2002;22:1402-1408.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zoccolella S, Simone IL, Capozzo R, et al. An exploratory study of serum urate levels in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol. 2011;258:238-243.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du Y, Chen CP, Tseng CY, Eisenberg Y, Firestein BL. Astroglia-mediated effects of uric acid to protect spinal cord neurons from glutamate toxicity. Glia. 2007;55:463-472.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paganoni S, Nicholson K, Chan J, et al. Urate levels predict survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: analysis of the expanded pooled resource open-access ALS clinical trials database. Muscle Nerve. 2018;57:430-434.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paganoni S, Zhang M, Quiroz Zarate A, et al. Uric acid levels predict survival in men with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol. 2012;259:1923-1928.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh SI, Baek S, Park JS, Piao L, Oh KW, Kim SH. Prognostic role of serum levels of uric acid in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Clin Neurol. 2015;11:376-382.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naganuma M, Inatomi Y, Nakajima M, Yonehara T, Ando Y. Associations between uric acid level and 3-month functional outcome in acute ischemic stroke patients treated with/without edaravone. Cerebrovasc Dis. 2018;45:115-123.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abe K, Itoyama Y, Sobue G, et al. Confirmatory double-blind, parallel-group, placebo-controlled study of efficacy and safety of edaravone (MCI-186) in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. Amyotrophic Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2014;15:610-617.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Writing Group on Behalf of the Edaravone ALS 17 Study Group. Exploratory double-blind, parallel-group, placebo-controlled extension study of edaravone (MCI-186) in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotrophic Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2017;18(Suppl 1):20-31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Writing Group; Edaravone (MCI-186) ALS 19 Study Group. Safety and efficacy of edaravone in well defined patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Lancet Neurol. 2017;16:505-512.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Reilly EJ, Liu D, Johns DR, et al. Serum urate at trial entry and ALS progression in EMPOWER. Amyotrophic Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2017;18:120-125.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cipriani S, Chen X, Schwarzschild MA. Urate: a novel biomarker of Parkinson's disease risk, diagnosis and prognosis. Biomark Med. 2010;4:701-712.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagase M, Yamamoto Y, Miyazaki Y, Yoshino H. Increased oxidative stress in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and the effect of edaravone administration. Redox. Rep. 2016;21:104-112.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshino H, Kimura A. Investigation of the therapeutic effects of edaravone, a free radical scavenger, on amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (phase II study). Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2006;7:241-245.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujisawa A, Yamamoto Y. Edaravone, a potent free radical scavenger, reacts with peroxynitrite to produce predominantly 4-NO-edaravone. Redox Rep. 2016;21:98-103.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>