<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36069419</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>08</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1473-6551</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>35</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Current opinion in neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Curr Opin Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Neuropathology and neuroanatomy of TDP-43 amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>660</StartPage><EndPage>671</EndPage><MedlinePgn>660-671</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/WCO.0000000000001098</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE OF REVIEW">Intracellular inclusions consisting of the abnormal TDP-43 protein and its nucleocytoplasmic mislocalization in selected cell types are hallmark pathological features of sALS. Descriptive (histological, morphological), anatomical, and molecular studies all have improved our understanding of the neuropathology of sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (sALS). This review highlights some of the latest developments in the field.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RECENT FINDINGS">Increasing evidence exists from experimental models for the prion-like nature of abnormal TDP-43, including a strain-effect, and with the help of neuroimaging-based studies, for spreading of disease along corticofugal connectivities in sALS. Progress has also been made with respect to finding and establishing reliable biomarkers (neurofilament levels, diffusor tensor imaging).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUMMARY">The latest findings may help to elucidate the preclinical phase of sALS and to define possible mechanisms for delaying or halting disease development and progression.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Del Tredici</LastName><ForeName>Kelly</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Neuroanatomy Section, Department of Neurology, Center for Biomedical Research, University of Ulm, Ulm, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Braak</LastName><ForeName>Heiko</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Curr Opin Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9319162</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1350-7540</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D004268">DNA-Binding Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004268" MajorTopicYN="N">DNA-Binding Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002479" MajorTopicYN="N">Inclusion Bodies</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009445" MajorTopicYN="N">Neuroanatomy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36069419</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/WCO.0000000000001098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00019052-202210000-00017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ou SH, Wu F, Harrich D, et al. Cloning and characterization of a novel cellular protein, TDP-43, that binds to human immunodeficiency virus type 1 TAR DNA sequence motifs. J Virol 1995; 69:3584&#x2013;3596.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buratti E, Baralle FE. Characterization and functional implications of the RNA binding properties of nuclear factor TDP-43, a novel splicing regulator of CFTR exon 9. J Biol Chem 2001; 276:36337&#x2013;36343.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arai T, Hasegawa M, Akiyama H, et al. TDP-43 is a component of ubiquitin-positive tau-negative inclusions in frontotemporal lobar degeneration and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Biochem Biophys Res Commun 2006; 351:602&#x2013;611.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neumann M, Sampathu DM, Kwong LK, et al. Ubiquitinated TDP-43 in frontotemporal lobar degeneration and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Science 2006; 314:130&#x2013;133.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neumann M, Kwong LK, Lee EB, et al. Phosphorylation of S409/410 of TDP-43 is a consistent feature in all sporadic and familial forms of TDP-43 proteinopathies. Acta Neuropathol 2009; 117:137&#x2013;149.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackenzie IR, Bigio EH, Ince PG, et al. Pathological TDP-43 distinguishes sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis from amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with SOD1 mutations. Ann Neurol 2007; 61:427&#x2013;434.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackenzie IR, Rademakers R, Neumann M. TDP-43 and FUS in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal dementia. Lancet Neurol 2010; 9:995&#x2013;1007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackenzie IR, Neumann M. Molecular neuropathology of frontotemporal dementia: insights into disease mechanisms from postmortem studies. J Neurochem 2016; 138: (Suppl 1): 54&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasegawa M, Arai T, Nonaka T, et al. Phosphorylated TDP-43 in frontotemporal lobar degeneration and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol 2008; 64:60&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geser F, Martinez-Lage M, Robinson J, et al. Clinical and pathological continuum of multisystem TDP-43 proteinopathies. Arch Neurol 2009; 66:180&#x2013;189.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cykowski MD, Takei H, Schulz PE, et al. TDP-43 pathology in the basal forebrain and hypothalamus of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathol Commun 2014; 2:171.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cykowski MD, Powell SZ, Peterson LE, et al. Clinical significance of TDP-43 neuropathology in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neuropathol Exp Neurol 2017; 76:402&#x2013;413.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braak H, Del Tredici K. Anterior cingulate cortex TDP-43 pathology in sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neuropathol Exp Neurol 2018; 77:74&#x2013;83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gregory JM, McDade K, Bak TH, et al. Executive, language and fluency dysfunction are markers of localised TDP-43 cerebral pathology in nondemented ALS. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2019; 91:149&#x2013;157.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawakami I, Arai T, Hasegawa M. The basis of clinicopathological heterogeneity in TDP-43 proteinopathy. Acta Neuropathol 2019; 38:751&#x2013;770.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pattle SB, O'Shaughnessy J, Rifai OM, et al. pTDP-43 aggregates accumulate in the gut and other noncentral nervous system tissues prior to symptom onset in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. bioRxiv 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arseni D, Hasegawa M, Murzin AG, et al. Structure of pathological TDP-43 filaments from ALS with FTLD. Nature 2022; 601:139&#x2013;143.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao Q, Boyer DR, Sawaya MR, et al. Cryo-EM structures of four polymorphic TDP-43 amyloid cores. Nat Struct Mol Biol 2019; 26:619&#x2013;627.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eisen A, Kiernan M, Mitsumoto H, Swash M. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a long preclinical period? J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2014; 85:1232&#x2013;1238.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenbohm A, Kassubek J, Weydt P, et al. ALS Schwaben Register Group. Can lesions to the motor cortex induce amyotrophic lateral sclerosis? J Neurol 2014; 261:283&#x2013;290.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakashima-Yasuda H, Uryu K, Robinson J, et al. Co-morbidity of TDP-43 proteinopathy in Lewy body related diseases. Acta Neuropathol 2007; 114:221&#x2013;229.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geser F, Robinson JL, Malunda JA, et al. Pathological 43-kDa transactivation response DNA-binding protein in older adults with and without severe mental illness. Arch Neurol 2010; 67:1238&#x2013;1250.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnold SJ, Dugger BN, Beach TG. TDP-43 deposition in prospectively followed, cognitively normal elderly individuals: Correlation with argyrophilic grains but not other concomitant pathologies. Acta Neuropathol 2013; 126:51&#x2013;57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uchino A, Takao M, Hatsuta H, et al. Incidence and extent of TDP-43 accumulation in aging human brain. Acta Neuropathol Comm 2015; 3:35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elobeid A, Libard S, Leino M, et al. Altered proteins in the aging brain. J Neuropathol Exp Neurol 2016; 75:316&#x2013;325.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson JL, Lee EB, Xie SX, et al. Neurodegenerative disease concomitant proteinopathies are prevalent, age-related and APOE4-associated. Brain 2018; 141:2181&#x2013;2193.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amador-Ortiz C, Lin WL, Ahmed Z, et al. TDP-43 immunoreactivity in hippocampal sclerosis and Alzheimer's disease. Ann Neurol 2007; 61:435&#x2013;445.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin WL, Dickson DW. Ultrastructural localization of TDP-43 in filamentous neuronal inclusions in various neurodegenerative diseases. Acta Neuropathol 2008; 116:205&#x2013;213.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKee AC, Gavett BE, Stern RA, et al. TDP-43 proteinopathy and motor neuron disease in chronic traumatic encephalopathy. J Neuropathol Exp Neurol 2010; 69:918&#x2013;929.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dardis A, Zampieri S, Canterini S, et al. Altered localization and functionality of TAR DNA binding protein 43 (TDP 43) in Niemann-pick disease type C. Acta Neuropathol Commun 2016; 4:52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neumann M, Lee EB, Mackenzie IR. FTLD-TDP pathological subtypes: clinical and mechanistic significance. Adv Exp Med Biol 2021; 1281:201&#x2013;217.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gowers WR. A Manual of Disease of the Nervous System. Vol. 2. Diseases of the Brain and Cranial Nerves, General and Functional Diseases of the Nervous System. London: J &amp; A Churchill; 1886.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wijesekera LC, Leigh PN. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Orphanet J Rare Dis 2009; 4:3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cleveland DW, Rothstein JD. From Charcot to Lou Gehrig: deciphering selective motor neuron death in ALS. Nat Rev Neurosci 2001; 2:806&#x2013;819.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiernan MC, Vucic S, Cheah BC, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet 2011; 377:942&#x2013;955.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nijssen J, Comley LH, Hedlund E. Motor neuron vulnerability and resistance in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathol 2017; 133:863&#x2013;885.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Graaff MM, Sage CA, Caan MW, et al. Upper and extra-motoneuron involvement in early motoneuron disease: a diffusion tensor imaging study. Brain 2011; 134:1211&#x2013;1228.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ludolph AC, Langen KJ, Regard M, et al. Frontal lobe function in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a neuropsychologic and positron emission tomography study. Acta Neurol Scand 1992; 85:81&#x2013;89.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wightman G, Anderson VE, Martin J, et al. Hippocampal and neocortical ubiquitin-immunoreactive inclusions in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with dementia. Neurosci Lett 1992; 139:269&#x2013;274.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson VE, Cairns NJ, Leigh PN. Involvement of the amygdala, dentate and hippocampus in motor neuron disease. J Neurol Sci 1995; 129: (Suppl): 75&#x2013;78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phukan J, Pender NP, Hardiman O. Cognitive impairment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet Neurol 2007; 6:994&#x2013;1003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Graaff MM, de Jong JM, Baas F, de Visser M. Upper motor neuron and extra-motor neuron involvement in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a clinical and brain imaging review. Neuromuscul Disord 2009; 19:53&#x2013;58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westeneng HJ, Verstraete E, Walhout R, et al. Subcortical structures in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurobiol Aging 2015; 36:1075&#x2013;1082.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dukic S, McMackin R, Buxo T, et al. Patterned functional network disruption in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Hum Brain Mapp 2019; 40:4827&#x2013;4842.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beswick E, Forbes D, Hassan Z, et al. A systematic review of nonmotor symptom evaluation in clinical trials for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol 2022; 269:411&#x2013;426.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lul&#xe9; D, Michels S, Finsel J, et al. Clinicoanatomical substrates of selfish behaviour in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis - an observational cohort study. Cortex 2022; 146:261&#x2013;270.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nana AL, Sidhu M, Gaus SE, et al. Neurons selectively targeted in frontotemporal dementia reveal early stage TDP-43 pathobiology. Acta Neuropathol 2019; 137:27&#x2013;46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butti C, Santos M, Uppal N, Hof PR. Von Economo neurons: clinical and evolutionary perspectives. Cortex 2013; 49:312&#x2013;326.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geser F, Brandmeir NJ, Kwong LK, et al. Evidence of multisystem disorder in whole-brain map of pathological TDP-43 in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Arch Neurol 2008; 65:636&#x2013;641.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishihira Y, Tan CF, Onodera O, et al. Sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: two pathological patterns shown by analysis of distribution of TDP-43-immunoreactive neuronal and glial cytoplasmic inclusions. Acta Neuropathol 2008; 116:169&#x2013;182.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H, Tan CF, Mori F, et al. TDP-43-immunoreactive neuronal and glial inclusions in the neostriatum in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with and without dementia. Acta Neuropathol 2008; 115:115&#x2013;122.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brettschneider J, Del Tredici K, Toledo JB, et al. Stages of pTDP-43 pathology in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol 2013; 74:20&#x2013;38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heo D, Ling JP, Molina-Castro GC, Nave KA, et al. Stage-specific control of oligodendrocyte survival and morphogenesis by TDP-43. elife 2022; 11:e75230.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sherwood CC, Lee PW, Rivara CB, et al. Evolution of specialized pyramidal neurons in primate visual and motor cortex. Brain Behav Evol 2003; 61:28&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heimer L, Van Hoesen GW. The limbic lobe and its output channels: implications for emotional functions and adaptive behavior. Neurosci Biobehav Rev 2006; 30:126&#x2013;147.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braak H, Brettschneider J, Ludolph AC, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis - a model of corticofugal axonal spread. Nat Rev Neurol 2013; 9:708&#x2013;714.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brettschneider J, Arai K, Del Tredici K, et al. TDP-43 pathology and neuronal loss in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis spinal cord. Acta Neuropathol 2014; 128:423&#x2013;437.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hammer RP Jr, Tomiyasu U, Scheibel AB. Degeneration of the human Betz cell due to amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Exp Neurol 1979; 63:336&#x2013;346.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nihei K, McKee AC, Kowall NW. Patterns of neuronal degeneration in the motor cortex of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. Acta Neuropathol 1993; 86:55&#x2013;64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braak H, Ludolph A, Thal DR, Del Tredici K. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: dash-like accumulation of phosphorylated TDP-43 in somatodendritic and axonal compartments of somatomotor neurons of the lower brainstem and spinal cord. Acta Neuropathol 2010; 120:67&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schr&#xf8;der HD, Reske-Nielsen E. Preservation of the nucleus X-pelvic floor motosystem in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Neuropathol 1984; 3:210&#x2013;216.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iwatsubo T, Kuzuhara S, Kanemitsu A, et al. Corticofugal projections to the motor nuclei of the brainstem and spinal cord in humans. Neurology 1990; 40:309&#x2013;312.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schellino R, Boido M, Vercelli A. The dual nature of Onuf's nucleus: neuroanatomical features and peculiarities in health and disease. Front Neuroanat 2020; 14:572013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lalancette-Hebert M, Sharma A, Lyashchenko AK, Shneider NA. Gamma motor neurons survive and exacerbate alpha motor neuron degeneration in ALS. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 2016; 113:E8316&#x2013;E8325.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roussel M, Lemieux M, Bretzner F. Whelan PJ, Sharples SA. Using mouse genetics to investigate supraspinal pathways of the brain important to locomotion. The neural control of movement: model systems and tools to study locomotor function. London, San Diego, Cambridge (MA), Oxford: Academic Press; 2020. 269&#x2013;313.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Catsman-Berrevoets CE, Kuypers HG. Cells of origin of cortical projections to dorsal column nuclei, spinal cord and bulbar medial reticular formation in the rhesus monkey. Neurosci Lett 1976; 3:245&#x2013;252.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heimer L, Switzer RD, Van Hoesen GW. Ventral striatum and ventral pallidum. Components of the motor system? Trends Neurosci 1982; 5:83&#x2013;87.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kassubek J, M&#xfc;ller HP, Del Tredici K, et al. Diffusion tensor imaging analysis of sequential spreading of disease in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis confirms patterns of TDP-43 pathology. Brain 2014; 137:1733&#x2013;1740.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kassubek J, M&#xfc;ller HP, Del Tredici K, et al. Imaging the pathoanatomy of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in vivo: targeting a propagation-based biological marker. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2018; 89:374&#x2013;381.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller HP, Turner MR, Grosskreutz J, et al. Neuroimaging Society in ALS (NiSALS) DTI Study Group. A large-scale multicentre cerebral diffusion tensor imaging study in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2016; 87:570&#x2013;579.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hornberger M, Kiernan MC. Emergence of an imaging biomarker for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: is the end point near? J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2016; 87:569.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt R, de Reus MA, Scholtens LH, et al. Simulating disease propagation across white matter connectome reveals anatomical substrate for neuropathology staging in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuroimage 2016; 124 (Pt a):762&#x2013;769.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorges M, Del Tredici K, Dreyhaupt J, et al. Corticoefferent pathology distribution in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: in vivo evidence from a meta-analysis of diffusion tensor imaging data. Sci Rep 2018; 8:15389.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fatima M, Tan R, Halliday GM, Kril JJ. Spread of pathology in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: assessment of phosphorylated TDP-43 along axonal pathways. Acta Neuropathol Comm 2015; 3:47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishihira Y, Tan CF, Hoshi Y, et al. Sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis of long duration is associated with relatively mild TDP-43 pathology. Acta Neuropathol 2009; 117:45&#x2013;53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geser F, Fellner L, Haybaeck J, Wenning GK. Development of neurodegeneration in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: from up or down? J Neural Transm 2020; 127:1097&#x2013;1105.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riku Y. Reappraisal of the anatomical spreading and propagation hypothesis about TDP-43 aggregation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal lobar degeneration. Neuropathology 2020; 40:426&#x2013;435.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuypers H, Brookhart J. Anatomy of the descending pathways. Handbook of physiology - the nervous system II. Mountcastle VB, Bethesda (MD): American Physiological Society. Williams and Williams; 1981; 597&#x2013;666.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalra S, M&#xfc;ller HP, Ishaque A, et al. A prospective harmonized multicenter DTI study of cerebral white matter degeneration in ALS. Neurology 2020; 95:e943&#x2013;e952.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suk TR, Rosseau MWC. The role of TDP-43 mislocalization in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Mol Neurodegener 2020; 15:45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wittstock M, Wolters A, Benecke R. Transcallosal inhibition in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Neurophysiol 2007; 118:301&#x2013;307.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filippini N, Douaud G, Mackay CE, et al. Corpus callosum involvement is a consistent feature of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology 2010; 75:1645&#x2013;1652.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng L, Tang X, Luo C, et al. Fiber-specific white matter reductions in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuroimage Clin 2020; 28:102516.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tu S, Wang C, Menke RAL, et al. Regional callosal integrity and bilaterality of limb weakness in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2020; 21:396&#x2013;402.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Bos MAJ, Higashihara M, Geevasinga N, et al. Pathophysiological associations of transcallosal dysfunction in ALS. Eur J Neurol 2021; 28:1172&#x2013;1180.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stephens B, Guiloff RJ, Navarrete R, et al. Widespread loss of neuronal populations in the spinal ventral horn in sporadic motor neuron disease. A morphometric study. J Neurol Sci 2006; 244:41&#x2013;58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maekawa S, Al-Sarraj S, Kibble M, et al. Cortical selective vulnerability in motor neuron disease: a morphometric study. Brain 2004; 127 (Pt 6):1237&#x2013;1251.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shatunov A, Mok K, Newhouse S, et al. Chromosome 9p21 in sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in the UK and seven other countries: a genome-wide association study. Lancet Neurol 2010; 9:986&#x2013;994.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perry DC, Brown JA, Possin KL, et al. Clinicopathological correlations in behavioural variant frontotemporal dementia. Brain 2017; 140:3329&#x2013;3345.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Es MA, Hardiman O, Chi&#xf2; A, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet 2017; 390:2084&#x2013;2098.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ling SC, Polymenidou M, Cleveland DW. Converging mechanisms in ALS and FTD: disrupted RNA and protein homeostasis. Neuron 2013; 79:416&#x2013;438.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mihevc SP, Darovic S, Kovanda A, et al. Nuclear trafficking in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal lobar degeneration. Brain 2017; 140:13&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitra J, Guerrero EN, Hegde PM, et al. Motor neuron disease-associated loss of nuclear TDP-43 is linked to DNA double-strand break repair defects. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA 2019; 116:4696&#x2013;4705.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keating SS, San Gil R, Swanson MEV, et al. TDP-43 pathology: from noxious assembly to therapeutic removal. Prog Neurobiol 2022; 211:102229.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sasaki S, Tsutsumi Y, Yamane K, Sakuma H, et al. Sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with extensive neurological involvement. Acta Neuropathol 1992; 84:211&#x2013;215.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buratti E, Baralle FE. The multiple roles of TDP-43 in prem-RNA processing and gene expression regulation. RNA Biol 2010; 7:420&#x2013;429.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ederle H, Dormann D. TDP-43 and FUS en route from the nucleus to the cytoplasm. FEBS Lett 2017; 591:1489&#x2013;1507.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayala YM, Zago P, D&#x2019;Ambrogio A, et al. Structural determinants of the cellular localization and shuttling of TDP-43. J Cell Sci 2008; 121:3778&#x2013;3785.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ederle H, Funk C, Abou-Ajram C, et al. Nuclear egress of TDP-43 and FUS occurs independently of Exportin-1/CRM1. Sci Rep 2018; 8:7084.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fallini C, Bassell G, Rossoll W. The ALS disease protein TDP-43 is actively transported in motor neuron axons and regulates axon outgrowth. Hum Mol Genet 2012; 21:3708&#x2013;3718.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowden H, Dormann D. Altered mRNP granule dynamics in FTLD/ALS pathogenesis. J Neurochem 2016; 138: (Suppl 1): 112&#x2013;133.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oberstadt M, Cla&#xdf;en J, Arendt T, Holzer M. TDP-43 and cytoskeletal proteins in ALS. Mol Neurobiol 2018; 55:3143&#x2013;3151.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee EB, Lee VMY, Trojanowski JQ, Neumann M. TDP-43 immunoreactivity in anoxic, ischemic and neoplastic lesions of the central nervous system. Acta Neuropathol 2008; 115:305&#x2013;311.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#x2019;Angelo MA, Raices M, Panowski SH, Hetzer MW. Age-dependent deterioration of nuclear pore complexes causes a loss of nuclear integrity in postmitotic cells. Cell 2009; 136:284&#x2013;295.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aizawa H, Yamashita T, Kato H, et al. Impaired nucleoporins are present in sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis motor neurons that exhibit mislocalization of the 43-kDa TAR DNA-binding protein. J Clin Neurol 2019; 15:62&#x2013;67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chandra S, Lusk CP. Emerging connections between nuclear pore complex homeostasis and ALS. Int J Mol Sci 2022; 23:1329.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buratti E, Romano M, Baralle FE. TDP-43 high throughput screening analyses in neurodegeneration: advantages and pitfalls. Mol Cell Neurosci 2013; 56:465&#x2013;474.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Onadera O, Sugai A, Konno T, et al. What is the key player in TDP-43 pathology in ALS: disappearance from the nucleus or inclusion formation in the cytoplasm? Neurol Clin Neurosci 2013; 1:11&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fahrenkrog B, Harel A. Perturbations in traffic: aberrant nucleocytoplasmic transport at the heart of neurodegeneration. Cells 2018; 7:232.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Igaz LM, Kwong LK, Xu Y, et al. Enrichment of C-terminal fragments in TAR DNA-binding protein-43 cytoplasmic inclusions in brain but not in spinal cord of frontotemporal lobar degeneration and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Am J Pathol 2008; 173:182&#x2013;194.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winton MJ, Igaz LM, Wong MM, et al. Disturbance of nuclear and cytoplasmic TAR DNA-binding protein (TDP-43) induces disease-like redistribution, sequestration, and aggregate formation. J Biol Chem 2008; 283:13302&#x2013;13309.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polymenidou M, Lagier-Tourrene C, Hutt KR, et al. Long premRNA depletion and RNA missplicing contribute to neuronal vulnerability from loss of TDP-43. Nature Neurosci 2011; 14:459&#x2013;468.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Highley JR, Kirby J, Jansweijer JA, et al. Loss of nuclear TDP-43 in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) causes altered expression of splicing machinery and widespread dysregulation of RNA splicing in motor neurones. Neuropathol Appl Neurobiol 2014; 40:670&#x2013;685.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang C, Wang H, Qiao T, et al. Partial loss of TDP-43 function causes phenotypes of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA 2014; 111:E1121&#x2013;E1129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boeynaems S, Bogaert E, Van Damme P, Van den Bosch L. Inside out: the role of nucleocytoplasmic transport in ALS and FTLD. Acta Neuropathol 2016; 132:159&#x2013;173.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klim JR, Williams LA, Limone F, et al. ALS-implicated protein TDP-43 sustains levels of STMN2, a mediator of motor neuron growth and repair. Nat Neurosci 2019; 22:167&#x2013;179.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giordana MT, Piccinini M, Grifoni S, et al. TDP-43 redistribution is an early event in sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain Pathol 2010; 20:351&#x2013;360.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y-J, Gendron TF, Xu YF, et al. Phosphorylation regulates proteasomal-mediated degradation and solubility of TAR DNA binding protein-43 C-terminal fragments. Mol Neurodegener 2010; 5:33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen TJ, Hwang AW, Restrepo CR, et al. An acetylation switch controls TDP-43 function and aggregation propensity. Nat Commun 2015; 6:5845.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hans F, Eckert M, von Zweydorf F, et al. Identification and characterization of ubiquitinylation sites in TAR DNA-binding protein of 43 kDa (TDP-43). J Biol Chem 2018; 293:16083&#x2013;16099.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rayner SL, Yang S, Farrawell NE, et al. TDP-43 is a ubiquitylation substrate of the SCF cyclinF complex. Neurobiol Dis 2022; 167:105673.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gruijs da Silva LA, Simonetti F, Hutten S, et al. Disease-linked TDP-43 hyperphosphorylation suppresses TDP-43 condensation and aggregation. EMBO J 2022; 41:e108443.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brady OA, Meng P, Zheng Y, et al. Regulation of TDP-43 aggregation by phosphorylation and p62/SQSTM1. J Neurochem 2011; 116:248&#x2013;259.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y-J, Xu Y-F, Cook C, et al. Aberrant cleavage of TDP-43 enhances aggregation and cellular toxicity. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 2009; 106:7607&#x2013;7612.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ito D, Suzuki N. Conjoint pathologic cascades mediated by ALS/FTLD-U linked RNA-binding proteins TDP-43 and FUS. Neurology 2011; 77:1636&#x2013;1643.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang LL, Che MX, Zhao J, et al. Structural transformation of the amyloidogenic core region of TDP-43 protein initiates its aggregation and cytoplasmic inclusion. J Biol Chem 2013; 288:19614&#x2013;19624.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a Morato J, Hans F, von Zweydorf F, et al. Sirtuin-1 sensitive lysine-136 acetylation drives phase separation and pathological aggregation of TDP-43. Nat Commun 2022; 13:1223.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braak H, Ludolph AC, Neumann M, Ravits J, et al. Pathological TDP-43 changes in Betz cells differ from those in bulbar and spinal &#x3b1;-motoneurons in sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathol 2017; 133:79&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwong LK, Irwin DJ, Walker AK, et al. Novel monoclonal antibodies to normal and pathologically altered human TDP-43 proteins. Acta Neuropathol Commun 2014; 2:33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scotter EL, Chen HJ, Shaw CE. TDP-43 Proteinopathy and ALS: Insights into disease mechanisms and therapeutic targets. Neurotherapeutics 2015; 12:352&#x2013;363.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalmar B, Lu CH, Greensmith L. The role of heat shock proteins in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: the therapeutic potential of arimoclomol. Pharmacol Ther 2014; 141:40&#x2013;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen HJ, Mitchell JC, Novoselov S, et al. The heat shock response plays an important role in TDP-43 clearance: evidence for dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain 2016; 139 (Pt 5):1417&#x2013;1432.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>San Gil R, Cox D, McAlary L, et al. Neurodegenerative disease-associated protein aggregates are poor inducers of the heat shock response in neuronal cells. J Cell Sci 2020; 133:jcs243709.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang CY, Rasband MN. Axon initial segments: structure, function, and disease. Ann N Y Acad Sci 2018; 1420:46&#x2013;61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feiler MS, Strobel B, Freischmidt A, et al. TDP-43 is intercellularly transmitted across axon terminals. J Cell Biol 2015; 211:897&#x2013;911.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maday S. Mechanisms of neuronal homeostasis: autophagy in the axon. Brain Res 2016; 1649:143&#x2013;150.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burk K, Pasterkamp RJ. Disrupted neuronal trafficking in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathol 2019; 137:859&#x2013;877.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riku Y, Watanabe H, Yoshida M, et al. Marked involvement of the striatal efferent system in TAR DNA-Binding Protein 43 kDa-related frontotemporal lobar degeneration and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neuropathol Exp Neurol 2016; 75:801&#x2013;811.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsang YM, Chiong F, Kuznetsov D, et al. Motor neurons are rich in nonphosphorylated neurofilaments: cross-species comparison and alterations in ALS. Brain Res 2000; 861:45&#x2013;58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szaro BG, Strong MJ. Posttranscriptional control of neurofilaments: new roles in development, regeneration and neurodegenerative disease. Trends Neurosci 2010; 33:27&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toivola DM, Strnad P, Habtezion A, Omary MD. Intermediate filaments take the heat as stress proteins. Trends Cell Biol 2010; 20:79&#x2013;91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan A, Rao MV, Veeranna, Nixon RA. Neurofilaments at a glance. J Cell Sci 2012; 125 (Pt 14):3257&#x2013;3263.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nefedova VV, Sudnitsyna MV, Gusev NB. Interaction of small heat shock proteins with light component of neurofilaments (NFL). Cell Stress Chaperones 2017; 22:467&#x2013;479.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stetler RA, Gan Y, Zhang W, et al. Heat shock proteins: cellular and molecular mechanisms in the central nervous system. Prog Neurobiol 2010; 92:184&#x2013;211.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parakh S, Atkin JD. Protein folding alterations in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain Res 2016; 1648 (Pt B):633&#x2013;649.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carpenter S. Proximal axonal enlargement in motor neuron disease. Neurology 1968; 18:841&#x2013;851.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirano A, Donnenfeld H, Sasaki S, Nakano I. Fine structural observations of neurofilamentous changes in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neuropathol Exp Neurol 1984; 43:461&#x2013;470.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munoz DG, Greene C, Perl DP, Selkoe DJ. Accumulation of phosphorylated neurofilaments in anterior horn motoneurons of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. J Neuropathol Exp Neurol 1988; 47:9&#x2013;18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergeron C, Beric-Maskarel K, Muntasser S, et al. Neurofilament light and polyadenylated mRNA levels are decreased in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis motor neurons. J Neuropathol Exp Neurol 1994; 53:221&#x2013;230.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strong MJ, Volkening K, Hammond R, et al. TDP43 is a human low molecular weight neurofilament (hNFL) mRNA-binding protein. Mol Cell Neurosci 2007; 35:320&#x2013;327.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tripathi VB, Baskaran P, Shaw CE, Guthrie S. Tar DNA-binding protein-43 (TDP-43) regualates axon growth in vitro and in vivo. Neurobiol Dis 2014; 65:25&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyazaki D, Nakamura A, Hineno A, et al. Elevation of serum heat-shock protein levels in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurol Sci 2016; 37:1277&#x2013;1281.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behzadi A, Pujol-Calder&#xf3;n F, Tjust AE, et al. Neurofilaments can differentiate ALS subgroups and ALS from common diagnostic mimics. Sci Rep 2021; 11:22128.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verde F, Otto M, Silani V. Neurofilament light chain as biomarker for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal dementia. Front Neurosci 2021; 15:679199.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okamoto K, Hirai S, Shoji M, et al. Axonal swellings in the corticospinal tracts in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathol 1990; 80:222&#x2013;226.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sasaki S, Maruyama S. Increase in diameter of the axonal initial segment is an early change in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Sci 1992; 110:114&#x2013;120.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR. The role of axonal transport in neurodegenerative disease spread: a meta-analysis of experimental and clinical poliomyelitis compares with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Can J Neurol Sci 1991; 18:435&#x2013;438.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ravits J, Laurie P, Fan Y, Moore DH. Implications of ALS focality: rostral-caudal distribution of lower motor neuron loss postmortem. Neurology 2007; 68:1576&#x2013;1582.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ravits JM, LaSpada AR. ALS motor phenotype heterogeneity, focality, and spread: deconstructing motor neuron degeneration. Neurology 2009; 73:805&#x2013;811.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanouchi T, Ohkubo T, Yokota T. Can regional spreading of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis motor symptoms be explained by prion-like propagation? J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2012; 83:739&#x2013;745.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ravits J. Focality, stochasticity and neuroanatomic propagation in ALS pathogenesis. Exp Neurol 2014; 262 (Pt B):121&#x2013;126.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furukawa Y, Kaneko K, Watanabe S, et al. A seeding reaction recapitulates intracellular formation of sarkosyl-insoluble transactivation response element (TAR) DNA-binding protein-43 inclusions. J Biol Chem 2011; 286:18664&#x2013;18672.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jucker M, Walker LC. Self-propagation of pathogenic protein aggregates in neurodegenerative diseases. Nature 2013; 501:45&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nonaka T, Masuda-Suzukake M, Arai T, et al. Prion-like properties of pathological TDP-43 aggregates from diseased brains. Cell Rep 2013; 4:124&#x2013;134.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee S, Kim JH. Prion-like mechanism in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: are protein aggregates the key? Exp Neurobiol 2015; 24:1&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smethurst P, Newcombe J, Troakes C, et al. In vitro prion-like behaviour of TDP-43 in ALS. Neurobiol Dis 2016; 96:236&#x2013;247.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smethurst P, Risse E, Tyzack GE, et al. Distinct response of neurons and astrocytes to TDP-43 proteinopathy in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain 2020; 143:430&#x2013;440.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Porta S, Xu Y, Restrepo CR, et al. Patient-derived frontotemporal lobar degeneration brain extracts induce formation and spreading of TDP-43 pathology in vivo. Nat Commun 2018; 9:4220.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nonaka T, Hasegawa M. TDP-43 prions. Cold Spring Harb Perspect Med 2018; 8:a024463.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McAlary L, Yerbury JJ, Cashman NR. The prion-like nature of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Prog Mol Biol Transl Sci 2020; 175:261&#x2013;296.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding X, Xiang Z, Qin C, et al. Spreading of TDP-43 pathology via pyramidal tract induces ALS-like phenotypes in TDP-43 transgenic mice. Acta Neuropathol Comm 2021; 9:15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang R, Chen Y, Wang X, et al. Spreading of pathological TDP-43 along corticospinal tract axons induces ALS-like phenotypes in Atg5 +/&#x2212; mice. Int J Biol Sci 2021; 17:390&#x2013;401.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou J, Gennatas ED, Kramer JH, et al. Predicting regional neurodegeneration from the healthy brain functional connectome. Neuron 2012; 73:1216&#x2013;1227.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spiller KJ, Cheung CJ, Restrepo CR, et al. Selective motor neuron resistance and recovery in a new inducible mouse model of TDP-43 proteinopathy. J Neurosci 2016; 36:7707&#x2013;7717.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takeda T, Kitagawa K, Arai K. Phenotypic variability and its pathological basis in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuropathology 2020; 40:40&#x2013;56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasegawa M, Nonanka T, Tsuij H, et al. Molecular dissection of TDP-43 proteinopathies. J Mol Neurosci 2011; 45:480&#x2013;485.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsuji H, Arai T, Kametani F, et al. Molecular analysis and biochemical classification of TDP-43 proteinopathy. Brain 2012; 135:3380&#x2013;33891.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimonaka S, Nonaka T, Suzuki G, et al. Templated aggregation of TAR DNA-binding protein of 43 kDa (TDP-43) by seeding with TDP-43 peptide fibrils. J Biol Chem 2016; 291:8896&#x2013;8907.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Porta S, Xu Y, Lehr T, et al. Distinct brain-derived TDP-43 strains from FTLD-TDP subtypes induce diverse morphological TDP-43 aggregates and spreading patterns in vitro and in vivo. Neuropathol Appl Neurobiol 2021; 47:1033&#x2013;1049.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berning BA, Walker AK. The pathobiology of TDP-43 terminal fragments in ALS and FTLD. Front Neurosci 2019; 13:1335.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walhout R, Verstraete E, van den Heuvel MP, et al. Patterns of symptom development in patients with motor neuron disease. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2018; 19:21&#x2013;28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moloney EB, de Winter F, Verhaagen J. ALS as a distal axonopathy: molecular mechanisms affecting neuromuscular junction stability in the presymptomatic stages of the disease. Front Neurosci 2014; 8:252.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ludolph AC, Emilian S, Dreyhaupt J, et al. Pattern of paresis in ALS is consistent with the physiology of the corticomotoneuronal projections to different muscle groups. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2020; 91:991&#x2013;998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eisen A, Braak H, Del Tredici K. Cortical influences drive amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2017; 88:917&#x2013;924.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eisen A. The dying forward hypothesis of ALS: tracing its history. Brain Sci 2021; 11:300.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hergesheimer RC, Chami AA, de Assis DR, et al. The debated toxic role of aggregated TDP-43 in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a resolution in sight? Brain 2019; 142:1176&#x2013;1194.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gois AM, Mendon&#xe7;a DMF, Freire MAM, Santos JR. In vitro and in vivo models of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: an updated overview. Brain Res Bull 2020; 159:32&#x2013;43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lemon RN, Griffiths J. Comparing the function of the corticospinal system in different species: organizational differences for motor specialization? Muscle Nerve 2005; 32:261&#x2013;279.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uchida A, Sasaguri H, Kimura N, et al. Nonhuman primate model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with cytoplasmic mislocalization of TDP-43. Brain 2012; 135:833&#x2013;846.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardiman O, Al-Chalabi A, Chio A, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat Rev Dis Primers 2017; 3:17071.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>