<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36116464</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>18</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1474-547X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>400</Volume><Issue>10360</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>15</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Lancet (London, England)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Lancet</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1363</StartPage><EndPage>1380</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1363-1380</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/S0140-6736(22)01272-7</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0140-6736(22)01272-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis is a fatal CNS neurodegenerative disease. Despite intensive research, current management of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis remains suboptimal from diagnosis to prognosis. Recognition of the phenotypic heterogeneity of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, global CNS dysfunction, genetic architecture, and development of novel diagnostic criteria is clarifying the spectrum of clinical presentation and facilitating diagnosis. Insights into the pathophysiology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, identification of disease biomarkers and modifiable risks, along with new predictive models, scales, and scoring systems, and a clinical trial pipeline of mechanism-based therapies, are changing the prognostic landscape. Although most recent advances have yet to translate into patient benefit, the idea of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis as a complex syndrome is already having tangible effects in the clinic. This Seminar will outline these insights and discuss the status of the management of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis for the general neurologist, along with future prospects that could improve care and outcomes for patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Feldman</LastName><ForeName>Eva L</ForeName><Initials>EL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Michigan Medicine, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, MI, USA. Electronic address: efeldman@umich.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Goutman</LastName><ForeName>Stephen A</ForeName><Initials>SA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Michigan Medicine, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, MI, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Petri</LastName><ForeName>Susanne</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Hannover Medical School, Hannover, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mazzini</LastName><ForeName>Letizia</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ALS Centre, Azienda Ospedaliero-Universitaria Maggiore della Carit&#xe0;, Novara, Italy; Department of Neurology, University of Piemonte Orientale, Novara, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Savelieff</LastName><ForeName>Masha G</ForeName><Initials>MG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Michigan Medicine, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, MI, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shaw</LastName><ForeName>Pamela J</ForeName><Initials>PJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sheffield Institute for Translational Neuroscience (SITraN), University of Sheffield, Sheffield, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sobue</LastName><ForeName>Gen</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Aichi Medical University, Nagakute, Aichi, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R01 TS000289</GrantID><Acronym>TS</Acronym><Agency>ATSDR CDC HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01TS000289</GrantID><Acronym>ACL</Acronym><Agency>ACL HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01 TS000327</GrantID><Acronym>TS</Acronym><Agency>ATSDR CDC HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>K23 ES027221</GrantID><Acronym>ES</Acronym><Agency>NIEHS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01 ES030049</GrantID><Acronym>ES</Acronym><Agency>NIEHS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01 NS120926</GrantID><Acronym>NS</Acronym><Agency>NINDS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01 NS127188</GrantID><Acronym>NS</Acronym><Agency>NINDS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Lancet</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>2985213R</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0140-6736</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D015415">Biomarkers</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015415" MajorTopicYN="N">Biomarkers</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005544" MajorTopicYN="N">Forecasting</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019636" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neurodegenerative Diseases</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011379" MajorTopicYN="N">Prognosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>Declaration of interests ELF and SAG have a patent issued (US20200253977A1). SAG reports personal fees from Biogen, ITF Pharma, and Watermark, outside the submitted work. SP reports grants from the German Neuromuscular Society, the German-Israeli Foundation for Scientific Research and Development (GIF), and personal fees from Cytokinetics, Desitin Pharma, Italfarmaco, Biogen, Roche, and Zambon outside the submitted work. PJS reports consultancy and advisory board membership with Biogen, Benevolent AI, QurALIS, Quell, and Aclipse Therapeutics, outside the submitted work. GS reports personal fees from Mitsubishi Tanabe Pharma Corporation, Cyberdyne, Biogen Japan, Takeda Pharmaceutical, Nihon Pharmaceutical, and Teijin Pharma, outside the submitted work. LM and MGS declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36116464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS1888207</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10089700</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(22)01272-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0140-6736(22)01272-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ryan M, Heverin M, McLaughlin RL, Hardiman O. Lifetime Risk and Heritability of Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. JAMA Neurol. 2019;76(11):1367&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6646974</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31329211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goutman SA, Hardiman O, Al-Chalabi A, Chi&#xf3; A, Savelieff MG, Kiernan MC, et al. Recent advances in the diagnosis and prognosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet Neurol. 2022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9513753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35334233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marin B, Fontana A, Arcuti S, Copetti M, Boum&#xe9;diene F, Couratier P, et al. Age-specific ALS incidence: a dose-response meta-analysis. Eur J Epidemiol. 2018;33(7):621&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29687175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehta P, Kaye W, Raymond J, Punjani R, Larson T, Cohen J, et al. Prevalence of Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis - United States, 2015. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2018;67(46):1285&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6289079</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30462626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luna J, Diagana M, Ait Aissa L, Tazir M, Ali Pacha L, Kacem I, et al. Clinical features and prognosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in Africa: the TROPALS study. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2019;90(1):20&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30242088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feigin VL, Vos T, Alahdab F, Amit AML, B&#xe4;rnighausen TW, Beghi E, et al. Burden of Neurological Disorders Across the US From 1990&#x2013;2017: A Global Burden of Disease Study. JAMA Neurol. 2021;78(2):165&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7607495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33136137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu L, Liu T, Liu L, Yao X, Chen L, Fan D, et al. Global variation in prevalence and incidence of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Neurol. 2020;267(4):944&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31797084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arthur KC, Calvo A, Price TR, Geiger JT, Chio A, Traynor BJ. Projected increase in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis from 2015 to 2040. Nat Commun. 2016;7:12408.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4987527</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27510634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gowland A, Opie-Martin S, Scott KM, Jones AR, Mehta PR, Batts CJ, et al. Predicting the future of ALS: the impact of demographic change and potential new treatments on the prevalence of ALS in the United Kingdom, 2020&#x2013;2116. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2019;20(3&#x2013;4):264&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6567553</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30961394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marin B, Boumediene F, Logroscino G, Couratier P, Babron MC, Leutenegger AL, et al. Variation in worldwide incidence of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a meta-analysis. Int J Epidemiol. 2017;46(1):57&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5407171</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27185810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longinetti E, Fang F. Epidemiology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: an update of recent literature. Curr Opin Neurol. 2019;32(5):771&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6735526</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31361627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fontana A, Marin B, Luna J, Beghi E, Logroscino G, Boum&#xe9;diene F, et al. Time-trend evolution and determinants of sex ratio in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis: a dose-response meta-analysis. J Neurol. 2021;268(8):2973&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33630135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy NA, Arthur KC, Tienari PJ, Houlden H, Chio A, Traynor BJ. Age-related penetrance of the C9orf72 repeat expansion. Sci Rep. 2017;7(1):2116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5437033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28522837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chio A, Moglia C, Canosa A, Manera U, D&#x2019;Ovidio F, Vasta R, et al. ALS phenotype is influenced by age, sex, and genetics: A population-based study. Neurology. 2020;94(8):e802&#x2013;e10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31907290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang T, Jozsa F, Al-Chalabi A. Nonmotor Symptoms in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis: A Systematic Review. Int Rev Neurobiol. 2017;134:1409&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28805578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walhout R, Verstraete E, van den Heuvel MP, Veldink JH, van den Berg LH. Patterns of symptom development in patients with motor neuron disease. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2018;19(1&#x2013;2):21&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29037065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2; A, Calvo A, Moglia C, Mazzini L, Mora G. Phenotypic heterogeneity of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a population based study. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2011;82(7):740&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21402743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenbohm A, Liu M, Nagel G, Peter RS, Cui B, Li X, et al. Phenotypic differences of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) in China and Germany. J Neurol. 2018;265(4):774&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29392461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beeldman E, Govaarts R, de Visser M, Klein Twennaar M, van der Kooi AJ, van den Berg LH, et al. Progression of cognitive and behavioural impairment in early amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 91 2020. p. 779&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7361007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32404381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pender N, Pinto-Grau M, Hardiman O. Cognitive and behavioural impairment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Curr Opin Neurol. 2020;33(5):649&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32833751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crockford C, Newton J, Lonergan K, Chiwera T, Booth T, Chandran S, et al. ALS-specific cognitive and behavior changes associated with advancing disease stage in ALS. Neurology. 2018;91(15):e1370&#x2013;e80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6177274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30209236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bersano E, Sarnelli MF, Solara V, Iazzolino B, Peotta L, De Marchi F, et al. Decline of cognitive and behavioral functions in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a longitudinal study. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2020;21(5&#x2013;6):373&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32484726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ringholz GM, Appel SH, Bradshaw M, Cooke NA, Mosnik DM, Schulz PE. Prevalence and patterns of cognitive impairment in sporadic ALS. Neurology. 2005;65(4):586&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16116120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicholson K, Murphy A, McDonnell E, Shapiro J, Simpson E, Glass J, et al. Improving symptom management for people with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 2018;57(1):20&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28561886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gregory JM, McDade K, Bak TH, Pal S, Chandran S, Smith C, et al. Executive, language and fluency dysfunction are markers of localised TDP-43 cerebral pathology in non-demented ALS. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2020;91(2):149&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6996101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31515300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iazzolino B, Peotta L, Zucchetti JP, Canosa A, Manera U, Vasta R, et al. Differential Neuropsychological Profile of Patients With Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis With and Without C9orf72 Mutation. Neurology. 2021;96(1):e141&#x2013;e52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33106391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang T, Hou Y, Li C, Cao B, Cheng Y, Wei Q, et al. Risk factors for cognitive impairment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2021;92(7):688&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33563800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basaia S, Agosta F, Cividini C, Trojsi F, Riva N, Spinelli EG, et al. Structural and functional brain connectome in motor neuron diseases: A multicenter MRI study. Neurology. 2020;95(18):e2552&#x2013;e64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7682834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32913015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams JR, Fitzhenry D, Grant L, Martyn D, Kerr DA. Diagnosis pathway for patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: retrospective analysis of the US Medicare longitudinal claims database. BMC Neurol. 2013;13:160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4029731</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24499173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Falc&#xe3;o de Campos C, Gromicho M, Uysal H, Grosskreutz J, Kuzma-Kozakiewicz M, Oliveira Santos M, et al. Delayed Diagnosis and Diagnostic Pathway of ALS Patients in Portugal: Where Can We Improve? Front Neurol. 2021;12:761355.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8596501</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34803894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>  https://www.als.org/thinkals/thinkals-tool.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, Miller RG, Swash M, Munsat TL. El Escorial revisited: revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord. 2000;1(5):293&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11464847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babu S, Pioro EP, Li J, Li Y. Optimizing muscle selection for electromyography in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 2017;56(1):36&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27759887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shayya L, Babu S, Pioro EP, Li J, Li Y. Distal Predominance of Electrodiagnostic Abnormalities in Early-Stage Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 2018;58(3):389&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29742797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shefner JM, Al-Chalabi A, Baker MR, Cui LY, de Carvalho M, Eisen A, et al. A proposal for new diagnostic criteria for ALS. Clinical neurophysiology : official journal of the International Federation of Clinical Neurophysiology. 2020;131(8):1975&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32387049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strong MJ, Abrahams S, Goldstein LH, Woolley S, McLaughlin P, Snowden J, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis - frontotemporal spectrum disorder (ALS-FTSD): Revised diagnostic criteria. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2017;18(3&#x2013;4):153&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7409990</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28054827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gosselt IK, Nijboer TCW, Van Es MA. An overview of screening instruments for cognition and behavior in patients with ALS: selecting the appropriate tool for clinical practice. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2020;21(5&#x2013;6):324&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32157912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neary D, Snowden JS, Gustafson L, Passant U, Stuss D, Black S, et al. Frontotemporal lobar degeneration: a consensus on clinical diagnostic criteria. Neurology. 1998;51(6):1546&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9855500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rascovsky K, Hodges JR, Knopman D, Mendez MF, Kramer JH, Neuhaus J, et al. Sensitivity of revised diagnostic criteria for the behavioural variant of frontotemporal dementia. Brain. 2011;134(Pt 9):2456&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3170532</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21810890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hodgins F, Mulhern S, Abrahams S. The clinical impact of the Edinburgh Cognitive and Behavioural ALS Screen (ECAS) and neuropsychological intervention in routine ALS care. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2020;21(1&#x2013;2):92&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31612737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goutman SA, Hardiman O, Al-Chalabi A, Chi&#xf3; A, Savelieff MG, Kiernan MC, et al. Emerging insights into the complex genetics and pathophysiology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet Neurol. 2022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9513754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35334234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Chalabi A, Lewis CM. Modelling the effects of penetrance and family size on rates of sporadic and familial disease. Hum Hered. 2011;71(4):281&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21846995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan M, Heverin M, Doherty MA, Davis N, Corr EM, Vajda A, et al. Determining the incidence of familiality in ALS: A study of temporal trends in Ireland from 1994 to 2016. Neurol Genet. 2018;4(3):e239.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5961194</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29845113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cady J, Allred P, Bali T, Pestronk A, Goate A, Miller TM, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis onset is influenced by the burden of rare variants in known amyotrophic lateral sclerosis genes. Ann Neurol. 2015;77(1):100&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4293318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25382069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chia R, Chio A, Traynor BJ. Novel genes associated with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: diagnostic and clinical implications. Lancet Neurol. 2018;17(1):94&#x2013;102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5901717</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29154141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goutman SA, Chen KS, Paez-Colasante X, Feldman EL. Emerging understanding of the genotype-phenotype relationship in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Handbook of clinical neurology. 2018;148:603&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29478603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zou ZY, Zhou ZR, Che CH, Liu CY, He RL, Huang HP. Genetic epidemiology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2017;88(7):540&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28057713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gregory JM, Fagegaltier D, Phatnani H, Harms MB. Genetics of Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. Current Genetic Medicine Reports. 2020;8(4):121&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rehm HL, Berg JS, Brooks LD, Bustamante CD, Evans JP, Landrum MJ, et al. ClinGen--the Clinical Genome Resource. N Engl J Med. 2015;372(23):2235&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4474187</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26014595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCann EP, Henden L, Fifita JA, Zhang KY, Grima N, Bauer DC, et al. Evidence for polygenic and oligogenic basis of Australian sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Med Genet. 2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32409511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shepheard SR, Parker MD, Cooper-Knock J, Verber NS, Tuddenham L, Heath P, et al. Value of systematic genetic screening of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2021;92(5):510&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8053339</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33589474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bandres-Ciga S, Noyce AJ, Hemani G, Nicolas A, Calvo A, Mora G, et al. Shared polygenic risk and causal inferences in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Annals of neurology. 2019;85(4):470&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6450729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30723964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li C, Ou R, Wei Q, Shang H. Shared genetic links between amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and obesity-related traits: a genome-wide association study. Neurobiol Aging. 2021;102:211 e1&#x2013;e9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33640203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicolas A, Kenna KP, Renton AE, Ticozzi N, Faghri F, Chia R, et al. Genome-wide Analyses Identify KIF5A as a Novel ALS Gene. Neuron. 2018;97(6):1268&#x2013;83 e6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5867896</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29566793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saez-Atienzar S, Bandres-Ciga S, Langston RG, Kim JJ, Choi SW, Reynolds RH, et al. Genetic analysis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis identifies contributing pathways and cell types. Sci Adv. 2021;7(3).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7810371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33523907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dekker AM, Diekstra FP, Pulit SL, Tazelaar GHP, van der Spek RA, van Rheenen W, et al. Exome array analysis of rare and low frequency variants in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Sci Rep. 2019;9(1):5931.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6459905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30976013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Theunissen F, Flynn LL, Anderton RS, Mastaglia F, Pytte J, Jiang L, et al. Structural Variants May Be a Source of Missing Heritability in sALS. Front Neurosci. 2020;14:47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7005198</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32082115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang S, Cooper-Knock J, Weimer AK, Shi M, Moll T, Marshall JNG, et al. Genome-wide identification of the genetic basis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuron. 2022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9017397</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35045337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goutman SA, Feldman EL. Voicing the Need for Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Environmental Research. JAMA Neurol. 2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7977264</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32119032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Chalabi A, Hardiman O. The epidemiology of ALS: a conspiracy of genes, environment and time. Nature reviews Neurology. 2013;9(11):617&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24126629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S, Higashihara M, Sobue G, Atsuta N, Doi Y, Kuwabara S, et al. ALS is a multistep process in South Korean, Japanese, and Australian patients. Neurology. 2020;94(15):e1657&#x2013;e63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7251515</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32071166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen PM, Abrahams S, Borasio GD, de Carvalho M, Chio A, Van Damme P, et al. EFNS guidelines on the clinical management of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (MALS)--revised report of an EFNS task force. Eur J Neurol. 2012;19(3):360&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21914052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goutman SA. Diagnosis and Clinical Management of Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis and Other Motor Neuron Disorders. Continuum (Minneap Minn). 2017;23(5, Peripheral Nerve and Motor Neuron Disorders):1332&#x2013;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28968365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Estevez-Fraga C, Magrinelli F, Hensman Moss D, Mulroy E, Di Lazzaro G, Latorre A, et al. Expanding the Spectrum of Movement Disorders Associated With C9orf72 Hexanucleotide Expansions. Neurol Genet. 2021;7(2):e575.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8105892</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33977144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooper-Knock J, Frolov A, Highley JR, Charlesworth G, Kirby J, Milano A, et al. C9ORF72 expansions, parkinsonism, and Parkinson disease: a clinicopathologic study. Neurology. 2013;81(9):808&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3908460</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23884045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hensman Moss DJ, Poulter M, Beck J, Hehir J, Polke JM, Campbell T, et al. C9orf72 expansions are the most common genetic cause of Huntington disease phenocopies. Neurology. 2014;82(4):292&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3929197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24363131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dewan R, Chia R, Ding J, Hickman RA, Stein TD, Abramzon Y, et al. Pathogenic Huntingtin Repeat Expansions in Patients with Frontotemporal Dementia and Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. Neuron. 2021;109(3):448&#x2013;60 e4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7864894</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33242422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Brien M, Burke T, Heverin M, Vajda A, McLaughlin R, Gibbons J, et al. Clustering of Neuropsychiatric Disease in First-Degree and Second-Degree Relatives of Patients With Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. JAMA Neurol. 2017;74(12):1425&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5822189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29049464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devenney EM, Ahmed RM, Halliday G, Piguet O, Kiernan MC, Hodges JR. Psychiatric disorders in C9orf72 kindreds: Study of 1,414 family members. Neurology. 2018;91(16):e1498&#x2013;e507.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30258023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westeneng HJ, Debray TPA, Visser AE, van Eijk RPA, Rooney JPK, Calvo A, et al. Prognosis for patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: development and validation of a personalised prediction model. The Lancet Neurology. 2018;17(5):423&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29598923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang MD, Little J, Gomes J, Cashman NR, Krewski D. Identification of risk factors associated with onset and progression of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis using systematic review and meta-analysis. Neurotoxicology. 2017;61:101&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27377857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goutman SA, Boss J, Patterson A, Mukherjee B, Batterman S, Feldman EL. High plasma concentrations of organic pollutants negatively impact survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Journal of neurology, neurosurgery, and psychiatry. 2019;90(8):907&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6625908</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30760645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benatar M, Wuu J, McHutchison C, Postuma RB, Boeve BF, Petersen R, et al. Preventing amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: insights from pre-symptomatic neurodegenerative diseases. Brain. 2022;145(1):27&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8967095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34677606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackenzie IR, Rademakers R, Neumann M. TDP-43 and FUS in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal dementia. Lancet Neurol. 2010;9(10):995&#x2013;1007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20864052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen HP, Van Broeckhoven C, van der Zee J. ALS Genes in the Genomic Era and their Implications for FTD. Trends Genet. 2018;34(6):404&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29605155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pokrishevsky E, Grad LI, Cashman NR. TDP-43 or FUS-induced misfolded human wild-type SOD1 can propagate intercellularly in a prion-like fashion. Sci Rep. 2016;6:22155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4772009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26926802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sackmann C, Sackmann V, Hallbeck M. TDP-43 Is Efficiently Transferred Between Neuron-Like Cells in a Manner Enhanced by Preservation of Its N-Terminus but Independent of Extracellular Vesicles. Front Neurosci. 2020;14:540.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7301158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32595443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitra J, Guerrero EN, Hegde PM, Liachko NF, Wang H, Vasquez V, et al. Motor neuron disease-associated loss of nuclear TDP-43 is linked to DNA double-strand break repair defects. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2019;116(10):4696&#x2013;705.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6410842</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30770445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chou CC, Zhang Y, Umoh ME, Vaughan SW, Lorenzini I, Liu F, et al. TDP-43 pathology disrupts nuclear pore complexes and nucleocytoplasmic transport in ALS/FTD. Nat Neurosci. 2018;21(2):228&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5800968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29311743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin YC, Kumar MS, Ramesh N, Anderson EN, Nguyen AT, Kim B, et al. Interactions between ALS-linked FUS and nucleoporins are associated with defects in the nucleocytoplasmic transport pathway. Nat Neurosci. 2021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8832378</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34059832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freibaum BD, Lu Y, Lopez-Gonzalez R, Kim NC, Almeida S, Lee KH, et al. GGGGCC repeat expansion in C9orf72 compromises nucleocytoplasmic transport. Nature. 2015;525(7567):129&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4631399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26308899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang YJ, Guo L, Gonzales PK, Gendron TF, Wu Y, Jansen-West K, et al. Heterochromatin anomalies and double-stranded RNA accumulation underlie C9orf72 poly(PR) toxicity. Science. 2019;363(6428).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6524780</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30765536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook CN, Wu Y, Odeh HM, Gendron TF, Jansen-West K, Del Rosso G, et al. C9orf72 poly(GR) aggregation induces TDP-43 proteinopathy. Sci Transl Med. 2020;12(559).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7989020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32878979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beers DR, Appel SH. Immune dysregulation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: mechanisms and emerging therapies. Lancet Neurol. 2019;18(2):211&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30663610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coque E, Salsac C, Espinosa-Carrasco G, Varga B, Degauque N, Cadoux M, et al. Cytotoxic CD8(+) T lymphocytes expressing ALS-causing SOD1 mutant selectively trigger death of spinal motoneurons. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2019;116(6):2312&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6369778</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30674678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCauley ME, O&#x2019;Rourke JG, Y&#xe1;&#xf1;ez A, Markman JL, Ho R, Wang X, et al. C9orf72 in myeloid cells suppresses STING-induced inflammation. Nature. 2020;585(7823):96&#x2013;101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7484469</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32814898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu CH, Davidson S, Harapas CR, Hilton JB, Mlodzianoski MJ, Laohamonthonkul P, et al. TDP-43 Triggers Mitochondrial DNA Release via mPTP to Activate cGAS/STING in ALS. Cell. 2020;183(3):636&#x2013;49.e18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7599077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33031745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murdock BJ, Famie JP, Piecuch CE, Raue KD, Mendelson FE, Pieroni CH, et al. Natural killer cells associate with amyotrophic lateral sclersois in a sex- and age-dependent manner. JCI Insight. 2021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8262328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33974561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murdock BJ, Zhou T, Kashlan SR, Little RJ, Goutman SA, Feldman EL. Correlation of Peripheral Immunity With Rapid Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Progression. JAMA neurology. 2017;74(12):1446&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5822195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28973548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guillot SJ, Bolborea M, Dupuis L. Dysregulation of energy homeostasis in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Curr Opin Neurol. 2021;34(5):773&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34343139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goutman SA, Guo K, Savelieff MG, Patterson A, Sakowski SA, Habra H, et al. Metabolomics identifies shared lipid pathways in independent amyotrophic lateral sclerosis cohorts. Brain. 2022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9762943</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35088843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLaughlin R, Vajda A, Hardiman O. Heritability of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Insights from disparate numbers. JAMA neurology. 2015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26029874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chio A, Mazzini L, D&#x2019;Alfonso S, Corrado L, Canosa A, Moglia C, et al. The multistep hypothesis of ALS revisited: The role of genetic mutations. Neurology. 2018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6105040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30045958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su FC, Goutman SA, Chernyak S, Mukherjee B, Callaghan BC, Batterman S, et al. Association of Environmental Toxins With Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. JAMA Neurol. 2016;73(7):803&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5032145</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27159543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peters S, Broberg K, Gallo V, Levi M, Kippler M, Vineis P, et al. Blood Metal Levels and Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Risk: A Prospective Cohort. Ann Neurol. 2021;89(1):125&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7756568</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33068316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Figueroa-Romero C, Mikhail KA, Gennings C, Curtin P, Bello GA, Botero TM, et al. Early life metal dysregulation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Clin Transl Neurol. 2020;7(6):872&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7318091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32438517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westeneng HJ, van Veenhuijzen K, van der Spek RA, Peters S, Visser AE, van Rheenen W, et al. Associations between lifestyle and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis stratified by C9orf72 genotype: a longitudinal, population-based, case-control study. Lancet Neurol. 2021;20(5):373&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33894192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Julian TH, Glascow N, Barry ADF, Moll T, Harvey C, Klimentidis YC, et al. Physical exercise is a risk factor for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Convergent evidence from Mendelian randomisation, transcriptomics and risk genotypes. EBioMedicine. 2021;68:103397.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8170114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34051439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daneshvar DH, Mez J, Alosco ML, Baucom ZH, Mahar I, Baugh CM, et al. Incidence of and Mortality From Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis in National Football League Athletes. JAMA Netw Open. 2021;4(12):e2138801.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8674746</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34910152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKay KA, Smith KA, Smertinaite L, Fang F, Ingre C, Taube F. Military service and related risk factors for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neurol Scand. 2021;143(1):39&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7756624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32905613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Eijk RPA, de Jongh AD, Nikolakopoulos S, McDermott CJ, Eijkemans MJC, Roes KCB, et al. An old friend who has overstayed their welcome: the ALSFRS-R total score as primary endpoint for ALS clinical trials. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2021;22(3&#x2013;4):300&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33527843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pirola A, De Mattia E, Lizio A, Sannicol&#xf2; G, Carraro E, Rao F, et al. The prognostic value of spirometric tests in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis patients. Clin Neurol Neurosurg. 2019;184:105456.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31382080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fournier CN, Bedlack R, Quinn C, Russell J, Beckwith D, Kaminski KH, et al. Development and Validation of the Rasch-Built Overall Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Disability Scale (ROADS). JAMA neurology. 2019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6990811</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31886839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roche JC, Rojas-Garcia R, Scott KM, Scotton W, Ellis CE, Burman R, et al. A proposed staging system for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain : a journal of neurology. 2012;135(Pt 3):847&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3286327</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22271664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2; A, Hammond ER, Mora G, Bonito V, Filippini G. Development and evaluation of a clinical staging system for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2015;86(1):38&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24336810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang T, Al Khleifat A, Stahl DR, Lazo La Torre C, Murphy C, Young C, et al. Comparison of the King&#x2019;s and MiToS staging systems for ALS. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2017;18(3&#x2013;4):227&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5425622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28054828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luna J, Couratier P, Lahmadi S, Lautrette G, Fontana A, Tortelli R, et al. Comparison of the ability of the King&#x2019;s and MiToS staging systems to predict disease progression and survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2021:1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33829938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>  https://www.nice.org.uk/guidance/ng42 [</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>  https://www.cmaj.ca/content/cmaj/192/46/E1453.full.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klav&#x17e;ar P, Koritnik B, Leonardis L, Dolenc Gro&#x161;elj L, Kirbi&#x161; M, Risti&#x107; Kova&#x10d;i&#x10d; S, et al. Improvements in the multidisciplinary care are beneficial for survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS): experience from a tertiary ALS center. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2020;21(3&#x2013;4):203&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32248716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller RG, Jackson CE, Kasarskis EJ, England JD, Forshew D, Johnston W, et al. Practice parameter update: the care of the patient with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: multidisciplinary care, symptom management, and cognitive/behavioral impairment (an evidence-based review): report of the Quality Standards Subcommittee of the American Academy of Neurology. Neurology. 2009;73(15):1227&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2764728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19822873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller RG, Jackson CE, Kasarskis EJ, England JD, Forshew D, Johnston W, et al. Practice parameter update: the care of the patient with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: drug, nutritional, and respiratory therapies (an evidence-based review): report of the Quality Standards Subcommittee of the American Academy of Neurology. Neurology. 2009;73(15):1218&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2764727</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19822872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller RG, Brooks BR, Swain-Eng RJ, Basner RC, Carter GT, Casey P, et al. Quality improvement in neurology: amyotrophic lateral sclerosis quality measures: report of the quality measurement and reporting subcommittee of the American Academy of Neurology. Neurology. 2013;81(24):2136&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3863352</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24271651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shoesmith C, Abrahao A, Benstead T, Chum M, Dupre N, Izenberg A, et al. Canadian best practice recommendations for the management of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Cmaj. 2020;192(46):E1453&#x2013;e68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7683000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33199452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fearon C, Murray B, Mitsumoto H. Disorders of Upper and Lower Motor Neurons, Chapter 97. In: Jankovic, Joseph, Mazziotta CJ, Pomeroy LS, et al., editors. Bradley and Daroff&#x2019;s Neurology in Clinical Practice. 8th ed: Elsevier; 2022. p. 1535&#x2013;67.e5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang T, Al Khleifat A, Meurgey JH, Jones A, Leigh PN, Bensimon G, et al. Stage at which riluzole treatment prolongs survival in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a retrospective analysis of data from a dose-ranging study. Lancet Neurol. 2018;17(5):416&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5899963</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29525492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrews JA, Jackson CE, Heiman-Patterson TD, Bettica P, Brooks BR, Pioro EP. Real-world evidence of riluzole effectiveness in treating amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2020;21(7&#x2013;8):509&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32573277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shefner J, Heiman-Patterson T, Pioro EP, Wiedau-Pazos M, Liu S, Zhang J, et al. Long-term edaravone efficacy in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Post-hoc analyses of Study 19 (MCI186&#x2013;19). Muscle Nerve. 2020;61(2):218&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7004197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31621933</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lunetta C, Moglia C, Lizio A, Caponnetto C, Dubbioso R, Giannini F, et al. The Italian multicenter experience with edaravone in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol. 2020;267(11):3258&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32556567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Witzel S, Maier A, Steinbach R, Grosskreutz J, Koch JC, Sarikidi A, et al. Safety and Effectiveness of Long-term Intravenous Administration of Edaravone for Treatment of Patients With Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. JAMA Neurol. 2022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8749709</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35006266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A post-hoc subgroup analysis of outcomes in the first phase III clinical study of edaravone (MCI-186) in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2017;18(sup1):11&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28872917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Safety and efficacy of edaravone in well defined patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Lancet Neurol. 2017;16(7):505&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28522181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, Thisted RA, Appel SH, Bradley WG, Olney RK, Berg JE, et al. Treatment of pseudobulbar affect in ALS with dextromethorphan/quinidine: a randomized trial. Neurology. 2004;63(8):1364&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15505150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radunovic A, Annane D, Rafiq MK, Brassington R, Mustfa N. Mechanical ventilation for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis/motor neuron disease. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2017;10(10):Cd004427.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6485636</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28982219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niedermeyer S, Murn M, Choi PJ. Respiratory Failure in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. Chest. 2019;155(2):401&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29990478</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf3;pez-G&#xf3;mez JJ, Ballesteros-Pomar MD, Torres-Torres B, Pintor-De la Maza B, Penacho-L&#xe1;zaro MA, Palacio-Mures JM, et al. Impact of Percutaneous Endoscopic Gastrostomy (PEG) on the Evolution of Disease in Patients with Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis (ALS). Nutrients. 2021;13(8).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8401888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34444925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hesters A, Amador MDM, Debs R, Le Forestier N, Lenglet T, Pradat PF, et al. Predictive factors for prognosis after gastrostomy placement in routine non-invasive ventilation users ALS patients. Sci Rep. 2020;10(1):15117.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7492246</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32934263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ludolph AC, Dorst J, Dreyhaupt J, Weishaupt JH, Kassubek J, Weiland U, et al. Effect of High-Caloric Nutrition on Survival in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. Ann Neurol. 2020;87(2):206&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31849093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiernan MC, Vucic S, Talbot K, McDermott CJ, Hardiman O, Shefner JM, et al. Improving clinical trial outcomes in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nature reviews Neurology. 2021;17(2):104&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7747476</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33340024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Eijk RPA, Nikolakopoulos S, Roes KCB, Kendall L, Han SS, Lavrov A, et al. Innovating Clinical Trials for Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis: Challenging the Established Order. Neurology. 2021;97(11):528&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8456357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34315786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller T, Cudkowicz M, Shaw PJ, Andersen PM, Atassi N, Bucelli RC, et al. Phase 1&#x2013;2 Trial of Antisense Oligonucleotide Tofersen for SOD1 ALS. The New England journal of medicine. 2020;383(2):109&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32640130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mullard A ALS antisense drug falters in phase III. Nat Rev Drug Discov. 20. England 2021. p. 883&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34716445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amado DA, Davidson BL. Gene therapy for ALS: A review. Mol Ther. 2021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8636154</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33839324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poulin-Bri&#xe8;re A, Rezaei E, Pozzi S. Antibody-Based Therapeutic Interventions for Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis: A Systematic Literature Review. Front Neurosci. 2021;15:790114.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8667723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34912191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Camu W, Mickunas M, Veyrune JL, Payan C, Garlanda C, Locati M, et al. Repeated 5-day cycles of low dose aldesleukin in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (IMODALS): A phase 2a randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. EBioMedicine. 2020;59:102844.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7502670</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32651161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thonhoff JR, Beers DR, Zhao W, Pleitez M, Simpson EP, Berry JD, et al. Expanded autologous regulatory T-lymphocyte infusions in ALS: A phase I, first-in-human study. Neurol Neuroimmunol Neuroinflamm. 2018;5(4):e465.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5961523</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29845093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mora JS, Genge A, Chio A, Estol CJ, Chaverri D, Hern&#xe1;ndez M, et al. Masitinib as an add-on therapy to riluzole in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a randomized clinical trial. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2020;21(1&#x2013;2):5&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31280619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goutman SA, Savelieff MG, Sakowski SA, Feldman EL. Stem cell treatments for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a critical overview of early phase trials. Expert Opin Investig Drugs. 2019;28(6):525&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6697143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31189354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morata-Tarifa C, Azkona G, Glass J, Mazzini L, Sanchez-Pernaute R. Looking backward to move forward: a meta-analysis of stem cell therapy in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. NPJ Regen Med. 2021;6(1):20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8016966</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33795700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang F, Zhu Y, Hsiao-Nakamoto J, Tang X, Dugas JC, Moscovitch-Lopatin M, et al. Longitudinal biomarkers in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Clin Transl Neurol. 2020;7(7):1103&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7359115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32515902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poesen K, De Schaepdryver M, Stubendorff B, Gille B, Muckova P, Wendler S, et al. Neurofilament markers for ALS correlate with extent of upper and lower motor neuron disease. Neurology. 2017;88(24):2302&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28500227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benatar M, Zhang L, Wang L, Granit V, Statland J, Barohn R, et al. Validation of serum neurofilaments as prognostic and potential pharmacodynamic biomarkers for ALS. Neurology. 2020;95(1):e59&#x2013;e69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7371380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32385188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benatar M, Wuu J, Andersen PM, Lombardi V, Malaspina A. Neurofilament light: A candidate biomarker of presymptomatic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and phenoconversion. Annals of neurology. 2018;84(1):130&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30014505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bjornevik K, O&#x2019;Reilly EJ, Molsberry S, Kolonel LN, Le Marchand L, Paganoni S, et al. Prediagnostic Neurofilament Light Chain Levels in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. Neurology. 2021;97(15):e1466&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8575132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34380747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dorst J, Schuster J, Dreyhaupt J, Witzel S, Weishaupt JH, Kassubek J, et al. Effect of high-caloric nutrition on serum neurofilament light chain levels in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 91. England 2020. p. 1007&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32788256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fabes J, Matthews L, Filippini N, Talbot K, Jenkinson M, Turner MR. Quantitative FLAIR MRI in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. Acad Radiol. 2017;24(10):1187&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5605225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28572001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weidman EK, Schweitzer AD, Niogi SN, Brady EJ, Starikov A, Askin G, et al. Diffusion tensor imaging and quantitative susceptibility mapping as diagnostic tools for motor neuron disorders. Clin Imaging. 2019;53:6&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30286313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Welton T, Maller JJ, Lebel RM, Tan ET, Rowe DB, Grieve SM. Diffusion kurtosis and quantitative susceptibility mapping MRI are sensitive to structural abnormalities in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuroimage Clin. 2019;24:101953.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6664242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31357149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acosta-Cabronero J, Machts J, Schreiber S, Abdulla S, Kollewe K, Petri S, et al. Quantitative Susceptibility MRI to Detect Brain Iron in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. Radiology. 2018;289(1):195&#x2013;203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6166868</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30040038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bertrand A, Wen J, Rinaldi D, Houot M, Sayah S, Camuzat A, et al. Early Cognitive, Structural, and Microstructural Changes in Presymptomatic C9orf72 Carriers Younger Than 40 Years. JAMA Neurol. 2018;75(2):236&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5838615</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29197216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#x2019;Hulst L, Van Weehaeghe D, Chio A, Calvo A, Moglia C, Canosa A, et al. Multicenter validation of [(18)F]-FDG PET and support-vector machine discriminant analysis in automatically classifying patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis versus controls. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2018;19(7&#x2013;8):570&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29862846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alshikho MJ, Zurcher NR, Loggia ML, Cernasov P, Reynolds B, Pijanowski O, et al. Integrated magnetic resonance imaging and [(11) C]-PBR28 positron emission tomographic imaging in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol. 2018;83(6):1186&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6105567</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29740862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dukic S, McMackin R, Buxo T, Fasano A, Chipika R, Pinto-Grau M, et al. Patterned functional network disruption in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Hum Brain Mapp. 2019;40(16):4827&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6852475</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31348605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nasseroleslami B, Dukic S, Broderick M, Mohr K, Schuster C, Gavin B, et al. Characteristic Increases in EEG Connectivity Correlate With Changes of Structural MRI in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. Cereb Cortex. 2019;29(1):27&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29136131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sorrentino P, Rucco R, Jacini F, Trojsi F, Lardone A, Baselice F, et al. Brain functional networks become more connected as amyotrophic lateral sclerosis progresses: a source level magnetoencephalographic study. Neuroimage Clin. 2018;20:564&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6120607</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30186760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huynh W, Dharmadasa T, Vucic S, Kiernan MC. Functional Biomarkers for Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. Front Neurol. 2018;9:1141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6328463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30662429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menon P, Yiannikas C, Kiernan MC, Vucic S. Regional motor cortex dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Clin Transl Neurol. 2019;6(8):1373&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6689694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31402622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higashihara M, Pavey N, van den Bos M, Menon P, Kiernan MC, Vucic S. Association of Cortical Hyperexcitability and Cognitive Impairment in Patients With Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. Neurology. 2021;96(16):e2090&#x2013;e7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33827958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menon P, Higashihara M, van den Bos M, Geevasinga N, Kiernan MC, Vucic S. Cortical hyperexcitability evolves with disease progression in ALS. Ann Clin Transl Neurol. 2020;7(5):733&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7261748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32304186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dharmadasa T, Howells J, Matamala JM, Simon NG, Burke D, Vucic S, et al. Cortical inexcitability defines an adverse clinical profile in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Eur J Neurol. 2021;28(1):90&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7820947</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32902860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wainger BJ, Macklin EA, Vucic S, McIlduff CE, Paganoni S, Maragakis NJ, et al. Effect of Ezogabine on Cortical and Spinal Motor Neuron Excitability in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis: A Randomized Clinical Trial. JAMA Neurol. 2021;78(2):186&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7684515</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33226425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neuwirth C, Braun N, Claeys KG, Bucelli R, Fournier C, Bromberg M, et al. Implementing Motor Unit Number Index (MUNIX) in a large clinical trial: Real world experience from 27 centres. Clin Neurophysiol. 2018;129(8):1756&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29803404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>