<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36169607</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1468-1331</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>30</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Mutation-specific metabolic profiles in presymptomatic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>87</StartPage><EndPage>95</EndPage><MedlinePgn>87-95</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/ene.15584</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND PURPOSE">Growing evidence shows that ALS patients feature a disturbed energy metabolism. However, these features have rarely been investigated in the presymptomatic stage.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">A total of 60 presymptomatic ALS mutation carriers and 70 age- and gender-matched controls (non-mutation carriers from the same families) were recruited. All subjects underwent assessments of their metabolic profiles under fasting conditions at enrollment, including body mass index (BMI), blood pressure and serum levels of blood glucose, total cholesterol, triglycerides, high-density lipoprotein (HDL) and low-density lipoprotein.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">All mutations combined, no differences between presymptomatic ALS gene carriers and controls were found. From a cardiovascular point of view, presymptomatic chromosome 9 open reading frame 72 (C9ORF72) gene carriers showed lower cardiovascular risk profiles compared to healthy controls, including lower BMI (median 22.9, interquartile range [IQR] 20.6-26.1 kg/m<sup>2</sup> vs. 24.9, IQR 22.7-30.5 kg/m<sup>2</sup> ; p&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.007), lower systolic blood pressure (120, IQR 110-130&#x2009;mmHg vs. 128, IQR 120-140&#x2009;mmHg; p&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.02), lower fasting serum glucose (89.0, IQR 85.0-97.0 mg/dl vs. 96.0, IQR 89.3-102.0 mg/dl; p&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.005) and higher HDL (1.6, IQR 1.3-1.8&#x2009;mmol/l vs. 1.2, IQR 1.0-1.4&#x2009;mmol/l; p&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.04). However, presymptomatic superoxide dismutase 1 (SOD1) gene mutation carriers showed higher cardiovascular risk profiles compared to healthy controls, including higher BMI (28.0,&#xa0;IQR 26.1-31.5 kg/m<sup>2</sup> vs. 24.9, IQR 22.7-30.5 kg/m<sup>2</sup> ; p&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.02), higher fasting serum glucose (100.0, IQR 94.0-117.0 mg/dl vs. 96.0, IQR 89.3-102.0 mg/dl; p&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.04) and lower HDL (1.2, IQR 1.0-1.4&#x2009;mmol/l vs. 1.4, IQR 1.2-1.7&#x2009;mmol/l; p&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.01). These features were most prominent in patients carrying SOD1 gene mutations associated with slow disease progression.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">This study identified distinct metabolic profiles in presymptomatic ALS gene carriers, which might be associated with disease progression in the symptomatic phase.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022 The Authors. European Journal of Neurology published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of European Academy of Neurology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xia</LastName><ForeName>Kailin</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Peking University Third Hospital, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Beijing Key Laboratory of Biomarker and Translational Research in Neurodegenerative Diseases, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory for Neuroscience, National Health Commission/Ministry of Education, Peking University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Ulm University, Ulm, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Witzel</LastName><ForeName>Simon</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Ulm University, Ulm, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Witzel</LastName><ForeName>Christina</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Ulm University, Ulm, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Klose</LastName><ForeName>Veronika</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>German Center for Neurodegenerative Diseases (DZNE), Ulm, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fan</LastName><ForeName>Dongsheng</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6679-0864</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Peking University Third Hospital, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Beijing Key Laboratory of Biomarker and Translational Research in Neurodegenerative Diseases, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory for Neuroscience, National Health Commission/Ministry of Education, Peking University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ludolph</LastName><ForeName>Albert C</ForeName><Initials>AC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Ulm University, Ulm, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>German Center for Neurodegenerative Diseases (DZNE), Ulm, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dorst</LastName><ForeName>Johannes</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6352-0909</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Ulm University, Ulm, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9506311</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1351-5101</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 1.15.1.1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000072105">Superoxide Dismutase-1</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D001786">Blood Glucose</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000072105" MajorTopicYN="N">Superoxide Dismutase-1</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001786" MajorTopicYN="N">Blood Glucose</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018450" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Progression</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055442" MajorTopicYN="N">Metabolome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">presymptomatic gene carriers</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36169607</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ene.15584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Masrori P, Van Damme P. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a clinical review. Eur J Neurol. 2020;27:1918-1929.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abramzon YA, Fratta P, Traynor BJ, Chia R. The overlapping genetics of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal dementia. Front Neurosci. 2020;14:42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicolas A, Kenna KP, Renton AE, et al. Genome-wide analyses identify KIF5A as a novel ALS gene. Neuron. 2018;97:1268-1283.e1266.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dupuis L, Pradat PF, Ludolph AC, Loeffler JP. Energy metabolism in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet Neurol. 2011;10:75-82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saffer D, Morley J, Bill P. Carbohydrate metabolism in motor neurone disease. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 1977;40:533-537.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pradat P-F, Bruneteau G, Gordon PH, et al. Impaired glucose tolerance in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2010;11:166-171.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dupuis L, Corcia P, Fergani A, et al. Dyslipidemia is a protective factor in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology. 2008;70:1004-1009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murai A, Miyahara T, Tanaka T, Kaneko T, Sako Y, Kameyama M. Abnormalities of lipoprotein and carbohydrate metabolism in degenerative diseases of the nervous system-motor neuron disease and spinocerebellar degeneration. Tohoku J Exp Med. 1983;139:365-376.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desport JC, Preux PM, Magy L, et al. Factors correlated with hypermetabolism in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Am J Clin Nutr. 2001;74:328-334.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fayemendy P, Marin B, Labrunie A, et al. Hypermetabolism is a reality in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis compared to healthy subjects. J Neurol Sci. 2021;420:117257.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouteloup C, Desport J-C, Clavelou P, et al. Hypermetabolism in ALS patients: an early and persistent phenomenon. J Neurol. 2009;256:1236-1242.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mariosa D, Beard JD, Umbach DM, et al. Body mass index and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a study of US military veterans. Am J Epidemiol. 2017;185:362-371.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peter RS, Rosenbohm A, Dupuis L, et al. Life course body mass index and risk and prognosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: results from the ALS registry Swabia. Eur J Epidemiol. 2017;32:901-908.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desport JC, Preux P, Truong T, Vallat J, Sautereau D, Couratier P. Nutritional status is a prognostic factor for survival in ALS patients. Neurology. 1999;53:1059.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marin B, Desport J-C, Kajeu P, et al. Alteration of nutritional status at diagnosis is a prognostic factor for survival of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2011;82:628-634.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dupuis L, di Scala F, Rene F, et al. Up-regulation of mitochondrial uncoupling protein 3 reveals an early muscular metabolic defect in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. FASEB J. 2003;17:1-19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crugnola V, Lamperti C, Lucchini V, et al. Mitochondrial respiratory chain dysfunction in muscle from patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Arch Neurol. 2010;67:849-854.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorges M, Vercruysse P, M&#xfc;ller H-P, et al. Hypothalamic atrophy is related to body mass index and age at onset in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2017;88:1033-1041.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cykowski MD, Takei H, Schulz PE, Appel SH, Powell SZ. TDP-43 pathology in the basal forebrain and hypothalamus of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathol Commun. 2014;2:1-11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ludolph AC, Dorst J, Dreyhaupt J, et al. Effect of high-caloric nutrition on survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol. 2020;87:206-216.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dorst J, Schuster J, Dreyhaupt J, et al. Effect of high-caloric nutrition on serum neurofilament light chain levels in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2020;91:1007-1009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wills A-M, Hubbard J, Macklin EA, et al. Hypercaloric enteral nutrition in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled phase 2 trial. Lancet. 2014;383:2065-2072.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vasta R, D'Ovidio F, Logroscino G, Chi&#xf2; A. The links between diabetes mellitus and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurol Sci. 2021;42:1377-1387.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J, Luo X, Chen X, Shang H. Lipid profile in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Neurol. 2020;11:5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Timmins HC, Saw W, Cheah BC, et al. Cardiometabolic health and risk of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 2017;56:721-725.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fergani A, Oudart H, Gonzalez De Aguilar JL, et al. Increased peripheral lipid clearance in an animal model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Lipid Res. 2007;48:1571-1580.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palamiuc L, Schlagowski A, Ngo ST, et al. A metabolic switch toward lipid use in glycolytic muscle is an early pathologic event in a mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. EMBO Mol Med. 2015;7:526-546.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dupuis L, Oudart H, Ren&#xe9; F, de Aguilar J-LG, Loeffler J-P. Evidence for defective energy homeostasis in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: benefit of a high-energy diet in a transgenic mouse model. Proc Natl Acad Sci. 2004;101:11159-11164.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D'Amico E, Grosso G, Nieves JW, Zangh&#xec; A, Factor-Litvak P, Mitsumoto H. Metabolic abnormalities, dietary risk factors and nutritional management in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nutrients. 2021;13(7):2273.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ingre C, Chen L, Zhan Y, Termorshuizen J, Yin L, Fang F. Lipids, apolipoproteins, and prognosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology. 2020;94:e1835-e1844.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirk SE, Tracey TJ, Steyn FJ, Ngo ST. Biomarkers of metabolism in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Front Neurol. 2019;10:191.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2; A, Borghero G, Restagno G, et al. Clinical characteristics of patients with familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis carrying the pathogenic GGGGCC hexanucleotide repeat expansion of C9ORF72. Brain. 2012;135:784-793.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang L, Dorst J, Chen L, et al. A natural history comparison of SOD1-mutant patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis between Chinese and German populations. Transl Neurodegener. 2021;10:42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bali T, Self W, Liu J, et al. Defining SOD1 ALS natural history to guide therapeutic clinical trial design. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2017;88:99-105.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Synofzik M, Ronchi D, Keskin I, et al. Mutant superoxide dismutase-1 indistinguishable from wild-type causes ALS. Hum Mol Genet. 2012;21:3568-3574.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pasinelli P, Belford ME, Lennon N, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-associated SOD1 mutant proteins bind and aggregate with Bcl-2 in spinal cord mitochondria. Neuron. 2004;43:19-30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damiano S, Sozio C, La Rosa G, et al. Metabolism regulation and redox state: insight into the role of superoxide dismutase 1. Int J Mol Sci. 2020;21:6606.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xfc;nther R, Pal A, Williams C, et al. Alteration of mitochondrial integrity as upstream event in the pathophysiology of SOD1-ALS. Cell. 2022;11:11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He J, Fu J, Zhao W, et al. Hypermetabolism associated with worse prognosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol. 2022;269(3):1447-1455.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vercruysse P, Sinniger J, El Oussini H, et al. Alterations in the hypothalamic melanocortin pathway in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain. 2016;139:1106-1122.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Echaniz-Laguna A, Zoll J, Ponsot E, et al. Muscular mitochondrial function in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis is progressively altered as the disease develops: a temporal study in man. Exp Neurol. 2006;198:25-30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dupuis L, Gonzalez De Aguilar J-L, Echaniz-Laguna A, et al. Muscle mitochondrial uncoupling dismantles neuromuscular junction and triggers distal degeneration of motor neurons. PLoS One. 2009;4:e5390.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi P, Gal J, Kwinter DM, Liu X, Zhu H. Mitochondrial dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Biochim Biophys Acta. 2010;1802:45-51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang YJ, Fan DS. Elimination rate of serum lactate is correlated with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis progression. Chin Med J (Engl). 2016;129:28-32.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>