<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36217681</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-4598</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>66</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Muscle &amp; nerve</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Muscle Nerve</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A clinical bulbar assessment scale (CBAS) for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>694</StartPage><EndPage>701</EndPage><MedlinePgn>694-701</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/mus.27738</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION/AIMS">Comprehensive and valid bulbar assessment scales for use within amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) clinics are critically needed. The aims of this study are to develop the Clinical Bulbar Assessment Scale (CBAS) and complete preliminary validation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">The authors selected CBAS items from among the literature and expert opinion, and content validity ratio (CVR) was calculated. Following consent, the CBAS was administered to a pilot sample of English-speaking adults with El Escorial defined ALS (N&#xa0;=&#xa0;54) from a multidisciplinary clinic, characterizing speech, swallowing, and extrabulbar features. Criterion validity was assessed by correlating CBAS scores with commonly used ALS scales, and internal consistency reliability was obtained.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Expert raters reported strong agreement for the CBAS items (CVR&#xa0;=&#xa0;1.00; 100% agreement). CBAS scores yielded a moderate, significant, negative correlation with ALS Functional Rating Scale-Revised (ALSFRS-R) total scores (r&#xa0;=&#xa0;-0.652, p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;.001), and a strong, significant, negative correlation with ALSFRS-R bulbar subscale scores (r&#xa0;=&#xa0;-0.795, p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;.001). There was a strong, significant, positive correlation with Center for Neurologic Studies Bulbar Function Scale (CNS-BFS) scores (r&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.819, p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;.001). CBAS scores were significantly higher for bulbar onset (mean&#xa0;=&#xa0;38.9% of total possible points, SD&#xa0;=&#xa0;22.6) than spinal onset (mean&#xa0;=&#xa0;18.7%, SD&#xa0;=&#xa0;15.8; p&#xa0;=&#xa0;.004). Internal consistency reliability (Cronbach's alpha) values were: (a) total CBAS, &#x3b1;&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.889; (b) Speech subscale, &#x3b1;&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.903; and (c) Swallowing subscale, &#x3b1;&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.801.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION">The CBAS represents a novel means of standardized bulbar data collection using measures of speech, swallowing, respiratory, and cognitive-linguistic skills. Preliminary evidence suggests the CBAS is a valid, reliable scale for clinical assessment of bulbar dysfunction.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ball</LastName><ForeName>Laura J</ForeName><Initials>LJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2465-3279</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Speech-Language Pathology, Mississippi University for Women, Columbus, Mississippi, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Geske</LastName><ForeName>Jenenne A</ForeName><Initials>JA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8578-6783</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Family Medicine, University of Nebraska Medical Center, Omaha, Nebraska, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Burton</LastName><ForeName>Elizabeth</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Speech-Language Pathology, Madonna Rehabilitation Institute, Lincoln, Nebraska, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pattee</LastName><ForeName>Gary L</ForeName><Initials>GL</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8365-6707</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Nebraska Medical Center, Neurology Associates, PC, Lincoln, Nebraska, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Muscle Nerve</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7803146</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0148-639X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015203" MajorTopicYN="N">Reproducibility of Results</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003679" MajorTopicYN="N">Deglutition</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011795" MajorTopicYN="N">Surveys and Questionnaires</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013060" MajorTopicYN="N">Speech</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">assessment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bulbar ALS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dysarthria</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dysphagia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">motor neuron dysfunction</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36217681</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.27738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Kim Y, Kent R, Weismer G. An acoustic study of the relationships among neurologic disease, dysarthria type, and severity of dysarthria. J Speech Hear Res. 2011;54(April):417-430. doi:10.1044/1092-4388(2010/10-0020)a</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Felgoise SH, Zaccheo V, Duff J, Simmons Z. Verbal communication impacts quality of life in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotrophic Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2016;17(3-4):179-183. doi:10.3109/21678421.1125499</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee J, Madhavan A, Krajewski E, Lingenfelter S. Assessment of dysarthria and dysphagia in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: review of the current evidence. Muscle Nerve. 2021;64(5):520-531. doi:10.1002/mus.27361</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon PH, Miller RG, Moore DH. ALSFRS-R. Amyotrophic Lateral Scler Other Mot Neuron Disord. 2004;5(SUPPL. 1):90-93. doi:10.1080/17434470410019906</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chapin JL, Gray LT, Vasilopoulos T, et al. Diagnostic utility of the amyotrophic lateral sclerosis functional rating scale-revised to detect pharyngeal dysphagia in individuals with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. PLoS One. 2020;15(8):1-12. doi:10.1371/JOURNAL.PONE.0236804</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith RA, Macklin EA, Myers KJ, et al. Assessment of bulbar function in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: validation of a self-report scale (Center for Neurologic Study Bulbar Function Scale). Eur J Neurol. 2018;25(7):907-916. doi:10.1111/ene.13638</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pattee GL, Plowman EK, Brooks BR, et al. Best practices protocol for the evaluation of bulbar dysfunction: summary recommendations from the NEALS bulbar subcommittee symposium. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Front Degener. 2018;19(3-4):311-312. doi:10.1080/21678421.2017.1404109</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yunusova Y, Plowman EK, Green JR, Barnett C, Bede P. Clinical measures of bulbar dysfunction in ALS. Front Neurol. 2019;10(106):1-11. doi:10.3389/fneur.2019.00106</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pattee GL, Plowman EK, Garand KL, et al. Provisional best practices guidelines for the evaluation of bulbar dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 2019;59(5):531-536. doi:10.1002/MUS.26408</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuhnlein P, Gdynia H, Sperfeld A, et al. Diagnosis and treatment of bulbar symptoms in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat Clin Pract Neurol. 2008;4(7):366-374. doi:10.1038/ncpneuro0853</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ball LJ, Willis A, Beukelman DR, Pattee GL. A protocol for identification of early bulbar signs in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Sci. 2001;191(1-2):43-53. doi:10.1016/S0022-510X(01)00623-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rong P, Yunusova Y, Wang J, Green JR. Predicting early bulbar decline in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a speech subsystem approach. Behav Neurol. 2015;183027:11. doi:10.1155/2015/183027</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mano T, Katsuno M, Banno H, et al. Tongue pressure as a novel biomarker of spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Neurology. 2014;82:255-262. doi:10.1212/WNL.0000000000000041</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tena A, Claria F, Solsona F, Meister E, Povedano M. Detection of bulbar involvement in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis by machine learning voice analysis: diagnostic decision support development study. JMIR Med Inf. 2021;9(3):e21331. doi:10.2196/21331</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Makkonen T, Ruottinen H, Puhto R, Helminen M, Palmio J. Speech deterioration in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) after manifestation of bulbar symptoms. Int J Lang Commun Disord. 2018;53(2):385-392. doi:10.1111/1460-6984.12357</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wadman RI, van Bruggen HW, Witkamp TD, et al. Bulbar muscle MRI changes in patients with SMA with reduced mouth opening and dysphagia. Neurology. 2014;83(12):1060-1066. doi:10.1212/WNL.0000000000000796</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gwathmey KG, Berggren KN. Reflections on the implementation of the provisional best practices guidelines for the evaluation of bulbar dysfunction in ALS. Muscle Nerve. 2019;59(5):523-524. doi:10.1002/MUS.26453</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yunusova Y, Green JR, Lindstrom MJ, Ball LJ, Pattee GL, Zinman L. Kinematics of disease progression in bulbar ALS. J Commun Disord. 2010;43(1):6-20. doi:10.1016/J.JCOMDIS.2009.07.003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith R, Pioro E, Myers K, et al. Enhanced bulbar function in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: the Nuedexta treatment trial. Neurotherapeutics. 2017;14(3):762-772. doi:10.1007/S13311-016-0508-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plowman EK, Tabor LC, Wymer J, Pattee G. The evaluation of bulbar dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: survey of clinical practice patterns in the United States. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Front Degener. 2017;10(5-6):351-357. doi:10.1080/21678421.2017.1313868</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanson EK, Yorkston KM, Britton D. Dysarthria in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a systematic review of characteristics, speech treatment and augmentative and alternative communication options. J Med Speech Lang Pathol. 2011;19:12-30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Towards a common language for functioning, disability and health: ICF. Int Classif Funct Disability Health. 2002;1149:1-22. http://www.who.int/classifications/icf/training/icfbeginnersguide.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duffy JR. Motor Speech Disorders: Substrates, Differential Diagnosis, and Management. 4th ed. Elsevier; 2020. https://www.elsevier.com/books/motor-speech-disorders/duffy/978-0-323-53054-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bunton K, Kent RD, Duffy JR, Rosenbek JC, Kent JF. Listener agreement for auditory- perceptual ratings of dysarthria. J Speech Lang Hear Res. 2007;50(December):1481-1496. doi:10.1044/1092-4388(2007/102)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yorkston KM, Dowden PA, Beukelman DR. Intelligibility measurement as a tool in the clinical management of dysarthric speakers. In: Kent RD, ed. Intelligibility in Speech Disorders. John Benjamin Publishing Company; 1992:265-285.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kent RD, Weismer G, Kent JF, Rosenbek JC. Toward phonetic intelligibility testing in dysarthria. J Speech Hear Disord. 1989;54:482-499.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kent RD, Kim Y-J. Toward an acoustic typology of motor speech disorders. Clin Linguist Phon. 2003;17(6):427-445. doi:10.1080/0269920031000086248</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langmore SE, Lehman ME. Physiologic deficits in the orofacial system underlying dysarthria in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Speech Hear Res. 1994;37(February):28-37. doi:10.1044/jshr.3701.28</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lomas J, Pickard L, Bester S, Elbard H, Finlayson A, Zoghaib C. The communicative effectiveness index: developmental and psychometric evaluation of a functional communication measure for adult aphasia. J Speech Hear Disord. 1989;54(1):113-124. doi:10.1044/JSHD.5401.113</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beukelman DR, Fager S, Ball L, Dietz A. AAC for adults with acquired neurological conditions: a review. Augment Altern Commun. 2007;23(3):230-242. doi:10.1080/07434610701553668</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ball LJ, Beukelman DR, Ullman C, Maassen K, Pattee GL. Monitoring speaking rate by telephone for persons with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Med Speech Lang Pathol. 2005;13(4):233-240.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ball L, Pattee G. Administering and interpreting a clinical bulbar scale for ALS. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2010;11(Suppl. 1):153-158. doi:10.3109/17482968.2010.519506</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jani MP, Gore GB. Swallowing characteristics in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. NeuroRehabilitation. 2016;39(2):273-276. doi:10.3233/NRE-161357</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva L, Mourao L, Silva A. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: combined nutritional, respiratory, and functional assessment. Arq Neuropsiquiatr. 2008;66:354-359.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leder SB, Suiter DM. The Yale Swallow Protocol An Evidence-Based Approach to Decision Making. Springer; 2014:1-157. doi:10.1007/978-3-319-05113-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yorkston K, Beukelman D. Assessment of Intelligibility in Dysarthric Speakers. CC Publications; 1984.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yorkston KM, Beukelman DR, Hakel ME, Dorsey M. Speech Intelligibility Test (SIT). 2007. http://www.madonna.org/researcher/communication/software.html.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ball LJ, Beukelman DR, Pattee GL. Communication effectiveness of individuals with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Commun Disord. 2004;37(3):197-215. doi:10.1016/J.JCOMDIS.2003.09.002</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donovan NJ, Kendall DL, Young ME, Rosenbek JC. The communicative effectiveness survey: preliminary evidence of construct validity. Am J Speech Lang Pathol. 2008;17:335-347.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yorkston KM, Beukelman DR, Strand EA, Hakel ME. Clinical examination of motor speech disorders. Management of Motor Speech Disorders in Children and Adults. 3rd ed. PRO-ED; 2010:25-75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andreatta RD, Barlow SM. Movement-related modulation of vibrotactile detection thresholds in the human orofacial system. Exp Brain Res. 2003;149:75-82. doi:10.1007/s00221-002-1336-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hodge MM. Speech mechanism assessment. In: Yoder D, Kent RD, eds. Decision Making in Speech-Language Pathology. B.C. Decker; 1988:104-109.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanchip C, Guarin DL, McKinlay S, et al. Validating automatic diadochokinesis analysis methods across dysarthria severity and syllable task in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Speech Lang Hear Res. 2022;65(3):940-953. doi:10.1044/2021_JSLHR-21-00503</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nordio S, Bernitsas E, Meneghello F, et al. Expiratory and phonation times as measures of disease severity in patients with multiple sclerosis. A case-control study. Mult Scler Relat Disord. 2018;23:27-32. doi:10.1016/J.MSARD.2018.04.010</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kent RD, Kent JF, Rosenbek JC. Maximum performance tests of speech production. J Speech Hear Disord. 1987;52(4):367-387. doi:10.1044/jshd.5204.367</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ball LJ, Beukelman DR, Pattee GL. Timing of speech deterioration in people with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Med Speech Lang Pathol. 2002;10(4):231-235.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mulligan M, Carpenter J, Riddel J, et al. Intelligibility and the acoustic characteristics of speech in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). J Speech Hear Res. 1994;37(3):496-503. doi:10.1044/JSHR.3703.496</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solomon NP. What is orofacial fatigue and how does it affect function for swallowing and speech? Semin Speech Lang. 2006;27(4):268-282. doi:10.1055/S-2006-955117</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solomon NP, Makashay MJ, Helou LB, Clark HM. Neurogenic orofacial weakness and speech in adults with dysarthria. Am J Speech Lang Pathol. 2017;26(3):951-960. doi:10.1044/2017_AJSLP-16-0144</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacAllister WS, Christodoulou C, Troxell R, et al. Fatigue and quality of life in pediatric multiple sclerosis. Mult Scler. 2009;15(12):1502-1508. doi:10.1177/1352458509345902</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen SM, Elackattu A, Noordzij JP, Walsh MJ, Langmore SE. Palliative treatment of dysphonia and dysarthria. Otolaryngol Clin North Am. 2009;42(1):107-121. doi:10.1016/J.OTC.2008.09.010</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hidecker MJC, Paneth N, Rosenbaum PL, et al. Developing and validating the communication function classification system for individuals with cerebral palsy. Dev Med Child Neurol. 2011;53(8):704-710. doi:10.1111/j.1469-8749.2011.03996.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kent RD. Perceptual sensorimotor speech examination for motor speech disorders. In: McNeil MR, ed. Clinical Management of Sensorimotor Speech Disorders. Thieme Medical; 2008:19-29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riddel J, McCauley RJ, Mulligan M, Tandan R. Intelligibility and phonetic contrast errors in highly intelligible speakers with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Speech Hear Res. 1995;38(2):304-314. doi:10.1044/JSHR.3802.304</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DePaul R, Brooks BR. Multiple orofacial indices in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Speech Hear Res. 1993;36(6):1158-1167. doi:10.1044/jshr.3606.1158</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samlan RA, Weismer G. The relationship of selected perceptual measures of diadochokinesis to speech intelligibility in dysarthric speakers with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Am J Speech Lang Pathol. 1995;4(2):9-13. doi:10.1044/1058-0360.0402.09</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rvachew S, Hodge M, Ohberg A, Canada a B. Obtaining and interpreting maximum performance tasks from children: a tutorial. J Speech Lang Pathol Audiol. 2005;29(4):146-157.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kent JF, Kent RD, Rosenbek JC, et al. Quantitative description of the dysarthria in women with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Speech Hear Res. 1992;35(4):723-733. doi:10.1044/jshr.3504.723</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xe9;v&#xea;que N, Slis A, Lancia L, Bruneteau G, Fougeron C. Acoustic change over time in spastic and / or flaccid dysarthria in motor neuron diseases. J Speech Hear Res. 2022;65:1767-1783. doi:10.1044/2022_JSLHR-21-00434</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel R, Connaghan K, Franco D, Edsall E, Forgit D. &#x201c;The Caterpillar&#x201d;: a novel Reading passage for assessment of motor speech disorders. Am J Speech Lang Pathol. 2013;22(February):1-9. doi:10.1044/1058-0360(2012/11-0134)b</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walshe M, Miller N, Leahy M, Murray A. Intelligibility of dysarthric speech: perceptions of speakers and listeners. Int J Lang Commun Disord. 2008;43(6):633-648. doi:10.1080/13682820801887117</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yorkston KM, Beukelman DR. Communication efficiency of dysarthric speakers as measured by sentence intelligibility and speaking rate. J Speech Hear Disord. 1981;46(3):296-301. doi:10.1007/BF0041789</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allen IE, Seaman CA. Likert scales and data analyses. Qual Prog. 2007;40(7):64-65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Likert R. A technique for the measurement of attitudes. Arch Psychol. 1932;140:1-55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rofes L, Arreola V, Mukherjee R, Clav&#xe9; P. Sensitivity and specificity of the eating assessment tool and the volume-viscosity swallow test for clinical evaluation of oropharyngeal dysphagia. Neurogastroenterol Motil. 2014;26(9):1256-1265. doi:10.1111/nmo.12382</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDonagh M. Nutritional and metabolic support in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Perspect Swallowing Swallowing Disord. 2013;22(1):12-16. doi:10.1044/sasd22.1.12</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DePippo K, Holas M, Reding M. Validation of the 3-oz water swallow test for aspiration following stroke. Arch Neurol. 1992;49:1259-1261. doi:10.1001/archneur.1992.00530360057018</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Logemann JA, Veis SL, Colangelo L. A screening procedure for oropharyngeal dysphagia. Dysphagia. 1999;14(1):44-51. doi:10.1007/PL00009583</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luchesi KF, Kitamura S, Mour&#xe3;o LF. Management of dysphagia in Parkinson's disease and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. CoDAS. 2013;25(4):358-364. doi:10.1590/s2317-17822013000400010</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lisiecka D, Kelly H, Jackson J. How do people with motor neurone disease experience dysphagia? A qualitative investigation of personal experiences. Disabil Rehabil. 2019;43(4):479-488. doi:10.1080/09638288.2019.1630487</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lisiecka D, Kelly H, Jackson J. &#x201c;This is your golden time. You enjoy it and you've planty time for crying after&#x201d;: how dysphagia impacts family caregivers of people with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-a qualitative study. Palliat Med. 2020;34(8):1097-1107. doi:10.1177/0269216320932754</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tabor L, Gaziano J, Watts S, Robison R, Plowman EK. Defining swallowing-related quality of life profiles in individuals with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Dysphagia. 2016;31:376-382. doi:10.1007/s00455-015-9686-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Onesti E, Schettino I, Gori MC, et al. Dysphagia in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: impact on patient behavior, diet adaptation, and riluzole management. Front Neurol. 2017;8:1-18. doi:10.3389/fneur.2017.00094</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rashnoo P, Daniel SJ. Drooling quantification: correlation of different techniques. Int J Pediatr Otorhinolaryngol. 2015;79(8):1201-1205. doi:10.1016/J.IJPORL.2015.05.010</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reid SM, Johnson HM, Reddihough DS. The drooling impact scale: a measure of the impact of drooling in children with developmental disabilities. Dev Med Child Neurol. 2010;52(2):e23-e28. doi:10.1111/J.1469-8749.2009.03519.X</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hyun SE, Yi G, Shin H-I. Reliability and validity of the eating and drinking ability classification system in adults with cerebral palsy. Dysphagia. 2021;36:351-361. doi:10.1007/s00455-020-10141-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenbek JC, Robbins JA, Roecker PDEB, Coyle JL, Wood JL. A penetration-aspiration scale. Dysphagia. 1996;11(2):93-98. doi:10.1007/BF0041789</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butler SG, Markley L, Sanders B, Stuart A. Reliability of the penetration aspiration scale with flexible endoscopic evaluation of swallowing. Ann Otol Rhinol Laryngol. 2015;124(6):480-483. doi:10.1177/0003489414566267</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hassan HE, Aboloyoun AI. The value of bedside tests in dysphagia evaluation. Egypt J Ear, Nose, Throat Allied Sci. 2014;15(3):197-203. doi:10.1016/J.EJENTA.2014.07.007</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clav&#xe9; P, Arreola V, Romea M, Medina L, Palomera E, Serra-Prat M. Accuracy of the volume-viscosity swallow test for clinical screening of oropharyngeal dysphagia and aspiration. Clin Nutr. 2008;27(6):806-815. doi:10.1016/J.CLNU.2008.06.011</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guenard-Lampron V, Masson M, Blumenthal D. Critical review of sensory texture descriptors: from pureed to transitional foods for dysphagia patients. J Texture Stud. 2021;52(5-6):665-678. doi:10.1111/jtxs.12604</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bach JR. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Communication status and survival with ventilatory support. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 1993;72(6):343-349. http://europepmc.org/abstract/MED/8260126</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldstein LH. Syntactic processing as a marker for cognitive impairment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotrophic Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2015;17:69-76. doi:10.3109/21678421.2015.1071397</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor LJ, Brown RG, Tsermentseli S, et al. Is language impairment more common than executive dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis? J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2013;84(5):494-498. doi:10.1136/jnnp-2012-303526</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fried-Oken M, Mooney A, Peters B. Supporting communication for patients with neurodegenerative disease. NeuroRehabilitation. 2015;37(1):69-87. doi:10.3233/NRE-151241</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boschi V, Catrical&#xe0; E, Consonni M, Chesi C, Moro A, Cappa SF. Connected speech in neurodegenerative language disorders: a review. Front Psychol. 2017;8:8. doi:10.3389/fpsyg.2017.00269</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yorkston KM, Spencer KA, Duffy JR. Behavioral management of respiratory/phonatory dysfunction from dysarthria: a systematic review of the evidence. J Med Speech Lang Pathol. 2003;11(2):xiii-xxxviii.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spencer KA, Yorkston KM. Evidence for the treatment of respiratory/Phonatory dysfunction from dysarthria. Perspect Neurophysiol Neurogenic Speech Lang Disord. 2002;12(4):4-16. doi:10.1044/NNSLD12.4.4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tortelli R, Arcuti S, Copetti M, et al. Pseudobulbar affect as a negative prognostic indicator in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neurol Scand. 2018;138(1):55-61. doi:10.1111/ANE.12918</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Floeter MK, Katipally R, Kim MP, et al. Impaired corticopontocerebellar tracts underlie pseudobulbar affect in motor neuron disorders. Neurology. 2014;83(7):620-627. doi:10.1212/WNL.0000000000000693</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taule T, S&#xf8;vik M, Lein RK, Wehling E, A&#xdf;mus J, Rekand T. Psychometric properties of cognitive assessment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a systematic review. Patient Relat Outcome Meas. 2020;11:181-194. doi:10.2147/PROM.S256828</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawshe C. A quantitative approach to content validity. Pers Psychol. 1975;28(4):563-575. doi:10.1111/j.1744-6570.1975.tb01393.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zamanzadeh V, Ghahramanian A, Rassouli M, Abbaszadeh A, Alavi-Majd H, Nikanfar A-R. Design and implementation content validity study: development of an instrument for measuring patient-centered communication. J Caring Sci. 2015;4(2):165-178. doi:10.15171/JCS.2015.017</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayre C, Scally AJ. Critical values for Lawshe's content validity ratio: revisiting the original methods of calculation. Meas Eval Couns Dev. 2014;47(1):79-86. doi:10.1177/0748175613513808</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR. Escorial World Federation of Neurology criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Sci. 1994;124(Suppl):96-107. doi:10.1016/0022-510x(94)90191-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, Miller RG, Swash M, Munsat TL. El Escorial revisited: revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2000;1(5):293-299. doi:10.1080/146608200300079536</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>IBM Corp. Released 2021. IBM SPSS Statistics for Windows, Version 28.0. Armonk, NY: IBM Corp.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chronbach L. Coefficient alpha and the internal structure of tests. Psychometrika. 1951;16(3):297-334. doi:10.1007/bf02310555</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schober P, Schwarte LA. Correlation coefficients: appropriate use and interpretation. Anesth Analg. 2018;126(5):1763-1768. doi:10.1213/ANE.0000000000002864</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical Power Analysis for the Behavioral Sciences. 2nd ed. Erlbaum; 1988.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Threats TT. The ICF and speech-language pathology: aspiring to a fuller realization of ethical and moral issues*. Int J Speech Lang Pathol. 2010;12(2):87-93. doi:10.3109/17549500903568476</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dykstra AD, Hakel ME, Adams SG. Application of the ICF in reduced speech intelligibility in dysarthria. Semin Speech Lang. 2007;28(4):301-311. doi:10.1055/s-2007-986527</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>