<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36214183</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-4598</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>67</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Muscle &amp; nerve</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Muscle Nerve</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Clinical and neurophysiological biomarkers of disease progression in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>17</StartPage><EndPage>24</EndPage><MedlinePgn>17-24</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/mus.27736</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION/AIMS">Rate of disease progression (&#x394;FS), measured as change in the revised Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Functional Rating Scale (ALSFRS-R) and body mass index (BMI), are predictors of survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). Our aim in this study was to assess the utility of these clinical biomarkers along with neurophysiological measures, such as the split hand index (SI), in monitoring disease progression.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Clinical trial data were collected from 107 patients recruited into the Tecfidera in ALS trial. The prognostic utility of clinical and neurophysiological measures, including &#x394;FS, BMI, SI, and neurophysiological index (NPI), were assessed cross-sectionally and longitudinally (40&#x2009;weeks). The outcome measures of disease severity and progression included: (i) ALSFRS-R score; (ii) Medical Research Council (MRC) score; and (iii) forced vital capacity and sniff nasal inspiratory pressure.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Fast-progressor ALS patients (&#x394;FS&#x2009;&#x2265;1.1) exhibited significantly lower ALSFRS-R and total MRC scores at baseline. A baseline &#x394;FS score&#x2009;&#x2265;1.1 was associated with a greater reduction in ALSFRS-R (P&#xa0;=&#xa0;.002) and MRC (P&#xa0;=&#xa0;.002) scores over 40&#x2009;weeks. Baseline BMI &lt;25 was also associated with faster reduction of ALSFRS-R and MRC scores. SI and NPI were associated with disease severity at baseline, but not with subsequent rate of disease progression.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION">Implementation of the assessed clinical and neurophysiological biomarkers may assist in patient management and stratification into clinical trials.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hannaford</LastName><ForeName>Andrew</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Brain and Nerve Research Centre, Concord Clinical School, University of Sydney, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Byth</LastName><ForeName>Karen</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>NHMRC Clinica Trials Center, Westmead Hospital, Research and Education Network, Westmead, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>NHMRC Clinical Trials Centre, University of Sydney, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pavey</LastName><ForeName>Nathan</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Brain and Nerve Research Centre, Concord Clinical School, University of Sydney, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Henderson</LastName><ForeName>Robert D</ForeName><Initials>RD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Royal Brisbane &amp; Women's Hospital, Brisbane, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mathers</LastName><ForeName>Susan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Calvary Health Care Bethlehem, Melbourne, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Clinical Sciences, Monash University, Melbourne, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Needham</LastName><ForeName>Merrilee</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Fiona Stanley Hospital, Murdoch, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Molecular Medicine, Murdoch University, Perth, Western Australia, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Perron Institute for Neurological and Translational Science, Nedlands, Western Australia, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of Notre Dame, Fremantle, Western Australia, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schultz</LastName><ForeName>David</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Flinders Medical Centre, Bedford Park, South Australia, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Flinders University of South Australia, Bedford Park, South Australia, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Menon</LastName><ForeName>Parvathi</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Brain and Nerve Research Centre, Concord Clinical School, University of Sydney, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kiernan</LastName><ForeName>Matthew C</ForeName><Initials>MC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Brain and Mind Centre, University of Sydney, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Royal Prince Alfred Hospital, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vucic</LastName><ForeName>Steve</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8323-873X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Brain and Nerve Research Centre, Concord Clinical School, University of Sydney, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Acronym>MRC_</Acronym><Agency>Medical Research Council</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Muscle Nerve</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7803146</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0148-639X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D015415">Biomarkers</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018450" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Progression</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011379" MajorTopicYN="N">Prognosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015415" MajorTopicYN="N">Biomarkers</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015992" MajorTopicYN="N">Body Mass Index</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ALS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">biomarker</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">body mass index</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">split hand index</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">&#x394;FS</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36214183</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.27736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Goutman SA, Hardiman O, Al-Chalabi A, et al. Recent advances in the diagnosis and prognosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet Neurol. 2022;21:480-493.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiernan MC, Vucic S, Talbot K, et al. Improving clinical trial outcomes in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat Rev Neurol. 2020;17:1-15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum JM, Stambler N, Malta E, et al. The ALSFRS-R: a revised ALS Functional Rating Scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. BDNF ALS study group (phase III). J Neurol Sci. 1999;169:13-21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rooney J, Burke T, Vajda A, Heverin M, Hardiman O. What does the ALSFRS-R really measure? A longitudinal and survival analysis of functional dimension subscores in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2017;88:381-385.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zoccolella S, Beghi E, Palagano G, et al. Analysis of survival and prognostic factors in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a population based study. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2008;79:33-37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Labra J, Menon P, Byth K, Morrison S, Vucic S. Rate of disease progression: a prognostic biomarker in ALS. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2016;87:628-632.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gold J, Rowe DB, Kiernan MC, et al. Safety and tolerability of Triumeq in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: the Lighthouse Trial. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2019;20:595-604.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westeneng HJ, Debray TPA, Visser AE, et al. Prognosis for patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: development and validation of a personalised prediction model. Lancet Neurol. 2018;17:423-433.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roche JC, Rojas-Garcia R, Scott KM, et al. A proposed staging system for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain J Neurol. 2012;135:847-852.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2; A, Hammond ER, Mora G, Bonito V, Filippini G. Development and evaluation of a clinical staging system for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2015;86:38-44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S, Rutkove SB. Neurophysiological biomarkers in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Curr Opin Neurol. 2018;31:640-647.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barp A, Lizio A, Gerardi F, et al. Neurophysiological indices in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis correlate with functional outcome measures, staging and disease progression. Clin Neurophysiol. 2021;132:1564-1571.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hannaford A, Higashihara M, Pavey N, et al. Split-hand index: a diagnostic and prognostic marker in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis across varying regions of onset. Clin Neurophysiol. 2021;132:2130-1235.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu LQ, Hu W, Guo QF, et al. Median nerve-neurophysiological index correlates with the survival of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Front Neurol. 2020;11:570227.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao B, Wei Q, Ou R, et al. Neurophysiological index is associated with the survival of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Neurophysiol. 2019;130:1730-1733.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S, Henderson RD, Mathers S, Needham M, Schultz D, Kiernan MC. Safety and efficacy of dimethyl fumarate in ALS: randomised controlled study. Ann Clin Transl Neurol. 2021;8:1991-1999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S, Ryder J, Mekhael L, et al. Phase 2 randomized placebo controlled double blind study to assess the efficacy and safety of Tecfidera in Patients with Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis (TEALS study): study protocol clinical trial (SPIRIT compliant). Medicine. 2020;99:e18904.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kimura F, Fujimura C, Ishida S, et al. Progression rate of ALSFRS-R at time of diagnosis predicts survival time in ALS. Neurology. 2006;66:265-267.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weber M, Eisen A, Stewart H, Hirota N. The split hand in ALS has a cortical basis. J Neurol Sci. 2000;180:66-70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menon P, Bae JS, Mioshi E, Kiernan MC, Vucic S. Split-hand plus sign in ALS: differential involvement of the flexor pollicis longus and intrinsic hand muscles. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2013;14:315-318.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Swash M. Sensitivity of electrophysiological tests for upper and lower motor neuron dysfunction in ALS: a six-month longitudinal study. Muscle Nerve. 2010;41:208-211.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon PH, Miller RG, Moore DH. ALSFRS-R. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord. 2004;5(Suppl 1)):90-93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kjaeldgaard AL, Pilely K, Olsen KS, et al. Prediction of survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a nationwide, Danish cohort study. BMC Neurol. 2021;21:164.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Limousin N, Blasco H, Corcia P, et al. Malnutrition at the time of diagnosis is associated with a shorter disease duration in ALS. J Neurol Sci. 2010;297:36-39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dorst J, Chen L, Rosenbohm A, et al. Prognostic factors in ALS: a comparison between Germany and China. J Neurol. 2019;266:1516-1525.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dardiotis E, Siokas V, Sokratous M, et al. Body mass index and survival from amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a meta-analysis. Neurol Clin Pract. 2018;8:437-444.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huisman MH, Seelen M, van Doormaal PT, et al. Effect of presymptomatic body mass index and consumption of fat and alcohol on amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. JAMA Neurol. 2015;72:1155-1162.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed RM, Caga J, Devenney E, et al. Cognition and eating behavior in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: effect on survival. J Neurol. 2016;263:1593-1603.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janssens JP, Adler D, Iancu Ferfoglia R, et al. Assessing inspiratory muscle strength for early detection of respiratory failure in motor neuron disease: should we use MIP, SNIP, or both? Respir Int Rev Thorac Dis. 2019;98:114-124.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinto S, de Carvalho M. Sniff nasal inspiratory pressure (SNIP) in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: relevance of the methodology for respiratory function evaluation. Clin Neurol Neurosurg. 2018;171:42-45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fitting JW, Paillex R, Hirt L, Aebischer P, Schluep M. Sniff nasal pressure: a sensitive respiratory test to assess progression of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol. 1999;46:887-893.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zoccolella S, Capozzo R, Quaranta VN, et al. Reduction of sniff nasal inspiratory pressure (SNIP) as an early indicator of the need of enteral nutrition in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain Sci. 2021;11:1091.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tilanus TBM, Groothuis JT, TenBroek-Pastoor JMC, et al. The predictive value of respiratory function tests for non-invasive ventilation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Respir Res. 2017;18:144.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinto S, Geraldes R, Vaz N, Pinto A, de Carvalho M. Changes of the phrenic nerve motor response in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: longitudinal study. Clin Neurophysiol. 2009;120:2082-2085.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>