<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36223668</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2213-1582</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>36</Volume><PubDate><Year>2022</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>NeuroImage. Clinical</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Neuroimage Clin</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Clinical relevance of single-subject brain metabolism patterns in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis mutation carriers.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>103222</StartPage><MedlinePgn>103222</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">103222</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.nicl.2022.103222</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S2213-1582(22)00287-X</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The ALS diagnosis requires an integrative approach, combining the clinical examination and supporting tests. Nevertheless, in several cases, the diagnosis proves to be suboptimal, and for this reason, new diagnostic methods and novel biomarkers are catching on. The <sup>18</sup>F-fluorodeoxyglucose (<sup>18</sup>F-FDG)-PET could be a helpful method, but it still requires additional research for sensitivity and specificity. We performed an <sup>18</sup>F-FDG-PET single-subject analysis in a sample of familial ALS patients carrying different gene mutations, investigating the genotype-phenotype correlations and exploring metabolism correlations with clinical and neuropsychological data.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We included ten ALS patients with pathogenic gene mutation who underwent a complete clinical and neuropsychological evaluation and an <sup>18</sup>F-FDG-PET scan at baseline. Patients were recruited between 2018 and 2022 at the ALS Tertiary Centre in Novara, Italy. Patients were selected based on the presence of ALS gene mutation (C9orf72, SOD1, TBK1, and KIF5A). Following a validated voxel-based Statistical Parametric Mapping (SPM) procedure, we obtained hypometabolism maps at single-subject level. We extracted regional hypometabolism from the SPM maps, grouping significant hypometabolism regions into three meta-ROIs (motor, prefrontal association and limbic). Then, the corresponding <sup>18</sup>F-FDG-PET regional hypometabolism was correlated with clinical and neuropsychological features.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Classifying the patients with C9orf72-ALS based on the rate of disease progression from symptoms onset to the time of scan, we observed two different patterns of brain hypometabolism: an extensive motor and prefrontal hypometabolism in patients classified as fast progressors, and a more limited brain hypometabolism in patients grouped as slow progressors. Patients with SOD1-ALS showed a hypometabolic pattern involving the motor cortex and prefrontal association regions, with a minor involvement of the limbic regions. The patient with TBK1-ALS showed an extended hypometabolism, in limbic systems, along with typical motor involvement, while the hypometabolism in the patient with KIF5A-ALS involved almost exclusively the motor regions, supporting the predominantly motor impairment linked to this gene mutation. Additionally, we observed strong correlations between the hypometabolism in the motor, prefrontal association and limbic meta-ROI and the specific neuropsychological performances.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">To our knowledge, this is the first study investigating brain hypometabolism at the single-subject level in genetic ALS patients carrying different mutations. Our results show high heterogeneity in the hypometabolism maps and some commonalities in groups sharing the same mutation. Specifically, in patients with C9orf72-ALS the brain hypometabolism was larger in patients classified as fast progressors than slow progressors. In addition, in the whole group, the brain metabolism showed specific correlations with clinical and neuropsychological impairment, confirming the ability of <sup>18</sup>F-FDG-PET in revealing pattern of neuronal dysfunction, aiding the diagnostic workup in genetic ALS patients.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022 The Authors. Published by Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tondo</LastName><ForeName>Giacomo</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vita-Salute San Raffaele University, Milan, Italy; Division of Neuroscience, IRCCS San Raffaele Scientific Institute, Milan, Italy; Department of Neurology, S. Andrea Hospital, University of Piemonte Orientale, Vercelli, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mazzini</LastName><ForeName>Letizia</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ALS Centre, Department of Neurology, Maggiore della Carit&#xe0; Hospital, University of Piemonte Orientale, Novara, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Caminiti</LastName><ForeName>Silvia Paola</ForeName><Initials>SP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vita-Salute San Raffaele University, Milan, Italy; Division of Neuroscience, IRCCS San Raffaele Scientific Institute, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sarnelli</LastName><ForeName>Maria Francesca</ForeName><Initials>MF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ALS Centre, Department of Neurology, Maggiore della Carit&#xe0; Hospital, University of Piemonte Orientale, Novara, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Corrado</LastName><ForeName>Lucia</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Sciences, Interdisciplinary Research Center of Autoimmune Diseases (IRCAD), University of Piemonte Orientale, Novara, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Matheoud</LastName><ForeName>Roberta</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Physics, Maggiore della Carit&#xe0; Hospital, Novara, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>D'Alfonso</LastName><ForeName>Sandra</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Sciences, Interdisciplinary Research Center of Autoimmune Diseases (IRCAD), University of Piemonte Orientale, Novara, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cantello</LastName><ForeName>Roberto</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ALS Centre, Department of Neurology, Maggiore della Carit&#xe0; Hospital, University of Piemonte Orientale, Novara, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sacchetti</LastName><ForeName>Gian Mauro</ForeName><Initials>GM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nuclear Medicine, Maggiore della Carit&#xe0; Hospital, Novara, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Perani</LastName><ForeName>Daniela</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vita-Salute San Raffaele University, Milan, Italy; Division of Neuroscience, IRCCS San Raffaele Scientific Institute, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Comi</LastName><ForeName>Cristoforo</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, S. Andrea Hospital, University of Piemonte Orientale, Vercelli, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>De Marchi</LastName><ForeName>Fabiola</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ALS Centre, Department of Neurology, Maggiore della Carit&#xe0; Hospital, University of Piemonte Orientale, Novara, Italy. Electronic address: fabiola.demarchi@uniupo.it.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Neuroimage Clin</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101597070</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2213-1582</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0Z5B2CJX4D</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D019788">Fluorodeoxyglucose F18</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C500506">KIF5A protein, human</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 3.6.4.4</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D016547">Kinesins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000092522" MajorTopicYN="N">Clinical Relevance</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019788" MajorTopicYN="N">Fluorodeoxyglucose F18</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D049268" MajorTopicYN="N">Positron-Emission Tomography</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001921" MajorTopicYN="N">Brain</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009154" MajorTopicYN="N">Mutation</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016547" MajorTopicYN="N">Kinesins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">(18)F-FDG-PET</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Brain metabolism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Genetic</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neurodegenerative diseases</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Positron emission tomography</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of Competing Interest The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36223668</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9668615</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nicl.2022.103222</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2213-1582(22)00287-X</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Agosta F., Al-Chalabi A., Filippi M., Hardiman O., Kaji R., Meininger V., Nakano I., Shaw P., Shefner J., Van Den Berg L.H. The El Escorial criteria: strengths and weaknesses. Amyotroph. Lateral Scler. Front. Degener. 2015;16:1&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25482030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agosta F., Altomare D., Festari C., Orini S., Gandolfo F., Boccardi M., Arbizu J., Bouwman F., Drzezga A., Nestor P. Clinical utility of FDG-PET in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and Huntington&#x2019;s disease. Eur. J. Nucl. Med. Mol. Imaging. 2018;45:1546&#x2013;1556.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29717332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agosta, F., Valsasina, P., Riva, N., Copetti, M., Messina, M.J., Prelle, A., Comi, G., Filippi, M., 2012. The cortical signature of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3412820</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22880116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boeve B.F., Boylan K.B., Graff-Radford N.R., DeJesus-Hernandez M., Knopman D.S., Pedraza O., Vemuri P., Jones D., Lowe V., Murray M.E., Dickson D.W., Josephs K.A., Rush B.K., Machulda M.M., Fields J.A., Ferman T.J., Baker M., Rutherford N.J., Adamson J., Wszolek Z.K., Adeli A., Savica R., Boot B., Kuntz K.M., Gavrilova R., Reeves A., Whitwell J., Kantarci K., Jack C.R.J., Parisi J.E., Lucas J.A., Petersen R.C., Rademakers R. Characterization of frontotemporal dementia and/or amyotrophic lateral sclerosis associated with the GGGGCC repeat expansion in C9ORF72. Brain. 2012;135:765&#x2013;783.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3286335</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22366793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brettschneider J., Del Tredici K., Toledo J.B., Robinson J.L., Irwin D.J., Grossman M., Suh E., Van Deerlin V.M., Wood E.M., Baek Y. Stages of pTDP-43 pathology in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann. Neurol. 2013;74:20&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3785076</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23686809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caminiti S.P., Sala A., Presotto L., Chincarini A., Sestini S., Perani D., Schillaci O., Berti V., Calcagni M.L., Cistaro A. Validation of FDG-PET datasets of normal controls for the extraction of SPM-based brain metabolism maps. Eur. J. Nucl. Med. Mol. Imaging. 2021;48:2486&#x2013;2499.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33423088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canosa A., Pagani M., Cistaro A., Montuschi A., Iazzolino B., Fania P., Cammarosano S., Ilardi A., Moglia C., Calvo A., Chi&#xf2; A. 18 F-FDG-PET correlates of cognitive impairment in ALS. Neurology. 2016;86:44&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26590270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canosa A., Calvo A., Moglia C., Vasta R., Palumbo F., Fuda G., Di Pede F., Cabras S., Arena V., Novara A. Brain 18fluorodeoxyglucose-positron emission tomography changes in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with TARDBP mutations. J. Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatry. 2022</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35351820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canosa A., Calvo A., Moglia C., Vasta R., Palumbo F., Solero L., Di Pede F., Cabras S., Arena V., Zocco G. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with SOD1 mutations shows distinct brain metabolic changes. Eur. J. Nucl. Med. Mol. Imaging. 2022:1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9165265</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35076740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carluer L., Mondou A., Buhour M.-S., Laisney M., P&#xe9;lerin A., Eustache F., Viader F., Desgranges B. Neural substrate of cognitive theory of mind impairment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Cortex. 2015;65:19&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25618325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castelnovo V., Caminiti S.P., Riva N., Magnani G., Silani V., Perani D. Heterogeneous brain FDG-PET metabolic patterns in patients with C9orf72 mutation. Neurol. Sci. 2019;40:515&#x2013;521.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30554355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum J.M., Stambler N., Malta E., Fuller C., Hilt D., Thurmond B., Nakanishi A., Group, B.A.S., Group, 1A complete listing of the BDNF Study The ALSFRS-R: a revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. J. Neurol. Sci. 1999;169:13&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10540002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chia R., Chi&#xf2; A., Traynor B.J. Novel genes associated with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: diagnostic and clinical implications. Lancet Neurol. 2018;17:94&#x2013;102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5901717</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29154141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2; A., Mora G., Calvo A., Mazzini L., Bottacchi E., Mutani R. Epidemiology of ALS in Italy: a 10-year prospective population-based study. Neurology. 2009;72:725&#x2013;731.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19237701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2; A., Moglia C., Canosa A., Manera U., D&#x2019;Ovidio F., Vasta R., Grassano M., Brunetti M., Barberis M., Corrado L., D&#x2019;Alfonso S., Iazzolino B., Peotta L., Sarnelli M.F., Solara V., Zucchetti J.P., De Marchi F., Mazzini L., Mora G., Calvo A. ALS phenotype is influenced by age, sex, and genetics: A population-based study. Neurology. 2020;94 doi: 10.1212/WNL.0000000000008869.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000008869</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31907290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cipolotti L., MacPherson S.E., Gharooni S., van-Harskamp N., Shallice T., Chan E., Nachev P. Cognitive estimation: Performance of patients with focal frontal and posterior lesions. Neuropsychologia. 2018;1(115):70&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6018564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28811256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cistaro A., Valentini M.C., Chi&#xf2; A., Nobili F., Calvo A., Moglia C., Montuschi A., Morbelli S., Salmaso D., Fania P. Brain hypermetabolism in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a FDG PET study in ALS of spinal and bulbar onset. Eur. J. Nucl. Med. Mol. Imaging. 2012;39:251&#x2013;259.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22089661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cistaro A., Pagani M., Montuschi A., Calvo A., Moglia C., Canosa A., Restagno G., Brunetti M., Traynor B.J., Nobili F. The metabolic signature of C9ORF72-related ALS: FDG PET comparison with nonmutated patients. Eur. J. Nucl. Med. Mol. Imaging. 2014;41:844&#x2013;852.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8957062</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24445987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeJesus-Hernandez M., Mackenzie I.R., Boeve B.F., et al. Expanded GGGGCC hexanucleotide repeat in noncoding region of C9ORF72 causes chromosome 9p-linked FTD and ALS. Neuron. 2011;72(2):245&#x2013;256. doi: 10.1016/j.neuron.2011.09.011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuron.2011.09.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3202986</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21944778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Della Rosa P.A., Cerami C., Gallivanone F., Prestia A., Caroli A., Castiglioni I., Gilardi M.C., Frisoni G., Friston K., Ashburner J. A standardized [18F]-FDG-PET template for spatial normalization in statistical parametric mapping of dementia. Neuroinformatics. 2014;12:575&#x2013;593.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24952892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghanavati E., Salehinejad M.A., Nejati V., Nitsche M.A. Differential role of prefrontal, temporal and parietal cortices in verbal and figural fluency: Implications for the supramodal contribution of executive functions. Sci. Rep. 2019;9(1):3700.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6403289</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30842493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goutman S.A., Hardiman O., Al-Chalabi A., Chi&#xf3; A., Savelieff M.G., Kiernan M.C., Feldman E.L. Recent advances in the diagnosis and prognosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet Neurol. 2022</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9513753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35334233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guedj E., Varrone A., Boellaard R., Albert N.L., Barthel H., van Berckel B., Brendel M., Cecchin D., Ekmekcioglu O., Garibotto V., Lammertsma A.A., Law I., Pe&#xf1;uelas I., Semah F., Traub-Weidinger T., van de Giessen E., Van Weehaeghe D., Morbelli S. EANM procedure guidelines for brain PET imaging using [18F]FDG, version 3. Eur. J. Nucl. Med. Mol. Imaging. 2022;49(2):632&#x2013;651. doi: 10.1007/s00259-021-05603-w. Epub 2021 Dec 9. Erratum in: Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging. 2022 Mar 7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00259-021-05603-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8803744</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34882261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hannaford A., Pavey N., van den Bos M., Geevasinga N., Menon P., Shefner J.M., Kiernan M.C., Vucic S. Diagnostic utility of gold coast criteria in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann. Neurol. 2021;89:979&#x2013;986.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33565111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kopp B., R&#xf6;sser N., Tabeling S., St&#xfc;renburg H.J., de Haan B., Karnath H.O., Wessel K. Performance on the Frontal Assessment Battery is sensitive to frontal lobe damage in stroke patients. BMC Neurol. 2013;16(13):179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4225667</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24237624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao, G., Tang, Y., Yu, J., Hu, S., 2020. The metabolism pattern of brain FDG-PET in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ludolph A.C., Langen K.J., Regard M., Herzog H., Kemper B., Kuwert T., B&#xf6;ttger I.G., Feinendegen L. Frontal lobe function in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a neuropsychologic and positron emission tomography study. Acta Neurol. Scand. 1992;85:81&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1574993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacPherson S.E., Cox S.R., Dickie D.A., Karama S., Starr J.M., Evans A.C., Bastin M.E., Wardlaw J.M., Deary I.J. Processing speed and the relationship between Trail Making Test-B performance, cortical thinning and white matter microstructure in older adults. Cortex. 2017;95:92&#x2013;103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5637162</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28865241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsuoka T., Narumoto J., Okamura A., Taniguchi S., Kato Y., Shibata K., Nakamura K., Okuyama C., Yamada K., Fukui K. Neural correlates of the components of the clock drawing test. Int. Psychogeriatr. 2013;25(8):1317&#x2013;1323.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23676356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazumder S., Kiernan M.C., Halliday G.M., Timmins H.C., Mahoney C.J. The contribution of brain banks to knowledge discovery in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a systematic review. Neuropathol. Appl. Neurobiol. 2022;3:e12845.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35921237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mejzini R., Flynn L.L., Pitout I.L., Fletcher S., Wilton S.D., Akkari P.A. ALS genetics, mechanisms, and therapeutics: Where are we now? Front. Neurosci. 2019;6(13):1310.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6909825</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31866818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicolas A., Kenna K.P., Renton A.E., Ticozzi N., Faghri F., Chia R., Dominov J.A., Kenna B.J., Nalls M.A., Keagle P., Rivera A.M., van Rheenen W., Murphy N.A., van Vugt J.J.F.A., Geiger J.T., Van der Spek R.A., Pliner H.A., Shankaracharya, Smith B.N., Marangi G., Topp S.D., Abramzon Y., Gkazi A.S., Eicher J.D., Kenna A., ITALSGEN Consortium, Mora G., Calvo A., Mazzini L., Riva N., Mandrioli J., Caponnetto C., Battistini S., Volanti P., La Bella V., Conforti F.L., Borghero G., Messina S., Simone I.L., Trojsi F., Salvi F., Logullo F.O., D'Alfonso S., Corrado L., Capasso M., Ferrucci L., Genomic Translation for ALS Care (GTAC) Consortium, Moreno CAM, Kamalakaran S., Goldstein D.B., ALS Sequencing Consortium, Gitler A.D., Harris T., Myers R.M., NYGC ALS Consortium, Phatnani H., Musunuri R.L., Evani U.S., Abhyankar A., Zody M.C., Answer ALS Foundation, Kaye J., Finkbeiner S., Wyman S.K., LeNail A., Lima L., Fraenkel E., Svendsen C.N., Thompson L.M., Van Eyk J.E., Berry J.D., Miller T.M., Kolb S.J., Cudkowicz M., Baxi E., Clinical Research in ALS and Related Disorders for Therapeutic Development (CReATe) Consortium, Benatar M., Taylor J.P., Rampersaud E., Wu G., Wuu J., SLAGEN Consortium, Lauria G., Verde F., Fogh I., Tiloca C., Comi G.P., Sorar&#xf9; G., Cereda C., French ALS Consortium, Corcia P., Laaksovirta H., Myllykangas L., Jansson L., Valori M., Ealing J., Hamdalla H., Rollinson S., Pickering-Brown S., Orrell R.W., Sidle K.C., Malaspina A., Hardy J., Singleton A.B., Johnson J.O., Arepalli S., Sapp P.C., McKenna-Yasek D., Polak M., Asress S., Al-Sarraj S., King A., Troakes C., Vance C., de Belleroche J., Baas F., Ten Asbroek A.L.M.A., Mu&#xf1;oz-Blanco J.L., Hernandez D.G., Ding J., Gibbs J.R., Scholz S.W., Floeter M.K., Campbell R.H., Landi F., Bowser R., Pulst S.M., Ravits J.M., MacGowan D.J.L., Kirby J., Pioro E.P., Pamphlett R., Broach J., Gerhard G., Dunckley T.L., Brady C.B., Kowall N.W., Troncoso J.C., Le Ber I., Mouzat K., Lumbroso S., Heiman-Patterson T.D., Kamel F., Van Den Bosch L., Baloh R.H., Strom T.M., Meitinger T., Shatunov A., Van Eijk K.R., de Carvalho M., Kooyman M., Middelkoop B., Moisse M., McLaughlin R.L., Van Es M.A., Weber M., Boylan K.B., Van Blitterswijk M., Rademakers R., Morrison K.E., Basak A.N., Mora J.S., Drory V.E., Shaw P.J., Turner M.R., Talbot K., Hardiman O., Williams K.L., Fifita J.A., Nicholson G.A., Blair I.P., Rouleau G.A., Esteban-P&#xe9;rez J., Garc&#xed;a-Redondo A., Al-Chalabi A., Project MinE ALS Sequencing Consortium, Rogaeva E., Zinman L., Ostrow L.W., Maragakis N.J., Rothstein J.D., Simmons Z., Cooper-Knock J., Brice A., Goutman S.A., Feldman E.L., Gibson S.B., Taroni F., Ratti A., Gellera C., Van Damme P., Robberecht W., Fratta P., Sabatelli M., Lunetta C., Ludolph A.C., Andersen P.M., Weishaupt J.H., Camu W., Trojanowski J.Q., Van Deerlin V.M., Brown R.H., Jr, van den Berg L.H., Veldink J.H., Harms M.B., Glass J.D., Stone D.J., Tienari P., Silani V., Chi&#xf2; A., Shaw C.E., Traynor B.J., Landers J.E. Genome-wide Analyses Identify KIF5A as a Novel ALS Gene. Neuron. 2018;97(6) 1268-1283.e6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5867896</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29566793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pagani M., Chi&#xf2; A., Valentini M.C., &#xd6;berg J., Nobili F., Calvo A., Moglia C., Bertuzzo D., Morbelli S., De Carli F. Functional pattern of brain FDG-PET in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology. 2014;83:1067&#x2013;1074.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25122207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perani D., Della Rosa P.A., Cerami C., Gallivanone F., Fallanca F., Vanoli E.G., Panzacchi A., Nobili F., Pappat&#xe0; S., Marcone A. Validation of an optimized SPM procedure for FDG-PET in dementia diagnosis in a clinical setting. NeuroImage Clin. 2014;6:445&#x2013;454.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4225527</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25389519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pozzi L., Valenza F., Mosca L., et al. TBK1 mutations in Italian patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: genetic and functional characterisation. J. Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatry. 2017;88(10):869&#x2013;875. doi: 10.1136/jnnp-2017-316174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp-2017-316174</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5629935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28822984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajagopalan V., Pioro E.P. Comparing brain structural MRI and metabolic FDG-PET changes in patients with ALS-FTD:&#x2018;the chicken or the egg?&#x2019;question. J. Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatry. 2015;86:952&#x2013;958.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25520437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renton A.E., Majounie E., Waite A., et al. A hexanucleotide repeat expansion in C9ORF72 Is the cause of chromosome 9p21-Linked ALS-FTD. Neuron. 2011;72(2) doi: 10.1016/j.neuron.2011.09.010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuron.2011.09.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3200438</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21944779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richards S., Aziz N., Bale S., et al. Standards and guidelines for the interpretation of sequence variants: a joint consensus recommendation of the American College of Medical Genetics and Genomics and the Association for Molecular Pathology. Genet. Med. 2015;17(5):405&#x2013;424. doi: 10.1038/gim.2015.30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/gim.2015.30</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4544753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25741868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riello M., Frangakis C.E., Ficek B., Webster K.T., Desmond J.E., Faria A.V., Hillis A.E., Tsapkini K. Neural correlates of letter and semantic fluency in primary progressive aphasia. Brain Sci. 2021;12(1):1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8773895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35053745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sala A., Iaccarino L., Fania P., Vanoli E.G., Fallanca F., Pagnini C., Cerami C., Calvo A., Canosa A., Pagani M. Testing the diagnostic accuracy of [18F] FDG-PET in discriminating spinal-and bulbar-onset amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Eur. J. Nucl. Med. Mol. Imaging. 2019;46:1117&#x2013;1131.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30617963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strong M.J., Abrahams S., Goldstein L.H., Woolley S., Mclaughlin P., Snowden J., Mioshi E., Roberts-South A., Benatar M., Hortob&#xe1;Gyi T. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-frontotemporal spectrum disorder (ALS-FTSD): Revised diagnostic criteria. Amyotroph. lateral Scler. Front. Degener. 2017;18:153&#x2013;174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7409990</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28054827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Talwar N.A., Churchill N.W., Hird M.A., Pshonyak I., Tam F., Fischer C.E., Graham S.J., Schweizer T.A. The neural correlates of the clock-drawing test in healthy aging. Front. Hum. Neurosci. 2019;5(13):25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6370722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30804769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tish M.M., Geerling J.C. The brain and the bladder: forebrain control of urinary (in)continence. Front. Physiol. 2020;3(11):658.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7349519</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32719609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomberg T., Braschinsky M., Rannikm&#xe4;e K., Kepler J., Kepler K., K&#xf5;rv J., Linnam&#xe4;gi &#xdc;., Asser T. Functional MRI of the cortical sensorimotor system in patients with hereditary spastic paraplegia. Spinal Cord. 2012;50(12):885&#x2013;890.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22751186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tondo G., De Marchi F. From biomarkers to precision medicine in neurodegenerative diseases: Where are we? J Clin Med. 2022;11(15):4515.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9369634</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35956130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tondo G., Iaccarino L., Cerami C., Vanoli G.E., Presotto L., Masiello V., Coliva A., Salvi F., Bartolomei I., Mosca L., Lunetta C., Perani D. 11 C-PK11195 PET-based molecular study of microglia activation in SOD1 amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann. Clin. Transl. Neurol. 2020;7(9):1513&#x2013;1523.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7480909</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32762033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tzourio-Mazoyer N., Landeau B., Papathanassiou D., Crivello F., Etard O., Delcroix N., Mazoyer B., Joliot M. Automated anatomical labeling of activations in SPM using a macroscopic anatomical parcellation of the MNI MRI single-subject brain. Neuroimage. 2002;15:273&#x2013;289.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11771995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Laere K., Vanhee A., Verschueren J., De Coster L., Driesen A., Dupont P., Robberecht W., Van Damme P. Value of 18fluorodeoxyglucose&#x2013;positron-emission tomography in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a prospective study. JAMA Neurol. 2014;71:553&#x2013;561.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24615479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walhout R., Westeneng H.-J., Verstraete E., Hendrikse J., Veldink J.H., Van Den Heuvel M.P., Van Den Berg L.H. Cortical thickness in ALS: towards a marker for upper motor neuron involvement. J. Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatry. 2015;86:288&#x2013;294.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25121571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woessner H., Vibhute P., Barrett K. Acute loss of bladder control in a stroke of the frontal cortex. Neurohospitalist. 2012;2(4):129&#x2013;131.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3726109</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23983877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>