<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36262610</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1687-5273</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>2022</Volume><PubDate><Year>2022</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Computational intelligence and neuroscience</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Comput Intell Neurosci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Analysis and Construction of the User Characteristic Model in the Adaptive Learning System for Personalized Learning.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>5503153</StartPage><MedlinePgn>5503153</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">5503153</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1155/2022/5503153</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Adaptive Learning System (ALS) is a supportive environment, which dynamically provides learners with services that can satisfy their demand for personalized learning in accordance with the differentiation of their individual traits. At present, study on ALS is still in the exploratory stage, and there are still many fields that deserve to be studied thoroughly. User characteristic model is the foundation and core of ALS and the key to the implementation of intelligent and personalized recommendation service. Based on this, this paper intends to analyze learners' characteristics in ALS through several dimensions, such as basic information, interest, preference, cognitive level and learning style, through which learners' user characteristic model is established. In the end, ALS, which supports the function of personalized recommendation, is implemented based on this model. It is suggested by the result of the simulation experiment that ALS, which is developed through this model, demonstrates a satisfying effect in recommendation, and it can dynamically recommend appropriate learning resources in accordance with learners' personalized demands through which learners' quality and efficiency of learning can be effectively enhanced to a certain extent.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022 Xuekong Zhao et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Xuekong</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Education Technology and Information Management Center, Guangxi College of Education, Nanning 530023, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Long</LastName><ForeName>Shirong</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8749-2877</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Education Technology and Information Management Center, Guangxi College of Education, Nanning 530023, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hu</LastName><ForeName>Defa</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4777-8701</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hunan University of Technology and Business, Changsha 410205, Hunan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Comput Intell Neurosci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101279357</NlmUniqueID></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007858" MajorTopicYN="N">Learning</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003198" MajorTopicYN="N">Computer Simulation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36262610</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9576355</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2022/5503153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Voiskovskii A. P., Kuznetsov K. V., Yakimenko V. A. Adaptive algorithms in a universal integrated navigation system based on low-cost instruments. Russian Engineering Research . 2021;41(1):68&#x2013;71. doi: 10.3103/s1068798x21010251.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3103/s1068798x21010251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghadirli H. M., Rastgarpour M. A web-based adaptive and intelligent tutor by expert systems. Advances in Computing and Information Technology . 2013;177:87&#x2013;95. doi: 10.1007/978-3-642-31552-7_10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-3-642-31552-7_10</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaziev V. M., Glukhova L. V. Adaptive and intelligent web-based learning and control technologies. Handbook on Intelligent Techniques in the Educational Process . 2022;29</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alghofaily B. I., Ding C. Data mining service recommendation based on dataset features. Service Oriented Computing and Applications . 2019;13(3):261&#x2013;277. doi: 10.1007/s11761-019-00272-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11761-019-00272-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rafiq M. S., Jianshe X., Arif M., Barra P. Intelligent query optimization and course recommendation during online lectures in E-learning system. Journal of Ambient Intelligence and Humanized Computing . 2021;12(11):10375&#x2013;10394. doi: 10.1007/s12652-020-02834-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12652-020-02834-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sridharan S., Saravanan D., Srinivasan A. K., Murugan B. Adaptive learning management expert system with evolving knowledge base and enhanced learnability. Education and Information Technologies . 2021;26(5):5895&#x2013;5916. doi: 10.1007/s10639-021-10560-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10639-021-10560-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarus J. K., Niu Z., Kalui D. A hybrid recommender system for e-learning based on context awareness and sequential pattern mining. Soft Computing . 2018;22(8):2449&#x2013;2461. doi: 10.1007/s00500-017-2720-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00500-017-2720-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhavithra J., Saradha A. Personalized web page recommendation using case-based clustering and weighted association rule mining. Cluster Computing . 2019;22(S3):6991&#x2013;7002. doi: 10.1007/s10586-018-2053-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10586-018-2053-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ambulgekar H. P., Pathak M. K., Kokare M. B. A survey on collaborative filtering: tasks, approaches and applications. Proceedings of the International Ethical Hacking Conference 2018. Advances in Intelligent Systems and Computing; October 2019; Kolkata, India.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iaquinta L., Gemmis M., Lops P. Can a Recommender System Induce Serendipitous Encounters . London, UK: InTech; 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babori A., Falih N., Ouchitachen H. A framework for adaptive E-learning systems based on self-regulated learning strategies. Proceedings of the International Conference on Digital Technologies and Applications Digital Technologies and Applications. ICDTA 2022; January 2022; Fez, Morocco.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vesin B., Mangaroska K., Giannakos M. Learning in smart environments: user-centered design and analytics of an adaptive learning system. Smart Learn. Environ . 2018;5(1) doi: 10.1186/s40561-018-0071-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40561-018-0071-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y. User behavior identification and personalized recommendation based on web data mining. International Journal of Circuits, Systems and Signal Processing . 2021;15:643&#x2013;650. doi: 10.46300/9106.2021.15.72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.46300/9106.2021.15.72</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sweta S., Lal K. Personalized adaptive learner model in E-learning system using FCM and fuzzy inference system. International Journal of Fuzzy Systems . 2017;19(4):1249&#x2013;1260. doi: 10.1007/s40815-017-0309-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40815-017-0309-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fatahi S. An experimental study on an adaptive e-learning environment based on learner&#x2019;s personality and emotion. Education and Information Technologies . 2019;24(4):2225&#x2013;2241. doi: 10.1007/s10639-019-09868-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10639-019-09868-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lwande C., Oboko R., Muchemi L. Learner behavior prediction in a learning management system. Education and Information Technologies . 2020;26(3):2743&#x2013;2766. doi: 10.1007/s10639-020-10370-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10639-020-10370-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao X. M. Research on learner model of adaptive learning system. Proceedings of the International Conference on Computer Science &amp; Education (ICCSE); May 2021; Lancaster, UK.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ICCSE51940.2021.9569673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joy J., Pillai R. V. G. Review and classification of content recommenders in E-learning environment. Journal of King Saud University - Computer and Information Sciences . 2022;34(9):7670&#x2013;7685. doi: 10.1016/j.jksuci.2021.06.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jksuci.2021.06.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Felder R. M., Spurlin J. Applications, reliability and validity of the index of learning styles. Journal of Engineering Education . 2005;21:103&#x2013;112.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao X. K., Cen L., Long S. R., Wang P. Study on and realization of hybrid recommendation-based adaptive learning system. Journal of Software Engineering . 2015;9(4):886&#x2013;894. doi: 10.3923/jse.2015.886.894.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3923/jse.2015.886.894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao X. K., Long S. R. Research on Key Technologies of constructing personalized learning environment based on Web. University Education . 2018;3:67&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dag F., Erkan K. A personalized learning system based on semantic web technologies. Intelligent Tutoring Systems in E-Learning Environments . 2011:258&#x2013;284. doi: 10.4018/978-1-61692-008-1.ch013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4018/978-1-61692-008-1.ch013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song Z. Research on User Interest Model Based on Web Browsing Behavior&#x201d; . Mianyang, China: Southwest University of science and Technology; 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xing L., Song Z., Ma Q. User interest model based on hybrid behaviors interest rate. Application Research of Computers . 2016;33(3):661&#x2013;665.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao X. K., Xu X. D., Long S. R. Research on personalized recommendation service of adaptive learning system based on B/S mode. China distance education . 2015;10:71&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X., Wu H., Sun R., Jiang W. A fast multipole boundary element method for half-space acoustic problems in a subsonic uniform flow. Engineering Analysis with Boundary Elements . 2022;137:16&#x2013;28. doi: 10.1016/j.enganabound.2022.01.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.enganabound.2022.01.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cen L. Research on personalized recommendation service of e-learning system based on user learning style. Journal of Guangxi Institute of Education . 2017;5:139&#x2013;143.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu H., Zhao W., Liang M. Pedagogical strategy model in adaptive learning system focusing on learning styles. Entertainment for Education. Digital Techniques and Systems . 2010;6249:156&#x2013;164. doi: 10.1007/978-3-642-14533-9_16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-3-642-14533-9_16</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cen L., Zhao X. K. A personalized recommendation service in E-learning system from the perspective of learning style. Boletin Tecnico/Technical Bulletin . 2017;55(9):448&#x2013;456.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>