<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36328774</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>03</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1440-1789</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>43</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Neuropathology : official journal of the Japanese Society of Neuropathology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Neuropathology</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Symptomatology and Neuropathology of patients presenting with focal cortical signs.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>27</StartPage><EndPage>43</EndPage><MedlinePgn>27-43</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/neup.12854</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Here, we describe two patients who presented with focal cortical signs and underwent neuropathological examination. Case 1 was a 73-year-old woman with progressive speech disorder and abnormal behavior. She showed agraphia of the frontal lobe type, featured by the omission of kana letters when writing, other than pyramidal tract signs, pseudobulbar palsy, and frontal lobe dementia. Neuropathological examination, including TAR DNA-binding protein 43 (TDP-43) immunohistochemistry, revealed bilateral frontal and anterior temporal lobe lesions accentuated in the precentral gyrus and posterior part of the middle frontal gyrus. Both upper and lower motor neurons showed pathological changes compatible with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Case 2 was a 62-year-old man with progressive speech disorder and hand clumsiness. He had a motor speech disorder, compatible with apraxia of speech, and limb apraxia of the limb-kinetic and ideomotor type. Neuropathological examination revealed degeneration in the left frontal lobe, including the precentral gyrus, anterior temporal, and parietal lobe cortices. Moreover, numerous argyrophilic neuronal intracytoplasmic inclusions (Pick body) and ballooned neurons were observed in these lesions and the limbic system. The pathological diagnosis was Pick disease involving the peri-Rolandic area and parietal lobe. In these two cases, the distribution of neuropathological changes in the cerebral cortices correlated with the clinical symptoms observed.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022 Japanese Society of Neuropathology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ishihara</LastName><ForeName>Kenji</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7027-6243</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Showa University School of Medicine, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Asahi Hospital of Neurology and Rehabilitation, Chiba, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fukui</LastName><ForeName>Toshiya</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Showa University School of Medicine, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kawasaki Memorial Hospital, Kawasaki, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kawamura</LastName><ForeName>Mitsuru</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Showa University School of Medicine, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Okusawa Hospital, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shiota</LastName><ForeName>Jun-Ichi</ForeName><Initials>JI</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Showa University School of Medicine, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ushioda Home Clinic, Yokohama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nakano</LastName><ForeName>Imaharu</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Jichi Medical University, Tochigi, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Australia</Country><MedlineTA>Neuropathology</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9606526</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0919-6544</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009046" MajorTopicYN="N">Motor Neurons</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003704" MajorTopicYN="Y">Dementia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013702" MajorTopicYN="N">Temporal Lobe</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001072" MajorTopicYN="Y">Apraxias</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pick disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">agraphia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">apraxia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neuropathology</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>22</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36328774</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/neup.12854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Ishihara K. Pathology of dementia (in Japanese with English abstract). Shinkei Shinrigaku 2021; 37: 181-190.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishihara K, Ichikawa H, Suzuki Y, Shiota J, Nakano I, Kawamura M. Is lesion of Exner's area linked to progressive agraphia in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with dementia? An autopsy case report. Behav Neurol 2010; 23: 153-158.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dubois B, Slachevsky A, Litvan I, Pillon B. The FAB: A frontal assessment battery at bedside. Neurology 2000; 55: 1621-1626.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hosokawa T, Yamada Y, Isagoda A, Nakamura R. Psychometric equivalence of the Hasegawa dementia scale-revised with the mini-mental state examination in stroke patients. Percept Mot Skills 1994; 79: 664-666.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKenzie IRA, Neumann M, Baborie A et al. A harmonized classification system for FTLD-TDP pathology. Acta Neuropathol 2011; 122: 111-113.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fukui T, Sugita K, Kawamura M, Shiota J, Nakano I. Primary progressive apraxia in Pick's disease. A clinicopathologic study. Neurology 1996; 47: 467-473.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neary D, Snowden JS, Gustafson L et al. Frontotemporal lobar degeneration. A consensus on clinical diagnostic criteria. Neurology 1998; 51: 1546-1554.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ichikawa H, Koyama S, Ohno H, Ishihara K, Nagumo K, Kawamura M. Writing errors and anosognosia in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with dementia. Behav Neurol 2008; 19: 107-116.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanzaki M, Sato M, Ogawa G et al. A case of dementia with motor neuron disease associated with agraphia - the omission of kana letters - (in Japanese with English abstract). Rhinsho Shinkeigaku 2004; 44: 673-676.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferguson JH, Boller F. A different form of agraphia: Syntactic writing errors in patients with motor speech and movement disorders. Brain Lang 1977; 4: 382-389.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Satoh M, Takeda K, Kuzuhara S. Agraphia in intellectually normal Japanese patients with ALS: Omission of kana letters. J Neurol 2009; 256: 1455-1460.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui B, Cui L-Y, Gao J et al. Agraphia in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with frontotemporal lobe degeneration. Chin Med J 2016; 129: 612-614.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marcie P, H&#xe9;can H. Agraphia: Writing disorders associated with unilateral cortical lesions. In: Heilman KM, Valenstine E, (eds). Clinical Neuropsychology. New York and Oxford: Oxford University Press, 1979; 92-127.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackenzie IRA. The neuropathology of FTD associated with ALS. Alzheimer Dis Assoc Disord 2007; 4: S44-S49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Exner S. Unterschingen &#xfc;ber die Localisation der Functionen in der Gr&#xf6;sshirnrinde des Menschen. Wien: W. Braumuller, 1881.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agnosia NJ, Apraxia A. Their Value in Cerebral Localization. New York: P.B. Hoeber, 1946.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordinier HC. A case of brain tumor at the base of the second left frontal convolution. Am J Med Sci 1899; 117: 526-535.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aimard G, Devic M, Lebel M, Trouillas P, Boisson D. Agraphie pure (dynamique?) d'origine frontale. A propos d'un observation. Rev Neurol 1975; 131: 505-512.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson SW, Damasio AR, Damasio H. Troubled letters but not numbers. Domain-specific cognitive impairment following focal damage in frontal cortex. Brain 1990; 113: 749-766.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abe K, Yokoyama R, Yorifuji S, Yanagihara T. A jargon agraphia and selective agraphia of kana resulting from an infarct in the left middle frontal gyrus (in Japanese with English abstract). Shinkei Shinrigaku 1993; 9: 196-201.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tohgi H, Saitoh K, Takahashi S et al. Agraphia and acalculia after a left prefrontal (F1, F2) infarction. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 1995; 58: 629-632.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakurai Y, Matsumura K, Iwatsubo T, Momose T. Frontal pure agraphia for kanji or kana: Dissociation between morphology and phonology. Neurology 1997; 49: 946-952.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawamura M, Mochizuki S. Primary progressive apraxia. Neuropathology 1999; 19: 249-258.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Snowden J, Neary J, Mann D. Frontotemporal lobar degeneration: Clinical and pathological relationships. Acta Neuropathol 2007; 114: 31-38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chand P, Grafman J, Dickson D, Ishizawa K, Litvan I. Alzheimer's disease presenting as corticobasal syndrome. Mov Disord 2006; 21: 2018-2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alladi S, Xuereb J, Bak T et al. Focal cortical presentations of Alzheimer's disease. Brain 2007; 130: 2636-2645.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Josephs KA, Duffy JR, Strand EA et al. Characterizing a neurodegenerative syndrome: Primary progressive apraxia of speech. Brain 2012; 135: 1522-1536.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duffy JR, Strand EA, Clark H, Machulda M, Whitwell JL, Josephs KA. Primary progressive apraxia of speech: Clinical features and acoustic and neurologic correlates. Am J Speech Lang Pathol 2015; 24: 88-100.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Itabashi R, Nishio Y, Kataoka Y et al. Damage to the left precentral gyrus is associated with apraxia of speech in acute stroke. Stroke 2016; 47: 31-36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duffy JR, Utianski RL, Josephs KA. Primary progressive apraxia of speech: From recognition to diagnosis and care. Aphasiology 2021; 35: 460-591.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorno-Tempini ML, Hillis AE, Weintraub S et al. Classification of primary progressive aphasia and its variants. Neurology 2011; 76: 1006-1014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Josephs KA, Duffy JR, Utianski RL, Strand EA, Machulda MM, Botha H. A molecular pathology, neurobiology, biochemical, genetic and neuroimaging study of progressive apraxia of speech. Nat Commun 2021; 12: 1-17. Article number: 3452 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Botha H, Josephs KA. Primary progressive aphasias and apraxia of speech. Continuum (Minneapolis, Minn.) 2019; 25: 101-127.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kleist K. Apraxie. Jarbuch Psychiatr Neurol 1907; 28: 46-112.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heilman KM, Watson RT, Roth LG. Disorders of skilled movements: Limb apraxia. In: Feinberg TE, Farah MJ, (eds). Behavioral Neurology and Neuropsychology. New York: McGraw-Hill, 1997; 227-235.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gross RG, Grossman M. Update on apraxia. Curr Neurol Neurosci Rep 2008; 8: 490-496.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leiguarda RC, Pramstaller PP, Merello M, Starkstein S, Lees AJ, Marsden CD. Apraxia in Parkinson's disease, progressive supranuclear palsy, multiple system atrophy and neuroleptic-induced parkinsonism. Brain 1997; 120: 75-90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsuchiya K, Ikeda K, Uchihara T, Oda T, Shimada H. Distribution of cerebral cortical lesions in corticobasal degeneration: A clinicopathological study of five autopsy cases in Japan. Acta Neuropathol 1997; 94: 416-424.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rothi LJ, Ochipa C, Heilman KM. A cognitive neuropsychological model of limb praxis. Cogn Neuropsychol 1991; 8: 443-458.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heilman KM, Rothi LJG. Apraxia. In: Heilman KM, Valenstein E, (eds). Clinical Neuropsychology, 3dr edn. New York and Oxford: Oxford University Press, 1993; 141-163.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zadikoff C, Lang AE. Apraxia in movement disorders. Brain 2005; 128: 1480-1497.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boeve BF, Lang AE, Litvan I. Coriticobasal degeneration and its relationship to progressive supranuclear palsy and frontotemporal dementia. Ann Neurol 2003; 54: S15-S19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee SE, Rabinovici GD, Mayo MC et al. Clinicopathological correlations in corticobasal degeneration. Ann Neurol 2011; 70: 327-340.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murray R, Neumann M, Forman MS et al. Cognitive and motor assessment in autopsy-proven corticobasal degeneration. Neurology 2007; 68: 1274-1283.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Josephs KA, Duffy JR, Strand EA et al. The evolution of primary progressive apraxia of speech. Brain 2014; 137: 2783-2795.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tetzloff KA, Duffy JR et al. Clinical and imaging progression over 10&#x2009;years in a patient with primary progressive apraxia of speech and autopsy-confirmed corticobasal degeneration. Neurocase 2018; 24: 111-120.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dickson DW. Neuropathology of Pick's disease. Neurology 2001; 56: S16-S20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cambier J, Masson M, Dairou R et al. &#xc9;tude anatomo-clinique d'une forme pari&#xe9;tale de maladie de Pick. Rev Neurol (Paris) 1981; 137: 33-38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lang AE, Bergeron C, Pollanen MS, Ashby P. Parietal Pick's disease mimicking cortical-basal ganglionic degeneration. Neurology 1994; 44: 1436-1440.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mesulam MM, Weintraub S, Rogalski EJ, Wieneke C, Geula C, Bigio EH. Asymmetry and heterogeneity of Alzheimer's and frontotemporal pathology in primary progressive aphasia. Brain 2014; 137: 1176-1192.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsuchiya K, Ikeda M, Hasegawa K et al. Distribution of cerebral cortical lesions in Pick's disease with pick bodies: A clinicopathological study of six autopsy cases showing unusual clinical presentations. Acta Neuropathol 2001; 102: 553-571.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Irwin DJ, Brettschneider J, McMillan CT et al. Deep clinical and neuropathological phenotyping of Pick disease. Ann Neurol 2016; 79: 272-287.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choudhury P, Scharf EL, Michael A et al. Pick's disease: Clinicopathologic characterization of 21 cases. J Neurol 2020; 267: 2697-2704.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>