<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36447292</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>01</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2051-5960</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>10</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>29</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Acta neuropathologica communications</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Acta Neuropathol Commun</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Response to the letter by de Boer et al. (2022).</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>173</StartPage><MedlinePgn>173</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">173</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s40478-022-01474-w</ELocationID><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kaivola</LastName><ForeName>Karri</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1218-4014</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Translational Immunology Research Program, University of Helsinki, Helsinki, Finland. karri.kaivola@helsinki.fi.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tienari</LastName><ForeName>Pentti J</ForeName><Initials>PJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Translational Immunology Research Program, University of Helsinki, Helsinki, Finland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurocenter, Helsinki University Hospital, Helsinki, Finland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016422">Letter</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016420">Comment</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Acta Neuropathol Commun</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101610673</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2051-5960</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000073885">C9orf72 Protein</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C568651">C9orf72 protein, human</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="CommentOn"><RefSource>Acta Neuropathol Commun. 2022 Sep 21;10(1):141</RefSource><PMID Version="1">36131298</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Frontotemporal Dementia</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000073885" MajorTopicYN="N">C9orf72 Protein</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000483" MajorTopicYN="N">Alleles</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020774" MajorTopicYN="Y">Pick Disease of the Brain</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>Pentti J. Tienari holds a patent in C9orf72 diagnostics and treatment of ALS/FTD.&#xa0;Other authors declare that they have no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36447292</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9710074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40478-022-01474-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s40478-022-01474-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Majounie E, Renton AE, Mok K, Dopper EG, Waite A, Rollinson S, Chio A, Restagno G, Nicolaou N, Simon-Sanchez J, van Swieten JC, Abramzon Y, Johnson JO, Sendtner M, Pamphlett R, Orrell RW, Mead S, Sidle KC, Houlden H, Rohrer JD, Morrison KE, Pall H, Talbot K, Ansorge O, Consortium ITALSGEN, Hernandez DG, Arepalli S, Sabatelli M, Mora G, Corbo M, Giannini F, Calvo A, Englund E, Borghero G, Floris GL, Remes AM, Laaksovirta H, McCluskey L, Trojanowski JQ, Van Deerlin VM, Schellenberg GD, Nalls MA, Drory VE, Lu CS, Yeh TH, Ishiura H, Takahashi Y, Tsuji S, Le Ber I, Brice A, Drepper C, Williams N, Kirby J, Shaw P, Hardy J, Tienari PJ, Heutink P, Morris HR, Pickering-Brown S, Traynor BJ Frequency of the C9orf72 hexanucleotide repeat expansion in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal dementia: a cross-sectional study. Lancet Neurol. 2012;2011:323&#x2013;330.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3322422</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22406228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laaksovirta H, Launes J, Jansson L, Traynor BJ, Kaivola K, Tienari PJ. ALS in Finland: major genetic variants and clinical characteristics of patients with and without the C9orf72 hexanucleotide repeat expansion. Neurol Genetics. 2022;8(2):e665. doi: 10.1212/NXG.0000000000000665.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/NXG.0000000000000665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8922337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35295181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaivola K, Salmi SJ, Jansson L, Launes J, Hokkanen L, Niemi AK, Majamaa K, Lahti J, Eriksson JG, Strandberg T, Laaksovirta H. Tienari PJ carriership of two copies of C9orf72 hexanucleotide repeat intermediate-length alleles is a risk factor for ALS in the finnish population. Acta Neuropathol Commun. 2020;8(1):187. doi: 10.1186/s40478-020-01059-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40478-020-01059-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7654028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33168078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Boer SCM, Woolley L, Mol MO, Serpente M, Reus LM, van Minkelen R, van Vugt JFA, Sorrentino F, Veldink JH, Seelaar H, Galimberti D, van Ruissen F, Mead S, Rogaeva E, Pijnenburg YAL, van der Lee SJ. Letter to the editor on a paper by Kaivola et al (2020): carriership of two copies of C9orf72 hexanucleotide repeat intermediate-length alleles is not associated with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis or frontotemporal dementia. Acta Neuropathol Commun 10(1):141.10.1186/s40478-022-01438-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9494883</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36131298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Zee J, Gijselinck I, Dillen L, Van Langenhove T, Theuns J, Engelborghs S, Philtjens S, Vandenbulcke M, Sleegers K, Sieben A, Baumer V, Maes G, Corsmit E, Borroni B, Padovani A, Archetti S, Perneczky R, Diehl-Schmid J, de Mendonca A, Miltenberger-Miltenyi G, Pereira S, Pimentel J, Nacmias B, Bagnoli S, Sorbi S, Graff C, Chiang HH, Westerlund M, Sanchez-Valle R, Llado A, Gelpi E, Santana I, Almeida MR, Santiago B, Frisoni G, Zanetti O, Bonvicini C, Synofzik M, Maetzler W, Vom Hagen JM, Schols L, Heneka MT, Jessen F, Matej R, Parobkova E, Kovacs GG, Strobel T, Sarafov S, Tournev I, Jordanova A, Danek A, Arzberger T, Fabrizi GM, Testi S, Salmon E, Santens P, Martin JJ, Cras P, Vandenberghe R, De Deyn PP, Cruts M, Van Broeckhoven C, van der Zee J, Gijselinck I, Dillen L, Van Langenhove T, Theuns J, Philtjens S, Sleegers K, Baumer V, Maes G, Corsmit E, Cruts M, Van Broeckhoven C, van der Zee J, Gijselinck I, Dillen L, Van Langenhove T, Philtjens S, Theuns J, Sleegers K, Baumer V, Maes G, Cruts M, Van Broeckhoven C, Engelborghs S, De Deyn PP, Cras P, Engelborghs S, De Deyn PP, Vandenbulcke M, Vandenbulcke M, Borroni B, Padovani A, Archetti S, Perneczky R, Diehl-Schmid J, Synofzik M, Maetzler W, Muller Vom Hagen J, Schols L, Synofzik M, Maetzler W, Muller Vom Hagen J, Schols L, Heneka MT, Jessen F, Ramirez A, Kurzwelly D, Sachtleben C, Mairer W, de Mendonca A, Miltenberger-Miltenyi G, Pereira S, Firmo C, Pimentel J, Sanchez-Valle R, Llado A, Antonell A, Molinuevo J, Gelpi E, Graff C, Chiang HH, Westerlund M, Graff C, Kinhult Stahlbom A, Thonberg H, Nennesmo I, Borjesson-Hanson A, Nacmias B, Bagnoli S, Sorbi S, Bessi V, Piaceri I, Santana I, Santiago B, Santana I, Helena Ribeiro M, Rosario Almeida M, Oliveira C, Massano J, Garret C, Pires P, Frisoni G, Zanetti O, Bonvicini C, Sarafov S, Tournev I, Jordanova A, Tournev I, Kovacs GG, Strobel T, Heneka MT, Jessen F, Ramirez A, Kurzwelly D, Sachtleben C, Mairer W, Jessen F, Matej R, Parobkova E, Danel A, Arzberger T, Maria Fabrizi G, Testi S, Ferrari S, Cavallaro T, Salmon E, Santens P, Cras P, European Early-Onset Dementia Consortium A pan-European study of the C9orf72 repeat associated with FTLD: geographic prevalence, genomic instability, and intermediate repeats. Hum Mutat. 2013;34:363&#x2013;373. doi: 10.1002/humu.22244.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/humu.22244</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3638346</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23111906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gijselinck I, Van Mossevelde S, van der Zee J, Sieben A, Engelborghs S, De Bleecker J, Ivanoiu A, Deryck O, Edbauer D, Zhang M, Heeman B, Baumer V, Van den Broeck M, Mattheijssens M, Peeters K, Rogaeva E, De Jonghe P, Cras P, Martin JJ, de Deyn PP, Cruts M, Van Broeckhoven C. The C9orf72 repeat size correlates with onset age of disease, DNA methylation and transcriptional downregulation of the promoter. Mol Psychiatry. 2016;21:1112&#x2013;1124. doi: 10.1038/mp.2015.159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/mp.2015.159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4960451</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26481318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beck J, Poulter M, Hensman D, Rohrer JD, Mahoney CJ, Adamson G, Campbell T, Uphill J, Borg A, Fratta P, Orrell RW, Malaspina A, Rowe J, Brown J, Hodges J, Sidle K, Polke JM, Houlden H, Schott JM, Fox NC, Rossor MN, Tabrizi SJ, Isaacs AM, Hardy J, Warren JD, Collinge J, Mead S. Large C9orf72 hexanucleotide repeat expansions are seen in multiple neurodegenerative syndromes and are more frequent than expected in the UK population. Am J Hum Genet. 2013;92:345&#x2013;353. doi: 10.1016/j.ajhg.2013.01.011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ajhg.2013.01.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3591848</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23434116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaivola K, Kiviharju A, Jansson L, Rantalainen V, Eriksson JG, Strandberg TE, Laaksovirta H, Renton AE, Traynor BJ, Myllykangas L, Tienari PJ (2019) C9orf72 hexanucleotide repeat length in older population: normal variation and effects on cognition. Neurobiol Aging 84:242e7&#x2013;242e12.&#xa0;10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2019.02.026</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8981799</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30979436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thys RG, Wang YH. DNA replication dynamics of the GGGGCC repeat of the C9orf72 gene. J Biol Chem. 2015;290(48):28953&#x2013;28962. doi: 10.1074/jbc.M115.660324.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1074/jbc.M115.660324</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4661408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26463209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rostalski H, Korhonen V, Kuulasmaa T, Solje E, Kr&#xfc;ger J, Gen F, Kaivola K, Eide PK, Lambert JC, Julkunen V, Tienari PJ, Remes AM, Leinonen V, Hiltunen M, Haapasalo A. A novel genetic marker for the C9orf72 repeat expansion in the finnish population. J Alzheimers Dis. 2021;83(3):1325&#x2013;1332. doi: 10.3233/JAD-210599.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/JAD-210599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34397416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>