<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36504126</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>07</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1432-1912</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>396</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Naunyn-Schmiedeberg's archives of pharmacology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Naunyn Schmiedebergs Arch Pharmacol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Proinflammatory IL-17 levels in serum/cerebrospinal fluid of patients with neurodegenerative diseases: a meta-analysis study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>577</StartPage><EndPage>588</EndPage><MedlinePgn>577-588</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s00210-022-02357-6</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>IL-17 is one of the major proinflammatory cytokine implicated in the pathophysiology of various chronic inflammatory diseases. However, a clear association between the levels of IL-17 and various neurodegenerative diseases is inconclusive due to lack of consistent results reported in several studies. Therefore, we designed and performed a meta-analysis study to assess the levels of IL-17 cytokine in various neurodegenerative diseases. The aim of this meta-analysis study was to assess the level of IL-17 in cerebrospinal fluid/serum of the patients with neurodegenerative diseases such as Alzheimer's disease, Parkinson disease, multiple sclerosis, and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. An extensive search was performed on electronic databases including PubMed, Cochrane, and Google Scholar to find out the relevant studies for analysis. The quality of selected studies was assessed by Newcastle-Ottawa scale for cohort and case control studies. The standardized mean difference of level of IL-17 in patients with neurodegenerative diseases and control was calculated using RevMan 5 software. A significant increase in the level of serum IL-17 was found to in the patients with neurodegenerative diseases like Alzheimer's disease (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.001) and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.009), whereas IL-17 level in serum of Parkinson's disease (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.22), multiple sclerosis (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.09), and in peripheral blood mononuclear cells of MS patients (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.34) was not found to be significant. IL-17 may be involved in regulation of neuronal inflammation during the pathogenesis of these neurodegenerative disease, and its specific inhibition could be a potential therapeutic target.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer-Verlag GmbH Germany, part of Springer Nature.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gautam</LastName><ForeName>Avtar Singh</ForeName><Initials>AS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacology and Toxicology, National Institute of Pharmaceutical Education and Research, Raebareli, Transit Campus, Bijnour-Sisendi Road, Sarojini Nagar, Lucknow, 226002, Uttar Pradesh, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pulivarthi</LastName><ForeName>Chinna Babu</ForeName><Initials>CB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Regulatory Toxicology, National Institute of Pharmaceutical Education and Research, Raebareli, Transit Campus, Bijnour-Sisendi Road, Sarojini Nagar, Lucknow, 226002, Uttar Pradesh, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Singh</LastName><ForeName>Rakesh Kumar</ForeName><Initials>RK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacology and Toxicology, National Institute of Pharmaceutical Education and Research, Raebareli, Transit Campus, Bijnour-Sisendi Road, Sarojini Nagar, Lucknow, 226002, Uttar Pradesh, India. rakesh.singh@niperraebareli.edu.in.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Naunyn Schmiedebergs Arch Pharmacol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0326264</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0028-1298</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D020381">Interleukin-17</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D016207">Cytokines</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019636" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neurodegenerative Diseases</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000544" MajorTopicYN="Y">Alzheimer Disease</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020381" MajorTopicYN="N">Interleukin-17</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007963" MajorTopicYN="N">Leukocytes, Mononuclear</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010300" MajorTopicYN="Y">Parkinson Disease</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016207" MajorTopicYN="N">Cytokines</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009103" MajorTopicYN="Y">Multiple Sclerosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Biomarkers</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">IL-17</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neuroinflammation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Proinflammatory cytokine</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36504126</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00210-022-02357-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s00210-022-02357-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Aa H, Ak M, Ad&#x2019;hiah A, Af A (2014) The level of IL-1&#x3b1;, IL-10 and IL-17A in Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease patients: comparative study. Joutrnal of Baghdad for Science 11:1486&#x2013;1492</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21123/bsj.11.4.1486-1492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashtari F, Madanian R, Shaygannejad V, Zarkesh SH, Ghadimi K (2019) Serum levels of IL-6 and IL-17 in multiple sclerosis, neuromyelitis optica patients and healthy subjects. International Journal of Physiology, Pathophysiology and Pharmacology 11:267&#x2013;273</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babaloo Z, Yeganeh RK, Farhoodi M, Baradaran B, Bonyadi M, Aghebati L (2013) Increased IL-17A but decreased IL-27 serum levels in patients with multiple sclerosis. Iranian Journal of Immunology&#x202f;: IJI 10:47&#x2013;54</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brigas HC, Ribeiro M, Coelho JE, Gomes R, Gomez-Murcia V, Carvalho K, Faivre E, Costa-Pereira S, Darrigues J, de Almeida AA, Bu&#xe9;e L, Dunot J, Marie H, Pousinha PA, Blum D, Silva-Santos B, Lopes LV, Ribot JC (2021) IL-17 triggers the onset of cognitive and synaptic deficits in early stages of Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. Cell Rep 36:109574</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.celrep.2021.109574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen H, Tang X, Li J, Hu B, Yang W, Zhan M, Ma T, Xu S (2022) IL-17 crosses the blood&#x2013;brain barrier to trigger neuroinflammation: a novel mechanism in nitroglycerin-induced chronic migraine. J Headache Pain 23:1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s10194-021-01374-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen J, Liu X, Zhong Y (2020) Interleukin-17A: the key cytokine in neurodegenerative diseases. Front Aging Neurosci 12:566922. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnagi.2020.566922</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnagi.2020.566922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen JM, Jiang GX, Li QW, Zhou ZM, Cheng Q (2014) Increased serum levels of interleukin-18, -23 and -17 in Chinese patients with Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. Dement Geriatr Cogn Disord 38:321&#x2013;329</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000360606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen X, Hu Y, Cao Z, Liu Q, Cheng Y (2018) Cerebrospinal fluid inflammatory cytokine aberrations in alzheimer&#x2019;s disease, Parkinson&#x2019;s disease and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Immunol 9:2122. https://doi.org/10.3389/fimmu.2018.02122</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen YC, Chen SD, Miao L, Liu ZG, Li W, Zhao ZX, Sun XJ, Jiang GX, Cheng Q (2012) Serum levels of interleukin (IL)-18, IL-23 and IL-17 in Chinese patients with multiple sclerosis. J Neuroimmunol 243:56&#x2013;60</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jneuroim.2011.12.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cristiano C, Volpicelli F, Lippiello P, Buono B, Raucci F, Piccolo M, Iqbal AJ, Irace C, Miniaci MC, Perrone Capano C, Calignano A, Mascolo N, Maione F (2019) Neutralization of IL-17 rescues amyloid-&#x3b2;-induced neuroinflammation and memory impairment. Br J Pharmacol 176:3544&#x2013;3557</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bph.14586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#x2019;Anna L, Abu-Rumeileh S, Fabris M, Pistis C, Baldi A, Sanvilli N, Curcio F, Gigli GL, D&#x2019;Anna S, Valente M (2017) Serum interleukin-10 levels correlate with cerebrospinal fluid amyloid beta deposition in Alzheimer disease patients. Neurodegener Dis 17:227&#x2013;234</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000474940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de la Monte AM, Daiello LA, Hapel AJ, Tong M, Ott BR (2017) Altered serum and cerebrospinal fluid inflammatory cascades in mild cognitive impairment and alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. J Neuroinflamm Neurodegener Dis 1:100004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dubenko OE, Chyniak OS, Potapov OO (2021) Levels of proinflammatory cytokines IL-17 and IL-23 in patients with Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease, mild cognitive impairment and vascular dementia. Wiadomosci lekarskie (Warsaw, Poland&#x202f;: 1960) 74:68&#x2013;71</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.36740/WLek202101113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esendagli G, Kurne AT, Sayat G, Kilic AK, Guc D, Karabudak R (2013) Evaluation of Th17-related cytokines and receptors in multiple sclerosis patients under interferon &#x3b2;-1 therapy. J Neuroimmunol 255:81&#x2013;84</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jneuroim.2012.10.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fiala M, Chattopadhay M, La Cava A, Tse E, Liu G, Lourenco E, Eskin A, Liu PT, Magpantay L, Tse S, Mahanian M, Weitzman R, Tong J, Nguyen C, Cho T, Koo P, Sayre J, Martinez-Maza O, Rosenthal MJ, Wiedau-Pazos M (2010) IL-17A is increased in the serum and in spinal cord CD8 and mast cells of ALS patients. J Neuroinflammation 7:76</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1742-2094-7-76</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furukawa T, Matsui N, Fujita K, Nodera H, Shimizu F, Miyamoto K, Takahashi Y, Kanda T, Kusunoki S, Izumi Y, Kaji R (2015) CSF cytokine profile distinguishes multifocal motor neuropathy from progressive muscular atrophy. Neurology (R) Neuroimmunol Neuroinflammation 2:e138</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/NXI.0000000000000138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graber JJ, Allie SR, Mullen KM, Jones MV, Wang T, Krishnan C, Kaplin AI, Nath A, Kerr DA, Calabresi PA (2008) Interleukin-17 in transverse myelitis and multiple sclerosis. J Neuroimmunol 196:124&#x2013;132</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jneuroim.2008.02.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green HF, Khosousi S, Svenningsson P (2019) Plasma IL-6 and IL-17A correlate with severity of motor and non-motor symptoms in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. J Parkinsons Dis 9:705&#x2013;709</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/JPD-191699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guzman-Martinez L, Maccioni RB, Andrade V, Navarrete LP, Pastor MG, Ramos-Escobar N (2019) Neuroinflammation as a common feature of neurodegenerative disorders. Front Pharmacol 10:1008. https://doi.org/10.3389/fphar.2019.01008</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harrington LE, Hatton RD, Mangan PR, Turner H, Murphy TL, Murphy KM, Weaver CT (2005) Interleukin 17-producing CD4+ effector T cells develop via a lineage distinct from the T helper type 1 and 2 lineages. Nat Immunol 6:1123&#x2013;1132</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ni1254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Havrdov&#xe1; E, Belova A, Goloborodko A, Tisserant A, Wright A, Wallstroem E, Garren H, Maguire RP, Johns DR (2016) Activity of secukinumab, an anti-IL-17A antibody, on brain lesions in RRMS: results from a randomized, proof-of-concept study. J Neurol 263:1287&#x2013;1295</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00415-016-8128-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hofstetter HH, Ibrahim SM, Koczan D, Kruse N, Weishaupt A, Toyka KV, Gold R (2005) Therapeutic efficacy of IL-17 neutralization in murine experimental autoimmune encephalomyelitis. Cell Immunol 237:123&#x2013;130</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cellimm.2005.11.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin M, Akg&#xfc;n K, Ziemssen T, Kipp M, G&#xfc;nther R, Hermann A (2021) Interleukin-17 and Th17 lymphocytes directly impair motoneuron survival of wildtype and FUS-ALS mutant human iPSCs. Int J Mol Sci 22:8042. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms22158042</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kebir H, Kreymborg K, Ifergan I, Dodelet-Devillers A, Cayrol R, Bernard M, Giuliani F, Arbour N, Becher B, Prat A (2007) Human TH17 lymphocytes promote blood-brain barrier disruption and central nervous system inflammation. Nat Med 13:1173&#x2013;1175</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nm1651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan D, Ansar Ahmed S (2015) Regulation of IL-17 in autoimmune diseases by transcriptional factors and microRNAs. Front Genet 6:236. https://doi.org/10.3389/fgene.2015.00236</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuwabara T, Ishikawa F, Kondo M, Kakiuchi T (2017) The role of IL-17 and related cytokines in inflammatory autoimmune diseases. Mediators Inflamm 2017:3908061</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2017/3908061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y-F, Zhang S-X, Ma X-W, Xue Y-L, Gao C, Li X-Y (2017) Levels of peripheral Th17 cells and serum Th17-related cytokines in patients with multiple sclerosis: a meta-analysis. Multiple Sclerosis and Related Disorders 18:20&#x2013;25</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.msard.2017.09.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Wang H, Long Y, Lu Z, Hu X (2011) Increased memory Th17 cells in patients with neuromyelitis optica and multiple sclerosis. J Neuroimmunol 234:155&#x2013;160</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jneuroim.2011.03.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Z, Qiu AW, Huang Y, Yang Y, Chen JN, Gu TT, Cao BB, Qiu YH, Peng YP (2019) IL-17A exacerbates neuroinflammation and neurodegeneration by activating microglia in rodent models of Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Brain Behav Immun 81:630&#x2013;645</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbi.2019.07.026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGeachy MJ, Cua DJ, Gaffen SL (2019) The IL-17 family of cytokines in health and disease. Immunity 50:892&#x2013;906</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.immuni.2019.03.021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGinley AM, Sutton CE, Edwards SC, Leane CM, DeCourcey J, Teijeiro A, Hamilton JA, Boon L, Djouder N, Mills KHG (2020) Interleukin-17A serves a priming role in autoimmunity by recruiting IL-1&#x3b2;-producing myeloid cells that promote pathogenic T cells. Immunity 52:342-356.e346</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.immuni.2020.01.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melnikov M, Sharanova S, Sviridova A, Rogovskii V, Murugina N, Nikolaeva A, Dagil Y, Murugin V, Ospelnikova T, Boyko A, Pashenkov M (2020) The influence of glatiramer acetate on Th17-immune response in multiple sclerosis. PLoS ONE 15:e0240305</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0240305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miksys SL, Tyndale RF (2010) Neurodegenerative Diseases: a Growing Challenge 88:427&#x2013;430</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milovanovic J, Arsenijevic A, Stojanovic B, Kanjevac T, Arsenijevic D, Radosavljevic G, Milovanovic M, Arsenijevic N (2020) Interleukin-17 in Chronic inflammatory neurological diseases. Front Immunol 11:947. https://doi.org/10.3389/fimmu.2020.00947</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Modesti PA, Reboldi G, Cappuccio FP, Agyemang C, Remuzzi G, Rapi S, Perruolo E, Parati G, Settings, E.S.H.W.G.o.C.R.i.L.R. (2016) Panethnic differences in blood pressure in Europe: a systematic review and meta-analysis. PLoS ONE 11:e0147601</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0147601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morgan RL, Whaley P, Thayer KA, Sch&#xfc;nemann HJ (2018) Identifying the PECO: A framework for formulating good questions to explore the association of environmental and other exposures with health outcomes. Environ Int 121:1027&#x2013;1031</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.envint.2018.07.015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Motta C, Finardi A, Toniolo S, Di Lorenzo F, Scaricamazza E, Loizzo S, Mercuri NB, Furlan R, Koch G, Martorana A (2020) Protective role of cerebrospinal fluid inflammatory cytokines in patients with amnestic mild cognitive impairment and early Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease carrying apolipoprotein E4 genotype. Journal of Alzheimer&#x2019;s Disease&#x202f;: JAD 76:681&#x2013;689</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/JAD-191250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oberstein TJ, Taha L, Spitzer P, Hellstern J, Herrmann M, Kornhuber J, Maler JM (2018) Imbalance of circulating T(h)17 and regulatory T cells in Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease: a case control study. Front Immunol 9:1213</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2018.01213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orallar HS, Karab&#xf6;cek &#x15e;, Bozat BG, Ayd&#x131;n V, Turkoglu SA (2019) Cerebrospinal fluid (CSF) IL-17A, IL-17F, IL-34 and CXCL-13 levels in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS/MND) patients. Medical Sciences (NWSAMS) 14:154&#x2013;162</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rentzos M, Rombos A, Nikolaou C, Zoga M, Zouvelou V, Dimitrakopoulos A, Alexakis T, Tsoutsou A, Samakovli A, Michalopoulou M, Evdokimidis J (2010) Interleukin-17 and interleukin-23 are elevated in serum and cerebrospinal fluid of patients with ALS: a reflection of Th17 cells activation? Acta Neurol Scand 122:425&#x2013;429</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1600-0404.2010.01333.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rouvier E, Luciani MF, Matt&#xe9;i MG, Denizot F, Golstein P (1993) CTLA-8, cloned from an activated T cell, bearing AU-rich messenger RNA instability sequences, and homologous to a herpesvirus saimiri gene. J Immunol 150:5445&#x2013;5456</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4049/jimmunol.150.12.5445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shabgah AG, Fattahi E, Shahneh FZ (2014) Interleukin-17 in human inflammatory diseases. Postepy Dermatol Alergol 31:256&#x2013;261</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/pdia.2014.40954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siffrin V, Radbruch H, Glumm R, Niesner R, Paterka M, Herz J, Leuenberger T, Lehmann SM, Luenstedt S, Rinnenthal JL, Laube G, Luche H, Lehnardt S, Fehling HJ, Griesbeck O, Zipp F (2010) In vivo imaging of partially reversible th17 cell-induced neuronal dysfunction in the course of encephalomyelitis. Immunity 33:424&#x2013;436</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.immuni.2010.08.018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tateishi T, Yamasaki R, Tanaka M, Matsushita T, Kikuchi H, Isobe N, Ohyagi Y, Kira J (2010) CSF chemokine alterations related to the clinical course of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neuroimmunol 222:76&#x2013;81</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jneuroim.2010.03.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wells GA, Shea BJ, O&#x2019;Connell D, Peterson J, Welch V, Losos M, Tugwell P (2014) The Newcastle-Ottawa Scale (NOS) for assessing the quality of non-randomised studies in meta-analyses. ScienceOpen</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu S, Cao X (2010) Interleukin-17 and its expanding biological functions. Cell Mol Immunol 7:164&#x2013;174</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/cmi.2010.21</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang F, Li B, Li L, Zhang H (2016) The clinical significance of the imbalance of Th17 and Treg cells and their related cytokines in peripheral blood of Parkinson&#x2019;s disease patients. Int J Clin Exp Med 9:17946&#x2013;179519</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang J, Kou J, Lalonde R, Fukuchi KI (2017) Intracranial IL-17A overexpression decreases cerebral amyloid angiopathy by upregulation of ABCA1 in an animal model of Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. Brain Behav Immun 65:262&#x2013;273</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbi.2017.05.012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zenobia C, Hajishengallis G (2015a) Basic biology and role of interleukin-17 in immunity and inflammation. Periodontol 69:142&#x2013;159</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/prd.12083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zenobia C, Hajishengallis G (2015b) Basic biology and role of interleukin-17 in immunity and inflammation. Periodontol 69:142&#x2013;159</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/prd.12083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>