<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36511398</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>29</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1531-8249</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>93</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Annals of neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Ann Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Longitudinal Effects of Asymptomatic C9orf72 Carriership on Brain Morphology.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>668</StartPage><EndPage>680</EndPage><MedlinePgn>668-680</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/ana.26572</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">We investigated effects of C9orf72 repeat expansion and gene expression on longitudinal cerebral changes before symptom onset.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">We enrolled 79 asymptomatic family members (AFMs) from 9 families with C9orf72 repeat expansion. Twenty-eight AFMs carried the mutation (C9+). Participants had up to 3 magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) scans, after which we compared motor cortex and motor tracts between C9+ and C9- AFMs using mixed effects models, incorporating kinship to correct for familial relations and lessen effects of other genetic factors. We also compared cortical, subcortical, cerebellar, and connectome structural measurements in a hypothesis-free analysis. We correlated regional C9orf72 expression in donor brains with the pattern of cortical thinning in C9+ AFMs using meta-regression. For comparison, we included 42 C9+ and 439 C9- patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) in this analysis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">C9+ AFM motor cortex had less gyrification and was thinner than in C9- AFMs, without differences in motor tracts. Whole brain analysis revealed thinner cortex and less gyrification in parietal, occipital, and temporal regions, smaller thalami and right hippocampus, and affected frontotemporal connections. Thinning of bilateral precentral, precuneus, and left superior parietal cortex was faster in C9+ than in C9- AFMs. Higher C9orf72 expression correlated with thinner cortex in both C9+ AFMs and C9+ ALS patients.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="INTERPRETATION">In asymptomatic C9orf72 repeat expansion carriers, brain MRI reveals widespread features suggestive of impaired neurodevelopment, along with faster decline of motor and parietal cortex than found in normal aging. C9orf72 expression might play a role in cortical development, and consequently explain the specific brain abnormalities of mutation carriers. ANN NEUROL 2023;93:668-680.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022 The Authors. Annals of Neurology published by Wiley Periodicals LLC on behalf of American Neurological Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>van Veenhuijzen</LastName><ForeName>Kevin</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4386-2351</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Brain Center, University Medical Center Utrecht, Utrecht University, Utrecht, the Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Westeneng</LastName><ForeName>Henk-Jan</ForeName><Initials>HJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7138-3852</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Brain Center, University Medical Center Utrecht, Utrecht University, Utrecht, the Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tan</LastName><ForeName>Harold H G</ForeName><Initials>HHG</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2981-9680</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Brain Center, University Medical Center Utrecht, Utrecht University, Utrecht, the Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nitert</LastName><ForeName>Abram D</ForeName><Initials>AD</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7941-6663</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Brain Center, University Medical Center Utrecht, Utrecht University, Utrecht, the Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>van der Burgh</LastName><ForeName>Hannelore K</ForeName><Initials>HK</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2898-0429</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Brain Center, University Medical Center Utrecht, Utrecht University, Utrecht, the Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gosselt</LastName><ForeName>Isabel</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Brain Center, University Medical Center Utrecht, Utrecht University, Utrecht, the Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center of Excellence for Rehabilitation Medicine, Brain Center, University Medical Center Utrecht and De Hoogstraat Rehabilitation, Utrecht, the Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>van Es</LastName><ForeName>Michael A</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7709-5883</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Brain Center, University Medical Center Utrecht, Utrecht University, Utrecht, the Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nijboer</LastName><ForeName>Tanja C W</ForeName><Initials>TCW</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6683-0267</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Experimental Psychology, Utrecht University, Utrecht, the Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Veldink</LastName><ForeName>Jan H</ForeName><Initials>JH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5572-9657</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Brain Center, University Medical Center Utrecht, Utrecht University, Utrecht, the Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>van den Berg</LastName><ForeName>Leonard H</ForeName><Initials>LH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5203-9674</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Brain Center, University Medical Center Utrecht, Utrecht University, Utrecht, the Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Ann Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7707449</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0364-5134</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000073885">C9orf72 Protein</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C568651">C9orf72 protein, human</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000073885" MajorTopicYN="N">C9orf72 Protein</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001921" MajorTopicYN="N">Brain</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009154" MajorTopicYN="N">Mutation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008279" MajorTopicYN="N">Magnetic Resonance Imaging</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D042622" MajorTopicYN="N">DNA Repeat Expansion</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Frontotemporal Dementia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36511398</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.26572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>van Es MA, Hardiman O, Chio A, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet 2017;390:2084-2098.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Majounie E, Renton AE, Mok K, et al. Frequency of the C9orf72 hexanucleotide repeat expansion in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal dementia: a cross-sectional study. Lancet Neurol 2012;11:323-330.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayl K, Shaw CE, Lee Y-B. Disease mechanisms and therapeutic approaches in C9orf72 ALS-FTD. Biomedicine 2021;9:601.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bede P, Bokde ALW, Byrne S, et al. Multiparametric MRI study of ALS stratified for the C9orf72 genotype. Neurology 2013;81:361-369.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westeneng H-J, Walhout R, Straathof M, et al. Widespread structural brain involvement in ALS is not limited to the C9orf72 repeat expansion. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2016;87:1354-1360.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walhout R, Schmidt R, Westeneng H-J, et al. Brain morphologic changes in asymptomatic C9orf72 repeat expansion carriers. Neurology 2015;85:1780-1788.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blokland GAM, de Zubicaray GI, McMahon KL, Wright MJ. Genetic and environmental influences on neuroimaging phenotypes: a meta-analytical perspective on twin imaging studies. Twin Res Hum Genet 2012;15:351-371.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nitert AD, Tan HHG, Walhout R, et al. Sensitivity of brain MRI and neurological examination for detection of upper motor neurone degeneration in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2022;93(1):82-92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakker LA, Schr&#xf6;der CD, Spreij LA. Derivation of norms for the Dutch version of the Edinburgh cognitive and behavioral ALS screen. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2019;20:19-27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, Miller RG, Swash M, et al. El Escorial revisited: revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord 2000;1:293-299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum JM, Stambler N, Malta E, et al. The ALSFRS-R: a revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. J Neurol Sci 1999;169:13-21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huisman MHB, de Jong SW, van Doormaal PTC, et al. Population based epidemiology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis using capture-recapture methodology. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2011;82:1165-1170.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Rheenen W, van Blitterswijk M, Huisman MHB, et al. Hexanucleotide repeat expansions in C9ORF72 in the spectrum of motor neuron diseases. Neurology 2012;79:878-882.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verstraete E, Veldink JH, Mandl RCW, et al. Impaired structural motor connectome in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. PLoS One 2011;6:e24239.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desikan RS, S&#xe9;gonne F, Fischl B, et al. An automated labeling system for subdividing the human cerebral cortex on MRI scans into gyral based regions of interest. Neuroimage 2006;31:968-980.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han S, Carass A, He Y, Prince JL. Automatic cerebellum anatomical parcellation using U-Net with locally constrained optimization. Neuroimage 2020;218:116819.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reuter M, Rosas HD, Fischl B. Highly accurate inverse consistent registration: a robust approach. Neuroimage 2010;53:1181-1196.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reuter M, Schmansky NJ, Rosas HD, Fischl B. Within-subject template estimation for unbiased longitudinal image analysis. Neuroimage 2012;61:1402-1418.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schaer M, Cuadra MB, Schmansky N, et al. How to measure cortical folding from MR images: a step-by-step tutorial to compute local gyrification index. J Visualized Exp 2012;59:e3417.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yendiki A, Panneck P, Srinivasan P, et al. Automated probabilistic reconstruction of white-matter pathways in health and disease using an atlas of the underlying anatomy. Front Neuroinform 2011;5:23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mori S, Crain BJ, Chacko VP, van Zijl PC. Three-dimensional tracking of axonal projections in the brain by magnetic resonance imaging. Ann Neurol 1999;45:265-269.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Reus MA, van den Heuvel MP. Estimating false positives and negatives in brain networks. Neuroimage 2013;70:402-409.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allen T. ALLEN human Brain Atlas Technical White Paper: Microarray Survey [Internet] [cited 2021 Dec 17] Available from: https://help.brain-map.org/download/attachments/2818165/WholeBrainMicroarray_WhitePaper.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnatkeviciute A, Fulcher BD, Fornito A. A practical guide to linking brain-wide gene expression and neuroimaging data. Neuroimage 2019;189:353-367.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hawrylycz M, Miller JA, Menon V, et al. Canonical genetic signatures of the adult human brain. Nat Neurosci 2015;18:1832-1844.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>French L, Paus T. A FreeSurfer view of the cortical transcriptome generated from the Allen human brain atlas. Front Neurosci 2015;9:323.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fulcher BD, Little MA, Jones NS. Highly comparative time-series analysis: the empirical structure of time series and their methods. J R Soc Interface 2013;10:20130048.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lezak MD, Howieson DB, Bigler ED, Tranel D. Neuropsychological Assessment. 5th ed. New York, NY: Oxford University Press, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao B, Mwangi B, Passos IC, et al. Lifespan Gyrification trajectories of human brain in healthy individuals and patients with major psychiatric disorders. Sci Rep 2017;7:511.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davison AC, Hinkley DV. Bootstrap methods and their application. Cambridge, England: Cambridge University Press, 1997.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zalesky A, Fornito A, Bullmore ET. Network-based statistic: identifying differences in brain networks. Neuroimage 2010;53:1197-1207.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caverzasi E, Battistella G, Chu SA, et al. Gyrification abnormalities in presymptomatic c9orf72 expansion carriers. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2019;90:1005-1010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>White T, Su S, Schmidt M, et al. The development of gyrification in childhood and adolescence. Brain Cogn 2010;72:36-45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeh T-H, Liu H-F, Li Y-W, et al. C9orf72 is essential for neurodevelopment and motility mediated by cyclin G1. Exp Neurol 2018;304:114-124.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lall D, Lorenzini I, Mota TA, et al. C9orf72 deficiency promotes microglial-mediated synaptic loss in aging and amyloid accumulation. Neuron 2021;109:2275-2291.e8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee SE, Sias AC, Mandelli ML, et al. Network degeneration and dysfunction in presymptomatic C9ORF72 expansion carriers. Neuroimage 2017;14:286-297.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Popuri K, Dowds E, Beg MF, et al. Gray matter changes in asymptomatic C9orf72 and GRN mutation carriers. Neuroimage 2018;18:591-598.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bertrand A, Wen J, Rinaldi D, et al. Early cognitive, structural, and microstructural changes in presymptomatic C9orf72 carriers younger than 40&#x2009;years. JAMA Neurol 2018;75:236-245.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wen J, Zhang H, Alexander DC, et al. Neurite density is reduced in the presymptomatic phase of C9orf72 disease. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2019;90:387-394.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bocchetta M, Todd EG, Peakman G, et al. Differential early subcortical involvement in genetic FTD within the GENFI cohort. Neuroimage 2021;30:102646.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Floeter MK, Bageac D, Danielian LE, et al. Longitudinal imaging in C9orf72 mutation carriers: relationship to phenotype. Neuroimage 2016;12:1035-1043.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panman JL, Jiskoot LC, Bouts MJRJ, et al. Gray and white matter changes in presymptomatic genetic frontotemporal dementia: a longitudinal MRI study. Neurobiol Aging 2019;76:115-124.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le Blanc G, Jett&#xe9; Pomerleau V, McCarthy J, et al. Faster cortical thinning and surface area loss in presymptomatic and symptomatic C9orf72 repeat expansion adult carriers. Ann Neurol 2020;88:113-122.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Burgh HK, Westeneng H-J, Walhout R, et al. Multimodal longitudinal study of structural brain involvement in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology 2020;94:e2592-e2604.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coup&#xe9; P, Catheline G, Lanuza E, et al. Towards a unified analysis of brain maturation and aging across the entire lifespan: a MRI analysis. Hum Brain Mapp 2017;38:5501-5518.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balendra R, Isaacs AM. C9orf72-mediated ALS and FTD: multiple pathways to disease. Nat Rev Neurol 2018;14:544-558.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dick JPR. The deep tendon and the abdominal reflexes. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2003;74:150-153.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niven E, Newton J, Foley J, et al. Validation of the Edinburgh cognitive and behavioural amyotrophic lateral sclerosis screen (ECAS): a cognitive tool for motor disorders. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2015;16:172-179.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>