<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36527420</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-4159</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>164</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of neurochemistry</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Neurochem</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>MicroRNA-183-5p regulates TAR DNA-binding protein 43 neurotoxicity via SQSTM1/p62 in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>643</StartPage><EndPage>657</EndPage><MedlinePgn>643-657</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/jnc.15744</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) is a fatal neurodegenerative disease that selectively attacks motor neurons, and leads to progressive muscle weakness and death. A common pathological feature is the misfolding, aggregation, and cytoplasmic mislocalization of TAR DNA-binding protein 43 (TDP-43) proteins in more than 95% of ALS patients, suggesting a universal role TDP-43 proteinopathy in ALS. Mutations in SQSTM1/p62 have been identified in familial and sporadic cases of ALS. MicroRNAs (miRNAs) are small non-coding RNAs that post-transcriptionally regulate their target genes. Emerging evidence indicates that miRNA dysregulation is associated with neuronal toxicity and mitochondrial dysfunction, and also plays a pivotal role in ALS pathogenesis. Here, we report the first evidence that miR-183-5p is aberrantly upregulated in spinal cords of patients with ALS. Using luciferase reporter assays and miR-183-5p agomirs, we demonstrate that miR-183-5p regulates the SQSTM1/p62 3'-untranslated region to suppress expression. A miR-183-5p agomir attenuated SOSTM1/p62 expression and led to an increase in TDP-43 protein levels in neuronal and non-neuronal cells. In contrast, a miR-183-5p antagomir decreased TDP-43 but increased SQSTM1/p62 protein levels. The antagomir repressed formation of stress granules and aggregated TDP43 protein in neuronal cells under stress-induced conditions and protected against cytotoxicity. Knockdown of SQSTM1/p62 decreased total ubiquitination and increased TDP-43 protein aggregation, indicating that SQSTM1/p62 may play a protective role in cells. In summary, our study reveals a novel mechanism of TDP-43 proteinopathy mediated by the miR-183-5p and provides a molecular link between aberrant RNA processing and protein degradation, two major pillars in ALS pathogenesis.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022 International Society for Neurochemistry.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Han-Cheon</ForeName><Initials>HC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1960-5048</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Baylor College of Medicine, Houston, Texas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Michael E. DeBakey VA Medical Center, Houston, Texas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Yan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Baylor College of Medicine, Houston, Texas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Michael E. DeBakey VA Medical Center, Houston, Texas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>King</LastName><ForeName>Peter H</ForeName><Initials>PH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of Alabama at Birmingham, Birmingham, Alabama, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Birmingham VA Medical Center, Birmingham, Alabama, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lu</LastName><ForeName>Liang</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1276-2358</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Baylor College of Medicine, Houston, Texas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Michael E. DeBakey VA Medical Center, Houston, Texas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R01 NS092651</GrantID><Acronym>NS</Acronym><Agency>NINDS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R21 NS111275</GrantID><Acronym>NS</Acronym><Agency>NINDS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013486">Research Support, U.S. Gov't, Non-P.H.S.</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Neurochem</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>2985190R</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0022-3042</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000071456">Sequestosome-1 Protein</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000070416">Antagomirs</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D035683">MicroRNAs</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D004268">DNA-Binding Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C099718">SQSTM1 protein, human</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C533449">MIRN183 microRNA, human</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000071456" MajorTopicYN="N">Sequestosome-1 Protein</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019636" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neurodegenerative Diseases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000070416" MajorTopicYN="N">Antagomirs</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009046" MajorTopicYN="N">Motor Neurons</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D035683" MajorTopicYN="Y">MicroRNAs</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004268" MajorTopicYN="N">DNA-Binding Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SQSTM1/p62</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">TAR DNA-binding protein 43 (TDP-43)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">aggregation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">microRNAs</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neurotoxicity</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36527420</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jnc.15744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Bartel, D. P. (2004). MicroRNAs: Genomics, biogenesis, mechanism, and function. Cell, 116, 281-297.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blokhuis, A. M., Groen, E. J., Koppers, M., van den Berg, L. H., &amp; Pasterkamp, R. J. (2013). Protein aggregation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathologica, 125, 777-794.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brady, O. A., Meng, P., Zheng, Y., Mao, Y., &amp; Hu, F. (2011). Regulation of TDP-43 aggregation by phosphorylation and p62/SQSTM1. Journal of Neurochemistry, 116, 248-259.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buratti, E., &amp; Baralle, F. E. (2008). Multiple roles of TDP-43 in gene expression, splicing regulation, and human disease. Frontiers in Bioscience, 13, 867-878.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, C. Z., Li, L., Lodish, H. F., &amp; Bartel, D. P. (2004). MicroRNAs modulate hematopoietic lineage differentiation. Science, 303, 83-86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, M. L., Hong, C. G., Yue, T., Li, H. M., Duan, R., Hu, W. B., Cao, J., Wang, Z. X., Chen, C. Y., Hu, X. K., Wu, B., Liu, H. M., Tan, Y. J., Liu, J. H., Luo, Z. W., Zhang, Y., Rao, S. S., Luo, M. J., Yin, H., &#x2026; Liu, Z. Z. (2021). Inhibition of miR-331-3p and miR-9-5p ameliorates Alzheimer's disease enhancing autophagy. Theranostics, 11, 2395-2409.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chu, C. T. (2019). Mechanisms of selective autophagy and mitophagy: Implications for neurodegenerative diseases. Neurobiology of Disease, 122, 23-34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cleveland, D. W., &amp; Rothstein, J. D. (2001). From Charcot to Lou Gehrig: Deciphering selective motor neuron death in ALS. Nature Reviews. Neuroscience, 2, 806-819.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen, T. J., Lee, V. M., &amp; Trojanowski, J. Q. (2011). TDP-43 functions and pathogenic mechanisms implicated in TDP-43 proteinopathies. Trends in Molecular Medicine, 17, 659-667.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Da Cruz, S., &amp; Cleveland, D. W. (2011). Understanding the role of TDP-43 and FUS/TLS in ALS and beyond. Current Opinion in Neurobiology, 21, 904-919.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Boer, E. M. J., Orie, V. K., Williams, T., Baker, M. R., De Oliveira, H. M., Polvikoski, T., Silsby, M., Menon, P., van den Bos, M., Halliday, G. M., van den Berg, L. H., Van Den Bosch, L., van Damme, P., Kiernan, M. C., van Es, M. A., &amp; Vucic, S. (2021). TDP-43 proteinopathies: A new wave of neurodegenerative diseases. Journal of Neurology, Neurosurgery, and Psychiatry, 92, 86-95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Felice, B., Guida, M., Guida, M., Coppola, C., De Mieri, G., &amp; Cotrufo, R. (2012). A miRNA signature in leukocytes from sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Gene, 508, 35-40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esteller, M. (2011). Non-coding RNAs in human disease. Nature Reviews. Genetics, 12, 861-874.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foster, A. D., Flynn, L. L., Cluning, C., Cheng, F., Davidson, J. M., Lee, A., Polain, N., Mejzini, R., Farrawell, N., Yerbury, J. J., Layfield, R., Akkari, P. A., &amp; Rea, S. L. (2021). p62 overexpression induces TDP-43 cytoplasmic mislocation, aggregation and cleavage and neuronal death. Scientific Reports, 11, 11474-11489.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gregory, J. M., Barros, T. P., Meehan, S., Dobson, C. M., &amp; Luheshi, L. M. (2012). The aggregation and neurotoxicity of TDP-43 and its ALS-associated 25 kDa fragment are differentially affected by molecular chaperones in drosophila. PLoS One, 7, e31899.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta, R., Ambasta, R. K., &amp; Kumar, P. (2021). Autophagy and apoptosis cascade: Which is more prominent in neuronal death? Cellular and Molecular Life Sciences, 78, 8001-8047.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hadano, S., Mitsui, S., Pan, L., Otomo, A., Kubo, M., Sato, K., Ono, S., Onodera, W., Abe, K., Chen, X., Koike, M., Uchiyama, Y., Aoki, M., Warabi, E., Yamamoto, M., Ishii, T., Yanagawa, T., Shang, H. F., &amp; Yoshii, F. (2016). Functional links between SQSTM1 and ALS2 in the pathogenesis of ALS: Cumulative impact on the protection against mutant SOD1- mediated motor dysfunction in mice. Human Molecular Genetics, 25, 3321-3340.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaur, P., Armugam, A., &amp; Jeyaseelan, K. (2012). MicroRNAs in neurotoxicity. International Journal of Toxicology, 2012, 870150-870115.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kosik, K. S., &amp; Nowakowski, T. (2018). Evolution of new miRNAs and Cerebro-cortical development. Annual Review of Neuroscience, 41, 119-137.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, X., Li, S., Zhao, Y., Ma, X., Zhang, K., He, X., &amp; Wang, Z. (2013). Interaction domains of p62: A bridge between p62 and selective autophagy. DNA and Cell Biology, 32, 220-227.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, Y. C., Lin, J. F., Tsai, T. F., Chou, K. Y., Chen, H. E., &amp; Hwang, T. I. (2017). Tumor suppressor miRNA-204-5p promotes apoptosis by targeting BCL2 in prostate cancer cells. Asian Journal of Surgery, 40, 396-406.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, W. J., Ye, L., Huang, W. F., Guo, L. J., Xu, Z. G., Wu, H. L., Yang, C., &amp; Liu, H. F. (2016). p62 links the autophagy pathway and the ubiquitin-proteasome system upon ubiquitinated protein degradation. Cellular &amp; Molecular Biology Letters, 21, 29-42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mens, M. M. J., &amp; Ghanbari, M. (2018). Cell cycle regulation of stem cells by MicroRNAs. Stem Cell Reviews, 14, 309-322. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12015-018-9808-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neumann, M., Sampathu, D. M., Kwong, L. K., Truax, A. C., Micsenyi, M. C., Chou, T. T., Bruce, J., Schuck, T., Grossman, M., Clark, C. M., McCluskey, L. F., Miller, B. L., Masliah, E., Mackenzie, I. R., Feldman, H., Feiden, W., Kretzschmar, H. A., Trojanowski, J. Q., &amp; Lee, V. M. Y. (2006). Ubiquitinated TDP-43 in frontotemporal lobar degeneration and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Science, 314, 130-133.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pasinelli, P., &amp; Brown, R. H. (2006). Molecular biology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Insights from genetics. Nature Reviews. Neuroscience, 7, 710-723.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pham, J., Keon, M., Brennan, S., &amp; Saksena, N. (2020). Connecting RNA-modifying similarities of TDP-43, FUS, and SOD1 with microRNA dysregulation amidst a renewed network perspective of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis proteinopathy. International Journal of Molecular Sciences, 21, 3464-3493.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prasad, A., Bharathi, V., Sivalingam, V., Girdhar, A., &amp; Patel, B. K. (2019). Molecular mechanisms of TDP-43 misfolding and pathology in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Frontiers in Molecular Neuroscience, 12, 25. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnmol.2019.00025</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajgor, D. (2018). Macro roles for microRNAs in neurodegenerative diseases. Non-coding RNA Research, 3, 154-159.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ravnik-Glava&#x10d;, M., &amp; Glava&#x10d;, D. (2020). Circulating RNAs as potential biomarkers in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. International Journal of Molecular Sciences, 21, 1714-1734.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rothstein, J. D. (2009). Current hypotheses for the underlying biology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Annals of Neurology, 65(suppl), S3-S9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rupaimoole, R., &amp; Slack, F. J. (2017). MicroRNA therapeutics: Towards a new era for the management of cancer and other diseases. Nature Reviews. Drug Discovery, 16, 203-222.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russell, A. P., Wada, S., Vergani, L., Hock, M. B., Lamon, S., L&#xe9;ger, B., Ushida, T., Cartoni, R., Wadley, G. D., &amp; Hespel, P. (2013). Disruption of skeletal muscle mitochondrial network genes and miRNAs in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurobiology of Disease, 49, 107-117.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saucier, D., Wajnberg, G., Roy, J., Beauregard, A. P., Chacko, S., Crapoulet, N., Fournier, S., Ghosh, A., Lewis, S. M., Marrero, A., O'Connell, C., Ouellette, R. J., &amp; Morin, P., Jr. (2019). Identification of a circulating miRNA signature in extracellular vesicles collected from amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. Brain Research, 1708, 100-108.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shin, J. (1998). p62 and the sequestosome, a novel mechanism for protein metabolism. Archives of Pharmacal Research, 21, 629-633.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soliman, A. M., Das, S., Abd Ghafar, N., &amp; Teoh, S. L. (2018). Role of MicroRNA in proliferation phase of wound healing. Frontiers in Genetics, 9, 38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swinnen, B., &amp; Robberecht, W. (2014). The phenotypic variability of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nature Reviews. Neurology, 10, 661-670.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tal, T. L., &amp; Tanguay, R. L. (2012). Non-coding RNAs--novel targets in neurotoxicity. Neurotoxicology, 33, 530-544.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teyssou, E., Takeda, T., Lebon, V., Boill&#xe9;e, S., Doukour&#xe9;, B., Bataillon, G., Sazdovitch, V., Cazeneuve, C., Meininger, V., LeGuern, E., Salachas, F., Seilhean, D., &amp; Millecamps, S. (2013). Mutations in SQSTM1 encoding p62 in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Genetics and neuropathology. Acta Neuropathologica, 125, 511-522.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, I. F., Wu, L. S., &amp; Shen, C. K. (2008). TDP-43: An emerging new player in neurodegenerative diseases. Trends in Molecular Medicine, 14, 479-485.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, X., &amp; Terpstra, E. J. (2013). Ubiquitin receptors and protein quality control. Journal of Molecular and Cellular Cardiology, 55, 73-84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wijesekera, L. C., &amp; Leigh, P. N. (2009). Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Orphanet Journal of Rare Diseases, 4, 3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winton, M. J., Igaz, L. M., Wong, M. M., Kwong, L. K., Trojanowski, J. Q., &amp; Lee, V. M. (2008). Disturbance of nuclear and cytoplasmic TAR DNA-binding protein (TDP-43) induces disease-like redistribution, sequestration, and aggregate formation. The Journal of Biological Chemistry, 283, 13302-13309.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, T., Mullane, P. C., Periz, G., &amp; Wang, J. (2011). TDP-43 neurotoxicity and protein aggregation modulated by heat shock factor and insulin/IGF-1 signaling. Human Molecular Genetics, 20, 1952-1965.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>