<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">36599142</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>13</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1728-7731</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>86</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of the Chinese Medical Association : JCMA</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Chin Med Assoc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Reduced-penetrance Huntington's disease-causing alleles with 39 CAG trinucleotide repeats could be a genetic factor of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>47</StartPage><EndPage>51</EndPage><MedlinePgn>47-51</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/JCMA.0000000000000837</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Expanded HTT alleles with 40 or more CAG repeats were recently found to be a rare cause of frontotemporal dementia and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) spectrum diseases. The aim of this study was to investigate the role of HTT repeat expansions in a Taiwanese cohort with ALS.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">We analyzed the numbers of CAG repeats in exon 1 of HTT in a cohort of 410 Taiwanese patients with ALS and 1514 control individuals by utilizing polymerase chain reaction and amplicon fragment length analysis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Only one of the 410 ALS patients carried a reduced-penetrance HD-causing allele with 39 CAG repeats, and none had an expanded HTT CAG repeats &#x2265;40. The patient presented with rapidly progressive bulbar-onset ALS with disease onset at the age of 64 years. He had neither chorea nor cognitive impairment. He had a family history of chorea, but no other family member manifested with ALS. None of the 1514 control individuals carried an HTT expanded allele with CAG repeats larger than 37 repeats.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">The HTT allele with 39 CAG repeats could be a genetic factor linked to ALS susceptibility.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022, the Chinese Medical Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jih</LastName><ForeName>Kang-Yang</ForeName><Initials>KY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Taipei Veterans General Hospital, Taipei, Taiwan, ROC.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology, National Yang Ming Chiao Tung University School of Medicine, Taipei, Taiwan, ROC.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, National Yang Ming Chiao Tung University School of Medicine, Taipei, Taiwan, ROC.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lai</LastName><ForeName>Kuan-Lin</ForeName><Initials>KL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Taipei Veterans General Hospital, Taipei, Taiwan, ROC.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, National Yang Ming Chiao Tung University School of Medicine, Taipei, Taiwan, ROC.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Brain Research Center, National Yang Ming Chiao Tung University, Taipei, Taiwan, ROC.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lin</LastName><ForeName>Kon-Ping</ForeName><Initials>KP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Taipei Veterans General Hospital, Taipei, Taiwan, ROC.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, National Yang Ming Chiao Tung University School of Medicine, Taipei, Taiwan, ROC.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liao</LastName><ForeName>Yi-Chu</ForeName><Initials>YC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Taipei Veterans General Hospital, Taipei, Taiwan, ROC.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, National Yang Ming Chiao Tung University School of Medicine, Taipei, Taiwan, ROC.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Brain Research Center, National Yang Ming Chiao Tung University, Taipei, Taiwan, ROC.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Yi-Chung</ForeName><Initials>YC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Taipei Veterans General Hospital, Taipei, Taiwan, ROC.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, National Yang Ming Chiao Tung University School of Medicine, Taipei, Taiwan, ROC.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Brain Research Center, National Yang Ming Chiao Tung University, Taipei, Taiwan, ROC.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>J Chin Med Assoc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101174817</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1726-4901</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D009419">Nerve Tissue Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C086055">HTT protein, human</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000483" MajorTopicYN="N">Alleles</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002819" MajorTopicYN="Y">Chorea</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006816" MajorTopicYN="Y">Huntington Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009419" MajorTopicYN="N">Nerve Tissue Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019683" MajorTopicYN="N">Penetrance</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018911" MajorTopicYN="N">Trinucleotide Repeats</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of interest: The authors declare that they have no conflicts of interest related to the subject matter or materials discussed in this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36599142</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/JCMA.0000000000000837</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">02118582-202301000-00010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Gregory JM, Fagegaltier D, Phatnani H, Harms MB. Genetics of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Curr Genet Med Rep 2020;1:11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chia R, Chio A, Traynor BJ. Novel genes associated with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: diagnostic and clinical implications. Lancet Neurol 2018;17:94&#x2013;102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conforti FL, Spataro R, Sproviero W, Mazzei R, Cavalcanti F, Condino F, et al. Ataxin-1 and ataxin-2 intermediate-length PolyQ expansions in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology 2012;79:2315&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elden AC, Kim HJ, Hart MP, Chen-Plotkin AS, Johnson BS, Fang X, et al. Ataxin-2 intermediate-length polyglutamine expansions are associated with increased risk for ALS. Nature 2010;466:1069&#x2013;75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jih KY, Lin KP, Tsai PC, Soong BW, Liao YC, Lee YC. Investigating TBP CAG/CAA trinucleotide repeat expansions in a Taiwanese cohort with ALS. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2020;1:6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramos EM, Keagle P, Gillis T, Lowe P, Mysore JS, Leclerc AL, et al. Prevalence of Huntington&#x2019;s disease gene CAG repeat alleles in sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. Amyotroph Lateral Scler 2012;13:265&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas Q, Coarelli G, Heinzmann A, Le Ber I, del Mar Amador M, Durr A. Questioning the causality of HTT CAG-repeat expansions in FTD/ALS. Neuron 2021;109:1945&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dewan R, Chia R, Ding J, Hickman RA, Stein TD, Abramzon Y, et al.; American Genome Center (TAGC). Pathogenic huntingtin repeat expansions in patients with frontotemporal dementia and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuron 2021;109:448&#x2013;60.e4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tada M, Coon EA, Osmand AP, Kirby PA, Martin W, Wieler M, et al. Coexistence of Huntington&#x2019;s disease and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a clinicopathologic study. Acta Neuropathol 2012;124:749&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith AL, Teener JW, Callaghan BC, Harrington J, Uhlmann W. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in a patient with a family history of huntington disease: genetic counseling challenges. J Genet Couns 2014;23:725&#x2013;33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ludolph A, Drory V, Hardiman O, Nakano I, Ravits J, Robberecht W, et al. A revision of the El Escorial criteria - 2015. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2015;16:291&#x2013;2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashburner J, Friston KJ. Unified segmentation. Neuroimage 2005;26:839&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rolls ET, Huang CC, Lin CP, Feng J, Joliot M. Automated anatomical labelling atlas 3. Neuroimage 2020;206:116189.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brett M, Anton JL, Valabregue R, Poline JB. Region of interest analysis using an SPM toolbox. In: 8th International conference on functional mapping of the human brain. Sendai, Japan: NeuroImage; 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frings L, Yew B, Flanagan E, Lam BYK, Hull M, Huppertz HJ, et al. Longitudinal grey and white matter changes in frontotemporal dementia and Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. PLoS One 2014;9:e90814.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kassubek J, Pinkhardt EH, Dietmaier A, Ludolph AC, Landwehrmeyer GB, Huppertz HJ. Fully automated atlas-based MR imaging volumetry in Huntington disease, compared with manual volumetry. AJNR Am J Neuroradiol 2011;32:1328&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bates GP, Dorsey R, Gusella JF, Hayden MR, Kay C, Leavitt BR, et al. Huntington disease. Nat Rev Dis Primers 2015;1:15005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teng EL, Hasegawa K, Homma A, Imai Y, Larson E, Graves A, et al. The Cognitive Abilities Screening Instrument (CASI): a practical test for cross-cultural epidemiological studies of dementia. Int Psychogeriatr 1994;6:45&#x2013;58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kay C, Collins JA, Miedzybrodzka Z, Madore SJ, Gordon ES, Gerry N, et al. Huntington disease reduced penetrance alleles occur at high frequency in the general population. Neurology 2016;87:282&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langbehn DR, Hayden MR, Paulsen JS; the PREDICT-HD Investigators of the Huntington Study Group. CAG-repeat length and the age of onset in Huntington disease (HD): a review and validation study of statistical approaches. Am J Med Genet B Neuropsychiatr Genet 2010;153:397&#x2013;408.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brinkman RR, Mezei MM, Theilmann J, Almqvist E, Hayden MR. The likelihood of being affected with Huntington disease by a particular age, for a specific CAG size. Am J Hum Genet 1997;60:1202&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quarrell OW, Rigby AS, Barron L, Crow Y, Dalton A, Dennis N, et al. Reduced penetrance alleles for Huntington&#x2019;s disease: a multi-centre direct observational study. J Med Genet 2007;44:e68.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cozzolino M, Carri MT. Mitochondrial dysfunction in ALS. Prog Neurobiol 2012;97:54&#x2013;66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardiman O, Al-Chalabi A, Chio A, Corr EM, Logroscino G, Robberecht W, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat Rev Dis Primers 2017;3:17085.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tabrizi SJ, Flower MD, Ross CA, Wild EJ. Huntington disease: new insights into molecular pathogenesis and therapeutic opportunities. Nat Rev Neurol 2020;16:529&#x2013;46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freibaum BD, Lu Y, Lopez-Gonzalez R, Kim NC, Almeida S, Lee KH, et al. GGGGCC repeat expansion in C9orf72 compromises nucleocytoplasmic transport. Nature 2015;525:129&#x2013;33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hensman Moss DJ, Poulter M, Beck J, Hehir J, Polke JM, Campbell T, et al. C9orf72 expansions are the most common genetic cause of Huntington disease phenocopies. Neurology 2014;82:292&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hickman RA, Dewan R, Cortes E, Traynor BJ, Marder K, Vonsattel JP. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis is over-represented in two Huntington&#x2019;s disease brain bank cohorts: further evidence to support genetic pleiotropy of pathogenic HTT gene expansion. Acta Neuropathol 2022;143:105&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsai CP, Wang KC, Hwang CS, Lee IT, Lee CTC. Incidence, prevalence, and medical expenditures of classical amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in Taiwan, 1999-2008. J Formos Med Assoc 2015;114:612&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>