<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36627836</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>17</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1531-8249</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>93</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>May</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Annals of neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Ann Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Protective Effects of Lovastatin in a Population-Based ALS Study and Mouse Model.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>881</StartPage><EndPage>892</EndPage><MedlinePgn>881-892</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/ana.26600</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">The objective of this study was to use a novel combined pharmacoepidemiologic and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) mouse model approach to identify potential motor neuron protective medications.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">We constructed a large, population-based case-control study to investigate motor neuron disease (MND) among US Medicare beneficiaries aged 66 to 90 in 2009. We included 1,128 incident MND cases and 56,400 age, sex, race, and ethnicity matched controls. We calculated MND relative risk for &gt;1,000 active ingredients represented in Part D (pharmacy) claims in 2006 to 2007 (&gt;1&#x2009;year before diagnosis/reference). We then applied a comprehensive screening approach to select medications for testing in SOD1<sup>G93A</sup> mice: sulfasalazine, telmisartan, and lovastatin. We treated mice with the human dose equivalent of the medication or vehicle via subcutaneous osmotic pump before onset of weakness. We then assessed weight, gait, and survival. In additional mice, we conducted histological studies.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">We observed previously established medical associations for MND and an inverse dose-response association between lovastatin and MND, with 28% reduced risk at 40&#x2009;mg/day. In SOD1<sup>G93A</sup> mouse studies, sulfasalazine and telmisartan conferred no benefit, whereas lovastatin treatment delayed onset and prolonged survival. Lovastatin treated mice also had less microgliosis, misfolded SOD1, and spinal motor neuron loss in the ventral horn.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="INTERPRETATION">Lovastatin reduced the risk of ALS in humans, which was confirmed in an ALS mouse model by delayed symptom onset, prolonged survival, and preservation of motor neurons. Although further studies to understand the mechanism are required, lovastatin may represent a potential neuroprotective therapy for patients with ALS. These data demonstrate the utility of a combined pharmacoepidemiologic and mouse model approach. ANN NEUROL 2023;93:881-892.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 American Neurological Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kreple</LastName><ForeName>Collin J</ForeName><Initials>CJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Washington University School of Medicine, St. Louis, MO.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Searles Nielsen</LastName><ForeName>Susan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Washington University School of Medicine, St. Louis, MO.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schoch</LastName><ForeName>Kathleen M</ForeName><Initials>KM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Washington University School of Medicine, St. Louis, MO.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shen</LastName><ForeName>Tao</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Washington University School of Medicine, St. Louis, MO.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shabsovich</LastName><ForeName>Mark</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Washington University School of Medicine, St. Louis, MO.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Song</LastName><ForeName>Yizhe</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Washington University School of Medicine, St. Louis, MO.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Racette</LastName><ForeName>Brad A</ForeName><Initials>BA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Washington University School of Medicine, St. Louis, MO.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Barrow Neurological Institute, Phoenix, AZ.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Public Health, Faculty of Health Sciences, University of the Witwatersrand, Parktown, South Africa.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Miller</LastName><ForeName>Timothy M</ForeName><Initials>TM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3424-5511</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Washington University School of Medicine, St. Louis, MO.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>K01 ES028295</GrantID><Acronym>ES</Acronym><Agency>NIEHS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>K24 ES017765</GrantID><Acronym>ES</Acronym><Agency>NIEHS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01 NS078398</GrantID><Acronym>NS</Acronym><Agency>NINDS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Ann Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7707449</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0364-5134</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 1.15.1.1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000072105">Superoxide Dismutase-1</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>3XC8GUZ6CB</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D012460">Sulfasalazine</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>U5SYW473RQ</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000077333">Telmisartan</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 1.15.1.1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D013482">Superoxide Dismutase</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014481" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">United States</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051379" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000072105" MajorTopicYN="N">Superoxide Dismutase-1</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012460" MajorTopicYN="N">Sulfasalazine</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016022" MajorTopicYN="N">Case-Control Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000077333" MajorTopicYN="N">Telmisartan</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013116" MajorTopicYN="N">Spinal Cord</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008822" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice, Transgenic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013482" MajorTopicYN="N">Superoxide Dismutase</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006278" MajorTopicYN="N">Medicare</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016472" MajorTopicYN="Y">Motor Neuron Disease</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004195" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Models, Animal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36627836</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.26600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Camacho-Soto A, Nielsen Searles S, Faust I, et al. Incidence of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in older adults. Muscle Nerve 2022;66:289-296.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Searles Nielsen S, Warden MN, Camacho-Soto A, et al. A predictive model to identify Parkinson disease from administrative claims data. Neurology 2017;89:1448-1456.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Searles Nielsen S, Gross A, Camacho-Soto A, et al. beta2-adrenoreceptor medications and risk of Parkinson disease. Ann Neurol 2018;84:683-693.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gross A, Racette BA, Camacho-Soto A, et al. Use of medical care biases associations between Parkinson disease and other medical conditions. Neurology 2018;90:e2155-e2165.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mariosa D, Kamel F, Bellocco R, et al. Antidiabetics, statins and the risk of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Eur J Neurol 2020;27:1010-1016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim WK, Liu X, Sandner J, et al. Study of 962 patients indicates progressive muscular atrophy is a form of ALS. Neurology 2009;73:1686-1692.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryu BR, Lee YA, Won SJ, et al. The novel neuroprotective action of sulfasalazine through blockade of NMDA receptors. J Pharmacol Exp Ther 2003;305:48-56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garrido-Gil P, Joglar B, Rodriguez-Perez AI, et al. Involvement of PPAR-gamma in the neuroprotective and anti-inflammatory effects of angiotensin type 1 receptor inhibition: effects of the receptor antagonist telmisartan and receptor deletion in a mouse MPTP model of Parkinson's disease. J Neuroinflammation 2012;9:38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan JQ, Sun JC, Zhai MM, et al. Lovastatin induces neuroprotection by inhibiting inflammatory cytokines in 6-hydroxydopamine treated microglia cells. Int J Clin Exp Med 2015;8:9030-9037.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J, Luo X, Chen X, Shang H. Lipid profile in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Neurol 2020;11:567753.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng P, Zhou X. Causal effects of blood lipids on amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a Mendelian randomization study. Hum Mol Genet 2019;28:688-697.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen X, Yazdani S, Piehl F, et al. Polygenic link between blood lipids and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurobiol Aging 2018;67:202.e1-202.e6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao Y, Wang T, Yu X, et al. Mendelian randomization implies no direct causal association between leukocyte telomere length and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Sci Rep 2020;10:12184.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bandres-Ciga S, Noyce AJ, Hemani G, et al. Shared polygenic risk and causal inferences in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol 2019;85:470-481.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ungard RG, Seidlitz EP, Singh G. Inhibition of breast cancer-cell glutamate release with sulfasalazine limits cancer-induced bone pain. Pain 2014;155:28-36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ager EI, Wen SW, Chan J, et al. Altered efficacy of AT1R-targeted treatment after spontaneous cancer cell-AT1R upregulation. BMC Cancer 2011;11:274.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rai P, Lederman R, Haque S, et al. Renin angiotensin system modulates mTOR pathway through AT2R in HIVAN. Exp Mol Pathol 2014;96:431-437.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assaggaf MA, Kantarci A, Sume SS, Trackman PC. Prevention of phenytoin-induced gingival overgrowth by lovastatin in mice. Am J Pathol 2015;185:1588-1599.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nair AB, Jacob S. A simple practice guide for dose conversion between animals and human. J Basic Clin Pharm 2016;7:27-31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bosco DA, Morfini G, Karabacak NM, et al. Wild-type and mutant SOD1 share an aberrant conformation and a common pathogenic pathway in ALS. Nat Neurosci 2010;13:1396-1403.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marin B, Fontana A, Arcuti S, et al. Age-specific ALS incidence: a dose-response meta-analysis. Eur J Epidemiol 2018;33:621-634.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rechtman L, Jordan H, Wagner L, et al. Racial and ethnic differences among amyotrophic lateral sclerosis cases in the United States. c 2015;16:65-71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cronin S, Hardiman O, Traynor BJ. Ethnic variation in the incidence of ALS: a systematic review. Neurology 2007;68:1002-1007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roos E, Mariosa D, Ingre C, et al. Depression in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology 2016;86:2271-2277.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longinetti E, Mariosa D, Larsson H, et al. Neurodegenerative and psychiatric diseases among families with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology 2017;89:578-585.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H, O'Reilly EJ, Weisskopf MG, et al. Smoking and risk of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a pooled analysis of 5 prospective cohorts. Arch Neurol 2011;68:207-213.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dupuis L, Corcia P, Fergani A, et al. Dyslipidemia is a protective factor in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology 2008;70:1004-1009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson AG, Talbot K, Turner MR. Higher blood high density lipoprotein and apolipoprotein A1 levels are associated with reduced risk of developing amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2022;93:75-81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mariosa D, Hammar N, Malmstrom H, et al. Blood biomarkers of carbohydrate, lipid, and apolipoprotein metabolisms and risk of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a more than 20-year follow-up of the Swedish AMORIS cohort. Ann Neurol 2017;81:718-728.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vasta R, D'Ovidio F, Logroscino G, Chio A. The links between diabetes mellitus and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurol Sci 2021;42:1377-1387.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang F, Zhang Q, Ke Y, et al. Serum uric acid levels in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a meta-analysis. Sci Rep 2018;8:1100.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colman E, Szarfman A, Wyeth J, et al. An evaluation of a data mining signal for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and statins detected in FDA's spontaneous adverse event reporting system. Pharmacoepidemiol Drug Saf 2008;17:1068-1076.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freedman DM, Kuncl RW, Cahoon EK, et al. Relationship of statins and other cholesterol-lowering medications and risk of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in the US elderly. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2018;19:538-546.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pfeiffer RM, Mayer B, Kuncl RW, et al. Identifying potential targets for prevention and treatment of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis based on a screen of medicare prescription drugs. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2020;3-4:235-245.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torrandell-Haro G, Branigan GL, Vitali F, et al. Statin therapy and risk of Alzheimer's and age-related neurodegenerative diseases. Alzheimers Dement 2020;6:e12108.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai L, Wang Y, Huo J, et al. Simvastatin accelerated motoneurons death in SOD1(G93A) mice through inhibiting Rab7-mediated maturation of late autophagic vacuoles. Cell Death Dis 2021;12:392.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su XW, Nandar W, Neely EB, et al. Statins accelerate disease progression and shorten survival in SOD1(G93A) mice. Muscle Nerve 2016;54:284-291.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McClure DL, Valuck RJ, Glanz M, et al. Statin and statin-fibrate use was significantly associated with increased myositis risk in a managed care population. J Clin Epidemiol 2007;60:812-818.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huisman MH, Seelen M, van Doormaal PT, et al. Effect of Presymptomatic body mass index and consumption of fat and alcohol on amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. JAMA Neurol 2015;72:1155-1162.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nelson LM, Matkin C, Longstreth WT Jr, McGuire V. Population-based case-control study of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in western Washington state. Ii Diet Am J Epidemiol 2000;151:164-173.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Endo A, Tsujita Y, Kuroda M, Tanzawa K. Effects of ML-236B on cholesterol metabolism in mice and rats: lack of hypocholesterolemic activity in normal animals. Biochim Biophys Acta 1979;575:266-276.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jula A, Marniemi J, Ronnemaa T, et al. Effects of diet and simvastatin on fatty acid composition in hypercholesterolemic men: a randomized controlled trial. Arterioscler Thromb Vasc Biol 2005;25:1952-1959.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cutler RG, Pedersen WA, Camandola S, et al. Evidence that accumulation of ceramides and cholesterol esters mediates oxidative stress-induced death of motor neurons in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol 2002;52:448-457.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duewell P, Kono H, Rayner KJ, et al. NLRP3 inflammasomes are required for atherogenesis and activated by cholesterol crystals. Nature 2010;464:1357-1361.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shapira KE, Shapira G, Schmukler E, et al. Autophagy is induced and modulated by cholesterol depletion through transcription of autophagy-related genes and attenuation of flux. Cell Death Discov 2021;7:320.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anzai I, Toichi K, Tokuda E, et al. Screening of drugs inhibiting In vitro Oligomerization of Cu/Zn-superoxide dismutase with a mutation causing amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Front Mol Biosci 2016;3:40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wishart DS, Feunang YD, Guo AC, et al. DrugBank 5.0: a major update to the DrugBank database for 2018. Nucleic Acids Res 2018;46:D1074-D1082.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janssen C, Schmalbach S, Boeselt S, et al. Differential histone deacetylase mRNA expression patterns in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neuropathol Exp Neurol 2010;69:573-581.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drory VE, Bronipolsky T, Artamonov I, Nefussy B. Influence of statins treatment on survival in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Sci 2008;273:81-83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schumacher J, Peter RS, Nagel G, et al. Statins, diabetes mellitus and prognosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: data from 501 patients of a population-based registry in Southwest Germany. Eur J Neurol 2020;27:1405-1414.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weisskopf MG, Levy J, Dickerson AS, et al. Statin medications and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis incidence and mortality. Am J Epidemiol 2022;191:1248-1257.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stone NJ, Robinson JG, Lichtenstein AH, et al. 2013 ACC/AHA guideline on the treatment of blood cholesterol to reduce atherosclerotic cardiovascular risk in adults: a report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association task force on practice guidelines. Circulation 2014;129:S1-S45.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>