<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36621656</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1879-0038</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>858</Volume><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>30</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Gene</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Gene</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>How villains are made: The translation of dipeptide repeat proteins in C9ORF72-ALS/FTD.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>147167</StartPage><MedlinePgn>147167</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.gene.2023.147167</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0378-1119(23)00008-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>A hexanucleotide repeat expansion in the C9ORF72 gene is the most common genetic alteration associated with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) and frontotemporal dementia (FTD). These neurodegenerative diseases share genetic, clinical and pathological features. The mutation in C9ORF72 appears to drive pathogenesis through a combination of loss of C9ORF72 normal function and gain of toxic effects due to the repeat expansion, which result in aggregation prone expanded RNAs and dipeptide repeat (DPR) proteins. Studies in cellular and animal models indicate that the DPR proteins are the more toxic species. Thus, a large body of research has focused on identifying the cellular pathways most directly impacted by these toxic proteins, with the goal of characterizing disease pathogenesis and nominating potential targets for therapeutic development. The preventative block of the production of the toxic proteins before they can cause harm is a second strategy of intense focus. Despite the considerable amount of effort dedicated to this prophylactic approach, it is still unclear how the DPR proteins are synthesized from RNAs harboring repeat expansions. In this review, we summarize our current knowledge of the specific protein translation mechanisms shown to account for the synthesis of DPR proteins. We will then discuss how enhanced understanding of the composition of these toxic effectors could help in refining disease mechanisms, and paving the way to identify and design effective prophylactic therapies for C9ORF72 ALS-FTD.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Published by Elsevier B.V.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Van't Spijker</LastName><ForeName>Heleen M</ForeName><Initials>HM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Program in Molecular Medicine, University of Massachusetts Chan Medical School, Worcester, MA 01605, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Almeida</LastName><ForeName>Sandra</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of Massachusetts Chan Medical School, Worcester, MA 01605, USA. Electronic address: Sandra.Almeida@umassmed.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R21 NS112766</GrantID><Acronym>NS</Acronym><Agency>NINDS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R21 NS119952</GrantID><Acronym>NS</Acronym><Agency>NINDS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Gene</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7706761</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0378-1119</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000073885">C9orf72 Protein</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D004151">Dipeptides</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D011506">Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>63231-63-0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D012313">RNA</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Frontotemporal Dementia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000073885" MajorTopicYN="N">C9orf72 Protein</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004151" MajorTopicYN="N">Dipeptides</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D042622" MajorTopicYN="N">DNA Repeat Expansion</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011506" MajorTopicYN="N">Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012313" MajorTopicYN="N">RNA</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">C9ORF72</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dipeptide repeat proteins</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Frontotemporal dementia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neurodegeneration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Translation initiation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of Competing Interest The authors declare the following financial interests/personal relationships which may be considered as potential competing interests: Sandra Almeida reports financial support was provided by National Institutes of Health.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>58</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36621656</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS1866847</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9928902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gene.2023.147167</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0378-1119(23)00008-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abeyrathne PD, Koh CS, Grant T, Grigorieff N, and Korostelev AA. 2016. &#x201c;Ensemble cryo-EM uncovers inchworm-like translocation of a viral IRES through the ribosome.&#x201d; Elife 5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4896748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27159452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alfano M, De Antoni L, Centofanti F, Visconti VV, Maestri S, Degli Esposti C, Massa R, D&#x2019;Apice MR, Novelli G, Delledonne M, Botta A, and Rossato M. 2022. &#x201c;Characterization of full-length.&#x201d; Elife 11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9462847</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36018009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almeida S, and Gao FB. 2016. &#x201c;Lost &amp; found: C9ORF72 and the autophagy pathway in ALS/FTD.&#x201d; EMBO J 35 (12): 1251&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4910530</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27154207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almeida S, Krishnan G, Rushe M, Gu Y, Kankel MW, and Gao FB. 2019. &#x201c;Production of poly(GA) in C9ORF72 patient motor neurons derived from induced pluripotent stem cells.&#x201d; Acta Neuropathol 138 (6): 1099&#x2013;1101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6851345</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31624870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andreev DE, Loughran G, Fedorova AD, Mikhaylova MS, Shatsky IN, and Baranov PV. 2022. &#x201c;Non-AUG translation initiation in mammals.&#x201d; Genome Biol 23 (1): 111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9082881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35534899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ash PE, Bieniek KF, Gendron TF, Caulfield T, Lin WL, Dejesus-Hernandez M, van Blitterswijk MM, Jansen-West K, Paul JW, Rademakers R, Boylan KB, Dickson DW, and Petrucelli L. 2013. &#x201c;Unconventional translation of C9ORF72 GGGGCC expansion generates insoluble polypeptides specific to c9FTD/ALS.&#x201d; Neuron 77 (4): 639&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3593233</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23415312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balendra R, and Isaacs AM. 2018. &#x201c;C9orf72-mediated ALS and FTD: multiple pathways to disease.&#x201d; Nat Rev Neurol 14 (9): 544&#x2013;558.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6417666</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30120348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ben-Dor I, Pacut C, Nevo Y, Feldman EL, and Reubinoff BE. 2021. &#x201c;Characterization of C9orf72 haplotypes to evaluate the effects of normal and pathological variations on its expression and splicing.&#x201d; PLoS Genet 17 (3): e1009445.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8031855</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33780440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boivin M, Pfister V, Gaucherot A, Ruffenach F, Negroni L, Sellier C, and Charlet-Berguerand N. 2020. &#x201c;Reduced autophagy upon C9ORF72 loss synergizes with dipeptide repeat protein toxicity in G4C2 repeat expansion disorders.&#x201d; EMBO J 39 (4): e100574.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7024836</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31930538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bo&#x17e;i&#x10d; J, Motaln H, Jane&#x17e; AP, Marki&#x10d; L, Tripathi P, Yamoah A, Aronica E, Lee YB, Heilig R, Fischer R, Thompson AJ, Goswami A, and Rogelj B. 2022. &#x201c;Interactome screening of C9orf72 dipeptide repeats reveals VCP sequestration and functional impairment by polyGA.&#x201d; Brain 145 (2): 684&#x2013;699.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9014755</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34534264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng W, Wang S, Mestre AA, Fu C, Makarem A, Xian F, Hayes LR, Lopez-Gonzalez R, Drenner K, Jiang J, Cleveland DW, and Sun S. 2018. &#x201c;C9ORF72 GGGGCC repeat-associated non-AUG translation is upregulated by stress through eIF2&#x3b1; phosphorylation.&#x201d; Nat Commun 9 (1): 51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5754368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29302060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dabrowski M, Bukowy-Bieryllo Z, and Zietkiewicz E. 2018. &#x201c;Advances in therapeutic use of a drug-stimulated translational readthrough of premature termination codons.&#x201d; Mol Med 24 (1): 25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6016875</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30134808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davidson YS, Barker H, Robinson AC, Thompson JC, Harris J, Troakes C, Smith B, Al-Saraj S, Shaw C, Rollinson S, Masuda-Suzukake M, Hasegawa M, Pickering-Brown S, Snowden JS, and Mann DM. 2014. &#x201c;Brain distribution of dipeptide repeat proteins in frontotemporal lobar degeneration and motor neurone disease associated with expansions in C9ORF72.&#x201d; Acta Neuropathol Commun 2: 70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4229740</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24950788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de la Parra C, Ernlund A, Alard A, Ruggles K, Ueberheide B, and Schneider RJ. 2018. &#x201c;A widespread alternate form of cap-dependent mRNA translation initiation.&#x201d; Nat Commun 9 (1): 3068.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6076257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30076308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeJesus-Hernandez M, Aleff RA, Jackson JL, Finch NA, Baker MC, Gendron TF, Murray ME, McLaughlin IJ, Harting JR, Graff-Radford NR, Oskarsson B, Knopman DS, Josephs KA, Boeve BF, Petersen RC, Fryer JD, Petrucelli L, Dickson DW, Rademakers R, Ebbert MTW, Wieben ED, and van Blitterswijk M. 2021. &#x201c;Long-read targeted sequencing uncovers clinicopathological associations for C9orf72-linked diseases.&#x201d; Brain 144 (4): 1082&#x2013;1088.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8105038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33889947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebbert MTW, Farrugia SL, Sens JP, Jansen-West K, Gendron TF, Prudencio M, McLaughlin IJ, Bowman B, Seetin M, DeJesus-Hernandez M, Jackson J, Brown PH, Dickson DW, van Blitterswijk M, Rademakers R, Petrucelli L, and Fryer JD. 2018. &#x201c;Long-read sequencing across the C9orf72 &#x2018;GGGGCC&#x2019; repeat expansion: implications for clinical use and genetic discovery efforts in human disease.&#x201d; Mol Neurodegener 13 (1): 46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6102925</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30126445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freibaum BD, Lu Y, Lopez-Gonzalez R, Kim NC, Almeida S, Lee KH, Badders N, Valentine M, Miller BL, Wong PC, Petrucelli L, Kim HJ, Gao FB, and Taylor JP. 2015. &#x201c;GGGGCC repeat expansion in C9orf72 compromises nucleocytoplasmic transport.&#x201d; Nature 525 (7567): 129&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4631399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26308899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao FB, Almeida S, and Lopez-Gonzalez R. 2017. &#x201c;Dysregulated molecular pathways in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-frontotemporal dementia spectrum disorder.&#x201d; EMBO J 36 (20): 2931&#x2013;2950.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5641681</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28916614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao J, Mewborne QT, Girdhar A, Sheth U, Coyne AN, Punathil R, Kang BG, Dasovich M, Veire A, DeJesus Hernandez M, Liu S, Shi Z, Dafinca R, Fouquerel E, Talbot K, Kam TI, Zhang YJ, Dickson D, Petrucelli L, van Blitterswijk M, Guo L, Dawson TM, Dawson VL, Leung AKL, Lloyd TE, Gendron TF, Rothstein JD, and Zhang K. 2022. &#x201c;Poly(ADP-ribose) promotes toxicity of.&#x201d; Sci Transl Med 14 (662): eabq3215.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36103513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gendron TF, Bieniek KF, Zhang YJ, Jansen-West K, Ash PE, Caulfield T, Daughrity L, Dunmore JH, Castanedes-Casey M, Chew J, Cosio DM, van Blitterswijk M, Lee WC, Rademakers R, Boylan KB, Dickson DW, and Petrucelli L. 2013. &#x201c;Antisense transcripts of the expanded C9ORF72 hexanucleotide repeat form nuclear RNA foci and undergo repeat-associated non-ATG translation in c9FTD/ALS.&#x201d; Acta Neuropathol 126 (6): 829&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3830741</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24129584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gendron TF, Chew J, Stankowski JN, Hayes LR, Zhang YJ, Prudencio M, Carlomagno Y, Daughrity LM, Jansen-West K, Perkerson EA, O&#x2019;Raw A, Cook C, Pregent L, Belzil V, van Blitterswijk M, Tabassian LJ, Lee CW, Yue M, Tong J, Song Y, Castanedes-Casey M, Rousseau L, Phillips V, Dickson DW, Rademakers R, Fryer JD, Rush BK, Pedraza O, Caputo AM, Desaro P, Palmucci C, Robertson A, Heckman MG, Diehl NN, Wiggs E, Tierney M, Braun L, Farren J, Lacomis D, Ladha S, Fournier CN, McCluskey LF, Elman LB, Toledo JB, McBride JD, Tiloca C, Morelli C, Poletti B, Solca F, Prelle A, Wuu J, Jockel-Balsarotti J, Rigo F, Ambrose C, Datta A, Yang W, Raitcheva D, Antognetti G, McCampbell A, Van Swieten JC, Miller BL, Boxer AL, Brown RH, Bowser R, Miller TM, Trojanowski JQ, Grossman M, Berry JD, Hu WT, Ratti A, Traynor BJ, Disney MD, Benatar M, Silani V, Glass JD, Floeter MK, Rothstein JD, Boylan KB, and Petrucelli L. 2017. &#x201c;Poly(GP) proteins are a useful pharmacodynamic marker for.&#x201d; Sci Transl Med 9 (383).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5576451</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28356511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gendron TF, van Blitterswijk M, Bieniek KF, Daughrity LM, Jiang J, Rush BK, Pedraza O, Lucas JA, Murray ME, Desaro P, Robertson A, Overstreet K, Thomas CS, Crook JE, Castanedes-Casey M, Rousseau L, Josephs KA, Parisi JE, Knopman DS, Petersen RC, Boeve BF, Graff-Radford NR, Rademakers R, Lagier-Tourenne C, Edbauer D, Cleveland DW, Dickson DW, Petrucelli L, and Boylan KB. 2015. &#x201c;Cerebellar c9RAN proteins associate with clinical and neuropathological characteristics of C9ORF72 repeat expansion carriers.&#x201d; Acta Neuropathol 130 (4): 559&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4575385</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26350237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gittings LM, Boeynaems S, Lightwood D, Clargo A, Topia S, Nakayama L, Troakes C, Mann DMA, Gitler AD, Lashley T, and Isaacs AM. 2020. &#x201c;Symmetric dimethylation of poly-GR correlates with disease duration in C9orf72 FTLD and ALS and reduces poly-GR phase separation and toxicity.&#x201d; Acta Neuropathol 139 (2): 407&#x2013;410.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6989575</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31832771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gleason AC, Ghadge G, Chen J, Sonobe Y, and Roos RP. 2022. &#x201c;Machine learning predicts translation initiation sites in neurologic diseases with nucleotide repeat expansions.&#x201d; PLoS One 17 (6): e0256411.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9159584</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35648796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gleixner AM, Verdone BM, Otte CG, Anderson EN, Ramesh N, Shapiro OR, Gale JR, Mauna JC, Mann JR, Copley KE, Daley EL, Ortega JA, Cicardi ME, Kiskinis E, Kofler J, Pandey UB, Trotti D, and Donnelly CJ. 2022. &#x201c;NUP62 localizes to ALS/FTLD pathological assemblies and contributes to TDP-43 insolubility.&#x201d; Nat Commun 13 (1): 3380.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9192689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35697676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodman LD, Prudencio M, Kramer NJ, Martinez-Ramirez LF, Srinivasan AR, Lan M, Parisi MJ, Zhu Y, Chew J, Cook CN, Berson A, Gitler AD, Petrucelli L, and Bonini NM. 2019. &#x201c;Toxic expanded GGGGCC repeat transcription is mediated by the PAF1 complex in C9orf72-associated FTD.&#x201d; Nat Neurosci 22 (6): 863&#x2013;874.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6535128</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31110321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodman LD, Prudencio M, Srinivasan AR, Rifai OM, Lee VM, Petrucelli L, and Bonini NM. 2019. &#x201c;eIF4B and eIF4H mediate GR production from expanded G4C2 in a Drosophila model for C9orf72-associated ALS.&#x201d; Acta Neuropathol Commun 7 (1): 62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6485101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31023341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green KM, Glineburg MR, Kearse MG, Flores BN, Linsalata AE, Fedak SJ, Goldstrohm AC, Barmada SJ, and Todd PK. 2017. &#x201c;RAN translation at C9orf72-associated repeat expansions is selectively enhanced by the integrated stress response.&#x201d; Nat Commun 8 (1): 2005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5722904</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29222490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green KM, Miller SL, Malik I, and Todd PK. 2022. &#x201c;Non-canonical initiation factors modulate repeat-associated non-AUG translation.&#x201d; Hum Mol Genet 31 (15): 2521&#x2013;2534.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9618161</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35220421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haeusler AR, Donnelly CJ, Periz G, Simko EA, Shaw PG, Kim MS, Maragakis NJ, Troncoso JC, Pandey A, Sattler R, Rothstein JD, and Wang J. 2014. &#x201c;C9orf72 nucleotide repeat structures initiate molecular cascades of disease.&#x201d; Nature 507 (7491): 195&#x2013;200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4046618</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24598541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haizel SA, Bhardwaj U, Gonzalez RL, Mitra S, and Goss DJ. 2020. &#x201c;5&#x2019;-UTR recruitment of the translation initiation factor eIF4GI or DAP5 drives cap-independent translation of a subset of human mRNAs.&#x201d; J Biol Chem 295 (33): 11693&#x2013;11706.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7450097</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32571876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He F, Flores BN, Krans A, Frazer M, Natla S, Niraula S, Adefioye O, Barmada SJ, and Todd PK. 2020. &#x201c;The carboxyl termini of RAN translated GGGGCC nucleotide repeat expansions modulate toxicity in models of ALS/FTD.&#x201d; Acta Neuropathol Commun 8 (1): 122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7401224</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32753055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ichihara K, Matsumoto A, Nishida H, Kito Y, Shimizu H, Shichino Y, Iwasaki S, Imami K, Ishihama Y, and Nakayama KI. 2021. &#x201c;Combinatorial analysis of translation dynamics reveals eIF2 dependence of translation initiation at near-cognate codons.&#x201d; Nucleic Acids Res 49 (13): 7298&#x2013;7317.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8287933</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34226921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ingolia NT, Ghaemmaghami S, Newman JR, and Weissman JS. 2009. &#x201c;Genome-wide analysis in vivo of translation with nucleotide resolution using ribosome profiling.&#x201d; Science 324 (5924): 218&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2746483</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19213877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ingolia NT, Lareau LF, and Weissman JS. 2011. &#x201c;Ribosome profiling of mouse embryonic stem cells reveals the complexity and dynamics of mammalian proteomes.&#x201d; Cell 147 (4): 789&#x2013;802.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3225288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22056041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang J, Zhu Q, Gendron TF, Saberi S, McAlonis-Downes M, Seelman A, Stauffer JE, Jafar-Nejad P, Drenner K, Schulte D, Chun S, Sun S, Ling SC, Myers B, Engelhardt J, Katz M, Baughn M, Platoshyn O, Marsala M, Watt A, Heyser CJ, Ard MC, De Muynck L, Daughrity LM, Swing DA, Tessarollo L, Jung CJ, Delpoux A, Utzschneider DT, Hedrick SM, de Jong PJ, Edbauer D, Van Damme P, Petrucelli L, Shaw CE, Bennett CF, Da Cruz S, Ravits J, Rigo F, Cleveland DW, and Lagier-Tourenne C. 2016. &#x201c;Gain of Toxicity from ALS/FTD-Linked Repeat Expansions in C9ORF72 Is Alleviated by Antisense Oligonucleotides Targeting GGGGCC-Containing RNAs.&#x201d; Neuron 90 (3): 535&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4860075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27112497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnstone TG, Bazzini AA, and Giraldez AJ. 2016. &#x201c;Upstream ORFs are prevalent translational repressors in vertebrates.&#x201d; EMBO J 35 (7): 706&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4818764</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26896445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jovi&#x10d;i&#x107; A, Mertens J, Boeynaems S, Bogaert E, Chai N, Yamada SB, Paul JW, Sun S, Herdy JR, Bieri G, Kramer NJ, Gage FH, Van Den Bosch L, Robberecht W, and Gitler AD. 2015. &#x201c;Modifiers of C9orf72 dipeptide repeat toxicity connect nucleocytoplasmic transport defects to FTD/ALS.&#x201d; Nat Neurosci 18 (9): 1226&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4552077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26308983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kearse MG, Green KM, Krans A, Rodriguez CM, Linsalata AE, Goldstrohm AC, and Todd PK. 2016. &#x201c;CGG Repeat-Associated Non-AUG Translation Utilizes a Cap-Dependent Scanning Mechanism of Initiation to Produce Toxic Proteins.&#x201d; Mol Cell 62 (2): 314&#x2013;322.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4854189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27041225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khosravi B, LaClair KD, Riemenschneider H, Zhou Q, Frottin F, Mareljic N, Czuppa M, Farny D, Hartmann H, Michaelsen M, Arzberger T, Hartl FU, Hipp MS, and Edbauer D. 2020. &#x201c;Cell-to-cell transmission of C9orf72 poly-(Gly-Ala) triggers key features of ALS/FTD.&#x201d; EMBO J 39 (8): e102811.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7156967</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32175624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraft JJ, Treder K, Peterson MS, and Miller WA. 2013. &#x201c;Cation-dependent folding of 3&#x2019; cap-independent translation elements facilitates interaction of a 17-nucleotide conserved sequence with eIF4G.&#x201d; Nucleic Acids Res 41 (5): 3398&#x2013;413.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3597692</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23361463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kramer NJ, Carlomagno Y, Zhang YJ, Almeida S, Cook CN, Gendron TF, Prudencio M, Van Blitterswijk M, Belzil V, Couthouis J, Paul JW, Goodman LD, Daughrity L, Chew J, Garrett A, Pregent L, Jansen-West K, Tabassian LJ, Rademakers R, Boylan K, Graff-Radford NR, Josephs KA, Parisi JE, Knopman DS, Petersen RC, Boeve BF, Deng N, Feng Y, Cheng TH, Dickson DW, Cohen SN, Bonini NM, Link CD, Gao FB, Petrucelli L, and Gitler AD. 2016. &#x201c;Spt4 selectively regulates the expression of C9orf72 sense and antisense mutant transcripts.&#x201d; Science 353 (6300): 708&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5823025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27516603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krishnan G, Raitcheva D, Bartlett D, Prudencio M, McKenna-Yasek DM, Douthwright C, Oskarsson BE, Ladha S, King OD, Barmada SJ, Miller TM, Bowser R, Watts JK, Petrucelli L, Brown RH, Kankel MW, and Gao FB. 2022. &#x201c;Poly(GR) and poly(GA) in cerebrospinal fluid as potential biomarkers for C9ORF72-ALS/FTD.&#x201d; Nat Commun 13 (1): 2799.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9119980</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35589711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lagier-Tourenne C, Baughn M, Rigo F, Sun S, Liu P, Li HR, Jiang J, Watt AT, Chun S, Katz M, Qiu J, Sun Y, Ling SC, Zhu Q, Polymenidou M, Drenner K, Artates JW, McAlonis-Downes M, Markmiller S, Hutt KR, Pizzo DP, Cady J, Harms MB, Baloh RH, Vandenberg SR, Yeo GW, Fu XD, Bennett CF, Cleveland DW, and Ravits J. 2013. &#x201c;Targeted degradation of sense and antisense C9orf72 RNA foci as therapy for ALS and frontotemporal degeneration.&#x201d; Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 110 (47): E4530&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3839752</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24170860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lampasona A, Almeida S, and Gao FB. 2021. &#x201c;Translation of the poly(GR) frame in C9ORF72-ALS/FTD is regulated by cis-elements involved in alternative splicing.&#x201d; Neurobiol Aging 105: 327&#x2013;332.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8338774</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34157654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee YB, Baskaran P, Gomez-Deza J, Chen HJ, Nishimura AL, Smith BN, Troakes C, Adachi Y, Stepto A, Petrucelli L, Gallo JM, Hirth F, Rogelj B, Guthrie S, and Shaw CE. 2017. &#x201c;C9orf72 poly GA RAN-translated protein plays a key role in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis via aggregation and toxicity.&#x201d; Hum Mol Genet 26 (24): 4765&#x2013;4777.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5886201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28973350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu F, Morderer D, Wren MC, Vettleson-Trutza SA, Wang Y, Rabichow BE, Salemi MR, Phinney BS, Oskarsson B, Dickson DW, and Rossoll W. 2022. &#x201c;Proximity proteomics of C9orf72 dipeptide repeat proteins identifies molecular chaperones as modifiers of poly-GA aggregation.&#x201d; Acta Neuropathol Commun 10 (1): 22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8842533</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35164882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackenzie IR, Arzberger T, Kremmer E, Troost D, Lorenzl S, Mori K, Weng SM, Haass C, Kretzschmar HA, Edbauer D, and Neumann M. 2013. &#x201c;Dipeptide repeat protein pathology in C9ORF72 mutation cases: clinico-pathological correlations.&#x201d; Acta Neuropathol 126 (6): 859&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24096617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackenzie IR, Frick P, Gr&#xe4;sser FA, Gendron TF, Petrucelli L, Cashman NR, Edbauer D, Kremmer E, Prudlo J, Troost D, and Neumann M. 2015. &#x201c;Quantitative analysis and clinico-pathological correlations of different dipeptide repeat protein pathologies in C9ORF72 mutation carriers.&#x201d; Acta Neuropathol 130 (6): 845&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26374446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Majounie E, Renton AE, Mok K, Dopper EG, Waite A, Rollinson S, Chi&#xf2; A, Restagno G, Nicolaou N, Simon-Sanchez J, van Swieten JC, Abramzon Y, Johnson JO, Sendtner M, Pamphlett R, Orrell RW, Mead S, Sidle KC, Houlden H, Rohrer JD, Morrison KE, Pall H, Talbot K, Ansorge O, Hernandez DG, Arepalli S, Sabatelli M, Mora G, Corbo M, Giannini F, Calvo A, Englund E, Borghero G, Floris GL, Remes AM, Laaksovirta H, McCluskey L, Trojanowski JQ, Van Deerlin VM, Schellenberg GD, Nalls MA, Drory VE, Lu CS, Yeh TH, Ishiura H, Takahashi Y, Tsuji S, Le Ber I, Brice A, Drepper C, Williams N, Kirby J, Shaw P, Hardy J, Tienari PJ, Heutink P, Morris HR, Pickering-Brown S, Traynor BJ, Chromosome 9-ALS/FTD Consortium, French research network on FTLD/FTLD/ALS, and ITALSGEN Consortium. 2012. &#x201c;Frequency of the C9orf72 hexanucleotide repeat expansion in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal dementia: a cross-sectional study.&#x201d; Lancet Neurol 11 (4): 323&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3322422</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22406228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manjunath LE, Singh A, Som S, and Eswarappa SM. 2022. &#x201c;Mammalian proteome expansion by stop codon readthrough.&#x201d; Wiley Interdiscip Rev RNA: e1739.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35570338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>May S, Hornburg D, Schludi MH, Arzberger T, Rentzsch K, Schwenk BM, Gr&#xe4;sser FA, Mori K, Kremmer E, Banzhaf-Strathmann J, Mann M, Meissner F, and Edbauer D. 2014. &#x201c;C9orf72 FTLD/ALS-associated Gly-Ala dipeptide repeat proteins cause neuronal toxicity and Unc119 sequestration.&#x201d; Acta Neuropathol 128 (4): 485&#x2013;503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4159571</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25120191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meeter LHH, Gendron TF, Sias AC, Jiskoot LC, Russo SP, Donker Kaat L, Papma JM, Panman JL, van der Ende EL, Dopper EG, Franzen S, Graff C, Boxer AL, Rosen HJ, Sanchez-Valle R, Galimberti D, Pijnenburg YAL, Benussi L, Ghidoni R, Borroni B, Laforce R, Del Campo M, Teunissen CE, van Minkelen R, Rojas JC, Coppola G, Geschwind DH, Rademakers R, Karydas AM, &#xd6;ijerstedt L, Scarpini E, Binetti G, Padovani A, Cash DM, Dick KM, Bocchetta M, Miller BL, Rohrer JD, Petrucelli L, van Swieten JC, and Lee SE. 2018. &#x201c;Poly(GP), neurofilament and grey matter deficits in.&#x201d; Ann Clin Transl Neurol 5 (5): 583&#x2013;597.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5945959</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29761121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mizielinska S, Gr&#xf6;nke S, Niccoli T, Ridler CE, Clayton EL, Devoy A, Moens T, Norona FE, Woollacott IOC, Pietrzyk J, Cleverley K, Nicoll AJ, Pickering-Brown S, Dols J, Cabecinha M, Hendrich O, Fratta P, Fisher EMC, Partridge L, and Isaacs AM. 2014. &#x201c;C9orf72 repeat expansions cause neurodegeneration in Drosophila through arginine-rich proteins.&#x201d; Science 345 (6201): 1192&#x2013;1194.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4944841</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25103406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moens TG, Niccoli T, Wilson KM, Atilano ML, Birsa N, Gittings LM, Holbling BV, Dyson MC, Thoeng A, Neeves J, Glaria I, Yu L, Bussmann J, Storkebaum E, Pardo M, Choudhary JS, Fratta P, Partridge L, and Isaacs AM. 2019. &#x201c;C9orf72 arginine-rich dipeptide proteins interact with ribosomal proteins in vivo to induce a toxic translational arrest that is rescued by eIF1A.&#x201d; Acta Neuropathol 137 (3): 487&#x2013;500.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6514073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30604225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mori K, Weng SM, Arzberger T, May S, Rentzsch K, Kremmer E, Schmid B, Kretzschmar HA, Cruts M, Van Broeckhoven C, Haass C, and Edbauer D. 2013. &#x201c;The C9orf72 GGGGCC repeat is translated into aggregating dipeptide-repeat proteins in FTLD/ALS.&#x201d; Science 339 (6125): 1335&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23393093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neumann M, Sampathu DM, Kwong LK, Truax AC, Micsenyi MC, Chou TT, Bruce J, Schuck T, Grossman M, Clark CM, McCluskey LF, Miller BL, Masliah E, Mackenzie IR, Feldman H, Feiden W, Kretzschmar HA, Trojanowski JQ, and Lee VM. 2006. &#x201c;Ubiquitinated TDP-43 in frontotemporal lobar degeneration and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.&#x201d; Science 314 (5796): 130&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17023659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niblock M, Smith BN, Lee YB, Sardone V, Topp S, Troakes C, Al-Sarraj S, Leblond CS, Dion PA, Rouleau GA, Shaw CE, and Gallo JM. 2016. &#x201c;Retention of hexanucleotide repeat-containing intron in C9orf72 mRNA: implications for the pathogenesis of ALS/FTD.&#x201d; Acta Neuropathol Commun 4: 18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4766718</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26916632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Premasiri AS, Gill AL, and Vieira FG. 2020. &#x201c;Type I PRMT Inhibition Protects Against C9ORF72 Arginine-Rich Dipeptide Repeat Toxicity.&#x201d; Front Pharmacol 11: 569661.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7508178</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33013410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quaegebeur A, Glaria I, Lashley T, and Isaacs AM. 2020. &#x201c;Soluble and insoluble dipeptide repeat protein measurements in C9orf72-frontotemporal dementia brains show regional differential solubility and correlation of poly-GR with clinical severity.&#x201d; Acta Neuropathol Commun 8 (1): 184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7650212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33168090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renton AE, Majounie E, Waite A, Sim&#xf3;n-S&#xe1;nchez J, Rollinson S, Gibbs JR, Schymick JC, Laaksovirta H, van Swieten JC, Myllykangas L, Kalimo H, Paetau A, Abramzon Y, Remes AM, Kaganovich A, Scholz SW, Duckworth J, Ding J, Harmer DW, Hernandez DG, Johnson JO, Mok K, Ryten M, Trabzuni D, Guerreiro RJ, Orrell RW, Neal J, Murray A, Pearson J, Jansen IE, Sondervan D, Seelaar H, Blake D, Young K, Halliwell N, Callister JB, Toulson G, Richardson A, Gerhard A, Snowden J, Mann D, Neary D, Nalls MA, Peuralinna T, Jansson L, Isoviita VM, Kaivorinne AL, H&#xf6;ltt&#xe4;-Vuori M, Ikonen E, Sulkava R, Benatar M, Wuu J, Chi&#xf2; A, Restagno G, Borghero G, Sabatelli M, Heckerman D, Rogaeva E, Zinman L, Rothstein JD, Sendtner M, Drepper C, Eichler EE, Alkan C, Abdullaev Z, Pack SD, Dutra A, Pak E, Hardy J, Singleton A, Williams NM, Heutink P, Pickering-Brown S, Morris HR, Tienari PJ, Traynor BJ, and ITALSGEN Consortium. 2011. &#x201c;A hexanucleotide repeat expansion in C9ORF72 is the cause of chromosome 9p21-linked ALS-FTD.&#x201d; Neuron 72 (2): 257&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3200438</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21944779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saberi S, Stauffer JE, Jiang J, Garcia SD, Taylor AE, Schulte D, Ohkubo T, Schloffman CL, Maldonado M, Baughn M, Rodriguez MJ, Pizzo D, Cleveland D, and Ravits J. 2018. &#x201c;Sense-encoded poly-GR dipeptide repeat proteins correlate to neurodegeneration and uniquely colocalize with TDP-43 in dendrites of repeat-expanded C9orf72 amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.&#x201d; Acta Neuropathol 135 (3): 459&#x2013;474.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5935138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29196813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakae N, Bieniek KF, Zhang YJ, Ross K, Gendron TF, Murray ME, Rademakers R, Petrucelli L, and Dickson DW. 2018. &#x201c;Poly-GR dipeptide repeat polymers correlate with neurodegeneration and Clinicopathological subtypes in C9ORF72-related brain disease.&#x201d; Acta Neuropathol Commun 6 (1): 63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6054740</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30029693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Satoh J, Yamamoto Y, Kitano S, Takitani M, Asahina N, and Kino Y. 2014. &#x201c;Molecular network analysis suggests a logical hypothesis for the pathological role of c9orf72 in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis/frontotemporal dementia.&#x201d; J Cent Nerv Syst Dis 6: 69&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4149381</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25210488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmitz A, Pinheiro Marques J, Oertig I, Maharjan N, and Saxena S. 2021. &#x201c;Emerging Perspectives on Dipeptide Repeat Proteins in C9ORF72 ALS/FTD.&#x201d; Front Cell Neurosci 15: 637548.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7930069</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33679328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sckaff M, Gill K, Sachdev A, Birk AM, Aladesuyi Arogundade O, Watry HL, Keough KC, Tsai Y-C, Ziegle J, Conklin BR, and Clelland CD. 2022. &#x201c;Two therapeutic CRISPR/Cas9 gene editing approaches revert FTD/ALS cellular pathology caused by a C9orf72 repeat expansion mutation in patient derived cells.&#x201d; bioRxiv: 2022.05.21.492887.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sellier C, Buijsen RAM, He F, Natla S, Jung L, Tropel P, Gaucherot A, Jacobs H, Meziane H, Vincent A, Champy MF, Sorg T, Pavlovic G, Wattenhofer-Donze M, Birling MC, Oulad-Abdelghani M, Eberling P, Ruffenach F, Joint M, Anheim M, Martinez-Cerdeno V, Tassone F, Willemsen R, Hukema RK, Viville S, Martinat C, Todd PK, and Charlet-Berguerand N. 2017. &#x201c;Translation of Expanded CGG Repeats into FMRpolyG Is Pathogenic and May Contribute to Fragile X Tremor Ataxia Syndrome.&#x201d; Neuron 93 (2): 331&#x2013;347.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5263258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28065649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sellier C, Campanari ML, Julie Corbier C, Gaucherot A, Kolb-Cheynel I, Oulad-Abdelghani M, Ruffenach F, Page A, Ciura S, Kabashi E, and Charlet-Berguerand N. 2016. &#x201c;Loss of C9ORF72 impairs autophagy and synergizes with polyQ Ataxin-2 to induce motor neuron dysfunction and cell death.&#x201d; EMBO J 35 (12): 1276&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4910533</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27103069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shao W, Todd TW, Wu Y, Jones CY, Tong J, Jansen-West K, Daughrity LM, Park J, Koike Y, Kurti A, Yue M, Castanedes-Casey M, Del Rosso G, Dunmore JA, Zanetti Alepuz D, Oskarsson B, Dickson DW, Cook CN, Prudencio M, Gendron TF, Fryer JD, Zhang YJ, and Petrucelli L. 2022. &#x201c;Two FTD-ALS genes converge on the endosomal pathway to induce TDP-43 pathology and degeneration.&#x201d; Science 378 (6615): 94&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36201573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shatsky IN, Terenin IM, Smirnova VV, and Andreev DE. 2018. &#x201c;Cap-Independent Translation: What&#x2019;s in a Name?&#x201d; Trends Biochem Sci 43 (11): 882&#x2013;895.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29789219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sonobe Y, Ghadge G, Masaki K, Sendoel A, Fuchs E, and Roos RP. 2018. &#x201c;Translation of dipeptide repeat proteins from the C9ORF72 expanded repeat is associated with cellular stress.&#x201d; Neurobiol Dis 116: 155&#x2013;165.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6331062</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29792928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sznajder &#x141;J, Thomas JD, Carrell EM, Reid T, McFarland KN, Cleary JD, Oliveira R, Nutter CA, Bhatt K, Sobczak K, Ashizawa T, Thornton CA, Ranum LPW, and Swanson MS. 2018. &#x201c;Intron retention induced by microsatellite expansions as a disease biomarker.&#x201d; Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 115 (16): 4234&#x2013;4239.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5910826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29610297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tabet R, Schaeffer L, Freyermuth F, Jambeau M, Workman M, Lee CZ, Lin CC, Jiang J, Jansen-West K, Abou-Hamdan H, D&#xe9;saubry L, Gendron T, Petrucelli L, Martin F, and Lagier-Tourenne C. 2018. &#x201c;CUG initiation and frameshifting enable production of dipeptide repeat proteins from ALS/FTD C9ORF72 transcripts.&#x201d; Nat Commun 9 (1): 152.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5764992</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29323119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van &#x2018;t Spijker HM, Stackpole EE, Almeida S, Katsara O, Liu B, Shen K, Schneider RJ, Gao FB, and Richter JD. 2021. &#x201c;Ribosome Profiling Reveals Novel Regulation of C9ORF72 GGGGCC Repeat-Containing RNA Translation.&#x201d; RNA.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8906550</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34848561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Ende EL, Jackson JL, White A, Seelaar H, van Blitterswijk M, and Van Swieten JC. 2021. &#x201c;Unravelling the clinical spectrum and the role of repeat length in.&#x201d; J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 92 (5): 502&#x2013;509.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8053328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33452054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vance C, Al-Chalabi A, Ruddy D, Smith BN, Hu X, Sreedharan J, Siddique T, Schelhaas HJ, Kusters B, Troost D, Baas F, de Jong V, and Shaw CE. 2006. &#x201c;Familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with frontotemporal dementia is linked to a locus on chromosome 9p13.2&#x2013;21.3.&#x201d; Brain 129 (Pt 4): 868&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16495328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S, Latallo MJ, Zhang Z, Huang B, Bobrovnikov DG, Dong D, Livingston NM, Tjoeng W, Hayes LR, Rothstein JD, Ostrow LW, Wu B, and Sun S. 2021. &#x201c;Nuclear export and translation of circular repeat-containing intronic RNA in C9ORF72-ALS/FTD.&#x201d; Nat Commun 12 (1): 4908.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8363653</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34389711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamada SB, Gendron TF, Niccoli T, Genuth NR, Grosely R, Shi Y, Glaria I, Kramer NJ, Nakayama L, Fang S, Dinger TJI, Thoeng A, Rocha G, Barna M, Puglisi JD, Partridge L, Ichida JK, Isaacs AM, Petrucelli L, and Gitler AD. 2019. &#x201c;RPS25 is required for efficient RAN translation of C9orf72 and other neurodegenerative disease-associated nucleotide repeats.&#x201d; Nat Neurosci 22 (9): 1383&#x2013;1388.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6713615</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31358992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young SK, and Wek RC. 2016. &#x201c;Upstream Open Reading Frames Differentially Regulate Gene-specific Translation in the Integrated Stress Response.&#x201d; J Biol Chem 291 (33): 16927&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5016099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27358398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuva-Aydemir Y, Almeida S, Krishnan G, Gendron TF, and Gao FB. 2019. &#x201c;Transcription elongation factor AFF2/FMR2 regulates expression of expanded GGGGCC repeat-containing C9ORF72 allele in ALS/FTD.&#x201d; Nat Commun 10 (1): 5466.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6884579</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31784536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zu T, Gibbens B, Doty NS, Gomes-Pereira M, Huguet A, Stone MD, Margolis J, Peterson M, Markowski TW, Ingram MA, Nan Z, Forster C, Low WC, Schoser B, Somia NV, Clark HB, Schmechel S, Bitterman PB, Gourdon G, Swanson MS, Moseley M, and Ranum LP. 2011. &#x201c;Non-ATG-initiated translation directed by microsatellite expansions.&#x201d; Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 108 (1): 260&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3017129</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21173221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zu T, Liu Y, Ba&#xf1;ez-Coronel M, Reid T, Pletnikova O, Lewis J, Miller TM, Harms MB, Falchook AE, Subramony SH, Ostrow LW, Rothstein JD, Troncoso JC, and Ranum LP. 2013. &#x201c;RAN proteins and RNA foci from antisense transcripts in C9ORF72 ALS and frontotemporal dementia.&#x201d; Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 110 (51): E4968&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3870665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24248382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>