<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36655874</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>18</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-4598</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>67</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>May</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Muscle &amp; nerve</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Muscle Nerve</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Pulmonary care for ALS: Progress, gaps, and paths forward.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>341</StartPage><EndPage>353</EndPage><MedlinePgn>341-353</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/mus.27779</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION">Adults with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) have been using home mechanical ventilation for over 50&#x2009;years. More recently, home respiratory care has evolved to include portable home ventilators, airway clearance devices, and physiological assessments with telemonitoring capability.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CURRENT STATE OF RESPIRATORY CARE">National organizations currently offer incentives for providing a pulmonary care specialist within a multidisciplinary ALS clinic; however, several critical gaps exist between the available technology and employing a clinician with the necessary expertise.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="GAPS IN CARE">Lack of formal training and poor financial incentives have led to a paucity of both clinicians and active clinical research engaging in the home respiratory care of ALS. Criteria for noninvasive ventilation (NIV) initiation are controversial, and few guidelines exist on the ideal subsequent adjustments of NIV with evolving disease. Consequently, many patients with ALS tolerate NIV poorly and must face the harrowing decision of hospice vs tracheostomy. Advancement of respiratory care in ALS has been hindered by critical gaps in pulmonologist availability, training in chronic respiratory failure, financial support, clinical research, and clarity on ventilation management beyond initiation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="BRINGING RESPIRATORY CARE UP TO SPEED">Only a multifaceted approach will suffice for addressing the voids in ALS respiratory care, including various education initiatives, financial incentives, clinical research programs, and elevating the standard of respiratory care.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Author. Muscle &amp; Nerve published by Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ackrivo</LastName><ForeName>Jason</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4379-1255</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pulmonary, Allergy, and Critical Care Division, Department of Medicine, Perelman School of Medicine at the University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>K23 HL151879</GrantID><Acronym>HL</Acronym><Agency>NHLBI NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>K23 HL-151879</GrantID><Acronym>NH</Acronym><Agency>NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Muscle Nerve</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7803146</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0148-639X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012121" MajorTopicYN="N">Respiration, Artificial</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D063087" MajorTopicYN="Y">Noninvasive Ventilation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012122" MajorTopicYN="N">Ventilators, Mechanical</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014139" MajorTopicYN="N">Tracheostomy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012131" MajorTopicYN="Y">Respiratory Insufficiency</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chronic respiratory failure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neuromuscular disorder</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">noninvasive ventilation</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36655874</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.27779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Lehner WE, Ballard IM, Figueroa WG, Woodruff DS. Home care utilizing a ventilator in a patient with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Fam Pract. 1980;10:39-42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bourke SC, Tomlinson M, Williams TL, Bullock RE, Shaw PJ, Gibson GJ. Effects of non-invasive ventilation on survival and quality of life in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a randomised controlled trial. Lancet Neurol. 2006;5:140-147. doi:10.1016/s1474-4422(05)70326-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen PM, Abrahams S, Borasio GD, et al. EFNS Guidelines on the Clinical Management of Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis (MALS)---revised report of an EFNS task force. Eur J Neurol. 2012;19:360-375. doi:10.1111/j.1468-1331.2011.03501.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rimmer KP, Kaminska M, Nonoyama M, et al. Home mechanical ventilation for patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a Canadian Thoracic Society clinical practice guideline. Can J Respir Crit Care Sleep Med. 2019;3:d7-3b8d-4c1f-8c0b-d00fe8ab1295&gt;3:1-19. doi:10.1080/24745332.2018.1559644</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Georges M, Perez T, Rabec C, et al. Proposals from a French expert panel for respiratory care in ALS patients. Respir Med Res. 2022;81:100901. doi:10.1016/j.resmer.2022.100901</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hansen-Flaschen J. Respiratory care for patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in the US. JAMA Neurol. 2021;78:1047-1048. doi:10.1001/jamaneurol.2021.2400</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corcia P, Meininger V. Grey matter 150th anniversary of Charcot's description of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain. 2019;142:3306-3313. doi:10.1093/brain/awz280</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veit H. Dynamic view of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Nerv Ment Dis. 1947;106:129-136. doi:10.1097/00005053-194710620-00003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hind M, Polkey MI, Simonds AK. AJRCCM: 100-year anniversary. Homeward bound: a centenary of home mechanical ventilation. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2017;195:1140-1149. doi:10.1164/rccm.201702-0285ci</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sivak ED, Cordasco EM, Gipson WT. Pulmonary mechanical ventilation at home: a reasonable and less expensive alternative. Respir Care. 1983;28:42-49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janiszewski DW, Caroscio JT, Wisham LH. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a comprehensive rehabilitation approach. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 1983;64:304-307.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bach J. Respiratory muscle aids for the prevention of pulmonary morbidity and mortality. Semin Neurol. 1995;15:72-83. doi:10.1055/s-2008-1041010</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaplan LM, Hollander D. Respiratory dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Chest Med. 1994;15:675-681.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sherman MS, Paz HL. Review of respiratory care of the patient with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Respiration. 1994;61:61-67. doi:10.1159/000196308</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aboussouan LS, Khan SU, Meeker DP, Stelmach K, Mitsumoto H. Effect of noninvasive positive-pressure ventilation on survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Intern Med. 1997;127:450. doi:10.7326/0003-4819-127-6-199709150-00006</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kleopa KA, Sherman M, Neal B, Romano GJ, Heiman-Patterson T. Bipap improves survival and rate of pulmonary function decline in patients with ALS. J Neurol Sci. 1999;164:82-88. doi:10.1016/s0022-510x(99)00045-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melo J, Homma A, Iturriaga E, et al. Pulmonary evaluation and prevalence of non-invasive ventilation in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a multicenter survey and proposal of a pulmonary protocol. J Neurol Sci. 1999;169:114-117.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services. Local coverage determination. Respiratory Assist Devices L33800. https://www.cms.gov/medicare-coverage-database/view/lcd.aspx?LCDId=33800&amp;DocID=L33800. Accessed July 11, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polverino M, Polverino F, Fasolino M, And&#xf2; F, Alfieri A, Blasio FD. Anatomy and neuro-pathophysiology of the cough reflex arc. Multidiscip Respir Med. 2012;7:5. doi:10.1186/2049-6958-7-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benditt JO. Mechanical insufflation-exsufflation: more than just cough assist. Respir Care. 2018;63:1076-1077. doi:10.4187/respcare.06439</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bach JR, Saporito LR. Criteria for extubation and tracheostomy tube removal for patients with ventilatory failure. Chest. 1996;110:1566-1571. doi:10.1378/chest.110.6.1566</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toussaint M, Chatwin M, Gonzales J, et al. 228Th ENMC International Workshop: Airway Clearance Techniques In Neuromuscular Disorders 3-5 March, 2017, Naarden, The Netherlands. Neuromuscul Disord. 2017;28:289-298. doi:10.1016/j.nmd.2017.10.008</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chatwin M, Toussaint M, Gon&#xe7;alves MR, et al. Airway clearance techniques in neuromuscular disorders: a state of the art review. Respir Med. 2018;136:98-110. doi:10.1016/j.rmed.2018.01.012</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katz SL, Barrowman N, Monsour A, Su S, Hoey L, McKim D. Long-term effects of lung volume recruitment on maximal inspiratory capacity and vital capacity in Duchenne muscular dystrophy. Ann Am Thorac Soc. 2016;13:217-222. doi:10.1513/annalsats.201507-475bc</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canadian Alternatives in Noninvasive Ventilation. Phase 2: Interventions - Manually Assisted Cough. https://www.ohri.ca//nivam/default.aspx?slideid=660. Accessed July 11, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services. Mechanical In-exsufflation Devices. https://www.cms.gov/medicare-coverage-database/view/lcd.aspx?lcdid=33795. Accessed November 16, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen TM, Sandnes A, Fondenes O, et al. Laryngeal responses to mechanically assisted cough in progressing amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Respir Care. 2018;63:538-549. doi:10.4187/respcare.05924</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen TM, Hov B, Halvorsen T, R&#xf8;ksund OD, Vollsaeter M. Upper airway assessment and responses during mechanically assisted cough-a narrative review. Respir Care. 2021;66:respcare.08960:1196-1213. doi:10.4187/respcare.08960</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swingwood E, Shah NM, Rose L. Oscillations with mechanical insufflation-exsufflation in ALS: time to pause and return to basics? Respir Care. 2021;66:536-537. doi:10.4187/respcare.08954</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ackrivo J, Elman L, Hansen-Flaschen J. Telemonitoring for home-assisted ventilation: a narrative review. Ann Am Thorac Soc. 2021;18:1761-1772. doi:10.1513/annalsats.202101-033cme</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rutkove SB, Narayanaswami P, Berisha V, et al. Improved ALS clinical trials through frequent at-home self-assessment: a proof of concept study. Ann Clin Transl Neurol. 2020;7:1148-1157. doi:10.1002/acn3.51096</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrews JA, Berry JD, Baloh RH, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis care and research in the United States during the COVID-19 pandemic: challenges and opportunities. Muscle Nerve. 2020;62:182-186. doi:10.1002/mus.26989</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haulman A, Geronimo A, Chahwala A, Simmons Z. The use of telehealth to enhance care in ALS and other neuromuscular disorders. Muscle Nerve. 2020;61:682-691. doi:10.1002/mus.26838</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geronimo A, Simmons Z. Evaluation of remote pulmonary function testing in motor neuron disease. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2019;20:348-355. doi:10.1080/21678421.2019.1587633</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelly CR, Parra-Cantu C, Thapa P, et al. Comparative performance of different respiratory test parameters for detection of early respiratory insufficiency in patients with ALS. Neurology. 2022;99:e743-e750. doi:10.1212/WNL.0000000000200758</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nassar BS, Schmidt GA. Estimating arterial partial pressure of carbon dioxide in ventilated patients: how valid are surrogate measures? Ann Am Thorac Soc. 2017;14:1005-1014. doi:10.1513/annalsats.201701-034fr</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quigg KH, Wilson MW, Choi PJ. Transcutaneous CO2 monitoring as indication for inpatient non-invasive ventilation initiation in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 2021;65:444-447. doi:10.1002/mus.27457</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ackrivo J, Geronimo A. Transcutaneous carbon dioxide monitoring in ALS: assessment of hypoventilation heats up. Muscle Nerve. 2022;65:371-373. doi:10.1002/mus.27502</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rafiq MK, Bradburn M, Proctor AR, et al. Using transcutaneous carbon dioxide monitor (TOSCA 500) to detect respiratory failure in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a validation study. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2012;13:528-532. doi:10.3109/17482968.2012.688836</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conway A, Tipton E, Liu W-H, et al. Accuracy and precision of transcutaneous carbon dioxide monitoring: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Thorax. 2019;74:157-163. doi:10.1136/thoraxjnl-2017-211466</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller RG, Jackson CE, Kasarskis EJ, et al. Practice parameter update: the care of the patient with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis&amp;colon; multidisciplinary care, symptom management, and cognitive/behavioral impairment (an evidence-based review). Neurology. 2009;73:1227-1233. doi:10.1212/wnl.0b013e3181bc01a4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller R, Jackson C, Kasarskis E, et al. Practice parameter update: the care of the patient with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: drug, nutritional, and respiratory therapies (an evidence-based review) report of the quality standards Subcommittee of the American Academy of Neurology. Neurology. 2009;73:1218-1226. doi:10.1212/wnl.0b013e3181bc0141</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldberg A. Clinical indications for noninvasive positive pressure ventilation in chronic respiratory failure due to restrictive lung disease, COPD, and nocturnal hypoventilation-a consensus conference report. Chest. 1999;116:521-534. doi:10.1378/chest.116.2.521</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Association. More information on certified centers &amp; clinics. https://www.als.org/local-support/certified-centers-clinics/more-information-certified-centers-clinics#:~:text=To%20become%20certified%20as%20a,complete%20a%20comprehensive%20site%20review. Accessed April 28, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MDA Care Center Network. https://www.mda.org/care/mda-care-centers. Accessed April 28, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heiman-Patterson TD, Cudkowicz ME, Carvalho MD, et al. Understanding the use of NIV in ALS: results of an international ALS specialist survey. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2018;19:1-11. doi:10.1080/21678421.2018.1457058</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ackrivo J, Hsu JY, Hansen-Flaschen J, Elman L, Kawut SM. Non-invasive ventilation use is associated with better survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Am Thorac Soc. 2021;18:486-494. doi:10.1513/annalsats.202002-169oc</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berlowitz DJ, Howard ME, Fiore JF, et al. Identifying who will benefit from non-invasive ventilation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis/motor neurone disease in a clinical cohort. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2016;87:280-286. doi:10.1136/jnnp-2014-310055</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westeneng H-J, Debray TP, Visser AE, et al. Prognosis for patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: development and validation of a personalised prediction model. Lancet Neurol. 2018;17:423-433. doi:10.1016/s1474-4422(18)30089-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ackrivo J, Hansen-Flaschen J, Wileyto EP, Schwab RJ, Elman L, Kawut SM. Development of a prognostic model of respiratory insufficiency or death in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Eur Respir J. 2019;53:1802237. doi:10.1183/13993003.02237-2018</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pirola A, Mattia ED, Lizio A, et al. The prognostic value of spirometric tests in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. Clin Neurol Neurosurg. 2019;184:105456. doi:10.1016/j.clineuro.2019.105456</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt EP, Drachman DB, Wiener CM, Clawson L, Kimball R, Lechtzin N. Pulmonary predictors of survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: use in clinical trial design. Muscle Nerve. 2005;33:127-132. doi:10.1002/mus.20450</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Czaplinski A, Yen A, Appel S. Forced vital capacity (FVC) as an indicator of survival and disease progression in an ALS clinic population. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2006;77:390-392. doi:10.1136/jnnp.2005.072660</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Czaplinski A, Yen AA, Appel SH. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: early predictors of prolonged survival. J Neurol. 2006;253:1428-1436. doi:10.1007/s00415-006-0226-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ackrivo J, Hansen-Flaschen J, Jones BL, et al. Classifying patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis by changes in FVC. A group-based trajectory analysis. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2019;200:1513-1521. doi:10.1164/rccm.201902-0344oc</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finkelstein SM, Lindgren B, Prasad B, et al. Reliability and validity of spirometry measurements in a paperless home monitoring diary program for lung transplantation. Heart Lung. 1993;22:523-533.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burton DL, LeMay KS, Saini B, et al. The reliability and utility of spirometry performed on people with asthma in community pharmacies. J Asthma. 2015;52:913-919. doi:10.3109/02770903.2015.1004684</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fallat RJ, Jewitt B, Bass M, Kamm B, Norris FH. Spirometry in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Arch Neurol. 1979;36:74-80. doi:10.1001/archneur.1979.00500380044004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lechtzin N, Scott Y, Busse AM, Clawson LL, Kimball R, Wiener CM. Early use of non-invasive ventilation prolongs survival in subjects with ALS. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2007;8:185-188. doi:10.1080/17482960701262392</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolfe LF, Benditt JO, Aboussouan L, Hess DR, Coleman JM 3rd, ONMAP Technical Expert Panel. Optimal noninvasive Medicare access promotion: patients with thoracic restrictive diseases a technical expert panel report from the American College of Chest Physicians, the American Association for Respiratory Care, the American Academy of Sleep Medicine, and the American Thoracic Society. Chest. 2021;160:e399-e408. doi:10.1016/j.chest.2021.05.075</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fitting J-W. Sniff nasal inspiratory pressure: simple or too simple? Eur Respir J. 2006;27:881-883. doi:10.1183/09031936.06.00007906</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lechtzin N, Cudkowicz ME, de Carvalho M, et al. Respiratory measures in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2018;19:321-330. doi:10.1080/21678421.2018.1452945</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Georges M, Nguyen-Baranoff D, Griffon L, et al. Usefulness of transcutaneous PCO2to assess nocturnal hypoventilation in restrictive lung disorders: diagnosis of nocturnal hypoventilation. Respirology. 2016;21:1300-1306. doi:10.1111/resp.12812</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Georges M, Rabec C, Monin E, et al. Monitoring of noninvasive ventilation: comparative analysis of different strategies. Respir Res. 2020;21:324. doi:10.1186/s12931-020-01586-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boentert M, Glatz C, Helmle C, Okegwo A, Young P. Prevalence of sleep apnoea and capnographic detection of nocturnal hypoventilation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2018;89:418-424. doi:10.1136/jnnp-2017-316515</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thakore NJ, Lapin BR, Pioro EP, Aboussouan LS. Variation in noninvasive ventilation use in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology. 2019;93:e306-e316. doi:10.1212/wnl.0000000000007776</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larkindale J, Yang W, Hogan PF, et al. Cost of illness for neuromuscular diseases in the United States. Muscle Nerve. 2014;49:431-438. doi:10.1002/mus.23942</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peters SG. New billing rules for outpatient office visit codes. Chest. 2020;158:298-302. doi:10.1016/j.chest.2020.01.028</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services. DMEPOS fee schedule. https://www.cms.gov/medicare/medicare-fee-for-service-payment/dmeposfeesched/dmepos-fee-schedule. Accessed August 17, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Escalating medicare billing for ventilators raises concerns. US Department of Health &amp; Human Services, Office of Inspector General. https://oig.hhs.gov/oei/reports/oei-12-15-00370.pdf. Accessed May 28, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sivak ED, Gipson WT, Hanson MR. Long-term management of respiratory failure in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol. 1982;12:18-23. doi:10.1002/ana.410120104</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institutes of Health RePORTER. https://reporter.nih.gov. Accessed August 15, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Notice of Special Interest (NOSI): Respiratory Complications of the Muscular Dystrophies (R01). https://grants.nih.gov/grants/guide/notice-files/NOT-HL-22-025.html. Accessed July 23, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institutes of Health, National Institute of Neurological Disorders and Stroke. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) request for public comment on the draft ALS strategic plan. https://www.ninds.nih.gov/about-ninds/strategic-plans-evaluations/strategic-plans/amyotrophic-lateral-sclerosis-als. Accessed November 28, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Academy of Neurology. Richard Olney Clinician Scientist Development Award in ALS. https://www.aan.com/research/richard-olney-award-als. Accessed June 6, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muscular Dystrophy Association. Funding opportunities: MDA development grants. https://www.mda.org/science/funding-opportunities. Accessed June 6, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Thoracic Society. Programs: eligibility criteria. https://research.thoracic.org/grants/eligibility-criteria.php. Accessed July 11, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Accreditation Council for Graduate Medical Education. ACGME. Program requirements for graduate medical education in pulmonary disease and critical care medicine. Accessed May 2, 2022. https://www.acgme.org/globalassets/pfassets/programrequirements/156_pccm_2022.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hazenberg A, Kerstjens HA, Prins SC, Vermeulen KM, Wijkstra PJ. Is chronic ventilatory support really effective in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis? J Neurol. 2016;263:2456-2461. doi:10.1007/s00415-016-8288-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Markaki A, Malhotra S, Billings R, Theus L. Training needs assessment: tool utilization and global impact. BMC Med Educ. 2021;21:310. doi:10.1186/s12909-021-02748-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Academy of Sleep Medicine. AIRE pilot programs. innovative sleep medicine training. https://aasm.org/professional-development/choose-sleep/aire-pilot-programs. Accessed June 25, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S.1512---CONNECT for Health Act of 2021. 1-26. https://www.congress.gov/bill/117th-congress/senate-bill/1512/text?format=txt. Accessed July 7, 2022.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>