<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36692202</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>06</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1468-1331</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>30</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>May</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Severity of in vivo corticospinal tract degeneration is associated with survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a longitudinal, multicohort study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1220</StartPage><EndPage>1231</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1220-1231</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/ene.15686</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND PURPOSE">This study sought to evaluate the relationship of progressive corticospinal tract (CST) degeneration with survival in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Forty-one ALS patients and 42 healthy controls were prospectively recruited from the Canadian ALS Neuroimaging Consortium. Magnetic resonance imaging scanning and clinical evaluations were performed on participants at three serial visits with 4-month intervals. Texture analysis was performed on T1-weighted magnetic resonance imaging scans and the texture feature 'autocorrelation' was quantified. Whole-brain group-level comparisons were performed between patient subgroups. Linear mixed models were used to evaluate longitudinal progression. Region-of-interest and 3D voxel-wise Cox proportional-hazards regression models were constructed for survival prediction. For all survival analyses, a second independent cohort was used for model validation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Autocorrelation of the bilateral CST was increased at baseline and progressively increased over time at a faster rate in ALS short survivors. Cox proportional-hazards regression analyses revealed autocorrelation of the CST as a significant predictor of survival at 5&#x2009;years follow-up (hazard ratio 1.28, p&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.005). Similarly, voxel-wise whole-brain survival analyses revealed that increased autocorrelation of the CST was associated with shorter survival. ALS patients stratified by median autocorrelation in the CST had significantly different survival times using the Kaplan-Meier curve and log-rank tests (&#x3c7;<sup>2</sup> &#xa0;=&#x2009;7.402, p&#x2009;=&#xa0;0.007).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Severity of cerebral degeneration is associated with survival in ALS. CST degeneration progresses faster in subgroups of patients with shorter survival. Neuroimaging holds promise as a tool to improve patient management and facilitation of clinical trials.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 European Academy of Neurology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ta</LastName><ForeName>Daniel</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4975-2970</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neuroscience and Mental Health Institute, University of Alberta, Edmonton, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ishaque</LastName><ForeName>Abdullah H</ForeName><Initials>AH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Neurosurgery, Department of Surgery, University of Toronto, Toronto, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Elamy</LastName><ForeName>Adam</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neuroscience and Mental Health Institute, University of Alberta, Edmonton, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Anand</LastName><ForeName>Tanushka</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2575-1663</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neuroscience and Mental Health Institute, University of Alberta, Edmonton, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Andrew</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neuroscience and Mental Health Institute, University of Alberta, Edmonton, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Eurich</LastName><ForeName>Dean T</ForeName><Initials>DT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Public Health, University of Alberta, Edmonton, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Luk</LastName><ForeName>Collin</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Neurology, Department of Medicine, University of Alberta, Edmonton, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Yee Hong</ForeName><Initials>YH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computing Science, University of Alberta, Edmonton, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kalra</LastName><ForeName>Sanjay</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4762-8746</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neuroscience and Mental Health Institute, University of Alberta, Edmonton, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Neurology, Department of Medicine, University of Alberta, Edmonton, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>CIHR</Agency><Country>Canada</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9506311</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1351-5101</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011712" MajorTopicYN="N">Pyramidal Tracts</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002170" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Canada</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008279" MajorTopicYN="N">Magnetic Resonance Imaging</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D059906" MajorTopicYN="N">Neuroimaging</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ALS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">corticospinal tract</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">prognosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">survival</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">texture analysis</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36692202</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ene.15686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2; A, Logroscino G, Hardiman O, et al. Prognostic factors in ALS: a critical review. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2009;10(5-6):310-323. doi:10.3109/17482960802566824</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su WM, Cheng YF, Jiang Z, et al. Predictors of survival in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a large meta-analysis. EBioMedicine. 2021;74:103732. doi:10.1016/j.ebiom.2021.103732</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner MR, Kiernan MC, Leigh PN, Talbot K. Biomarkers in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet Neurol. 2009;8(1):94-109. doi:10.1016/S1474-4422(08)70293-X</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalra S, M&#xfc;ller HP, Ishaque A, et al. A prospective harmonized multicenter DTI study of cerebral white matter degeneration in ALS. Neurology. 2020;95(8):e943-e952. doi:10.1212/WNL.0000000000010235</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agosta F, Pagani E, Petrolini M, et al. Assessment of white matter tract damage in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a diffusion tensor MR imaging tractography study. Am J Neuroradiol. 2010;31:1457-1461. doi:10.3174/ajnr.A2105</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishaque A, Mah D, Seres P, et al. Corticospinal tract degeneration in ALS unmasked in T1-weighted images using texture analysis. Hum Brain Mapp. 2019;40(4):1174-1183. doi:10.1002/hbm.24437</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walhout R, Westeneng HJ, Verstraete E, et al. Cortical thickness in ALS: towards a marker for upper motor neuron involvement. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2015;86:288-294. doi:10.1136/jnnp-2013-306839</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verstraete E, Veldink JH, Hendrikse J, Schelhaas HJ, van den Heuvel MP, van den Berg LH. Structural MRI reveals cortical thinning in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2012;83(4):383-388. doi:10.1136/JNNP-2011-300909</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ill&#xe1;n-Gala I, Montal V, Pegueroles J, et al. Cortical microstructure in the amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-frontotemporal dementia continuum. Neurology. 2020;95(18):e2565-e2576. doi:10.1212/WNL.0000000000010727</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuster C, Hardiman O, Bede P. Survival prediction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis based on MRI measures and clinical characteristics. BMC Neurol. 2017;17(1):73. doi:10.1186/s12883-017-0854-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalra S, Vitale A, Cashman NR, Genge A, Arnold DL. Cerebral degeneration predicts survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2006;77(11):1253-1255. doi:10.1136/jnnp.2006.090696</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agosta F, Spinelli EG, Riva N, et al. Survival prediction models in motor neuron disease. Eur J Neurol. 2019;26:1143-1152. doi:10.1111/ene.13957</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed RM, Devenney EM, Strikwerda-Brown C, Hodges JR, Piguet O, Kiernan MC. Phenotypic variability in ALS-FTD and effect on survival. Neurology. 2020;94(19):e2005-e2013. doi:10.1212/WNL.0000000000009398</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Burgh HK, Schmidt R, Westeneng HJ, de Reus MA, van den Berg LH, van den Heuvel MP. Deep learning predictions of survival based on MRI in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. NeuroImage Clin. 2017;13:361-369. doi:10.1016/j.nicl.2016.10.008</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agosta F, Pagani E, Petrolini M, et al. MRI predictors of long-term evolution in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Eur J Neurosci. 2010;32(9):1490-1496. doi:10.1111/j.1460-9568.2010.07445.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanstock C, Sun K, Choi C, et al. Spectroscopic markers of neurodegeneration in the mesial prefrontal cortex predict survival in ALS. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Front Degener. 2020;21:246-251. doi:10.1080/21678421.2020.1727926</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishaque A, Mah D, Seres P, et al. Evaluating the cerebral correlates of survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Clin Transl Neurol. 2018;5(11):1350-1361. doi:10.1002/acn3.655</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haralick RM, Dinstein I, Shanmugam K. Textural features for image classification. IEEE Trans Syst Man Cybern. 1973;SMC-3(6):610-621. doi:10.1109/TSMC.1973.4309314</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kassner A, Thornhill RE. Texture analysis: a review of neurologic MR imaging applications. Am J Neuroradiol. 2010;31(5):809-816. doi:10.3174/ajnr.A2061</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maani R, Yang YH, Kalra S. Voxel-based texture analysis of the brain. PLoS One. 2015;10(3):e0117759. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0117759</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maani R, Yang Y-H, Emery D, Kalra S. Cerebral degeneration in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis revealed by 3-dimensional texture analysis. Front Neurosci. 2016;10:120. doi:10.3389/fnins.2016.00120</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishaque A, Maani R, Satkunam J, et al. Texture analysis to detect cerebral degeneration in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Can J Neurol Sci. 2018;45(5):533-539. doi:10.1017/cjn.2018.267</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johns SLM, Ishaque A, Khan M, Yang Y-H, Wilman AH, Kalra S. Quantifying changes on susceptibility weighted images in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis using MRI texture analysis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Front Degener. 2019;20(5-6):396-403. doi:10.1080/21678421.2019.1599024</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Albuquerque M, Anjos LGV, Maia Tavares de Andrade H, et al. MRI texture analysis reveals deep gray nuclei damage in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neuroimaging. 2016;26(2):201-206. doi:10.1111/jon.12262</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanjay Kalra A, Khan M, Barlow L, et al. The Canadian ALS Neuroimaging Consortium (CALSNIC)-a multicentre platform for standardized imaging and clinical studies in ALS. medRxiv. 2020. doi:10.1101/2020.07.10.20142679</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, Miller RG, Swash M, Munsat TL, World Federation of Neurology Research Group on Motor Neuron Diseases. El Escorial revisited: revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord. 2000;1(5):293-299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum JM, Stambler N, Malta E, et al. The ALSFRS-R: a revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. J Neurol Sci. 1999;169(1-2):13-21. doi:10.1016/S0022-510X(99)00210-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ta D, Ishaque A, Srivastava O, et al. Progressive neurochemical abnormalities in cognitive and motor subgroups of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a prospective multicenter study. Neurology. 2021;97:e803-e813. doi:10.1212/WNL.0000000000012367</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abrahams S, Newton J, Niven E, Foley J, Bak TH. Screening for cognition and behaviour changes in ALS. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Front Degener. 2014;15(1-2):9-14. doi:10.3109/21678421.2013.805784</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMillan CT, Wuu J, Rascovsky K, et al. Defining cognitive impairment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: an evaluation of empirical approaches. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Front Degener. 2022;23:517-526. doi:10.1080/21678421.2022.2039713</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longinetti E, Fang F. Epidemiology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: an update of recent literature. Curr Opin Neurol. 2019;32(5):771-776. doi:10.1097/WCO.0000000000000730</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishaque A, Ta D, Khan M, et al. Distinct patterns of progressive gray and white matter degeneration in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Hum Brain Mapp. 2022;43(5):1519-1534. doi:10.1002/HBM.25738</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luk CC, Ishaque A, Khan M, et al. Alzheimer's disease: 3-dimensional MRI texture for prediction of conversion from mild cognitive impairment. Alzheimers Dement. 2018;10:755-763. doi:10.1016/J.DADM.2018.09.002</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ta D, Khan M, Ishaque A, et al. Reliability of 3D texture analysis: a multicenter MRI study of the brain. J Magn Reson Imaging. 2020;51:1200-1209. doi:10.1002/jmri.26904</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawyer T, Netsky MG. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a clinicoanatomic study of fifty-three cases. Arch Neurol Psychiatry. 1953;69(2):171-192. doi:10.1001/archneurpsyc.1953.02320260029002</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brettschneider J, Del Tredici K, Toledo JB, et al. Stages of pTDP-43 pathology in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol. 2013;74(1):20-38. doi:10.1002/ana.23937</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kassubek J, M&#xfc;ller HP, Del Tredici K, et al. Imaging the pathoanatomy of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in vivo: targeting a propagation-based biological marker. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2018;89(4):374-381. doi:10.1136/jnnp-2017-316365</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beaulieu C. The basis of anisotropic water diffusion in the nervous system-a technical review. NMR Biomed. 2002;15(7-8):435-455. doi:10.1002/nbm.782</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elamin M, Bede P, Montuschi A, Pender N, Chio A, Hardiman O. Predicting prognosis in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a simple algorithm. J Neurol. 2015;262(6):1447-1454. doi:10.1007/s00415-015-7731-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westeneng HJ, Debray TPA, Visser AE, et al. Prognosis for patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: development and validation of a personalised prediction model. Lancet Neurol. 2018;17(5):423-433. doi:10.1016/S1474-4422(18)30089-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devine MS, Ballard E, Orourke P, Kiernan MC, McCombe PA, Henderson RD. Targeted assessment of lower motor neuron burden is associated with survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2016;17(3-4):184-190. doi:10.3109/21678421.2015.1125502</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grollemund V, Le Chat G, Secchi-Buhour MS, et al. Development and validation of a 1-year survival prognosis estimation model for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis using manifold learning algorithm UMAP. Sci Rep. 2020;10(1):13378. doi:10.1038/S41598-020-70125-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Imai E, Nakamura T, Atsuta N, et al. A nerve conduction study predicts the prognosis of sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol. 2020;267(9):2524-2532. doi:10.1007/S00415-020-09858-5/FIGURES/4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dreger M, Steinbach R, Otto M, Turner MR, Grosskreutz J. Cerebrospinal fluid biomarkers of disease activity and progression in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2022;93(4):422-435. doi:10.1136/JNNP-2021-327503</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Picher-Martel V, Magnussen C, Blais M, et al. CAPTURE ALS: the comprehensive analysis platform to understand, remedy and eliminate ALS. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2023;24(1-2):33-39. doi:10.1080/21678421.2022.2041668</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardenas-Blanco A, Machts J, Acosta-Cabronero J, et al. Structural and diffusion imaging versus clinical assessment to monitor amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuroimage Clin. 2016;11:408-414. doi:10.1016/j.nicl.2016.03.011. http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phukan J, Elamin M, Bede P, et al. The syndrome of cognitive impairment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a population-based study. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2012;83(1):102-108. doi:10.1136/jnnp-2011-300188</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lillo P, Mioshi E, Burrell JR, Kiernan MC, Hodges JR, Hornberger M. Grey and white matter changes across the amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-frontotemporal dementia continuum. PLoS One. 2012;7:e43993. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0043993</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bharti K, Khan M, Beaulieu C, et al. Involvement of the dentate nucleus in the pathophysiology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a multi-center and multi-modal neuroimaging study. Neuroimage Clin. 2020;28:102385. doi:10.1016/j.nicl.2020.102385</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller HP, Del Tredici K, Lul&#xe9; D, et al. In vivo histopathological staging in C9orf72-associated ALS: a tract of interest DTI study. NeuroImage Clin. 2020;27:102298. doi:10.1016/j.nicl.2020.102298</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>