<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36703268</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>19</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2753</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>29</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of evaluation in clinical practice</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Eval Clin Pract</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Perceived benefits from peer-support among family caregivers of people with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and cognitive impairments in a palliative rehabilitation blended online learning programme.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>602</StartPage><EndPage>613</EndPage><MedlinePgn>602-613</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/jep.13808</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="RATIONALE">Family caregivers of persons with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and cognitive and/or behavioural impairments (PALS/CIs) experience various challenges and needs, including emotional and practical support from peers. Various forms of peer-support have shown different strengths and weaknesses; however, little is known about how family caregivers of PALS/CIs&#xa0;interact with and perceive virtual face-to-face peer-support.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="AIMS AND OBJECTIVES">The aim of this study was to understand how caregivers of PALS/CIs&#xa0;interact with and perceive virtual face-to-face peer-support in a palliative rehabilitation programme designed to promote targeted palliative rehabilitation initiatives for caregivers of PALS/CIs.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHOD">A qualitative design using participant observations of 17 recorded virtual group-facilitated meetings from two rounds of a 4-month intervention was performed. The Medical Research Council framework, the inductive interpretive description methodology and the theoretical framework of Sense of Coherence guided the study. Nineteen participants, divided into four groups, were included.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Three themes emerged: 'Relating my situation to others', 'Making room for forbidden thoughts' and 'Longing for normalcy'. The themes reflected the various ways participants interacted in online group meetings and how the interactions evolved around practical, emotional&#xa0;and forbidden thoughts. Sharing personal and sorrowful concerns and frustrations engendered feelings of trust and a sense of belonging, which empowered the participants to address their genuine wish and longing for normalcy with all the trivialities of which ALS/CIs had robbed them.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">Virtual face-to-face peer-support can enable caregivers of PALS/CIs&#xa0;to share experiences of everyday life challenges that cannot always be shared elsewhere. Being able to relate to and learn from other's&#xa0;experiences alleviated feelings of loneliness, frustration, and concerns and thereby enhanced comprehensibility, manageability&#xa0;and meaningfulness. Online palliative rehabilitation interventions should provide an opportunity for caregivers to meet regularly in interactive group meetings. Familiarization takes time online and is necessary to improve their sense of feeling safe to share their deepest thoughts. Such group interventions, facilitated by trained healthcare professionals, offer a means to support dynamic group interactions and discussion of sensitive topics.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Olesen</LastName><ForeName>Lene Klem</ForeName><Initials>LK</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0225-6045</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The National Rehabilitation Center for Neuromuscular Diseases, (RCFM), Aarhus, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health, Faculty of Health, University of Aarhus, Aarhus, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>la Cour</LastName><ForeName>Karen</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Occupational Science, the Research Unit of User Perspectives and Community-based Interventions, University of Southern Denmark, Odense, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Thorne</LastName><ForeName>Sally</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Nursing, University of British Columbia, Vancouver, British Columbia, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>With</LastName><ForeName>Heidi</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The National Rehabilitation Center for Neuromuscular Diseases, (RCFM), Aarhus, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Handberg</LastName><ForeName>Charlotte</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1378-2449</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The National Rehabilitation Center for Neuromuscular Diseases, (RCFM), Aarhus, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health, Faculty of Health, University of Aarhus, Aarhus, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>The patient organization the Danish Foundation for Neuromuscular Diseases, the Institute of Public Health, University of Aarhus, Denmark</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Eval Clin Pract</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9609066</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1356-1294</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017028" MajorTopicYN="N">Caregivers</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020375" MajorTopicYN="Y">Education, Distance</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003376" MajorTopicYN="N">Counseling</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D060825" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cognitive Dysfunction</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D036301" MajorTopicYN="N">Qualitative Research</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005190" MajorTopicYN="N">Family</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">behavioural impairments</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cognitive impairments</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">family caregivers</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">palliative rehabilitation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">participant observation</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36703268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jep.13808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Turner MR, Jenkins L. Fast Facts:&#xa0;Diagnosing Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. S. Karger Publishers Ltd; 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caga J, Zoing MC, Foxe D, et al. Problem-focused coping underlying lower caregiver burden in ALS-FTD: implications for caregiver intervention. Amyotroph&#xa0;Lateral Scler&#xa0;Front&#xa0;Degener. 2021;22(5-6):434-441.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schischlevskij P, Cordts I, G&#xfc;nther R, et al. Informal caregiving in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS): a high caregiver burden and drastic consequences on caregivers' lives. Brain Sci. 2021;11(6):748.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tramonti F, Bonfiglio L, Bongioanni P, et al. Caregiver burden and family functioning in different neurological diseases. Psychol Health Med. 2019;24(1):27-34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Wit J, Bakker LA, van Groenestijn AC, et al. Caregiver burden in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a systematic review. Palliat Med. 2017;32(1):231-245.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsieh S, Leyton CE, Caga J, et al. The evolution of caregiver burden in frontotemporal dementia with and without amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Alzheimer's Dis. 2016;49(3):875-885.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2; A, Vignola A, Mastro E, et al. Neurobehavioral symptoms in ALS are negatively related to caregivers' burden and quality of life. Eur J Neurol. 2010;17(10):1298-1303.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weisser FB, Bristowe K, Jackson D. Experiences of burden, needs, rewards and resilience in family caregivers of people living with motor neurone disease/amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a secondary thematic analysis of qualitative interviews. Palliat Med. 2015;29(8):737-745.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galvin M, Carney S, Corr B, Mays I, Pender N, Hardiman O. Needs of informal caregivers across the caregiving course in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a qualitative analysis. BMJ Open. 2018;8(1):e018721.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh J, Kim JA. Supportive care needs of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis/motor neuron disease and their caregivers: a scoping review. J Clin Nurs. 2017;26(23-24):4129-4152.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aoun SM, Deas K, Kristjanson LJ, Kissane DW. Identifying and addressing the support needs of family caregivers of people with motor neurone disease using the Carer Support Needs Assessment Tool. Palliat Support&#xa0;Care. 2017;15(1):32-43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Wit J, Schr&#xf6;der CD, El Mecky J, Beelen A, van den Berg LH, Visser-Meily J. Support needs of caregivers of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a qualitative study. Palliat Support Care. 2019;17(2):195-201.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galvin M, Corr B, Madden C, et al. Caregiving in ALS-a mixed methods approach to the study of burden. BMC Palliat Care. 2016;15(1):81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Brien MR, Whitehead B, Jack BA, Mitchell JD. From symptom onset to a diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis/motor neuron disease (ALS/MND): experiences of people with ALS/MND and family carers-a qualitative study. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. 2011;12(2):97-104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Brien MR, Whitehead B, Jack BA, Mitchell JD. The need for support services for family carers of people with motor neurone disease (MND): views of current and former family caregivers a qualitative study. Disabil Rehabil. 2011;34(3):247-256.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diehl-Schmid J, Schmidt EM, Nunnemann S, et al. Caregiver burden and needs in frontotemporal dementia. J Geriatr Psychiatry Neurol. 2013;26(4):221-229.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riedijk S, Duivenvoorden H, Rosso S, Van Swieten J, Niermeijer M, Tibben A. Frontotemporal dementia: change of familial caregiver burden and partner relation in a Dutch cohort of 63 patients. Dementia Geriatr Cognit Disord. 2008;26(5):398-406.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cipolletta S, Gammino GR, Francescon P, Palmieri A. Mutual support groups for family caregivers of people with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in Italy: a pilot study. Health Soc Care Community. 2018;26(4):556-563.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olesen LK, la Cour K, With H, Mahoney AF, Handberg C. A cross-sectional evaluation of acceptability of an online palliative rehabilitation program for family caregivers of people with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and cognitive and behavioral impairments. BMC Health Serv Res. 2022;22(1):697.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N&#xf8;rskov KH, Overgaard D, Lomborg K, Kjeldsen L, Jarden M. Patient ambassador support: experiences of the mentorship between newly diagnosed patients with acute leukaemia and their patient ambassadors. Eur J Cancer Care. 2020;29(6):e13289.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madsen LS, Jeppesen J, and Handberg C. &#x201c;Understanding my ALS&#x201d;. Experiences and reflections of persons with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and relatives on participation in peer group rehabilitation. Disabil Rehabil. 2019;41(12):1410-1418.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lloyd-Evans B, Mayo-Wilson E, Harrison B, et al. A systematic review and meta-analysis of randomised controlled trials of peer support for people with severe mental illness. BMC Psychiatry. 2014;14:39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pfeiffer PN, Heisler M, Piette JD, Rogers MAM, Valenstein M. Efficacy of peer support interventions for depression: a meta-analysis. Gen Hosp Psychiatry. 2011;33(1):29-36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyamoto Y, Sono T. Lessons from peer support among individuals with mental health difficulties: a review of the literature. Clin&#xa0;Pract&#xa0;Epidemiology&#xa0;Men&#xa0;Health. 2012;8:22-29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharbafshaaer M, Buonanno D, Passaniti C, et al. Psychological support for family caregivers of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis at the time of the coronavirus disease 2019 pandemic: a pilot study using a telemedicine approach. Front Psychiatry. 2022;13:904841.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wright KB, Bell SB, Wright KB, Bell SB. Health-related support groups on the Internet: linking empirical findings to social support and computer-mediated communication theory. J Health Psychol. 2003;8(1):39-54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geronimo A, Wright C, Morris A, Walsh S, Snyder B, Simmons Z. Incorporation of telehealth into a multidisciplinary ALS Clinic: feasibility and acceptability. Amyotroph&#xa0;Lateral Scler&#xa0;Front&#xa0;Degener. 2017;18(7-8):555-561.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olesen LK, Cour K, With H, Handberg C. Reflections of family caregivers and health professionals on the everyday challenges of caring for persons with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and cognitive impairments: a qualitative study. Palliat&#xa0;Care&#xa0;Soc&#xa0;Pract. 2022;16:26323524221077702.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skivington K, Matthews L, Simpson SA, et al. A new framework for developing and evaluating complex interventions: update of Medical Research Council guidance. BMJ. 2021;374:n2061.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skivington K, Matthews L, Simpson SA, et al. Framework for the development and evaluation of complex interventions: gap analysis, workshop and consultation-informed update. Health Technol Assess. 2021;25(57):1-132.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonovsky A. Unraveling the Mystery of Health: How People Manage Stress and Stay Well, 1987.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thorne SE. Interpretive Description: Qualitative Research for Applied Practice, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>James S, Desborough J, McInnes S, Halcomb E. Strategies for using non-participatory video research methods in general practice. Nurse Res. 2019;27(2):32-37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thorne S, Thorne SE. Interpretive Description: Developing Qualitative Inquiry. Vol 2. Left Coast Press; 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonovsky A. Health, Stress, and Coping. 1979.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonovsky A. The salutogenic model as a theory to guide health promotion. Health Promot Int. 1996;11(1):11-18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braun-Lewensohn O, Idan O, Lindstr&#xf6;m B, Margalit M. Salutogenesis: Sense of Coherence in Adolescence.&#xa0;In: Mittelmark MB, ed. The Handbook of Salutogenesis. Springer; 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raaphorst J, Beeldman E, Schmand B, et al. The ALS-FTD-Q A new screening tool for behavioral disturbances in ALS. Neurology. 2012;79(13):1377-1383.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hammersley M, Atkinson P. Ethnography: Principles in Practice. 4 ed. Routledge; 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuschieri S. The STROBE guidelines. Saudi J Anaesth. 2019;13(5):31-34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Medical Association. World Medical Association Declaration&#xa0;of&#xa0;Helsinki:&#xa0;ethical principles&#xa0;for&#xa0;medical research involving human subjects. JAMA. 2013;310(20):2191-2194.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scharett E, Madathil KC, Lopes S, et al. An investigation of the information sought by caregivers of Alzheimer's patients on online peer support groups. Cyberpsychol Behav Soc Netw. 2017;20(10):640-657.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bilenchi VA, Banfi P, Pagnini F, Volpato E. Psychoeducational groups for people with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and their caregiver: a qualitative study. Neurol Sci. 2022;43:4239-4255.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Wit J, Vervoort SCJM, van Eerden E, et al. User perspectives on a psychosocial blended support program for partners of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and progressive muscular atrophy: a qualitative study. BMC Psychol. 2019;7(1):35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazanderani F, Locock L,&#xa0;Powell J. Being differently the same: the mediation of identity tensions in the sharing of illness experiences. Soc Sci Med (1982), 2012;74(4):546-553.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suler J. The online disinhibition effect. Cyberpsychol Behav. 2004;7(3):321-326.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Locock L, Brown JB. &#x2018;All in the same boat&#x2019;? Patient and carer attitudes to peer support and social comparison in motor neurone disease (MND). Soc&#xa0;Sci&#xa0;Med. 2010;71(8):1498-1505.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dowrick C, Dunn G, Ayuso-Mateos JL, et al. Problem solving treatment and group psychoeducation for depression: multicentre randomised controlled trial. BMJ. 2000;321(7274):1450.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ng L, Amatya B, Khan F. Outcomes of a peer support program in multiple sclerosis in an Australian community cohort: a prospective study. J Neurodegener Dis. 2013;2013:1-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Danel-Brunaud V, Touzet L, Chevalier L, et al. Ethical considerations and palliative care in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a review. Rev Neurol. 2017;173(5):300-307.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin JL, Lipstein EA, Wittenberg E, et al. Intergenerational decision making: the role of family relationships in medical decision making. MDM Policy Pract. 2021;6(2):238146832110394.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nottelmann L, Groenvold M, Vejlgaard TB, Petersen MA, Jensen LH. Early, integrated palliative rehabilitation improves quality of life of patients with newly diagnosed advanced cancer: the Pal-Rehab randomized controlled trial. Palliat Med. 2021;35(7):1344-1355.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>