<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36739888</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>06</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1468-1331</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>30</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>May</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Not a benign motor neuron disease: longitudinal imaging captures relentless motor connectome disintegration in primary lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1232</StartPage><EndPage>1245</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1232-1245</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/ene.15725</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND PURPOSE">Primary lateral sclerosis (PLS) is a progressive upper motor neuron disorder associated with considerable clinical disability. Symptoms are typically exclusively linked to primary motor cortex degeneration and the contribution of pre-motor, supplementary motor, cortico-medullary and inter-hemispheric connectivity alterations are less well characterized.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">In a single-centre, prospective, longitudinal neuroimaging study 41 patients with PLS were investigated. Patients underwent standardized neuroimaging, genetic profiling with whole exome sequencing, and comprehensive clinical assessments including upper motor neuron scores, tapping rates, mirror movements, spasticity assessment, cognitive screening and evaluation for pseudobulbar affect. Longitudinal neuroimaging data from 108 healthy controls were used for image interpretation. A standardized imaging protocol was implemented including 3D T1-weighted structural, diffusion tensor imaging and resting-state functional magnetic resonance imaging. Following somatotopic segmentation, cortical thickness analyses, probabilistic tractography, blood oxygenation level dependent signal analyses and brainstem volumetry were conducted to evaluate cortical, brainstem, cortico-medullary and inter-hemispheric connectivity alterations both cross-sectionally and longitudinally.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Our data confirm progressive primary motor cortex degeneration, considerable supplementary motor and pre-motor area involvement, progressive brainstem atrophy, cortico-medullary and inter-hemispheric disconnection, and close associations between clinical upper motor neuron scores and somatotopic connectivity indices in PLS.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION">Primary lateral sclerosis is associated with relentlessly progressive motor connectome degeneration. Clinical disability in PLS is likely to stem from a combination of intra- and inter-hemispheric connectivity decline and primary, pre- and supplementary motor cortex degeneration. Simple 'bedside' clinical tools, such as tapping rates, are excellent proxies of the integrity of the relevant fibres of the contralateral corticospinal tract.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Authors. European Journal of Neurology published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of European Academy of Neurology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tahedl</LastName><ForeName>Marlene</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Computational Neuroimaging Group (CNG), Biomedical Sciences Institute, Trinity College Dublin, Dublin, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tan</LastName><ForeName>Ee Ling</ForeName><Initials>EL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Computational Neuroimaging Group (CNG), Biomedical Sciences Institute, Trinity College Dublin, Dublin, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shing</LastName><ForeName>Stacey Li Hi</ForeName><Initials>SLH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Computational Neuroimaging Group (CNG), Biomedical Sciences Institute, Trinity College Dublin, Dublin, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chipika</LastName><ForeName>Rangariroyashe H</ForeName><Initials>RH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Computational Neuroimaging Group (CNG), Biomedical Sciences Institute, Trinity College Dublin, Dublin, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Siah</LastName><ForeName>We Fong</ForeName><Initials>WF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Computational Neuroimaging Group (CNG), Biomedical Sciences Institute, Trinity College Dublin, Dublin, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hengeveld</LastName><ForeName>Jennifer C</ForeName><Initials>JC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Smurfit Institute of Genetics, Trinity College Dublin, Dublin, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Doherty</LastName><ForeName>Mark A</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Smurfit Institute of Genetics, Trinity College Dublin, Dublin, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McLaughlin</LastName><ForeName>Russell L</ForeName><Initials>RL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Smurfit Institute of Genetics, Trinity College Dublin, Dublin, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hardiman</LastName><ForeName>Orla</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Computational Neuroimaging Group (CNG), Biomedical Sciences Institute, Trinity College Dublin, Dublin, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Finegan</LastName><ForeName>Eoin</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Computational Neuroimaging Group (CNG), Biomedical Sciences Institute, Trinity College Dublin, Dublin, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bede</LastName><ForeName>Peter</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0492-4772</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Computational Neuroimaging Group (CNG), Biomedical Sciences Institute, Trinity College Dublin, Dublin, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, St James's Hospital, Dublin, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9506311</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1351-5101</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D056324" MajorTopicYN="N">Diffusion Tensor Imaging</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D063132" MajorTopicYN="Y">Connectome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011446" MajorTopicYN="N">Prospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008279" MajorTopicYN="N">Magnetic Resonance Imaging</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016472" MajorTopicYN="Y">Motor Neuron Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">biomarkers</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">clinical trials</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">connectivity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">motor neuron disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neuroimaging</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">primary lateral sclerosis</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36739888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ene.15725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Mitsumoto H, Nagy PL, Gennings C, et al. Phenotypic and molecular analyses of primary lateral sclerosis. Neurol Genet. 2015;1:e3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brugman F, Veldink JH, Franssen H, et al. Differentiation of hereditary spastic paraparesis from primary lateral sclerosis in sporadic adult-onset upper motor neuron syndromes. Arch Neurol. 2009;66:509-514.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agosta F, Galantucci S, Riva N, et al. Intrahemispheric and interhemispheric structural network abnormalities in PLS and ALS. Hum Brain Mapp. 2014;35:1710-1722.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finegan E, Li Hi Shing S, Chipika RH, et al. Widespread subcortical grey matter degeneration in primary lateral sclerosis: a multimodal imaging study with genetic profiling. Neuroimage Clin. 2019;24:102089.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark MG, Smallwood Shoukry R, Huang CJ, Danielian LE, Bageac D, Floeter MK. Loss of functional connectivity is an early imaging marker in primary lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2018;19:562-569.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chipika RH, Christidi F, Finegan E, et al. Amygdala pathology in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and primary lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Sci. 2020;417:117039.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner MR, Hammers A, Al-Chalabi A, et al. Cortical involvement in four cases of primary lateral sclerosis using [(11)C]-flumazenil PET. J Neurol. 2007;254:1033-1036.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agosta F, Canu E, Inuggi A, et al. Resting state functional connectivity alterations in primary lateral sclerosis. Neurobiol Aging. 2014;35:916-925.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pioro EP, Turner MR, Bede P. Neuroimaging in primary lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2020;21:18-27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tu S, Menke RAL, Talbot K, Kiernan MC, Turner MR. Cerebellar tract alterations in PLS and ALS. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2019;20:281-284.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iwata NK, Kwan JY, Danielian LE, et al. White matter alterations differ in primary lateral sclerosis and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain. 2011;134:2642-2655.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muller HP, Agosta F, Gorges M, et al. Cortico-efferent tract involvement in primary lateral sclerosis and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a two-centre tract of interest-based DTI analysis. Neuroimage Clin. 2018;20:1062-1069.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bede P, Murad A, Lope J, et al. Phenotypic categorisation of individual subjects with motor neuron disease based on radiological disease burden patterns: a machine-learning approach. J Neurol Sci. 2021;432:120079.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller HP, Gorges M, Kassubek R, Dorst J, Ludolph AC, Kassubek J. Identical patterns of cortico-efferent tract involvement in primary lateral sclerosis and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a tract of interest-based MRI study. Neuroimage Clin. 2018;18:762-769.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verstraete E, Turner MR, Grosskreutz J, Filippi M, Benatar M. Mind the gap: the mismatch between clinical and imaging metrics in ALS. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2015;16:524-529.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pradat PF, Bernard E, Corcia P, et al. The French national protocol for Kennedy's disease (SBMA): consensus diagnostic and management recommendations. Orphanet J Rare Dis. 2020;15:90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackenzie IRA, Briemberg H. TDP-43 pathology in primary lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2020;21(sup1):52-58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitsumoto H, Chiuzan C, Gilmore M, et al. Primary lateral sclerosis (PLS) functional rating scale: PLS-specific clinimetric scale. Muscle Nerve. 2020;61:163-172.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bede P, Pradat PF, Lope J, Vourc'h P, Blasco H, Corcia P. Primary lateral sclerosis: clinical, radiological and molecular features. Rev Neurol (Paris). 2021;178:196-205.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner MR, Barohn RJ, Corcia P, et al. Primary lateral sclerosis: consensus diagnostic criteria. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2020;91:373-377.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinto-Grau M, Burke T, Lonergan K, et al. Screening for cognitive dysfunction in ALS: validation of the Edinburgh Cognitive and Behavioural ALS Screen (ECAS) using age and education adjusted normative data. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2017;18:99-106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newsom-Davis IC, Abrahams S, Goldstein LH, Leigh PN. The emotional lability questionnaire: a new measure of emotional lability in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Sci. 1999;169:22-25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abel O, Shatunov A, Jones AR, Andersen PM, Powell JF, Al-Chalabi A. Development of a smartphone app for a genetics website: the amyotrophic lateral sclerosis online genetics database (ALSoD). JMIR Mhealth Uhealth. 2013;1:e18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klebe S, Stevanin G, Depienne C. Clinical and genetic heterogeneity in hereditary spastic paraplegias: from SPG1 to SPG72 and still counting. Rev Neurol (Paris). 2015;171:505-530.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byrne S, Elamin M, Bede P, et al. Cognitive and clinical characteristics of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis carrying a C9orf72 repeat expansion: a population-based cohort study. Lancet Neurol. 2012;11:232-240.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bede P, Chipika RH, Christidi F, et al. Genotype-associated cerebellar profiles in ALS: focal cerebellar pathology and cerebro-cerebellar connectivity alterations. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2021;92:1197-1205.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayka MA, Corcos DM, Leurgans SE, Vaillancourt DE. Three-dimensional locations and boundaries of motor and premotor cortices as defined by functional brain imaging: a meta-analysis. Neuroimage. 2006;31:1453-1474.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan L, Li H, Zhuo J, et al. The human Brainnetome atlas: a new brain atlas based on connectional architecture. Cereb Cortex. 2016;26:3508-3526.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iglesias JE, Van Leemput K, Bhatt P, et al. Bayesian segmentation of brainstem structures in MRI. Neuroimage. 2015;113:184-195.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marcus DS, Harwell J, Olsen T, et al. Informatics and data mining tools and strategies for the human connectome project. Front Neuroinform. 2011;5:4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pruim RHR, Mennes M, van Rooij D, Llera A, Buitelaar JK, Beckmann CF. ICA-AROMA: a robust ICA-based strategy for removing motion artifacts from fMRI data. Neuroimage. 2015;112:267-277.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oosterhof NN, Connolly AC, Haxby JV. CoSMoMVPA: multi-modal multivariate pattern analysis of neuroimaging data in Matlab/GNU octave. Front Neuroinform. 2016;10:27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oostenveld R, Fries P, Maris E, Schoffelen JM. FieldTrip: open source software for advanced analysis of MEG, EEG, and invasive electrophysiological data. Comput Intell Neurosci. 2011;2011:1-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veraart J, Fieremans E, Novikov DS. Diffusion MRI noise mapping using random matrix theory. Magn Reson Med. 2016;76:1582-1593.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kellner E, Dhital B, Kiselev VG, Reisert M. Gibbs-ringing artifact removal based on local subvoxel-shifts. Magn Reson Med. 2016;76:1574-1581.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith SM, Jenkinson M, Woolrich MW, et al. Advances in functional and structural MR image analysis and implementation as FSL. Neuroimage. 2004;23(Suppl 1):S208-S219.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tustison NJ, Avants BB, Cook PA, et al. N4ITK: improved N3 bias correction. IEEE Trans Med Imaging. 2010;29:1310-1320.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tournier JD, Calamante F, Connelly A. Improved probabilistic streamlines tractography by 2nd order integration over fibre orientation distributions. Proceedings of the International Society for Magnetic Resonance in Medicine (ISMRM). 2010;18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tahedl M, Murad A, Lope J, Hardiman O, Bede P. Evaluation and categorisation of individual patients based on white matter profiles: single-patient diffusion data interpretation in neurodegeneration. J Neurol Sci. 2021;428:117584.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feron M, Couillandre A, Mseddi E, et al. Extrapyramidal deficits in ALS: a combined biomechanical and neuroimaging study. J Neurol. 2018;265:2125-2136.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finegan E, Hi Shing SL, Chipika RH, et al. Thalamic, hippocampal and basal ganglia pathology in primary lateral sclerosis and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: evidence from quantitative imaging data. Data Brief. 2020;29:105115.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abidi M, de Marco G, Grami F, et al. Neural correlates of motor imagery of gait in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Magn Reson Imaging. 2021;53:223-233.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abidi M, de Marco G, Couillandre A, et al. Adaptive functional reorganization in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: coexisting degenerative and compensatory changes. Eur J Neurol. 2020;27:121-128.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitsumoto H, Ulug AM, Pullman SL, et al. Quantitative objective markers for upper and lower motor neuron dysfunction in ALS. Neurology. 2007;68:1402-1410.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proudfoot M, Bede P, Turner MR. Imaging cerebral activity in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Front Neurol. 2018;9:1148.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christidi F, Karavasilis E, Argyropoulos GD, et al. Neurometabolic alterations in motor neuron disease: insights from magnetic resonance spectroscopy. J Integr Neurosci. 2022;21:87.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bede P, Murad A, Hardiman O. Pathological neural networks and artificial neural networks in ALS: diagnostic classification based on pathognomonic neuroimaging features. J Neurol. 2021;269(5):2440-2452.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bede P, Iyer PM, Finegan E, Omer T, Hardiman O. Virtual brain biopsies in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: diagnostic classification based on in vivo pathological patterns. Neuroimage Clin. 2017;15:653-658.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finegan E, Li Hi Shing S, Siah WF, et al. Evolving diagnostic criteria in primary lateral sclerosis: the clinical and radiological basis of &#x2018;probable PLS&#x2019;. J Neurol Sci. 2020;417:117052.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finegan E, Siah WF, Shing SLH, et al. Imaging and clinical data indicate considerable disease burden in &#x2018;probable&#x2019; PLS: patients with UMN symptoms for 2-4&#x2009;years. Data Brief. 2020;32:106247.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>