<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36747323</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>21</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-4598</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>67</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Muscle &amp; nerve</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Muscle Nerve</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Utilizing machine learning and lipidomics to distinguish primary lateral sclerosis from amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>306</StartPage><EndPage>310</EndPage><MedlinePgn>306-310</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/mus.27797</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION/AIMS">There are currently no imaging or blood diagnostic biomarkers that can differentiate amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) from primary lateral sclerosis (PLS) patients early in their disease courses. Our objective is to examine whether patients with PLS can be differentiated from ALS reliably by using plasma lipidome profile and supervised machine learning.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">40 ALS and 28 PLS patients derived from the Multicenter Cohort study of Oxidative Stress (COSMOS) and 28 healthy control volunteers (CTR) were included. ALS, PLS, and CTR were matched by age and sex. Plasma samples were obtained after overnight fasting. Lipids were extracted from the plasma samples and analyzed using liquid chromatography/mass spectrometry to obtain relative concentrations of 392 lipid species. The lipid data were partitioned into training and testing datasets randomly. An elastic net algorithm was trained using cross-validation to classify PLS vs ALS and PLS vs CTR. Final accuracy was evaluated in the testing dataset.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">The elastic net model trained with labeled PLS and ALS training lipid dataset demonstrated accuracy (number classified correctly/total number), sensitivity, and specificity of 100% in classifying PLS vs ALS in the unlabeled testing lipid dataset. Similarly, the elastic net model trained with labeled PLS and CTR training lipid datasets demonstrated accuracy, sensitivity, and specificity of 88% in classifying PLS vs CTR in the unlabeled testing lipid dataset.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION">Our study suggests PLS patients can be accurately distinguished from ALS and CTR by combining lipidome profile and supervised machine learning without clinical information.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Ikjae</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0537-9622</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Columbia University, New York, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stingone</LastName><ForeName>Jeanette A</ForeName><Initials>JA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Epidemiology, Mailman School of Public Health, Columbia University, New York, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chan</LastName><ForeName>Robin Barry</ForeName><Initials>RB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathology and Cell Biology, Columbia University, New York, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mitsumoto</LastName><ForeName>Hiroshi</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Columbia University, New York, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016448">Multicenter Study</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Muscle Nerve</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7803146</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0148-639X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D008055">Lipids</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000081362" MajorTopicYN="N">Lipidomics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015331" MajorTopicYN="N">Cohort Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000069550" MajorTopicYN="N">Machine Learning</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008055" MajorTopicYN="N">Lipids</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016472" MajorTopicYN="Y">Motor Neuron Disease</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Machine Learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Primary Lateral Sclerosis</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36747323</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.27797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Statland JM, Barohn RJ, Dimachkie MM, Floeter MK, Mitsumoto H. Primary lateral sclerosis. Neurol Clin. 2015;33(4):749-760.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner MR, Barohn RJ, Corcia P, et al. Primary lateral sclerosis: consensus diagnostic criteria. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2020;91(4):373-377.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goutman SA, Boss J, Guo K, et al. Untargeted metabolomics yields insight into ALS disease mechanisms. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2020;91(12):1329-1338.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blasco H, Veyrat-Durebex C, Bocca C, et al. Lipidomics reveals cerebrospinal-fluid signatures of ALS. Sci Rep. 2017;7(1):17652.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>FernAndez-Eulate G, Ruiz-Sanz JI, Riancho J, et al. A comprehensive serum lipidome profiling of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2020;21(3-4):252-262.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Area-Gomez E, Larrea D, Yun T, et al. Lipidomics study of plasma from patients suggest that ALS and PLS are part of a continuum of motor neuron disorders. Sci Rep. 2021;11(1):13562.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitsumoto H, Factor-Litvak P, Andrews H, et al. ALS multicenter cohort study of oxidative stress (ALS COSMOS): study methodology, recruitment, and baseline demographic and disease characteristics. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2014;15(3-4):192-203.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitsumoto H, Nagy PL, Gennings C, et al. Phenotypic and molecular analyses of primary lateral sclerosis. Neurol Genet. 2015;1(1):e3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, Miller RG, Swash M, Munsat TL. World Federation of Neurology Research Group on motor neuron D. El Escorial revisited: revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord. 2000;1(5):293-299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon PH, Cheng B, Katz IB, et al. The natural history of primary lateral sclerosis. Neurology. 2006;66(5):647-653.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan RB, Perotte AJ, Zhou B, et al. Elevated GM3 plasma concentration in idiopathic Parkinson's disease: a lipidomic analysis. PLoS One. 2017;12(2):e0172348.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hui Zou TH. Regularization and variable selection via the elastic net. J R Statist Soc B. 2005;67:301-320.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanchez AJ, Garcia-Merino A. Neuroprotective agents: cannabinoids. Clin Immunol. 2012;142(1):57-67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi Y, Cheng D. Beyond triglyceride synthesis: the dynamic functional roles of MGAT and DGAT enzymes in energy metabolism. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2009;297(1):E10-E18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marcus J, Honigbaum S, Shroff S, Honke K, Rosenbluth J, Dupree JL. Sulfatide is essential for the maintenance of CNS myelin and axon structure. Glia. 2006;53(4):372-381.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>