<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36872491</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>08</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1468-1331</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>30</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Respiratory phenotypes in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis as determined by respiratory questions on the Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Functional Rating Scale-Revised and their relation to respiratory tests.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1594</StartPage><EndPage>1599</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1594-1599</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/ene.15765</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND PURPOSE">Respiratory insufficiency and its complications are the main cause of death in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). Respiratory symptoms are scored in questions Q10 (dyspnoea) and Q11 (orthopnoea) of the Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Functional Rating Scale-Revised (ALSFRS-R). The association of respiratory test alterations with respiratory symptoms is unclear.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Patients with ALS and progressive muscular atrophy were included. We retrospectively recorded demographic data, ALSFRS-R, forced vital capacity (FVC), maximal inspiratory (MIP) and expiratory (MEP) pressures, mouth occlusion pressure at 100&#x2009;ms, nocturnal oximetry (SpO<sub>2</sub> mean), arterial blood gases, and phrenic nerve amplitude (PhrenAmpl). Three groups were categorized: G1, normal Q10 and Q11; G2, abnormal Q10; and G3, abnormal Q10 and Q11 or only abnormal Q11. A binary logistic regression model explored independent predictors.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">We included 276 patients (153 men, onset age&#xa0;=&#xa0;62.6&#xa0;&#xb1;&#x2009;11.0&#x2009;years, disease duration&#xa0;=&#xa0;13.0&#xa0;&#xb1;&#x2009;9.6&#x2009;months, spinal onset in 182) with mean survival of 40.1&#xa0;&#xb1;&#x2009;26.0&#x2009;months. Gender, onset region, and disease duration were similar in G1 (n&#xa0;=&#x2009;149), G2 (n&#xa0;=&#x2009;78), and G3 (n&#xa0;=&#x2009;49). Time to noninvasive ventilation (NIV) was shorter in G3 (p&#xa0;&lt;&#x2009;0.001), but survival was similar. ALSFRS-R subscores were significantly different (G1&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;G2&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;G3, p&#xa0;&lt;&#x2009;0.001), except for lower limb subscore (p&#xa0;=&#x2009;0.077). G2 and G3 patients were older than G1 (p&#xa0;&lt;&#x2009;0.001), and had lower FVC, MIP, MEP, PhrenAmpl, and SpO<sub>2</sub> mean. Independent predictors for G2 were MIP and SpO<sub>2</sub> mean; for G3, the only independent predictor was PhrenAmpl.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">These three distinct ALS phenotypic respiratory categories represent progressive stages of ventilatory dysfunction, supporting ALSFRS-R clinical relevance. Orthopnoea is a severe symptom that should prompt NIV, phrenic nerve response being an independent predictor. Early NIV promotes similar survival for G2 and G3.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Authors. European Journal of Neurology published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of European Academy of Neurology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pinto</LastName><ForeName>Susana</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0727-5897</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Physiology, Instituto de Medicina Molecular Jo&#xe3;o Lobo Antunes, Centro de Estudos Egas Moniz, Faculdade de Medicina, Universidade de Lisboa, Lisbon, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rehabiliteringsmedicin, Instituten f&#xf6;r Medicinska Vetenskaper, Uppsala Universitet-Akademiska Sjukhuset, Uppsala, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oliveira Santos</LastName><ForeName>Miguel</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8290-0410</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Physiology, Instituto de Medicina Molecular Jo&#xe3;o Lobo Antunes, Centro de Estudos Egas Moniz, Faculdade de Medicina, Universidade de Lisboa, Lisbon, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosciences and Mental Health, Hospital de Santa Maria, Centro Hospitalar Universit&#xe1;rio de Lisboa-Norte, Lisbon, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gromicho</LastName><ForeName>Marta</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2111-4579</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Physiology, Instituto de Medicina Molecular Jo&#xe3;o Lobo Antunes, Centro de Estudos Egas Moniz, Faculdade de Medicina, Universidade de Lisboa, Lisbon, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Swash</LastName><ForeName>Michael</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Physiology, Instituto de Medicina Molecular Jo&#xe3;o Lobo Antunes, Centro de Estudos Egas Moniz, Faculdade de Medicina, Universidade de Lisboa, Lisbon, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departments of Neurology and Neuroscience, Barts and London School of Medicine, Queen Mary University of London, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>de Carvalho</LastName><ForeName>Mamede</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7556-0158</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Physiology, Instituto de Medicina Molecular Jo&#xe3;o Lobo Antunes, Centro de Estudos Egas Moniz, Faculdade de Medicina, Universidade de Lisboa, Lisbon, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosciences and Mental Health, Hospital de Santa Maria, Centro Hospitalar Universit&#xe1;rio de Lisboa-Norte, Lisbon, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9506311</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1351-5101</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012129" MajorTopicYN="N">Respiratory Function Tests</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012131" MajorTopicYN="Y">Respiratory Insufficiency</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004417" MajorTopicYN="N">Dyspnea</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nocturnal pulsed oximetry</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">phrenic nerve</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">respiratory function</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">respiratory tests</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36872491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ene.15765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Pinto S, de Carvalho M. The R of ALSFRS-R: does it really mirror functional respiratory involvement in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis? Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2015;16:120-123.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinto S, de Carvalho M. Comparison of slow and forced vital capacities on ability to predict survival in ALS. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2017;18:528-533.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinto S, de Carvalho M. SVC is a marker of respiratory decline function, similar to FVC, in patients with ALS. Front Neurol. 2019;10:109.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calvo A, Vasta R, Moglia C, et al. Prognostic role of slow vital capacity in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol. 2020;267:1615-1621.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Carvalho M, Swash M, Pinto S. Diaphragmatic neurophysiology and respiratory markers in ALS. Front Neurol. 2019;10:143.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su&#xe1;rez AA, Pessolano FA, Monteiro SG, et al. Peak flow and peak cough flow in the evaluation of expiratory muscle weakness and bulbar impairment in patients with neuromuscular disease. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2002;81(7):506-511.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinto S, Swash M, de Carvalho M. Mouth occlusion pressure at 100ms (P0.1) as a respiratory biomarker in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2021;22:53-60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinto A, de Carvalho M, Evangelista T, Lopes A, Sales-Lu&#xed;s L. Nocturnal pulse oximetry: a new approach to establish the appropriate time for non-invasive ventilation in ALS patients. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord. 2003;4:31-35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bote SM, Martinez NP, Amarilla CE, et al. Overnight pulse oximetry to determine prognostic factors in subjects with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Respir Care. 2020;65:1128-1134.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Carvalho M, Costa J, Pinto S, Pinto A. Percutaneous nocturnal oximetry in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: periodic desaturation. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2009;10:154-161.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boentert M, Glatz C, Helmle C, Okegwo A, Young P. Prevalence of sleep apnoea and capnographic detection of nocturnal hypoventilation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2018;89:418-424.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manera U, Torrieri MC, Moglia C, et al. Arterial blood gas analysis: base excess and carbonate are predictive of noninvasive ventilation adaptation and survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2021;22(sup1):33-39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinto S, Pinto A, de Carvalho M. Phrenic nerve studies predict survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Neurophysiol. 2012;123:2454-2459.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shefner JM, al-Chalabi A, Baker MR, et al. A proposal for new diagnostic criteria for ALS. Clin Neurophysiol. 2020;131:1975-1978.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller MR, Hankinson J, Brusasco V, et al. Standardisation of spirometry. Eur Respir J. 2005;26:319-338.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quanjer PH, Tammeling GJ, Cotes JE, OF P, Peslin R, Yernault JC. Lung volumes and forced ventilatory flows. Report working party standardization of lung function tests. European Community for steel and coal. Official statement of the European Respiratory Society. Eur Respir J. 1993;6:5-40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laveneziana P, Albuquerque A, Aliverti A, et al. ERS statement on respiratory muscle testing at rest and during exercise. Eur Respir J. 2019;53:1801214.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verma AK, Roach P. The interpretation of arterial blood gases. www.nps.org.au/assets/AP/pdf/The-interpretation-of-arterial-blood-gases.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen PM, Abrahams S, Borasio GD, et al. EFNS guidelines on the clinical management of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (MALS)-revised report of an EFNS task force. Eur J Neurol. 2012;19:360-375.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bourke SC, Tomlinson M, Williams TL, Bullock RE, Shaw PJ, Gibson GJ. Effects of non-invasive ventilation on survival and quality of life in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a randomised controlled trial. Lancet Neurol. 2006;5:140-147.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pirola A, de Mattia E, Lizio A, et al. The prognostic value of spirometric tests in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. Clin Neurol Neurosurg. 2019;184:105456.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young C, Pinto S, Grosskreutz J, et al. Medical therapies for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-related respiratory decline: an appraisal of needs, opportunities and obstacles. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2022;23(1-2):66-75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helleman J, van Reenen ETK, Bakers J, et al. Using patient-reported symptoms of dyspnea for screening reduced respiratory function in patients with motor neuron diseases. J Neurol. 2020;267:3310-3318.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>