<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36951214</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>26</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2990</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>49</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Neuropathology and applied neurobiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Neuropathol Appl Neurobiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>TDP-43 pathology and functional deficits in wild-type and ALS/FTD mutant cyclin F mouse models.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e12902</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e12902</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/nan.12902</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="AIMS">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) is characterised by a progressive loss of upper and lower motor neurons leading to muscle weakness and eventually death. Frontotemporal dementia (FTD) presents clinically with significant behavioural decline. Approximately 10% of cases have a known family history, and disease-linked mutations in multiple genes have been identified in FTD and ALS. More recently, ALS and FTD-linked variants have been identified in the CCNF gene, which accounts for an estimated 0.6% to over 3% of familial ALS cases.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">In this study, we developed the first mouse models expressing either wild-type (WT) human CCNF or its mutant pathogenic variant S621G to recapitulate key clinical and neuropathological features of ALS and FTD linked to CCNF disease variants. We expressed human CCNF WT or CCNF<sup>S621G</sup> throughout the murine brain by intracranial delivery of adeno-associated virus (AAV) to achieve widespread delivery via somatic brain transgenesis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">These mice developed behavioural abnormalities, similar to the clinical symptoms of FTD patients, as early as 3&#xa0;months of age, including hyperactivity and disinhibition, which progressively deteriorated to include memory deficits by 8&#xa0;months of age. Brains of mutant CCNF_S621G mice displayed an accumulation of ubiquitinated proteins with elevated levels of phosphorylated TDP-43 present in both CCNF_WT and mutant CCNF_S621G mice. We also investigated the effects of CCNF expression on interaction targets of CCNF and found elevated levels of insoluble splicing factor proline and glutamine-rich (SFPQ). Furthermore, cytoplasmic TDP-43 inclusions were found in both CCNF_WT and mutant CCNF_S621G mice, recapitulating the key hallmark of FTD/ALS pathology.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">In summary, CCNF expression in mice reproduces clinical presentations of ALS, including functional deficits and TDP-43 neuropathology with altered CCNF-mediated pathways contributing to the pathology observed.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Authors. Neuropathology and Applied Neurobiology published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of British Neuropathological Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>van Hummel</LastName><ForeName>Annika</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dementia Research Centre, Macquarie Medical School, Faculty of Medicine, Health and Human Sciences, Macquarie University, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sabale</LastName><ForeName>Miheer</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dementia Research Centre, Macquarie Medical School, Faculty of Medicine, Health and Human Sciences, Macquarie University, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Przybyla</LastName><ForeName>Magdalena</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dementia Research Centre, Macquarie Medical School, Faculty of Medicine, Health and Human Sciences, Macquarie University, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>van der Hoven</LastName><ForeName>Julia</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dementia Research Centre, Macquarie Medical School, Faculty of Medicine, Health and Human Sciences, Macquarie University, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chan</LastName><ForeName>Gabriella</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dementia Research Centre, Macquarie Medical School, Faculty of Medicine, Health and Human Sciences, Macquarie University, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Feiten</LastName><ForeName>Astrid F</ForeName><Initials>AF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biomedical Center (BMC), Division of Metabolic Biochemistry, Faculty of Medicine, Ludwig-Maximilians-Universit&#xe4;t M&#xfc;nchen, Munich, 81377, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chung</LastName><ForeName>Roger S</ForeName><Initials>RS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Motor Neuron Disease Research, Macquarie Medical School, Faculty of Medicine, Health and Human Sciences, Macquarie University, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ittner</LastName><ForeName>Lars M</ForeName><Initials>LM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dementia Research Centre, Macquarie Medical School, Faculty of Medicine, Health and Human Sciences, Macquarie University, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ke</LastName><ForeName>Yazi D</ForeName><Initials>YD</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1423-0451</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dementia Research Centre, Macquarie Medical School, Faculty of Medicine, Health and Human Sciences, Macquarie University, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Neuropathol Appl Neurobiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7609829</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0305-1846</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D004268">DNA-Binding Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D016213">Cyclins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C578077">TDP-43 protein, mouse</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051379" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007223" MajorTopicYN="N">Infant</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Frontotemporal Dementia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009046" MajorTopicYN="N">Motor Neurons</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009154" MajorTopicYN="N">Mutation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004268" MajorTopicYN="N">DNA-Binding Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016213" MajorTopicYN="N">Cyclins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">TDP-43</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cyclin F</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">frontotemporal dementia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mouse models</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ubiquitination</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36951214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/nan.12902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Tan RH, Ke YD, Ittner LM, Halliday GM. ALS/FTLD: experimental models and reality. Acta Neuropathol. 2017;133(2):177-196. doi:10.1007/s00401-016-1666-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosen DR, Siddique T, Patterson D, et al. Mutations in cu/Zn superoxide dismutase gene are associated with familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nature. 1993;362(6415):59-62. doi:10.1038/362059a0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sreedharan J, Blair IP, Tripathi VB, et al. TDP-43 mutations in familial and sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Science. 2008;319(5870):1668-1672. doi:10.1126/science.1154584</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vance C, Rogelj B, Hortobagyi T, et al. Mutations in FUS, an RNA processing protein, cause familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis type 6. Science. 2009;323(5918):1208-1211. doi:10.1126/science.1165942</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng H-X, Chen W, Hong S-T, et al. Mutations in UBQLN2 cause dominant X-linked juvenile and adult-onset ALS and ALS/dementia. Nature. 2011;477(7363):211-215. doi:10.1038/nature10353</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu CH, Fallini C, Ticozzi N, et al. Mutations in the profilin 1 gene cause familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nature. 2012;488(7412):499-503. doi:10.1038/nature11280</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maruyama H, Morino H, Ito H, et al. Mutations of optineurin in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nature. 2010;465(7295):223-226. doi:10.1038/nature08971</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeJesus-Hernandez M, Mackenzie IR, Boeve BF, et al. Expanded GGGGCC hexanucleotide repeat in noncoding region of C9ORF72 causes chromosome 9p-linked FTD and ALS. Neuron. 2011;72(2):245-256. doi:10.1016/j.neuron.2011.09.011</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson JO, Mandrioli J, Benatar M, et al. Exome sequencing reveals VCP mutations as a cause of familial ALS. Neuron. 2010;68(5):857-864. doi:10.1016/j.neuron.2010.11.036</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson JO, Pioro EP, Boehringer A, et al. Italsgen: mutations in the Matrin 3 gene cause familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat Neurosci. 2014;17(5):664-666. doi:10.1038/nn.3688</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith BN, Ticozzi N, Fallini C, et al. Exome-wide rare variant analysis identifies TUBA4A mutations associated with familial ALS. Neuron. 2014;84(2):324-331. doi:10.1016/j.neuron.2014.09.027</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsai PC, Liao YC, Chen PL, et al. Investigating CCNF mutations in a Taiwanese cohort with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurobiol Aging. 2018;62:243.e1-243.e6. doi:10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2017.09.031</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan C, Jiao B, Xiao T, et al. Mutations of CCNF gene is rare in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal dementia from mainland China. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2017;18(3-4):265-268. doi:10.1080/21678421.2017.1293111</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams KL, Topp S, Yang S, et al. CCNF mutations in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal dementia. Nat Commun. 2016;7(1):11253. doi:10.1038/ncomms11253</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galper J, Rayner SL, Hogan AL, et al. Cyclin F: a component of an E3 ubiquitin ligase complex with roles in neurodegeneration and cancer. Int J Biochem Cell Biol. 2017;89:216-220. doi:10.1016/j.biocel.2017.06.011</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee A, Rayner SL, de Luca A, et al. Casein kinase II phosphorylation of cyclin F at serine 621 regulates the Lys48-ubiquitylation E3 ligase activity of the SCF((cyclin F)) complex. Open Biol. 2017;7(10):170058. doi:10.1098/rsob.170058</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hogan AL, Don EK, Rayner SL, et al. Expression of ALS/FTD-linked mutant CCNF in zebrafish leads to increased cell death in the spinal cord and an aberrant motor phenotype. Hum Mol Genet. 2017;26(14):2616-2626. doi:10.1093/hmg/ddx136</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee A, Rayner SL, Gwee SSL, et al. Pathogenic mutation in the ALS/FTD gene, CCNF, causes elevated Lys48-linked ubiquitylation and defective autophagy. Cell Mol Life Sci. 2018;75(2):335-354. doi:10.1007/s00018-017-2632-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ittner A, Chua SW, Bertz J, et al. Site-specific phosphorylation of tau inhibits amyloid-beta toxicity in Alzheimer's mice. Science. 2016;354(6314):904-908. doi:10.1126/science.aah6205</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bi M, Gladbach A, van Eersel J, et al. Tau exacerbates excitotoxic brain damage in an animal model of stroke. Nat Commun. 2017;8(1):473. doi:10.1038/s41467-017-00618-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cho AN, Bright F, Morey N, Au C, Ittner LM, Ke YD. Efficient gene expression in human stem cell derived-cortical organoids using adeno associated virus. Cell. 2022;11(20):3194. doi:10.3390/cells11203194</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan G, van Hummel A, van der Hoven J, Ittner LM, Ke YD. Neurodegeneration and motor deficits in the absence of astrogliosis upon transgenic mutant TDP-43 expression in mature mice. Am J Pathol. 2020;190(8):1713-1722. doi:10.1016/j.ajpath.2020.04.009</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Hummel A, Chan G, van der Hoven J, et al. Selective spatiotemporal vulnerability of central nervous system neurons to pathologic TAR DNA-binding protein 43 in aged transgenic mice. Am J Pathol. 2018;188(6):1447-1456. doi:10.1016/j.ajpath.2018.03.002</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ke YD, Delerue F, Gladbach A, Gotz J, Ittner LM. Experimental diabetes mellitus exacerbates tau pathology in a transgenic mouse model of Alzheimer's disease. PLoS ONE. 2009;4(11):e7917. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0007917</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Przybyla M, van Eersel J, van Hummel A, et al. Onset of hippocampal network aberration and memory deficits in P301S tau mice are associated with an early gene signature. Brain. 2020;143(6):1889-1904. doi:10.1093/brain/awaa133</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ke YD, van Hummel A, Stevens CH, et al. Short-term suppression of A315T mutant human TDP-43 expression improves functional deficits in a novel inducible transgenic mouse model of FTLD-TDP and ALS. Acta Neuropathol. 2015;130(5):661-678. doi:10.1007/s00401-015-1486-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ittner LM, Ke YD, Gotz J. Phosphorylated tau interacts with c-Jun N-terminal kinase-interacting protein 1 (JIP1) in Alzheimer disease. J Biol Chem. 2009;284(31):20909-20916. doi:10.1074/jbc.M109.014472</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebstein SY, Yagudayeva I, Shneider NA. Mutant TDP-43 causes early-stage dose-dependent motor neuron degeneration in a TARDBP Knockin mouse model of ALS. Cell Rep. 2019;26(2):364-373. doi:10.1016/j.celrep.2018.12.045</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haidet-Phillips AM, Hester ME, Miranda CJ, et al. Astrocytes from familial and sporadic ALS patients are toxic to motor neurons. Nat Biotechnol. 2011;29(9):824-828. doi:10.1038/nbt.1957</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neumann M, Sampathu DM, Kwong LK, et al. Ubiquitinated TDP-43 in frontotemporal lobar degeneration and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Science. 2006;314(5796):130-133. doi:10.1126/science.1134108</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neumann M, Kwong LK, Lee EB, et al. Phosphorylation of S409/410 of TDP-43 is a consistent feature in all sporadic and familial forms of TDP-43 proteinopathies. Acta Neuropathol. 2009;117(2):137-149. doi:10.1007/s00401-008-0477-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rayner SL, Cheng F, Hogan AL, et al. ALS/FTD-causing mutation in cyclin F causes the dysregulation of SFPQ. Hum Mol Genet. 2021;30(11):971-984. doi:10.1093/hmg/ddab073</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manno ANMFJMYKA, Noguchi M, Fukushi J, Motohashi Y, Kakizuka A. Enhanced ATPase activities as a primary defect of mutant valosin-containing proteins that cause inclusion body myopathy associated with Paget disease of bone and frontotemporal dementia. Genes Cells. 2010;15(8):911-922. doi:10.1111/j.1365-2443.2010.01428.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu Y, Nakagawa T, Morohoshi A, et al. Pathogenic mutations in the ALS gene CCNF cause cytoplasmic mislocalization of cyclin F and elevated VCP ATPase activity. Hum Mol Genet. 2019;28(20):3486-3497. doi:10.1093/hmg/ddz119</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swarup V, Phaneuf D, Bareil C, et al. Pathological hallmarks of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis/frontotemporal lobar degeneration in transgenic mice produced with TDP-43 genomic fragments. Brain. 2011;134(9):2610-2626. doi:10.1093/brain/awr159</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnold ES, Ling SC, Huelga SC, et al. ALS-linked TDP-43 mutations produce aberrant RNA splicing and adult-onset motor neuron disease without aggregation or loss of nuclear TDP-43. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2013;110(8):E736-E745. doi:10.1073/pnas.1222809110</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fratta P, Sivakumar P, Humphrey J, et al. Mice with endogenous TDP-43 mutations exhibit gain of splicing function and characteristics of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. EMBO j. 2018;37(11):37. doi:10.15252/embj.201798684</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hogan AL, Grima N, Fifita JA, et al. SFPQ intron retention, reduced expression and aggregate formation in central nervous system tissue are pathological features of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. 2020 bioRxiv:2020.09.22.309062.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seyfried NT, Gozal YM, Donovan LE, et al. Quantitative analysis of the detergent-insoluble brain proteome in frontotemporal lobar degeneration using SILAC internal standards. J Proteome Res. 2012;11(5):2721-2738. doi:10.1021/pr2010814</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rayner SL, Yang S, Farrawell NE, et al. TDP-43 is a ubiquitylation substrate of the SCF (cyclin F) complex. Neurobiol Dis. 2022;167:105673. doi:10.1016/j.nbd.2022.105673</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>