<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36960740</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>21</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-4598</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>68</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Muscle &amp; nerve</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Muscle Nerve</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Assessment of motor unit firing by high-density surface electromyography detects motor neuronal hyperexcitable state in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>149</StartPage><EndPage>156</EndPage><MedlinePgn>149-156</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/mus.27824</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION/AIMS">In amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS), the impact of motor neuron dysfunction on the motor unit (MU) firing pattern remains to be elucidated. The aim of this study was to clarify the characteristics of the MU firing rate and its association with clinical factors in ALS patients using high-density surface electromyography (HDSEMG) and MU decomposition analysis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Nineteen ALS patients and 20 controls prospectively underwent HDSEMG recording of the vastus lateralis muscle during ramp-up (30% of maximum voluntary contraction) and sustained (10% of maximal voluntary contraction for 60&#x2009;seconds) contractions on performing isometric knee extension. After decomposition analysis, instantaneous firing rates (IFRs) of individually identified MUs were calculated. Comparison of IFRs and clinical variables between ALS patients and controls and analysis of the correlation between individual mean IFR and clinical variables in ALS patients were performed.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">The number of identified MUs was lower in ALS patients than in controls (P&#x2009;=&#x2009;.017). Mean IFRs of MUs (i.e., mean MU firing rates) were higher in ALS patients than in controls at some force levels on ramp-up contraction (P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;.05) and at 50 to 60&#x2009;seconds during sustained contraction (9.1 [ALS] vs 8.3 [controls] pulses per second; P&#x2009;=&#x2009;.036). There was no correlation between the clinical parameters and mean IFR of each patient.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION">ALS patients had a higher MU firing rate during muscle contraction at a low force level. Noninvasive assessment of the MU firing rate by HDSEMG can detect a motor neuronal hyperexcitable state in ALS patients.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Noto</LastName><ForeName>Yu-Ichi</ForeName><Initials>YI</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1169-8574</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Graduate School of Medical Science, Kyoto Prefectural University of Medicine, Kyoto, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kitaoji</LastName><ForeName>Takamasa</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7381-7877</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Graduate School of Medical Science, Kyoto Prefectural University of Medicine, Kyoto, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Watanabe</LastName><ForeName>Kohei</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8918-5181</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Neuromuscular Biomechanics, School of Health and Sport Sciences, Chukyo University, Toyota, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mizuno</LastName><ForeName>Toshiki</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Graduate School of Medical Science, Kyoto Prefectural University of Medicine, Kyoto, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Muscle Nerve</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7803146</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0148-639X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="CommentIn"><RefSource>Muscle Nerve. 2023 Aug;68(2):103-105</RefSource><PMID Version="1">37165712</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004576" MajorTopicYN="N">Electromyography</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011999" MajorTopicYN="N">Recruitment, Neurophysiological</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009119" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Contraction</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007537" MajorTopicYN="N">Isometric Contraction</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">decomposition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">firing rate</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">motor unit</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">surface electromyography</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36960740</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.27824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Goutman SA, Hardiman O, Al-Chalabi A, et al. Recent advances in the diagnosis and prognosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet Neurol. 2022;21:480-493.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Swash M. Fasciculation potentials and earliest changes in motor unit physiology in ALS. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2013;84:963-968.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanai K, Kuwabara S, Misawa S, et al. Altered axonal excitability properties in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: impaired potassium channel function related to disease stage. Brain. 2006;129:953-962.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Poliakov A, Tavares C, Swash M. Interplay of upper and lower motor neuron degeneration in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Neurophysiol. 2017;128:2200-2204.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Turkman A, Swash M. Motor unit firing in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and other upper and lower motor neurone disorders. Clin Neurophysiol. 2012;123:2312-2318.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holobar A, Farina D, Gazzoni M, Merletti R, Zazula D. Estimating motor unit discharge patterns from high-density surface electromyogram. Clin Neurophysiol. 2009;120:551-562.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farina D, Holobar A, Merletti R, Enoka RM. Decoding the neural drive to muscles from the surface electromyogram. Clin Neurophysiol. 2010;121:1616-1623.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holobar A, Zazula D. Correlation-based decomposition of surface electromyograms at low contraction forces. Med Biol Eng Comput. 2004;42:487-495.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merletti R, Holobar A, Farina D. Analysis of motor units with high-density surface electromyography. J Electromyogr Kinesiol. 2008;18:879-890.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watanabe K, Holobar A, Mita Y, et al. Effect of resistance training and fish protein intake on motor unit firing pattern and motor function of elderly. Front Physiol. 2018;9:1733.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watanabe K, Kouzaki M, Moritani T. Effect of aging on regional neuromuscular regulation within human rectus femoris muscle during stair ascent and descent. Gait Posture. 2017;52:26-32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watanabe K, Holobar A, Kouzaki M, Ogawa M, Akima H, Moritani T. Age-related changes in motor unit firing pattern of vastus lateralis muscle during low-moderate contraction. Age. 2016;38:48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watanabe K, Kouzaki M, Moritani T. Spatial EMG potential distribution of biceps brachii muscle during resistance training and detraining. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2015;115:2661-2670.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noto YI, Watanabe K, Holobar A, et al. High-density surface electromyography to assess motor unit firing rate in Charcot-Marie-tooth disease type 1A patients. Clin Neurophysiol. 2021;132:812-818.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shefner JM, Al-Chalabi A, Baker MR, et al. A proposal for new diagnostic criteria for ALS. Clin Neurophysiol. 2020;131:1975-1978.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum JM, Stambler N, Malta E, et al. The ALSFRS-R: a revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. BDNF ALS study group (phase III). J Neurol Sci. 1999;169:13-21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watanabe K, Kouzaki M, Moritani T. Non-uniform surface electromyographic responses to change in joint angle within rectus femoris muscle. Muscle Nerve. 2014;50:794-802.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watanabe K, Kouzaki M, Merletti R, Fujibayashi M, Moritani T. Spatial EMG potential distribution pattern of vastus lateralis muscle during isometric knee extension in young and elderly men. J Electromyogr Kinesiol. 2012;22:74-79.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watanabe K, Gazzoni M, Holobar A, et al. Motor unit firing pattern of vastus lateralis muscle in type 2 diabetes mellitus patients. Muscle Nerve. 2013;48:806-813.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watanabe K, Miyamoto T, Tanaka Y, Fukuda K, Moritani T. Type 2 diabetes mellitus patients manifest characteristic spatial EMG potential distribution pattern during sustained isometric contraction. Diabetes Res Clin Pract. 2012;97:468-473.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adam A, De Luca CJ. Firing rates of motor units in human vastus lateralis muscle during fatiguing isometric contractions. J Appl Physiol. 2005;99:268-280.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Welsh SJ, Dinenno DV, Tracy BL. Variability of quadriceps femoris motor neuron discharge and muscle force in human aging. Exp Brain Res. 2007;179:219-233.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fuglevand AJ, Winter DA, Patla AE. Models of recruitment and rate coding organization in motor-unit pools. J Neurophysiol. 1993;70:2470-2488.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Dengler R, Eisen A, et al. Electrodiagnostic criteria for diagnosis of ALS. Clin Neurophysiol. 2008;119:497-503.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weddell T, Bashford J, Wickham A, et al. First-recruited motor units adopt a faster phenotype in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Physiol. 2021;599:4117-4130.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishikawa Y, Holobar A, Watanabe K, et al. Detecting motor unit abnormalities in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis using high-density surface EMG. Clin Neurophysiol. 2022;142:262-272.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilmore KJ, Kirk EA, Doherty TJ, Kimpinski K, Rice CL. Abnormal motor unit firing rates in chronic inflammatory demyelinating polyneuropathy. J Neurol Sci. 2020;414:116859.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noto Y, Shibuya K, Vucic S, Kiernan MC. Novel therapies in development that inhibit motor neuron hyperexcitability in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Expert Rev Neurother. 2016;16:1147-1154.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S, Kiernan MC. Novel threshold tracking techniques suggest that cortical hyperexcitability is an early feature of motor neuron disease. Brain. 2006;129:2436-2446.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menon P, Geevasinga N, Yiannikas C, Howell J, Kiernan MC, Vucic S. Sensitivity and specificity of threshold tracking transcranial magnetic stimulation for diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a prospective study. Lancet Neurol. 2015;14:478-484.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frey D, Schneider C, Xu L, Borg J, Spooren W, Caroni P. Early and selective loss of neuromuscular synapse subtypes with low sprouting competence in motoneuron diseases. J Neurosci. 2000;20:2534-2542.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hegedus J, Putman CT, Tyreman N, Gordon T. Preferential motor unit loss in the SOD1 G93A transgenic mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Physiol. 2008;586:3337-3351.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pun S, Santos AF, Saxena S, Xu L, Caroni P. Selective vulnerability and pruning of phasic motoneuron axons in motoneuron disease alleviated by CNTF. Nat Neurosci. 2006;9:408-419.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spiller KJ, Cheung CJ, Restrepo CR, et al. Selective motor neuron resistance and recovery in a new inducible mouse model of TDP-43 proteinopathy. J Neurosci. 2016;36:7707-7717.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morisaki Y, Niikura M, Watanabe M, et al. Selective expression of osteopontin in ALS-resistant motor neurons is a critical determinant of late phase neurodegeneration mediated by matrix metalloproteinase-9. Sci Rep. 2016;6:27354.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Eisen A, Krieger C, Swash M. Motoneuron firing in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). Front Hum Neurosci. 2014;8:719.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>