<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36999624</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>06</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1468-1331</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>30</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Lipids and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A two-sample Mendelian randomization study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1899</StartPage><EndPage>1906</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1899-1906</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/ene.15810</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">Previous observational studies revealed a potential but partially controversial relation between lipid metabolism and the risk of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS), potentially prone to bias. Therefore, we aimed to study whether lipid metabolism involves genetically determined risk factors for ALS through Mendelian randomization (MR) analysis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Using genome-wide association study summary-level data for total cholesterol (TC) (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;188,578), high-density lipoprotein cholesterol (HDL-C) (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;403,943), low-density lipoprotein cholesterol (LDL-C) (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;440,546), apolipoprotein A1 (ApoA1) (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;391,193), apolipoprotein B (ApoB) (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;439,214), and ALS (12,577 cases and 23,475 controls), we implemented a bidirectional MR study to evaluate a genetic relation between lipids and ALS risk. We performed a mediation analysis to assess whether LDL-C is a potential mediator on the pathway from traits of LDL-C-related polyunsaturated fatty acids (PUFAs) to ALS risk.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">We identified genetically predicted increased lipid levels to be associated with the risk of ALS, whereby elevated LDL-C had the most potent effect (OR 1.028, 95% CI 1.008-1.049, p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.006). The effect of increased levels of apolipoproteins on ALS was similar to their corresponding lipoproteins. ALS did not cause any changes in lipid levels. We found no relation between LDL-C-modifying lifestyles and ALS. The mediation analysis revealed that LDL-C could act as an active mediator for linoleic acid, with the mediation effect estimated to be 0.009.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">We provided high-level genetic evidence verifying the positive link between preclinically elevated lipid and ALS risk that had been described in previous genetic and observational studies. We also demonstrated the mediating role of LDL-C in the pathway from PUFAs to ALS.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Authors. European Journal of Neurology published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of European Academy of Neurology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xia</LastName><ForeName>Kailin</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Peking University Third Hospital, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Ulm University, Ulm, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>German Center for Neurodegenerative Diseases (DZNE), Ulm, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Beijing Key Laboratory of Biomarker and Translational Research in Neurodegenerative Diseases, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory for Neuroscience, National Health Commission/Ministry of Education, Peking University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Klose</LastName><ForeName>Veronika</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>German Center for Neurodegenerative Diseases (DZNE), Ulm, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>H&#xf6;gel</LastName><ForeName>Josef</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Ulm University, Ulm, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Tao</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics, School of Public Health, Peking University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Linjing</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Peking University Third Hospital, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Beijing Key Laboratory of Biomarker and Translational Research in Neurodegenerative Diseases, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory for Neuroscience, National Health Commission/Ministry of Education, Peking University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dorst</LastName><ForeName>Johannes</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6352-0909</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Ulm University, Ulm, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fan</LastName><ForeName>Dongsheng</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6679-0864</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Peking University Third Hospital, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Beijing Key Laboratory of Biomarker and Translational Research in Neurodegenerative Diseases, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory for Neuroscience, National Health Commission/Ministry of Education, Peking University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ludolph</LastName><ForeName>Albert C</ForeName><Initials>AC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Ulm University, Ulm, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>German Center for Neurodegenerative Diseases (DZNE), Ulm, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9506311</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1351-5101</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D008078">Cholesterol, LDL</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D014280">Triglycerides</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008078" MajorTopicYN="N">Cholesterol, LDL</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057182" MajorTopicYN="N">Mendelian Randomization Analysis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055106" MajorTopicYN="N">Genome-Wide Association Study</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012307" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020641" MajorTopicYN="N">Polymorphism, Single Nucleotide</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014280" MajorTopicYN="N">Triglycerides</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mendelian randomization</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">instrumental variables</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lipids</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36999624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ene.15810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Pandya VA, Patani R. Decoding the relationship between ageing and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a cellular perspective. Brain. 2019;143:1057-1072.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santos AL, Preta G. Lipids in the cell: organisation regulates function. Cell Mol Life Sci. 2018;75:1909-1927.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sacks FM, Jensen MK. From high-density lipoprotein cholesterol to measurements of function. Arterioscler Thromb Vasc Biol. 2018;38:487-499.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shapiro MD, Fazio S. Apolipoprotein B-containing lipoproteins and atherosclerotic cardiovascular disease. F1000Res. 2017;6:134.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cadby G, Melton PE, McCarthy NS, et al. Heritability of 596 lipid species and genetic correlation with cardiovascular traits in the Busselton Family Heart Study. J Lipid Res. 2020;61:537-545.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mariosa D, Hammar N, Malmstr&#xf6;m H, et al. Blood biomarkers of carbohydrate, lipid, and apolipoprotein metabolisms and risk of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a more than 20-year follow-up of the Swedish AMORIS cohort. Ann Neurol. 2017;81:718-728.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bjornevik K, O'Reilly &#xc9;J, Cortese M, et al. Pre-diagnostic plasma lipid levels and the risk of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2021;22:133-143.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seelen M, van Doormaal PTC, Visser AE, et al. Prior medical conditions and the risk of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol. 2014;261:1949-1956.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith GD, Ebrahim S. &#x2018;Mendelian randomization&#x2019;: can genetic epidemiology contribute to understanding environmental determinants of disease? Int J Epidemiol. 2003;32:1-22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haycock PC, Burgess S, Wade KH, Bowden J, Relton C, Davey Smith G. Best (but oft-forgotten) practices: the design, analysis, and interpretation of Mendelian randomization studies. Am J Clin Nutr. 2016;103:965-978.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng P, Zhou X. Causal effects of blood lipids on amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a Mendelian randomization study. Hum Mol Genet. 2019;28:688-697.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen X, Yazdani S, Piehl F, Magnusson PKE, Fang F. Polygenic link between blood lipids and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurobiol Aging. 2018;67(202):e201-202.e206.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Julian TH, Glascow N, Barry ADF, et al. Physical exercise is a risk factor for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: convergent evidence from Mendelian randomisation, transcriptomics and risk genotypes. EBioMedicine. 2021;68:103397.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang G, Zhang L, Tang L, Xia K, Huang T, Fan D. Physical activity and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a Mendelian randomization study. Neurobiol Aging. 2021;105(374):e371-374.e374.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenbohm A, Peter R, Dorst J, et al. Life course of physical activity and risk and prognosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in a German ALS registry. Neurology. 2021;97:e1955.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beynen AC, Katan MB. Why do polyunsaturated fatty acids lower serum cholesterol? Am J Clin Nutr. 1985;42:560-563.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veldink JH, Kalmijn S, Groeneveld G-J, et al. Intake of polyunsaturated fatty acids and vitamin E reduces the risk of developing amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2007;78:367-371.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reilly &#xc9;J, Bjornevik K, Furtado JD, et al. Prediagnostic plasma polyunsaturated fatty acids and the risk of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology. 2020;94:e811.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fitzgerald KC, O'Reilly &#xc9;J, Falcone GJ, et al. Dietary &#x3c9;-3 polyunsaturated fatty acid intake and risk for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. JAMA Neurol. 2014;71:1102-1110.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willer CJ, Schmidt EM, Sengupta S, et al. Discovery and refinement of loci associated with lipid levels. Nat Genet. 2013;45:1274-1283.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richardson TG, Sanderson E, Palmer TM, et al. Evaluating the relationship between circulating lipoprotein lipids and apolipoproteins with risk of coronary heart disease: a multivariable Mendelian randomisation analysis. PLoS Med. 2020;17:e1003062.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang J, Zaitlen NA, Goddard ME, Visscher PM, Price AL. Advantages and pitfalls in the application of mixed-model association methods. Nat Genet. 2014;46:100-106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnold M, Raffler J, Pfeufer A, Suhre K, Kastenm&#xfc;ller G. SNiPA: an interactive, genetic variant-centered annotation browser. Bioinformatics. 2015;31:1334-1336.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myers TA, Chanock SJ, Machiela MJ. LDlinkR: an R package for rapidly calculating linkage disequilibrium statistics in diverse populations. Front Genet. 2020;11:157.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Rheenen W, Shatunov A, Dekker AM, et al. Genome-wide association analyses identify new risk variants and the genetic architecture of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat Genet. 2016;48:1043-1048.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Rheenen W, van der Spek RAA, Bakker MK, et al. Common and rare variant association analyses in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis identify 15 risk loci with distinct genetic architectures and neuron-specific biology. Nat Genet. 2021;53:1636-1648.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clifton PM. Diet, exercise and weight loss and dyslipidaemia. Pathology. 2019;51:222-226.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>V. Adopting healthful lifestyle habits to lower LDL cholesterol and reduce CHD risk. Circulation. 2002;106:3253-3280.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hemani G, Zheng J, Elsworth B, et al. The MR-Base platform supports systematic causal inference across the human phenome. Elife. 2018;7:e34408.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guan W, Steffen BT, Lemaitre RN, et al. Genome-wide association study of plasma N6 polyunsaturated fatty acids within the cohorts for heart and aging research in genomic epidemiology consortium. Circ Cardiovasc Genet. 2014;7:321-331.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lemaitre RN, Tanaka T, Tang W, et al. Genetic loci associated with plasma phospholipid n-3 fatty acids: a meta-analysis of genome-wide association studies from the CHARGE consortium. PLoS Genet. 2011;7:e1002193.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kettunen J, Demirkan A, W&#xfc;rtz P, et al. Genome-wide study for circulating metabolites identifies 62 loci and reveals novel systemic effects of LPA. Nat Commun. 2016;7:11122.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shim H, Chasman DI, Smith JD, et al. A multivariate genome-wide association analysis of 10 LDL subfractions, and their response to statin treatment, in 1868 Caucasians. PLoS One. 2015;10:e0120758.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palmer TM, Lawlor DA, Harbord RM, et al. Using multiple genetic variants as instrumental variables for modifiable risk factors. Stat Methods Med Res. 2012;21:223-242.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowden J, Davey Smith G, Haycock PC, Burgess S. Consistent estimation in Mendelian randomization with some invalid instruments using a weighted median estimator. Genet Epidemiol. 2016;40:304-314.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verbanck M, Chen CY, Neale B, Do R. Detection of widespread horizontal pleiotropy in causal relationships inferred from Mendelian randomization between complex traits and diseases. Nat Genet. 2018;50:693-698.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hemani G, Zheng J, Elsworth B, et al. The MR-base platform supports systematic causal inference across the human phenome. Elife. 2018;7:e34408.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burgess S, Daniel RM, Butterworth AS, Thompson SG. Network Mendelian randomization: using genetic variants as instrumental variables to investigate mediation in causal pathways. Int J Epidemiol. 2015;44:484-495.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marini S, Merino J, Montgomery BE, et al. Mendelian randomization study of obesity and cerebrovascular disease. Ann Neurol. 2020;87:516-524.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bandres-Ciga S, Noyce AJ, Hemani G, et al. Shared polygenic risk and causal inferences in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol. 2019;85:470-481.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin Y, Oh K, Oh SI, Baek H, Kim SH, Park Y. Dietary intake of fruits and beta-carotene is negatively associated with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis risk in Koreans: a case-control study. Nutr Neurosci. 2014;17:104-108.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu P-F, Lu H, Zhou X, et al. Assessment of causal effects of physical activity on neurodegenerative diseases: a Mendelian randomization study. J Sport Health Sci. 2021;10:454-461.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia K, Wang Y, Zhang L, et al. Dietary-derived essential nutrients and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a two-sample Mendelian randomization study. Nutrients. 2022;14:920.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z&#xe1;rate R, el Jaber-Vazdekis N, Tejera N, P&#xe9;rez JA, Rodr&#xed;guez C. Significance of long chain polyunsaturated fatty acids in human health. Clin Transl Med. 2017;6:e25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wood KE, Lau A, Mantzioris E, Gibson RA, Ramsden CE, Muhlhausler BS. A low omega-6 polyunsaturated fatty acid (n-6 PUFA) diet increases omega-3 (n-3) long chain PUFA status in plasma phospholipids in humans. Prostaglandins Leukot Essent Fatty Acids. 2014;90:133-138.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia K, Witzel S, Witzel C, et al. Mutation-specific metabolic profiles in presymptomatic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Eur J Neurol. 2022;30:87-95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peter RS, Rosenbohm A, Dupuis L, et al. Life course body mass index and risk and prognosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: results from the ALS registry Swabia. Eur J Epidemiol. 2017;32:901-908.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westeneng H-J, van Veenhuijzen K, van der Spek RA, et al. Associations between lifestyle and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis stratified by C9orf72 genotype: a longitudinal, population-based, case-control study. Lancet Neurol. 2021;20:373-384.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>