<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37029777</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>06</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1468-1331</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>30</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Serum neurofilament light chain cut-off definition for clinical diagnosis and prognosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1919</StartPage><EndPage>1927</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1919-1927</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/ene.15813</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">The neurofilament light chain (NfL) assay is gradually becoming an essential diagnostic tool for the diagnosis of many neurological diseases including amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). Different methods for the determination of this biomarker in serum have been developed in recent years.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">We measured blood NfL in 429 patients referred to the tertiary ALS center of Montpellier, France using two different ultrasensitive methods (Ella&#x2122; and Simoa&#x2122;) and we compared the clinical performances of these two approaches. We also converted NfL values into age and body mass index-adjusted Z-scores to assess cut-off values of this biomarker in this clinical context.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">We show comparable diagnostic and prognostic performance of Ella&#x2122; and Simoa&#x2122; technologies in ALS, with specificities and sensitivities exceeding 80% for both. We propose cut-off values for serum NfL in this clinical context, thus enabling the routine clinical use of this biomarker.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">The use of NfL in routine clinical practice will help predict survival and improve diagnostic accuracy by distinguishing ALS from other neurological diseases and motor neuron disease mimics.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Authors. European Journal of Neurology published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of European Academy of Neurology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brousse</LastName><ForeName>Mehdi</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>LBPC-PPC, Universit&#xe9; Montpellier, CHU Montpellier, INM INSERM, Montpellier, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Delaby</LastName><ForeName>Constance</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8606-6814</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>LBPC-PPC, Universit&#xe9; Montpellier, CHU Montpellier, INM INSERM, Montpellier, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hospital de la Santa Creu i Sant Pau - Biomedical Research Institute Sant Pau - Universitat Aut&#xf2;noma de Barcelona, Barcelona, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>De La Cruz</LastName><ForeName>Elisa</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Explorations neurologiques et centre SLA, Universit&#xe9; Montpellier, CHU Gui de Chauliac, INM, INSERM, Montpellier, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kuhle</LastName><ForeName>Jens</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University Hospital and University of Basel, Basel, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Multiple Sclerosis Center and Research Center for Clinical Neuroimmunology and Neuroscience (RC2NB), Departments of Biomedicine and Clinical Research, University Hospital and University of Basel, Basel, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Benkert</LastName><ForeName>Pascal</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University Hospital and University of Basel, Basel, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Multiple Sclerosis Center and Research Center for Clinical Neuroimmunology and Neuroscience (RC2NB), Departments of Biomedicine and Clinical Research, University Hospital and University of Basel, Basel, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mondesert</LastName><ForeName>Etienne</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>LBPC-PPC, Universit&#xe9; Montpellier, CHU Montpellier, INM INSERM, Montpellier, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ginestet</LastName><ForeName>Nelly</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>LBPC-PPC, Universit&#xe9; Montpellier, CHU Montpellier, INM INSERM, Montpellier, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hirtz</LastName><ForeName>Christophe</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7313-0629</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>LBPC-PPC, Universit&#xe9; Montpellier, CHU Montpellier, INM INSERM, Montpellier, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Camu</LastName><ForeName>William</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1287-7355</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Explorations neurologiques et centre SLA, Universit&#xe9; Montpellier, CHU Gui de Chauliac, INM, INSERM, Montpellier, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lehmann</LastName><ForeName>Sylvain</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6117-562X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>LBPC-PPC, Universit&#xe9; Montpellier, CHU Montpellier, INM INSERM, Montpellier, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Esselin</LastName><ForeName>Florence</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Explorations neurologiques et centre SLA, Universit&#xe9; Montpellier, CHU Gui de Chauliac, INM, INSERM, Montpellier, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9506311</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1351-5101</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D015415">Biomarkers</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D016900">Neurofilament Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007382" MajorTopicYN="N">Intermediate Filaments</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011379" MajorTopicYN="N">Prognosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015415" MajorTopicYN="N">Biomarkers</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016900" MajorTopicYN="N">Neurofilament Proteins</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015992" MajorTopicYN="N">Body Mass Index</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ALS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neurofilament</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">prognosis</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37029777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ene.15813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Hardiman O, van den Berg LH, Kiernan MC. Clinical diagnosis and management of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat Rev Neurol. 2011;7:639-649. doi:10.1038/nrneurol.2011.153</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiernan MC, Vucic S, Cheah BC, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet 2011;2011;377(9769):942-955. https://www.thelancet.com/journals/lancet/article/PIIS0140-6736(10)61156-7/fulltext (Accessed 18 May 2021)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richards D, Morren JA, Pioro EP. Time to diagnosis and factors affecting diagnostic delay in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Sci. 2020;417:117054. doi:10.1016/j.jns.2020.117054</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herrmann H, Strelkov SV, Burkhard P, et al. Intermediate filaments: primary determinants of cell architecture and plasticity. J Clin Invest. 2009;119:1772-1783. doi:10.1172/JCI38214</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deisenhammer F, Egg R, Giovannoni G, et al. EFNS guidelines on disease-specific CSF investigations. Eur J Neurol. 2009;16:760-770. doi:10.1111/j.1468-1331.2009.02595.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khalil M, Teunissen CE, Otto M, et al. Neurofilaments as biomarkers in neurological disorders. Nat Rev Neurol. 2018;14:577-589. doi:10.1038/s41582-018-0058-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steinacker P, Feneberg E, Weishaupt J, et al. Neurofilaments in the diagnosis of motoneuron diseases: a prospective study on 455 patients. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2016;87:12-20. doi:10.1136/jnnp-2015-311,387</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poesen K, de Schaepdryver M, Stubendorff B, et al. Neurofilament markers for ALS correlate with extent of upper and lower motor neuron disease. Neurology. 2017;88:2302-2309. doi:10.1212/WNL.0000000000004029</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tortelli R, Copetti M, Ruggieri M, et al. Cerebrospinal fluid neurofilament light chain levels: marker of progression to generalized amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Eur J Neurol. 2015;22:215-218. doi:10.1111/ene.12421</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feneberg E, Oeckl P, Steinacker P, et al. Multicenter evaluation of neurofilaments in early symptom onset amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology. 2018;90:e22-e30. doi:10.1212/WNL.0000000000004761</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thouvenot E, Demattei C, Lehmann S, et al. Serum neurofilament light chain at time of diagnosis is an independent prognostic factor of survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Eur J Neurol. 2020;27:251-257. doi:10.1111/ene.14063</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu C-H, Macdonald-Wallis C, Gray E, et al. Neurofilament light chain: a prognostic biomarker in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology. 2015;84:2247-2257. doi:10.1212/WNL.0000000000001642</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norgren N, Karlsson J-E, Rosengren L, et al. Monoclonal antibodies selective for low molecular weight neurofilaments. Hybrid Hybridomics. 2002;21:53-59. doi:10.1089/15368590252917647</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaiottino J, Norgren N, Dobson R, et al. Increased neurofilament light chain blood levels in neurodegenerative neurological diseases. PLoS One. 2013;8:e75091. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0075091</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu C-H, Petzold A, Topping J, et al. Plasma neurofilament heavy chain levels and disease progression in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: insights from a longitudinal study. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2015;86:565-573. doi:10.1136/jnnp-2014-307,672</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rissin DM, Kan CW, Campbell TG, et al. Single-molecule enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay detects serum proteins at subfemtomolar concentrations. Nat Biotechnol. 2010;28:595-599. doi:10.1038/nbt.1641</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson DH, Rissin DM, Kan CW, et al. The Simoa HD-1 analyzer: a novel fully automated digital immunoassay analyzer with single-molecule sensitivity and multiplexing. J Lab Autom. 2016;21:533-547. doi:10.1177/2211068215589580</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuhle J, Barro C, Andreasson U, et al. Comparison of three analytical platforms for quantification of the neurofilament light chain in blood samples: ELISA, electrochemiluminescence immunoassay and Simoa. Clin Chem Lab Med. 2016;54:1655-1661. doi:10.1515/cclm-2015-1195</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dysinger M, Marusov G, Fraser S. Quantitative analysis of four protein biomarkers: an automated microfluidic cartridge-based method and its comparison to colorimetric ELISA. J Immunol Methods. 2017;451:1-10. doi:10.1016/j.jim.2017.08.009</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson AG, Gray E, Verber N, et al. Multicentre appraisal of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis biofluid biomarkers shows primacy of blood neurofilament light chain. Brain Commun. 2022;4:fcac029. doi:10.1093/braincomms/fcac029</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esselin F, de la Cruz E, Hirtz C, et al. Repeated neurofilament light chain measurements did not capture Riluzole therapeutic effect in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. CNS Neurosci Ther 2022;28:1532-1538. doi:10.1111/cns.13894</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benatar M, Zhang L, Wang L, et al. Validation of serum neurofilaments as prognostic and potential pharmacodynamic biomarkers for ALS. Neurology. 2020;95:e59-e69. doi:10.1212/WNL.0000000000009559</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behzadi A, Pujol-Calder&#xf3;n F, Tjust AE, et al. Neurofilaments can differentiate ALS subgroups and ALS from common diagnostic mimics. Sci Rep. 2021;11:22128. doi:10.1038/s41598-021-01499-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Traynor BJ, Codd MB, Corr B, Forde C, Frost E, Hardiman OM. Clinical features of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis according to the El Escorial and Airlie House diagnostic criteria: a population-based study. Arch Neurol. 2000;57(8):1171-1176. https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamaneurology/article-abstract/777262 (Accessed 31 May 2021)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teunissen CE, Petzold A, Bennett JL, et al. Deisenhammer: a consensus protocol for the standardization of cerebrospinal fluid collection and biobanking. Neurology. 2009;73:1914-1922.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bland JM, Altman DG. Statistical methods for assessing agreement between two methods of clinical measurement. Lancet. 1986;1:307-310.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Budczies J, Klauschen F, Sinn BV, et al. Cutoff finder: a comprehensive and straightforward web application enabling rapid biomarker cutoff optimization. PLoS One. 2012;7:e51862. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0051862</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pencina MJ, D'Agostino RB, D'Agostino RB, et al. Evaluating the added predictive ability of a new marker: from area under the ROC curve to reclassification and beyond. Stat Med. 2008;27:157-172; Discussion 207-212. doi:10.1002/sim.2929</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benkert P, Meier S, Schaedelin S, et al. Serum neurofilament light chain for individual prognostication of disease activity in people with multiple sclerosis: a retrospective modelling and validation study. Lancet Neurol. 2022;21:246-257. doi:10.1016/S1474-4422(22)00009-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>St&#xf6;ckl D, Rodr&#xed;guez Cabaleiro D, van Uytfanghe K, et al. Interpreting method comparison studies by use of the Bland-Altman plot: reflecting the importance of sample size by incorporating confidence limits and predefined error limits in the graphic. Clin Chem. 2004;50:2216-2218. doi:10.1373/clinchem.2004.036095</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeLong ER, DeLong DM, Clarke-Pearson DL. Comparing the areas under two or more correlated receiver operating characteristic curves: a nonparametric approach. Biometrics. 1988;44:837-845.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delaby C, Julian A, Page G, et al. NFL strongly correlates with TNF-R1 in the plasma of AD patients, but not with cognitive decline. Sci Rep. 2021;11:10283. doi:10.1038/s41598-021-89749-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alcolea D, Delaby C, Mu&#xf1;oz L, et al. Use of plasma biomarkers for AT(N) classification of neurodegenerative dementias. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2021;92(11):1206-1214. doi:10.1136/jnnp-2021-326603</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delaby C, Alcolea D, Carmona-Iragui M, et al. Differential levels of neurofilament light protein in cerebrospinal fluid in patients with a wide range of neurodegenerative disorders. Sci Rep. 2020;10:9161. doi:10.1038/s41598-020-66090-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gray E, Oeckl P, Amador MDM, et al. A multi-center study of neurofilament assay reliability and inter-laboratory variability. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2020;21:452-458. doi:10.1080/21678421.2020.1779300</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poesen K, van Damme P. Diagnostic and prognostic performance of neurofilaments in ALS. Front Neurol. 2018;9:1167. doi:10.3389/fneur.2018.01167</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaiani A, Martinelli I, Bello L, et al. Diagnostic and prognostic biomarkers in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: neurofilament light chain levels in definite subtypes of disease. JAMA Neurol. 2017;74:525-532. doi:10.1001/jamaneurol.2016.5398</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halbgebauer S, Steinacker P, Verde F, et al. Comparison of CSF and serum neurofilament light and heavy chain as differential diagnostic biomarkers for ALS. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2022;93:68-74. doi:10.1136/jnnp-2021-327,129</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manouchehrinia A, Piehl F, Hillert J, et al. Confounding effect of blood volume and body mass index on blood neurofilament light chain levels. Ann Clin Transl Neurol. 2020;7:139-143. doi:10.1002/acn3.50972</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gauthier A, Viel S, Perret M, et al. Comparison of SimoaTM and EllaTM to assess serum neurofilament-light chain in multiple sclerosis. Ann Clin Transl Neurol. 2021;8:1141-1150. doi:10.1002/acn3.51355</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darlix A, Hirtz C, Mollevi C, et al. Serum glial fibrillary acidic protein is a predictor of brain metastases in patients with metastatic breast cancer. Int J Cancer. 2021;149:1605-1618. doi:10.1002/ijc.33724</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bailey DM, Bain AR, Hoiland RL, et al. Hypoxemia increases blood-brain barrier permeability during extreme apnea in humans. J Cereb Blood Flow Metab. 2022;42:1120-1135; 271678X221075967. doi:10.1177/0271678X221075967</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>