<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37086196</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>22</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-4598</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>68</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Muscle &amp; nerve</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Muscle Nerve</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Far-field potential of the compound muscle action potential as a reliable marker in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>257</StartPage><EndPage>263</EndPage><MedlinePgn>257-263</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/mus.27829</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION/AIMS">Reliable neurophysiological markers in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) are of great interest. The compound muscle action potential (CMAP) amplitude has been a conventional marker, although it is greatly influenced by the electrode position. We propose the far-field potential of the CMAP (FFP-CMAP) as a new neurophysiological marker in ALS.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Patients with ALS and age-matched healthy controls were enrolled. We used a proximal reference (pref) in addition to the conventional distal reference (dref). Routine CMAP was recorded from the belly-dref lead and FFP-CMAP from the dref-pref lead for the ulnar and tibial nerves. Multiple point stimulation motor unit number estimation (MUNE) was also examined in the ulnar nerve. Inter-rater reproducibility was evaluated by two examiners, and some patients were followed up every 3&#x2009;mo for 1&#x2009;y.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">We tested 17 patients with ALS and 10 controls. The amplitudes of routine CMAP and FFP-CMAP in the ulnar and tibial nerves, and hypothenar MUNE value in the ulnar nerve were significantly decreased in ALS compared to controls. Ulnar FFP-CMAP achieved the highest inter-rater intraclass correlation coefficient (ICC) value (0.942) when compared with routine CMAP (0.880) and MUNE (0.839). The tibial FFP-CMAP had a higher ICC value (0.986) than the routine CMAP (0.697). In this way, the FFP-CMAP showed high inter-rater reproducibility because its shape was not much influenced by the electrode position. During 1-y follow-up, decline of CMAP, FFP, and MUNE showed significant correlations with the Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Functional Rating Scale - Revised (ALSFRS-R).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION">The FFP-CMAP shows promise as a reliable marker for ALS.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Higashihara</LastName><ForeName>Mana</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8015-2028</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Tokyo Metropolitan Geriatric Hospital, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yamazaki</LastName><ForeName>Hiroki</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Tokushima University Graduate School of Biomedical Sciences, Tokushima, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Izumi</LastName><ForeName>Yuishin</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Tokushima University Graduate School of Biomedical Sciences, Tokushima, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kobayashi</LastName><ForeName>Masahito</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Economics, Yokohama National University, Yokohama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nodera</LastName><ForeName>Hiroyuki</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5357-5081</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Tokushima University Graduate School of Biomedical Sciences, Tokushima, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Tenri Hospital, Tenri, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oishi</LastName><ForeName>Chizuko</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Kyorin University Hospital, Mitaka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Iwata</LastName><ForeName>Atsushi</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Tokyo Metropolitan Geriatric Hospital, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Murayama</LastName><ForeName>Shigeo</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Tokyo Metropolitan Geriatric Hospital, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kaji</LastName><ForeName>Ryuji</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Tokushima University Graduate School of Biomedical Sciences, Tokushima, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Utano National Hospital, Kyoto, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sonoo</LastName><ForeName>Masahiro</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2410-9468</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Teikyo University School of Medicine, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Muscle Nerve</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7803146</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0148-639X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="CommentIn"><RefSource>Muscle Nerve. 2023 Sep;68(3):237-239</RefSource><PMID Version="1">37269166</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009046" MajorTopicYN="N">Motor Neurons</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000200" MajorTopicYN="N">Action Potentials</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015203" MajorTopicYN="N">Reproducibility of Results</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ALS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CMAP</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">MUNE</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">far-field potential</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">inter-rater reproducibility</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37086196</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.27829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Benatar M, Boylan K, Jeromin A, et al. ALS biomarkers for therapy development: state of the field and future directions. Muscle Nerve. 2016;53:169-182.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nandedkar SD, Barkhaus PE, St&#xe5;lberg EV. Cumulative motor index: an index to study progression of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Clin Neurophysiol. 2015;32:79-85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higashihara M, Sonoo M, Yamamoto T, et al. Evaluation of spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy using the clustering index method. Muscle Nerve. 2011;44:539-546.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bromberg MB, Fries TJ, Forshew DA, Tandan R. Electrophysiologic endpoint measures in a multicenter ALS drug trial. J Neurol Sci. 2001;184:51-55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nandedkar SD, Nandedkar DS, Barkhaus PE, St&#xe5;lberg EV. Motor unit number index (MUNIX). IEEE Trans Biomed Eng. 2004;51:2209-2211.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobsen AB, Bostock H, Fuglsang-Frederiksen A, et al. Reproducibility, and sensitivity to motor unit loss in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, of a novel MUNE method: MScanFit MUNE. Clin Neurophysiol. 2017;128:1380-1388.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kohara N, Kimura J, Kaji R, et al. F-wave latency serves as the most reproducible measure in nerve conduction studies of diabetic polyneuropathy: multicentre analysis in healthy subjects and patients with diabetic polyneuropathy. Diabetologica. 2000;43:915-921.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kong X, Lesser EA, Megerian JT, Gozani SN. Repeatability of nerve conduction measurements using automation. J Clin Monit Comput. 2006;20:405-410.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinheiro DS, Manzano GM, N&#xf3;brega JA. Reproducibility in nerve conduction studies and F-wave analysis. Clin Neurophysiol. 2008;119:2070-2073.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Dijk JG, van der Kamp W, van Hilten BJ, van Someren P. Influence of recording site on CMAP amplitude on its variation over a length of nerve. Muscle Nerve. 1994;17:1286-1292.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bromberg MB, Spiegelberg T. The influence of active electrode placement on CMAP amplitude. Electroencephalogr Clin Neurophysiol. 1997;105:385-389.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kincaid JC, Brashear A, Markand ON. The influence of the reference electrode on CMAP configuration. Muscle Nerve. 1993;16:392-396.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brashear A, Kincaid JC. The influence of the reference electrode on CMAP configuration: leg nerve observations and an alternative reference site. Muscle Nerve. 1996;19:63-67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nandedkar SD, Barkhaus PE. Contribution of reference electrode to the compound muscle action potential. Muscle Nerve. 2007;36:87-92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sonoo M. Far-field potentials in the compound muscle action potential. Muscle Nerve. 2020;61:271-279.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Dengler R, Eisen A, et al. Electrodiagnostic criteria for diagnosis of ALS. Clin Neurophysiol. 2008;119:497-503.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higashihara M, Sonoo M, Yamamoto T, et al. Far-field potentials in hypothenar motor unit number estimation. Muscle Nerve. 2013;48:191-197.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kadrie HA, Yates SK, Milner-Brown HS, Brown WF. Multiple point electrical stimulation of ulnar and median nerves. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 1976;39:973-985.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doherty TJ, Brown WF. The estimated numbers and relative sizes of thenar motor units as selected by multiple point stimulation in young and older adults. Muscle Nerve. 1993;16:355-366.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daube JR. Motor unit number estimates: from a to Z. J Neurol Sci. 2006;242:23-35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bromberg MB. Updating motor unit number estimation (MUNE). Clin Neurophysiol. 2007;118:1-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum JM, Stambler N, Malta E, et al. The ALSFRS-R: a revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. BDNF ALS study group (phase III). J Neurol Sci. 1999;169:13-21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koo TK, Li MY. A guideline of selecting and reporting Intraclass correlation coefficients for reliability research. J Chiropr Med. 2016;15:155-163.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahn SW, Kim SH, Kim JE, et al. Reproducibility of the motor unit number index (MUNIX) in normal controls and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. Muscle Nerve. 2010;42:808-813.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nandedkar SD, Barkhaus PE, St&#xe5;lberg EV. Motor unit number index (MUNIX): principle, method, and findings in healthy subjects and in patients with motor neuron disease. Muscle Nerve. 2010;42:798-807.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neuwirth C, Nandedkar S, St&#xe5;lberg E, et al. Motor unit number index (MUNIX): a novel neurophysiological marker for neuromuscular disorders; test-retest reliability in healthy volunteers. Clin Neurophysiol. 2011;122:1867-1872.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furtula J, Johnsen B, Christensen PB, et al. MUNIX and incremental stimulation MUNE in ALS patients and control subjects. Clin Neurophysiol. 2013;124:610-618.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neuwirth C, Barkhaus PE, Burkhardt C, et al. Tracking motor neuron loss in a set of six muscles in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis using the motor unit number index (MUNIX): a 15-month longitudinal multicentre trial. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2015;86:1172-1179.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, Zong Y, Klein CS, Zhou P. Motor unit number estimation of human abductor hallucis from a compound muscle action potential scan. Muscle Nerve. 2018;58:735-737.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higashihara M, Menon P, van den Bos M, Pavey N, Vucic S. Reproducibility of motor unit number index and MScanFit motor unit number estimation across intrinsic hand muscles. Muscle Nerve. 2020;62:192-200.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bromberg MB, Larson WL. Relationships between motor-unit number estimates and isometric strength in distal muscles in ALS/MND. J Neurol Sci. 1996;139(Suppl):38-42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shefner JM, Jillapalli D, Bradshaw Y. Reducing intersubject variability in motor unit number estimation. Muscle Nerve. 1999;22:1457-1460.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lomen-Hoerth C, Olney RK. Comparison of multiple point and statistical motor unit number estimation. Muscle Nerve. 2000;23:1525-1533.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simmons Z, Epstein DK, Borg B, Mauger DT, Kothari MJ, Shefner JM. Reproducibility of motor unit number estimation in individual subjects. Muscle Nerve. 2001;24:467-473.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwon O, Lee KW. Reproducibility of statistical motor unit number estimates in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: comparisons between size- and number-weighted modifications. Muscle Nerve. 2004;29:211-217.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Porter CL, Alvarez A, Jones KE, Ming CK. Test-retest reliability of a modified multiple point stimulation technique for motor unit number estimation. Clin Neurophysiol. 2008;119:2287-2290.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goyal N, Salameh JS, Baldassari LE, David WS. Added sampling improves reproducibility of multipoint motor unit estimates. Muscle Nerve. 2010;41:114-116.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shefner JM, Watson ML, Simionescu L, et al. Multipoint incremental motor unit number estimation as an outcome measure in ALS. Neurology. 2011;77:235-241.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gawel M, Kostera-Pruszczy A. Effect of age and gender on the number of motor units in healthy subjects estimated by the multipoint incremental MUNE method. J Clin Neurophysiol. 2014;31:272-278.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higashihara M, Menon P, van den Bos M, Geevasinga N, Vucic S. Reproducibility of motor unit number index and multiple point stimulation motor unit number estimation in controls. Muscle Nerve. 2018;58:660-664.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobsen AB, Bostock H, Tankisi H. CMAP scan MUNE (MScan)-a novel motor unit number estimation (MUNE) method. J Vis Exp. 2018;7:56805.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xf8;rensen DM, Bostock H, Ballegaard M, et al. Assessing inter-rater reproducibility in MScanFit MUNE in a 6-subject, 12-rater "Round Robin" setup. Neurophysiol Clin. 2022;52:157-169.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiba T, Oishi C, Kobayashi M, Higashihara M, Sonoo M. The reproducibility of the amplitude of the far-field potential (FFP) of the compound muscle action potential (CMAP). Muscle Nerve. 2018;58:S80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuwabara S, Mizobuchi K, Ogawara K, Hattori T. Dissociated small hand muscle involvement in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis detected by motor unit number estimates. Muscle Nerve. 1999;22:870-873.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>