<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37148340</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>17</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1432-1459</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>270</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Identifying novel genes for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis by integrating human brain proteomes with genome-wide association data.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>4013</StartPage><EndPage>4023</EndPage><MedlinePgn>4013-4023</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s00415-023-11757-4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Genome-Wide Association Studies (GWAS) have identified numerous risk genes for Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis (ALS); however, the mechanisms by which these loci confer ALS risk are uncertain. This study aims to identify novel causal proteins in the brains of patients with ALS using an integrative analytical pipeline.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Using the datasets of Protein Quantitative Trait Loci (pQTL) (N<sub>pQTL1</sub>&#x2009;=&#x2009;376, N<sub>pQTL2</sub>&#x2009;=&#x2009;152), expression QTL (eQTL) (N&#x2009;=&#x2009;452), and the largest ALS GWAS (N<sub>ALS=</sub>27,205, N<sub>Controls</sub>&#x2009;=&#x2009;110,881), we performed a systematic analytical pipeline including Proteome-Wide Association Study (PWAS), Mendelian Randomization (MR), Bayesian colocalization, and Transcriptome-Wide Association Study (TWAS) to identify novel causal proteins for ALS in the brain.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Using PWAS, we found that the altered protein abundance of 12 genes in the brain was associated with ALS. Three genes (SCFD1, SARM1 and CAMLG) were identified as lead causal genes for ALS with solid evidence (False discovery rate&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05, in MR analysis; PPH4&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;80% for Bayesian colocalization). Specifically, an increased abundance of SCFD1 and CAMLG led to an increased risk of ALS, whereas a higher abundance of SARM1 led to a decreased risk of developing ALS. TWAS showed that SCFD1 and CAMLG were related to ALS at the transcriptional level.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">SCFD1, CAMLG, and SARM1 exhibited robust associations and causality with ALS. The study findings provide novel clues for identifying potential therapeutic targets in ALS. Further studies are required to explore the mechanisms underlying the identified genes.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer-Verlag GmbH Germany.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Gu</LastName><ForeName>Xiao-Jing</ForeName><Initials>XJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mental Health Center, West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu, 610041, Sichuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Su</LastName><ForeName>Wei-Ming</ForeName><Initials>WM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu, 610041, Sichuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Brain Science and Brain-Inspired Technology, West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu, 610041, Sichuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Rare Diseases, West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu, 610041, Sichuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dou</LastName><ForeName>Meng</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chengdu Institute of Computer Application, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Chengdu, 610041, Sichuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jiang</LastName><ForeName>Zheng</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu, 610041, Sichuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Brain Science and Brain-Inspired Technology, West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu, 610041, Sichuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Rare Diseases, West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu, 610041, Sichuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Duan</LastName><ForeName>Qing-Qing</ForeName><Initials>QQ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu, 610041, Sichuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Brain Science and Brain-Inspired Technology, West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu, 610041, Sichuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Rare Diseases, West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu, 610041, Sichuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Han</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathophysiology, West China College of Basic Medical Sciences and Forensic Medicine, Sichuan University, Chengdu, 610041, Sichuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ren</LastName><ForeName>Yan-Ling</ForeName><Initials>YL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathophysiology, West China College of Basic Medical Sciences and Forensic Medicine, Sichuan University, Chengdu, 610041, Sichuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cao</LastName><ForeName>Bei</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu, 610041, Sichuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Brain Science and Brain-Inspired Technology, West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu, 610041, Sichuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Rare Diseases, West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu, 610041, Sichuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Yi</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathophysiology, West China College of Basic Medical Sciences and Forensic Medicine, Sichuan University, Chengdu, 610041, Sichuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Yong-Ping</ForeName><Initials>YP</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5603-4192</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu, 610041, Sichuan, China. yongping.chen@wchscu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Brain Science and Brain-Inspired Technology, West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu, 610041, Sichuan, China. yongping.chen@wchscu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Rare Diseases, West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu, 610041, Sichuan, China. yongping.chen@wchscu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>No. 81971188</GrantID><Agency>the National Natural Science Fund of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>No. 2022NSFSC0749</GrantID><Agency>the National Natural Science Fund of Sichuan</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>No. 2021YFS0051</GrantID><Agency>the Science and Technology Bureau Fund of Sichuan Province</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>No. 2019YFS0216</GrantID><Agency>the Science and Technology Bureau Fund of Sichuan Province</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>No. 2019HXFH046</GrantID><Agency>the 1.3.5 project for disciplines of excellence, West China Hospital, Sichuan University</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>J Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0423161</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0340-5354</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D020543">Proteome</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055106" MajorTopicYN="N">Genome-Wide Association Study</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020543" MajorTopicYN="N">Proteome</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001499" MajorTopicYN="N">Bayes Theorem</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001921" MajorTopicYN="N">Brain</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020641" MajorTopicYN="N">Polymorphism, Single Nucleotide</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CAMLG</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mendelian randomization</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">QTL</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARM1</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SCFD1</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37148340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00415-023-11757-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s00415-023-11757-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Goutman SA, Hardiman O, Al-Chalabi A, Chi&#xf3; A, Savelieff MG, Kiernan MC, Feldman EL (2022) Recent advances in the diagnosis and prognosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet Neurol 21(5):480&#x2013;493</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35334233</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9513753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1474-4422(21)00465-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Rheenen W, van der Spek RAA, Bakker MK, van Vugt J, Hop PJ, Zwamborn RAJ, de Klein N, Westra HJ, Bakker OB, Deelen P, Shireby G, Hannon E, Moisse M, Baird D, Restuadi R, Dolzhenko E, Dekker AM, Gawor K, Westeneng HJ, Tazelaar GHP, van Eijk KR, Kooyman M, Byrne RP, Doherty M, Heverin M, Al Khleifat A, Iacoangeli A, Shatunov A, Ticozzi N, Cooper-Knock J, Smith BN, Gromicho M, Chandran S, Pal S, Morrison KE, Shaw PJ, Hardy J, Orrell RW, Sendtner M, Meyer T, Basak N, van der Kooi AJ, Ratti A, Fogh I, Gellera C, Lauria G, Corti S, Cereda C, Sproviero D, D&#x2019;Alfonso S, Soraru G, Siciliano G, Filosto M, Padovani A, Chio A, Calvo A, Moglia C, Brunetti M, Canosa A, Grassano M, Beghi E, Pupillo E, Logroscino G, Nefussy B, Osmanovic A, Nordin A, Lerner Y, Zabari M, Gotkine M, Baloh RH, Bell S, Vourc&#x2019;h P, Corcia P, Couratier P, Millecamps S, Meininger V, Salachas F, Mora Pardina JS, Assialioui A, Rojas-Garcia R, Dion PA, Ross JP, Ludolph AC, Weishaupt JH, Brenner D, Freischmidt A, Bensimon G, Brice A, Durr A, Payan CAM, Saker-Delye S, Wood NW, Topp S, Rademakers R, Tittmann L, Lieb W, Franke A, Ripke S, Braun A, Kraft J, Whiteman DC, Olsen CM, Uitterlinden AG, Hofman A, Rietschel M, Cichon S, Nothen MM, Amouyel P, Consortium S, Consortium P, Consortium S, Consortium S, Traynor BJ, Singleton AB, Mitne Neto M, Cauchi RJ, Ophoff RA, Wiedau-Pazos M, Lomen-Hoerth C, van Deerlin VM, Grosskreutz J, Roediger A, Gaur N, Jork A, Barthel T, Theele E, Ilse B, Stubendorff B, Witte OW, Steinbach R, Hubner CA, Graff C, Brylev L, Fominykh V, Demeshonok V, Ataulina A, Rogelj B, Koritnik B, Zidar J, Ravnik-Glavac M, Glavac D, Stevic Z, Drory V, Povedano M, Blair IP, Kiernan MC, Benyamin B, Henderson RD, Furlong S, Mathers S, McCombe PA, Needham M, Ngo ST, Nicholson GA, Pamphlett R, Rowe DB, Steyn FJ, Williams KL, Mather KA, Sachdev PS, Henders AK, Wallace L, de Carvalho M, Pinto S, Petri S, Weber M, Rouleau GA, Silani V, Curtis CJ, Breen G, Glass JD, Brown RH Jr, Landers JE, Shaw CE, Andersen PM, Groen EJN, van Es MA, Pasterkamp RJ, Fan D, Garton FC, McRae AF, Davey Smith G, Gaunt TR, Eberle MA, Mill J, McLaughlin RL, Hardiman O, Kenna KP, Wray NR, Tsai E, Runz H, Franke L, Al-Chalabi A, Van Damme P, van den Berg LH, Veldink JH (2021) Common and rare variant association analyses in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis identify 15 risk loci with distinct genetic architectures and neuron-specific biology. Nat Genet 53:1636&#x2013;1648</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34873335</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8648564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41588-021-00973-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Rheenen W, Shatunov A, Dekker AM, McLaughlin RL, Diekstra FP, Pulit SL, van der Spek RA, Vosa U, de Jong S, Robinson MR, Yang J, Fogh I, van Doormaal PT, Tazelaar GH, Koppers M, Blokhuis AM, Sproviero W, Jones AR, Kenna KP, van Eijk KR, Harschnitz O, Schellevis RD, Brands WJ, Medic J, Menelaou A, Vajda A, Ticozzi N, Lin K, Rogelj B, Vrabec K, Ravnik-Glavac M, Koritnik B, Zidar J, Leonardis L, Groselj LD, Millecamps S, Salachas F, Meininger V, de Carvalho M, Pinto S, Mora JS, Rojas-Garcia R, Polak M, Chandran S, Colville S, Swingler R, Morrison KE, Shaw PJ, Hardy J, Orrell RW, Pittman A, Sidle K, Fratta P, Malaspina A, Topp S, Petri S, Abdulla S, Drepper C, Sendtner M, Meyer T, Ophoff RA, Staats KA, Wiedau-Pazos M, Lomen-Hoerth C, Van Deerlin VM, Trojanowski JQ, Elman L, McCluskey L, Basak AN, Tunca C, Hamzeiy H, Parman Y, Meitinger T, Lichtner P, Radivojkov-Blagojevic M, Andres CR, Maurel C, Bensimon G, Landwehrmeyer B, Brice A, Payan CA, Saker-Delye S, Durr A, Wood NW, Tittmann L, Lieb W, Franke A, Rietschel M, Cichon S, Nothen MM, Amouyel P, Tzourio C, Dartigues JF, Uitterlinden AG, Rivadeneira F, Estrada K, Hofman A, Curtis C, Blauw HM, van der Kooi AJ, de Visser M, Goris A, Weber M, Shaw CE, Smith BN, Pansarasa O, Cereda C, Del Bo R, Comi GP, D&#x2019;Alfonso S, Bertolin C, Soraru G, Mazzini L, Pensato V, Gellera C, Tiloca C, Ratti A, Calvo A, Moglia C, Brunetti M, Arcuti S, Capozzo R, Zecca C, Lunetta C, Penco S, Riva N, Padovani A, Filosto M, Muller B, Stuit RJ, Registry P, Group S, Registry S, Consortium FS, Consortium S, Group NS, Blair I, Zhang K, McCann EP, Fifita JA, Nicholson GA, Rowe DB, Pamphlett R, Kiernan MC, Grosskreutz J, Witte OW, Ringer T, Prell T, Stubendorff B, Kurth I, Hubner CA, Leigh PN, Casale F, Chio A, Beghi E, Pupillo E, Tortelli R, Logroscino G, Powell J, Ludolph AC, Weishaupt JH, Robberecht W, Van Damme P, Franke L, Pers TH, Brown RH, Glass JD, Landers JE, Hardiman O, Andersen PM, Corcia P, Vourc&#x2019;h P, Silani V, Wray NR, Visscher PM, de Bakker PI, van Es MA, Pasterkamp RJ, Lewis CM, Breen G, Al-Chalabi A, van den Berg LH, Veldink JH (2016) Genome-wide association analyses identify new risk variants and the genetic architecture of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat Genet 48:1043&#x2013;1048</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27455348</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5556360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ng.3622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rolland DCM, Basrur V, Jeon YK, McNeil-Schwalm C, Fermin D, Conlon KP, Zhou Y, Ng SY, Tsou CC, Brown NA, Thomas DG, Bailey NG, Omenn GS, Nesvizhskii AI, Root DE, Weinstock DM, Faryabi RB, Lim MS, Elenitoba-Johnson KSJ (2017) Functional proteogenomics reveals biomarkers and therapeutic targets in lymphomas. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA 114:6581&#x2013;6586</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28607076</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5488937</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.1701263114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brandes N, Linial N, Linial M (2020) PWAS: proteome-wide association study-linking genes and phenotypes by functional variation in proteins. Genome Biol 21:173</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32665031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7386203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13059-020-02089-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emdin CA, Khera AV, Kathiresan S (2017) Mendelian randomization. JAMA 318:1925&#x2013;1926</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29164242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2017.17219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giambartolomei C, Vukcevic D, Schadt EE, Franke L, Hingorani AD, Wallace C, Plagnol V (2014) Bayesian test for colocalisation between pairs of genetic association studies using summary statistics. PLoS Genet 10:e1004383</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24830394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4022491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pgen.1004383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ou YN, Yang YX, Deng YT, Zhang C, Hu H, Wu BS, Liu Y, Wang YJ, Zhu Y, Suckling J, Tan L, Yu JT (2021) Identification of novel drug targets for Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease by integrating genetics and proteomes from brain and blood. Mol Psychiatry 26:6065&#x2013;6073</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34381170</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41380-021-01251-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Storm CS, Kia DA, Almramhi MM, Bandres-Ciga S, Finan C, International Parkinson&#x2019;s Disease Genomics C, Hingorani AD, Wood NW (2021) Finding genetically-supported drug targets for Parkinson&#x2019;s disease using Mendelian randomization of the druggable genome. Nat Commun 12:7342</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34930919</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8688480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-021-26280-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng YT, Ou YN, Wu BS, Yang YX, Jiang Y, Huang YY, Liu Y, Tan L, Dong Q, Suckling J, Li F, Yu JT (2022) Identifying causal genes for depression via integration of the proteome and transcriptome from brain and blood. Mol Psychiatry 27(6):2849&#x2013;2857</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35296807</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41380-022-01507-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang C, Farias FHG, Ibanez L, Suhy A, Sadler B, Fernandez MV, Wang F, Bradley JL, Eiffert B, Bahena JA, Budde JP, Li Z, Dube U, Sung YJ, Mihindukulasuriya KA, Morris JC, Fagan AM, Perrin RJ, Benitez BA, Rhinn H, Harari O, Cruchaga C (2021) Genomic atlas of the proteome from brain, CSF and plasma prioritizes proteins implicated in neurological disorders. Nat Neurosci 24:1302&#x2013;1312</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34239129</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8521603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41593-021-00886-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wingo AP, Liu Y, Gerasimov ES, Gockley J, Logsdon BA, Duong DM, Dammer EB, Robins C, Beach TG, Reiman EM, Epstein MP, De Jager PL, Lah JJ, Bennett DA, Seyfried NT, Levey AI, Wingo TS (2021) Integrating human brain proteomes with genome-wide association data implicates new proteins in Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease pathogenesis. Nat Genet 53:143&#x2013;146</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33510477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8130821</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41588-020-00773-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wingo AP, Fan W, Duong DM, Gerasimov ES, Dammer EB, Liu Y, Harerimana NV, White B, Thambisetty M, Troncoso JC, Kim N, Schneider JA, Hajjar IM, Lah JJ, Bennett DA, Seyfried NT, Levey AI, Wingo TS (2020) Shared proteomic effects of cerebral atherosclerosis and Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease on the human brain. Nat Neurosci 23:696&#x2013;700</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32424284</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7269838</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41593-020-0635-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Jager PL, Ma Y, McCabe C, Xu J, Vardarajan BN, Felsky D, Klein HU, White CC, Peters MA, Lodgson B, Nejad P, Tang A, Mangravite LM, Yu L, Gaiteri C, Mostafavi S, Schneider JA, Bennett DA (2018) A multi-omic atlas of the human frontal cortex for aging and Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease research. Sci Data 5:180142</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30084846</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6080491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/sdata.2018.142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beach TG, Adler CH, Sue LI, Serrano G, Shill HA, Walker DG, Lue L, Roher AE, Dugger BN, Maarouf C, Birdsill AC, Intorcia A, Saxon-Labelle M, Pullen J, Scroggins A, Filon J, Scott S, Hoffman B, Garcia A, Caviness JN, Hentz JG, Driver-Dunckley E, Jacobson SA, Davis KJ, Belden CM, Long KE, Malek-Ahmadi M, Powell JJ, Gale LD, Nicholson LR, Caselli RJ, Woodruff BK, Rapscak SZ, Ahern GL, Shi J, Burke AD, Reiman EM, Sabbagh MN (2015) Arizona study of aging and neurodegenerative disorders and brain and body donation program. Neuropathology 35:354&#x2013;389</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25619230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4593391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/neup.12189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wingo TS, Liu Y, Gerasimov ES, Gockley J, Logsdon BA, Duong DM, Dammer EB, Lori A, Kim PJ, Ressler KJ, Beach TG, Reiman EM, Epstein MP, De Jager PL, Lah JJ, Bennett DA, Seyfried NT, Levey AI, Wingo AP (2021) Brain proteome-wide association study implicates novel proteins in depression pathogenesis. Nat Neurosci 24:810&#x2013;817</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33846625</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8530461</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41593-021-00832-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fromer M, Roussos P, Sieberts SK, Johnson JS, Kavanagh DH, Perumal TM, Ruderfer DM, Oh EC, Topol A, Shah HR, Klei LL, Kramer R, Pinto D, G&#xfc;m&#xfc;&#x15f; ZH, Cicek AE, Dang KK, Browne A, Lu C, Xie L, Readhead B, Stahl EA, Xiao J, Parvizi M, Hamamsy T, Fullard JF, Wang YC, Mahajan MC, Derry JM, Dudley JT, Hemby SE, Logsdon BA, Talbot K, Raj T, Bennett DA, De Jager PL, Zhu J, Zhang B, Sullivan PF, Chess A, Purcell SM, Shinobu LA, Mangravite LM, Toyoshiba H, Gur RE, Hahn CG, Lewis DA, Haroutunian V, Peters MA, Lipska BK, Buxbaum JD, Schadt EE, Hirai K, Roeder K, Brennand KJ, Katsanis N, Domenici E, Devlin B, Sklar P (2016) Gene expression elucidates functional impact of polygenic risk for schizophrenia. Nat Neurosci 19:1442&#x2013;1453</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27668389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5083142</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nn.4399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gusev A, Ko A, Shi H, Bhatia G, Chung W, Penninx BW, Jansen R, de Geus EJ, Boomsma DI, Wright FA, Sullivan PF, Nikkola E, Alvarez M, Civelek M, Lusis AJ, Lehtimaki T, Raitoharju E, Kahonen M, Seppala I, Raitakari OT, Kuusisto J, Laakso M, Price AL, Pajukanta P, Pasaniuc B (2016) Integrative approaches for large-scale transcriptome-wide association studies. Nat Genet 48:245&#x2013;252</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26854917</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4767558</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ng.3506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee YH (2020) Overview of mendelian randomization analysis. J Rheum Dis 27(4):241&#x2013;246</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hemani G, Zheng J, Elsworth B, Wade KH, Haberland V, Baird D, Laurin C, Burgess S, Bowden J, Langdon R, Tan VY, Yarmolinsky J, Shihab HA, Timpson NJ, Evans DM, Relton C, Martin RM, Davey Smith G, Gaunt TR, Haycock PC (2018) The MR-Base platform supports systematic causal inference across the human phenome. Elife 7:e34408</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laufman O, Kedan A, Hong W, Lev S (2009) Direct interaction between the COG complex and the SM protein, Sly1, is required for Golgi SNARE pairing. Embo J 28:2006&#x2013;2017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19536132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2718288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/emboj.2009.168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang H, Ouyang Q, Zhu M, Yu H, Mei K, Liu R (2021) mTOR-mediated phosphorylation of VAMP8 and SCFD1 regulates autophagosome maturation. Nat Commun 12:6622</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34785650</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8595342</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-021-26824-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iacoangeli A, Fogh I, Selvackadunco S, Topp SD, Shatunov A, van Rheenen W, Al-Khleifat A, Opie-Martin S, Ratti A, Calvo A, Consortium UKBE, Van Damme P, Robberecht W, Chio A, Dobson RJ, Hardiman O, Shaw CE, van den Berg LH, Andersen PM, Smith BN, Silani V, Veldink JH, Breen G, Troakes C, Al-Chalabi A, Jones AR (2021) SCFD1 expression quantitative trait loci in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis are differentially expressed. Brain Commun 3:fcab236</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34708205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8545614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/braincomms/fcab236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ge YJ, Ou YN, Deng YT, Wu BS, Yang L, Zhang YR, Chen SD, Huang YY, Dong Q, Tan L, Yu JT, International FTDGC (2023) Prioritization of drug targets for neurodegenerative diseases by integrating genetic and proteomic data from brain and blood. Biol Psychiatry 93:770&#x2013;779</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36759259</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biopsych.2022.11.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hou N, Yang Y, Scott IC, Lou X (2017) The Sec domain protein Scfd1 facilitates trafficking of ECM components during chondrogenesis. Dev Biol 421:8&#x2013;15</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27851892</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ydbio.2016.11.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dascher C, Balch WE (1996) Mammalian Sly1 regulates syntaxin 5 function in endoplasmic reticulum to Golgi transport. J Biol Chem 271:15866&#x2013;15869</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8663406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1074/jbc.271.27.15866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borg R, Purkiss A, Cacciottolo R, Herrera P, Cauchi RJ (2023) Loss of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis risk factor SCFD1 causes motor dysfunction in Drosophila. Neurobiol Aging 126:67&#x2013;76</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36944290</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2023.02.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bloom AJ, Mao X, Strickland A, Sasaki Y, Milbrandt J, DiAntonio A (2022) Constitutively active SARM1 variants that induce neuropathy are enriched in ALS patients. Mol Neurodegener 17:1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34991663</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8739729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13024-021-00511-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilley J, Jackson O, Pipis M, Estiar MA, Al-Chalabi A, Danzi MC, van Eijk KR, Goutman SA, Harms MB, Houlden H, Iacoangeli A, Kaye J, Lima L, Queen Square G, Ravits J, Rouleau GA, Schule R, Xu J, Zuchner S, Cooper-Knock J, Gan-Or Z, Reilly MM, Coleman MP (2021) Enrichment of SARM1 alleles encoding variants with constitutively hyperactive NADase in patients with ALS and other motor nerve disorders. Elife 10:e70905</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerdts J, Brace EJ, Sasaki Y, DiAntonio A, Milbrandt J (2015) SARM1 activation triggers axon degeneration locally via NAD(+) destruction. Science 348:453&#x2013;457</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25908823</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4513950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.1258366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fischer LR, Culver DG, Tennant P, Davis AA, Wang M, Castellano-Sanchez A, Khan J, Polak MA, Glass JD (2004) Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis is a distal axonopathy: evidence in mice and man. Exp Neurol 185:232&#x2013;240</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14736504</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.expneurol.2003.10.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kibinge NK, Relton CL, Gaunt TR, Richardson TG (2020) Characterizing the causal pathway for genetic variants associated with neurological phenotypes using human brain-derived proteome data. Am J Hum Genet 106:885&#x2013;892</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32413284</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7273531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ajhg.2020.04.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>White MA, Lin Z, Kim E, Henstridge CM, Pena Altamira E, Hunt CK, Burchill E, Callaghan I, Loreto A, Brown-Wright H, Mead R, Simmons C, Cash D, Coleman MP, Sreedharan J (2019) Sarm1 deletion suppresses TDP-43-linked motor neuron degeneration and cortical spine loss. Acta Neuropathol Commun 7:166</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31661035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6819591</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40478-019-0800-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peters OM, Lewis EA, Osterloh JM, Weiss A, Salameh JS, Metterville J, Brown RH, Freeman MR (2018) Loss of Sarm1 does not suppress motor neuron degeneration in the SOD1G93A mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Hum Mol Genet 27:3761&#x2013;3771</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30010873</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6196650</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/hmg/ddy260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y, Malureanu L, Jeganathan KB, Tran DD, Lindquist LD, van Deursen JM, Bram RJ (2009) CAML loss causes anaphase failure and chromosome missegregation. Cell Cycle 8:940&#x2013;949</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19229138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4161/cc.8.6.7948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tran DD, Russell HR, Sutor SL, van Deursen J, Bram RJ (2003) CAML is required for efficient EGF receptor recycling. Dev Cell 5:245&#x2013;256</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12919676</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1534-5807(03)00207-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan X, Yao J, Norris D, Tran DD, Bram RJ, Chen G, Luscher B (2008) Calcium-modulating cyclophilin ligand regulates membrane trafficking of postsynaptic GABA(A) receptors. Mol Cell Neurosci 38:277&#x2013;289</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18424167</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2350232</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mcn.2008.03.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamamoto Y, Sakisaka T (2012) Molecular machinery for insertion of tail-anchored membrane proteins into the endoplasmic reticulum membrane in mammalian cells. Mol Cell 48:387&#x2013;397</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23041287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.molcel.2012.08.028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farkas &#xc1;, Bohnsack KE (2021) Capture and delivery of tail-anchored proteins to the endoplasmic reticulum. J Cell Biol&#xa0;220(8):e202105004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34264263</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8287540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1083/jcb.202105004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDowell MA, Heimes M, Fiorentino F, Mehmood S, Farkas &#xc1;, Coy-Vergara J, Wu D, Bolla JR, Schmid V, Heinze R, Wild K, Flemming D, Pfeffer S, Schwappach B, Robinson CV, Sinning I (2020) Structural basis of tail-anchored membrane protein biogenesis by the GET insertase complex. Mol Cell 80:72-86.e77</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32910895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.molcel.2020.08.012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pasetto L, Grassano M, Pozzi S, Luotti S, Sammali E, Migazzi A, Basso M, Spagnolli G, Biasini E, Micotti E, Cerovic M, Carli M, Forloni G, De Marco G, Manera U, Moglia C, Mora G, Traynor BJ, Chio A, Calvo A, Bonetto V (2021) Defective cyclophilin A induces TDP-43 proteinopathy: implications for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal dementia. Brain 144:3710&#x2013;3726</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34972208</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8719849</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awab333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao LY, Song J, Liu Y, Song CX, Yi C (2020) Mapping the epigenetic modifications of DNA and RNA. Protein Cell 11:792&#x2013;808</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32440736</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7647981</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13238-020-00733-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao C, Joehanes R, Johnson AD, Huan T, Liu C, Freedman JE, Munson PJ, Hill DE, Vidal M, Levy D (2017) Dynamic role of trans regulation of gene expression in relation to complex traits. Am J Hum Genet 100:571&#x2013;580</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28285768</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5384035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ajhg.2017.02.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burgess S, Davey Smith G, Davies NM, Dudbridge F, Gill D, Glymour MM, Hartwig FP, Holmes MV, Minelli C, Relton CL, Theodoratou E (2019) Guidelines for performing Mendelian randomization investigations. Wellcome Open Res 4:186</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32760811</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12688/wellcomeopenres.15555.1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>