<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37186563</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>17</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1558-2035</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>24</Volume><Issue>Suppl 2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>May</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of cardiovascular medicine (Hagerstown, Md.)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Cardiovasc Med (Hagerstown)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Systematic basic and advanced resuscitation training in medical students and fellows: a proposal from the Working Group on Cardiovascular Urgences and Emergencies of the Italian Society of Cardiology.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e128</StartPage><EndPage>e133</EndPage><MedlinePgn>e128-e133</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2459/JCM.0000000000001421</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Sudden cardiac arrest is a leading cause of death in Europe. High-quality cardiopulmonary resuscitation (CPR) and guidelines compliance of rescuers have been associated with better outcomes after cardiac arrest. However, wide variability in attempting bystander CPR manoeuvres has been reported. Educational programmes for teaching CPR to medical students and fellows are highly advisable in this context. However, there is no homogeneity regarding the CPR education offered by academic institutions. We surveyed 208 Italian medical students and 162 fellows in cardiology regarding the educational offer and needs in CPR. Among the 11 medical schools surveyed, 8 (73%) offer basic (BLS) courses but only 3 (38%) with formal certification of 'BLS provider', while none offers advanced (ACLS/ALS) courses. Among the 30 specialization schools in cardiology surveyed, 10 (33%) offer a BLS course (6 with formal certification of 'BLS provider'), and 8 (27%) offer an ACLS/ALS course (5 with formal certification). Only a minority of students and fellows perceive themselves as highly proficient either in BLS or ACLS/ALS, although most of the fellows were involved at least once in rescuing a cardiac arrest. The present position paper analyses and suggests the strategies that should be adopted by Italian medical and specialization schools to spread the CPR culture and increase the long-standing retention of CPR-related technical and nontechnical skills.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022 Italian Federation of Cardiology - I.F.C. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saba</LastName><ForeName>Pier Sergio</ForeName><Initials>PS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical and Interventional Cardiology, Azienda Ospedaliero-Universitaria di Sassari, Sassari.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Canonico</LastName><ForeName>Mario Enrico</ForeName><Initials>ME</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Advanced Biomedical Sciences, University of Naples Federico II, Naples.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gambaro</LastName><ForeName>Alessia</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Azienda Ospedaliera Universitaria di Verona, Verona.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gazale</LastName><ForeName>Giovanni</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Sports Medicine and Cardiology- Azienda Sanitaria Locale 1, Sassari.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Piga</LastName><ForeName>Stefania</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pediatric Cardiology, Azienda Ospedaliero-Universitaria di Sassari, Sassari.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Santomauro</LastName><ForeName>Maurizio</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Advanced Biomedical Sciences, University of Naples Federico II, Naples.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Roscio</LastName><ForeName>Giancarlo</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical, Internal, Anesthesiologic and Cardiovascular Sciences, University of Rome Sapienza, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><CollectiveName>Working Group on Cardiovascular Urgences, Emergencies of the Italian Society of Cardiology</CollectiveName></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Cardiovasc Med (Hagerstown)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101259752</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1558-2027</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016887" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cardiopulmonary Resuscitation</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000193" MajorTopicYN="N">education</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013337" MajorTopicYN="Y">Students, Medical</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004630" MajorTopicYN="N">Emergencies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006323" MajorTopicYN="Y">Heart Arrest</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007558" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Italy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002309" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cardiology</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37186563</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2459/JCM.0000000000001421</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">01244665-202305002-00005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Gr&#xe4;sner J-T, Herlitz J, Tjelmeland IBM, et al. European Resuscitation Council Guidelines 2021: epidemiology of cardiac arrest in Europe. Resuscitation 2021; 161:61&#x2013;79.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiguchi T, Okubo M, Nishiyama C, et al. Out-of-hospital cardiac arrest across the World: first report from the International Liaison Committee on Resuscitation (ILCOR). Resuscitation 2020; 152:39&#x2013;49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gr&#xe4;sner J-T, Lefering R, Koster RW, et al. EuReCa ONE-27 Nations, ONE Europe, ONE Registry: a prospective one month analysis of out-of-hospital cardiac arrest outcomes in 27 countries in Europe. Resuscitation 2016; 105:188&#x2013;195.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheskes S, Schmicker RH, Rea T, et al. The association between AHA CPR quality guideline compliance and clinical outcomes from out-of-hospital cardiac arrest. Resuscitation 2017; 116:39&#x2013;45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Son JW, Ryoo HW, Moon S, et al. Association between public cardiopulmonary resuscitation education and the willingness to perform bystander cardiopulmonary resuscitation: a metropolitan citywide survey. Clin Exp Emerg Med 2017; 4:80&#x2013;87.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wissenberg M, Lippert FK, Folke F, et al. Association of national initiatives to improve cardiac arrest management with rates of bystander intervention and patient survival after out-of-hospital cardiac arrest. JAMA 2013; 310:1377&#x2013;1384.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vetter VL, Griffis H, Dalldorf KF, et al. Impact of state laws: CPR education in high schools. J Am Coll Cardiol 2022; 79:2140&#x2013;2143.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cernuda Mart&#xed;nez JA, Castro Delgado R, Ferrero Fern&#xe1;ndez E, Arcos Gonz&#xe1;lez P. Self-perception of theoretical knowledge and practical skills by primary healthcare physicians in life-threatening emergencies. Prehosp Disaster Med 2018; 33:508&#x2013;518.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baldi E, Contri E, Bailoni A, et al. Final-year medical students&#x2019; knowledge of cardiac arrest and CPR: we must do more!. Int J Cardiol 2019; 296:76&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baldi E, Savastano S, Contri E, et al. Mandatory cardiopulmonary resuscitation competencies for undergraduate healthcare students in Europe. Eur J Anaesthesiol 2020; 37:839&#x2013;841.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conferenza permanente dei presidenti dei CLM di Medicina e Chirurgia. Core curriculum. 2018. http://presidenti-medicina.it/core-curriculum/ . [Accessed 13 October 2022].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Czerwi&#x144;ska-Jelonkiewicz K, Montero S, Ba&#xf1;eras J, et al. Current status and needs for changes in critical care training: the voice of the young cardiologists. Eur Heart J Acute Cardiovasc Care 2021; 10:94&#x2013;101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roppolo LP, Heymann R, Pepe P, et al. A randomized controlled trial comparing traditional training in cardiopulmonary resuscitation (CPR) to self-directed CPR learning in first year medical students: the two-person CPR study. Resuscitation 2011; 82:319&#x2013;325.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jauregui J, Bright S, Strote J, Shandro J. A novel approach to medical student peer-assisted learning through case-based simulations. West J Emerg Med 2018; 19:193&#x2013;197.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Topping K, Ehly S. Peer-assisted learning. New York: Routledge; 1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wadoodi A, Crosby JR. Twelve tips for peer-assisted learning: a classic concept revisited. Med Teacher 2002; 24:241&#x2013;244.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panchal AR, Norton G, Gibbons E, Buehler J, Kurz MC. Low dose- high frequency, case based psychomotor CPR training improves compression fraction for patients with in-hospital cardiac arrest. Resuscitation 2020; 146:26&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCoy CE, Rahman A, Rendon JC, et al. Randomized controlled trial of simulation vs. standard training for teaching medical students high-quality cardiopulmonary resuscitation. West J Emerg Med 2019; 20:15&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langdorf MI, Strom SL, Yang L, et al. High-fidelity simulation enhances ACLS training. Teaching Learn Med 2014; 26:266&#x2013;273.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berger C, Brinkrolf P, Ertmer C, et al. Combination of problem-based learning with high-fidelity simulation in CPR training improves short and long-term CPR skills: a randomised single blinded trial. BMC Med Educ 2019; 19:180.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blanco MA, Maderer A, Oriel A, Epstein SK. How we launched a developmental student-as-teacher (SAT) program for all medical students. Med Teacher 2014; 36:385&#x2013;389.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veloso SG, Pereira GS, Vasconcelos NN, Senger MH, de Faria RMD. Learning by teaching basic life support: a nonrandomized controlled trial with medical students. BMC Med Educ 2019; 19:67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flin R, O&#x2019;Connor P. Safety at the sharp end: a guide to nontechnical skills. London: CRC Press; 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Institute of Medicine (US) Committee on Quality of Health Care in America. To Err is Human: Building a Safer Health System. Kohn LT, Corrigan JM, Donaldson MS, editors. Washington (DC): National Academies Press (US); 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hull L, Arora S, Aggarwal R, Darzi A, Vincent C, Sevdalis N. The impact of nontechnical skills on technical performance in surgery: a systematic review. J Am Coll Surg 2012; 214:214&#x2013;230.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson PS, Shall E, Rakhit R. Cardiac arrest leadership: in need of resuscitation? Postgrad Med J 2016; 92:715&#x2013;720.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casali G, Lock G, Novoa NM. Teaching nontechnical skills: the patient centered approach. J Thorac Dis 2021; 13:2044&#x2013;2053.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon M, Darbyshire D, Baker P. Nontechnical skills training to enhance patient safety: a systematic review. Med Educ 2012; 46:1042&#x2013;1054.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ounounou E, Aydin A, Brunckhorst O, Khan MS, Dasgupta P, Ahmed K. Nontechnical skills in surgery: a systematic review of current training modalities. J Surg Educ 2019; 76:14&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lynch A. Simulation-based acquisition of nontechnical skills to improve patient safety. Semin Pediatr Surg 2020; 29:150906&#x2013;1150906.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lei C, Palm K. Crisis resource management training in medical simulation. 2022. https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK551708/ . [Accessed 13 October 2022].</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>