<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37209406</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>08</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1468-1331</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>30</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Diagnostic delay in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2595</StartPage><EndPage>2601</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2595-2601</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/ene.15874</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) is a progressive, fatal neurodegenerative disease, and the time from symptom onset to diagnosis remains long. With the advent of disease-modifying treatments, the need to identify and diagnose ALS in a timely fashion has never been greater.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">We reviewed the literature to define the severity of ALS diagnostic delay, the various factors that contribute to this delay (including patient and physician factors), and the role that site of symptom onset plays in a patient's diagnostic journey.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Diagnostic delay is influenced by general practitioners' lack of recognition of ALS due to disease rarity and heterogenous presentations. As a result, patients are referred to non-neurologists, have unnecessary diagnostic testing, and may ultimately be misdiagnosed. Patient factors include their illness behavior-which impacts diagnostic delay-and their site of symptom onset. Limb-onset patients have the greatest diagnostic delay because they are frequently misdiagnosed with degenerative spine disease or peripheral neuropathy.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">Prompt ALS diagnosis results in more effective clinical management, with earlier access to disease-modifying therapies, multidisciplinary care, and, if desired, clinical trial involvement. Due to lack of commercially available ALS biomarkers, alternative strategies to identify and triage patients who likely have ALS must be employed. Several diagnostic tools have been developed to encourage general practitioners to consider ALS and make an urgent referral to ALS specialists, bypassing unnecessary referrals to non-neurologists and unnecessary diagnostic workup.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Authors. European Journal of Neurology published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of European Academy of Neurology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gwathmey</LastName><ForeName>Kelly G</ForeName><Initials>KG</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7589-8826</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Virginia Commonwealth University, Richmond, Virginia, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Corcia</LastName><ForeName>Philippe</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1625-8845</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>CRMR SLA, CHU Tours, Tours, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>UMR1253 iBrain UMR, Universit&#xe9; de Tours, INSERM, Tours, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McDermott</LastName><ForeName>Chris J</ForeName><Initials>CJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1269-9053</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience, Sheffield Institute for Translational Neuroscience, University of Sheffield, Sheffield, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Genge</LastName><ForeName>Angela</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5587-9946</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery, McGill University, Montreal, Quebec, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sennf&#xe4;lt</LastName><ForeName>Stefan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7114-2757</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Karolinska University Hospital, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Neuroscience, Karolinska Institutet, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>de Carvalho</LastName><ForeName>Mamede</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7556-0158</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Physiology, Instituto de Medicina Molecular Jo&#xe3;o Lobo Antunes, Centro de Estudos Egas Moniz, Faculdade de Medicina, Universidade de Lisboa, Lisbon, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosciences and Mental Health, Hospital de Santa Maria, Centro Hospitalar Universit&#xe1;rio de Lisboa-Norte, Lisbon, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ingre</LastName><ForeName>Caroline</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5327-7204</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Karolinska University Hospital, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Neuroscience, Karolinska Institutet, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Acronym>DH_</Acronym><Agency>Department of Health</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9506311</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1351-5101</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057210" MajorTopicYN="N">Delayed Diagnosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019636" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neurodegenerative Diseases</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058005" MajorTopicYN="Y">General Practitioners</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">delayed diagnosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic errors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">motor neurone disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neurodegenerative diseases</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37209406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ene.15874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Richards D, Morren JA, Pioro EP. Time to diagnosis and factors affecting diagnostic delay in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Sci. 2020;417:117054. doi:10.1016/j.jns.2020.117054</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roche JC, Rojas-Garcia R, Scott KM, et al. A proposed staging system for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain J Neurol. 2012;135(pt 3):847-852. doi:10.1093/brain/awr351</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ackrivo J, Hansen-Flaschen J, Wileyto EP, Schwab RJ, Elman L, Kawut SM. Development of a prognostic model of respiratory insufficiency or death in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Eur Respir J. 2019;53(4):1802237. doi:10.1183/13993003.02237-2018</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2; A. ISIS survey: an international study on the diagnostic process and its implications in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol. 1999;246(suppl 3):III1-III5, III5. doi:10.1007/BF03161081</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Househam E, Swash M. Diagnostic delay in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: what scope for improvement? J Neurol Sci. 2000;180(1-2):76-81. doi:10.1016/s0022-510x(00)00418-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paganoni S, Macklin EA, Lee A, et al. Diagnostic timelines and delays in diagnosing amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2014;15(5-6):453-456. doi:10.3109/21678421.2014.903974</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khishchenko N, Allen KD, Coffman CJ, et al. Time to diagnosis in the National Registry of veterans with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2010;11(1-2):125-132. doi:10.3109/17482960802572681</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zoccolella S, Beghi E, Palagano G, et al. Predictors of delay in the diagnosis and clinical trial entry of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients: a population-based study. J Neurol Sci. 2006;250(1-2):45-49. doi:10.1016/j.jns.2006.06.027</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer M, Buerger M, Berlit P. Diagnostic problems and delay of diagnosis in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Neurol Neurosurg. 2010;112(2):103-105. doi:10.1016/j.clineuro.2009.10.014</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nzwalo H, de Abreu D, Swash M, Pinto S, de Carvalho M. Delayed diagnosis in ALS: the problem continues. J Neurol Sci. 2014;343(1-2):173-175. doi:10.1016/j.jns.2014.06.003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donaghy C, Dick A, Hardiman O, Patterson V. Timeliness of diagnosis in motor neurone disease: a population-based study. Ulster Med J. 2008;77(1):18-21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Falc&#xe3;o de Campos C, Gromicho M, Uysal H, et al. Delayed diagnosis and diagnostic pathway of ALS patients in Portugal: where can we improve? Front Neurol. 2021;12:761355. doi:10.3389/fneur.2021.761355</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;nez-Molina M, Argente-Escrig H, Polo MF, et al. Early referral to an ALS center reduces several months the diagnostic delay: a multicenter-based study. Front Neurol. 2020;11:604922. doi:10.3389/fneur.2020.604922</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calvo A, Moglia C, Lunetta C, et al. Factors predicting survival in ALS: a multicenter Italian study. J Neurol. 2017;264(1):54-63. doi:10.1007/s00415-016-8313-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palese F, Sartori A, Logroscino G, Pisa FE. Predictors of diagnostic delay in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a cohort study based on administrative and electronic medical records data. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2019;20(3-4):176-185. doi:10.1080/21678421.2018.1550517</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell JD, Callagher P, Gardham J, et al. Timelines in the diagnostic evaluation of people with suspected amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS)/motor neuron disease (MND)-a 20-year review: can we do better? Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2010;11(6):537-541. doi:10.3109/17482968.2010.495158</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armstrong MD, Hansen G, Schellenberg KL. Rural residence and diagnostic delay for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in Saskatchewan. Can J Neurol Sci. 2020;47(4):538-542. doi:10.1017/cjn.2020.38</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belsh JM, Schiffman PL. The amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) patient perspective on misdiagnosis and its repercussions. J Neurol Sci. 1996;139(suppl):110-116. doi:10.1016/0022-510x(96)00088-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cellura E, Spataro R, Taiello AC, La Bella V. Factors affecting the diagnostic delay in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Neurol Neurosurg. 2012;114(6):550-554. doi:10.1016/j.clineuro.2011.11.026</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galvin M, Ryan P, Maguire S, et al. The path to specialist multidisciplinary care in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a population-based study of consultations, interventions and costs. PLoS One. 2017;12(6):e0179796. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0179796</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sirri L, Fava GA, Sonino N. The unifying concept of illness behavior. Psychother Psychosom. 2013;82(2):74-81. doi:10.1159/000343508</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baxter S, McDermott CJ. Decision-making and referral processes for patients with motor neurone disease: a qualitative study of GP experiences and evaluation of a new decision-support tool. BMC Health Serv Res. 2017;17(1):339. doi:10.1186/s12913-017-2286-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner MR, Scaber J, Goodfellow JA, Lord ME, Marsden R, Talbot K. The diagnostic pathway and prognosis in bulbar-onset amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Sci. 2010;294(1-2):81-85. doi:10.1016/j.jns.2010.03.028</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belsh JM, Schiffman PL. Misdiagnosis in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Arch Intern Med. 1990;150(11):2301-2305.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>V&#xe1;zquez-Costa JF, Mart&#xed;nez-Molina M, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Polo M, Forn&#xe9;s-Ferrer V, Frasquet-Carrera M, Sevilla-Mantec&#xf3;n T. An&#xe1;lisis del trayecto y retraso diagn&#xf3;stico de los pacientes con esclerosis lateral amiotr&#xf3;fica en la Comunidad Valenciana. Neurologia. 2021;36(7):504-513. doi:10.1016/j.nrl.2018.03.026</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kano O, Iwamoto K, Ito H, et al. Limb-onset amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients visiting orthopedist show a longer time-to-diagnosis since symptom onset. BMC Neurol. 2013;13:19. doi:10.1186/1471-2377-13-19</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rocchetti I, Taruscio D, Pierannunzio D. Modeling delay to diagnosis for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: under reporting and incidence estimates. BMC Neurol. 2012;12(1):160. doi:10.1186/1471-2377-12-160</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zoccolella S, Beghi E, Palagano G, et al. Predictors of long survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a population-based study. J Neurol Sci. 2008;268(1-2):28-32. doi:10.1016/j.jns.2007.10.023</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westeneng HJ, Debray TPA, Visser AE, et al. Prognosis for patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: development and validation of a personalised prediction model. Lancet Neurol. 2018;17(5):423-433. doi:10.1016/S1474-4422(18)30089-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haverkamp LJ, Appel V, Appel SH. Natural history of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in a database population. Validation of a scoring system and a model for survival prediction. Brain. J Neurol. 1995;118(pt 3):707-719. doi:10.1093/brain/118.3.707</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christensen PB, H&#xf8;jer-Pedersen E, Jensen MDNB. Survival of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in 2 Danish counties. Neurology. 1990;40(4):600-604. doi:10.1212/WNL.40.4.600</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belsh JM. Diagnostic challenges in ALS. Neurology. 1999;53(8 suppl 5):S26-S30. discussion S35-S36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young CA, Ealing J, McDermott C, et al. The relationships between symptoms, disability, perceived health and quality of life in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis/motor neuron disease. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2019;20(5-6):317-327. doi:10.1080/21678421.2019.1615951</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desport JC, Preux PM, Truong TC, Vallat JM, Sautereau D, Couratier P. Nutritional status is a prognostic factor for survival in ALS patients. Neurology. 1999;53(5):1059. doi:10.1212/WNL.53.5.1059</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jawaid A, Murthy SB, Wilson AM, et al. A decrease in body mass index is associated with faster progression of motor symptoms and shorter survival in ALS. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2010;11(6):542-548. doi:10.3109/17482968.2010.482592</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marin B, Desport JC, Kajeu P, et al. Alteration of nutritional status at diagnosis is a prognostic factor for survival of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2011;82(6):628-634. doi:10.1136/jnnp.2010.211474</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paganoni S, Deng J, Jaffa M, Cudkowicz ME, Wills AM. Body mass index, not dyslipidemia, is an independent predictor of survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: body mass index predicts survival in ALS. Muscle Nerve. 2011;44(1):20-24. doi:10.1002/mus.22114</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The EFNS Task Force on Diagnosis and Management of Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis, Andersen PM, Abrahams S, et al. EFNS guidelines on the clinical management of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (MALS)-revised report of an EFNS task force. Eur J Neurol. 2012;19(3):360-375. doi:10.1111/j.1468-1331.2011.03501.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spataro R, Ficano L, Piccoli F, La Bella V. Percutaneous endoscopic gastrostomy in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: effect on survival. J Neurol Sci. 2011;304(1-2):44-48. doi:10.1016/j.jns.2011.02.016</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fasano A, Fini N, Ferraro D, et al. Percutaneous endoscopic gastrostomy, body weight loss and survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a population-based registry study. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2017;18(3-4):233-242. doi:10.1080/21678421.2016.1270325</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burkhardt C, Neuwirth C, Sommacal A, Andersen PM, Weber M. Is survival improved by the use of NIV and PEG in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS)? A post-mortem study of 80 ALS patients. PLoS One. 2017;12(5):e0177555. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0177555</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vergonjeanne M, Fayemendy P, Marin B, et al. Predictive factors for gastrostomy at time of diagnosis and impact on survival in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Nutr. 2020;39(10):3112-3118. doi:10.1016/j.clnu.2020.01.018</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiernan MC, Vucic S, Cheah BC, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet. 2011;377(9769):942-955. doi:10.1016/S0140-6736(10)61156-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sennf&#xe4;lt S, Kl&#xe4;ppe U, Thams S, et al. The path to diagnosis in ALS: delay, referrals, alternate diagnoses, and clinical progression. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2023;24(1-2):45-53. doi:10.1080/21678421.2022.2053722</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galvin M, Madden C, Maguire S, et al. Patient journey to a specialist amyotrophic lateral sclerosis multidisciplinary clinic: an exploratory study. BMC Health Serv Res. 2015;15:571. doi:10.1186/s12913-015-1229-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matharan M, Mathis S, Bonabaud S, Carla L, Soulages A, Le Masson G. Minimizing the diagnostic delay in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: the role of nonneurologist practitioners. Neurol Res Int. 2020;2020:1473981. doi:10.1155/2020/1473981</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner MR, Talbot K. Mimics and chameleons in motor neurone disease. Pract Neurol. 2013;13(3):153-164. doi:10.1136/practneurol-2013-000557</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshor D, Klugh A, Appel SH, Haverkamp LJ. Incidence and characteristics of spinal decompression surgery after the onset of symptoms of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurosurgery. 2005;57(5):984-989; discussion 984-989. doi:10.1227/01.neu.0000180028.64385.d3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Srinivasan J, Scala S, Jones HR, Saleh F, Russell JA. Inappropriate surgeries resulting from misdiagnosis of early amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 2006;34(3):359-360. doi:10.1002/mus.20555</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamada M, Furukawa Y, Hirohata M. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: frequent complications by cervical spondylosis. J Orthop Sci. 2003;8(6):878-881. doi:10.1007/s00776-003-0712-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nightingale S, Bates D, Bateman DE, Hudgson P, Ellis DA, Gibson GJ. Enigmatic dyspnoea: an unusual presentation of motor-neurone disease. Lancet. 1982;1(8278):933-935. doi:10.1016/s0140-6736(82)91934-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Shaikh B, Kinnear W, Higenbottam TW, Smith HS, Shneerson JM, Wilkinson I. Motor neurone disease presenting as respiratory failure. Br Med J (Clin Res Ed). 1986;292(6531):1325-1326. doi:10.1136/bmj.292.6531.1325</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shoesmith CL, Findlater K, Rowe A, Strong MJ. Prognosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with respiratory onset. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2007;78(6):629-631. doi:10.1136/jnnp.2006.103564</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gautier G, Verschueren A, Monnier A, Attarian S, Salort-Campana E, Pouget J. ALS with respiratory onset: clinical features and effects of non-invasive ventilation on the prognosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2010;11(4):379-382. doi:10.3109/17482960903426543</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinto S, Gromicho M, Oliveira Santos MO, Swash M, De Carvalho M. Respiratory onset in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: clinical features and spreading pattern. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2022;5:1-5. doi:10.1080/21678421.2022.2067777</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuisma MJ, Saarinen KV, Teirmaa HT. Undiagnosed amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and respiratory failure. Acta Anaesthesiol Scand. 1993;37(6):628-630. doi:10.1111/j.1399-6576.1993.tb03778.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Matias T, Coelho F, Evangelista T, Pinto A, Lu&#xed;s ML. Motor neuron disease presenting with respiratory failure. J Neurol Sci. 1996;139(suppl):117-122. doi:10.1016/0022-510x(96)00089-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drain JP, Virk SS, Jain N, Yu E. Dropped head syndrome: a systematic review. Clin Spine Surg. 2019;32(10):423-429. doi:10.1097/BSD.0000000000000811</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waclawik AJ, Lotz BP, Beinlich BR, Brooks BR. Dropped head syndrome. Neurology. 1997;48(2):550-551; author reply 551-552. doi:10.1212/wnl.48.2.550-b</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Falc&#xe3;o de Campos C, Gromicho M, Uysal H, et al. Trends in the diagnostic delay and pathway for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients across different countries. Front Neurol. 2023;13:1064619. doi:10.3389/fneur.2022.1064619</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinto S, Swash M, de Carvalho M. Does surgery accelerate progression of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis? J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2014;85(6):643-646. doi:10.1136/jnnp-2013-305770</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shefner JM, Al-Chalabi A, Baker MR, et al. A proposal for new diagnostic criteria for ALS. Clin Neurophysiol. 2020;131(8):1975-1978. doi:10.1016/j.clinph.2020.04.005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2; A, Bottacchi E, Buffa C, Mutani R, Mora G, PARALS. Positive effects of tertiary centres for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis on outcome and use of hospital facilities. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2006;77(8):948-950. doi:10.1136/jnnp.2005.083402</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yersak J, Birhane S, Heiman-Patterson T, Lomen-Hoerth C, Oskarrson B, Babu S. CMS-03 ThinkALS: a user-friendly and comprehensive ALS diagnosis and referral tool for general neurologists. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Front Degener. 2021;22(suppl 2):202-233. doi:10.1080/21678421.2021.1985802</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ThinkALS. The ALS Association. Accessed January 27, 2023. https://www.als.org/thinkals.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Red Flag Diagnosis Tool. MND Association. Accessed January 27, 2023. https://www.mndassociation.org/professionals/management-of-mnd/management-by-specific-professions/information-for-gps/red-flag-diagnosis-tool/. Published November 2, 2022.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>