<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37200320</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>22</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1932-6203</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PloS one</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PLoS One</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Prevention of modern slavery within sex work: Study protocol of a mixed methods project looking at the role of adult services websites.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e0285829</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e0285829</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e0285829</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1371/journal.pone.0285829</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">The core challenge this study addressed is that Adult Services Websites (ASWs) are an extensive and pervasive feature of the digital world that facilitate the advertising, negotiation and purchase of sexual services yet are also considered to be harbourers of sexual exploitation, modern slavery and human trafficking (MSHT) Giommoni L. et al. 2021, Milivojevic S. et al. 2020, Sanders, T., et al. 2018. Whilst awareness of cases of internet facilitated MSHT has entered the public and policy domain, little is known about the role and responsibilities of ASWs in this domain. Collaboratively with our partners, the findings from this study will first contribute to understanding how ASWs facilitate exploitation and second how they can become part of the prevention mechanisms and reporters of crimes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">We present the design of our mixed methods study, underpinned by a peer Action Learning Set (ALS) approach. By working closely with ten survivors of sexual exploitation from 7 countries, the peer group have informed the study through participation in the advisory group, instrument design, implementation, analysis and dissemination. A training and support needs analysis prior to engagement in the research project ascertained what skills people would bring, what they would need for further personal and career development and if there were any additional requirements to enable participation. We provided capacity building through a bespoke training package over the project's lifetime.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION">Conducting a peer-researcher ALS project informs the research topic by both empowering survivors of sexual exploitation, whilst engaging with their expertise and lived experience to shape the methods and focus. The summative evaluation of our methods informs wider peer research methodologies, little utilised in the field of MSHT research. Thus, this research produces evidence which acknowledges survivors as experts with value towards social science research.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2023 Keighley, Sanders. This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Keighley</LastName><ForeName>Rachel</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5245-933X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Criminology, University of Leicester, Leicester, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sanders</LastName><ForeName>Teela</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6392-6896</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Criminology, University of Leicester, Leicester, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PLoS One</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101285081</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1932-6203</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011477" MajorTopicYN="N">Sex Work</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D063947" MajorTopicYN="Y">Enslavement</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009790" MajorTopicYN="N">Occupations</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003415" MajorTopicYN="N">Crime</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37200320</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10194949</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0285829</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PONE-D-22-30647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Lanau A, Matolcsi A. Prostitution and sex work, who counts? Mapping local data to inform policy and service provision. Social Policy and Society. 2022. Apr 8:1&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poster WR. Data Battles, Platform Shutdowns, and Digital Rights in Surveillance: Labor Politics in the Online Sex Industry. Louis ULJ. 2020;65:169.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanders T., Scoular J., Campbell R., Pitcher J. and Cunningham S., 2018. Internet Sex Work: Beyond the Gaze. Palgrave Macmillan.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardy K, Barbagallo C. Hustling the Platform: Capitalist Experiments and Resistance in the Digital Sex Industry. South Atlantic Quarterly. 2021. Jul 1;120(3):533&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Home Office. 2021. UK Annual Report on Modern Slavery. London: Home Office. 2021</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>OSCE. Policy responses to technology-facilitated trafficking in human beings. Analysis of current approaches and considerations moving forward. OSCE: Office of the Special Representative and Co-ordinator for Combating Trafficking in Human Beings; 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milivojevic S, Moore H, Segrave M. Freeing the Modern Slaves, One Click at a Time: Theorising human trafficking, modern slavery, and technology. Anti-trafficking review. 2020. Apr 27(14):16&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skidmore M, Garner S, Desroches C, Saggu N. The threat of exploitation in the adult sex market: A pilot study of online sex worker advertisements. Policing: A Journal of Policy and Practice. 2018. Jun 1;12(2):210&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Online Safety Bill. London: HMSO; 2022. [internet] Available at: https://publications.parliament.uk/pa/bills/cbill/58-02/0285/210285.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DCMS (Department for Digital, Culture, Media &amp; Sport). Consultation on reviewing the regulatory framework for online advertising in the UK: The Online Advertising Programme [Internet].
London: DCMS; 2022. Available from: https://assets.publishing.service.gov.uk/government/uploads/system/uploads/attachment_data/file/1080608/20220601_Online_Advertising_Programme_Impact_Assessment_PUB_v2.docx.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prostitutescollective.net. Action Alert: Online Safety Bill&#x2013;Criminalising sex workers&#x2019; online adverts would undermine safety!. [Internet]. 2022 [cited 14 October 2022];. Available from: https://prostitutescollective.net/urgent-call-to-action-online-safety-bill/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oppenheim M.
Violence against sex workers will surge under new online safety bill, campaigners warn.
Independent [Internet].
2022.  [cited 21 June 2022];. Available from: https://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/home-news/sex-workers-online-safety-bill-b2039044.html</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scoular J, Pitcher J, Sanders T, Campbell R, Cunningham S. Beyond the gaze and well beyond Wolfenden: The practices and rationalities of regulating and policing sex work in the digital age. Journal of law and society. 2019. Jun;46(2):211&#x2013;39. doi: 10.1111/jols.12155</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jols.12155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donelan M.
Online Safety Update. DCMS; 2023. 
January
17. [cited 16 February 2023]. Available from: https://questions-statements.parliament.uk/written-statements/detail/2023-01-17/hcws500</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vajzovic D.
National Policing Sex Work and Prostitution Guidance [Internet].
Cambridgeshire Police: NPCC; 2022. Available from: https://library.college.police.uk/docs/appref/Sex-Work-and-Prostitution-Guidance-Jan-2019.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cunningham S, Sanders T, Scoular J, Campbell R, Pitcher J, Hill K, Valentine-Chase M, Melissa C, Aydin Y, Hamer R. Behind the screen: Commercial sex, digital spaces and working online. Technology in society. 2018. May 31;53:47&#x2013;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benoit C, Unsworth R, Healey P, Smith M, Jansson M. Centering sex workers&#x2019; voices in law and social policy. Sexuality Research and Social Policy. 2021. Dec;18(4):897&#x2013;908.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giommoni L, Ikwu R. Identifying human trafficking indicators in the UK online sex market. Trends in Organized Crime. 2021. Sep 17:1&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>House of Commons. Regulating online harms. London: House of Commons Library. 2022</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferris S, Lebovitch A, Allard D. Sex work research, ethics review processes, and institutional challenges for &#x201c;sensitive&#x201d; collaborative research. International Journal of Qualitative Methods. 2021. Oct 9;20:1&#x2013;12. doi: 10.1177/16094069211033437</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/16094069211033437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>UKRI. Citizen Science Exploration Grant&#x2014;UK Research and Innovation [ARCHIVED CONTENT]. The National Archives; 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lushey C. Peer research methodology: Challenges and solutions. SAGE Publications Ltd; 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuber-Skerritt O. An educational framework for participatory action learning and action research (PALAR). Educational Action Research. 2018. Aug 8;26(4):513&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuber-Skerritt O. Participatory action learning and action research (PALAR) for community engagement: A theoretical framework. Educational research for social change. 2015. Apr 1;4(1):5&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bawden R., and Williams M. The Learning Conference and Worldview Transformations. In Zuber-Skerritt O, editor. Conferences as sites of learning and development: Using participatory action learning and action research approaches. Taylor &amp; Francis; 2017. Feb 24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lushey CJ, Munro ER. Participatory peer research methodology: An effective method for obtaining young people&#x2019;s perspectives on transitions from care to adulthood?. Qualitative Social Work. 2015. Jul;14(4):522&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shier H. &#x2018;Pathways to participation&#x2019; revisited: learning from Nicaragua&#x2019;s child coffee-workers. In A handbook of children and young people&#x2019;s participation 2009. Sep 10 (pp. 237&#x2013;251). Routledge.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Attride-Stirling J. Thematic networks: an analytic tool for qualitative research. Qualitative research. 2001. Dec;1(3):385&#x2013;405.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toulmin SE. The uses of argument. Cambridge university press; 2003. Jul 7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kearney J, Wood L, Zuber-Skerritt O. Community-university partnerships: Using participatory action learning and action research (PALAR). Gateways: International Journal of Community Research and Engagement. 2013. Jan;6:113&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>