<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37219865</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>25</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1537-1611</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>24</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jun</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of clinical neuromuscular disease</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Clin Neuromuscul Dis</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Clenbuterol Treatment Is Safe and Associated With Slowed Disease Progression in a Small Open-Label Trial in Patients With Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>214</StartPage><EndPage>221</EndPage><MedlinePgn>214-221</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/CND.0000000000000438</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Clenbuterol, a beta-agonist, has plausible mechanisms for treating amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). In this highly inclusive open-label trial (NCT04245709), we aimed to study the safety and efficacy of clenbuterol in patients with ALS.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">All participants received clenbuterol starting at 40 &#x3bc;g daily and increased to 80 &#x3bc;g twice daily. Outcomes included safety, tolerability, ALS Functional Rating Score (ALSFRS-R) progression, forced vital capacity (FVC) progression, and myometry. ALSFRS-R and FVC slopes measured during treatment were compared with slopes before treatment (calculated by assuming ALSFRS-R was 48 and FVC was 100% at ALS onset).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The 25 participants had a mean age of 59, mean disease duration of 43 months, ALSFRS-R score at enrollment 34, and FVC at enrollment 77%. Forty-eight percent were female, 68% were taking riluzole, and none were taking edaravone. Two participants experienced severe adverse events, neither related to the study. Twenty-four participants experienced adverse events, most commonly tremors/jitters, cramps/spasms, insomnia, and stiffness/spasticity. Fourteen participants withdrew early from the trial, 13 due to adverse events. Patients who withdrew early were significantly older and more likely to be male. Per-protocol and intention-to-treat analyses showed meaningfully slower ALSFRS-R and FVC progression during treatment. Hand grip dynamometry and myometry changes were highly variable between participants; most declined slowly, but some showed improvements.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Clenbuterol was safe but less tolerable at the doses we selected compared with an earlier Italian case series. Consistent with that series, our study suggested benefits on ALS progression. However, the latter result should be interpreted with caution as our study is limited by small sample size, large drop out, lack of randomization, and blinding and placebo controls. A larger, more traditional trial now seems warranted.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 The Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Xiaoyan</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departments of Neurology and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Koeberl</LastName><ForeName>Dwight D</ForeName><Initials>DD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pediatrics, Duke University, Durham, NC.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lutz</LastName><ForeName>Michael W</ForeName><Initials>MW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departments of Neurology and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bedlack</LastName><ForeName>Richard</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departments of Neurology and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Clin Neuromuscul Dis</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100887391</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1522-0443</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>XTZ6AXU7KN</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D002976">Clenbuterol</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>7LJ087RS6F</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D019782">Riluzole</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002976" MajorTopicYN="Y">Clenbuterol</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018737" MajorTopicYN="N">Hand Strength</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019782" MajorTopicYN="N">Riluzole</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018450" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Progression</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>Supported by donations from one patient's family for which we are grateful. X. Li and M. W. Lutz report no conflict of interest. R. Bedlack has research support from: ALS Association, Healey, MediciNova, Orion. He has received consulting fees from AB Science, Alexion, ALS Association, Amylyx, Apellis, Biogen, Brainstorm Cell, Clene, Corcept, Cytokinetics, Guidepoint, Mallinkrodt, MT Pharma, New Biotic, Orphazyme, Shinkei, UCB Pharma, and Woolsey Pharma. D. D. Koeberl and Duke University might benefit financially, if the experimental treatments discussed here prove effective and are successful commercially. D. D. Koeberl has served as a consultant for Sangamo Therapeutics, Genzyme Sanofi, Amicus, Takeda, Askbio, and Vertex. He has received grant support from Sangamo Therapeutics, Pharming, Viking Therapeutics, Genzyme Sanofi, Roivant Rare Diseases, and Amicus. He has held equity in AskBio, which is developing gene therapy for rare diseases, including Pompe disease.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37219865</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/CND.0000000000000438</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00131402-202306000-00005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Whitsett TL, Manion CV, Wilson MF. Cardiac, pulmonary and neuromuscular effects of clenbuterol and terbutaline compared with placebo. Br J Clin Pharmacol. 1981;12:195&#x2013;200.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Gioacchino M, Mezzetti A, Mancini M, et al. Study of the cardiovascular effects of clenbuterol in exercise-induced asthma. Respiration. 1987;51:205&#x2013;213.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishiko O, Ushiroyama T, Saji F, et al. &#x3b2; 2 -Adrenergic agonists and pelvic floor exercises for female stress incontinence. Int J Gynecol Obstet. 2000;71:39&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soraru G, Pegoraro E, Spinella P, et al. A pilot trial with clenbuterol in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2006;7:252&#x2013;254.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsumoto T, Akutsu S, Wakana N, et al. The expressions of insulin-like growth factors, their receptors, and binding proteins are related to the mechanism regulating masseter muscle mass in the rat. Arch Oral Biol. 2006;51:603&#x2013;611.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Day JS, O'Neill E, Cawley C, et al. Noradrenaline acting on astrocytic &#x3b2;2-adrenoceptors induces neurite outgrowth in primary cortical neurons. Neuropharmacology. 2014;77:234&#x2013;248.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colangelo AM, Johnson PF, Mocchetti I. &#x3b2;-Adrenergic receptor-induced activation of nerve growth factor gene transcription in rat cerebral cortex involves CCAAT/enhancer-binding protein &#x3b4;. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 1998;95:10920&#x2013;10925.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teng YD, Choi H, Huang W, et al. Therapeutic effects of clenbuterol in a murine model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurosci Lett. 2006;397:155&#x2013;158.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koeberl DD, Case LE, Smith EC, et al. Correction of biochemical abnormalities and improved muscle function in a phase I/II clinical trial of clenbuterol in Pompe disease. Mol Ther. 2018;26:2304&#x2013;2314.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinto S, de Carvalho M. Correlation between forced vital capacity and slow vital capacity for the assessment of respiratory involvement in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a prospective study. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2017;18:86&#x2013;91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrews JA, Meng L, Kulke SF, et al. Association between decline in slow vital capacity and respiratory insufficiency, use of assisted ventilation, tracheostomy, or death in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. JAMA Neurol. 2018;75:58&#x2013;64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum JM, Stambler N, Malta E, et al. The ALSFRS-R: a revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. J Neurol Sci. 1999;169:13&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pradas J, Finison L, Andres PL, et al. The natural history of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and the use of natural history controls in therapeutic trials. Neurology. 1993;43:751&#x2013;755.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shefner JM, Wolff AA, Meng L, et al. A randomized, placebo-controlled, double-blind phase IIb trial evaluating the safety and efficacy of tirasemtiv in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2016;17:426&#x2013;435.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shefner JM, Liu D, Leitner ML, et al. Quantitative strength testing in ALS clinical trials. Neurology. 2016;87:617&#x2013;624.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon PH, Cheng B, Salachas F, et al. Progression in ALS is not linear but is curvilinear. J Neurol. 2010;257:1713&#x2013;1717.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>