<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37212068</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>11</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2214-3602</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>10</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of neuromuscular diseases</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Neuromuscul Dis</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Impact of Early Non-Invasive Ventilation in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis: A multicenter Randomized Controlled Trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>627</StartPage><EndPage>637</EndPage><MedlinePgn>627-637</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3233/JND-221658</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Forced vital capacity (FVC) less than 50% of predicted is one of the main parameters used for Non-Invasive Ventilation (NIV) initiation in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis (ALS). Recent studies suggest that higher values of FVC could be considered as a threshold. The aim of this study is to evaluate whether early use of NIV improves the prognosis of ALS patients compared with standard initiation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This is a randomized, parallel, multicenter, open-label, controlled clinical trial, with recruitment at the ALS outpatient multidisciplinary units of six Spanish hospitals. Patients were included when their FVC reached the 75% threshold and were randomized by computer, stratifying by center in an allocation ratio of 1:1 to Early NIV (FVC below 75%) or Standard NIV (FVC below 50%) initiation. The primary outcome was time to death or tracheostomy.Trial registration number ClinicalTrials.gov: NCT01641965.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Between May 2012 and June 2014, 42 patients were randomized to two groups, 20 to Early NIV and 22 to Standard NIV initiation. We found differences in survival in favor of the intervention group: an incidence of mortality (2.68 [1.87-5.50] vs. 3.33 [1.34-4.80] person-months) and a median survival (25.2 vs. 19.4 months), although without reaching statistical significance (p&#x200a;=&#x200a;0.267).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This trial did not reach the primary endpoint of survival; nevertheless, it is the first Randomized Controlled Trial (RCT) to demonstrate the benefits of early NIV in slowing the decline of respiratory muscle strength and reducing adverse events. Although not all the results reached statistical significance, all the analyzed data favor early NIV. In addition, this study demonstrates good tolerance and compliance with early NIV without quality of sleep impairment. These data reinforce the early respiratory evaluation of ALS patients and NIV initiation with an FVC of around 75%.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sarasate</LastName><ForeName>Mikel</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pneumology, UFIS-Respiratoria, Hospital Universitari de Bellvitge, Barcelona, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gonz&#xe1;lez</LastName><ForeName>Nuria</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pneumology, Hospital Residencia Sant Camil, Consorci Sanitari Alt Pended&#xe9;s-Garraf, Barcelona, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>C&#xf3;rdoba-Izquierdo</LastName><ForeName>Ana</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pneumology, UFIS-Respiratoria, Hospital Universitari de Bellvitge, Barcelona, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Prats</LastName><ForeName>Enric</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pneumology, UFIS-Respiratoria, Hospital Universitari de Bellvitge, Barcelona, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gonzalez-Moro</LastName><ForeName>Jose Miguel Rodriguez</ForeName><Initials>JMR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pulmonology, Hospital General Universitario Gregorio Mara&#xf1;&#xf3;n, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mart&#xed;</LastName><ForeName>Sergi</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, Hospital Universitari Vall d'Hebron, Barcelona, Spain; CIBER de Enfermedades Respiratorias (CIBERES), Instituto de Salud Carlos III, Madrid, Spain; Departament de Medicina, Universitat Aut&#xf2;noma deBarcelona (UAB), Barcelona, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lujan</LastName><ForeName>Manel</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pneumology, Corporaci&#xf3; Sanitaria Parc Taul&#xed;, Universitat Aut&#xf2;noma de Barcelona, Sabadell, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Calle</LastName><ForeName>Myriam</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pneumology, Hospital Cl&#xed;nico San Carlos, Department of Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, Complutense University of Madrid, San Carlos Clinical Hospital Institute of Health Research (IdISSC), Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ant&#xf3;n</LastName><ForeName>Antonio</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, Hospital de laSanta Creu i Sant Pau, Barcelona, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Povedano</LastName><ForeName>M&#xf3;nica</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Head of ALS Multidisciplinary Unit, Hospital Universitari de Bellvitge-IDIBELL, Barcelona, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Farrero</LastName><ForeName>Eva</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pneumology, UFIS-Respiratoria, Hospital Universitari de Bellvitge, Barcelona, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT01641965</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016448">Multicenter Study</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>J Neuromuscul Dis</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101649948</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2214-3599</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D063087" MajorTopicYN="Y">Noninvasive Ventilation</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012121" MajorTopicYN="N">Respiration, Artificial</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014797" MajorTopicYN="N">Vital Capacity</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010349" MajorTopicYN="N">Patient Compliance</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ALS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Early NIV</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">respiratory complications</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">respiratory insufficiency</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">survival</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37212068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10357175</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/JND-221658</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">JND221658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Miller RG, Mitchell JD, Lyon M, Moore DH. Riluzole for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS)/motor neuron disease (MND). In: Miller RG, editor. Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews. Chichester, UK: John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd; 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abe K, Aoki M, Tsuji S, Itoyama Y, Sobue G, Togo M, et al.. Safety and efficacy of edaravone in well defined patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Lancet Neurol. 2017;16(7):505&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28522181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paganoni S, Hendrix S, Dickson SP, Knowlton N, Macklin EA, Berry JD, et al.. Long-term survival of participants in the CENTAUR trial of sodium phenylbutyrate-taurursodiol in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 2021;63(1):31&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7820979</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33063909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spataro R, Lo Re M, Piccoli T, Piccoli F, La Bella V. Causes and place of death in Italian patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neurol Scand. 2010;122(3).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20078446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farrero E, Prats E, Povedano M, Martinez-Matos JA, Manresa F, Escarrabill J. Survival in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis With Home Mechanical Ventilation. Chest. 2005;127(6):2132&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15947331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bourke SC, Tomlinson M, Williams TL, Bullock RE, Shaw PJ, Gibson GJ. Effects of non-invasive ventilation on survival and quality of life in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A randomised controlled trial. Lancet Neurology. 2006;5(2).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16426990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morelot-Panzini C, Bruneteau G, Gonzalez-Bermejo J. NIV in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: The &#x2018;when&#x2019; and &#x2018;how&#x2019; of the matter. Respirology. 2019;24(6):521&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30912216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller RG, Jackson CE, Kasarskis EJ, England JD, Forshew D, Johnston W, et al.. Practice Parameter update: The care of the patient withamyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Multidisciplinary care, symptommanagement, and cognitive/behavioral impairment (an evidence-basedreview): Report of the Quality Standards Subcommittee of theAmerican Academy of Neurology. Neurology. 2009;73(15).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2764728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19822873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lechtzin N, Scott Y, Busse AM, Clawson LL, Kimball R, Wiener CM. Early use of non-invasive ventilation prolongs survival in subjects with ALS. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. 2007;8(3):185&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17538782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carrat&#xf9; P, Spicuzza L, Cassano A, Maniscalco M, Gadaleta F, Lacedonia D, et al.. Early treatment with noninvasive positivepressure ventilation prolongs survival in Amyotrophic LateralSclerosis patients with nocturnal respiratory insufficiency. Orphanet J Rare Dis. 2009;4(1):10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2660903</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19284546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khamankar N, Coan G, Weaver B, Mitchell CS. Associative Increases in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Survival Duration With Non-invasive Ventilation Initiation and Usage Protocols. Front Neurol. 2018;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6052254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30050497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR. El Escorial World Federation of Neurology criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Subcommittee on Motor Neuron Diseases/Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis of the World Federation of Neurology Research Group on Neuromuscular Diseases and the El Escorial &#x201c;Clinical limits of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis&#x201d; workshop contributors. J Neurol Sci. 1994;124(Suppl):96&#x2013;107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7807156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gruis KL, Brown DL, Weatherwax KJ, Feldman EL, Chervin RD. Evaluation of sham non-invasive ventilation for randomized, controlled trials in ALS. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. 2006;7(2):96&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16753973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Czaplinski A, Yen AA, Appel SH. Forced vital capacity (FVC) as an indicator of survival and disease progression in an ALS clinic population. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2006;77(3).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2077717</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16484652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vitacca M, Montini A, Lunetta C, Banfi P, Bertella E, De Mattia E, et al.. Impact of an early respiratory care programme with non-invasive ventilation adaptation in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Eur J Neurol. 2018;25(3):556&#x2013;e33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29266547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wijesekera LC, Mathers S, Talman P, Galtrey C, Parkinson MH, Ganesalingam J, et al.. Natural history and clinical features of the flail arm and flail leg ALS variants. Neurology. 2009;72(12):1087&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2821838</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19307543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Georges M, Mor&#xe9;lot-Panzini C, Similowski T, Gonzalez-Bermejo J. Noninvasive ventilation reduces energy expenditure in amyotrophiclateral sclerosis. BMC Pulm Med. 2014;14(1):17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3922008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24507664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen PM, Abrahams S, Borasio GD, de Carvalho M, Chio A, Van Damme P, et al.. EFNS guidelines on the Clinical Management of Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis (MALS) &#x2013;revised report of an EFNS task force. Eur J Neurol. 2012;19(3):360&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21914052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Georges M, Perez T, Rabec C, Jacquin L, Finet-Monnier A, Ramos C, et al.. Proposals from a French expert panel for respiratory care in ALS patients. Respir Med Res. 2022;81:100901.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35378353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janssens JP, Michel F, Schwarz EI, Prella M, Bloch K, Adler D, et al.. Long-Term Mechanical Ventilation: Recommendations of the Swiss Society of Pulmonology. Respiration. 2020;99(10):867&#x2013;902.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33302274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Georges M, Golmard JL, Llontop C, Shoukri A, Salachas F, Similowski T, et al.. Initiation of non-invasive ventilation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and clinical practice guidelines: Single-centre, retrospective, descriptive study in a national reference centre. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2017;18(1&#x2013;2):46&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27978772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vitacca M, Vianello A. Respiratory Outcomes of Patients With Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis: An Italian Nationwide Survey. Respir Care. 2013;58(9):143341.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23431306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terzano C, Romani S. Early use of non invasive ventilation in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: What benefits? Eur Rev Med Pharmacol Sci. 2015;19(22):4304&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26636518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tilanus TBM, Groothuis JT, TenBroek-Pastoor JMC, Feuth TB, Heijdra YF, Slenders JPL, et al.. The predictive value of respiratoryfunction tests for non-invasive ventilation in amyotrophic lateralsclerosis. Respir Res. 2017;18(1):144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5526316</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28743265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinto A, de Carvalho M, Evangelista T, Lopes A, Sales-Lu&#xed;s L. Nocturnal pulse oximetry: A new approach to establish theappropriate time for non-invasive ventilation in ALS patients. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis and Other Motor Neuron Disorders. 2003;4(1):31&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12745616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morgan RK, McNally S, Alexander M, Conroy R, Hardiman O, Costello RW. Use of Sniff Nasal-Inspiratory Force to Predict Survival in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2005;171(3):269&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15516537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Metha S, Hill NS. Noninvasive Ventilation. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2001;163(2):540&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11179136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ward S, Chatwin M, Heather S, Simonds AK. Randomised controlled trial of non-invasive ventilation (NIV) for nocturnal hypoventilation in neuromuscular and chest wall disease patients with daytime normocapnia. Thorax. 2005;60(12).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1747266</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16299118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corcia P, Pradat P, Salachas F, Bruneteau G, le Forestier N, Seilhean D, et al.. Causes of death in a post-mortem series of ALS patients. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. 2008;9(1):59&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17924236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang R, Huang R, Chen D, Song W, Zeng Y, Zhao B, et al.. Causes and places of death of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in south-west China. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. 2011;12(3):206&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21506897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson CE, Heiman-Patterson TD, Sherman M, Daohai YU, Kasarskis EJ, Heiman-Patterson T, et al.. Factors associated with Noninvasive ventilation compliance in patients with ALS/MND. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2021;22(S1):40&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34348541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobs TL, Brown DL, Baek J, Migda EM, Funckes T, Gruis KL. Trial of early noninvasive ventilation for ALS. Neurology. 2016;87(18):1878&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5100714</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27581221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitsumoto H, Rabkin JG. Palliative Care for Patients With Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. JAMA. 2007;298(2):207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17622602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>