<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37248728</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>22</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-4598</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>68</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Muscle &amp; nerve</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Muscle Nerve</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Needs of persons living with ALS at home and their family caregivers: A scoping review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>240</StartPage><EndPage>249</EndPage><MedlinePgn>240-249</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/mus.27849</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION/AIMS">Most persons with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) live at home with support of family caregivers, with escalating complexity of care over the trajectory of the disease requiring resources and support to mitigate negative physical, social, and emotional outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">This scoping review identifies the home health/home care needs of persons with ALS and their caregivers as a basis for creating a home health medical standard. We used the PRISMA Extension for Scoping Reviews (PRISMA-ScR) to examine studies describing home care needs published between 2011 and 2021.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Our search yielded 481 articles, of which 44 were included with a total of 3592 (9-273) participants. Most studies used a cross-sectional design and 20 (45%) were rated as high quality. We grouped the needs identified as emotional/psychological, assistive devices and technology, information and education, and human resources and professional services. Most studies demonstrated persistent unmet needs and that available interventions were helpful while needs generally were not met proactively, despite the predictable trajectory.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION">This review describes biopsychosocial and equipment interventions over the trajectory of ALS with implications for anticipatory planning by clinicians, as well as policy for coverage of necessary services and supports. Interdisciplinary expert teams could develop consensus around needs across the trajectory and recommended services and supports. To make knowledge more accessible, encourage availability of services, and clarify the need for coverage of services, we aim to develop an expert consensus-based ALS home health medical standard guidance document in collaboration with the American Association of Neuromuscular and Electrodiagnostic Medicine.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Young</LastName><ForeName>Heather M</ForeName><Initials>HM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1691-3993</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Family Caregiving Institute, Betty Irene Moore School of Nursing, University of California Davis, Sacramento, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kilaberia</LastName><ForeName>Tina R</ForeName><Initials>TR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Silver School of Social Work, New York University, New York, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Whitney</LastName><ForeName>Robin</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Valley Foundation School of Nursing, San Jose State University, San Jose, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Link</LastName><ForeName>Benjamin M</ForeName><Initials>BM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8396-5139</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Family Caregiving Institute, Betty Irene Moore School of Nursing, University of California Davis, Sacramento, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bell</LastName><ForeName>Janice F</ForeName><Initials>JF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Family Caregiving Institute, Betty Irene Moore School of Nursing, University of California Davis, Sacramento, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tonkikh</LastName><ForeName>Orly</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Family Caregiving Institute, Betty Irene Moore School of Nursing, University of California Davis, Sacramento, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Famula</LastName><ForeName>Jessica</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2858-6897</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Family Caregiving Institute, Betty Irene Moore School of Nursing, University of California Davis, Sacramento, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oskarsson</LastName><ForeName>Bj&#xf6;rn</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1725-9866</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mayo Clinic, Jacksonville, Florida, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Muscle Nerve</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7803146</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0148-639X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017028" MajorTopicYN="N">Caregivers</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003430" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Sectional Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006699" MajorTopicYN="Y">Home Care Services</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004644" MajorTopicYN="N">Emotions</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">assistive devices</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">home care</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">home health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">interdisciplinary care</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">motor neuron disease (MND)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">team-based care</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37248728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.27849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Poppe C, Kon&#xe9; I, Iseli L, et al. Differentiating needs of informal caregivers of individuals with ALS across the caregiving course: a systematic review. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2020;21(7-8):519-541.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh J, Kim J. Supportive care needs of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis/motor neuron disease and their caregivers: a scoping review. J Clin Nurs. 2017;26(23-24):4129-4152.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alankaya N, Karadakovan A. Home care needs of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and care burden of caregivers. Health Sci J. 2015;9(4).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krivickas L, Shockley L, Mitsumoto H. Home care of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). J Neurol Sci. 1997;152:s82-s89.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tikkanen R, Osborn R, Mossialos E, et al. International profiles of health care systems. Commonw Fund. 2020. https://www.commonwealthfund.org/publications/fund-reports/2017/may/international-profiles-health-care-systems</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Hanawi M. The healthcare system in Saudi Arabia: how can we best move forward with funding to protect equitable and accessible care for all. Int J Healthcare. 2017;3(2):78-94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gladman M, Zinman L. The economic impact of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a systematic review. Expert Rev Pharmacoecon Outcomes Res. 2015;15(3):439-450.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henschke C. Provision and financing of assistive technology devices in Germany: a bureaucratic odyssey? The case of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and Duchenne muscular dystrophy. Health Policy. 2012;105(2):176-184.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bede P, Oliver D, Stodart J, et al. Palliative care in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a review of current international guidelines and initiatives. BMJ Support Palliat Care. 2011;1(3):343-348.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng L, Bian A, Jordan S, et al. Profile of medical care costs in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in the Medicare programme and under commercial insurance. Amyotrophic Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2018;19(1):134-142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Social Security Administration. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS)-medicare waiting period waived. Administration USSS, ed. Vol DI 11036.001. Social Security Administration; 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tricco A, Lillie E, Zarin W, et al. PRISMA extension for scoping reviews (PRISMA-ScR): checklist and explanation. Ann Intern Med. 2018;169(7):467-473.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munn Z, Peters M, Stern C, et al. Systematic review or scoping review? Guidance for authors when choosing between a systematic or scoping review approach. BMC Med Res Methodol. 2018;18(1):143.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heyvaert M, Hannes K, Maes B, et al. Critical apprasial of mixed methods studies. J Mixed Methods Res. 2013;7(4):302-327.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Cathain A, Murphy E. The quality of mixed methods studies in health services research. J Health Serv Res Policy. 2008;13(2):92-98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caron J, Light J. My world has expanded even though I'm stuck at home: experiences of individuals with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis who use augmentative and alternative communication and social media. Am J Speech Lang Pathol. 2015;24(4):680-695.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakker M, Creemers H, Schipper K, et al. Need and value of case management in multidisciplinary ALS care: a qualitative study on the perspectives of patients, spousal caregivers and professionals. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2015;16(3-4):180-186.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larsson BJ, Frojd C, Nordin K, et al. Relatives of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: their experience of care and support. Palliat Support Care. 2015;13(6):1569-1577.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson NH, Gluyas C, Mathers S, et al. "A monster that lives in our lives": experiences of caregivers of people with motor neuron disease and identifying avenues for support. BMJ Support Palliat Care. 2019;9(4):e27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weisser F, Bristowe K, Jackson D. Experiences of burden, needs, rewards and resilience in family caregivers of people living with motor neurone disease/amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a secondary thematic analysis of qualitative interviews. Palliat Med. 2015;29(8):737-745.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cipolletta S, Gammino GR, Francescon P, et al. Mutual support groups for family caregivers of people with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in Italy: a pilot study. Health Soc Care Community. 2018;26(4):556-563.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galvin M, Carney S, Corr B, et al. Needs of informal caregivers across the caregiving course in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a qualitative analysis. BMJ Open. 2018;8(1):e018721.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McVeigh C, Donaghy C, Mc Laughlin B, et al. Palliative care for patients with motor neurone disease and their bereaved carers: a qualitative study. BMC Palliat Care. 2019;18(1):39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ang K, Umapathi T, Tong J, et al. Healthcare needs of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) in Singapore: a patient-centred qualitative study from multiple perspectives. J Palliat Care. 2015;31(3):150-157.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aoun SM, Deas K, Kristjanson LJ, et al. Identifying and addressing the support needs of family caregivers of people with motor neurone disease using the carer support needs assessment tool. Palliat Support Care. 2017;15(1):32-43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bolmsj&#xf6; I. Existential issues in palliative care: interviews of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Palliat Med. 2004;4(4):499-505.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kukulka K, Washington KT, Govindarajan R, et al. Stakeholder perspectives on the biopsychosocial and spiritual realities of living with ALS: implications for palliative care teams. Am J Hosp Palliat Care. 2019;36(10):851-857.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeWit J, Beelen A, Drossaert C, et al. Blended psychosocial support for partners of patients with ALS and PMA: results of a randomized controlled trial. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2020;21(5-6):344-354.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pagnini F, Rossi G, Lunetta C, et al. Burden, depression, and anxiety in caregivers of people with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Psychol Health Med. 2010;15(6):685-693.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qutub K, Lacomis D, Albert SM, et al. Life factors affecting depression and burden in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis caregivers. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2014;15(3-4):292-297.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pagnini F, Banfi P, Lunetta C, et al. Respiratory function of people with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and caregiver distress level: a correlational study. Biopsychosoc Med. 2012;6(1):1-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruletti G, Comini L, Scalvini S, et al. A two-year longitudinal study on strain and needs in caregivers of advanced ALS patients. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2015;16(3-4):187-195.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Creemers H, de Moree S, Veldink JH, et al. Factors related to caregiver strain in ALS: a longitudinal study. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2016;87(7):775-781.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ganzini L, Johnston W, Silveira M. The final month of life in patients with ALS. Neurology. 2002;59(3):428-431.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chio A, Gauthier A, Montuschi A, et al. A cross sectional study on determinants of quality of life in ALS. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2004;75(11):1597-1601.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trail M, Nelson N, Van J, et al. Major stressors facing patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS): a survey to identify their concerns and to compare with those of their caregivers. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord. 2004;5(1):40-45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams MT, Donnelly JP, Holmlund T, et al. ALS: family caregiver needs and quality of life. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2008;9(5):279-286.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bolmsj&#xf6; I, Hermer&#xe9;n G. Interviews with patients, family, and caregivers in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: comparing needs. J Palliat Care. 2001;17(4):236-240.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Teijlingen E, Friend E, Kamal A. Service use and needs of people with motor neurone disease and their carers in Scotland. Health Soc Care Community. 2001;9(6):397-403.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tobin K, Maguire S, Corr B, et al. Discrete choice experiment for eliciting preference for health services for patients with ALS and their informal caregivers. BMC Health Serv Res. 2021;21(1).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goy ER, Carter J, Ganzini L. Neurologic disease at the end of life: caregiver descriptions of Parkinson disease and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Palliat Med. 2008;11(4):548-554.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh J, Kim SH, Kim JA. Unmet supportive care needs mediate the relationship between functional status and quality of life in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Palliat Support Care. 2019;17(6):650-654.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bromberg MB, Brownell AA, Forshew DA, et al. A timeline for predicting durable medical equipment needs and interventions for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2010;11(1-2):110-115.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Connors KA, Mahony LM, Morgan P. Adaptive equipment use by people with motor neuron disease in Australia: a prospective, observational consecutive cohort study. Disabil Rehabil Assist Technol. 2019;14(1):62-67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fried-Oken M, Fox L, Rau MT, et al. Purposes of AAC device use for persons with ALS as reported by caregivers. Augment Altern Commun. 2006;22(3):209-221.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackenzie L, Bhuta P, Rusten K, et al. Communications technology and motor neuron disease: an Australian survey of people with motor neuron disease. JMIR Rehabil Assist Technol. 2016;3(1):e2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdulla S, Vielhaber S, Machts J, et al. Information needs and information-seeking preferences of ALS patients and their carers. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2014;15(7-8):505-512.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chu HS, Oh J. Information needs and preferences of family caregivers of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurosci Nurs. 2020;52(5):207-213.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh J, Kim J. Information-seeking behavior and information needs in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: analyzing an online patient community. CIN. 2017;35(7):345-351.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cappellato V, Bosco N, Chio A, et al. Curable or treatable? the implications of different definitions of illness when treating patients affected by amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2015;17(1-2):15-20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ng L, Talman P, Khan F. Motor neurone disease: disability profile and service needs in an Australian cohort. Int J Rehabil Res. 2011;34(2):151-159.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Brien M, Whitehead B, Jack B, et al. From symptom onset to a diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis/motor neuron disease (ALS/MND): experiences of people with ALS/MND and family carers-a qualitative study. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2011;12(2):97-104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakai M, Narita Y, Tomimoto H. An investigation of perspectives of respite admission among people living with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and the hospitals that support them. J Prim Care Community Health. 2017;8(3):163-168.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ganzini L, Silveira M, Johnston W. Predictors and correlates of interest in assisted suicide in the final month of life among ALS patients in Oregon and Washington. J Pain Symptom Manage. 2002;24(3):312-317.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kristjanson L, Aoun S, Oldham L. Palliative care and support for people with neurodegenerative conditions and their carers. Int J Palliat Nurs. 2006;12(8):368-377.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emanuel EJ, Fairclough DL, Slutsman J, et al. Understanding economic and other burdens of terminal illness: the experience of patients and their caregivers. Ann Intern Med. 2000;132(6):451-459.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang LH, Elliott MA, Jung Henson L, et al. Death with dignity in Washington patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology. 2016;87(20):2117-2122. doi:10.1212/WNL.0000000000003335</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liberati G, Pizzimenti A, Simione L, et al. Developing brain-computer interfaces from a user-centered perspective: assessing the needs of persons with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, caregivers, and professionals. Appl Ergon. 2015;50:139-146.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh J, An J, Oh S-I, et al. Socioeconomic costs of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis according to staging system. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2015;16(3-4):202-208.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopes de Almeida J, Pinto A, Pinto S, et al. Economic cost of home-telemonitoring care for BiPAP-assisted ALS individuals. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2012;13(6):533-537.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindeman D, Kim K, Gladstone C, et al. Technology and caregiving: emerging interventions and directions for research. Gerontologist. 2020;60:S41-S49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirby E, Lwin Z, Kenny K, et al. &#x201c;It doesn't exist&#x2026;&#x201d;: negotiating palliative care from a culturally and linguistically diverse patient and caregiver perspective. BMC Palliat Care. 2018;17(1):1-10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehta P, Raymond J, Punjani R, et al. Prevalence of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in the United States using established and novel methodologies. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2017;2022:1-9.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>