<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37269166</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>22</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-4598</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>68</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Muscle &amp; nerve</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Muscle Nerve</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Clinical utility of far field motor potentials in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>237</StartPage><EndPage>239</EndPage><MedlinePgn>237-239</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/mus.27852</ELocationID><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vucic</LastName><ForeName>Steve</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8323-873X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Brain and Nerve Research Center, The University of Sydney, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016421">Editorial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016420">Comment</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Muscle Nerve</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7803146</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0148-639X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="CommentOn"><RefSource>Muscle Nerve. 2023 Sep;68(3):257-263</RefSource><PMID Version="1">37086196</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005071" MajorTopicYN="N">Evoked Potentials</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37269166</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.27852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Goutman SA, Hardiman O, Al-Chalabi A, et al. Recent advances in the diagnosis and prognosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet Neurol. 2022;21:480-493.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shefner JM, Al-Chalabi A, Baker MR, et al. A proposal for new diagnostic criteria for ALS. Clin Neurophysiol. 2020;131:1975-1978.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Dengler R, Eisen A, et al. Electrodiagnostic criteria for diagnosis of ALS. Clin Neurophysiol. 2008;119:497-503.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks B, Miller R, Swash M, Munsat T. El Escorial revisited: revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord. 2000;1:293-299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S, Ferguson TA, Cummings C, et al. Gold Coast diagnostic criteria: implications for ALS diagnosis and clinical trial enrollment. Muscle Nerve. 2021;64:532-537.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum JM, Stambler N, Malta E, et al. The ALSFRS-R: a revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. BDNF ALS study group (phase III). J Neurol Sci. 1999;169:13-21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roche JC, Rojas-Garcia R, Scott KM, et al. A proposed staging system for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain. 2012;135:847-852.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2; A, Hammond ER, Mora G, Bonito V, Filippini G. Development and evaluation of a clinical staging system for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2015;86:38-44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westeneng HJ, Debray TPA, Visser AE, et al. Prognosis for patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: development and validation of a personalised prediction model. Lancet Neurol. 2018;17:423-433.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fournier CN, Bedlack R, Quinn C, et al. Development and validation of the Rasch-built overall amyotrophic lateral sclerosis disability scale (ROADS). JAMA Neurol. 2020;77:480-488.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S, Stanley Chen KH, Kiernan MC, et al. Clinical diagnostic utility of transcranial magnetic stimulation in neurological disorders. Updated report of an IFCN committee. Clin Neurophysiol. 2023;150:131-175.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menon P, Kiernan MC, Vucic S. ALS pathophysiology: insights form the split-hand phenomenon. Clin Neurophysiol. 2014;49:836-844.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hannaford A, Byth K, Pavey N, et al. Clinical and neurophysiological biomarkers of disease progression in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 2023;67:17-24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Chio A, Dengler R, Hecht M, Weber M, Swash M. Neurophysiological measures in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: markers of progression in clinical trials. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2005;6:17-28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bromberg MB, Forshew DA, Nau KL, Bromberg J, Simmons Z, Fries TJ. Motor unit number estimation, isometric strength, and electromyographic measures in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 1993;16:1213-1219.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nandedkar SD, Barkhaus PE, St&#xe5;lberg E. Motor unit number index (MUNIX) and compound muscle action potential amplitude: a reappraisal. Clin Neurophysiol. 2019;130:2010-2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobsen AB, Bostock H, Fuglsang-Frederiksen A, et al. Reproducibility, and sensitivity to motor unit loss in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, of a novel MUNE method: MScanFit MUNE. Clin Neurophysiol. 2017;128:1380-1388.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bromberg MB, Spiegelberg T. The influence of active electrode placement on CMAP amplitude. Electroencephalogr Clin Neurophysiol. 1997;105:385-389.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sonoo M. Far-field potentials in the compound muscle action potential. Muscle Nerve. 2020;61:271-279.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higashihara M, Yamazaki H, Izumi Y, et al. Far-field potential of the compound muscle action potential as a reliable marker in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 2023;68:257-263.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neuwirth C, Barkhaus PE, Burkhardt C, et al. Tracking motor neuron loss in a set of six muscles in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis using the motor unit number index (MUNIX): a 15-month longitudinal multicentre trial. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2015;86:1172-1179.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S, Kiernan MC. Novel threshold tracking techniques suggest that cortical hyperexcitability is an early feature of motor neuron disease. Brain. 2006;129:2436-2446.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menon P, Geevasinga N, Yiannikas C, Howells J, Kiernan MC, Vucic S. Sensitivity and specificity of threshold tracking transcranial magnetic stimulation for diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a prospective study. Lancet Neurol. 2015;14:478-484.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menon P, Geevasinga N, van den Bos M, Yiannikas C, Kiernan MC, Vucic S. Cortical hyperexcitability and disease spread in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Eur J Neurol. 2017;24:816-824.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dharmadasa T, Matamala JM, Howells J, Vucic S, Kiernan MC. Early focality and spread of cortical dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a regional study across the motor cortices. Clin Neurophysiol. 2020;131:958-966.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shibuya K, Park SB, Geevasinga N, et al. Motor cortical function determines prognosis in sporadic ALS. Neurology. 2016;87:513-520.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>