<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37277972</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>19</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-4159</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>166</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of neurochemistry</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Neurochem</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Aspects of degradation and translation of the expanded C9orf72 hexanucleotide repeat RNA.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>156</StartPage><EndPage>171</EndPage><MedlinePgn>156-171</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/jnc.15847</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>An hexanucleotide repeat expansion mutation in the non-coding region of C9orf72 gene causes frontotemporal dementia and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. This mutation is estimated to be the most frequent genetic cause of these currently incurable diseases. Since the mutation causes autosomal dominantly inherited diseases, disease cascade essentially starts from the expanded DNA repeats. However, molecular disease mechanism is inevitably complex because possible toxic entity for the disease is not just functional loss of translated C9ORF72 protein, if any, but potentially includes bidirectionally transcribed expanded repeat containing RNA and their unconventional repeat-associated non-AUG translation products in all possible reading frames. Although the field learned so much about the disease since the identification of the mutation in 2011, how the expanded repeat causes a particular type of fronto-temporal lobe dominant neurodegeneration and/or motor neuron degeneration is not yet clear. In this review, we summarize and discuss the current understandings of molecular mechanism of this repeat expansion mutation with focuses on the degradation and translation of the repeat containing RNA transcripts.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 International Society for Neurochemistry.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mori</LastName><ForeName>Kohji</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2629-0723</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Osaka University Graduate School of Medicine, Suita, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gotoh</LastName><ForeName>Shiho</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Osaka University Graduate School of Medicine, Suita, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ikeda</LastName><ForeName>Manabu</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Osaka University Graduate School of Medicine, Suita, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Neurochem</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>2985190R</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0022-3042</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000073885">C9orf72 Protein</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D011506">Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>63231-63-0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D012313">RNA</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C568651">C9orf72 protein, human</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000073885" MajorTopicYN="N">C9orf72 Protein</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011506" MajorTopicYN="N">Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012313" MajorTopicYN="N">RNA</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Frontotemporal Dementia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D042622" MajorTopicYN="N">DNA Repeat Expansion</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">C9orf72</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">RNA metabolism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">frontotemporal dementia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">frontotemporal lobar degeneration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">repeat-associated-AUG translation</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37277972</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jnc.15847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Alberti, S., &amp; Hyman, A. A. (2021). Biomolecular condensates at the nexus of cellular stress, protein aggregation disease and ageing. Nature Reviews Molecular Cell Biology, 22, 196-213.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almeida, S., Gascon, E., Tran, H., Chou, H. J., Gendron, T. F., DeGroot, S., Tapper, A. R., Sellier, C., Charlet-Berguerand, N., Karydas, A., Seeley, W. W., Boxer, A. L., Petrucelli, L., Miller, B. L., &amp; Gao, F. B. (2013). Modeling key pathological features of frontotemporal dementia with C9ORF72 repeat expansion in iPSC-derived human neurons. Acta Neuropathologica, 126, 385-399.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almeida, S., Krishnan, G., Rushe, M., Gu, Y., Kankel, M. W., &amp; Gao, F.-B. (2019). Production of poly (GA) in C9ORF72 patient motor neurons derived from induced pluripotent stem cells. Acta Neuropathologica, 138, 1099-1101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Sarraj, S., King, A., Troakes, C., Smith, B., Maekawa, S., Bodi, I., Rogelj, B., Al-Chalabi, A., Hortobagyi, T., &amp; Shaw, C. E. (2011). p62 positive, TDP-43 negative, neuronal cytoplasmic and intranuclear inclusions in the cerebellum and hippocampus define the pathology of C9orf72-linked FTLD and MND/ALS. Acta Neuropathologica, 122, 691-702.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arzberger, T., Schludi, M. H., Lehmer, C., Schmid, B., &amp; Edbauer, D. (2018). RNA versus protein toxicity in C9orf72 ALS/FTLD. Acta Neuropathologica, 135, 475-479.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ash, P. E., Bieniek, K. F., Gendron, T. F., Caulfield, T., Lin, W. L., Dejesus-Hernandez, M., van Blitterswijk, M. M., Jansen-West, K., Paul, J. W., 3rd, Rademakers, R., Boylan, K. B., Dickson, D. W., &amp; Petrucelli, L. (2013). Unconventional translation of C9ORF72 GGGGCC expansion generates insoluble polypeptides specific to c9FTD/ALS. Neuron, 77, 639-646.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balendra, R., &amp; Isaacs, A. M. (2018). C9orf72-mediated ALS and FTD: Multiple pathways to disease. Nature Reviews. Neurology, 14, 544-558.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bersano, E., Sarnelli, M. F., Solara, V., Iazzolino, B., Peotta, L., de Marchi, F., Facchin, A., Moglia, C., Canosa, A., Calvo, A., Chi&#xf2;, A., &amp; Mazzini, L. (2020). Decline of cognitive and behavioral functions in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A longitudinal study. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener, 21, 373-379.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boczonadi, V., Muller, J. S., Pyle, A., Munkley, J., Dor, T., Quartararo, J., Ferrero, I., Karcagi, V., Giunta, M., Polvikoski, T., Birchall, D., Princzinger, A., Cinnamon, Y., Lutzkendorf, S., Piko, H., Reza, M., Florez, L., Santibanez-Koref, M., Griffin, H., &#x2026; Horvath, R. (2014). EXOSC8 mutations alter mRNA metabolism and cause hypomyelination with spinal muscular atrophy and cerebellar hypoplasia. Nature Communications, 5, 4287.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boeynaems, S., Bogaert, E., Michiels, E., Gijselinck, I., Sieben, A., Jovi&#x10d;i&#x107;, A., de Baets, G., Scheveneels, W., Steyaert, J., Cuijt, I., Verstrepen, K. J., Callaerts, P., Rousseau, F., Schymkowitz, J., Cruts, M., van Broeckhoven, C., van Damme, P., Gitler, A. D., Robberecht, W., &amp; van den Bosch, L. (2016). Drosophila screen connects nuclear transport genes to DPR pathology in c9ALS/FTD. Scientific Reports, 6, 20877.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boivin, M., Pfister, V., Gaucherot, A., Ruffenach, F., Negroni, L., Sellier, C., &amp; Charlet-Berguerand, N. (2020). Reduced autophagy upon C9ORF72 loss synergizes with dipeptide repeat protein toxicity in G4C2 repeat expansion disorders. The EMBO Journal, 39, e100574.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braems, E., Bercier, V., Van Schoor, E., Heeren, K., Beckers, J., Fumagalli, L., Dedeene, L., Moisse, M., Geudens, I., &amp; Hersmus, N. (2022). HNRNPK alleviates RNA toxicity by counteracting DNA damage in C9orf72 ALS. Acta Neuropathologica, 144, 465-488.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burberry, A., Suzuki, N., Wang, J. Y., Moccia, R., Mordes, D. A., Stewart, M. H., Suzuki-Uematsu, S., Ghosh, S., Singh, A., Merkle, F. T., Koszka, K., Li, Q. Z., Zon, L., Rossi, D. J., Trowbridge, J. J., Notarangelo, L. D., &amp; Eggan, K. (2016). Loss-of-function mutations in the C9ORF72 mouse ortholog cause fatal autoimmune disease. Science Translational Medicine, 8, 347ra393.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burns, D. T., Donkervoort, S., M&#xfc;ller, J. S., Knierim, E., Bharucha-Goebel, D., Faqeih, E. A., Bell, S. K., AlFaifi, A. Y., Monies, D., Millan, F., Retterer, K., Dyack, S., MacKay, S., Morales-Gonzalez, S., Giunta, M., Munro, B., Hudson, G., Scavina, M., Baker, L., &#x2026; B&#xf6;nnemann, C. G. (2018). Variants in EXOSC9 disrupt the RNA exosome and result in cerebellar atrophy with spinal motor neuronopathy. The American Journal of Human Genetics, 102, 858-873.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bush, J. A., Aikawa, H., Fuerst, R., Li, Y., Ursu, A., Meyer, S. M., Benhamou, R. I., Chen, J. L., Khan, T., Wagner-Griffin, S., van Meter, M. J., Tong, Y., Olafson, H., McKee, K. K., Childs-Disney, J. L., Gendron, T. F., Zhang, Y., Coyne, A. N., Wang, E. T., &#x2026; Disney, M. D. (2021). Ribonuclease recruitment using a small molecule reduced c9ALS/FTD r(G(4)C(2)) repeat expansion in vitro and in vivo ALS models. Science Translational Medicine, 13, eabd5991.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bush, J. A., Meyer, S. M., Fuerst, R., Tong, Y., Li, Y., Benhamou, R. I., Aikawa, H., Zanon, P. R. A., Gibaut, Q. M. R., Angelbello, A. J., Gendron, T. F., Zhang, Y. J., Petrucelli, L., Heick Jensen, T., Childs-Disney, J. L., &amp; Disney, M. D. (2022). A blood-brain penetrant RNA-targeted small molecule triggers elimination of r(G(4)C(2))(exp) in c9ALS/FTD via the nuclear RNA exosome. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 119, e2210532119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang, A., Xiang, X., Wang, J., Lee, C., Arakhamia, T., Simjanoska, M., Wang, C., Carlomagno, Y., Zhang, G., Dhingra, S., Thierry, M., Perneel, J., Heeman, B., Forgrave, L. M., DeTure, M., DeMarco, M. L., Cook, C. N., Rademakers, R., Dickson, D. W., &#x2026; Fitzpatrick, A. W. P. (2022). Homotypic fibrillization of TMEM106B across diverse neurodegenerative diseases. Cell, 185(1346-1355), e1315.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng, W., Wang, S., Mestre, A. A., Fu, C., Makarem, A., Xian, F., Hayes, L. R., Lopez-Gonzalez, R., Drenner, K., Jiang, J., Cleveland, D. W., &amp; Sun, S. (2018). C9ORF72 GGGGCC repeat-associated non-AUG translation is upregulated by stress through eIF2&#x3b1; phosphorylation. Nature Communications, 9, 51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng, W., Wang, S., Zhang, Z., Morgens, D. W., Hayes, L. R., Lee, S., Portz, B., Xie, Y., Nguyen, B. V., Haney, M. S., Yan, S., Dong, D., Coyne, A. N., Yang, J., Xian, F., Cleveland, D. W., Qiu, Z., Rothstein, J. D., Shorter, J., &#x2026; Sun, S. (2019). CRISPR-Cas9 screens identify the RNA helicase DDX3X as a repressor of C9ORF72 (GGGGCC)n repeat-associated non-AUG translation. Neuron, 104, e888.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conlon, E. G., Lu, L., Sharma, A., Yamazaki, T., Tang, T., Shneider, N. A., &amp; Manley, J. L. (2016). The C9ORF72 GGGGCC expansion forms RNA G-quadruplex inclusions and sequesters hnRNP H to disrupt splicing in ALS brains. eLife, 5, 17820.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook, C. N., Wu, Y., Odeh, H. M., Gendron, T. F., Jansen-West, K., del Rosso, G., Yue, M., Jiang, P., Gomes, E., Tong, J., Daughrity, L. M., Avendano, N. M., Castanedes-Casey, M., Shao, W., Oskarsson, B., Tomassy, G. S., McCampbell, A., Rigo, F., Dickson, D. W., &#x2026; Petrucelli, L. (2020). C9orf72 poly (GR) aggregation induces TDP-43 proteinopathy. Science Translational Medicine, 12, eabb3774.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooper-Knock, J., Higginbottom, A., Stopford, M. J., Highley, J. R., Ince, P. G., Wharton, S. B., Pickering-Brown, S., Kirby, J., Hautbergue, G. M., &amp; Shaw, P. J. (2015). Antisense RNA foci in the motor neurons of C9ORF72-ALS patients are associated with TDP-43 proteinopathy. Acta Neuropathologica, 130, 63-75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooper-Knock, J., Walsh, M. J., Higginbottom, A., Robin Highley, J., Dickman, M. J., Edbauer, D., Ince, P. G., Wharton, S. B., Wilson, S. A., Kirby, J., Hautbergue, G. M., &amp; Shaw, P. J. (2014). Sequestration of multiple RNA recognition motif-containing proteins by C9orf72 repeat expansions. Brain, 137, 2040-2051.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coyne, A. N., Zaepfel, B. L., Hayes, L., Fitchman, B., Salzberg, Y., Luo, E. C., Bowen, K., Trost, H., Aigner, S., Rigo, F., Yeo, G. W., Harel, A., Svendsen, C. N., Sareen, D., &amp; Rothstein, J. D. (2020). G4C2 repeat RNA initiates a POM121-mediated reduction in specific nucleoporins in C9orf72 ALS/FTD. Neuron, 107, 1124-1140 e1111.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crockford, C., Newton, J., Lonergan, K., Chiwera, T., Booth, T., Chandran, S., Colville, S., Heverin, M., Mays, I., Pal, S., Pender, N., Pinto-Grau, M., Radakovic, R., Shaw, C. E., Stephenson, L., Swingler, R., Vajda, A., al-Chalabi, A., Hardiman, O., &amp; Abrahams, S. (2018). ALS-specific cognitive and behavior changes associated with advancing disease stage in ALS. Neurology, 91, e1370-e1380.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davidson, Y. S., Flood, L., Robinson, A. C., Nihei, Y., Mori, K., Rollinson, S., Richardson, A., Benson, B. C., Jones, M., Snowden, J. S., Pickering-Brown, S., Haass, C., Lashley, T., &amp; Mann, D. M. A. (2017). Heterogeneous ribonuclear protein A3 (hnRNP A3) is present in dipeptide repeat protein containing inclusions in frontotemporal lobar degeneration and motor Neurone disease associated with expansions in C9orf72 gene. Acta Neuropathologica Communications, 5, 31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeJesus-Hernandez, M., Aleff, R. A., Jackson, J. L., Finch, N. C. A., Baker, M. C., Gendron, T. F., Murray, M. E., McLaughlin, I. J., Harting, J. R., Graff-Radford, N. R., Oskarsson, B., Knopman, D. S., Josephs, K. A., Boeve, B. F., Petersen, R. C., Fryer, J. D., Petrucelli, L., Dickson, D. W., Rademakers, R., &#x2026; van Blitterswijk, M. (2021). Long-read targeted sequencing uncovers clinicopathological associations for C9orf72-linked diseases. Brain, 144, 1082-1088.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeJesus-Hernandez, M., Finch, N. A., Wang, X., Gendron, T. F., Bieniek, K. F., Heckman, M. G., Vasilevich, A., Murray, M. E., Rousseau, L., Weesner, R., Lucido, A., Parsons, M., Chew, J., Josephs, K. A., Parisi, J. E., Knopman, D. S., Petersen, R. C., Boeve, B. F., Graff-Radford, N. R., &#x2026; Rademakers, R. (2017). In-depth clinico-pathological examination of RNA foci in a large cohort of C9ORF72 expansion carriers. Acta Neuropathologica, 134, 255-269.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeJesus-Hernandez, M., Mackenzie, I. R., Boeve, B. F., Boxer, A. L., Baker, M., Rutherford, N. J., Nicholson, A. M., Finch, N. C. A., Flynn, H., Adamson, J., Kouri, N., Wojtas, A., Sengdy, P., Hsiung, G. Y. R., Karydas, A., Seeley, W. W., Josephs, K. A., Coppola, G., Geschwind, D. H., &#x2026; Rademakers, R. (2011). Expanded GGGGCC hexanucleotide repeat in noncoding region of C9ORF72 causes chromosome 9p-linked FTD and ALS. Neuron, 72, 245-256.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devenney, E., Hornberger, M., Irish, M., Mioshi, E., Burrell, J., Tan, R., Kiernan, M. C., &amp; Hodges, J. R. (2014). Frontotemporal dementia associated with the C9ORF72 mutation: A unique clinical profile. JAMA Neurology, 71, 331-339.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donnelly, C. J., Zhang, P. W., Pham, J. T., Haeusler, A. R., Mistry, N. A., Vidensky, S., Daley, E. L., Poth, E. M., Hoover, B., Fines, D. M., Maragakis, N., Tienari, P. J., Petrucelli, L., Traynor, B. J., Wang, J., Rigo, F., Bennett, C. F., Blackshaw, S., Sattler, R., &amp; Rothstein, J. D. (2013). RNA toxicity from the ALS/FTD C9ORF72 expansion is mitigated by antisense intervention. Neuron, 80, 415-428.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eberle, A. B., Lykke-Andersen, S., Muhlemann, O., &amp; Jensen, T. H. (2009). SMG6 promotes endonucleolytic cleavage of nonsense mRNA in human cells. Nature Structural &amp; Molecular Biology, 16, 49-55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feldman, E. L., Goutman, S. A., Petri, S., Mazzini, L., Savelieff, M. G., Shaw, P. J., &amp; Sobue, G. (2022). Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet, 400, 1363-1380.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fifita, J. A., Zhang, K. Y., Galper, J., Williams, K. L., McCann, E. P., Hogan, A. L., Saunders, N., Bauer, D., Tarr, I. S., Pamphlett, R., Nicholson, G. A., Rowe, D., Yang, S., &amp; Blair, I. P. (2017). Genetic and pathological assessment of hnRNPA1, hnRNPA2/B1, and hnRNPA3 in familial and sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurodegenerative Diseases, 17, 304-312.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fratta, P., Mizielinska, S., Nicoll, A. J., Zloh, M., Fisher, E., Parkinson, G., &amp; Isaacs, A. M. (2012). C9orf72 hexanucleotide repeat associated with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal dementia forms RNA G-quadruplexes. Scientific Reports, 2, 1-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frick, P., Sellier, C., Mackenzie, I. R. A., Cheng, C. Y., Tahraoui-Bories, J., Martinat, C., Pasterkamp, R. J., Prudlo, J., Edbauer, D., Oulad-Abdelghani, M., Feederle, R., Charlet-Berguerand, N., &amp; Neumann, M. (2018). Novel antibodies reveal presynaptic localization of C9orf72 protein and reduced protein levels in C9orf72 mutation carriers. Acta Neuropathologica Communications, 6, 72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gendron, T. F., Bieniek, K. F., Zhang, Y. J., Jansen-West, K., Ash, P. E. A., Caulfield, T., Daughrity, L., Dunmore, J. H., Castanedes-Casey, M., Chew, J., Cosio, D. M., van Blitterswijk, M., Lee, W. C., Rademakers, R., Boylan, K. B., Dickson, D. W., &amp; Petrucelli, L. (2013). Antisense transcripts of the expanded C9ORF72 hexanucleotide repeat form nuclear RNA foci and undergo repeat-associated non-ATG translation in c9FTD/ALS. Acta Neuropathologica, 126, 829-844.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gijselinck, I., Van Langenhove, T., van der Zee, J., Sleegers, K., Philtjens, S., Kleinberger, G., Janssens, J., Bettens, K., Van Cauwenberghe, C., Pereson, S., Engelborghs, S., Sieben, A., De Jonghe, P., Vandenberghe, R., Santens, P., De Bleecker, J., Maes, G., Baumer, V., Dillen, L., &#x2026; Van Broeckhoven, C. (2012). A C9orf72 promoter repeat expansion in a Flanders-Belgian cohort with disorders of the frontotemporal lobar degeneration-amyotrophic lateral sclerosis spectrum: A gene identification study. Lancet Neurology, 11, 54-65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorno-Tempini, M. L., Hillis, A. E., Weintraub, S., Kertesz, A., Mendez, M., Cappa, S. F., Ogar, J. M., Rohrer, J. D., Black, S., Boeve, B. F., Manes, F., Dronkers, N. F., Vandenberghe, R., Rascovsky, K., Patterson, K., Miller, B. L., Knopman, D. S., Hodges, J. R., Mesulam, M. M., &amp; Grossman, M. (2011). Classification of primary progressive aphasia and its variants. Neurology, 76, 1006-1014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green, K. M., Glineburg, M. R., Kearse, M. G., Flores, B. N., Linsalata, A. E., Fedak, S. J., Goldstrohm, A. C., Barmada, S. J., &amp; Todd, P. K. (2017). RAN translation at C9orf72-associated repeat expansions is selectively enhanced by the integrated stress response. Nature Communications, 8, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green, K. M., Miller, S. L., Malik, I., &amp; Todd, P. K. (2022). Non-canonical initiation factors modulate repeat-associated non-AUG translation. Human Molecular Genetics, 31, 2521-2534.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green, K. M., Sheth, U. J., Flores, B. N., Wright, S. E., Sutter, A. B., Kearse, M. G., Barmada, S. J., Ivanova, M. I., &amp; Todd, P. K. (2019). High-throughput screening yields several small-molecule inhibitors of repeat-associated non-AUG translation. Journal of Biological Chemistry, 294, 18624-18638.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo, Q., Lehmer, C., Martinez-Sanchez, A., Rudack, T., Beck, F., Hartmann, H., Perez-Berlanga, M., Frottin, F., Hipp, M. S., Hartl, F. U., Edbauer, D., Baumeister, W., &amp; Fernandez-Busnadiego, R. (2018). In situ structure of neuronal C9orf72 poly-GA aggregates reveals proteasome recruitment. Cell, 172(696-705), e612.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haeusler, A. R., Donnelly, C. J., Periz, G., Simko, E. A. J., Shaw, P. G., Kim, M. S., Maragakis, N. J., Troncoso, J. C., Pandey, A., Sattler, R., Rothstein, J. D., &amp; Wang, J. (2014). C9orf72 nucleotide repeat structures initiate molecular cascades of disease. Nature, 507, 195-200.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartmann, H., Hornburg, D., Czuppa, M., Bader, J., Michaelsen, M., Farny, D., Arzberger, T., Mann, M., Meissner, F., &amp; Edbauer, D. (2018). Proteomics and C9orf72 neuropathology identify ribosomes as poly-GR/PR interactors driving toxicity. Life Science Alliance, 1, e201800070.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayes, L. R., Duan, L., Bowen, K., Kalab, P., &amp; Rothstein, J. D. (2020). C9orf72 arginine-rich dipeptide repeat proteins disrupt karyopherin-mediated nuclear import. eLife, 9, 51685.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hutten, S., Usluer, S., Bourgeois, B., Simonetti, F., Odeh, H. M., Fare, C. M., Czuppa, M., Hruska-Plochan, M., Hofweber, M., Polymenidou, M., Shorter, J., Edbauer, D., Madl, T., &amp; Dormann, D. (2020). Nuclear import receptors directly bind to arginine-rich dipeptide repeat proteins and suppress their pathological interactions. Cell Reports, 33, 108538.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang, J., Zhu, Q., Gendron, T. F., Saberi, S., McAlonis-Downes, M., Seelman, A., Stauffer, J. E., Jafar-nejad, P., Drenner, K., Schulte, D., Chun, S., Sun, S., Ling, S. C., Myers, B., Engelhardt, J., Katz, M., Baughn, M., Platoshyn, O., Marsala, M., &#x2026; Lagier-Tourenne, C. (2016). Gain of toxicity from ALS/FTD-linked repeat expansions in C9ORF72 is alleviated by antisense oligonucleotides targeting GGGGCC-containing RNAs. Neuron, 90, 535-550.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang, Y. X., Cao, Q., Sawaya, M. R., Abskharon, R., Ge, P., DeTure, M., Dickson, D. W., Fu, J. Y., Ogorzalek Loo, R. R., Loo, J. A., &amp; Eisenberg, D. S. (2022). Amyloid fibrils in FTLD-TDP are composed of TMEM106B and not TDP-43. Nature, 605, 304-309.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jovicic, A., Mertens, J., Boeynaems, S., Bogaert, E., Chai, N., Yamada, S. B., Paul, J. W., 3rd, Sun, S., Herdy, J. R., Bieri, G., Kramer, N. J., Gage, F. H., Van Den Bosch, L., Robberecht, W., &amp; Gitler, A. D. (2015). Modifiers of C9orf72 dipeptide repeat toxicity connect nucleocytoplasmic transport defects to FTD/ALS. Nature Neuroscience, 18, 1226-1229.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanekura, K., Yagi, T., Cammack, A. J., Mahadevan, J., Kuroda, M., Harms, M. B., Miller, T. M., &amp; Urano, F. (2016). Poly-dipeptides encoded by the C9ORF72 repeats block global protein translation. Human Molecular Genetics, 25, 1803-1813.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawabe, Y., Mori, K., Yamashita, T., Gotoh, S., &amp; Ikeda, M. (2020). The RNA exosome complex degrades expanded hexanucleotide repeat RNA in C9orf72 FTLD/ALS. The EMBO Journal, 39, e102700.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khosravi, B., Hartmann, H., May, S., Mohl, C., Ederle, H., Michaelsen, M., Schludi, M. H., Dormann, D., &amp; Edbauer, D. (2017). Cytoplasmic poly-GA aggregates impair nuclear import of TDP-43 in C9orf72 ALS/FTLD. Human Molecular Genetics, 26, 790-800.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kramer, N. J., Haney, M. S., Morgens, D. W., Jovi&#x10d;i&#x107;, A., Couthouis, J., Li, A., Ousey, J., Ma, R., Bieri, G., Tsui, C. K., Shi, Y., Hertz, N. T., Tessier-Lavigne, M., Ichida, J. K., Bassik, M. C., &amp; Gitler, A. D. (2018). CRISPR-Cas9 screens in human cells and primary neurons identify modifiers of C9ORF72 dipeptide-repeat-protein toxicity. Nature Genetics, 50, 603-612.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kriachkov, V., Ormsby, A. R., Kusnadi, E. P., McWilliam, H. E. G., Mintern, J. D., Amarasinghe, S. L., Ritchie, M. E., Furic, L., &amp; Hatters, D. M. (2023). Arginine-rich C9ORF72 ALS proteins stall ribosomes in a manner distinct from a canonical ribosome-associated quality control substrate. The Journal of Biological Chemistry, 299, 102774.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurosaki, T., Popp, M. W., &amp; Maquat, L. E. (2019). Quality and quantity control of gene expression by nonsense-mediated mRNA decay. Nature Reviews Molecular Cell Biology, 20, 406-420.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwon, I., Xiang, S., Kato, M., Wu, L., Theodoropoulos, P., Wang, T., Kim, J., Yun, J., Xie, Y., &amp; McKnight, S. L. (2014). Poly-dipeptides encoded by the C9orf72 repeats bind nucleoli, impede RNA biogenesis, and kill cells. Science, 345, 1139-1145.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>LaClair, K. D., Zhou, Q., Michaelsen, M., Wefers, B., Brill, M. S., Janjic, A., Rathkolb, B., Farny, D., Cygan, M., de Angelis, M. H., Wurst, W., Neumann, M., Enard, W., Misgeld, T., Arzberger, T., &amp; Edbauer, D. (2020). Congenic expression of poly-GA but not poly-PR in mice triggers selective neuron loss and interferon responses found in C9orf72 ALS. Acta Neuropathologica, 140, 121-142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lagier-Tourenne, C., Baughn, M., Rigo, F., Sun, S., Liu, P., Li, H. R., Jiang, J., Watt, A. T., Chun, S., Katz, M., Qiu, J., Sun, Y., Ling, S. C., Zhu, Q., Polymenidou, M., Drenner, K., Artates, J. W., McAlonis-Downes, M., Markmiller, S., &#x2026; Ravits, J. (2013). Targeted degradation of sense and antisense C9orf72 RNA foci as therapy for ALS and frontotemporal degeneration. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 110, E4530-E4539.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lampasona, A., Almeida, S., &amp; Gao, F.-B. (2021). Translation of the poly (GR) frame in C9ORF72-ALS/FTD is regulated by cis-elements involved in alternative splicing. Neurobiology of Aging, 105, 327-332.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, K. H., Zhang, P., Kim, H. J., Mitrea, D. M., Sarkar, M., Freibaum, B. D., Cika, J., Coughlin, M., Messing, J., Molliex, A., Maxwell, B. A., Kim, N. C., Temirov, J., Moore, J., Kolaitis, R. M., Shaw, T. I., Bai, B., Peng, J., Kriwacki, R. W., &amp; Taylor, J. P. (2016). C9orf72 dipeptide repeats impair the assembly, dynamics, and function of membrane-less organelles. Cell, 167, 774-788 e717.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, Y. B., Baskaran, P., Gomez-Deza, J., Chen, H. J., Nishimura, A. L., Smith, B. N., Troakes, C., Adachi, Y., Stepto, A., Petrucelli, L., Gallo, J. M., Hirth, F., Rogelj, B., Guthrie, S., &amp; Shaw, C. E. (2017). C9orf72 poly GA RAN-translated protein plays a key role in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis via aggregation and toxicity. Human Molecular Genetics, 26, 4765-4777.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, Y. B., Chen, H. J., Peres, J. N., Gomez-Deza, J., Attig, J., &#x160;talekar, M., Troakes, C., Nishimura, A. L., Scotter, E. L., Vance, C., Adachi, Y., Sardone, V., Miller, J. W., Smith, B. N., Gallo, J. M., Ule, J., Hirth, F., Rogelj, B., Houart, C., &amp; Shaw, C. E. (2013). Hexanucleotide repeats in ALS/FTD form length-dependent RNA foci, sequester RNA binding proteins, and are neurotoxic. Cell Reports, 5, 1178-1186.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leeds, P., Peltz, S. W., Jacobson, A., &amp; Culbertson, M. R. (1991). The product of the yeast UPF1 gene is required for rapid turnover of mRNAs containing a premature translational termination codon. Genes &amp; Development, 5, 2303-2314.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, S., Wu, Z., Tantray, I., Li, Y., Chen, S., Dong, J., Glynn, S., Vogel, H., Snyder, M., &amp; Lu, B. (2020). Quality-control mechanisms targeting translationally stalled and C-terminally extended poly(GR) associated with ALS/FTD. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 117, 25104-25115.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Licata, N. V., Cristofani, R., Salomonsson, S., Wilson, K. M., Kempthorne, L., Vaizoglu, D., D'Agostino, V. G., Pollini, D., Loffredo, R., Pancher, M., Adami, V., Bellosta, P., Ratti, A., Viero, G., Quattrone, A., Isaacs, A. M., Poletti, A., &amp; Provenzani, A. (2022). C9orf72 ALS/FTD dipeptide repeat protein levels are reduced by small molecules that inhibit PKA or enhance protein degradation. The EMBO Journal, 41, e105026.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, Y., Mori, E., Kato, M., Xiang, S., Wu, L., Kwon, I., &amp; McKnight, S. L. (2016). Toxic PR poly-dipeptides encoded by the C9orf72 repeat expansion target LC domain polymers. Cell, 167, 789-802 e712.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, H., Lu, Y.-N., Paul, T., Periz, G., Banco, M. T., Ferr&#xe9;-D'Amar&#xe9;, A. R., Rothstein, J. D., Hayes, L. R., Myong, S., &amp; Wang, J. (2021). A helicase unwinds hexanucleotide repeat RNA G-quadruplexes and facilitates repeat-associated non-AUG translation. Journal of the American Chemical Society, 143, 7368-7379.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Y., Andreucci, A., Iwamoto, N., Yin, Y., Yang, H., Liu, F., Bulychev, A., Hu, X. S., Lin, X., Lamore, S., Patil, S., Mohapatra, S., Purcell-Estabrook, E., Taborn, K., Dale, E., &amp; Vargeese, C. (2022). Preclinical evaluation of WVE-004, aninvestigational stereopure oligonucleotide forthe treatment of C9orf72-associated ALS or FTD. Molecular Therapy-Nucleic Acids, 28, 558-570.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Y., Dodart, J. C., Tran, H., Berkovitch, S., Braun, M., Byrne, M., Durbin, A. F., Hu, X. S., Iwamoto, N., Jang, H. G., Kandasamy, P., Liu, F., Longo, K., Ruschel, J., Shelke, J., Yang, H., Yin, Y., Donner, A., Zhong, Z., &#x2026; Brown, R. H., Jr. (2021). Variant-selective stereopure oligonucleotides protect against pathologies associated with C9orf72-repeat expansion in preclinical models. Nature Communications, 12, 847.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Y., Huang, Z., Liu, H., Ji, Z., Arora, A., Cai, D., Wang, H., Liu, M., Simko, E. A. J., Zhang, Y., Periz, G., Liu, Z., &amp; Wang, J. (2023). DNA-initiated epigenetic cascades driven by C9orf72 hexanucleotide repeat. Neuron, 111, 1205-1221.e9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loh, B., Jonas, S., &amp; Izaurralde, E. (2013). The SMG5-SMG7 heterodimer directly recruits the CCR4-NOT deadenylase complex to mRNAs containing nonsense codons via interaction with POP2. Genes &amp; Development, 27, 2125-2138.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loveland, A. B., Svidritskiy, E., Susorov, D., Lee, S., Park, A., Zvornicanin, S., Demo, G., Gao, F.-B., &amp; Korostelev, A. A. (2022). Ribosome inhibition by C9ORF72-ALS/FTD-associated poly-PR and poly-GR proteins revealed by cryo-EM. Nature Communications, 13, 1-13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackenzie, I. R., Arzberger, T., Kremmer, E., Troost, D., Lorenzl, S., Mori, K., Weng, S. M., Haass, C., Kretzschmar, H. A., Edbauer, D., &amp; Neumann, M. (2013). Dipeptide repeat protein pathology in C9ORF72 mutation cases: Clinico-pathological correlations. Acta Neuropathologica, 126, 859-879.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackenzie, I. R., Frick, P., Grasser, F. A., Gendron, T. F., Petrucelli, L., Cashman, N. R., Edbauer, D., Kremmer, E., Prudlo, J., Troost, D., &amp; Neumann, M. (2015). Quantitative analysis and clinico-pathological correlations of different dipeptide repeat protein pathologies in C9ORF72 mutation carriers. Acta Neuropathologica, 130, 845-861.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackenzie, I. R., Neumann, M., Baborie, A., Sampathu, D. M., Du Plessis, D., Jaros, E., Perry, R. H., Trojanowski, J. Q., Mann, D. M., &amp; Lee, V. M. (2011). A harmonized classification system for FTLD-TDP pathology. Acta Neuropathologica, 122, 111-113.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mann, D. M., Rollinson, S., Robinson, A., Bennion Callister, J., Thompson, J. C., Snowden, J. S., Gendron, T., Petrucelli, L., Masuda-Suzukake, M., Hasegawa, M., Davidson, Y., &amp; Pickering-Brown, S. (2013). Dipeptide repeat proteins are present in the p62 positive inclusions in patients with frontotemporal lobar degeneration and motor neurone disease associated with expansions in C9ORF72. Acta Neuropathologica Communications, 1, 68.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathieu, C., Pappu, R. V., &amp; Taylor, J. P. (2020). Beyond aggregation: Pathological phase transitions in neurodegenerative disease. Science, 370, 56-60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>May, S., Hornburg, D., Schludi, M. H., Arzberger, T., Rentzsch, K., Schwenk, B. M., Gr&#xe4;sser, F. A., Mori, K., Kremmer, E., Banzhaf-Strathmann, J., Mann, M., Meissner, F., &amp; Edbauer, D. (2014). C9orf72 FTLD/ALS-associated Gly-ala dipeptide repeat proteins cause neuronal toxicity and Unc119 sequestration. Acta Neuropathologica, 128, 485-503.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McEachin, Z. T., Gendron, T. F., Raj, N., Garc&#xed;a-Murias, M., Banerjee, A., Purcell, R. H., Ward, P. J., Todd, T. W., Merritt-Garza, M. E., Jansen-West, K., Hales, C. M., Garc&#xed;a-Sobrino, T., Quint&#xe1;ns, B., Holler, C. J., Taylor, G., San Mill&#xe1;n, B., Teijeira, S., Yamashita, T., Ohkubo, R., &#x2026; Bassell, G. J. (2020). Chimeric peptide species contribute to divergent dipeptide repeat pathology in c9ALS/FTD and SCA36. Neuron, 107(292-305), e296.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mizielinska, S., Gr&#xf6;nke, S., Niccoli, T., Ridler, C. E., Clayton, E. L., Devoy, A., Moens, T., Norona, F. E., Woollacott, I. O. C., Pietrzyk, J., Cleverley, K., Nicoll, A. J., Pickering-Brown, S., Dols, J., Cabecinha, M., Hendrich, O., Fratta, P., Fisher, E. M. C., Partridge, L., &amp; Isaacs, A. M. (2014). C9orf72 repeat expansions cause neurodegeneration in drosophila through arginine-rich proteins. Science, 345, 1192-1194.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moens, T. G., Mizielinska, S., Niccoli, T., Mitchell, J. S., Thoeng, A., Ridler, C. E., Gr&#xf6;nke, S., Esser, J., Heslegrave, A., Zetterberg, H., Partridge, L., &amp; Isaacs, A. M. (2018). Sense and antisense RNA are not toxic in drosophila models of C9orf72-associated ALS/FTD. Acta Neuropathologica, 135, 445-457.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moens, T. G., Niccoli, T., Wilson, K. M., Atilano, M. L., Birsa, N., Gittings, L. M., Holbling, B. V., Dyson, M. C., Thoeng, A., Neeves, J., Glaria, I., Yu, L., Bussmann, J., Storkebaum, E., Pardo, M., Choudhary, J. S., Fratta, P., Partridge, L., &amp; Isaacs, A. M. (2019). C9orf72 arginine-rich dipeptide proteins interact with ribosomal proteins in vivo to induce a toxic translational arrest that is rescued by eIF1A. Acta Neuropathologica, 137, 487-500.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monteuuis, G., Wong, J. J. L., Bailey, C. G., Schmitz, U., &amp; Rasko, J. E. J. (2019). The changing paradigm of intron retention: Regulation, ramifications and recipes. Nucleic Acids Research, 47, 11497-11513.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore, S., Alsop, E., Lorenzini, I., Starr, A., Rabichow, B. E., Mendez, E., Levy, J. L., Burciu, C., Reiman, R., Chew, J., Belzil, V. V., W. Dickson, D., Robertson, J., Staats, K. A., Ichida, J. K., Petrucelli, L., van Keuren-Jensen, K., &amp; Sattler, R. (2019). ADAR2 mislocalization and widespread RNA editing aberrations in C9orf72-mediated ALS/FTD. Acta Neuropathologica, 138, 49-65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mori, K., Arzberger, T., Grasser, F. A., Gijselinck, I., May, S., Rentzsch, K., Weng, S. M., Schludi, M. H., van der Zee, J., Cruts, M., Van Broeckhoven, C., Kremmer, E., Kretzschmar, H. A., Haass, C., &amp; Edbauer, D. (2013). Bidirectional transcripts of the expanded C9orf72 hexanucleotide repeat are translated into aggregating dipeptide repeat proteins. Acta Neuropathologica, 126, 881-893.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mori, K., Gotoh, S., Yamashita, T., Uozumi, R., Kawabe, Y., Tagami, S., Kamp, F., Nuscher, B., Edbauer, D., Haass, C., Nagai, Y., &amp; Ikeda, M. (2021). The porphyrin TMPyP4 inhibits elongation during the noncanonical translation of the FTLD/ALS-associated GGGGCC repeat in the C9orf72 gene. The Journal of Biological Chemistry, 297, 101120.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mori, K., &amp; Ikeda, M. (2022). Biological basis and psychiatric symptoms in frontotemporal dementia. Psychiatry and Clinical Neurosciences, 76, 351-360.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mori, K., Lammich, S., Mackenzie, I. R., Forne, I., Zilow, S., Kretzschmar, H., Edbauer, D., Janssens, J., Kleinberger, G., Cruts, M., Herms, J., Neumann, M., Van Broeckhoven, C., Arzberger, T., &amp; Haass, C. (2013). hnRNP A3 binds to GGGGCC repeats and is a constituent of p62-positive/TDP43-negative inclusions in the hippocampus of patients with C9orf72 mutations. Acta Neuropathologica, 125, 413-423.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mori, K., Nihei, Y., Arzberger, T., Zhou, Q., Mackenzie, I. R., Hermann, A., Hanisch, F., German Consortium for Frontotemporal Lobar Degeneration, Bavarian Brain Banking Alliance, Kamp, F., Nuscher, B., Orozco, D., Edbauer, D., &amp; Haass, C. (2016). Reduced hnRNPA3 increases C9orf72 repeat RNA levels and dipeptide-repeat protein deposition. EMBO Reports, 17, 1314-1325.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mori, K., Weng, S. M., Arzberger, T., May, S., Rentzsch, K., Kremmer, E., Schmid, B., Kretzschmar, H. A., Cruts, M., van Broeckhoven, C., Haass, C., &amp; Edbauer, D. (2013). The C9orf72 GGGGCC repeat is translated into aggregating dipeptide-repeat proteins in FTLD/ALS. Science, 339, 1335-1338.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morita, M., Al-Chalabi, A., Andersen, P. M., Hosler, B., Sapp, P., Englund, E., Mitchell, J. E., Habgood, J. J., de Belleroche, J., Xi, J., Jongjaroenprasert, W., Horvitz, H. R., Gunnarsson, L. G., &amp; Brown, R. H., Jr. (2006). A locus on chromosome 9p confers susceptibility to ALS and frontotemporal dementia. Neurology, 66, 839-844.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nanaura, H., Kawamukai, H., Fujiwara, A., Uehara, T., Aiba, Y., Nakanishi, M., Shiota, T., Hibino, M., Wiriyasermkul, P., Kikuchi, S., Nagata, R., Matsubayashi, M., Shinkai, Y., Niwa, T., Mannen, T., Morikawa, N., Iguchi, N., Kiriyama, T., Morishima, K., &#x2026; Mori, E. (2021). C9orf72-derived arginine-rich poly-dipeptides impede phase modifiers. Nature Communications, 12, 5301.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neary, D., Snowden, J. S., Gustafson, L., Passant, U., Stuss, D., Black, S., Freedman, M., Kertesz, A., Robert, P. H., Albert, M., Boone, K., Miller, B. L., Cummings, J., &amp; Benson, D. F. (1998). Frontotemporal lobar degeneration: a consensus on clinical diagnostic criteria. Neurology, 51, 1546-1554.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nedelsky, N. B., &amp; Taylor, J. P. (2022). Pathological phase transitions in ALS-FTD impair dynamic RNA-protein granules. RNA, 28, 97-113.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niblock, M., Smith, B. N., Lee, Y.-B., Sardone, V., Topp, S., Troakes, C., al-Sarraj, S., Leblond, C. S., Dion, P. A., Rouleau, G. A., Shaw, C. E., &amp; Gallo, J. M. (2016). Retention of hexanucleotide repeat-containing intron in C9orf72 mRNA: Implications for the pathogenesis of ALS/FTD. Acta Neuropathologica Communications, 4, 1-12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nihei, Y., Mori, K., Werner, G., Arzberger, T., Zhou, Q., Khosravi, B., Japtok, J., Hermann, A., Sommacal, A., Weber, M., German Consortium for Frontotemporal Lobar, D, Bavarian Brain Banking, A, Kamp, F., Nuscher, B., Edbauer, D., &amp; Haass, C. (2020). Poly-glycine-alanine exacerbates C9orf72 repeat expansion-mediated DNA damage via sequestration of phosphorylated ATM and loss of nuclear hnRNPA3. Acta Neuropathologica, 139, 99-118.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nonaka, T., Masuda-Suzukake, M., Hosokawa, M., Shimozawa, A., Hirai, S., Okado, H., &amp; Hasegawa, M. (2018). C9ORF72 dipeptide repeat poly-GA inclusions promote intracellular aggregation of phosphorylated TDP-43. Human Molecular Genetics, 27, 2658-2670.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nordin, A., Akimoto, C., Wuolikainen, A., Alstermark, H., Forsberg, K., Baumann, P., Pinto, S., de Carvalho, M., H&#xfc;bers, A., Nordin, F., Ludolph, A. C., Weishaupt, J. H., Meyer, T., Grehl, T., Schweikert, K., Weber, M., Burkhardt, C., Neuwirth, C., Holm&#xf8;y, T., &#x2026; Andersen, P. M. (2017). Sequence variations in C9orf72 downstream of the hexanucleotide repeat region and its effect on repeat-primed PCR interpretation: A large multinational screening study. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener, 18, 256-264.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Connell, M. A., Krause, S., Higuchi, M., Hsuan, J. J., Totty, N. F., Jenny, A., &amp; Keller, W. (1995). Cloning of cDNAs encoding mammalian double-stranded RNA-specific adenosine deaminase. Molecular and Cellular Biology, 15, 1389-1397.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohki, Y., Wenninger-Weinzierl, A., Hruscha, A., Asakawa, K., Kawakami, K., Haass, C., Edbauer, D., &amp; Schmid, B. (2017). Glycine-alanine dipeptide repeat protein contributes to toxicity in a zebrafish model of C9orf72 associated neurodegeneration. Molecular Neurodegeneration, 12, 6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Rourke, J. G., Bogdanik, L., Yanez, A., Lall, D., Wolf, A. J., Muhammad, A. K., Ho, R., Carmona, S., Vit, J. P., Zarrow, J., Kim, K. J., Bell, S., Harms, M. B., Miller, T. M., Dangler, C. A., Underhill, D. M., Goodridge, H. S., Lutz, C. M., &amp; Baloh, R. H. (2016). C9orf72 is required for proper macrophage and microglial function in mice. Science, 351, 1324-1329.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ortega, J. A., Daley, E. L., Kour, S., Samani, M., Tellez, L., Smith, H. S., Hall, E. A., Esengul, Y. T., Tsai, Y. H., Gendron, T. F., Donnelly, C. J., Siddique, T., Savas, J. N., Pandey, U. B., &amp; Kiskinis, E. (2020). Nucleocytoplasmic proteomic analysis uncovers eRF1 and nonsense-mediated decay as modifiers of ALS/FTD C9orf72 toxicity. Neuron, 106, 90-107.e113.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park, J., Lee, J., Kim, J.-H., Lee, J., Park, H., &amp; Lim, C. (2021). ZNF598 co-translationally titrates poly (GR) protein implicated in the pathogenesis of C9ORF72-associated ALS/FTD. Nucleic Acids Research, 49, 11294-11311.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perneel, J., Neumann, M., Heeman, B., Cheung, S., van den Broeck, M., Wynants, S., Baker, M., Vicente, C. T., Faura, J., Rademakers, R., &amp; Mackenzie, I. R. A. (2023). Accumulation of TMEM106B C-terminal fragments in neurodegenerative disease and aging. Acta Neuropathologica, 145, 285-302.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proudfoot, M., Gutowski, N. J., Edbauer, D., Hilton, D. A., Stephens, M., Rankin, J., &amp; Mackenzie, I. R. (2014). Early dipeptide repeat pathology in a frontotemporal dementia kindred with C9ORF72 mutation and intellectual disability. Acta Neuropathologica, 127, 451-458.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prudencio, M., Belzil, V. V., Batra, R., Ross, C. A., Gendron, T. F., Pregent, L. J., Murray, M. E., Overstreet, K. K., Piazza-Johnston, A. E., Desaro, P., Bieniek, K. F., DeTure, M., Lee, W. C., Biendarra, S. M., Davis, M. D., Baker, M. C., Perkerson, R. B., van Blitterswijk, M., Stetler, C. T., &#x2026; Petrucelli, L. (2015). Distinct brain transcriptome profiles in C9orf72-associated and sporadic ALS. Nature Neuroscience, 18, 1175-1182.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quaegebeur, A., Glaria, I., Lashley, T., &amp; Isaacs, A. M. (2020). Soluble and insoluble dipeptide repeat protein measurements in C9orf72-frontotemporal dementia brains show regional differential solubility and correlation of poly-GR with clinical severity. Acta Neuropathologica Communications, 8, 1-13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramesh, N., Daley, E. L., Gleixner, A. M., Mann, J. R., Kour, S., Mawrie, D., Anderson, E. N., Kofler, J., Donnelly, C. J., Kiskinis, E., &amp; Pandey, U. B. (2020). RNA dependent suppression of C9orf72 ALS/FTD associated neurodegeneration by Matrin-3. Acta Neuropathologica Communications, 8, 177.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rascovsky, K., Hodges, J. R., Knopman, D., Mendez, M. F., Kramer, J. H., Neuhaus, J., van Swieten, J. C., Seelaar, H., Dopper, E. G. P., Onyike, C. U., Hillis, A. E., Josephs, K. A., Boeve, B. F., Kertesz, A., Seeley, W. W., Rankin, K. P., Johnson, J. K., Gorno-Tempini, M. L., Rosen, H., &#x2026; Miller, B. L. (2011). Sensitivity of revised diagnostic criteria for the behavioural variant of frontotemporal dementia. Brain, 134, 2456-2477.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renton, A. E., Majounie, E., Waite, A., Sim&#xf3;n-S&#xe1;nchez, J., Rollinson, S., Gibbs, J. R., Schymick, J. C., Laaksovirta, H., van Swieten, J., Myllykangas, L., Kalimo, H., Paetau, A., Abramzon, Y., Remes, A. M., Kaganovich, A., Scholz, S. W., Duckworth, J., Ding, J., Harmer, D. W., &#x2026; Traynor, B. J. (2011). A hexanucleotide repeat expansion in C9ORF72 is the cause of chromosome 9p21-linked ALS-FTD. Neuron, 72, 257-268.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riemslagh, F. W., Lans, H., Seelaar, H., Severijnen, L. A. W. F. M., Melhem, S., Vermeulen, W., Aronica, E., Pasterkamp, R. J., van Swieten, J. C., &amp; Willemsen, R. (2019). HR23B pathology preferentially co-localizes with p62, pTDP-43 and poly-GA in C9ORF72-linked frontotemporal dementia and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathologica Communications, 7, 39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ringholz, G. M., Appel, S. H., Bradshaw, M., Cooke, N. A., Mosnik, D. M., &amp; Schulz, P. E. (2005). Prevalence and patterns of cognitive impairment in sporadic ALS. Neurology, 65, 586-590.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rollinson, S., Callister, J. B., Young, K., Ryan, S. J., Druyeh, R., Rohrer, J. D., Snowden, J., Richardson, A., Jones, M., &amp; Harris, J. (2015). A small deletion in C9orf72 hides a proportion of expansion carriers in FTLD. Neurobiology of Aging, 36(1601), e1601-e1601.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossi, S., Serrano, A., Gerbino, V., Giorgi, A., di Francesco, L., Nencini, M., Bozzo, F., Schinin&#xe0;, M. E., Bagni, C., Cestra, G., Carr&#xec;, M. T., Achsel, T., &amp; Cozzolino, M. (2015). Nuclear accumulation of mRNAs underlies G4C2-repeat-induced translational repression in a cellular model of C9orf72 ALS. Journal of Cell Science, 128, 1787-1799.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saberi, S., Stauffer, J. E., Jiang, J., Garcia, S. D., Taylor, A. E., Schulte, D., Ohkubo, T., Schloffman, C. L., Maldonado, M., Baughn, M., Rodriguez, M. J., Pizzo, D., Cleveland, D., &amp; Ravits, J. (2018). Sense-encoded poly-GR dipeptide repeat proteins correlate to neurodegeneration and uniquely co-localize with TDP-43 in dendrites of repeat-expanded C9orf72 amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathologica, 135, 459-474.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakae, N., Bieniek, K. F., Zhang, Y. J., Ross, K., Gendron, T. F., Murray, M. E., Rademakers, R., Petrucelli, L., &amp; Dickson, D. W. (2018). Poly-GR dipeptide repeat polymers correlate with neurodegeneration and clinicopathological subtypes in C9ORF72-related brain disease. Acta Neuropathologica Communications, 6, 63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sareen, D., O'Rourke, J. G., Meera, P., Muhammad, A. K., Grant, S., Simpkinson, M., Bell, S., Carmona, S., Ornelas, L., Sahabian, A., Gendron, T., Petrucelli, L., Baughn, M., Ravits, J., Harms, M. B., Rigo, F., Bennett, C. F., Otis, T. S., Svendsen, C. N., &amp; Baloh, R. H. (2013). Targeting RNA foci in iPSC-derived motor neurons from ALS patients with a C9ORF72 repeat expansion. Science Translational Medicine, 5, 208ra149.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schleich, S., Strassburger, K., Janiesch, P. C., Koledachkina, T., Miller, K. K., Haneke, K., Cheng, Y. S., K&#xfc;chler, K., Stoecklin, G., Duncan, K. E., &amp; Teleman, A. A. (2014). DENR-MCT-1 promotes translation re-initiation downstream of uORFs to control tissue growth. Nature, 512, 208-212.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schludi, M. H., May, S., Grasser, F. A., Rentzsch, K., Kremmer, E., Kupper, C., Klopstock, T., German Consortium for Frontotemporal Lobar, D, Bavarian Brain Banking, A, Arzberger, T., &amp; Edbauer, D. (2015). Distribution of dipeptide repeat proteins in cellular models and C9orf72 mutation cases suggests link to transcriptional silencing. Acta Neuropathologica, 130, 537-555.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schweighauser, M., Arseni, D., Bacioglu, M., Huang, M., L&#xf6;vestam, S., Shi, Y., Yang, Y., Zhang, W., Kotecha, A., Garringer, H. J., Vidal, R., Hallinan, G. I., Newell, K. L., Tarutani, A., Murayama, S., Miyazaki, M., Saito, Y., Yoshida, M., Hasegawa, K., &#x2026; Scheres, S. H. W. (2022). Age-dependent formation of TMEM106B amyloid filaments in human brains. Nature, 605, 310-314.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi, K. Y., Mori, E., Nizami, Z. F., Lin, Y., Kato, M., Xiang, S., Wu, L. C., Ding, M., Yu, Y., Gall, J. G., &amp; McKnight, S. (2017). Toxic PRn poly-dipeptides encoded by the C9orf72 repeat expansion block nuclear import and export. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 114, E1111-E1117.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi, Y., Lin, S., Staats, K. A., Li, Y., Chang, W. H., Hung, S. T., Hendricks, E., Linares, G. R., Wang, Y., Son, E. Y., Wen, X., Kisler, K., Wilkinson, B., Menendez, L., Sugawara, T., Woolwine, P., Huang, M., Cowan, M. J., Ge, B., &#x2026; Ichida, J. K. (2018). Haploinsufficiency leads to neurodegeneration in C9ORF72 ALS/FTD human induced motor neurons. Nature Medicine, 24, 313-325.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simone, R., Balendra, R., Moens, T. G., Preza, E., Wilson, K. M., Heslegrave, A., Woodling, N. S., Niccoli, T., Gilbert-Jaramillo, J., Abdelkarim, S., Clayton, E. L., Clarke, M., Konrad, M. T., Nicoll, A. J., Mitchell, J. S., Calvo, A., Chio, A., Houlden, H., Polke, J. M., &#x2026; Isaacs, A. M. (2018). G-quadruplex-binding small molecules ameliorate C9orf72 FTD/ALS pathology in vitro and in vivo. EMBO Molecular Medicine, 10, 22-31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Snowden, J. S., Rollinson, S., Thompson, J. C., Harris, J. M., Stopford, C. L., Richardson, A. M. T., Jones, M., Gerhard, A., Davidson, Y. S., Robinson, A., Gibbons, L., Hu, Q., DuPlessis, D., Neary, D., Mann, D. M. A., &amp; Pickering-Brown, S. M. (2012). Distinct clinical and pathological characteristics of frontotemporal dementia associated with C9ORF72 mutations. Brain, 135, 693-708.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sonobe, Y., Aburas, J., Krishnan, G., Fleming, A. C., Ghadge, G., Islam, P., Warren, E. C., Gu, Y., Kankel, M. W., Brown, A. E. X., Kiskinis, E., Gendron, T. F., Gao, F. B., Roos, R. P., &amp; Kratsios, P. (2021). A C. elegans model of C9orf72-associated ALS/FTD uncovers a conserved role for eIF2D in RAN translation. Nature Communications, 12, 6025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sonobe, Y., Ghadge, G., Masaki, K., Sendoel, A., Fuchs, E., &amp; Roos, R. P. (2018). Translation of dipeptide repeat proteins from the C9ORF72 expanded repeat is associated with cellular stress. Neurobiology of Disease, 116, 155-165.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su, Z., Zhang, Y., Gendron, T. F., Bauer, P. O., Chew, J., Yang, W. Y., Fostvedt, E., Jansen-West, K., Belzil, V. V., Desaro, P., Johnston, A., Overstreet, K., Oh, S. Y., Todd, P. K., Berry, J. D., Cudkowicz, M. E., Boeve, B. F., Dickson, D., Floeter, M. K., &#x2026; Disney, M. D. (2014). Discovery of a biomarker and lead small molecules to target r(GGGGCC)-associated defects in c9FTD/ALS. Neuron, 83, 1043-1050.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudria-Lopez, E., Koppers, M., de Wit, M., van der Meer, C., Westeneng, H. J., Zundel, C. A. C., Youssef, S. A., Harkema, L., de Bruin, A., Veldink, J. H., van den Berg, L. H., &amp; Pasterkamp, R. J. (2016). Full ablation of C9orf72 in mice causes immune system-related pathology and neoplastic events but no motor neuron defects. Acta Neuropathologica, 132, 145-147.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swinnen, B., Bento-Abreu, A., Gendron, T. F., Boeynaems, S., Bogaert, E., Nuyts, R., Timmers, M., Scheveneels, W., Hersmus, N., Wang, J., Mizielinska, S., Isaacs, A. M., Petrucelli, L., Lemmens, R., van Damme, P., van den Bosch, L., &amp; Robberecht, W. (2018). A zebrafish model for C9orf72 ALS reveals RNA toxicity as a pathogenic mechanism. Acta Neuropathologica, 135, 427-443.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swinnen, B., Robberecht, W., &amp; Van Den Bosch, L. (2020). RNA toxicity in non-coding repeat expansion disorders. The EMBO Journal, 39, e101112.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sznajder, &#x141;. J., Thomas, J. D., Carrell, E. M., Reid, T., McFarland, K. N., Cleary, J. D., Oliveira, R., Nutter, C. A., Bhatt, K., Sobczak, K., Ashizawa, T., Thornton, C. A., Ranum, L. P. W., &amp; Swanson, M. S. (2018). Intron retention induced by microsatellite expansions as a disease biomarker. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, 115, 4234-4239.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tabet, R., Schaeffer, L., Freyermuth, F., Jambeau, M., Workman, M., Lee, C. Z., Lin, C. C., Jiang, J., Jansen-West, K., Abou-Hamdan, H., D&#xe9;saubry, L., Gendron, T., Petrucelli, L., Martin, F., &amp; Lagier-Tourenne, C. (2018). CUG initiation and frameshifting enable production of dipeptide repeat proteins from ALS/FTD C9ORF72 transcripts. Nature Communications, 9, 152.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taminato, T., Takeuchi, T., Ueyama, M., Mori, K., Ikeda, M., Mochizuki, H., &amp; Nagai, Y. (2023). Therapeutic reduction of GGGGCC repeat RNA levels by hnRNPA3 suppresses neurodegeneration in drosophila models of C9orf72-linked ALS/FTD. Human Molecular Genetics, 32, 1673-1682.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomecki, R., Kristiansen, M. S., Lykke-Andersen, S., Chlebowski, A., Larsen, K. M., Szczesny, R. J., Drazkowska, K., Pastula, A., Andersen, J. S., Stepien, P. P., Dziembowski, A., &amp; Jensen, T. H. (2010). The human core exosome interacts with differentially localized processive RNases: hDIS3 and hDIS3L. The EMBO Journal, 29, 2342-2357.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tran, H., Almeida, S., Moore, J., Gendron, T. F., Chalasani, U. D., Lu, Y., du, X., Nickerson, J. A., Petrucelli, L., Weng, Z., &amp; Gao, F. B. (2015). Differential toxicity of nuclear RNA foci versus dipeptide repeat proteins in a drosophila model of C9ORF72 FTD/ALS. Neuron, 87, 1207-1214.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tran, H., Moazami, M. P., Yang, H., McKenna-Yasek, D., Douthwright, C. L., Pinto, C., Metterville, J., Shin, M., Sanil, N., Dooley, C., Puri, A., Weiss, A., Wightman, N., Gray-Edwards, H., Marosfoi, M., King, R. M., Kenderdine, T., Fabris, D., Bowser, R., &#x2026; Brown, R. H., Jr. (2022). Suppression of mutant C9orf72 expression by a potent mixed backbone antisense oligonucleotide. Nature Medicine, 28, 117-124.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tseng, Y.-J., Sandwith, S. N., Green, K. M., Chambers, A. E., Krans, A., Raimer, H. M., Sharlow, M. E., Reisinger, M. A., Richardson, A. E., Routh, E. D., Smaldino, M. A., Wang, Y. H., Vaughn, J. P., Todd, P. K., &amp; Smaldino, P. J. (2021). The RNA helicase DHX36-G4R1 modulates C9orf72 GGGGCC hexanucleotide repeat-associated translation. Journal of Biological Chemistry, 297, 100914.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ursu, A., Baisden, J. T., Bush, J. A., Taghavi, A., Choudhary, S., Zhang, Y. J., Gendron, T. F., Petrucelli, L., Yildirim, I., &amp; Disney, M. D. (2021). A small molecule exploits hidden structural features within the RNA repeat expansion that causes c9ALS/FTD and rescues pathological hallmarks. ACS Chemical Neuroscience, 12, 4076-4089.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Blitterswijk, M., Gendron, T. F., Baker, M. C., DeJesus-Hernandez, M., Finch, N. C. A., Brown, P. H., Daughrity, L. M., Murray, M. E., Heckman, M. G., Jiang, J., Lagier-Tourenne, C., Edbauer, D., Cleveland, D. W., Josephs, K. A., Parisi, J. E., Knopman, D. S., Petersen, R. C., Petrucelli, L., Boeve, B. F., &#x2026; Rademakers, R. (2015). Novel clinical associations with specific C9ORF72 transcripts in patients with repeat expansions in C9ORF72. Acta Neuropathologica, 130, 863-876.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Blitterswijk, M., Mullen, B., Nicholson, A. M., Bieniek, K. F., Heckman, M. G., Baker, M. C., DeJesus-Hernandez, M., Finch, N. C. A., Brown, P. H., Murray, M. E., Hsiung, G. Y. R., Stewart, H., Karydas, A. M., Finger, E., Kertesz, A., Bigio, E. H., Weintraub, S., Mesulam, M., Hatanpaa, K. J., &#x2026; Rademakers, R. (2014). TMEM106B protects C9ORF72 expansion carriers against frontotemporal dementia. Acta Neuropathologica, 127, 397-406.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Zee, J., Gijselinck, I., Dillen, L., van Langenhove, T., Theuns, J., Engelborghs, S., Philtjens, S., Vandenbulcke, M., Sleegers, K., Sieben, A., B&#xe4;umer, V., Maes, G., Corsmit, E., Borroni, B., Padovani, A., Archetti, S., Perneczky, R., Diehl-Schmid, J., de Mendon&#xe7;a, A., &#x2026; European Early-Onset Dementia Consortium. (2013). A pan-European study of the C9orf72 repeat associated with FTLD: Geographic prevalence, genomic instability and intermediate repeats. Human Mutation, 34, 363-373.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van't Spijker, H. M., Stackpole, E. E., Almeida, S., Katsara, O., Liu, B., Shen, K., Schneider, R. J., Gao, F. B., &amp; Richter, J. D. (2022). Ribosome profiling reveals novel regulation of C9ORF72 GGGGCC repeat-containing RNA translation. RNA, 28, 123-138.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vanneste, J., Vercruysse, T., Boeynaems, S., Sicart, A., Van Damme, P., Daelemans, D., &amp; Van Den Bosch, L. (2019). C9orf72-generated poly-GR and poly-PR do not directly interfere with nucleocytoplasmic transport. Scientific Reports, 9, 15728.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viera Ortiz, A. P., Cajka, G., Olatunji, O. A., Mikytuck, B., Shalem, O., &amp; Lee, E. B. (2022). Impaired ribosome-associated quality control of C9orf72 arginine-rich dipeptide-repeat proteins. Brain, awac479.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walker, C., Herranz-Martin, S., Karyka, E., Liao, C., Lewis, K., Elsayed, W., Lukashchuk, V., Chiang, S. C., Ray, S., Mulcahy, P. J., Jurga, M., Tsagakis, I., Iannitti, T., Chandran, J., Coldicott, I., de Vos, K. J., Hassan, M. K., Higginbottom, A., Shaw, P. J., &#x2026; el-Khamisy, S. F. (2017). C9orf72 expansion disrupts ATM-mediated chromosomal break repair. Nature Neuroscience, 20, 1225-1235.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wan, J., Yourshaw, M., Mamsa, H., Rudnik-Sch&#xf6;neborn, S., Menezes, M. P., Hong, J. E., Leong, D. W., Senderek, J., Salman, M. S., Chitayat, D., Seeman, P., von Moers, A., Graul-Neumann, L., Kornberg, A. J., Castro-Gago, M., Sobrido, M. J., Sanefuji, M., Shieh, P. B., Salamon, N., &#x2026; Jen, J. C. (2012). Mutations in the RNA exosome component gene EXOSC3 cause pontocerebellar hypoplasia and spinal motor neuron degeneration. Nature Genetics, 44, 704-708.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Q., Conlon, E. G., Manley, J. L., &amp; Rio, D. C. (2020). Widespread intron retention impairs protein homeostasis in C9orf72 ALS brains. Genome Research, 30, 1705-1715.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, S., Latallo, M. J., Zhang, Z., Huang, B., Bobrovnikov, D. G., Dong, D., Livingston, N. M., Tjoeng, W., Hayes, L. R., Rothstein, J. D., Ostrow, L. W., Wu, B., &amp; Sun, S. (2021). Nuclear export and translation of circular repeat-containing intronic RNA in C9ORF72-ALS/FTD. Nature Communications, 12, 1-14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Z. F., Ursu, A., Childs-Disney, J. L., Guertler, R., Yang, W. Y., Bernat, V., Rzuczek, S. G., Fuerst, R., Zhang, Y. J., Gendron, T. F., Yildirim, I., Dwyer, B. G., Rice, J. E., Petrucelli, L., &amp; Disney, M. D. (2019). The hairpin form of r(G(4)C(2))(exp) in c9ALS/FTD is repeat-associated non-ATG translated and a target for bioactive small molecules. Cell Chemical Biology, 26, 179-190 e112.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wen, X., Tan, W., Westergard, T., Krishnamurthy, K., Markandaiah, S. S., Shi, Y., Lin, S., Shneider, N. A., Monaghan, J., Pandey, U. B., Pasinelli, P., Ichida, J. K., &amp; Trotti, D. (2014). Antisense proline-arginine RAN dipeptides linked to C9ORF72-ALS/FTD form toxic nuclear aggregates that initiate in vitro and in vivo neuronal death. Neuron, 84, 1213-1225.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westergard, T., McAvoy, K., Russell, K., Wen, X., Pang, Y., Morris, B., Pasinelli, P., Trotti, D., &amp; Haeusler, A. (2019). Repeat-associated non-AUG translation in C9orf72-ALS/FTD is driven by neuronal excitation and stress. EMBO Molecular Medicine, 11, e9423.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong, J. J., &amp; Schmitz, U. (2022). Intron retention: Importance, challenges, and opportunities. Trends in Genetics, 38, 789-792.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, W., Bao, P., Jiang, X., Wang, H., Qin, M., Wang, R., Wang, T., Yang, Y., Lorenzini, I., Liao, L., Sattler, R., &amp; Xu, J. (2019). Reactivation of nonsense-mediated mRNA decay protects against C9orf72 dipeptide-repeat neurotoxicity. Brain, 142, 1349-1364.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, Z., Poidevin, M., Li, X., Li, Y., Shu, L., Nelson, D. L., Li, H., Hales, C. M., Gearing, M., Wingo, T. S., &amp; Jin, P. (2013). Expanded GGGGCC repeat RNA associated with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal dementia causes neurodegeneration. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 110, 7778-7783.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamada, S. B., Gendron, T. F., Niccoli, T., Genuth, N. R., Grosely, R., Shi, Y., Glaria, I., Kramer, N. J., Nakayama, L., Fang, S., Dinger, T. J. I., Thoeng, A., Rocha, G., Barna, M., Puglisi, J. D., Partridge, L., Ichida, J. K., Isaacs, A. M., Petrucelli, L., &amp; Gitler, A. D. (2019). RPS25 is required for efficient RAN translation of C9orf72 and other neurodegenerative disease-associated nucleotide repeats. Nature Neuroscience, 22, 1383-1388.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zamiri, B., Reddy, K., Macgregor, R. B., Jr., &amp; Pearson, C. E. (2014). TMPyP4 porphyrin distorts RNA G-quadruplex structures of the disease-associated r(GGGGCC)n repeat of the C9orf72 gene and blocks interaction of RNA-binding proteins. The Journal of Biological Chemistry, 289, 4653-4659.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Y. J., Gendron, T. F., Grima, J. C., Sasaguri, H., Jansen-West, K., Xu, Y. F., Katzman, R. B., Gass, J., Murray, M. E., Shinohara, M., Lin, W. L., Garrett, A., Stankowski, J. N., Daughrity, L., Tong, J., Perkerson, E. A., Yue, M., Chew, J., Castanedes-Casey, M., &#x2026; Petrucelli, L. (2016). C9ORF72 poly(GA) aggregates sequester and impair HR23 and nucleocytoplasmic transport proteins. Nature Neuroscience, 19, 668-677.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Y. J., Jansen-West, K., Xu, Y. F., Gendron, T. F., Bieniek, K. F., Lin, W. L., Sasaguri, H., Caulfield, T., Hubbard, J., Daughrity, L., Chew, J., Belzil, V. V., Prudencio, M., Stankowski, J. N., Castanedes-Casey, M., Whitelaw, E., Ash, P. E. A., DeTure, M., Rademakers, R., &#x2026; Petrucelli, L. (2014). Aggregation-prone c9FTD/ALS poly(GA) RAN-translated proteins cause neurotoxicity by inducing ER stress. Acta Neuropathologica, 128, 505-524.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu, Q., Jiang, J., Gendron, T. F., McAlonis-Downes, M., Jiang, L., Taylor, A., Diaz Garcia, S., Ghosh Dastidar, S., Rodriguez, M. J., King, P., Zhang, Y., la Spada, A. R., Xu, H., Petrucelli, L., Ravits, J., da Cruz, S., Lagier-Tourenne, C., &amp; Cleveland, D. W. (2020). Reduced C9ORF72 function exacerbates gain of toxicity from ALS/FTD-causing repeat expansion in C9orf72. Nature Neuroscience, 23, 615-624.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zu, T., Gibbens, B., Doty, N. S., Gomes-Pereira, M., Huguet, A., Stone, M. D., Margolis, J., Peterson, M., Markowski, T. W., Ingram, M. A. C., Nan, Z., Forster, C., Low, W. C., Schoser, B., Somia, N. V., Clark, H. B., Schmechel, S., Bitterman, P. B., Gourdon, G., &#x2026; Ranum, L. P. W. (2011). Non-ATG-initiated translation directed by microsatellite expansions. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 108, 260-265.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zu, T., Guo, S., Bardhi, O., Ryskamp, D. A., Li, J., Khoramian Tusi, S., Engelbrecht, A., Klippel, K., Chakrabarty, P., Nguyen, L., Golde, T. E., Sonenberg, N., &amp; Ranum, L. P. W. (2020). Metformin inhibits RAN translation through PKR pathway and mitigates disease in C9orf72 ALS/FTD mice. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 117, 18591-18599.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zu, T., Liu, Y., Banez-Coronel, M., Reid, T., Pletnikova, O., Lewis, J., Miller, T. M., Harms, M. B., Falchook, A. E., Subramony, S. H., Ostrow, L. W., Rothstein, J. D., Troncoso, J. C., &amp; Ranum, L. P. (2013). RAN proteins and RNA foci from antisense transcripts in C9ORF72 ALS and frontotemporal dementia. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 110, E4968-E4977.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>