<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37313936</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1998-3751</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>55</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Season>Mar-Apr</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Indian journal of pharmacology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Indian J Pharmacol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Proteome architecture of human-induced pluripotent stem cell-derived three-dimensional organoids as a tool for early diagnosis of neuronal disorders.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>108</StartPage><EndPage>118</EndPage><MedlinePgn>108-118</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4103/ijp.ijp_56_23</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND OBJECTIVES">Induced pluripotent stem cells (iPSCs) derived three-dimensional (3D) model for rare neurodegenerative disorders such as amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) is emerging as a novel alternative to human diseased tissue to explore the disease etiology and potential drug discovery. In the interest of the same, we have generated a TDP-43-mutated human iPSCs (hiPSCs) derived 3D organoid model of ALS disease. The high-resolution mass spectrometry (MS)-based proteomic approach is used to explore the differential mechanism under disease conditions and the suitability of a 3D model to study the disease.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS">The hiPSCs cell line was procured from a commercial source, grown, and characterized following standard protocols. The mutation in hiPSCs was accomplished using CRISPR/Cas-9 technology and predesigned gRNA. The two groups of organoids were produced by normal and mutated hiPSCs and subjected to the whole proteomic profiling by high-resolution MS in two biological replicates with three technical replicas of each.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">The proteomic analysis of normal and mutated organoids revealed the proteins associated with pathways of neurodegenerative disorders, proteasomes, autophagy, and hypoxia-inducible factor-1 signaling. Differential proteomic analysis revealed that the mutation in TDP-43 gene caused proteomic deregulation, which impaired protein quality mechanisms. Furthermore, this impairment may contribute to the generation of stress conditions that may ultimately lead to the development of ALS pathology.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">The developed 3D model represents the majority of candidate proteins and associated biological mechanisms altered in ALS disease. The study also offers novel protein targets that may uncloud the precise disease pathological mechanism and be considered for future diagnostic and therapeutic purposes for various neurodegenerative disorders.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Negi</LastName><ForeName>R</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Developmental Toxicology Division, Systems Toxicology and Health Risk Assessment Group, CSIR-Indian Institute of Toxicology Research, Lucknow; Academy of Scientific and Innovative Research, Ghaziabad, Uttar Pradesh, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Srivastava</LastName><ForeName>A</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biochemistry, University of Lucknow, Lucknow, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Srivastava</LastName><ForeName>A K</ForeName><Initials>AK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Developmental Toxicology Division, Systems Toxicology and Health Risk Assessment Group, CSIR-Indian Institute of Toxicology Research, Lucknow, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pandeya</LastName><ForeName>Abhishek</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Developmental Toxicology Division, Systems Toxicology and Health Risk Assessment Group, CSIR-Indian Institute of Toxicology Research, Lucknow, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vatsa</LastName><ForeName>P</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Developmental Toxicology Division, Systems Toxicology and Health Risk Assessment Group, CSIR-Indian Institute of Toxicology Research, Lucknow; Academy of Scientific and Innovative Research, Ghaziabad, Uttar Pradesh, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ansari</LastName><ForeName>U A</ForeName><Initials>UA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Developmental Toxicology Division, Systems Toxicology and Health Risk Assessment Group, CSIR-Indian Institute of Toxicology Research, Lucknow; Academy of Scientific and Innovative Research, Ghaziabad, Uttar Pradesh, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pant</LastName><ForeName>A B</ForeName><Initials>AB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Developmental Toxicology Division, Systems Toxicology and Health Risk Assessment Group, CSIR-Indian Institute of Toxicology Research, Lucknow; Academy of Scientific and Innovative Research, Ghaziabad, Uttar Pradesh, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>India</Country><MedlineTA>Indian J Pharmacol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7902477</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0253-7613</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D020543">Proteome</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D004268">DNA-Binding Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020543" MajorTopicYN="N">Proteome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057026" MajorTopicYN="Y">Induced Pluripotent Stem Cells</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D040901" MajorTopicYN="N">Proteomics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D042241" MajorTopicYN="N">Early Diagnosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004268" MajorTopicYN="N">DNA-Binding Proteins</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009940" MajorTopicYN="N">Organoids</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">brain organoids</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">human-induced pluripotent stem cells</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neurodegenerative disorders</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">proteome profiling</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>None</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37313936</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10335645</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/ijp.ijp_56_23</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">Indian J Pharmacol_2023_55_2_108_378032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Penney J, Ralvenius WT, Tsai LH. Modeling Alzheimer's disease with iPSC-derived brain cells. Mol Psychiatry. 2020;25:148&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6906186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31391546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heger LM, Wise RM, Hees JT, Harbauer AB, Burbulla LF. Mitochondrial phenotypes in Parkinson's diseases &#x2013; A Focus on human iPSC-derived dopaminergic neurons. Cells. 2021;10:3436.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8699816</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34943944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujimori K, Ishikawa M, Otomo A, Atsuta N, Nakamura R, Akiyama T, et al. Modeling sporadic ALS in iPSC-derived motor neurons identifies a potential therapeutic agent. Nat Med. 2018;24:1579&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30127392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pomeshchik Y, Klementieva O, Gil J, Martinsson I, Hansen MG, de Vries T, et al. Human iPSC-derived hippocampal spheroids: An innovative tool for stratifying Alzheimer disease patient-specific cellular phenotypes and developing therapies. Stem Cell Reports. 2020;15:256&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7363942</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32589876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen M, Lee HK, Moo L, Hanlon E, Stein T, Xia W. Common proteomic profiles of induced pluripotent stem cell-derived three-dimensional neurons and brain tissue from Alzheimer patients. J Proteomics. 2018;182:21&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7457321</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29709615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beers J, Gulbranson DR, George N, Siniscalchi LI, Jones J, Thomson JA, et al. Passaging and colony expansion of human pluripotent stem cells by enzyme-free dissociation in chemically defined culture conditions. Nat Protoc. 2012;7:2029&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3571618</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23099485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajpurohit CS, Kumar V, Cheffer A, Oliveira D, Ulrich H, Okamoto OK, et al. Mechanistic insights of astrocyte-mediated hyperactive autophagy and loss of motor neuron function in SOD1(L39R) linked amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Mol Neurobiol. 2020;57:4117&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32676988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Srivastava AK, Yadav SS, Mishra S, Yadav SK, Parmar D, Yadav S. A combined microRNA and proteome profiling to investigate the effect of ZnO nanoparticles on neuronal cells. Nanotoxicology. 2020;14:757&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32393089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pereira JD, DuBreuil DM, Devlin AC, Held A, Sapir Y, Berezovski E, et al. Human sensorimotor organoids derived from healthy and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis stem cells form neuromuscular junctions. Nat Commun. 2021;12:4744.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8346474</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34362895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Notaras M, Lodhi A, Fang H, Greening D, Colak D. The proteomic architecture of schizophrenia iPSC-derived cerebral organoids reveals alterations in GWAS and neuronal development factors. Transl Psychiatry. 2021;11:541.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8526592</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34667143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iridoy MO, Zubiri I, Zelaya MV, Martinez L, Aus&#xed;n K, Lachen-Montes M, et al. Neuroanatomical quantitative proteomics reveals common pathogenic biological routes between amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) and frontotemporal dementia (FTD) Int J Mol Sci. 2018;20:4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6337647</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30577465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baxi EG, Thompson T, Li J, Kaye JA, Lim RG, Wu J, et al. Answer ALS, a large-scale resource for sporadic and familial ALS combining clinical and multi-omics data from induced pluripotent cell lines. Nat Neurosci. 2022;25:226&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8825283</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35115730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohanty L, Henderson RD, McCombe PA, Lee A. Levels of clusterin, CD5L, ficolin-3, and gelsolin in ALS patients and controls. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2020;21:631&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32558599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filimonenko M, Stuffers S, Raiborg C, Yamamoto A, Maler&#xf8;d L, Fisher EM, et al. Functional multivesicular bodies are required for autophagic clearance of protein aggregates associated with neurodegenerative disease. J Cell Biol. 2007;179:485&#x2013;500.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2064794</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17984323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galli C, Bernasconi R, Sold&#xe0; T, Calanca V, Molinari M. Malectin participates in a backup glycoprotein quality control pathway in the mammalian ER. PLoS One. 2011;6:e16304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3027649</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21298103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamelgarn M, Chen J, Kuang L, Jin H, Kasarskis EJ, Zhu H. ALS mutations of FUS suppress protein translation and disrupt the regulation of nonsense-mediated decay. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2018;115:E11904&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6304956</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30455313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neumann M, Bentmann E, Dormann D, Jawaid A, DeJesus-Hernandez M, Ansorge O, et al. FET proteins TAF15 and EWS are selective markers that distinguish FTLD with FUS pathology from amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with FUS mutations. Brain. 2011;134:2595&#x2013;609.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3170539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21856723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alves CJ, Maximino JR, Chadi G. Dysregulated expression of death, stress and mitochondrion related genes in the sciatic nerve of presymptomatic SOD1(G93A) mouse model of Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. Front Cell Neurosci. 2015;9:332.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4555015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26339226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castellanos-Montiel MJ, Chaineau M, Durcan TM. The neglected genes of ALS: Cytoskeletal dynamics impact synaptic degeneration in ALS. Front Cell Neurosci. 2020;14:594975.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7691654</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33281562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farah CA, Nguyen MD, Julien JP, Leclerc N. Altered levels and distribution of microtubule-associated proteins before disease onset in a mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurochem. 2003;84:77&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12485403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Theunissen F, West PK, Brennan S, Petrovi&#x107; B, Hooshmand K, Akkari PA, et al. New perspectives on cytoskeletal dysregulation and mitochondrial mislocalization in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Transl Neurodegener. 2021;10:46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8597313</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34789332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao P, Yuan Y, Liu Z, Hou X, Li W, Wen J, et al. Association of variants in the KIF1A gene with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Transl Neurodegener. 2022;11:46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9597953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36284339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gockley J, Montgomery KS, Poehlman WL, Wiley JC, Liu Y, Gerasimov E, et al. Multi-tissue neocortical transcriptome-wide association study implicates 8 genes across 6 genomic loci in Alzheimer's disease. Genome Med. 2021;13:76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8094491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33947463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ikemoto A, Hirano A, Akiguchi I. Increased expression of growth-associated protein 43 on the surface of the anterior horn cells in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathol. 1999;98:367&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10502042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katzeff JS, Bright F, Lo K, Kril JJ, Connolly A, Crossett B, et al. Altered serum protein levels in frontotemporal dementia and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis indicate calcium and immunity dysregulation. Sci Rep. 2020;10:13741.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7426269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32792518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin J, Huang P, Chen W, Ye C, Su H, Yao X. Key molecules and pathways underlying sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Integrated analysis on gene expression profiles of motor neurons. Front Genet. 2020;11:578143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7680998</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33240324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taetzsch T, Brayman VL, Valdez G. FGF binding proteins (FGFBPs): Modulators of FGF signaling in the developing, adult, and stressed nervous system. Biochim Biophys Acta Mol Basis Dis. 2018;1864:2983&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6417432</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29902550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cali&#xf3; ML, Henriques E, Siena A, Bertoncini CR, Gil-Mohapel J, Rosenstock TR. Mitochondrial dysfunction, neurogenesis, and epigenetics: Putative implications for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis neurodegeneration and treatment. Front Neurosci. 2020;14:679.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7373761</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32760239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh ET, Kim JW, Kim JM, Kim SJ, Lee JS, Hong SS, et al. NQO1 inhibits proteasome-mediated degradation of HIF-1&#x3b1;. Nat Commun. 2016;7:13593.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5171868</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27966538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>