<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37316187</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1473-0480</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>57</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>British journal of sports medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Br J Sports Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Examining later-in-life health risks associated with sport-related concussion and repetitive head impacts: a systematic review of case-control and cohort studies.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>810</StartPage><EndPage>821</EndPage><MedlinePgn>810-821</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1136/bjsports-2023-106890</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Concern exists about possible problems with later-in-life brain health, such as cognitive impairment, mental health problems and neurological diseases, in former athletes. We examined the future risk for adverse health effects associated with sport-related concussion, or exposure to repetitive head impacts, in former athletes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DESIGN" NlmCategory="METHODS">Systematic review.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DATA SOURCES" NlmCategory="METHODS">Search of MEDLINE, Embase, Cochrane, CINAHL Plus and SPORTDiscus in October 2019 and updated in March 2022.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="ELIGIBILITY CRITERIA" NlmCategory="METHODS">Studies measuring future risk (cohort studies) or approximating that risk (case-control studies).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Ten studies of former amateur athletes and 18 studies of former professional athletes were included. No postmortem neuropathology studies or neuroimaging studies met criteria for inclusion. Depression was examined in five studies in former amateur athletes, none identifying an increased risk. Nine studies examined suicidality or suicide as a manner of death, and none found an association with increased risk. Some studies comparing professional athletes with the general population reported associations between sports participation and dementia or amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) as a cause of death. Most did not control for potential confounding factors (eg, genetic, demographic, health-related or environmental), were ecological in design and had high risk of bias.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Evidence does not support an increased risk of mental health or neurological diseases in former amateur athletes with exposure to repetitive head impacts. Some studies in former professional athletes suggest an increased risk of neurological disorders such as ALS and dementia; these findings need to be confirmed in higher quality studies with better control of confounding factors.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PROSPERO REGISTRATION NUMBER" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">CRD42022159486.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; Author(s) (or their employer(s)) 2023. No commercial re-use. See rights and permissions. Published by BMJ.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Iverson</LastName><ForeName>Grant L</ForeName><Initials>GL</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7348-9570</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sports Concussion Program, MassGeneral Hospital for Children, Boston, Massachusetts, USA giverson@mgh.harvard.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, Harvard Medical School, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, Spaulding Rehabilitation Hospital, Charlestown, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, Schoen Adams Research Institute at Spaulding Rehabilitation, Charlestown, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Home Base, A Red Sox Foundation and Massachusetts General Hospital Program, Massachusetts General Hospital, Charlestown, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Castellani</LastName><ForeName>Rudolph J</ForeName><Initials>RJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathology, Northwestern University Feinberg School of Medicine, Chicago, Illinois, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cassidy</LastName><ForeName>J David</ForeName><Initials>JD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Epidemiology, Dalla Lana School of Public Health, University of Toronto, Toronto, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schneider</LastName><ForeName>Geoff M</ForeName><Initials>GM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, Cumming School of Medicine, University of Calgary, Calgary, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schneider</LastName><ForeName>Kathryn J</ForeName><Initials>KJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5951-5899</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sport Injury Prevention Research Centre, Faculty of Kinesiology, University of Calgary, Calgary, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Echemendia</LastName><ForeName>Ruben J</ForeName><Initials>RJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6116-8462</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, University of Missouri-Kansas City, Kansas City, Missouri, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University Orthopedic Centre, Concussion Care Clinic, State College, Pennsylvania, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bailes</LastName><ForeName>Julian E</ForeName><Initials>JE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, NorthShore University HealthSystem, Evanston, Illinois, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, University of Chicago Pritzker School of Medicine, Chicago, Illinois, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hayden</LastName><ForeName>K Alix</ForeName><Initials>KA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Libraries and Cultural Resources, University of Calgary, Calgary, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Koerte</LastName><ForeName>Inga K</ForeName><Initials>IK</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1281-9286</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>cBRAIN, Department of Child and Adolescent Psychiatry, Psychosomatic, and Psychotherapy, University Hospital, Ludwig-Maximilians-Universit&#xe4;t, Munich, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Psychiatry Neuroimaging Laboratory, Brigham and Women's Hospital, Mass General Brigham, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Massachusetts General Hospital, Boston, MA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Manley</LastName><ForeName>Geoffrey T</ForeName><Initials>GT</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0926-3128</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, University of California San Francisco, San Francisco, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McNamee</LastName><ForeName>Michael</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Movement Sciences, KU Leuven, Leuven, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sport and Exercise Sciences, Swansea University, Swansea, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Patricios</LastName><ForeName>Jon S</ForeName><Initials>JS</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6829-4098</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wits Sport and Health (WiSH), School of Clinical Medicine, Faculty of Health Sciences, University of the Witwatersrand, Johannesburg, South Africa.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tator</LastName><ForeName>Charles H</ForeName><Initials>CH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7335-4246</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgery and Division of Neurosurgery, Temerty Faculty of Medicine, University of Toronto, Toronto, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Canadian Concussion Centre, Toronto Western Hospital, Toronto, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cantu</LastName><ForeName>Robert C</ForeName><Initials>RC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Boston University School of Medicine, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Robert C. Cantu Concussion Center, Emerson Hospital, Concord, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dvorak</LastName><ForeName>Jiri</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2178-2326</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Schulthess Clinic Zurich, Zurich, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Br J Sports Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0432520</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0306-3674</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013177" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sports</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001924" MajorTopicYN="Y">Brain Concussion</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015331" MajorTopicYN="N">Cohort Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016022" MajorTopicYN="N">Case-Control Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003704" MajorTopicYN="Y">Dementia</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">athletes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">brain concussion</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">depression</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neurology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">suicide</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Competing interests: GLI serves as a scientific advisor for NanoDX, Sway Operations and Highmark. He has a clinical and consulting practice in forensic neuropsychology, including expert testimony, involving individuals who have sustained mild TBIs (including former athletes), and on the topic of suicide. He has received past research support or funding from several test publishing companies, including ImPACT Applications, CNS Vital Signs and Psychological Assessment Resources. He receives royalties from the sales of one neuropsychological test (WCST-64). He has received travel support and honorariums for presentations at conferences and meetings. He has received research funding as a principal investigator from the National Football League (NFL), and subcontract grant funding as a collaborator from the Harvard Integrated Programme to Protect and Improve the Health of NFL Players Association Members. He has received research funding from the Wounded Warrior Project. He acknowledges unrestricted philanthropic support from ImPACT Applications, the Mooney-Reed Charitable Foundation, the National Rugby League, Boston Bolts and the Schoen Adams Research Institute at Spaulding Rehabilitation. RJC is a collaborator on a grant funded by the NFL to study the spectrum of concussion, including possible long-term effects. He has a consulting practice in forensic neuropathology, including expert testimony, which has involved former athletes at amateur and professional levels. JDC has provided expert epidemiological testimony in court cases on the long-term effects of concussions in sports. GMS is an owner of a multidisciplinary practice (managing patients with MSK pain disorders). He is a board member of Hockey Calgary (Calgary, Alberta, Canada) and Chair of the Alberta Association of Physiotherapy. He received funding for the administrative aspects of the writing of two of the systematic reviews that informed the consensus process. KJS has received grant funding from the CIHR, NFL Scientific Advisory Board, International Olympic Committee Medical and Scientific Research Fund, World Rugby, Mitacs Accelerate, University of Calgary, with funds paid to her institution and not to her personally. She is an Associate Editor of BJSM (unpaid), Independent consultant to World Rugby and has received travel and accommodation support for meetings where she has presented. She coordinated the writing of the systematic reviews that informed Amsterdam International Consensus on Concussion in Sport, for which she has received an educational grant to assist with the administrative costs associated with the writing of the reviews (with funds paid to her institution). She is a member of the AFL Concussion Scientific Committee (unpaid position), Brain Canada (unpaid positions) and Board member of the Concussion in Sport Group (CISG)(unpaid). She works as a physiotherapy consultant and treats athletes of all levels of sport from grass roots to professional. RJE is a paid consultant for the NHL and cochair of the NHL/NHLPA Concussion Subcommittee. He is also a paid consultant and chair of the Major League Soccer concussion committee, and a consultant to the US Soccer Federation. He previously served as a neuropsychology consultant to Princeton University Athletic Medicine and EyeGuide. He is currently a co-Principal Investigator for a grant funded by the NFL (NFL-Long) through Boston Children&#x2019;s Hospital. He occasionally provides expert testimony in matters related to MTBI and sports concussion, and occasionally receives honoraria and travel support/reimbursement for professional meetings. JB serves as the Chairman of the Medical Advisory Committee of Pop Warrner Football and is a member of the NFL Head, Neck, and Spine Committee, NFLPA Mackey-White Health and Safety Committee and the NCAA Concussion Task Force, all without remuneration. He is a consultant for BrainLab and has provided expert testimony on TBI medicolegal cases. IKK is a professor at Ludwig-Maximilians-Universit&#xe4;t Munich (paid position). She serves as European Editor at Journal of Neurotrauma (unpaid position) and as Vice President of the European Neurotrauma Organisation (unpaid position). She receives research grant funding from the National Institutes of Health, the European Research Council, the German Ministry for Research and Education. She receives funding for a research study on sport-related concussion from Abbott. The university hospital received donations for her research from the Schatt Foundation and Mary Ann Liebert. She receives royalties for book chapters published by Thieme Publishers. Her spouse is employee at Siemens and she thus holds stock options at Siemens and Siemens Healthineers. In-kind contribution: PhD students working under her supervision receive scholarships from the Villigst Foundation, the China Scholarship Council collaboration with Ludwig-Maximilians-University Munich and Fulbright. GM discloses grants from the United States Department of Defense&#x2014;TBI End points Development Initiative (grant #W81XWH-14-2-0176), TRACK-TBI Precision Medicine (grant # W81XWH-18-2-0042) and TRACK-TBI NETWORK (grant # W81XWH-15-9-0001); NIH-NINDS&#x2013;TRACK-TBI (grant #U01NS086090) and the NFL Scientific Advisory Board&#x2014;TRACK-TBI LONGITUDINAL. The United States Department of Energy supports GM for a precision medicine collaboration. One Mind has provided funding for TRACK-TBI patients stipends and support to clinical sites. He has received an unrestricted gift from the NFL to the UCSF Foundation to support research efforts of the TRACK-TBI NETWORK. GM has also received funding from NeuroTruama Sciences to support TRACK-TBI data curation efforts. Additionally, Abbott Laboratories has provided funding for add-in TRACK-TBI clinical studies. MMcN has the following disclosures: (i) Chair, Ethics Expert Group, WADA (2021&#x2013;23) (paid); (ii) Member, International Boxing Association, Ethics and Integrity Committee, (2021&#x2013;22; resigned October 2022) (paid); (iii) Chair, Therapeutic Use Exemption Fairness Committee (2020&#x2013;Present) (paid); (iv) Member, Steering Group, Sex Segregation in Sport, IAAF/World Athletics (2019&#x2013;20) (unpaid); (v) Member, International Ice Hockey Federation, Ethics and Integrity Committee (2019&#x2013;21) (paid); (vi) Member, IOC Consensus Statement Expert Group on Injuries in Children and Adolescents (2017) (unpaid); (vii) Member, Ethics Expert Group, WADA (2016&#x2013;21) (unpaid) and (viii) Member, IOC Consensus Statement Expert Group on Pain Management (2016) (unpaid). JP is a sports and exercise medicine physician at Waterfall Sports Orthopaedic Surgery, Johannesburg, South Africa. He is Director of Sports Concussion South Africa and a Visiting Professor, Wits Sport and Health (WiSH), School of Clinical Medicine, Faculty of Health Sciences, University of the Witwatersrand. As an Editor of BJSM, he receives an honorarium and serves as a consultant (unremunerated) to World Rugby Concussion Advisory Group, South African Rugby, EyeGuide Scientific Advisory Board and the Union of European Football Associations. He is co-chair of the Scientific Committee, 6th International Conference on Concussion in Sport (unpaid) and a Board member of the Concussion in Sport Group (unpaid). RCC serves as a scientific advisor for the NFL's Head Neck and Spine Committee, VP and Chair of the Scientific Advisory Committee for the National Operating Committee on Standards for Athletic Equipment (NOCSAE), and as co-founder and Medical Director of the Concussion Legacy Foundation. He currently receives research support from the NINDS UNITE and Diagnose CTE grants. He has received travel support and honorariums for presentations at conferences and meetings. He receives royalties from Houghton Mifflin Harcourt publishing. He has a clinical and consulting practice in forensic neurology and neurosurgery, including expert testimony, especially individuals with traumatic brain and spinal cord injuries. He is a member of the National Collegiate Athletic Association Student-Athlete Concussion Injury Litigation Medical Science Committee.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>8</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37316187</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2023-106890</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">57/12/810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>