<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37338894</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>19</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1473-6551</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>36</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Current opinion in neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Curr Opin Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Abnormal energy metabolism in ALS: a key player?</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>338</StartPage><EndPage>345</EndPage><MedlinePgn>338-345</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/WCO.0000000000001164</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE OF THE REVIEW">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) is an adult-onset neurodegenerative disease of the motor system due to the selective and progressive degeneration of both upper and lower motor neurons. Disturbances in energy homeostasis were repeatedly associated with the ALS pathogenesis and appear early during the disease process. In this review, we highlight recent work demonstrating the crucial role of energy metabolism in ALS and discuss its potential clinical relevance.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RECENT FINDINGS">The alteration of various metabolic pathways contributes to the heterogeneity of the clinical phenotype of ALS. Recent work showed that different ALS mutations selectively impact these pathways and translate to the disease phenotypes in patients and disease models. Strikingly, a growing number of studies point towards an early, even presymptomatic, contribution of abnormal energy homeostasis to the ALS pathogenesis. Advances in metabolomics generated valuable tools to study altered metabolic pathways, to test their therapeutic potential, and to develop personalized medicine. Importantly, recent preclinical studies and clinical trials demonstrated that targeting energy metabolism is a promising therapeutic approach.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUMMARY">Abnormal energy metabolism is a key player in ALS pathogenesis, emerging as a source of potential disease biomarkers and therapeutic targets.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 The Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Burg</LastName><ForeName>Thibaut</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departement of Neuroscience, Experimental Neurology, Leuven Brain Institute and KU Leuven.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Neurobiology, VIB Center for Brain &amp; Disease Research, Leuven, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Van Den Bosch</LastName><ForeName>Ludo</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departement of Neuroscience, Experimental Neurology, Leuven Brain Institute and KU Leuven.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Neurobiology, VIB Center for Brain &amp; Disease Research, Leuven, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Curr Opin Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9319162</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1350-7540</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019636" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neurodegenerative Diseases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009046" MajorTopicYN="N">Motor Neurons</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004734" MajorTopicYN="N">Energy Metabolism</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057285" MajorTopicYN="N">Precision Medicine</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>
<i>There are no conflicts of interest.</i>
</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37338894</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10328537</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/WCO.0000000000001164</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00019052-990000000-00072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Masrori P, Van Damme P. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a clinical review. Eur J Neurol 2020; 27:1918&#x2013;1929.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7540334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32526057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vandoorne T, De Bock K, Van Den Bosch L. Energy metabolism in ALS: an underappreciated opportunity? Acta Neuropathol 2018; 135:489&#x2013;509.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5978930</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29549424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myers MG, Jr, Affinati AH, Richardson N, et al. . Central nervous system regulation of organismal energy and glucose homeostasis. Nat Metab 2021; 3:737&#x2013;750.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34158655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goutman SA, Boss J, Iyer G, et al. . Body mass index associates with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis survival and metabolomic profiles. Muscle Nerve 2023; 67:208&#x2013;216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9957813</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36321729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janse van Mantgem MR, van Eijk RPA, van der Burgh HK, et al. . Prognostic value of weight loss in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a population-based study. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2020; 91:867&#x2013;875.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32576612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei Q, Ou R, Chen Y, et al. . RNM-01 Weight stability is associated with longer survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2019; 20:309&#x2013;326.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31702466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei QQ, Ou R, Cao B, et al. . Early weight instability is associated with cognitive decline and poor survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain Res Bull 2021; 171:10&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33636227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Reilly EJ, Wang M, Adami HO, et al. . Prediagnostic body size and risk of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis death in 10 studies. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2018; 19:396&#x2013;406.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6423444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29658324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindauer E, Dupuis L, Muller HP, et al. . Adipose tissue distribution predicts survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. PLoS One 2013; 8:e67783.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3694869</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23826340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagel G, Peter RS, Rosenbohm A, et al. . Adipokines, C-reactive protein and Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis - results from a population- based ALS registry in Germany. Sci Rep 2017; 7:1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5491500</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28663573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallo V, Wark PA, Jenab M, et al. . Prediagnostic body fat and risk of death from amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: the EPIC cohort. Neurology 2013; 80:829&#x2013;838.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3598455</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23390184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moglia C, Calvo A, Grassano M, et al. . Early weight loss in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: outcome relevance and clinical correlates in a population-based cohort. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2019; 90:666&#x2013;673.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30630957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ngo ST, van Eijk RPA, Chachay V, et al. . Loss of appetite is associated with a loss of weight and fat mass in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2019; 20:497&#x2013;505.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31144522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mezoian T, Belt E, Garry J, et al. . Loss of appetite in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis is associated with weight loss and decreased calorie consumption independent of dysphagia. Muscle Nerve 2020; 61:230&#x2013;234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31650547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jesus P, Fayemendy P, Marin B, et al. . Increased resting energy expenditure compared with predictive theoretical equations in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nutrition 2020; 77:1&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32371347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fayemendy P, Marin B, Labrunie A, et al. . Hypermetabolism is a reality in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis compared to healthy subjects. J Neurol Sci 2021; 420:1&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33290920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steyn FJ, Ioannides ZA, van Eijk RPA, et al. . Hypermetabolism in ALS is associated with greater functional decline and shorter survival. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2018; 89:1016&#x2013;1023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6166607</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29706605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He J, Fu J, Zhao W, et al. . Hypermetabolism associated with worse prognosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol 2022; 269:1447&#x2013;1455.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34274994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cykowski MD, Takei H, Schulz PE, et al. . TDP-43 pathology in the basal forebrain and hypothalamus of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathol Commun 2014; 2:1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4297460</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25539830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabery S, Ahmed RM, Caga J, et al. . Loss of the metabolism and sleep regulating neuronal populations expressing orexin and oxytocin in the hypothalamus in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuropathol Appl Neurobiol 2021; 47:979&#x2013;989.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33755993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bolborea M, Vercruysse P, Daria T, et al. . Loss of hypothalamic MCH decreases food intake in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Acta Neuropathol 2023; 145:773&#x2013;791.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10175407</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37058170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorges M, Vercruysse P, Muller HP, et al. . Hypothalamic atrophy is related to body mass index and age at onset in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2017; 88:1033&#x2013;1041.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28596251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang J, Shaw TB, Holdom CJ, et al. . Lower hypothalamic volume with lower body mass index is associated with shorter survival in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Eur J Neurol 2023; 30:57&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10099625</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36214080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tse NY, Bocchetta M, Todd EG, et al. . Distinct hypothalamic involvement in the amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-frontotemporal dementia spectrum. Neuroimage Clin 2023; 37:1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9731897</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36495857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu S, Ren Q, Gong G, et al. . Hypothalamic subregion abnormalities are related to body mass index in patients with sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol 2022; 269:2980&#x2013;2988.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34779889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bayer D, Antonucci S, Muller HP, et al. . Disruption of orbitofrontal-hypothalamic projections in a murine ALS model and in human patients. Transl Neurodegener 2021; 10:1&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8168014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34059131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pradat PF, Bruneteau G, Gordon PH, et al. . Impaired glucose tolerance in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler 2010; 11:166&#x2013;171.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20184518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed RM, Phan K, Highton-Williamson E, et al. . Eating peptides: biomarkers of neurodegeneration in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and frontotemporal dementia. Ann Clin Transl Neurol 2019; 6:486&#x2013;495.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6414477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30911572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dorst J, Kuhnlein P, Hendrich C, et al. . Patients with elevated triglyceride and cholesterol serum levels have a prolonged survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol 2011; 258:613&#x2013;617.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21128082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez De Aguilar JL. Lipid biomarkers for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Front Neurol 2019; 10:1&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6458258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31019485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seelen M, van Doormaal PT, Visser AE, et al. . Prior medical conditions and the risk of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol 2014; 261:1949&#x2013;1956.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25059395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dupuis L, Corcia P, Fergani A, et al. . Dyslipidemia is a protective factor in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology 2008; 70:1004&#x2013;1009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18199832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janse van Mantgem MR, van Rheenen W, Hackeng AV, et al. . Association between serum lipids and survival in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a meta-analysis and population-based study. Neurology 2023; 100:1062&#x2013;1071.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9990853</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36460467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia K, Klose V, Hogel J, et al. . Lipids and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a two-sample mendelian randomization study. Eur J Neurol 2023; 00:1&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36999624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng P, Zhou X. Causal effects of blood lipids on amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a Mendelian randomization study. Hum Mol Genet 2019; 28:688&#x2013;697.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6360326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30445611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen X, Yazdani S, Piehl F, et al. . Polygenic link between blood lipids and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurobiol Aging 2018; 67: 202 e1-e6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29685649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bandres-Ciga S, Noyce AJ, Hemani G, et al. . Shared polygenic risk and causal inferences in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol 2019; 85:470&#x2013;481.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6450729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30723964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michels S, Kurz D, Rosenbohm A, et al. . Association of blood lipids with onset and prognosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: results from the ALS Swabia registry. J Neurol 2023; 270:3082&#x2013;3090.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10193299</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36853389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bjornevik K, O&#x2019;Reilly EJ, Cortese M, et al. . Prediagnostic plasma lipid levels and the risk of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2021; 22:133&#x2013;143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8004541</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32985910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakamura R, Kurihara M, Ogawa N, et al. . Investigation of the prognostic predictive value of serum lipid profiles in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: roles of sex and hypermetabolism. Sci Rep 2022; 12:1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8814149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35115598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson AG, Talbot K, Turner MR. Higher blood high density lipoprotein and apolipoprotein A1 levels are associated with reduced risk of developing amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2022; 93:75&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8685635</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34518331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barros A, Dourado MET, Jr, Pedrosa LFC, et al. . Association of copper status with lipid profile and functional status in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Nutr Metab 2018; 2018:1&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6079445</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30116640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Germeys C, Vandoorne T, Bercier V, et al. . Existing and emerging metabolomic tools for ALS research. Genes (Basel) 2019; 10:1&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6947647</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31817338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goutman SA, Guo K, Savelieff MG, et al. . Metabolomics identifies shared lipid pathways in independent amyotrophic lateral sclerosis cohorts. Brain 2022; 145:4425&#x2013;4439.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9762943</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35088843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dorst J, Weydt P, Brenner D, et al. . Metabolic alterations precede neurofilament changes in presymptomatic ALS gene carriers. EBioMedicine 2023; 90:1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10024076</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36917918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bjornevik K, O&#x2019;Reilly EJ, Molsberry S, et al. . Prediagnostic neurofilament light chain levels in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology 2021; 97:e1466&#x2013;e1474.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8575132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34380747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verde F, Milone I, Colombo E, et al. . Phenotypic correlates of serum neurofilament light chain levels in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Front Aging Neurosci 2023; 15:1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10050442</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37009451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenbohm A, Peter R, Dorst J, et al. . Life course of physical activity and risk and prognosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in a German ALS registry. Neurology 2021; 97:e1955&#x2013;e1963.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34670816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palamiuc L, Schlagowski A, Ngo ST, et al. . A metabolic switch toward lipid use in glycolytic muscle is an early pathologic event in a mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. EMBO Mol Med 2015; 7:526&#x2013;546.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4492815</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25820275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scaricamazza S, Salvatori I, Giacovazzo G, et al. . Skeletal-Muscle Metabolic Reprogramming in ALS-SOD1(G93A) mice predates disease onset and is a promising therapeutic target. iScience 2020; 23:1&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7200935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32371370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lanznaster D, Bruno C, Bourgeais J, et al. . Metabolic profile and pathological alterations in the muscle of patients with early-stage amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Biomedicines 2022; 10:1&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9220134</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35740329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goutman SA, Boss J, Guo K, et al. . Untargeted metabolomics yields insight into ALS disease mechanisms. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2020; 91:1329&#x2013;1338.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7677469</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32928939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akcimen F, Lopez ER, Landers JE, et al. . Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: translating genetic discoveries into therapies. Nat Rev Genet 2023; 1&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37024676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Vocht J, Van Weehaeghe D, Ombelet F, et al. . Differences in cerebral glucose metabolism in ALS patients with and without C9orf72 and SOD1 mutations. Cells 2023; 12:1&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10047407</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36980274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canosa A, Calvo A, Moglia C, et al. . Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with SOD1 mutations shows distinct brain metabolic changes. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging 2022; 49:2242&#x2013;2250.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9165265</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35076740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia K, Witzel S, Witzel C, et al. . Mutation-specific metabolic profiles in presymptomatic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Eur J Neurol 2023; 30:87&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36169607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calvo A, Canosa A, Moglia C, et al. . Clinical and metabolic signature of UNC13A rs12608932 variant in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurol Genet 2022; 8:e200033.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9608390</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36313067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakamura R, Misawa K, Tohnai G, et al. . A multiethnic meta-analysis identifies novel genes, including ACSL5, associated with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Commun Biol 2020; 3:1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7511394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32968195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saez-Atienzar S, Bandres-Ciga S, Langston RG, et al. . Genetic analysis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis identifies contributing pathways and cell types. Sci Adv 2021; 7:1&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7810371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33523907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iacoangeli A, Lin T, Al Khleifat A, et al. . Genome-wide meta-analysis finds the ACSL5-ZDHHC6 locus is associated with ALS and links weight loss to the disease genetics. Cell Rep 2020; 33:1&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7610013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33113361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajkumar A, Liaghati A, Chan J, et al. . ACSL5 genotype influence on fatty acid metabolism: a cellular, tissue, and whole-body study. Metabolism 2018; 83:271&#x2013;279.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29605434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hop PJ, Zwamborn RAJ, Hannon E, et al. . Genome-wide study of DNA methylation shows alterations in metabolic, inflammatory, and cholesterol pathways in ALS. Sci Transl Med 2022; 14:eabj0264.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10040186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35196023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim MA, Bence KK, Sandesara I, et al. . Genetically altering organismal metabolism by leptin-deficiency benefits a mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Hum Mol Genet 2014; 23:4995&#x2013;5008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4140473</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24833719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dupuis L, Oudart H, Ren&#xe9; F, et al. . Evidence for defective energy homeostasis in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: benefit of a high-energy diet in a transgenic mouse model. Proc Natl Acad Sci 2004; 101:11159&#x2013;11164.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC503756</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15263088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coughlan KS, Halang L, Woods I, et al. . A high-fat jelly diet restores bioenergetic balance and extends lifespan in the presence of motor dysfunction and lumbar spinal cord motor neuron loss in TDP-43A315T mutant C57BL6/J mice. Dis Model Mech 2016; 9:1029&#x2013;1037.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5047697</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27491077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wills AM, Hubbard J, Macklin EA, et al. . Hypercaloric enteral nutrition in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled phase 2 trial. Lancet 2014; 383:2065&#x2013;2072.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4176708</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24582471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ludolph AC, Dorst J, Dreyhaupt J, et al. . Effect of high-caloric nutrition on survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol 2020; 87:206&#x2013;216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31849093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dorst J, Schuster J, Dreyhaupt J, et al. . Effect of high-caloric nutrition on serum neurofilament light chain levels in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2020; 91:1007&#x2013;1009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32788256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dorst J, Doenz J, Kandler K, et al. . Fat-rich versus carbohydrate-rich nutrition in ALS: a randomised controlled study. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2022; 93:298&#x2013;302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35022317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trabjerg MS, Andersen DC, Huntjens P, et al. . Downregulating carnitine palmitoyl transferase 1 affects disease progression in the SOD1 G93A mouse model of ALS. Commun Biol 2021; 4:1&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8087699</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33931719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paganoni S, Hendrix S, Dickson SP, et al. . Effect of sodium phenylbutyrate/taurursodiol on tracheostomy/ventilation-free survival and hospitalisation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: long-term results from the CENTAUR trial. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2022; 93:871&#x2013;875.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9304116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35577511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paganoni S, Hendrix S, Dickson SP, et al. . Long-term survival of participants in the CENTAUR trial of sodium phenylbutyrate-taurursodiol in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve 2021; 63:31&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7820979</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33063909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klingl YE, Pakravan D, Van Den Bosch L. Opportunities for histone deacetylase inhibition in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Br J Pharmacol 2021; 178:1353&#x2013;1372.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9327724</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32726472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kusaczuk M. Tauroursodeoxycholate-bile acid with chaperoning activity: molecular and cellular effects and therapeutic perspectives. Cells 2019; 8:1&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6952947</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31757001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaelin WG, Jr, McKnight SL. Influence of metabolism on epigenetics and disease. Cell 2013; 153:56&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3775362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23540690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen C, Wang Z, Qin Y. Connections between metabolism and epigenetics: mechanisms and novel anticancer strategy. Front Pharmacol 2022; 13:1&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9354823</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35935878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fels JA, Dash J, Leslie K, et al. . Effects of PB-TURSO on the transcriptional and metabolic landscape of sporadic ALS fibroblasts. Ann Clin Transl Neurol 2022; 9:1551&#x2013;1564.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9539390</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36083004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veyrat-Durebex C, Bris C, Codron P, et al. . Metabo-lipidomics of fibroblasts and mitochondrial-endoplasmic reticulum extracts from ALS patients shows alterations in purine, pyrimidine, energetic, and phospholipid metabolisms. Mol Neurobiol 2019; 56:5780&#x2013;5791.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30680691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerou M, Hall B, Woof R, et al. . Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis alters the metabolic aging profile in patient derived fibroblasts. Neurobiol Aging 2021; 105:64&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8346650</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34044197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allen SP, Duffy LM, Shaw PJ, et al. . Altered age-related changes in bioenergetic properties and mitochondrial morphology in fibroblasts from sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. Neurobiol Aging 2015; 36:2893&#x2013;2903.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26344876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossaert E, Pollari E, Jaspers T, et al. . Restoration of histone acetylation ameliorates disease and metabolic abnormalities in a FUS mouse model. Acta Neuropathol Commun 2019; 7:1&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6612190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31277703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burg T, Rossaert E, Moisse M, et al. . Histone deacetylase inhibition regulates lipid homeostasis in a mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Int J Mol Sci 2021; 22:1&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8541517</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34681883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>