<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37335396</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>08</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1468-1331</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>30</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Cognitive impairment is associated with gait variability and fall risk in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>3056</StartPage><EndPage>3067</EndPage><MedlinePgn>3056-3067</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/ene.15936</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">In amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS), gait abnormalities contribute to poor mobility and represent a relevant risk for falls. To date, gait studies in ALS patients have focused on the motor dimension of the disease, underestimating the cognitive aspects.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Using a wearable gait analysis device, we compared gait patterns in ambulatory ALS patients with mild cognitive impairment (ALS MCI+; n&#x2009;=&#x2009;18), and without MCI (ALS MCI-; n&#x2009;=&#x2009;24), and healthy subjects (HS; n&#x2009;=&#x2009;16) under two conditions: (1) normal gait (single task) and (2) walking while counting backward (dual task). Finally, we examined if the occurrence and number of falls in the 3&#x2009;months following the baseline test were related to cognition.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">In the single task condition, ALS patients, regardless of cognition, displayed higher gait variability than HS, especially for stance and swing time (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001). The dual task condition revealed additional differences in gait variability parameters between ALS MCI+ and ALS MCI- for cadence (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.005), stance time (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.04), swing time (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.04) and stability index (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.02). Moreover, ALS MCI+ showed a higher occurrence (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.001) and number of falls (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001) at the follow-up. Regression analyses demonstrated that MCI condition predicted the occurrence of future falls (&#x3b2;&#x2009;=&#x2009;3.649; p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.01) and, together with executive dysfunction, was associated with the number of falls (cognitive impairment: &#x3b2;&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.63; p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001; executive dysfunction: &#x3b2;&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.39; p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.03), regardless of motor impairment at clinical examination.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">In ALS, MCI is associated with exaggerated gait variability and predicts the occurrence and number of short-term falls.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Authors. European Journal of Neurology published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of European Academy of Neurology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dubbioso</LastName><ForeName>Raffaele</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2487-4741</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosciences, Reproductive Sciences and Odontostomatology, University Federico II of Naples, Naples, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Spisto</LastName><ForeName>Myriam</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8245-6703</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosciences, Reproductive Sciences and Odontostomatology, University Federico II of Naples, Naples, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, University of Campania Luigi Vanvitelli, Naples, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hausdorff</LastName><ForeName>Jeffrey M</ForeName><Initials>JM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1608-0776</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for the Study of Movement, Cognition and Mobility, Tel Aviv Sourasky Medical Center, Tel Aviv, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sagol School of Neuroscience, Tel Aviv University, Tel Aviv, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy, Sackler Faculty of Medicine, Tel Aviv University, Tel Aviv, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rush Alzheimer's Disease Center and Department of Orthopedic Surgery, Rush University Medical Center, Chicago, Illinois, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aceto</LastName><ForeName>Gabriella</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosciences, Reproductive Sciences and Odontostomatology, University Federico II of Naples, Naples, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Iuzzolino</LastName><ForeName>Valentina Virginia</ForeName><Initials>VV</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0002-8046-4122</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosciences, Reproductive Sciences and Odontostomatology, University Federico II of Naples, Naples, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Senerchia</LastName><ForeName>Gianmaria</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0001-1386-1411</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosciences, Reproductive Sciences and Odontostomatology, University Federico II of Naples, Naples, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>De Marco</LastName><ForeName>Stefania</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosciences, Reproductive Sciences and Odontostomatology, University Federico II of Naples, Naples, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, University of Campania Luigi Vanvitelli, Naples, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Marcuccio</LastName><ForeName>Laura</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Istituti Clinici Scientifici Maugeri IRCCS, Neurological Rehabilitation Unit of Telese Terme Institute, Benevento, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Femiano</LastName><ForeName>Cinzia</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Istituti Clinici Scientifici Maugeri IRCCS, Neurological Rehabilitation Unit of Telese Terme Institute, Benevento, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Iodice</LastName><ForeName>Rosa</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6939-4760</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosciences, Reproductive Sciences and Odontostomatology, University Federico II of Naples, Naples, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Salvatore</LastName><ForeName>Elena</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1493-5133</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Advanced Biomedical Sciences, Federico II University, Naples, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Santangelo</LastName><ForeName>Gabriella</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7728-852X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, University of Campania Luigi Vanvitelli, Naples, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Trojano</LastName><ForeName>Luigi</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0328-9642</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, University of Campania Luigi Vanvitelli, Naples, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moretta</LastName><ForeName>Pasquale</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2244-254X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Istituti Clinici Scientifici Maugeri IRCCS, Neurological Rehabilitation Unit of Telese Terme Institute, Benevento, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9506311</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1351-5101</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D060825" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cognitive Dysfunction</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005684" MajorTopicYN="N">Gait</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016138" MajorTopicYN="N">Walking</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003071" MajorTopicYN="N">Cognition</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cognition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">falls</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">gait analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">wearable sensors</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>8</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37335396</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ene.15936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Montero-Odasso M, Verghese J, Beauchet O, Hausdorff JM. Gait and cognition: a complementary approach to understanding brain function and the risk of falling. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2012;60(11):2127-2136.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morris R, Lord S, Bunce J, Burn D, Rochester L. Gait and cognition: mapping the global and discrete relationships in ageing and neurodegenerative disease. Neurosci Biobehav Rev. 2016;64:326-345.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bahureksa L, Najafi B, Saleh A, et al. The impact of mild cognitive impairment on gait and balance: a systematic review and meta-analysis of studies using instrumented assessment. Gerontology. 2016;63(1):67-83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stolze H, Klebe S, Zechlin C, Baecker C, Friege L, Deuschl G. Falls in frequent neurological diseases: prevalence, risk factors and aetiology. J Neurol. 2004;251(1):79-84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gil J, Funalot B, Verschueren A, et al. Causes of death amongst French patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a prospective study. Eur J Neurol. 2008;15(11):1245-1251.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldfarb B, Simon S. Gait patterns in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 1984;65(2):61-65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schell WE, Mar VS, Da Silva CP. Correlation of falls in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with objective measures of balance, strength, and spasticity. NeuroRehabilitation. 2019;44(1):85-93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montes J, Cheng B, Diamond B, Doorish C, Mitsumoto H, Gordon PH. The Timed Up and Go test: predicting falls in ALS. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2007;8(5):292-295.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feron M, Couillandre A, Mseddi E, et al. Extrapyramidal deficits in ALS: a combined biomechanical and neuroimaging study. J Neurol. 2018 Sep;265(9):2125-2136.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elamin M, Phukan J, Bede P, et al. Executive dysfunction is a negative prognostic indicator in patients with ALS without dementia. Neurology. 2011;76(14):1263-1269.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elamin M, Bede P, Byrne S, et al. Cognitive changes predict functional decline in ALS: a population-based longitudinal study. Neurology. 2013;80(17):1590-1597.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olney RK, Murphy J, Forshew D, et al. The effects of executive and behavioral dysfunction on the course of ALS. Neurology. 2005;65(11):1774-1777.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amboni M, Barone P, Hausdorff JM. Cognitive contributions to gait and falls: evidence and implications. Mov Disord. 2013;28(11):1520-1533.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Segev-Jacubovski O, Herman T, Yogev-Seligmann G, Mirelman A, Giladi N, Hausdorff JM. The interplay between gait, falls and cognition: can cognitive therapy reduce fall risk? Expert Rev Neurother. 2011;11(7):1057-1075.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheridan PL, Solomont J, Kowall N, Hausdorff JM. Influence of executive function on locomotor function: divided attention increases gait variability in Alzheimer's disease. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2003;51(11):1633-1637.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheridan PL, Hausdorff JM. The role of higher-level cognitive function in gait: executive dysfunction contributes to fall risk in Alzheimer's disease. Dement Geriatr Cogn Disord. 2007;24(2):125-137.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mirelman A, Herman T, Brozgol M, et al. Executive function and falls in older adults: new findings from a five-year prospective study link fall risk to cognition. PLoS One. 2012;7(6):1-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mak MK, Wong A, Pang MY. Impaired executive function can predict recurrent falls in Parkinson's disease. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2014;95(12):2390-2395.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muir-Hunter SW, Wittwer JE. Dual-task testing to predict falls in community-dwelling older adults: a systematic review. Physiotherapy. 2016;102(1):29-40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montero-Odasso MM, Sarquis-Adamson Y, Speechley M, et al. Association of dual-task gait with incident dementia in mild cognitive impairment: results from the Gait and Brain Study. JAMA Neurol. 2017;74(7):857-865.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Springer S, Giladi N, Peretz C, Yogev G, Simon ES, Hausdorff JM. Dual-tasking effects on gait variability: the role of aging, falls, and executive function. Mov Disord. 2006;21(7):950-957.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pieruccini-Faria F, Black SE, Masellis M, et al. Gait variability across neurodegenerative and cognitive disorders: results from the Canadian Consortium of Neurodegeneration in Aging (CCNA) and the gait and brain study. Alzheimers Dementia. 2021;17(8):1317-1338.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yogev G, Giladi N, Peretz C, Springer S, Simon ES, Hausdorff JM. Dual tasking, gait rhythmicity, and Parkinson's disease: which aspects of gait are attention demanding? Eur J Neurosci. 2005;22(5):1248-1256.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radovanovi&#x107; S, Mili&#x107;ev M, Peri&#x107; S, Basta I, Kosti&#x107; V, Stevi&#x107; Z. Gait in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: is gait pattern differently affected in spinal and bulbar onset of the disease during dual task walking? Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2014;15(7-8):488-493.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montero-Odasso M, Muir SW, Speechley M. Dual-task complexity affects gait in people with mild cognitive impairment: the interplay between gait variability, dual tasking, and risk of falls. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2012;93(2):293-299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hausdorff JM, Lertratanakul A, Cudkowicz ME, et al. Dynamic markers of altered gait rhythm in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Appl Physiol. 2000;88(6):2045-2053.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, Miller RG, Swash M, Munsat TL. El Escorial revisited: revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2000;1(5):293-299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strong MJ, Abrahams S, Goldstein LH, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis - frontotemporal spectrum disorder (ALS-FTSD): revised diagnostic criteria. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2017;18(3-4):153-174.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dyck PJ, Boes CJ, Mulder D, et al. History of standard scoring, notation, and summation of neuromuscular signs. A current survey and recommendation. J Peripher Nerv Syst. 2005;10(2):158-173.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum JM, Stambler N, Malta E, et al. The ALSFRS-R: a revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. BDNF ALS study group (phase III). J Neurol Sci. 1999;169(1-2):13-21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quinn C, Edmundson C, Dahodwala N, Elman L. Reliable and efficient scale to assess upper motor neuron disease burden in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 2020;61(4):508-511.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou J, Manor B, Yu W, et al. Targeted tDCS mitigates dual-task costs to gait and balance in older adults. Ann Neurol. 2021;90(3):428-439.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kahya M, Gouskova NA, Lo OY, et al. Brain activity during dual-task standing in older adults. J Neuroeng Rehabil. 2022;19(1):123. doi:10.1186/s12984-022-01095-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maidan I, Nieuwhof F, Bernad-Elazari H, et al. Evidence for differential effects of 2 forms of exercise on prefrontal plasticity during walking in Parkinson's disease. Neurorehabil Neural Repair. 2018;32(3):200-208.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen M, Herman T, Ganz N, Badichi I, Gurevich T, Hausdorff JM. Multidisciplinary intensive rehabilitation program for people with Parkinson's disease: gaps between the clinic and real-world mobility. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2023;20(5):1-12. doi:10.3390/ijerph20053806</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poole VN, Dawe RJ, Lamar M, et al. Dividing attention during the Timed Up and Go enhances associations of several subtask performances with MCI and cognition. PLoS One. 2022;17:e0269398. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0269398</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park G, Woo Y. Comparison between a center of mass and a foot pressure sensor system for measuring gait parameters in healthy adults. J Phys Ther Sci. 2015;27(10):3199-3202.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Ridder R, Lebleu J, Willems T, De Blaiser C, Detrembleur C, Roosen P. Concurrent validity of a commercial wireless trunk triaxial accelerometer system for gait analysis. J Sport Rehabil. 2019;28(6):4-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schneider N, Dagan M, Katz R, et al. Combining transcranial direct current stimulation with a motor-cognitive task: the impact on dual-task walking costs in older adults. J Neuroeng Rehabil. 2021;18(1):1-13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moretta P, Spisto M, Ausiello FP, et al. Alteration of interoceptive sensitivity: expanding the spectrum of behavioural disorders in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurol Sci. 2022;43(9):5403-5410.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Lucia N, Ausiello FP, Spisto M, Manganelli F, Salvatore E, Dubbioso R. The emotional impact of COVID-19 outbreak in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients: evaluation of depression, anxiety and interoceptive awareness. Neurol Sci. 2020;41(9):2339-2341.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Folstein M, Folstein S, McHugh P. &#x201c;Mini-mental state&#x201d;. A practical method for grading the cognitive state of patients for the clinician. J Psychiatr Res. 1975;12(3):189-198.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abrahams S, Newton J, Niven E, Foley J, Bak TH. Screening for cognition and behaviour changes in ALS. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2014;15:9-14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dubois B, Slachevsky A, Litvan I, Pillon B. The FAB: a frontal assessment battery at bedside. Neurology. 2000;55(11):1621-1626.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carlesimo C, Caltagirone C, Gainotti G. The Mental Deterioration Battery: normative data, diagnostic reliability and qualitative analyses of cognitive impairment. The Group for the Standardization of the Mental Deterioration Battery. Eur Neurol. 1996;36(6):378-384.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milner B. Effects of different brain lesions on card sorting the role of the frontal lobes. Arch Neurol. 1963;9(1):90-100.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbarotto R, Laiacona M, Frosio R, Vecchio M, Farinato A, Capitani E. A normative study on visual reaction times and two Stroop colour-word tests. Neurol Sci. 1998;19(3):161-170.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monaco M, Costa A, Caltagirone C, Carlesimo GA. Forward and backward span for verbal and visuo-spatial data: standardization and normative data from an Italian adult population. Neurol Sci. 2013;34(5):749-754.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mondini S, Mapelli D, Vestri A, Arcara G, Bisiacchi PS. Una batteria di test per lo screening neuropsicologico. In: Esame neuropsicologico breve. Raffaello Cortina Editore; 2003:49-51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caffarra P, Vezzadini G, Dieci F, Zonato F, Venneri A. Rey-Osterrieth complex figure: normative values in an Italian population sample. Neurol Sci. 2002;22(6):443-447.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Litvan I, Goldman JG, Tr&#xf6;ster AI, et al. Diagnostic criteria for mild cognitive impairment in Parkinson's disease: Movement Disorder Society Task Force guidelines. Mov Disord. 2012;27(3):349-356.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller RG, Jackson CE, Kasarskis EJ, et al. Practice parameter update: the care of the patient with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: drug, nutritional, and respiratory therapies (an evidence-based review): report of the quality standards subcommittee of the American Academy of Neurology. Neurology. 2009;73:1218-1226.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boulgarides LK, McGinty SM, Willett JA, Barnes CW. Use of clinical and impairment-based tests to predict falls by community-dwelling older adults. Phys Ther. 2003;83(4):328-339.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muir SW, Speechley M, Wells J, Borrie M, Gopaul K, Montero-Odasso M. Gait assessment in mild cognitive impairment and Alzheimer's disease: the effect of dual-task challenges across the cognitive spectrum. Gait Posture. 2012;35(1):96-100.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desai J, Swash M. Extrapyramidal involvement in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: backward falls and retropulsion. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 1999;67(2):214-216.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>