<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37354059</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>08</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1468-1331</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>30</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Diagnostic accuracy of nerve excitability and compound muscle action potential scan derived biomarkers in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>3068</StartPage><EndPage>3078</EndPage><MedlinePgn>3068-3078</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/ene.15954</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND PURPOSE">The lack of reliable early biomarkers still causes substantial diagnostic delays in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). The aim was to assess the diagnostic accuracy of a novel electrophysiological protocol in patients with suspected motor neuron disease (MND).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Consecutive patients with suspected MND were prospectively recruited at our tertiary referral centre for MND in Utrecht, The Netherlands. Procedures were performed in accordance with the Standards for Reporting of Diagnostic Accuracy. In addition to the standard diagnostic workup, an electrophysiological protocol of compound muscle action potential (CMAP) scans and nerve excitability tests was performed on patients' thenar muscles. The combined diagnostic yield of nerve excitability and CMAP scan based motor unit number estimation was compared to the Awaji and Gold Coast criteria and their added value was determined.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">In all, 153 ALS or progressive muscular atrophy patients, 63 disease controls and 43 healthy controls were included. Our electrophysiological protocol had high diagnostic accuracy (area under the curve [AUC] 0.85, 95% confidence interval [95% CI] 0.80-0.90), even in muscles with undetectable axon loss (AUC 0.78, 95% CI 0.70-0.85) and in bulbar-onset patients (AUC 0.85, 95% CI 0.73-0.95). Twenty-four of 33 (73%) ALS patients who could not be diagnosed during the same visit were correctly identified, as well as 8/13 (62%) ALS patients not meeting the Gold Coast criteria and 49/59 (83%) ALS patients not meeting the Awaji criteria during this first visit.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Our practical and non-invasive electrophysiological protocol may improve early diagnosis in clinically challenging patients with suspected ALS. Routine incorporation may boost early diagnosis, enhance patient selection and generate baseline measures for clinical trials.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Authors. European Journal of Neurology published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of European Academy of Neurology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stikvoort Garc&#xed;a</LastName><ForeName>D J L</ForeName><Initials>DJL</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3984-1635</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Brain Center Utrecht, University Medical Center Utrecht, Utrecht, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sleutjes</LastName><ForeName>B T H M</ForeName><Initials>BTHM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6618-3573</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Brain Center Utrecht, University Medical Center Utrecht, Utrecht, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>van Schelven</LastName><ForeName>L J</ForeName><Initials>LJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Technology and Clinical Physics, University Medical Center Utrecht, Utrecht, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Goedee</LastName><ForeName>H S</ForeName><Initials>HS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Brain Center Utrecht, University Medical Center Utrecht, Utrecht, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>van den Berg</LastName><ForeName>L H</ForeName><Initials>LH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Brain Center Utrecht, University Medical Center Utrecht, Utrecht, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9506311</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1351-5101</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>7440-57-5</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D006046">Gold</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="CommentIn"><RefSource>Nat Rev Neurol. 2023 Aug;19(8):459</RefSource><PMID Version="1">37402805</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000200" MajorTopicYN="N">Action Potentials</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016472" MajorTopicYN="Y">Motor Neuron Disease</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006046" MajorTopicYN="N">Gold</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ALS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Awaji criteria</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CMAP scan</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">EMG</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Gold Coast criteria</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">MND</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nerve excitability</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37354059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ene.15954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>van Es MA, Hardiman O, Chio A, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet. 2017;390(10107):2084-2098.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner MR. Diagnosing ALS: the Gold Coast criteria and the role of EMG. Pract Neurol. 2022;22:176-178.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paganoni S, Macklin EA, Lee A, Murphy A, Chang J, Zipf A. Diagnostic timelines and delays in diagnosing amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2014;15(5-6):453-456.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mccomas AJ, Fawcett PRW, Campbell MJ, Sica REP. Electrophysiological estimation of the number of motor units within a human muscle. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiat. 1971;34:121-131.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner MR, Kiernan MC, Leigh PN, Talbot K. Biomarkers in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet Neurol. 2009;8(1):94-109.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benatar M, Turner MR, Wuu J. Defining pre-symptomatic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2019;20(5-6):303-309.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobsen AB, Bostock H, Fuglsang-Frederiksen A, et al. Reproducibility, and sensitivity to motor unit loss in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, of a novel MUNE method: MScanFit MUNE. Clin Neurophysiol. 2017;128(7):1380-1388.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobsen A, Bostock H. Following disease progression in motor neuron disorders with 3 motor unit number estimation methods. Muscle Nerve. 2019;59(1):82-87.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bostock H. Estimating motor unit numbers from a CMAP scan. Muscle Nerve. 2016;53(6):889-896.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sleutjes BTHM, Montfoort I, Maathuis EM, et al. CMAP scan discontinuities: automated detection and relation to motor unit loss. Clin Neurophysiol. 2014;125(2):388-395.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sleutjes B, Montfoort I, Van Doorn PA. Diagnostic accuracy of electrically elicited multiplet discharges in patients with motor neuron disease. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2015;86:1234-1239.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Kiernan MC, Swash M. Fasciculation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: origin and pathophysiological relevance. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2017;88(9):773-779.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S, Kiernan MC. Axonal excitability properties in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Neurophysiol. 2006;117(7):1458-1466.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiernan MC, Bostock H, Park SB, et al. Measurement of axonal excitability: consensus guidelines. Clin Neurophysiol. 2020;131(1):308-323.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bostock H, Sharief MK, Reid G, Murray NM. Axonal ion channel dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain. 1995;118(Pt 1):217-225.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanai K, Kuwabara S, Misawa S, et al. Altered axonal excitability properties in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: impaired potassium channel function related to disease stage. Brain. 2006;129(Pt 4):953-962.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howells J, Matamala JM, Park SB, et al. In vivo evidence for reduced ion channel expression in motor axons of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Physiol. 2018;596(22):5379-5396.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iwai Y, Shibuya K, Misawa S, et al. Axonal dysfunction precedes motor neuronal death in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. PLoS One. 2016;11(7):e0158596.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheah BC, Lin CS, Park SB, Vucic S, Krishnan AV, Kiernan MC. Progressive axonal dysfunction and clinical impairment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Neurophysiol. 2012;123(12):2460-2467.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mogyoros I, Kiernan MC, Burke D, Bostock H. Strength&#x2212;duration properties of sensory and motor axons in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain. 1998;121(Pt 5):851-859.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huisman MHB, De Jong SW, Van Doormaal PTC, et al. Population based epidemiology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis using capture&#x2212;recapture methodology. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2011;82(10):1165-1170.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kovalchuk MO, Franssen H, Van Schelven LJ, Sleutjes BTHM. Comparing excitability at 37&#xb0;C versus at 20&#xb0;C: differences between motor and sensory axons. Muscle Nerve. 2018;57(4):574-580.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kovalchuk MO, Franssen H, van den Berg LH, van Schelven LJ, Sleutjes BTHM. Excitability of motor and sensory axons in multifocal motor neuropathy. Clin Neurophysiol. 2020;131(11):2641-2650.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiernan MC, Shefner JM, Kaji R, Burke D. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a new diagnostic paradigm. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2020;91(9):903-904.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum JM, Stambler N, Malta E, et al. The ALSFRS-R: a revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. J Neurol Sci. 1999;169(1-2):13-21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karcioglu O, Topacoglu H, Dikme O, Dikme O. A systematic review of the pain scales in adults: which to use? Am J Emerg Med. 2018;36(4):707-714.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kovalchuk MO, Franssen H, Scheijmans FEV, Van Schelven LJ, Van Den Berg LH, Sleutjes B. Warming nerves for excitability testing. Muscle Nerve. 2019;60(3):279-285.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kovalchuk MO, Heuberger J, Sleutjes B, et al. Acute effects of riluzole and retigabine on axonal excitability in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, crossover trial. Clin Pharmacol Ther. 2018;104(6):1136-1145.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lugg A, Schindle M, Sivak A, Tankisi H, Jones KE. Nerve excitability as a biomarker for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a systematic review and meta-analysis. medRxiv. Published online February 13, 2022:2022.02.11.22270866.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiernan MC, Burke D, Andersen KV, Bostock H. Multiple measures of axonal excitability: a new approach in clinical testing. Muscle Nerve. 2000;23(3):399-409.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stikvoort Garcia DJL, Kovalchuk MO, Goedee HS, et al. Motor unit integrity in multifocal motor neuropathy: a systematic evaluation with CMAP scans. Muscle Nerve. 2022;65(3):317-325.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Dengler R, Eisen A, et al. The Awaji criteria for diagnosis of ALS. Muscle Nerve. 2011;44(3):456-457.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, Miller RG, Swash M, Munsat TL, Gr WFNR. El Escorial revisited: revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord. 2000;1(5):293-299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bostock H, Rothwell JC. Latent addition in motor and sensory fibres of human peripheral nerve. J Physiol. 1997;498(1):277-294.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Krom MCTFM, Knipschild PG, Kester ADM, Thijs CT, Boekkooi PF, Spaans F. Carpal tunnel syndrome: prevalence in the general population. J Clin Epidemiol. 1992;45(4):373-376.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geevasinga N, Menon P, Scherman DB, et al. Diagnostic criteria in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology. 2016;87(7):684-690.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pugdahl K, Camdessanch&#xe9; JP, Cengiz B, et al. Gold Coast diagnostic criteria increase sensitivity in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Neurophysiol. 2021;132(12):3183-3189.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hannaford A, Pavey N, van den Bos M, et al. Diagnostic utility of Gold Coast criteria in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol. 2021;89(5):979-986.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shibuya K, Misawa S, Nasu S, et al. Split hand syndrome in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: different excitability changes in the thenar and hypothenar motor axons. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2013;84(9):969-972.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krishnan AV, Lin CSY, Kiernan MC. Nerve excitability properties in lower-limb motor axons: evidence for a length-dependent gradient. Muscle Nerve. 2004;29(5):645-655.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sorensen DM, Bostock H, Ballegaard M, et al. Assessing inter-rater reproducibility in MScanFit MUNE in a 6-subject, 12-rater &#x201c;round Robin&#x201d; setup. Neurophysiol Clin. 2021;52(2):157-169.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menon P, Geevasinga N, Yiannikas C, Howells J, Kiernan MC, Vucic S. Sensitivity and specificity of threshold tracking transcranial magnetic stimulation for diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a prospective study. Lancet Neurol. 2015;14(5):478-484.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geevasinga N, Howells J, Menon P, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis diagnostic index: toward a personalized diagnosis of ALS. Neurology. 2019;92(6):e536-e547.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiernan MC, Vucic S, Talbot K, et al. Improving clinical trial outcomes in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nature Reviews Neurology. 2020;17(2):104-118.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wainger BJ, Macklin EA, Vucic S, et al. Effect of ezogabine on cortical and spinal motor neuron excitability in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA Neurol. 2021;78(2):186-196.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanai K, Shibuya K, Sato Y, et al. Motor axonal excitability properties are strong predictors for survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2012;83(7):734-738.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shibuya K, Misawa S, Kimura H, et al. Increased motor axonal persistent sodium currents predict rapid functional declines in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurol Clin Neurosci. 2016;4(3):108-111.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>