<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37387467</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>19</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1473-6551</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>36</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Current opinion in neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Curr Opin Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Cortical hyperexcitability in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: from pathogenesis to diagnosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>353</StartPage><EndPage>359</EndPage><MedlinePgn>353-359</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/WCO.0000000000001162</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE OF REVIEW">Identification of upper motor neuron involvement remains a critical component of a diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS), although supportive clinical signs are often not easily appreciated, particularly in the early symptomatic stages of the disease. Although diagnostic criteria have been developed to facilitate improved detection of lower motor neuron impairment through electrophysiological features that have improved diagnostic sensitivity, assessment of upper motor neuron involvement remains problematic.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RECENT FINDINGS">Recent evidence has emerged about pathophysiological processes, particularly glutamate-mediated excitotoxicity, which has resulted in the development of novel diagnostic investigations and uncovered potential therapeutic targets. Advances in genetics, including the C9orf72 gene, have changed concepts of ALS, from being classified as a neuromuscular disease to a disease that forms a continuum with other primary neurodegenerative disorders, particularly frontotemporal dementia. Transcranial magnetic stimulation has been utilized to provide pathophysiological insights, leading to the development of diagnostic and therapeutic biomarkers, which are now being introduced into the clinical setting.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUMMARY">Specifically, the advent of cortical hyperexcitability has been consistently identified as an early and intrinsic feature of ALS. With greater accessibility of TMS techniques promoting clinical utilization, TMS measures of cortical function may develop as a diagnostic biomarker, with further potential utility in the clinical trial setting for monitoring of neuroprotective and genetic-based therapies.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Timmins</LastName><ForeName>Hannah C</ForeName><Initials>HC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Brain and Mind Centre.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vucic</LastName><ForeName>Steve</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Brain, Nerve Research Centre, The University of Sydney.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kiernan</LastName><ForeName>Matthew C</ForeName><Initials>MC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Brain and Mind Centre.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Royal Prince Alfred Hospital, Sydney, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Curr Opin Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9319162</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1350-7540</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D015415">Biomarkers</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009046" MajorTopicYN="N">Motor Neurons</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D050781" MajorTopicYN="N">Transcranial Magnetic Stimulation</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Frontotemporal Dementia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015415" MajorTopicYN="N">Biomarkers</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37387467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/WCO.0000000000001162</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00019052-990000000-00071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Vucic S, Higashihara M, Sobue G, et al. PACTALS Consortium. ALS is a multistep process in South Korean, Japanese, and Australian patients. Neurology 2020; 94:e1657&#x2013;e1663.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiernan MC, Vucic S, Cheah BC, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet 2011; 377:942&#x2013;955.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shefner JM, Al-Chalabi A, Baker MR, et al. A proposal for new diagnostic criteria for ALS. Clinical neurophysiology: official journal of the International Federation of Clinical Neurophysiology 2020; 131:1975&#x2013;1978.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Timmins HC, Saw W, Cheah BC, et al. Cardiometabolic health and risk of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve 2017; 56:721&#x2013;725.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S, Kiernan MC. Novel threshold tracking techniques suggest that cortical hyperexcitability is an early feature of motor neuron disease. Brain 2006; 129 (Pt 9):2436&#x2013;2446.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eisen A, Braak H, Del Tredici K, et al. Cortical influences drive amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2017; 88:917&#x2013;924.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiernan MC, Vucic S, Talbot K, et al. Improving clinical trial outcomes in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat Rev Neurol 2021; 17:104&#x2013;118.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Lazzaro V, Ranieri F, Profice P, et al. Transcranial direct current stimulation effects on the excitability of corticospinal axons of the human cerebral cortex. Brain Stimul 2013; 6:641&#x2013;643.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higashihara M, Van den Bos MAJ, Menon P, et al. Interneuronal networks mediate cortical inhibition and facilitation. Clin Neurophysiol 2020; 131:1000&#x2013;1010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swash M, Burke D, Turner MR, et al. Occasional essay: Upper motor neuron syndrome in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2020; 91:227&#x2013;234.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S, Ziemann U, Eisen A, et al. Transcranial magnetic stimulation and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: pathophysiological insights. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2013; 84:1161&#x2013;1170.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Bos MAJ, Geevasinga N, Higashihara M, et al. Pathophysiology and diagnosis of ALS: insights from advances in neurophysiological techniques. Int J Mol Sci 2019; 20:2818.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menon P, Kiernan MC, Vucic S. Cortical hyperexcitability precedes lower motor neuron dysfunction in ALS. Clin Neurophysiol 2015; 126:803&#x2013;809.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menon P, Geevasinga N, Yiannikas C, et al. Sensitivity and specificity of threshold tracking transcranial magnetic stimulation for diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a prospective study. Lancet Neurol 2015; 14:478&#x2013;484.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eisen A, Weber M. The motor cortex and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve 2001; 24:564&#x2013;573.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirota N, Eisen A, Weber M. Complex fasciculations and their origin in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and Kennedy's disease. Muscle Nerve 2000; 23:1872&#x2013;1875.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swash M. Why are upper motor neuron signs difficult to elicit in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis? J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2012; 83:659&#x2013;662.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S, Kiernan MC. Transcranial magnetic stimulation for the assessment of neurodegenerative disease. Neurotherapeutics 2017; 14:91&#x2013;106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kujirai T, Caramia MD, Rothwell JC, et al. Corticocortical inhibition in human motor cortex. J Physiol 1993; 471:501&#x2013;519.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher RJ, Nakamura Y, Bestmann S, et al. Two phases of intracortical inhibition revealed by transcranial magnetic threshold tracking. Exp. Brain Res 2002; 143:240&#x2013;248.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S, Howells J, Trevillion L, Kiernan MC. Assessment of cortical excitability using threshold tracking techniques. Muscle Nerve 2006; 33:477&#x2013;486.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samusyte G, Bostock H, Rothwell J, Koltzenburg M. Short-interval intracortical inhibition: comparison between conventional and threshold-tracking techniques. Brain stimulation 2018; 11:806&#x2013;817.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stefan K, Kunesch E, Benecke R, Classen J. Effects of riluzole on cortical excitability in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol 2001; 49:536&#x2013;539.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zanette G, Tamburin S, Manganotti P, et al. Different mechanisms contribute to motor cortex hyperexcitability in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Neurophysiol 2002; 113:1688&#x2013;1697.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S, Kiernan MC. Cortical excitability testing distinguishes Kennedy's disease from amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Neurophysiol 2008; 119:1088&#x2013;1096.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S, Nicholson GA, Kiernan MC. Cortical hyperexcitability may precede the onset of familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain 2008; 131 (Pt 6):1540&#x2013;1550.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menon P, Higashihara M, van den Bos M, et al. Cortical hyperexcitability evolves with disease progression in ALS. Ann Clin Transl Neurol 2020; 7:733&#x2013;741.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suzuki YI, Shibuya K, Misawa S, et al. Relationship between motor cortical and peripheral axonal hyperexcitability in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol 2022; 93:1074&#x2013;1079.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shibuya K, Park SB, Geevasinga N, et al. Motor cortical function determines prognosis in sporadic ALS. Neurology 2016; 87:513&#x2013;520.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shibuya K, Simon NG, Geevasinga N, et al. The evolution of motor cortical dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clinical Neurophysiology 2017; 128:1075&#x2013;1082.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dharmadasa T, Kiernan MC. Riluzole, disease stage and survival in ALS. Lancet Neurol 2018; 17:385&#x2013;386.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menon P, Geevasinga N, van den Bos M, et al. Cortical hyperexcitability and disease spread in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Eur J Neurol 2017; 24:816&#x2013;824.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dharmadasa T, Matamala JM, Howells J, et al. Early focality and spread of cortical dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a regional study across the motor cortices. Clin Neurophysiol 2020; 131:958&#x2013;966.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walhout R, Verstraete E, van den Heuvel MP, et al. Patterns of symptom development in patients with motor neuron disease. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2018; 19:21&#x2013;28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menon P, Yiannikas C, Kiernan MC, Vucic S. Regional motor cortex dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Clin Transl Neurol 2019; 6:1373&#x2013;1382.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wittstock M, Wolters A, Benecke R. Transcallosal inhibition in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Neurophysiol 2007; 118:301&#x2013;307.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Bos MAJ, Higashihara M, Geevasinga N, et al. Pathophysiological associations of transcallosal dysfunction in ALS. Eur J Neurol 2021; 28:1172&#x2013;1180.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eisen A. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-evolutionary and other perspectives. Muscle Nerve 2009; 40:297&#x2013;304.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neumann M, Sampathu DM, Kwong LK, et al. Ubiquitinated TDP-43 in frontotemporal lobar degeneration and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Science 2006; 314:130&#x2013;133.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higashihara M, Pavey N, van den Bos M, et al. Association of cortical hyperexcitability and cognitive impairment in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology 2021; 96:e2090&#x2013;e2097.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beeldman E, Raaphorst J, Klein Twennaar M, et al. The cognitive profile of ALS: a systematic review and meta-analysis update. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2016; 87:611&#x2013;619.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2; A, Moglia C, Canosa A, et al. Cognitive impairment across ALS clinical stages in a population-based cohort. Neurology 2019; 93:e984&#x2013;e994.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeJesus-Hernandez M, Mackenzie Ian R, Boeve Bradley F, et al. Expanded GGGGCC hexanucleotide repeat in noncoding region of C9ORF72 causes Chromosome 9p-Linked FTD and ALS. Neuron 2011; 72:245&#x2013;256.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wainger BJ, Kiskinis E, Mellin C, et al. Intrinsic membrane hyperexcitability of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patient-derived motor neurons. Cell Rep 2014; 7:1&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haidar M, Viden A, Cuic B, et al. Cortical hyperexcitability drives dying forward ALS symptoms and pathology in mice. Neurosci Lett 2021; 759:136039.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Lazzaro V, Pilato F, Saturno E, et al. Theta-burst repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation suppresses specific excitatory circuits in the human motor cortex. J Physiol 2005; 565 (Pt 3):945&#x2013;950.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Lazzaro V, Pilato F, Dileone M, et al. Low-frequency repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation suppresses specific excitatory circuits in the human motor cortex. J Physiol 2008; 586:4481&#x2013;4487.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S, Stanley Chen K-H, Kiernan MC, et al. Clinical diagnostic utility of transcranial magnetic stimulation in neurological disorders. Updated report of an IFCN committee. Clin Neurophysiol 2023; 150:131&#x2013;175.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pavey N, Menon P, van den Bos MAJ, et al. Cortical inhibition and facilitation are mediated by distinct physiological processes. Neurosci Lett 2023; 803:137191.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aberra AS, Wang B, Grill WM, Peterchev AV. Simulation of transcranial magnetic stimulation in head model with morphologically-realistic cortical neurons. Brain stimulation 2020; 13:175&#x2013;189.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bensimon G, Lacomblez L, Meininger V. A controlled trial of riluzole in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. ALS/Riluzole Study Group. N Engl J Med 1994; 330:585&#x2013;591.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zoing MC, Burke D, Pamphlett R, Kiernan MC. Riluzole therapy for motor neurone disease: an early Australian experience (1996&#x2013;2002). J Clin Neurosci 2006; 13:78&#x2013;83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheah BC, Vucic S, Krishnan AV, Kiernan MC. Riluzole, neuroprotection and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Curr Med Chem 2010; 17:1942&#x2013;2199.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S, Lin CS-Y, Cheah BC, et al. Riluzole exerts central and peripheral modulating effects in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain 2013; 136 (Pt 5):1361&#x2013;1370.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang T, Al Khleifat A, Meurgey J-H, et al. Stage at which riluzole treatment prolongs survival in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a retrospective analysis of data from a dose-ranging study. Lancet Neurol 2018; 17:416&#x2013;422.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geevasinga N, Menon P, Ng K, et al. Riluzole exerts transient modulating effects on cortical and axonal hyperexcitability in ALS. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2016; 17:580&#x2013;588.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, Miller RG, Swash M, Munsat TL. El Escorial revisited: revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord 2000; 1:293&#x2013;299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks B. El Escorial World Federation of Neurology criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Subcommittee on Motor Neuron Diseases/Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis of the World Federation of Neurology Research Group on Neuromuscular Diseases and the El Escorial &#x2018;Clinical limits of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis&#x2019; workshop contributors. J Neurol Sci 1994; 124: (Suppl): 96&#x2013;107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner MR, Kiernan MC, Leigh PN, Talbot K. Biomarkers in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet Neurol 2009; 8:94&#x2013;109.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hannaford A, Pavey N, van den Bos M, et al. Diagnostic utility of gold coast criteria in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol 2021; 89:979&#x2013;986.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen D, Yang X, Wang Y, et al. The Gold Coast criteria increases the diagnostic sensitivity for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in a Chinese population. Transl Neurodegener 2021; 10:28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jewett G, Khayambashi S, Frost GS, et al. Gold Coast criteria expand clinical trial eligibility in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve 2022; 66:397&#x2013;403.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Jongh AD, Braun N, Weber M, et al. Characterising ALS disease progression according to El Escorial and Gold Coast criteria. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2022; 93:865&#x2013;870.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higashihara M, Sonoo M, Imafuku I, et al. Fasciculation potentials in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and the diagnostic yield of the Awaji algorithm. Muscle Nerve 2012; 45:175&#x2013;182.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tankisi H, Nielsen CS, Howells J, et al. Early diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis by threshold tracking and conventional transcranial magnetic stimulation. Eur J Neurol 2021; 28:3030&#x2013;3039.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dharmadasa T, Howells J, Matamala JM, et al. Cortical inexcitability defines an adverse clinical profile in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Eur J Neurol 2021; 28:90&#x2013;97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S, Cheah BC, Yiannikas C, Kiernan MC. Cortical excitability distinguishes ALS from mimic disorders. Clin Neurophysiol 2011; 122:1860&#x2013;1866.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tankisi H, Pia H, Strunge K, et al. Three different short-interval intracortical inhibition methods in early diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2023; 24:139&#x2013;147.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agarwal S, Highton-Williamson E, Caga J, et al. Motor cortical excitability predicts cognitive phenotypes in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Sci Rep 2021; 11:2172.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>