<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37382103</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>19</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1473-6551</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>36</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Current opinion in neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Curr Opin Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Presymptomatic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: from characterization to prevention.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>360</StartPage><EndPage>364</EndPage><MedlinePgn>360-364</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/WCO.0000000000001168</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE OF REVIEW">Significant progress in characterizing presymptomatic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) is ushering in an era of potential disease prevention. Although these advances have largely been based on cohorts of deep-phenotyped mutation carriers at an elevated risk for ALS, there are increasing opportunities to apply principles and insights gleaned, to the broader population at risk for ALS [and frontotemporal dementia (FTD)].</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RECENT FINDINGS">The discovery that blood neurofilament light chain (NfL) level increases presymptomatically and may serve as a susceptibility biomarker, predicting timing of phenoconversion in some mutation carriers, has empowered the first-ever prevention trial in SOD1 -ALS. Moreover, there is emerging evidence that presymptomatic disease is not uniformly clinically silent, with mild motor impairment (MMI), mild cognitive impairment (MCI), and/or mild behavioral impairment (MBI) representing a prodromal stage of disease. Structural and functional brain abnormalities, as well as systemic markers of metabolic dysfunction, have emerged as potentially even earlier markers of presymptomatic disease. Ongoing longitudinal studies will determine the extent to which these reflect an endophenotype of genetic risk.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUMMARY">The discovery of presymptomatic biomarkers and the delineation of prodromal states is yielding unprecedented opportunities for earlier diagnosis, treatment, and perhaps even prevention of genetic and apparently sporadic forms of disease.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Benatar</LastName><ForeName>Michael</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of Miami, Miami, Florida, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Turner</LastName><ForeName>Martin R</ForeName><Initials>MR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nuffield Department of Clinical Neurosciences, University of Oxford, Oxford, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wuu</LastName><ForeName>Joanne</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of Miami, Miami, Florida, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R01 NS105479</GrantID><Acronym>NS</Acronym><Agency>NINDS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>31</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Curr Opin Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9319162</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1350-7540</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D015415">Biomarkers</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Frontotemporal Dementia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008137" MajorTopicYN="N">Longitudinal Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015415" MajorTopicYN="N">Biomarkers</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058070" MajorTopicYN="N">Asymptomatic Diseases</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>MB reports grants from the National Institutes of Health, the Muscular Dystrophy Association, and the ALS Association; as well as consulting fees for Alector, Alexion, Annexon, Arrowhead, Biogen, Cartesian, Denali, Eli Lilly, Horizon, Immunovant, Novartis, Roche, Sanofi, Takeda, UCB, and UniQure. The University of Miami has licensed intellectual property to Biogen to support design of the ATLAS study. MRT reports paid service for consulting on the ATLAS study of tofersen in pre-symptomatic SOD1-ALS (Biogen). JW reports grants from the National Institutes of Health and the ALS Association.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37382103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS1903460</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10524989</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/WCO.0000000000001168</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00019052-990000000-00076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Talbot K, Feneberg E, Scaber J, Thompson AG, Turner MR. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: the complex path to precision medicine. Journal of neurology. 2018;265(10):2454&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6182683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30054789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swash M, Ingram D. Preclinical and subclinical events in motor neuron disease. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 1988;51(2):165&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1031524</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3346681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aggarwal A, Nicholson G. Detection of preclinical motor neurone loss in SOD1 mutation carriers using motor unit number estimation. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2002;73(2):199&#x2013;201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1737965</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12122184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benatar M, Wuu J. Presymptomatic studies in ALS: rationale, challenges, and approach. Neurology. 2012;79(16):1732&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3468777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23071166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eisen A, Kiernan M, Mitsumoto H, Swash M. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a long preclinical period? J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2014; 85:1232&#x2013;1238.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24648037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitsumoto H, Kasarskis EJ, Simmons Z. Hastening the Diagnosis of Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. Neurology. 2022. May 16:10.1212/WNL.0000000000200799. doi: 10.1212/WNL.0000000000200799.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000200799</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35577578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benatar M, Wuu J, McHutchison C, Postuma RB, Boeve BF, Petersen R, et al. Preventing amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: insights from pre-symptomatic neurodegenerative diseases. Brain : a journal of neurology. 2022;145(1):27&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8967095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34677606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosen DR, Siddique T, Patterson D, Figlewicz DA, Sapp P, Hentati A, et al. Mutations in Cu/Zn superoxide dismutase gene are associated with familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nature. 1993;362(6415):59&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8446170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siddique N, Siddique T. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Overview. In: Adam MP, Mirzaa GM, Pagon RA, Wallace SE, Bean LJH, Gripp KW, et al., editors. GeneReviews((R)). Seattle (WA)1993.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benatar M, Wuu J, Lombardi V, Jeromin A, Bowser R, Andersen PM, et al. Neurofilaments in pre-symptomatic ALS and the impact of genotype. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2019;20(7&#x2013;8):538&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6768722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31432691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Staffaroni AM, Quintana M, Wendelberger B, Heuer HW, Russell LL, Cobigo Y, et al. Temporal order of clinical and biomarker changes in familial frontotemporal dementia. Nature medicine. 2022;28(10):2194&#x2013;206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9951811</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36138153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benatar M, Goutman SA, Staats KA, Feldman EL, Weisskopf M, Talbott E, et al. A roadmap to ALS prevention: strategies and priorities. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2023;94(5):399&#x2013;402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10176353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36690429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benatar M, Granit V, Andersen PM, Grignon AL, McHutchison C, Cosentino S, et al. Mild motor impairment as prodromal state in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a new diagnostic entity. Brain : a journal of neurology. 2022;145(10):3500&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9586537</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35594156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joza S, Hu MT, Jung KY, Kunz D, Stefani A, Dusek P, et al. Progression of clinical markers in prodromal Parkinson&#x2019;s disease and dementia with Lewy bodies: a multicentre study. Brain : a journal of neurology. 2023. Mar 7;awad072. doi: 10.1093/brain/awad072. Online ahead of print.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awad072</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36881989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Hi Shing S, McKenna MC, Siah WF, Chipika RH, Hardiman O, Bede P. The imaging signature of C9orf72 hexanucleotide repeat expansions: implications for clinical trials and therapy development. Brain Imaging Behav. 2021;15(5):2693&#x2013;719.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33398779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Veenhuijzen K, Westeneng HJ, Tan HHG, Nitert AD, van der Burgh HK, Gosselt I, et al. Longitudinal Effects of Asymptomatic C9orf72 Carriership on Brain Morphology. Annals of neurology. 2023;93(4):668&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36511398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benatar M, Wuu J, Andersen PM, Lombardi V, Malaspina A. Neurofilament light: A candidate biomarker of pre-symptomatic ALS and phenoconversion. Annals of neurology. 2018;84:130&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30014505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bjornevik K, O&#x2019;Reilly EJ, Molsberry S, Kolonel LN, Le Marchand L, Paganoni S, et al. Prediagnostic Neurofilament Light Chain Levels in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. Neurology. 2021;97(15):e1466&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8575132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34380747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rojas JC, Wang P, Staffaroni AM, Heller C, Cobigo Y, Wolf A, et al. Plasma Neurofilament Light for Prediction of Disease Progression in Familial Frontotemporal Lobar Degeneration. Neurology. 2021;96(18):e2296&#x2013;e312.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8166434</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33827960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gendron TF, Heckman MG, White LJ, Veire AM, Pedraza O, Burch AR, et al. Comprehensive cross-sectional and longitudinal analyses of plasma neurofilament light across FTD spectrum disorders. Cell Rep Med. 2022;3(4):100607.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9044101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35492244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westeneng HJ, van Veenhuijzen K, van der Spek RA, Peters S, Visser AE, van Rheenen W, et al. Associations between lifestyle and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis stratified by C9orf72 genotype: a longitudinal, population-based, case-control study. Lancet Neurol. 2021;20(5):373&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33894192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dorst J, Weydt P, Brenner D, Witzel S, Kandler K, Huss A, et al. Metabolic alterations precede neurofilament changes in presymptomatic ALS gene carriers. EBioMedicine. 2023;90:104521.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10024076</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36917918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kmetzsch V, Anquetil V, Saracino D, Rinaldi D, Camuzat A, Gareau T, et al. Plasma microRNA signature in presymptomatic and symptomatic subjects with C9orf72-associated frontotemporal dementia and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2021;92(5):485&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8053348</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33239440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mariosa D, Hammar N, Malmstrom H, Ingre C, Jungner I, Ye W, et al. Blood biomarkers of carbohydrate, lipid, and apolipoprotein metabolisms and risk of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A more than 20-year follow-up of the Swedish AMORIS cohort. Annals of neurology. 2017;81(5):718&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28437840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson AG, Talbot K, Turner MR. Higher blood high density lipoprotein and apolipoprotein A1 levels are associated with reduced risk of developing amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2022;93(1):75&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8685635</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34518331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Irwin KE, Jasin P, Braunstein KE, Sinha I, Bowden KD, Moghekar A, et al. A fluid biomarker reveals loss of TDP-43 splicing repression in pre-symptomatic ALS. bioRxiv. 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller TM, Cudkowicz ME, Genge A, Shaw PJ, Sobue G, Bucelli RC, et al. Trial of Antisense Oligonucleotide Tofersen for SOD1 ALS. The New England journal of medicine. 2022;387(12):1099&#x2013;110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36129998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benatar M, Wuu J, Turner MR. Neurofilament light chain in drug development for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a critical appraisal. Brain : a journal of neurology. 2022. Oct 31;awac394. doi: 10.1093/brain/awac394.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awac394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10316774</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36310538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benatar M, Wuu J, Andersen PM, Bucelli RC, Andrews JA, Otto M, et al. Design of a Randomized, Placebo-Controlled, Phase 3 Trial of Tofersen Initiated in Clinically Presymptomatic SOD1 Variant Carriers: the ATLAS Study. Neurotherapeutics. 2022;19(4):1248&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9587202</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35585374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benatar M, Turner MR, Wuu J. Defining pre-symptomatic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2019;20(5&#x2013;6):303&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6613999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30892087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.S. Food and Drug Administration. Division of Clinical Outcome Assessment (DCOA). 2021.  [Available from: https://www.fda.gov/about-fda/center-drug-evaluation-and-research-cder/division-clinical-outcome-assessment-dcoa.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>FDA-NIH Biomarker Working Group. BEST (Biomarkers, EndpointS, and other Tools) Resource. Silver Spring (MD): Food and Drug Administration (US). Co-published by National Institutes of Health (US), Bethesda (MD); 2016. Available from: Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK326791/.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27010052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>