<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37399044</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1537-1603</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>40</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jul</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of clinical neurophysiology : official publication of the American Electroencephalographic Society</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Clin Neurophysiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Different Tendencies in Muscle Ultrasound Characteristic in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis and Chronic Inflammatory Demyelinating Polyradiculoneuropathy.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>450</StartPage><EndPage>455</EndPage><MedlinePgn>450-455</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/WNP.0000000000000898</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The difference in muscle ultrasound (MUS) characteristics in primary axonal degeneration and demyelination has not been well established. The authors aimed to investigate the subject based on the correlation between MUS findings (echo intensity and muscle thickness) and compound muscle action potential (CMAP) amplitude in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) and chronic inflammatory demyelinating polyradiculoneuropathy.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Fifteen patients with ALS and 16 patients with chronic inflammatory demyelinating polyradiculoneuropathy were examined. For each patient, echo intensity and muscle thickness of the abductor pollicis brevis, abductor digiti minimi, and first dorsal interosseous muscles were investigated. Compound muscle action potential amplitudes were measured by median and ulnar nerve conduction studies.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">In total, 45 muscles were evaluated in each group. The ALS group showed a linear correlation between the MUS finding and CMAP amplitude (rs = -0.70 and 0.59 for echo intensity and muscle thickness, respectively), whereas the chronic inflammatory demyelinating polyradiculoneuropathy group showed a weaker correlation than the ALS group (rs = -0.32 for echo intensity and rs = 0.34 for muscle thickness).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The relationship between MUS abnormalities and CMAP amplitude showed different tendencies in ALS and chronic inflammatory demyelinating polyradiculoneuropathy. The results suggested that MUS abnormalities substantially reflect the muscle function in primary axonal degeneration, whereas a discrepancy between MUS findings and muscle function can be frequently seen in demyelination; specifically, MUS findings tend to be normal even though CMAP showed a reduction. These tendencies originating from underlying pathophysiology should be considered when MUS findings are used as biomarkers of disease severity.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022 by the American Clinical Neurophysiology Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hokkoku</LastName><ForeName>Keiichi</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1509-8672</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Teikyo University School of Medicine, Tokyo, Japan; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tsukamoto</LastName><ForeName>Hiroshi</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Teikyo University School of Medicine, Tokyo, Japan; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Uchida</LastName><ForeName>Yudai</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Teikyo University School of Medicine, Tokyo, Japan; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gatto</LastName><ForeName>Dario M</ForeName><Initials>DM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Geriatrics, Neurosciences and Orthopaedics, Catholic University of the Sacred Heart, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sonoo</LastName><ForeName>Masahiro</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Teikyo University School of Medicine, Tokyo, Japan; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Clin Neurophysiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8506708</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0736-0258</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020277" MajorTopicYN="Y">Polyradiculoneuropathy, Chronic Inflammatory Demyelinating</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000200" MajorTopicYN="N">Action Potentials</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000294" MajorTopicYN="N">innervation</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001132" MajorTopicYN="N">Arm</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009431" MajorTopicYN="N">Neural Conduction</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors have no conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>58</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37399044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/WNP.0000000000000898</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00004691-202307000-00010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Heckmatt JZ, Leeman S, Dubowitz V. Ultrasound imaging in the diagnosis of muscle disease. J Pediatr 1982;101:656&#x2013;660.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gunreben G, Bogdahn U. Real&#x2010;time sonography of acute and chronic muscle denervation. Muscle Nerve 1991;14:654&#x2013;664.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pillen S, Arts IM, Zwarts MJ. Muscle ultrasound in neuromuscular disorders. Muscle Nerve 2008;37:679&#x2013;693.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;nez-Pay&#xe1; JJ, del Ba&#xf1;o-Aledo ME, R&#xed;os-D&#xed;az J, Tembl-Ferrair&#xf3; JI, V&#xe1;zquez-Costa JF, Medina-Mirapeix F. Muscular echovariation: a new biomarker in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ultrasound Med Biol 2017;43:1153&#x2013;1162.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisse AL, Fiegert S, Stoykova Z, et al. Increased muscle echointensity correlates with clinical disability and muscle strength in chronic inflammatory demyelinating polyneuropathy. Eur J Neurol 2021;28:1698&#x2013;1705.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Alfen N, Gijsbertse K, de Korte CL. How useful is muscle ultrasound in the diagnostic workup of neuromuscular diseases? Curr Opin Neurol 2018;31:568&#x2013;574.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaidman CM, Holland MR, Noetzel MJ, Park TS, Pestronk A. Newborn brachial plexus palsy: evaluation of severity using quantitative ultrasound of muscle. Muscle Nerve 2013;47:246&#x2013;254.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arts IM, van Rooij FG, Overeem S, et al. Quantitative muscle ultrasonography in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ultrasound Med Biol 2008;34:354&#x2013;361.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arts IMP, Overeem S, Pillen S, Jurgen Schelhaas H, Zwarts MJ. Muscle changes in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a longitudinal ultrasonography study. Clin Neurophysiol 2011;122:623&#x2013;628.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simon NG, Ralph JW, Lomen-Hoerth C, et al. Quantitative ultrasound of denervated hand muscles. Muscle Nerve 2015;52:221&#x2013;230.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seok HY, Park J, Kim YH, Oh KW, Kim SH, Kim BJ. Split hand muscle echo intensity index as a reliable imaging marker for differential diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2018;89:943&#x2013;948.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, Miller RG, Swash M, Munsat TL. El Escorial revisited: revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Mot Neuron Disord 2000;1:293&#x2013;299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abraham A, Drory VE, Fainmesser Y, Algom AA, Lovblom LE, Bril V. Muscle thickness measured by ultrasound is reduced in neuromuscular disorders and correlates with clinical and electrophysiological findings. Muscle Nerve 2019;60:687&#x2013;692.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abraham A, Fainmesser Y, Lovblom LE, Bril V, Drory VE. Superiority of sonographic evaluation of contracted versus relaxed muscle thickness in motor neuron diseases. Clin Neurophysiol 2020;131:1480&#x2013;1486.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hokkoku K, Matsukura K, Uchida Y, et al. Quantitative muscle ultrasound is useful for evaluating secondary axonal degeneration in chronic inflammatory demyelinating polyneuropathy. Brain Behav 2017;7:e00812.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boukhris S, Magy L, Kabore R, et al. Atypical electrophysiologic findings in chronic inflammatory demyelinating polyneuropathy (CIDP): diagnosis confirmed by nerve biopsy. Neurophysiol Clin 2004;34:71&#x2013;79.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dyck PJB, Tracy JA. History, diagnosis, and management of chronic inflammatory demyelinating polyradiculoneuropathy. Mayo Clin Proc 2018;93:777&#x2013;793.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Dijk JG, Van Benten I, Kramer CGS, Stegeman DF. CMAP amplitude cartography of muscles innervated by the median, ulnar, peroneal, and tibial nerves. Muscle Nerve 1999;22:378&#x2013;389.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tankisi H, Pugdahl K, Johnsen B, Fuglsang-Frederiksen A. Correlations of nerve conduction measures in axonal and demyelinating polyneuropathies. Clin Neurophysiol 2007;118:2383&#x2013;2392.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hadden R. European federation of neurological societies/peripheral nerve society guideline * on management of paraproteinemic demyelinating neuropathies. Report of a joint task force of the European federation of neurological societies and the peripheral nerve society. J Peripher Nervous Syst 2010;15:185&#x2013;195.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arts IM, Pillen S, Schelhaas HJ, Overeem S, Zwarts MJ. Normal values for quantitative muscle ultrasonography in adults. Muscle Nerve 2010;41:32&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuwabara S, Ogawara K, Misawa S, Mori M, Hattori T. Distribution patterns of demyelination correlate with clinical profiles in chronic inflammatory demyelinating polyneuropathy. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2002;72:37&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuwabara S, Misawa S, Mori M, Tamura N, Kubota M, Hattori T. Long term prognosis of chronic inflammatory demyelinating polyneuropathy: a five year follow up of 38 cases. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2006;77:66&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohyama K, Koike H, Katsuno M, et al. Muscle atrophy in chronic inflammatory demyelinating polyneuropathy: a computed tomography assessment. Eur J Neurol 2014;21:1002&#x2013;1010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harbo T, Andersen H, Jakobsen J. Length-dependent weakness and electrophysiological signs of secondary axonal loss in chronic inflammatory demyelinating polyradiculoneuropathy. Muscle Nerve 2008;38:1036&#x2013;1045.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>