<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37395323</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>07</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1098-1136</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>71</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Glia</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Glia</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Astrocytic K<sup>+</sup> clearance during disease progression in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2456</StartPage><EndPage>2472</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2456-2472</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/glia.24435</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) is a neurodegenerative disorder in which patients lose motor functions due to progressive loss of motor neurons in the cortex, brainstem, and spinal cord. Whilst the loss of neurons is central to the disease, it is becoming clear that glia, specifically astrocytes, contribute to the onset and progression of neurodegeneration. Astrocytes play an important role in maintaining ion homeostasis in the extracellular milieu and regulate multiple brain functions by altering their extracellular concentrations. In this study, we have investigated the ability of astrocytes to maintain K<sup>+</sup> homeostasis in the brain via direct measurement of the astrocytic K<sup>+</sup> clearance rate in the motor and somatosensory cortices of an ALS mouse model (SOD1<sup>G93A</sup> ). Using electrophysiological recordings from acute brain slices, we show region-specific alterations in the K<sup>+</sup> clearance rate, which was significantly reduced in the primary motor cortex but not the somatosensory cortex. This decrease was accompanied by significant changes in astrocytic morphology, impaired conductivity via Kir4.1 channels and low coupling ratio in astrocytic networks in the motor cortex, which affected their ability to form the K<sup>+</sup> gradient needed to disperse K<sup>+</sup> through the astrocytic syncytium. These findings indicate that the supportive function astrocytes typically provide to motoneurons is diminished during disease progression and provides a potential explanation for the increased vulnerability of motoneurons in ALS.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Authors. GLIA published by Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stevenson</LastName><ForeName>Rebecca</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, Western Sydney University, Campbelltown, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Samokhina</LastName><ForeName>Evgeniia</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, Western Sydney University, Campbelltown, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mangat</LastName><ForeName>Armaan</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, Western Sydney University, Campbelltown, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rossetti</LastName><ForeName>Ilaria</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, Western Sydney University, Campbelltown, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Purushotham</LastName><ForeName>Sushmitha S</ForeName><Initials>SS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, Western Sydney University, Campbelltown, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Malladi</LastName><ForeName>Chandra S</ForeName><Initials>CS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, Western Sydney University, Campbelltown, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Morley</LastName><ForeName>John W</ForeName><Initials>JW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, Western Sydney University, Campbelltown, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Buskila</LastName><ForeName>Yossi</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8500-469X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, Western Sydney University, Campbelltown, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The MARCS Institute, Western Sydney University, Penrith, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Glia</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8806785</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0894-1491</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 1.15.1.1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000072105">Superoxide Dismutase-1</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 1.15.1.1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D013482">Superoxide Dismutase</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051379" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001253" MajorTopicYN="N">Astrocytes</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000072105" MajorTopicYN="N">Superoxide Dismutase-1</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009046" MajorTopicYN="N">Motor Neurons</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013116" MajorTopicYN="N">Spinal Cord</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004195" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Models, Animal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018450" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Progression</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008822" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice, Transgenic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013482" MajorTopicYN="N">Superoxide Dismutase</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">K+ spatial buffering</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SOD1</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">astrocytes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">excitability</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37395323</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/glia.24435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Batavelji&#x107;, D., Nikoli&#x107;, L., Milosevi&#x107;, M., Todorovi&#x107;, N., &amp; Andjus, P. R. (2012). Changes in the astrocytic aquaporin-4 and inwardly rectifying potassium channel expression in the brain of the amyotrophic lateral sclerosis SOD1G93A rat model. Glia, 60, 1991-2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bedner, P., Dupper, A., H&#xfc;ttmann, K., M&#xfc;ller, J., Herde, M. K., Dublin, P., Deshpande, T., Schramm, J., H&#xe4;ussler, U., Haas, C. A., Henneberger, C., Theis, M., &amp; Steinh&#xe4;user, C. (2015). Astrocyte uncoupling as a cause of human temporal lobe epilepsy. Brain: A Journal of Neurology, 138, 1208-1222.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellot-Saez, A., Cohen, G., van Schaik, A., Ooi, L., Wm, J., &amp; Buskila, Y. (2018). Astrocytic modulation of cortical oscillations. Scientific Reports, 8(1), 11565. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-018-30003-w</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellot-Saez, A., Kekesi, O., Morley, J. W., &amp; Buskila, Y. (2017). Astrocytic modulation of neuronal excitability through K(+) spatial buffering. Neuroscience and Biobehavioral Reviews, 77, 87-97. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neubiorev.2017.03.002</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellot-Saez, A., Stevenson, R., Kekesi, O., Samokhina, E., Ben-Abu, Y., Morley, J. W., &amp; Buskila, Y. (2021). Neuromodulation of astrocytic K(+) clearance. International Journal of Molecular Sciences, 22(5), 1-19. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms22052520</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brand-Schieber, E., Werner, P., Iacobas, D. A., Iacobas, S., Beelitz, M., Lowery, S. L., Spray, D. C., &amp; Scemes, E. (2005). Connexin43, the major gap junction protein of astrocytes, is down-regulated in inflamed white matter in an animal model of multiple sclerosis. Journal of Neuroscience Research, 80, 798-808.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breen, P. P., &amp; Buskila, Y. (2014). Braincubator: an incubation system to extend brain slice lifespan for use in neurophysiology. Annu Int Conf IEEE Eng Med Biol Soc, 2014, 4864-4867. https://doi.org/10.1109/EMBC.2014.6944713</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buosi, A. S., Matias, I., Araujo, A. P. B., Batista, C., &amp; Gomes, F. C. A. (2018). Heterogeneity in Synaptogenic Profile of Astrocytes from Different Brain Regions. Molecular Neurobiology, 55(1), 751-762. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12035-016-0343-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buskila, Y., Bellot-Saez, A., K&#xe9;kesi, O., Cameron, M., &amp; Morley, J. (2020). Extending the life span of acute neuronal tissue for imaging and electrophysiological studies. In N. Wright (Ed.), Basic neurobiology techniques (Vol. 152, pp. 235-259). Springer US. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-1-4939-9944-6_10</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buskila, Y., Bellot-Saez, A., &amp; Morley, J. W. (2019). Generating brain waves, the power of astrocytes. Frontiers in Neuroscience, 13, 1125. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnins.2019.01125</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buskila, Y., Breen, P. P., Tapson, J., van Schaik, A., Barton, M., &amp; Morley, J. W. (2014). Extending the viability of acute brain slices. Scientific Reports, 4, 5309. https://doi.org/10.1038/srep05309</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buskila, Y., Morley, J. W., Tapson, J., &amp; van Schaik, A. (2013). The adaptation of spike backpropagation delays in cortical neurons. Frontiers in Cellular Neuroscience, 7, 192. https://doi.org/10.3389/fncel.2013.00192</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butt, A. M., &amp; Kalsi, A. (2006). Inwardly rectifying potassium channels (Kir) in central nervous system glia: A special role for Kir4.1 in glial functions. Journal of Cellular and Molecular Medicine, 10(1), 33-44. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1582-4934.2006.tb00289.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cameron, M. A., Kekesi, O., Morley, J. W., Bellot-Saez, A., Kueh, S., Breen, P., van Schaik, A., Tapson, J., &amp; Buskila, Y. (2017). Prolonged Incubation of Acute Neuronal Tissue for Electrophysiology and Calcium-imaging. J Vis Exp (120), e55396. https://doi.org/10.3791/55396</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell, S. C., Munoz-Ballester, C., Chaunsali, L., Mills, W. A., 3rd, Yang, J. H., Sontheimer, H., &amp; Robel, S. (2020). Potassium and glutamate transport is impaired in scar-forming tumor-associated astrocytes. Neurochemistry International, 133, 104628. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuint.2019.104628</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Capuani, C., Melone, M., Tottene, A., Bragina, L., Crivellaro, G., Santello, M., Casari, G., Conti, F., &amp; Pietrobon, D. (2016). Defective glutamate and K+ clearance by cortical astrocytes in familial hemiplegic migraine type 2. EMBO Molecular Medicine, 8(8), 967-986. https://doi.org/10.15252/emmm.201505944</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chai, H., Diaz-Castro, B., Shigetomi, E., Monte, E., Octeau, J. C., Yu, X., Cohn, W., Rajendran, P. S., Vondriska, T. M., Whitelegge, J. P., Coppola, G., &amp; Khakh, B. S. (2017). Neural circuit-specialized astrocytes: Transcriptomic, proteomic, morphological, and functional evidence. Neuron, 95, 531-549.e539.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, K. C., &amp; Nicholson, C. (2000). Spatial buffering of potassium ions in brain extracellular space. Biophysical Journal, 78(6), 2776-2797. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0006-3495(00)76822-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chever, O., Djukic, B., McCarthy, K. D., &amp; Amzica, F. (2010). Implication of Kir4.1 channel in excess potassium clearance: An in vivo study on anesthetized glial-conditional Kir4.1 knock-out mice. The Journal of Neuroscience, 30(47), 15769-15777. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.2078-10.2010</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui, Y., Masaki, K., Yamasaki, R., Imamura, S., Suzuki, S. O., Hayashi, S., Sato, S., Nagara, Y., Kawamura, M. F., &amp; Kira, J.-I. (2014). Extensive dysregulations of oligodendrocytic and astrocytic connexins are associated with disease progression in an amyotrophic lateral sclerosis mouse model. Journal of Neuroinflammation, 11(1), 42. https://doi.org/10.1186/1742-2094-11-42</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui, Y., Yang, Y., Ni, Z., Dong, Y., Cai, G., Foncelle, A., Ma, S., Sang, K., Tang, S., Li, Y., Shen, Y., Berry, H., Wu, S., &amp; Hu, H. (2018). Astroglial Kir4.1 in the lateral habenula drives neuronal bursts in depression. In Nature (Vol. 554, pp. 323-327). Nature Publishing Group.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Das, M. M., &amp; Svendsen, C. N. (2015). Astrocytes show reduced support of motor neurons with aging that is accelerated in a rodent model of ALS. In Neurobiology of aging (Vol. 36, pp. 1130-1139). Elsevier Ltd.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desplantez, T., Verma, V., Leybaert, L., Evans, W. H., &amp; Weingart, R. (2012). Gap26, a connexin mimetic peptide, inhibits currents carried by connexin43 hemichannels and gap junction channels. In Pharmacological research (Vol. 65, pp. 546-552). Elsevier Ltd.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diaz-Castro, B., Bernstein, A. M., Coppola, G., Sofroniew, M. V., &amp; Khakh, B. S. (2021). Molecular and functional properties of cortical astrocytes during peripherally induced neuroinflammation. Cell Reports, 36(6), 109508. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.celrep.2021.109508</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Djukic, B., Casper, K. B., Philpot, B. D., Chin, L. S., &amp; McCarthy, K. D. (2007). Conditional knock-out of Kir4.1 leads to glial membrane depolarization, inhibition of potassium and glutamate uptake, and enhanced short-term synaptic potentiation. Journal of Neuroscience, 27, 11354-11365.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Do-Ha, D., Buskila, Y., &amp; Ooi, L. (2018). Impairments in motor neurons, interneurons and astrocytes contribute to hyperexcitability in ALS: Underlying mechanisms and paths to therapy. Molecular Neurobiology, 55(2), 1410-1418. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12035-017-0392-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Escartin, C., Galea, E., Lakatos, A., O'Callaghan, J. P., Petzold, G. C., Serrano-Pozo, A., Steinhauser, C., Volterra, A., Carmignoto, G., Agarwal, A., Allen, N. J., Araque, A., Barbeito, L., Barzilai, A., Bergles, D. E., Bonvento, G., Butt, A. M., Chen, W. T., Cohen-Salmon, M., &amp; Verkhratsky, A. (2021). Reactive astrocyte nomenclature, definitions, and future directions. Nature Neuroscience, 24(3), 312-325. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41593-020-00783-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gutnick, M. J., Connors, B. W., &amp; Ransom, B. R. (1981). Dye-coupling between glial cells in the Guinea pig neocortical slice. Brain Research, 213(2), 486-492. https://doi.org/10.1016/0006-8993(81)90259-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guttenplan, K. A., Weigel, M. K., Adler, D. I., Couthouis, J., Liddelow, S. A., Gitler, A. D., &amp; Barres, B. A. (2020). Knockout of reactive astrocyte activating factors slows disease progression in an ALS mouse model. Nature Communications, 11(1), 3753. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-020-17514-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hatzipetros, T., Kidd, J. D., Moreno, A. J., Thompson, K., Gill, A., &amp; Vieira, F. G. (2015). A quick phenotypic neurological scoring system for evaluating disease progression in the SOD1-G93A mouse model of ALS. Journal of Visualized Experiments, 104, 1-6. https://doi.org/10.3791/53257</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heuser, K., Eid, T., Lauritzen, F., Thoren, A. E., Vindedal, G. F., Tauboll, E., Gjerstad, L., Spencer, D. D., Ottersen, O. P., Nagelhus, E. A., &amp; de Lanerolle, N. C. (2012). Loss of perivascular Kir4.1 potassium channels in the sclerotic hippocampus of patients with mesial temporal lobe epilepsy. Journal of Neuropathology and Experimental Neurology, 71(9), 814-825. https://doi.org/10.1097/NEN.0b013e318267b5af</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higashi, K., Fujita, A., Inanobe, A., Tanemoto, M., Doi, K., Kubo, T., &amp; Kurachi, Y. (2001). An inwardly rectifying K+ channel, Kir4. 1, expressed in astrocytes surrounds synapses and blood vessels in brain. American Journal of Physiology-Cell Physiology, 281(3), C922-C931.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johann, S., Heitzer, M., Kanagaratnam, M., Goswami, A., Rizo, T., Weis, J., Troost, D., &amp; Beyer, C. (2015). NLRP3 inflammasome is expressed by astrocytes in the SOD1 mouse model of ALS and in human sporadic ALS patients. Glia, 63, 2260-2273.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kadala, A., Verdier, D., Morquette, P., &amp; Kolta, A. (2015). Ion homeostasis in rhythmogenesis: The interplay between neurons and astroglia. Physiology, 30, 371-388.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaiser, M., Maletzki, I., Hulsmann, S., Holtmann, B., Schulz-Schaeffer, W., Kirchhoff, F., Bahr, M., &amp; Neusch, C. (2006). Progressive loss of a glial potassium channel (KCNJ10) in the spinal cord of the SOD1 (G93A) transgenic mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Journal of Neurochemistry, 99(3), 900-912. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1471-4159.2006.04131.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelley, K. W., Ben Haim, L., Schirmer, L., Tyzack, G. E., Tolman, M., Miller, J. G., Tsai, H. H., Chang, S. M., Molofsky, A. V., Yang, Y., Patani, R., Lakatos, A., Ullian, E. M., &amp; Rowitch, D. H. (2018). Kir4.1-dependent astrocyte-fast motor neuron interactions are required for peak strength. In Neuron (Vol. 98, pp. 306-319.e307). Elsevier Inc.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leiserson, W. M., &amp; Keshishian, H. (2011). Maintenance and regulation of extracellular volume and the ion environment in drosophila larval nerves. Glia, 59(9), 1312-1321. https://doi.org/10.1002/glia.21132</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang, Z., Wang, X., Hao, Y., Qiu, L., Lou, Y., Zhang, Y., Ma, D., &amp; Feng, J. (2020). The multifaceted role of astrocyte connexin 43 in ischemic stroke through forming hemichannels and gap junctions. Frontiers in Neurology, 11, 1-12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma, B., Buckalew, R., Du, Y., Kiyoshi, C. M., Alford, C. C., Wang, W., McTigue, D. M., Enyeart, J. J., Terman, D., &amp; Zhou, M. (2016). Gap junction coupling confers isopotentiality on astrocyte syncytium. Glia, 64(2), 214-226. https://doi.org/10.1002/glia.22924</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma, B., Xu, G., Wang, W., Enyeart, J. J., &amp; Zhou, M. (2014). Dual patch voltage clamp study of low membrane resistance astrocytes in situ. Molecular Brain, 7, 1-12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matias, I., Morgado, J., &amp; Gomes, F. C. A. (2019). Astrocyte heterogeneity: Impact to brain aging and disease. Frontiers in Aging Neuroscience, 11, 1-18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNeill, J., Rudyk, C., Hildebrand, M. E., &amp; Salmaso, N. (2021). Ion channels and electrophysiological properties of astrocytes: Implications for emergent stimulation technologies. Frontiers in Cellular Neuroscience, 15, 644126. https://doi.org/10.3389/fncel.2021.644126</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xe9;ndez-Gonz&#xe1;lez, M. P., Rivera-Aponte, D. E., Benedikt, J., Maldonado-Mart&#xed;nez, G., Tejeda-Bayron, F., Skatchkov, S. N., &amp; Eaton, M. J. (2020). Downregulation of astrocytic Kir4. 1 potassium channels is associated with hippocampal neuronal hyperexcitability in type 2 diabetic mice. Brain Sciences, 10(2), 72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagai, M., Re, D. B., Nagata, T., Chalazonitis, A., Jessell, T. M., Wichterle, H., &amp; Przedborski, S. (2007). Astrocytes expressing ALS-linked mutated SOD1 release factors selectively toxic to motor neurons. Nature Neuroscience, 10(5), 615-622. https://doi.org/10.1038/nn1876</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Octeau, J. C., Faas, G., Mody, I., &amp; Khakh, B. S. (2018). Making, testing, and using potassium ion selective microelectrodes in tissue slices of adult brain. Journal of Visualized Experiments, 2018, 1-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orkand, R. K., Nicholls, J. G., &amp; Kuffler, S. W. (1966). Effect of nerve impulses on the membrane potential of glial cells in the central nervous system of amphibia. Journal of Neurophysiology, 29, 788-806.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel, D. C., Tewari, B. P., Chaunsali, L., &amp; Sontheimer, H. (2019). Neuron-glia interactions in the pathophysiology of epilepsy. Nature Reviews Neuroscience, 20(5), 282-297.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pekny, M., Pekna, M., Messing, A., Steinhauser, C., Lee, J. M., Parpura, V., Hol, E. M., Sofroniew, M. V., &amp; Verkhratsky, A. (2016). Astrocytes: A central element in neurological diseases. Acta Neuropathologica, 131(3), 323-345. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00401-015-1513-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poopalasundaram, S., Knott, C., Shamotienko, O. G., Foran, P. G., Dolly, J. O., Ghiani, C. A., Gallo, V., &amp; Wilkin, G. P. (2000). Glial heterogeneity in expression of the inwardly rectifying K+ channel, Kir4. 1, in adult rat CNS. Glia, 30(4), 362-372.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ransom, B. (1996). Do glial gap junctions play a role in extracellular ion homeostasis? In D. C. Spray &amp; R. Dermietzel (Eds.), Gap junctions in the nervous system (pp. 159-173). R.G. Landes Company.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ransom, C. B., &amp; Sontheimer, H. (1995). Biophysical and pharmacological characterization of inwardly rectifying K+ currents in rat spinal cord astrocytes. Journal of Neurophysiology, 73, 333-346.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rasmussen, R., Nedergaard, M., &amp; Petersen, N. C. (2016). Sulforhodamine 101, a widely used astrocyte marker, can induce cortical seizure-like activity at concentrations commonly used. Scientific Reports, 6, 30433. https://doi.org/10.1038/srep30433</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rose, C. R., &amp; Verkhratsky, A. (2016). Glial ionic excitability: The role for sodium. Glia, 64(10), 1609-1610. https://doi.org/10.1002/glia.23012</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scholl, U. I., Choi, M., Liu, T., Ramaekers, V. T., H&#xe4;usler, M. G., Grimmer, J., Tobe, S. W., Farhi, A., Nelson-Williams, C., &amp; Lifton, R. P. (2009). Seizures, sensorineural deafness, ataxia, mental retardation, and electrolyte imbalance (SeSAME syndrome) caused by mutations in KCNJ10. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, 106(14), 5842-5847.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shibuya, K., Misawa, S., Arai, K., Nakata, M., Kanai, K., Yoshiyama, Y., Ito, K., Isose, S., Noto, Y.-i., &amp; Nasu, S. (2011). Markedly reduced axonal potassium channel expression in human sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: An immunohistochemical study. Experimental Neurology, 232(2), 149-153.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simon, N. G., Turner, M. R., Vucic, S., Al-Chalabi, A., Shefner, J., Lomen-Hoerth, C., &amp; Kiernan, M. C. (2014). Quantifying disease progression in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Annals of Neurology, 76(5), 643-657.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sirabella, R., Valsecchi, V., Anzilotti, S., Cuomo, O., Vinciguerra, A., Cepparulo, P., Brancaccio, P., Guida, N., Blondeau, N., Canzoniero, L. M. T., Franco, C., Amoroso, S., Annunziato, L., &amp; Pignataro, G. (2018). Ionic homeostasis maintenance in ALS: Focus on new therapeutic targets. Frontiers in Neuroscience, 12, 1-14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stevenson, R., Samokhina, E., Rossetti, I., Morley, J. W., &amp; Buskila, Y. (2020). Neuromodulation of glial function during neurodegeneration. Frontiers in Cellular Neuroscience, 14, 278. https://doi.org/10.3389/fncel.2020.00278</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor, J. P., Brown, R. H., Jr., &amp; Cleveland, D. W. (2016). Decoding ALS: From genes to mechanism. Nature, 539(7628), 197-206. https://doi.org/10.1038/nature20413</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomson, A. M., &amp; Armstrong, W. E. (2011). Biocytin-labelling and its impact on late 20th century studies of cortical circuitry. Brain Research Reviews, 66(1-2), 43-53. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.brainresrev.2010.04.004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tong, X., Ao, Y., Faas, G., Nwaobi, S., Xu, J., Haustein, M., Anderson, M., &amp; Mody, I. (2014). Astrocyte Kir4.1 ion channel deficits contribute to 819 neuronal dysfunction in Huntington's disease model mice. Nature Neuroscience, 17, 694-703.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tong, X., Ao, Y., Faas, G. C., Nwaobi, S. E., Xu, J., Haustein, M. D., Anderson, M. A., Mody, I., Olsen, M. L., Sofroniew, M. V., &amp; Khakh, B. S. (2014). Astrocyte Kir4.1 ion channel deficits contribute to neuronal dysfunction in Huntington's disease model mice. Nature Neuroscience, 17(5), 694-703. https://doi.org/10.1038/nn.3691</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tripathi, P., Rodriguez-Muela, N., Klim, J. R., de Boer, A. S., Agrawal, S., Sandoe, J., Lopes, C. S., Ogliari, K. S., Williams, L. A., Shear, M., Rubin, L. L., Eggan, K., &amp; Zhou, Q. (2017). Reactive astrocytes promote ALS-like degeneration and intracellular protein aggregation in human motor neurons by disrupting autophagy through TGF-beta1. Stem Cell Reports, 9(2), 667-680. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.stemcr.2017.06.008</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallraff, A., Kohling, R., Heinemann, U., Theis, M., Willecke, K., &amp; Steinhauser, C. (2006). The impact of astrocytic gap junctional coupling on potassium buffering in the hippocampus. The Journal of Neuroscience, 26(20), 5438-5447. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.0037-06.2006</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilcock, D. M., Vitek, M. P., &amp; Colton, C. A. (2009). Vascular amyloid alters astrocytic water and potassium channels in mouse models and humans with Alzheimer's disease. Neuroscience, 159(3), 1055-1069.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamanaka, K., Chun, S. J., Boillee, S., Fujimori-Tonou, N., Yamashita, H., Gutmann, D. H., Takahashi, R., Misawa, H., &amp; Cleveland, D. W. (2008). Astrocytes as determinants of disease progression in inherited amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nature Neuroscience, 11(3), 251-253. https://doi.org/10.1038/nn2047</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin, X., Feng, L., Ma, D., Yin, P., Wang, X., Hou, S., Hao, Y., Zhang, J., Xin, M., &amp; Feng, J. (2018). Roles of astrocytic connexin-43, hemichannels, and gap junctions in oxygen-glucose deprivation/reperfusion injury induced neuroinflammation and the possible regulatory mechanisms of salvianolic acid B and carbenoxolone. Journal of Neuroinflammation, 15(1), 97. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12974-018-1127-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhong, S., Du, Y., Kiyoshi, C. M., Ma, B., Alford, C. C., Wang, Q., Yang, Y., Liu, X., &amp; Zhou, M. (2016). Electrophysiological behavior of neonatal astrocytes in hippocampal stratum radiatum. Molecular Brain, 9, 34. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13041-016-0213-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, M., Du, Y., Aten, S., &amp; Terman, D. (2021). On the electrical passivity of astrocyte potassium conductance. Journal of Neurophysiology, 126(4), 1403-1419. https://doi.org/10.1152/jn.00330.2021</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>