<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37424512</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>22</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-4598</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>68</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Muscle &amp; nerve</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Muscle Nerve</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A comparative study of cognitive and behavioral profiles between sporadic and type 8 amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>316</StartPage><EndPage>322</EndPage><MedlinePgn>316-322</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/mus.27927</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION/AIMS">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) type 8 (ALS8) is caused by VAPB gene mutations. The differences between neuropsychological and behavioral profiles of patients with sporadic ALS (sALS) and those with ALS8 are unclear. We aimed to compare cognitive performance and behavioral aspects between sALS and ALS8 patients.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Our study included 29 symptomatic ALS8 patients (17 men; median age 49&#x2009;years), 20 sALS patients (12 men; median age 55&#x2009;years), and 30 healthy controls (16 men; median age 50&#x2009;years), matched for sex, age, and education. Participants underwent neuropsychological assessments focused on executive functions, visual memory, and facial emotion recognition. Behavioral and psychiatric symptoms were evaluated using the Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale and the Cambridge Behavioral Inventory.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Clinical groups (sALS and ALS8) exhibited lower global cognitive efficiency and impaired cognitive flexibility, processing speed, and inhibitory control compared with controls. ALS8 and sALS showed similar performance in most executive tests, except for poorer verbal (lexical) fluency in those with sALS. Apathy, anxiety, and stereotypical behaviors were frequent in both clinical groups.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION">sALS and ALS8 patients demonstrated similar deficits in most cognitive domains and had comparable behavioral profiles. These findings should be considered in the care of patients.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>de Alc&#xe2;ntara</LastName><ForeName>C&#xe1;ssia</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3444-5628</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Programa de P&#xf3;s-gradua&#xe7;&#xe3;o em Neuroci&#xea;ncias, Universidade Federal de Minas Gerais, Belo Horizonte, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cruzeiro</LastName><ForeName>Marcelo Maroco</ForeName><Initials>MM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departamento de Cl&#xed;nica M&#xe9;dica, Universidade Federal de Juiz de Fora, Juiz de Fora, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fran&#xe7;a</LastName><ForeName>Marcondes Cavalcante</ForeName><Initials>MC</Initials><Suffix>Jr</Suffix><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0898-2419</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departamento de Neurologia, Universidade Estadual de Campinas, Campinas, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alencar</LastName><ForeName>Mariana Asmar</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departamento de Fisioterapia, Universidade Federal de Minas Gerais, Belo Horizonte, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jaeger</LastName><ForeName>Ant&#xf4;nio</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5093-6198</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Programa de P&#xf3;s-gradua&#xe7;&#xe3;o em Neuroci&#xea;ncias, Universidade Federal de Minas Gerais, Belo Horizonte, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departamento de Psicologia, Faculdade de Filosofia e de Ci&#xea;ncias Humanas, Universidade Federal de Minas Gerais, Belo Horizonte, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>de Ara&#xfa;jo</LastName><ForeName>Caroline Martins</ForeName><Initials>CM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Programa de P&#xf3;s-gradua&#xe7;&#xe3;o em Neuroci&#xea;ncias, Universidade Federal de Minas Gerais, Belo Horizonte, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>da Gama</LastName><ForeName>Nat&#xe1;lia Ara&#xfa;jo Sundfeld</ForeName><Initials>NAS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Programa de P&#xf3;s-gradua&#xe7;&#xe3;o em Neuroci&#xea;ncias, Universidade Federal de Minas Gerais, Belo Horizonte, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Camargos</LastName><ForeName>Sarah Teixeira</ForeName><Initials>ST</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9829-6783</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Programa de P&#xf3;s-gradua&#xe7;&#xe3;o em Neuroci&#xea;ncias, Universidade Federal de Minas Gerais, Belo Horizonte, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departamento de Cl&#xed;nica M&#xe9;dica, Faculdade de Medicina, Universidade Federal de Minas Gerais, Belo Horizonte, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>de Souza</LastName><ForeName>Leonardo Cruz</ForeName><Initials>LC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5027-9722</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Programa de P&#xf3;s-gradua&#xe7;&#xe3;o em Neuroci&#xea;ncias, Universidade Federal de Minas Gerais, Belo Horizonte, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departamento de Cl&#xed;nica M&#xe9;dica, Faculdade de Medicina, Universidade Federal de Minas Gerais, Belo Horizonte, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Muscle Nerve</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7803146</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0148-639X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><SupplMeshList><SupplMeshName Type="Disease" UI="C563895">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis 8</SupplMeshName></SupplMeshList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D056344" MajorTopicYN="N">Executive Function</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057565" MajorTopicYN="Y">Apathy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003071" MajorTopicYN="N">Cognition</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009483" MajorTopicYN="N">Neuropsychological Tests</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">behavior</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cognition</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37424512</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.27927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Beeldman E, Raaphorst J, Klein Twennaar M, de Visser M, Schmand BA, de Haan RJ. The cognitive profile of ALS: a systematic review and meta-analysis update. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2016;87:611-619.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Es MA, Hardiman O, Chio A, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet. 2017;390:2084-2098.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lillo P, Caramelli P, Musa G, et al. Inside minds, beneath diseases: social cognition in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-frontotemporal spectrum disorder. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2020;91:1279-1282.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martins AP, Prado LGR, Lillo P, Mioshi E, Teixeira AL, de Souza LC. Deficits in emotion recognition as markers of frontal behavioral dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neuropsychiatry Clin Neurosci. 2019;31:165-169.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beeldman E, Raaphorst J, Klein Twennaar M, et al. The cognitive profile of behavioural variant FTD and its similarities with ALS: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2018;89:995-1002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strong MJ, Abrahams S, Goldstein LH, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-frontotemporal spectrum disorder (ALS-FTSD): revised diagnostic criteria. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2017;18:153-174.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim G, Gautier O, Tassoni-Tsuchida E, Ma XR, Gitler AD. ALS genetics: gains, losses, and implications for future therapies. Neuron. 2020;108:822-842.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Novis LE, Spitz M, Teive HAG. The history behind ALS type 8: from the first phenotype description to the discovery of VAPB mutation. Arq Neuropsiquiatr. 2021;79:743-747.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishimura AL, Mitne-Neto M, Silva HC, et al. A mutation in the vesicle-trafficking protein VAPB causes late-onset spinal muscular atrophy and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Am J Hum Genet. 2004;75:822-831.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richieri-Costa A, Rogatko A, Levisky R, Finkel N, Frota-Pessoa O. Autosomal dominant late adult spinal muscular atrophy, type Finkel. Am J Med Genet. 1981;9:119-128.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kosac V, Freitas MR, Prado FM, Nascimento OJ, Bittar C. Familial adult spinal muscular atrophy associated with the VAPB gene: report of 42 cases in Brazil. Arq Neuropsiquiatr. 2013;71:788-790.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marques VD, Barreira AA, Davis MB, et al. Expanding the phenotypes of the Pro56Ser VAPB mutation: proximal SMA with dysautonomia. Muscle Nerve. 2006;34:731-739.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marques VD, Marques W Jr. Neurophysiological findings of the late-onset, dominant, proximal spinal muscular atrophies with dysautonomia because of the VAPB PRO56SER mutation. J Clin Neurophysiol. 2008;25:233-235.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Alcantara C, Cruzeiro MM, Franca MC Jr, Camargos ST, de Souza LC. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis type 8 is not a pure motor disease: evidence from a neuropsychological and behavioural study. J Neurol. 2019;266:1980-1987.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Temp AGM, Dyrba M, Kasper E, Teipel S, Prudlo J. Case report: cognitive conversion in a non-Brazilian VAPB mutation carrier (ALS8). Front Neurol. 2021;12:668772.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leoni TB, Rezende TJR, Peluzzo TM, et al. Structural brain and spinal cord damage in symptomatic and pre-symptomatic VAPB-related ALS. J Neurol Sci. 2022;434:120126.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho M, Dengler R, Eisen A, et al. Electrodiagnostic criteria for diagnosis of ALS. Clin Neurophysiol. 2008;119:497-503.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brucki SM, Nitrini R, Caramelli P, Bertolucci PH, Okamoto IH. Suggestions for utilization of the Mini-Mental State Examination in Brazil. Arq Neuropsiquiatr. 2003;61:777-781.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Botega NJ, Bio MR, Zomignani MA, Garcia C Jr, Pereira WA. Mood disorders among inpatients in ambulatory and validation of the anxiety and depression scale HAD. Rev Saude Publica. 1995;29:355-363.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carvalho VA, Caramelli P. Brazilian adaptation of the Addenbrooke's Cognitive Examination - Revised (ACE-R). Dement Neuropsychol. 2007;1:212-216.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Machado TH, Fichman HC, Santos EL, et al. Normative data for healthy elderly on the phonemic verbal fluency task-FAS. Dement Neuropsychol. 2009;3:55-60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abrahams S, Leigh PN, Harvey A, Vythelingum GN, Grise D, Goldstein LH. Verbal fluency and executive dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). Neuropsychologia. 2000;38:734-747.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wechsler D, Nascimento E. Wechsler Adult Intelligence Scale. 3rd ed. Casa do Psic&#xf3;logo; 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paula JJ, Querino EH, Oliveira TD, Sedo M, Malloy-Diniz LF. Transcultural issues on the assessment of executive functions and processing speed in older adults with low formal education: usefulness of the Five Digits Test in the assessment of dementia. Geriatr Gerontol Int. 2015;15:388-389.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zimmermann N, Cardoso CO, Kristensen CH, Fonseca RP. Brazilian norms and effects of age and education on the Hayling and Trail Making Tests. Trends Psychiatry Psychother. 2017;39:188-195.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Souza LC, Bertoux M, Vaz de Faria AR, et al. The effects of gender, age, schooling, and cultural background on the identification of facial emotions: a transcultural study. Int Psychogeriatr. 2018;30:1861-1870.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nitrini R, Caramelli P, Herrera Junior E, et al. Performance of illiterate and literate nondemented elderly subjects in two tests of long-term memory. J Int Neuropsychol Soc. 2004;10:634-638.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guedes K, Pereira C, Pavan K, Valerio BC. Cross-cultural adaptation and validation of ALS Functional Rating Scale-Revised in the Portuguese language. Arq Neuropsiquiatr. 2010;68:44-47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wear HJ, Wedderburn CJ, Mioshi E, et al. The Cambridge Behavioural Inventory revised. Dement Neuropsychol. 2008;2:102-107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dadar M, Manera AL, Zinman L, et al. Cerebral atrophy in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis parallels the pathological distribution of TDP43. Brain Commun. 2020;2:fcaa061.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lillo P, Mioshi E, Burrell JR, Kiernan MC, Hodges JR, Hornberger M. Grey and white matter changes across the amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-frontotemporal dementia continuum. PLoS One. 2012;7:e43993.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menke RA, Korner S, Filippini N, et al. Widespread grey matter pathology dominates the longitudinal cerebral MRI and clinical landscape of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain. 2014;137:2546-2555.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bueno APA, Bertoux M, de, LC S, Hornberger M. How predictive are temporal lobe changes of underlying TDP-43 pathology in the ALS-FTD continuum? Ann Clin Neurophysiol. 2017;19:101-112.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Consonni M, Rossi S, Cerami C, et al. Executive dysfunction affects word list recall performance: evidence from amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and other neurodegenerative diseases. J Neuropsychol. 2017;11:74-90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mantovan MC, Baggio L, Dalla Barba G, et al. Memory deficits and retrieval processes in ALS. Eur J Neurol. 2003;10:221-227.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moscovitch M, Cabeza R, Winocur G, Nadel L. Episodic memory and beyond: the hippocampus and neocortex in transformation. Annu Rev Psychol. 2016;67:105-134.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Souza LC, Sarazin M, Goetz C, Dubois B. Clinical investigations in primary care. Front Neurol Neurosci. 2009;24:1-11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carelli L, Solca F, Tagini S, et al. Emotional processing and experience in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a systematic and critical review. Brain Sci. 2021;11:1356.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lillo P, Mioshi E, Zoing MC, Kiernan MC, Hodges JR. How common are behavioural changes in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis? Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2011;12:45-51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rascovsky K, Hodges JR, Knopman D, et al. Sensitivity of revised diagnostic criteria for the behavioural variant of frontotemporal dementia. Brain. 2011;134:2456-2477.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schreiber H, Gaigalat T, Wiedemuth-Catrinescu U, Graf M, Uttner I, Muche R, et al. Cognitive function in bulbar- and spinal-onset amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. A longitudinal study in 52 patients. J Neurol. 2005;252(7):772-781.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mioshi E, Lillo P, Yew B, et al. Cortical atrophy in ALS is critically associated with neuropsychiatric and cognitive changes. Neurology. 2013;80:1117-1123.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matias-Guiu JA, Cabrera-Martin MN, Valles-Salgado M, et al. Inhibition impairment in frontotemporal dementia, amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, and Alzheimer's disease: clinical assessment and metabolic correlates. Brain Imaging Behav. 2019;13:651-659.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bueno APA, de Souza LC, Pinaya WHL, et al. Papez circuit gray matter and episodic memory in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and behavioural variant frontotemporal dementia. Brain Imaging Behav. 2021;15:996-1006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manera U, Peotta L, Iazzolino B, et al. The characteristics of cognitive impairment in ALS patients depend on the lateralization of motor damage. Brain Sci. 2020;10:650.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palumbo F, Iazzolino B, Peotta L, et al. Social cognition deficits in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a pilot cross-sectional population-based study. Eur J Neurol. 2022;29:2211-2219.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crespi C, Cerami C, Dodich A, et al. Microstructural white matter correlates of emotion recognition impairment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Cortex. 2014;53:1-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niven E, Newton J, Foley J, et al. Validation of the Edinburgh Cognitive and Behavioural Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Screen (ECAS): a cognitive tool for motor disorders. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2015;16:172-179.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>