<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37422655</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>18</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1532-6535</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>114</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Clinical pharmacology and therapeutics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Clin Pharmacol Ther</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Hybrid Controlled Clinical Trials Using Concurrent Registries in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis: A Feasibility Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>883</StartPage><EndPage>892</EndPage><MedlinePgn>883-892</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/cpt.2994</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Hybrid designs with both randomized arms and an external control cohort preserve key features of randomization and utilize external information to augment clinical trials. In this study, we propose to leverage high-quality, patient-level concurrent registries to enhance clinical trials and illustrate the impact on trial design for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. The proposed methodology was evaluated in a randomized, placebo-controlled clinical trial. We used patient-level information from a well-defined, population-based registry, that was running parallel to the randomized clinical trial, to identify concurrently nonparticipating, eligible patients who could be matched with trial participants, and integrate them into the statistical analysis. We assessed the impact of the addition of the external controls on the treatment effect estimate, precision, and time to reach a conclusion. During the runtime of the trial, a total of 1,141 registry patients were alive; 473 (41.5%) of them fulfilled the eligibility criteria and 133 (11.7%) were enrolled in the study. A matched control population could be identified among the nonparticipating patients. Augmenting the randomized controls with matched external controls could have avoided unnecessary randomization of 17 patients (-12.8%) as well as reducing the study duration from 30.1&#x2009;months to 22.6&#x2009;months (-25.0%). Matching eligible external controls from a different calendar period led to bias in the treatment effect estimate. Hybrid trial designs utilizing a concurrent registry with rigorous matching can minimize bias due to a mismatch in calendar time and differences in standard of care, and may accelerate the development of new treatments.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Authors. Clinical Pharmacology &amp; Therapeutics published by Wiley Periodicals LLC on behalf of American Society for Clinical Pharmacology and Therapeutics.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>van Eijk</LastName><ForeName>Ruben P A</ForeName><Initials>RPA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7132-5967</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Data Science and Centre for Innovative Study Design, School of Medicine, Stanford University, Stanford, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, UMC Utrecht Brain Centre, University Medical Centre Utrecht, Utrecht, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>van den Berg</LastName><ForeName>Leonard H</ForeName><Initials>LH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5203-9674</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, UMC Utrecht Brain Centre, University Medical Centre Utrecht, Utrecht, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Roes</LastName><ForeName>Kit C B</ForeName><Initials>KCB</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6775-1963</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Section Biostatistics, Department of Health Evidence, Radboud Medical Centre, Nijmegen, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tian</LastName><ForeName>Lu</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5893-0169</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Data Science and Centre for Innovative Study Design, School of Medicine, Stanford University, Stanford, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lai</LastName><ForeName>Tze L</ForeName><Initials>TL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Data Science and Centre for Innovative Study Design, School of Medicine, Stanford University, Stanford, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nelson</LastName><ForeName>Lorene M</ForeName><Initials>LM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9813-8088</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Epidemiology and Population Health, School of Medicine, Stanford University, Stanford, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Chenyu</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Data Science and Centre for Innovative Study Design, School of Medicine, Stanford University, Stanford, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Scowcroft</LastName><ForeName>Anna</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4727-9243</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>UCB Pharma, Brussels, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Garcia-Segovia</LastName><ForeName>Jesus</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>UCB Pharma, Brussels, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lu</LastName><ForeName>Ying</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7698-8962</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Data Science and Centre for Innovative Study Design, School of Medicine, Stanford University, Stanford, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Epidemiology and Population Health, School of Medicine, Stanford University, Stanford, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Clin Pharmacol Ther</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0372741</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0009-9236</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005240" MajorTopicYN="N">Feasibility Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012107" MajorTopicYN="N">Research Design</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37422655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cpt.2994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Avorn, J. The $2.6 billion pill-methodologic and policy considerations. N. Engl. J. Med. 372, 1877-1879 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jansen-van der Weide, M.C. et al. Rare disease registries: potential applications towards impact on development of new drug treatments. Orphanet J. Rare Dis. 13, 154 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arlett, P., Kjaer, J., Broich, K. &amp; Cooke, E. Real-world evidence in EU medicines regulation: enabling use and establishing value. Clin. Pharmacol. Ther. 111, 21-23 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Purpura, C.A., Garry, E.M., Honig, N., Case, A. &amp; Rassen, J.A. The role of real-world evidence in FDA-approved new drug and biologics license applications. Clin. Pharmacol. Ther. 111, 135-144 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Food Drug Administration Center for Drugs Evaluation Research Complex innovative trial design meeting program. &lt;https://www.fda.gov/drugs/development-resources/complex-innovative-trial-design-meeting-program&gt; (2022). Accessed December 27, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Food Drug Administration Center for Drugs Evaluation Research Complex innovative trial designs. &lt;https://fda.report/media/129256/Complex+Innovative+Trial+Designs+Brochure_508.pdf&gt; (2022). Accessed December 27, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>European Medicines Agency Accelerating Clinical Trials in the EU: Workplan 2022-2026. &lt;https://www.ema.europa.eu/en/documents/other/act-eu-multi-annual-workplan-2022-2026_en.pdf&gt; (2022). Accessed December 27, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hall, K.T. et al. Historical controls in randomized clinical trials: opportunities and challenges. Clin. Pharmacol. Ther. 109, 343-351 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghadessi, M. et al. A roadmap to using historical controls in clinical trials-by drug information association adaptive design scientific working group (DIA-ADSWG). Orphanet J. Rare Dis. 15, 69 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, Y., Wang, F., Tang, J., Nussinov, R. &amp; Cheng, F. Artificial intelligence in COVID-19 drug repurposing. Lancet Digit Health 2, e667-e676 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeon, J.Y. et al. Development of an external control arm using electronic health record-based real-world data to evaluate the efficacy of COVID-19 treatment. Clin. Pharmacol. Ther. 113, 1274-1283 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burger, H.U. et al. The use of external controls: to what extent can it currently be recommended? Pharm. Stat. 20, 1002-1016 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahman, R. et al. Leveraging external data in the design and analysis of clinical trials in neuro-oncology. Lancet Oncol. 22, e456-e465 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan, J., Liu, J., Zhu, R., Lu, Y. &amp; Palm, U. Design of randomized controlled confirmatory trials using historical control data to augment sample size for concurrent controls. J. Biopharm. Stat. 29, 558-573 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hernan, M.A., Sauer, B.C., Hernandez-Diaz, S., Platt, R. &amp; Shrier, I. Specifying a target trial prevents immortal time bias and other self-inflicted injuries in observational analyses. J. Clin. Epidemiol. 79, 70-75 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stern, A.D. et al. Advancing digital health applications: priorities for innovation in real-world evidence generation. Lancet Digit Health 4, e200-e206 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chio, A. et al. ALS clinical trials: do enrolled patients accurately represent the ALS population? Neurology 77, 1432-1437 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verstraete, E. et al. Lithium lacks effect on survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a phase IIb randomised sequential trial. J.&#xa0;Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatry 83, 557-564 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fornai, F. et al. Lithium delays progression of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 105, 2052-2057 (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks, B.R., Miller, R.G., Swash, M., Munsat, T.L. &amp; World Federation of Neurology Research Group on Motor Neuron Diseases El Escorial revisited: revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph. Lateral Scler. Other Motor Neuron Disord. 1, 293-299 (2000).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Jongh, A.D. et al. Incidence, prevalence and geographical clustering of motor neuron disease in The Netherlands. Neurology 96, e1227-e1236 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pocock, S.J. The combination of randomized and historical controls in clinical trials. J. Chronic Dis. 29, 175-188 (1976).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kimura, F. et al. Progression rate of ALSFRS-R at time of diagnosis predicts survival time in ALS. Neurology 66, 265-267 (2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rubin, D.B. &amp; Schenker, N. Multiple imputation in health-care databases: an overview and some applications. Stat. Med. 10, 585-598 (1991).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morisot, A., Bessaoud, F., Landais, P., R&#xe9;billard, X., Tr&#xe9;tarre, B. &amp; Daur&#xe8;s, J.P. Prostate cancer: net survival and cause-specific survival rates after multiple imputation. BMC Med. Res. Methodol. 15, 54 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu, Y. &amp; Tian, L. Statistical considerations for sequential analysis of the restricted mean survival time for randomized clinical trials. Stat. Biopharm. Res. 13, 210-218 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rooney, J.P.K., Brayne, C., Tobin, K., Logroscino, G., Glymour, M.M. &amp; Hardiman, O. Benefits, pitfalls, and future design of population-based registers in neurodegenerative disease. Neurology 88, 2321-2329 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitehead, J. The Design and Analysis of Sequential Clinical Trials Revised 2nd edn. (J. Wiley &amp; Sons, Chichester; New York, 1997).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, J. Statistical Methods for Survival Trial Design: With Applications to Cancer Clinical Trials Using R (Taylor &amp; Francis, Boca Raton, FL, 2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Rosmalen, J., Dejardin, D., van Norden, Y., L&#xf6;wenberg, B. &amp; Lesaffre, E. Including historical data in the analysis of clinical trials: is it worth the effort? Stat. Methods Med. Res. 27, 3167-3182 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, R.S., Croteau-Chonka, D.C., Silverman, E.K., Loscalzo, J., Weiss, S.T. &amp; Hall, K.T. Pharmacogenomics and placebo response in a randomized clinical trial in asthma. Clin. Pharmacol. Ther. 106, 1261-1267 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook, S.F. et al. A descriptive review of global real world evidence efforts to advance drug discovery and clinical development in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Front. Neurol. 12, 770001 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baumfeld Andre, E., Reynolds, R., Caubel, P., Azoulay, L. &amp; Dreyer, N.A. Trial designs using real-world data: the changing landscape of the regulatory approval process. Pharmacoepidemiol. Drug Saf. 29, 1201-1212 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld, D.A. &amp; Richter, J.R. Nomograms for calculating the number of patients needed for a clinical trial with survival as an endpoint. Biometrics 38, 163-170 (1982).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Eijk, R.P.A. et al. Critical design considerations for time-to-event endpoints in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis clinical trials. J.&#xa0;Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatry 90, 1331-1337 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kopp-Schneider, A., Calderazzo, S. &amp; Wiesenfarth, M. Power gains by using external information in clinical trials are typically not possible when requiring strict type I error control. Biom. J. 62, 361-374 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Y. et al. Matching design for augmenting the control arm of a randomized controlled trial using real-world data. J. Biopharm. Stat. 32, 124-140 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidli, H., Haring, D.A., Thomas, M., Cassidy, A., Weber, S. &amp; Bretz, F. Beyond randomized clinical trials: use of external controls. Clin. Pharmacol. Ther. 107, 806-816 (2020).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>