<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37433093</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>13</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1936-2692</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>29</Volume><Issue>7 Suppl</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The American journal of managed care</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Am J Manag Care</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Managed care considerations to improve health care utilization for patients with ALS.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>S120</StartPage><EndPage>S126</EndPage><MedlinePgn>S120-S126</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.37765/ajmc.2023.89388</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) is a fatally progressive degenerative disease, with many patients succumbing to the condition within 3 to 5 years after diagnosis. It is a rare, orphan disease with an estimated US prevalence of 25,000 patients. Patients with ALS and their caregivers are faced with a substantial financial burden as a result of the condition, as ALS has an estimated national financial burden of $1.03 billion. A significant driver of the patient financial burden includes the continued need for caregiver support as the weakening of muscles progresses to dysphagia and dyspnea, making it difficult to complete activities of daily living as the disease progresses. Caregivers also experience financial burdens, as well as feelings of anxiety, depression, and decreased quality of life. In addition to needed caregiver support, patients with ALS and their families also incur substantial nonmedical costs including travel expenses, home modifications such as ramps, and indirect costs such as productivity loss. Due to the wide range of clinical symptoms that patients may exhibit when first presenting with ALS symptoms, diagnosis is often delayed, which negatively affects patient outcomes and impacts missed opportunity for clinical trial recruitment aimed at developing new disease-modifying therapies. Additionally, delay in diagnosis and referral to ALS treatment centers results in increased overall health care costs. Telemedicine may be a tool used to promote timely care from an ALS treatment center in addition to clinical trial participation for those patients who cannot overcome mobility barriers for care. Currently, 4 therapies are approved for the treatment of ALS. Riluzole has demonstrated modest improvement in survival. Other recently approved therapies include oral edaravone, a combination therapy of sodium phenylbutyrate and taurursodiol (PB/TURSO), and tofersen, which is administered intrathecally and approved under an accelerated approval. Long-term studies have shown PB/TURSO to have a dual benefit on survival and function. The Institute for Clinical and Economic Review (ICER) 2022 Evidence Report for ALS does not value the high price points of edaravone and PB/TURSO as cost-effective based on the current evidence, despite valuing the need for new treatment options for this patient population.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wong</LastName><ForeName>Winston</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>President, W-Squared Group, in Longboat Key, FL. Email: wwong@wsquaredgroup.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Am J Manag Care</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9613960</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1088-0224</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>S798V6YJRP</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000077553">Edaravone</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C000723627">sodium phenylbutyrate and taurursodiol</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000077553" MajorTopicYN="N">Edaravone</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000203" MajorTopicYN="N">Activities of Daily Living</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010342" MajorTopicYN="N">Patient Acceptance of Health Care</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008329" MajorTopicYN="N">Managed Care Programs</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37433093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.37765/ajmc.2023.89388</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">89388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>