<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37436778</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1530-6860</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>37</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>FASEB journal : official publication of the Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>FASEB J</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Therapy of autoimmune inflammation in sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: Dimethyl fumarate and H-151 downregulate inflammatory cytokines in the cGAS-STING pathway.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e23068</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e23068</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1096/fj.202300573R</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>In sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (sALS), IL-17A- and granzyme-positive cytotoxic T lymphocytes (CTL), IL-17A-positive mast cells, and inflammatory macrophages invade the brain and spinal cord. In some patients, the disease starts following a trauma or a severe infection. We examined cytokines and cytokine regulators over the disease course and found that, since the early stages, peripheral blood mononuclear cells (PBMC) exhibit increased expression of inflammatory cytokines IL-12A, IFN-&#x3b3;, and TNF-&#x3b1;, as well as granzymes and the transcription factors STAT3 and STAT4. In later stages, PBMCs upregulated the autoimmunity-associated cytokines IL-23A and IL-17B, and the chemokines CXCL9 and CXCL10, which attract CTL and monocytes into the central nervous system. The inflammation is fueled by the downregulation of IL-10, TGF&#x3b2;, and the inhibitory T-cell co-receptors CTLA4, LAG3, and PD-1, and, in vitro, by stimulation with the ligand PD-L1. We investigated in two sALS patients the regulation of the macrophage transcriptome by dimethyl fumarate (DMF), a drug approved against multiple sclerosis and psoriasis, and the cyclic GMP-AMP synthase/stimulator of interferon genes (cGAS/STING) pathway inhibitor H-151. Both DMF and H-151 downregulated the expression of granzymes and the pro-inflammatory cytokines IL-1&#x3b2;, IL-6, IL-15, IL-23A, and IFN-&#x3b3;, and induced a pro-resolution macrophage phenotype. The eicosanoid epoxyeicosatrienoic acids (EET) from arachidonic acid was anti-inflammatory in synergy with DMF. H-151 and DMF are thus candidate drugs targeting the inflammation and autoimmunity in sALS via modulation of the NF&#x3ba;B and cGAS/STING pathways.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Authors. The FASEB Journal published by Wiley Periodicals LLC on behalf of Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zamiri</LastName><ForeName>Kurosh</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Integrative Biology and Physiology, UCLA School of Life Sciences, University of California, Los Angeles, Los Angeles, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kesari</LastName><ForeName>Santosh</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pacific Neuroscience Institute, Saint John's Cancer Institute at Providence Saint John's Health Center, Santa Monica, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Paul</LastName><ForeName>Ketema</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Integrative Biology and Physiology, UCLA School of Life Sciences, University of California, Los Angeles, Los Angeles, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hwang</LastName><ForeName>Sung Hee</ForeName><Initials>SH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Entomology and Nematology, UC Davis Comprehensive Cancer Center, University of California, Davis, Davis, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hammock</LastName><ForeName>Bruce</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1408-8317</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Entomology and Nematology, UC Davis Comprehensive Cancer Center, University of California, Davis, Davis, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kaczor-Urbanowicz</LastName><ForeName>Karolina El&#x17c;bieta</ForeName><Initials>KE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>UCLA Institute for Quantitative and Computational Biosciences, University of California at Los Angeles, Los Angeles, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Control and Computation Engineering, Warsaw University of Technology, Warsaw, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Urbanowicz</LastName><ForeName>Andrzej</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>UCLA Institute for Quantitative and Computational Biosciences, University of California at Los Angeles, Los Angeles, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Control and Computation Engineering, Warsaw University of Technology, Warsaw, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gao</LastName><ForeName>Lucy</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Semel Institute, David Geffen School of Medicine at UCLA, Los Angeles, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Whitelegge</LastName><ForeName>Julian</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Semel Institute, David Geffen School of Medicine at UCLA, Los Angeles, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fiala</LastName><ForeName>Milan</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8023-6053</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Integrative Biology and Physiology, UCLA School of Life Sciences, University of California, Los Angeles, Los Angeles, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R35 ES030443</GrantID><Acronym>ES</Acronym><Agency>NIEHS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>FASEB J</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8804484</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0892-6638</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D016207">Cytokines</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D020381">Interleukin-17</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>FO2303MNI2</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000069462">Dimethyl Fumarate</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 3.4.21.-</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D053804">Granzymes</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 2.7.7.-</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D009713">Nucleotidyltransferases</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><SupplMeshList><SupplMeshName Type="Disease" UI="C531617">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis 1</SupplMeshName></SupplMeshList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016207" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cytokines</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020381" MajorTopicYN="N">Interleukin-17</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000069462" MajorTopicYN="N">Dimethyl Fumarate</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007963" MajorTopicYN="N">Leukocytes, Mononuclear</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053804" MajorTopicYN="N">Granzymes</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007249" MajorTopicYN="N">Inflammation</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009713" MajorTopicYN="N">Nucleotidyltransferases</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">
IFN&#x3b3;
</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">
IL-17B
</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">
IL-1&#x3b2;
</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">
TNF&#x3b1;
</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">H-151</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">autoimmunity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cGAS-STING pathway</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dimethyl fumarate</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37436778</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1096/fj.202300573R</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Peters OM, Ghasemi M, Brown RH Jr. Emerging mechanisms of molecular pathology in ALS. J Clin Invest. 2015;125:1767-1779.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu D, Ou S, Tang M, Yin Z, Wang Z, Liu G. Trauma and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2021;22:170-185.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lotz SK, Blackhurst BM, Reagin KL, Funk KE. Microbial infections are a risk factor for neurodegenerative diseases. Front Cell Neurosci. 2021;15:691136.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lam L, Halder RC, Montoya DJ, et al. Anti-inflammatory therapies of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis guided by immune pathways. Am J Neurodegener Dis. 2015;4:28-39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu CH, Davidson S, Harapas CR, et al. TDP-43 triggers mitochondrial DNA release via mPTP to activate cGAS/STING in ALS. Cell. 2020;183:636-649 e618.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ablasser A, Chen ZJ. cGAS in action: expanding roles in immunity and inflammation. Science. 2019;363:eaat8657.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Decout A, Katz JD, Venkatraman S, Ablasser A. The cGAS-STING pathway as a therapeutic target in inflammatory diseases. Nat Rev Immunol. 2021;21:548-569.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graves MC, Fiala M, Dinglasan LA, et al. Inflammation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis spinal cord and brain is mediated by activated macrophages, mast cells and T cells. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord. 2004;5:213-219.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bobardt MD, Salmon P, Wang L, et al. Contribution of proteoglycans to human immunodeficiency virus type 1 brain invasion. J Virol. 2004;78:6567-6584.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henkel JS, Engelhardt JI, Siklos L, et al. Presence of dendritic cells, MCP-1, and activated microglia/macrophages in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis spinal cord tissue. Ann Neurol. 2004;55:221-235.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fiala M. RE-balancing of inflammation and amyloid-beta immunity as a therapeutic for Alzheimer's disease-view from the bedside. CNS Neurol Disord Drug Targets. 2010;9:192-196.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu G, Fiala M, Mizwicki MT, et al. Neuronal phagocytosis by inflammatory macrophages in ALS spinal cord: inhibition of inflammation by resolvin D1. Am J Neurodegener Dis. 2012;1:60-74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rose TE, Morisseau C, Liu JY, et al. 1-Aryl-3-(1-acylpiperidin-4-yl)urea inhibitors of human and murine soluble epoxide hydrolase: structure-activity relationships, pharmacokinetics, and reduction of inflammatory pain. J Med Chem. 2010;53:7067-7075.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dobin A, Davis CA, Schlesinger F, et al. STAR: ultrafast universal RNA-seq aligner. Bioinformatics. 2013;29:15-21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anders S, Pyl PT, Huber W. HTSeq-a python framework to work with high-throughput sequencing data. Bioinformatics. 2015;31:166-169.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vivian J, Rao AA, Nothaft FA, et al. Toil enables reproducible, open source, big biomedical data analyses. Nat Biotechnol. 2017;35:314-316.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen KB, Watford WT, Salomon R, et al. Critical role for STAT4 activation by type 1 interferons in the interferon-gamma response to viral infection. Science. 2002;297:2063-2066.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hameed A, Lowrey DM, Lichtenheld M, Podack ER. Characterization of three serine esterases isolated from human IL-2 activated killer cells. J Immunol. 1988;141:3142-3147.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newby BN, Brusko TM, Zou B, Atkinson MA, Clare-Salzler M, Mathews CE. Type 1 interferons potentiate human CD8(+) T-cell cytotoxicity through a STAT4- and Granzyme B-dependent pathway. Diabetes. 2017;66:3061-3071.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar P, Bhattacharya P, Prabhakar BS. A comprehensive review on the role of co-signaling receptors and Treg homeostasis in autoimmunity and tumor immunity. J Autoimmun. 2018;95:77-99.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beers DR, Zhao W, Appel SH. The role of regulatory T lymphocytes in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. JAMA Neurol. 2018;75(6):656-658.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pai SY, Kim C, Williams DA. Rac GTPases in human diseases. Dis Markers. 2010;29:177-187.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibbs KL, Kalmar B, Rhymes ER, et al. Inhibiting p38 MAPK alpha rescues axonal retrograde transport defects in a mouse model of ALS. Cell Death Dis. 2018;9:596.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Imamura K, Izumi Y, Watanabe A, et al. The Src/c-Abl pathway is a potential therapeutic target in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Sci Transl Med. 2017;9:eaaf3962.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez-Fernandez C, Gonzalez P, Rodriguez FJ. New insights into Wnt signaling alterations in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a potential therapeutic target? Neural Regen Res. 2020;15:1580-1589.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marques RF, Duncan KE. SYNGR4 and PLEKHB1 deregulation in motor neurons of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis models: potential contributions to pathobiology. Neural Regen Res. 2022;17:266-270.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao RQ, Ren C, Xia ZF, Yao YM. Organelle-specific autophagy in inflammatory diseases: a potential therapeutic target underlying the quality control of multiple organelles. Autophagy. 2021;17:385-401.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiot A, Zaidi S, Iltis C, et al. Modifying macrophages at the periphery has the capacity to change microglial reactivity and to extend ALS survival. Nat Neurosci. 2020;23:1339-1351.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicholson LB, Raveney BJ, Munder M. Monocyte dependent regulation of autoimmune inflammation. Curr Mol Med. 2009;9:23-29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fukasawa T, Yoshizaki A, Ebata S, et al. Contribution of soluble forms of programmed death 1 and programmed death ligand 2 to disease severity and progression in systemic sclerosis. Arthritis Rheumatol. 2017;69:1879-1890.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beers DR, Zhao W, Thonhoff JR, et al. Serum programmed cell death proteins in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain Behav Immun Health. 2021;12:100209.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S, Henderson RD, Mathers S, et al. Safety and efficacy of dimethyl fumarate in ALS: randomised controlled study. Ann Clin Transl Neurol. 2021;8:1991-1999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fiala M, Chattopadhay M, La Cava A, et al. IL-17A is increased in the serum and in spinal cord CD8 and mast cells of ALS patients. J. Neuroinflammation. 2010;7:1-14.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>