<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37440197</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>17</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1439-7633</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>24</Volume><Issue>16</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>15</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Chembiochem : a European journal of chemical biology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Chembiochem</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Dessert or Poison? The Roles of Glycosylation in Alzheimer's, Parkinson's, Huntington's Disease, and Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e202300017</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e202300017</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/cbic.202300017</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Ministry of Education and Key Laboratory of Neurons and glial cells of the central nervous system (CNS) are modified by glycosylation and rely on glycosylation to achieve normal neural function. Neurodegenerative disease is a common disease of the elderly, affecting their healthy life span and quality of life, and no effective treatment is currently available. Recent research implies that various glycosylation traits are altered during neurodegenerative diseases, suggesting a potential implication of glycosylation in disease pathology. Herein, we summarized the current knowledge about glycosylation associated with Alzheimer's disease (AD), Parkinson's disease (PD), Huntington's disease (HD), and Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) pathogenesis, focusing on their promising functional avenues. Moreover, we collected research aimed at highlighting the need for such studies to provide a wealth of disease-related glycosylation information that will help us better understand the pathophysiological mechanisms and hopefully specific glycosylation information to provide further diagnostic and therapeutic directions for neurodegenerative diseases.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 Wiley-VCH Verlag GmbH.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Jiajun</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biochemistry and Molecular Biology School of Basic Medical Science, Guizhou Medical University, Guiyang, 550004, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Endemic and Ethenic Diseases Medical Molecular Biology of Guizhou Province Guizhou Medical University, Guiyang, 550004, Guizhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Hongmei</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biochemistry and Molecular Biology School of Basic Medical Science, Guizhou Medical University, Guiyang, 550004, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Endemic and Ethenic Diseases Medical Molecular Biology of Guizhou Province Guizhou Medical University, Guiyang, 550004, Guizhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Yuhui</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4873-8157</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Endemic and Ethenic Diseases Medical Molecular Biology of Guizhou Province Guizhou Medical University, Guiyang, 550004, Guizhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Guizhou Medical University, Guiyang, 550004, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Chembiochem</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100937360</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1439-4227</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D011042">Poisons</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006816" MajorTopicYN="Y">Huntington Disease</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019636" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neurodegenerative Diseases</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000544" MajorTopicYN="Y">Alzheimer Disease</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010300" MajorTopicYN="Y">Parkinson Disease</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006031" MajorTopicYN="N">Glycosylation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011042" MajorTopicYN="Y">Poisons</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Abnormal glycosylation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Alternations</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Glycans biomarkers</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Glycosylation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neurodegenerative diseases</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37440197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cbic.202300017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>W. Wang, S. Gopal, R. Pocock, Z. Xiao, Molecules 2019, 24, 4604.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. A. Flynn, K. Pedram, S. A. Malaker, P. J. Batista, B. A. H. Smith, A. G. Johnson, B. M. George, K. Majzoub, P. W. Villalta, J. E. Carette, C. R. Bertozzi, Cell 2021, 184, 3109-3124.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. L. Schnaar, R. Gerardy-Schahn, H. Hildebrandt, Physiol. Rev. 2014, 94, 461-518.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Wyss-Coray, Nature 2016, 539, 180-186.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iqbal S, Ghanimi Fard M, Everest-Dass A, Packer NH, Parker LM. Understanding cellular glycan surfaces in the central nervous system. Biochem Soc Trans 2019, 47: 89-100.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Abou-Abbass, H. Abou-El-Hassan, H. Bahmad, K. Zibara, A. Zebian, R. Youssef, J. Ismail, R. Zhu, S. Zhou, X. Dong, M. Nasser, M. Bahmad, H. Darwish, Y. Mechref, F. Kobeissy, Electrophoresis 2016, 37, 1549-1561.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. N. Masbuchin, M. S. Rohman, P. Y. Liu, Int. J. Mol. Sci. 2021, 22, 9829.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. W. Moremen, R. S. Haltiwanger, Nat. Chem. Biol. 2019, 15, 853-864.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. De Vellis, S. Pietrobono, B. Stecca, Cells 2021, 10, 2136.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Passaponti, V. Pavone, L. Cresti, F. Ietta, Tissue Cell 2021, 73, 101630.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Varki, Glycobiology 2017, 27, 3-49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. R. Conroy, T. R. Hawkinson, L. E. A. Young, M. S. Gentry, R. C. Sun, Trends Endocrinol. Metab. 2021, 32, 980-993.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Sonnino, A. Prinetti, Glycoconjugate J. 2018, 35, 343-344.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. W. Moremen, M. Tiemeyer, A. V. Nairn, Nat. Rev. Mol. Cell Biol. 2012, 13, 448-462.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Yang, M. Yin, Y. Hou, H. Li, Y. Guo, H. Yu, K. Zhang, C. Zhang, L. Jia, F. Zhang, X. Li, H. Bian, Z. Li, Cell. Biosci. 2022, 12, 16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Kleene, M. Schachner, Nat. Rev. Neurosci. 2004, 5, 195-208.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. L. Rebelo, M. T. Chevalier, L. Russo, A. Pandit, Trends Mol. Med. 2022, 28, 270-289.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Scott, V. M. Panin, Adv. Neurobiol. 2014, 9, 367-994.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Scott, V. M. Panin, Glycobiology 2014, 24, 407-417.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. Y. Wani, J. C. Chatham, V. Darley-Usmar, L. L. McMahon, J. Zhang, Brain Res. Bull. 2017, 133, 80-87.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. O&#x2032;Flaherty, I. Trbojevi&#x107;-Akma&#x10d;i&#x107;, G. Greville, P. M. Rudd, G. Lauc, Expert Rev. Proteomics 2018, 15, 13-29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Yang, X. Liu, J. Shu, Y. Hou, M. Chen, H. Yu, T. Ma, H. Du, J. Zhang, Y. Qiao, J. He, L. Niu, F. Yang, Z. Li, Glycocon. J. 2020, 37, 373-394.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. J. Gabius, Wiley Blackwell 2009, Weinheim.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. Sterner, N. Flanagan, J. C. Gildersleeve, ACS Chem. Biol. 2016, 11, 1773-1783.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. Cheng, R. Xie, L. Dong, X. Chen, ChemBioChem 2016, 17, 11-27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. V. Everest-Dass, E. S. X. Moh, C. Ashwood, A. M. M. Shathil, N. H. Packer, Expert. Rev. 2018, 15, 165-182.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N. Leymarie, J. Zaia, Anal. Chem. 2012, 84, 3040-3048.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Pu, M. E. Ridgeway, R. S. Glaskin, M. A. Park, C. E. Costello, C. Lin, Anal. Chem. 2016, 88, 3440-3443.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Haukedal, K. K. Freude, Front. Neurol. Neurosci. 2021, 14, 625348.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Terracciano, A. R. Sutin, Y. An, R. J. O'Brien, L. Ferrucci, A. B. Zonderman, S. M. Resnick, Alzheimer&#x2032;s Dementia 2014, 10, 79-186.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. F. Tao, H. C. Huang, ACS. Chem. Neurosci. 2019, 10, 2115-2124.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. Scheltens, K. Blennow, M. M. Breteler, B. de Strooper, G. B. Frisoni, S. Salloway, V. M. Van der Flier, Lancet 2016, 388, 505-517.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Kizuka, S. Kitazume, N. Taniguchi, Biochim. Biophys. Acta Gen. Subj. 2017, 1861: 2447-2454.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. Fang, J. Xie, S. Sang, L. Zhang, M. Liu, L. Yang, Y. Xu, G. Yan, J. Yao, X. Gao, W. Qian, Z. Wang, Y. Zhang, P. Yang, H. Shen, Anal. Chem. 2020, 92: 867-874.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. Gu, T. Fukuda, T. Isaji, Q. Hang, H. H. Lee, S. Sakai, J. Morise, J. Mitoma, H. Higashi, N. Taniguchi, H. Yawo, S. Oka, J. Gu, J. Biol. Chem. 2015, 290, 17566-17575.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Schedin-Weiss, S. Gaunitz, P. Sui, Q. Chen, S. M. Haslam, K. Blennow, B. Winblad, A. Dell, L. O. Tjernberg, FEBS J. 2019, 287, 3221-3234.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Gaunitz, L. O. Tjernberg, S. Schedin-Weiss, J. Neurochem. 2021, 159, 292-304.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. T. Gizaw, T. Ohashi, M. Tanaka, H. Hinou, S. Nishimura, Biochim. Biophys. Acta. 2016, 1860, 1716-1727.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>I. McFarlane, N. Georgopoulou, C. M. Coughlan, A. M. Gillian, K. C. Breen, Neuroscience 1999, 90, 15-25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Takahashi, Y. Kuroki, K. Ohtsubo, N. Taniguchi, Carbohydr. Res. 2009, 344, 1387-1390.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. Olsson, R. Lautner, U. Andreasson, A. &#xd6;hrfelt, E. Portelius, M. Bjerke, M. H&#xf6;ltt&#xe4;, C. Ros&#xe9;n, C. Olsson, G. Strobel, E. Wu, K. Dakin, M. Petzold, K. Blennow, H. Zetterberg, Lancet Neurol. 2016, 15, 673-684.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Perneczky, P. Alexopoulos, A. Kurz, Trends Mol. Med. 2014, 20, 8-15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. P. Boix, I. Lopez-Font, I. Cuchillo-Iba&#xf1;ez, J. S&#xe1;ez-Valero, Alzheimer's Res. Ther. 2020, 12, 96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Kizuka, S. Kitazume, R. Fujinawa, T. Saito, N. Iwata, T. C, Saido, EMBO Mol. Med. 2015, 7, 175-189.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Kizuka, M. Nakano, S. Kitazume, T. Saito, T. C. Saido, N. Taniguchi, Biochem. J. 2016, 473, 21-30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O. Vanoni, P. Paganetti, M. Molinari, Mol. Biol. Cell. 2008, 19, 4086-4098.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Tan, G. Evin, J. Neurochem. 2012, 120, 869-880.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. Jorissen, J. Prox, C. Bernreuther, S. Weber, R. Schwanbeck, L. Serneels, A. Snellinx, K. Craessaerts, A. Thathiah, I. Tesseur, U. Bartsch, G. Weskamp, C. P. Blobel, M. Glatzel, B. De Strooper, P. Saftig, J. Neurosci. 2010, 30, 4833-4844.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Escrevente, V. A. Morais, S. Keller, C. M. Soares, P. Altevogt, Costa, Biochim. Biophys. Acta. 2008, 1780, 905-913.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang DS, Tandon A, Chen F, Yu G, Yu H, Arawaka S. Mature glycosylation and trafficking of nicastrin modulate its binding to presenilins. J. Biol. Chem. 2002, 277: 28135-28142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. Regan, P. L. McClean, T. Smyth, M. Doherty, Medicine 2019, 6, 92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Zhu, X. Shan, S. A. Yuzwa, D. J. Vocadlo, J. Biol. Chem. 2014, 289, 34472-34481.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Frenkel-Pinter, M. D. Shmueli, C. Raz, M. Yanku, S. Zilberzwige, E. Gazit, D. Segal, Sci. Adv. 2017, 3, e1601576.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. A. Ngoh, T. Hamid, S. D. Prabhu, S. P. Jones, Am. J. Physiol. Heart Circ. Physiol. 2009, 297, H1711-H1719.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Bose, F. Mouton-Liger, C. Paquet, P. Mazot, M. Vigny, F. Gray, J. Hugon, Brain Pathol. 2011, 21, 189-200.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. N. Skorobogatko, J. Deuso, J. Adolf-Bryfogle, M. G. Nowak, Y. Gong, C. F. Lippa, K. Vosseller, Amino Acids 2011, 40, 765-779.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Deng, B. Li, Y. Liu, K. Iqbal, I. Grundke-Iqbal, C. X. Gong, Am. J. Pathol. 2009, 175, 2089-2098.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. A. Yuzwa, X. Shan, M. S. Macauley, T. Clark, Y. Skorobogatko, K. Vosseller, K. D. J. Vocadlo, Nat. Chem. Biol. 2012, 8, 393-399.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Liu, T. Zaidi, K. Iqbal, I. Grundke-Iqbal, C. X. Gong, Neuroscience 2002, 115, 829-837.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. S. Arnold, G. V. Johnson, R, N, Cole, D. L. Dong, M. Lee, G. W. Hart, J. Biol. Chem. 1996, 271, 28741-28744.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. L. Graham, A. J. Gray, J. A. Joyce, D. Yu, J. O&#x2032;Moore, G. A. Carlson, M. S. Shearman, T. L. Dellovade, H. Hering, Neuropharmacology 2014, 79, 307-313.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N. Nakamura, A. Kurosaka, J. Biochem. 2019, 165, 205-208.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. S. Chun, O. H. Kwon, S. Chung, Biochem. Biophys. Res. Commun. 2017, 490, 486-491.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. S. Chun, Y. Park, H. G. Oh, T. W. Kim, H. O. Yang, M. K. Park, C. Sungkwon, J. Alzheimer&#x2032;s Dis. 2015, 44, 261-275.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. F. Tao, H. C. Huang, ACS Chem. Neurosci. 2019, 10, 2115-2124.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Kim, D. W. Nam, S. Y. Park, H. Song, H. S. Hong, J. H. Boo, E. S. Jung, Y. Kim, J. Y. Baek, K. S. Kim, J. W. Cho, I. Mook-Jung, Neurobiol. Aging. 2013, 34, 275-285.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. S. Pinho, S. C. Correia, G. Perry, A. F. Ambr&#xf3;sio, P. I. Moreira, Biochim. Biophys. Acta Mol. Basis Dis. 2019, 1865, 2048-2059.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. Y. Chen, C. C. Lin, Y. T. Chang, S. C. Lin, S. I. Chan, Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA 2002, 99, 12633-12638.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Akasaka-Manya, M. Kawamura, H. Tsumoto, Y. Saito, Y. Tachida, S. Kitazume, H. Hatsuta, Y. Miura, S. I. Hisanaga, S. Murayama, Y. Hashimoto, H. Manya, T. Endo, J. Biochem. 2017, 161, 99-111.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. A. Rodriguez, E. Piddini, T. Hasegawa, T. Miyagi, C. G. Dotti, J. Neurosci. 2001, 21, 8387-8395.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. P. Monnier, S. G. Beck, J. Bolz, S. Henke-Fahle, Dev. Biol. 2001, 229, 1-14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Salminen, K. Kaarniranta, J. Mol. Med (Berl). 2009, 87, 697-701.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. Rawal, L. Zhao, Front. Neurol. Neurosci. 2021, 15, 648617.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. M. Maguire, K. C. Breen, Dement. Geriatr. Cogn. Disord. 1995, 6, 185-190.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. M. Maguire, A. M. Gillian, D. O'Mahony, C. M. Coughlan, K. C. Breen, Neurobiol. Aging. 1994, 15, 99-102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Taniguchi, Y. Okayama, Y. Hashimoto, M. Kitaura, D. Jimbo, Y. Wakutani, K. Wada-Isoe, K. Nakashima, H. Akatsu, K. Furukawa, H. Arai, K. Urakami, Dement. Geriatr. Cogn. Disord. 2008, 26, 117-122.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. Brinkmalm, E. Portelius, A. &#xd6;hrfelt, N. Mattsson, R. Persson, M. K. Gustavsson, C. H. Vite, J. Gobom, J. E. M&#xe5;nsson, J. Nilsson, A. Halim, G. Larson, U. R&#xfc;etschi, H. Zetterberg, K. Blennow, A. Brinkmalm, J. Mass Spectrom. 2012, 47, 591-603.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Nakagaw, S. Kitazume, R. Oka, K. Maruyama, T. C. Saido, Y. Sato, T. Endo, Y. Hashimoto, J. Neurochem. 2006, 96, 924-933.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Kitazume, K. Nakagawa, R. Oka, Y. Tachida, K. Ogawa, Y. Luo, M. Citron, H. Shitara, C. Taya, H. Yonekawa, J. C. Paulson, E. Miyoshi, N. Taniguchi, Y. Hashimoto, J. Biol. Chem. 2005, 280, 8589-8595.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. A. Q. Videira, M. Castro-Caldas, Front. Neurol. Neurosci. 2018, 12, 381.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Blauwendraat, M. A. Nalls, A. B. Singleton, Lancet Neurol. 2020, 19, 170-178.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Schrag, Z. Anastasiou, G. Ambler, A. Noyce, K. Walters, Mov. Disord. 2019, 34, 480-486.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O. B. Tysnes, A. Storstein, J. Neural Transm. 2017, 124, 901-905.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Lehtonen, T. M. Sonninen, S. Wojciechowski, G. Goldsteins, J. Koistinaho, Front. Neurol. Neurosci. 2019, 13, 457.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Storch, A. C. Ludolph, J. Schwarz, J. Neural Transm. 2004, 111, 1267-1286.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. E. Torres, A. Carneiro, K. Seamans, C. Fiorentini, A. Sweeney, W. D. Yao, M. G. Caron, J. Biol. Chem. 2003, 278, 2731-2739.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. B. Li, N. Chen, S. Ramamoorthy, L. Chi, X. N. Cui, L. C. Wang, E. A. R. Maarten, J. Biol. Chem. 2004, 279, 21012-21020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Rayaprolu, B. Mullen, M. Baker, T. Lynch, E. Finger, W. W. Seeley, K. J. Hatanpaa, C. Lomen-Hoerth, A. Kertesz, E. H. Bigio, C. Lippa, K. A. Josephs, D. S. Knopman, C. L. White, R. Caselli, I. R. Mackenzie, B. L. Miller, M. Boczarska-Jedynak, G. Opala, A. Krygowska-Wajs, M. Barcikowska, S. G. Younkin, R. C. Petersen, N. Ertekin-Taner, R. J. Uitti, J. F. Meschia, K. B. Boylan, B. F. Boeve, N. R. Graff-Radford, Z. K. Wszolek, D. W. Dickson, R. Rademakers, O. A. Ross, Mol. Neurodegener. 2013, 8, 19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. S. Park, I. J. Ji, H. J. An, M. J. Kang, S. W. Kang, D. H. Kim, Y. Seung-Yong, Traffic 2015, 16, 510-518.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N. P. Marotta, Y. H. Lin, Y. E. Lewis, M. R. Ambroso, B. W. Zaro, M. T. Roth, D. B. Arnold, R. Langen, M. R. Pratt, Nat. Chem. 2015, 7, 913-920.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. E. Lewis, A. Galesic, P. M. Levine, C. A. De Leon, N. Lamiri, C. K. Brennan, M. R. Pratt, ACS Chem. Biol. 2017, 12, 1020-1027.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. M. Levine, A. Galesic, A. T. Balana, A. L. Mahul-Mellier, M. X. Navarro, C. A. De Leon, H. A. Lashuel, M. R. Pratt, Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA 2019, 116, 1511-1519.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Farrer, P. Chan, R. Chen, L. Tan, S. Lincoln, D. Hernandez, L. Forno, K. Gwinn-Hardy, L. Petrucelli, J. Hussey, A. Singleton, C. Tanner, J. Hardy, J. W. Langston, Ann. Neurol. 2001, 50, 293-300.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. K. Ta, L. M. Skipper, Hum. Mutat. 2007, 28, 641-653.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Wakabayashi, K. Tanji, F. Mori, H. Takahashi, Neuropathology 2007, 27, 494-506.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Shimura, M. G. Schlossmacher, H. Hattori, M. P. Frosch, A. Trockenbacher, R. Schneider, Y. Mizuno, K. S. Kosik, D. J. Selkoe, Science 2001, 293, 263-269.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N. P. Marotta, Y. H. Lin, Y. E. Lewis, M. R. Ambroso, B. W. Zaro, M. T. Roth, D. B. Arnold, R. Langen, M. R. Pratt, Nat. Chem. 2015, 7, 913-920.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Wilkinson, K. A. Thomsson, A. L. Rebelo, M. Hilliard, A. Pandit, P. M. Rudd, N. G. Karlsson, R. Saldova, J. Proteome Res. 2021, 20, 3913-3924.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. J. Crespo, J. T. Lau, P. A. Videira, Front. Immunol. 2013, 4: 491.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. Wu, Z. H. Lu, N. Kulkarni, R. Amin, R. W. Ledeen, Neurochem. Res. 2011, 36, 1706-1714.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Perissinotto, V. Rondelli, P. Parisse, N. Tormena, A. Zunino, L. Alm&#xe1;sy, D. G. Merkel, L. Botty&#xe1;n, S. Sajti, L. Casalis, Biophys. Chem. 2019, 255, 106272.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. Wu, Z. H. Lu, J, H, Seo, S. K. Alselehdar, S. DeFrees, R. W. Ledeen, Exp. Neurol. 2020, 329, 113284.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. Chiricozzi, L. Mauri, G. Lunghi, E. Di Biase, M. Fazzari, M. Maggioni, Sci. Rep. 2019, 9, 19330.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. H. Ba, Int. J. Neurosci. 2016, 126, 163-167.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. S. Schneider, PLoS ONE 2018, 13, e0199189.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. Wu, Z. H. Lu, N. Kulkarni, R. W. Ledeen, J. Neurosci. Res. 2012, 90, 1997-2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. J. Wild, S. J. Tabrizi, Lancet. Neurol. 2017, 16, 837-847.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Zheng, Diamond. Prog. Mol. Biol. Transl. Sci. 2012, 107, 189-214.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. W. Ho, R. Brown, M. Maxwell, A. Wyttenbach, D. C. Rubinsztein, J. Med. Genet. 2001, 38, 450-452.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Jimenez-Sanchez, F. Licitra, B. R. Underwood, D. C. Rubinsztein, Cold. Spring. Harb. Perspect. Med. 2017, 7, a024240.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. C. Jr. Nucifora, M. Sasaki, M. F. Peters, H. Huang, J. K. Cooper, M. Yamada, H. Takahashi, S. Tsuji, J. Troncoso, V. L. Dawson, T. M. Dawson, C. A. Ross, Science 2001, 291, 2423-2428.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. T. Gizaw, T. Koda, M. Amano, K. Kamimura, T. Ohashi, H. Hinou, S. A. Nishimura, Biochim. Biophys. Acta. 2015, 1850, 1704-1718.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. A. Desplats, C. A. Denny, K. E. Kass, T. Gilmartin, S. R. Head, J. G. Sutcliffe, T. N. Seyfried, E. A. Thomas, Neurobiol. Dis. 2007, 27, 265-277.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Kumar, P. K. Singh, R. Parihar, V. Dwivedi, S. C. Lakhotia, S. Ganesh, J. Biol. Chem. 2014, 289, 13543-13553.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. H. Brown, A. Al-Chalabi, N. Engl. J. Med. 2017, 377, 162-172.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>V. M. Van Deerlin, J. B. Leverenz, L. M. Bekris, T. D. Bird, W. Yuan, L. B. Elman, D. Clay, E. M. Wood, A. S. Chen-Plotkin, M. Martinez-Lage, E. Steinbart, L. McCluskey, M. Grossman, M. Neumann, I. L. Wu, W. S. Yang, R. Kalb, D. R. Galasko, T. J. Montine, J. Q. Trojanowski, V. M. Lee, G. D. Schellenberg, C. E. Yu, Lancet. Neurol. 2008, 7, 409-416.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Vance, B. Rogelj, T. Hortob&#xe1;gyi, K. J. De Vos, A. L. Nishimura, J. Sreedharan, X. Hu, B. Smith, D. Ruddy, P. Wright, J. Ganesalingam, K. L. Williams, V. Tripathi, S. Al-Saraj, A. Al-Chalabi, P. N. Leigh, I. P. Blair, G. Nicholson, J. de Belleroche, J. M. Gallo, C. C. Miller, C. E. Shaw, Science 2009, 323, 1208-1211.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. I. Bruijn, M. K. Ouseweart, S. Kato, K. L. Anderson, S. D. Anderson, E. Ohama, A. G. Reaume, R, W. Scott, D. W. Cleveland, Science 1998, 281, 1851-1854.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Cooper-Knock, T. Moll, Ramesh, L. Castelli, A. Beer, H. Robins, I. Fox, I. Niedermoser, P. Van Damme, M. Moisse, W. Robberecht, O. Hardiman, M. P. Panades, A. Assialioui, J. S. Mora, A. N. Basak, K. E. Morrison, C. E. Shaw, A. Al-Chalabi, J. E. Landers, M. Wyles, P. R. Heath, A. Higginbottom, T. Walsh, M. Kazoka, C. J. McDermott, G. M. Hautbergue, J. Kirby, P. J. Shaw, Cell. Rep. 2019, 26, 2298-2306.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. R. Heath, P. J. Shaw, Muscle. Nerve. 2002, 26, 438-458.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. C. Kiernan, S. Vucic, B. C. Cheah, M. R. Turner, A. Eisen, O. Hardiman, J. R. Burrell, M. C. Zoing, Lancet 2011, 377, 942-955.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Edri-Brami, B. Rosental, D. Hayoun, M. Welt, H. Rosen, I. Wirguin, B. Nefussy, V. E. Drory, A. Porgador, R. G. Lichtenstein, PLoS One 2012, 7, e35772.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Costa, L. Streich, S. Pinto, A. Pronto-Laborinho, M. Nimtz, H. S. Conradt, M. de Carvalho, Mol. Neurobiol. 2019, 56, 5729-5739.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Gon&#xe7;alves, L. Tillack, M. de Carvalho, S. Pinto, H. S. Conradt, J. Costa, Amyotrophic Lateral Scler. Frontotemporal Degener. 2017, 18, 134-136.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N. L&#xfc;demann, A. Clement, V. H. Hans, J. Leschik, C. Behl, R. Brandt, J. Biol. Chem. 2005, 280, 31648-31658.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>