<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37452624</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1440-169X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>65</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Development, growth &amp; differentiation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Dev Growth Differ</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Dysregulated TDP-43 proteostasis perturbs excitability of spinal motor neurons during brainstem-mediated fictive locomotion in zebrafish.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>446</StartPage><EndPage>452</EndPage><MedlinePgn>446-452</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/dgd.12879</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Spinal motor neurons (SMNs) are the primary target of degeneration in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). Degenerating motor neurons accumulate cytoplasmic TAR DNA-binding protein 43 (TDP-43) aggregates in most ALS cases. This SMN pathology can occur without mutation in the coding sequence of the TDP-43-encoding gene, TARDBP. Whether and how wild-type TDP-43 drives pathological changes in SMNs in vivo remains largely unexplored. In this study, we develop a two-photon calcium imaging setup in which tactile-evoked neural responses of motor neurons in the brainstem and spinal cord can be monitored using the calcium indicator GCaMP. We devise a piezo-assisted tactile stimulator that reproducibly evokes a brainstem descending neuron upon tactile stimulation of the head. A direct comparison between caudal primary motor neurons (CaPs) with or without TDP-43 overexpression in contiguous spinal segments demonstrates that CaPs overexpressing TDP-43 display attenuated Ca<sup>2+</sup> transients during fictive escape locomotion evoked by the tactile stimulation. These results show that excessive amounts of TDP-43 protein reduce the neuronal excitability of SMNs and potentially contribute to asymptomatic pathological lesions of SMNs and movement disorders in patients with ALS.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Authors. Development, Growth &amp; Differentiation published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Australia, Ltd on behalf of Japanese Society of Developmental Biologists.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Asakawa</LastName><ForeName>Kazuhide</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0628-1176</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Molecular and Developmental Biology, National Institute of Genetics, Mishima, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Handa</LastName><ForeName>Hiroshi</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Molecular Pharmacology, Center for Future Medical Research, Institute of Medical Science, Tokyo Medical University, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kawakami</LastName><ForeName>Koichi</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Molecular and Developmental Biology, National Institute of Genetics, Mishima, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Graduate University for Advanced Studies (SOKENDAI), Mishima, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>Daiichi-Sankyo Foundation of Life Science</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>JP23gm6410011h0003</GrantID><Agency>Japan Agency for Medical Research and Development</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>JP16K07045</GrantID><Agency>Japan Society for the Promotion of Science</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>JP19K06933</GrantID><Agency>Japan Society for the Promotion of Science</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>JP21H02463</GrantID><Agency>Japan Society for the Promotion of Science</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>JP22H02958</GrantID><Agency>Japan Society for the Promotion of Science</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>JP23H04266</GrantID><Agency>Japan Society for the Promotion of Science</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><Agency>Nakabayashi Trust For ALS Research</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><Agency>National BioResource Project (NBRP)</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><Agency>Takeda Science Foundation</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><Agency>The Kato Memorial Trust For Nambyo Research</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Japan</Country><MedlineTA>Dev Growth Differ</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0356504</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0012-1592</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>SY7Q814VUP</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D002118">Calcium</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D004268">DNA-Binding Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015027" MajorTopicYN="N">Zebrafish</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002118" MajorTopicYN="N">Calcium</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000074702" MajorTopicYN="N">Proteostasis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009046" MajorTopicYN="N">Motor Neurons</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013116" MajorTopicYN="N">Spinal Cord</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004268" MajorTopicYN="N">DNA-Binding Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ALS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">TDP-43</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">calcium imaging</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">locomotion</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">spinal motor neuron</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37452624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/dgd.12879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Acharya, K. K., Govind, C. K., Shore, A. N., Stoler, M. H., &amp; Reddi, P. P. (2006). Cis-requirement for the maintenance of round spermatid-specific transcription. Developmental Biology, 295(2), 781-790. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ydbio.2006.04.443</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arai, T., Hasegawa, M., Akiyama, H., Ikeda, K., Nonaka, T., Mori, H., &amp; Oda, T. (2006). TDP-43 is a component of ubiquitin-positive tau-negative inclusions in frontotemporal lobar degeneration and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Biochemical and Biophysical Research Communications, 351(3), 602-611. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bbrc.2006.10.093</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Araki, K., Araki, A., Honda, D., Izumoto, T., Hashizume, A., Hijikata, Y., &amp; Katsuno, M. (2019). TDP-43 regulates early-phase insulin secretion via CaV1.2-mediated exocytosis in islets. The Journal of Clinical Investigation, 129(9), 3578-3593. https://doi.org/10.1172/JCI124481</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armstrong, G. A., &amp; Drapeau, P. (2013). Calcium channel agonists protect against neuromuscular dysfunction in a genetic model of TDP-43 mutation in ALS. The Journal of Neuroscience, 33(4), 1741-1752. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.4003-12.2013</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnold, E. S., Ling, S. C., Huelga, S. C., Lagier-Tourenne, C., Polymenidou, M., Ditsworth, D., &amp; Cleveland, D. W. (2013). ALS-linked TDP-43 mutations produce aberrant RNA splicing and adult-onset motor neuron disease without aggregation or loss of nuclear TDP-43. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 110(8), E736-E745. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1222809110</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asakawa, K., Abe, G., &amp; Kawakami, K. (2013). Cellular dissection of the spinal cord motor column by BAC transgenesis and gene trapping in zebrafish. Front Neural Circuits, 7, 100. https://doi.org/10.3389/fncir.2013.00100</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asakawa, K., Handa, H., &amp; Kawakami, K. (2020). Optogenetic modulation of TDP-43 oligomerization accelerates ALS-related pathologies in the spinal motor neurons. Nature Communications, 11(1), 1004. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-020-14815-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asakawa, K., &amp; Kawakami, K. (2018). Protocadherin-mediated cell repulsion controls the central topography and efferent projections of the Abducens nucleus. Cell Reports, 24(6), 1562-1572. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.celrep.2018.07.024</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asakawa, K., Suster, M. L., Mizusawa, K., Nagayoshi, S., Kotani, T., Urasaki, A., &amp; Kawakami, K. (2008). Genetic dissection of neural circuits by Tol2 transposon-mediated Gal4 gene and enhancer trapping in zebrafish. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 105(4), 1255-1260. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.0704963105</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barmada, S. J., Skibinski, G., Korb, E., Rao, E. J., Wu, J. Y., &amp; Finkbeiner, S. (2010). Cytoplasmic mislocalization of TDP-43 is toxic to neurons and enhanced by a mutation associated with familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. The Journal of Neuroscience, 30(2), 639-649. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.4988-09.2010</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown, A. L., Wilkins, O. G., Keuss, M. J., Hill, S. E., Zanovello, M., Lee, W. C., &amp; Fratta, P. (2022). TDP-43 loss and ALS-risk SNPs drive mis-splicing and depletion of UNC13A. Nature, 603(7899), 131-137. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41586-022-04436-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buratti, E., Dork, T., Zuccato, E., Pagani, F., Romano, M., &amp; Baralle, F. E. (2001). Nuclear factor TDP-43 and SR proteins promote in vitro and in vivo CFTR exon 9 skipping. The EMBO Journal, 20(7), 1774-1784. https://doi.org/10.1093/emboj/20.7.1774</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang, J. C., Hazelett, D. J., Stewart, J. A., &amp; Morton, D. B. (2014). Motor neuron expression of the voltage-gated calcium channel cacophony restores locomotion defects in a drosophila, TDP-43 loss of function model of ALS. Brain Research, 1584, 39-51. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.brainres.2013.11.019</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dyer, M. S., Reale, L. A., Lewis, K. E., Walker, A. K., Dickson, T. C., Woodhouse, A., &amp; Blizzard, C. A. (2021). Mislocalisation of TDP-43 to the cytoplasm causes cortical hyperexcitability and reduced excitatory neurotransmission in the motor cortex. Journal of Neurochemistry, 157(4), 1300-1315. https://doi.org/10.1111/jnc.15214</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Estes, P. S., Boehringer, A., Zwick, R., Tang, J. E., Grigsby, B., &amp; Zarnescu, D. C. (2011). Wild-type and A315T mutant TDP-43 exert differential neurotoxicity in a drosophila model of ALS. Human Molecular Genetics, 20(12), 2308-2321. https://doi.org/10.1093/hmg/ddr124</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson, B. S., McCaffery, J. M., Lindquist, S., &amp; Gitler, A. D. (2008). A yeast TDP-43 proteinopathy model: Exploring the molecular determinants of TDP-43 aggregation and cellular toxicity. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 105(17), 6439-6444. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.0802082105</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jontes, J. D., Buchanan, J., &amp; Smith, S. J. (2000). Growth cone and dendrite dynamics in zebrafish embryos: Early events in synaptogenesis imaged in vivo. Nature Neuroscience, 3(3), 231-237. https://doi.org/10.1038/72936</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kabashi, E., Lin, L., Tradewell, M. L., Dion, P. A., Bercier, V., Bourgouin, P., &amp; Drapeau, P. (2010). Gain and loss of function of ALS-related mutations of TARDBP (TDP-43) cause motor deficits in vivo. Human Molecular Genetics, 19(4), 671-683. https://doi.org/10.1093/hmg/ddp534</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kimmel, C. B., Hatta, K., &amp; Metcalfe, W. K. (1990). Early axonal contacts during development of an identified dendrite in the brain of the zebrafish. Neuron, 4(4), 535-545. https://doi.org/10.1016/0896-6273(90)90111-r</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koike, Y., Pickles, S., Estades Ayuso, V., Jansen-West, K., Qi, Y. A., Li, Z., &amp; Prudencio, M. (2023). TDP-43 and other hnRNPs regulate cryptic exon inclusion of a key ALS/FTD risk gene, UNC13A. PLoS Biology, 21(3), e3002028. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pbio.3002028</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, T. D., Murano, K., Kitano, T., Guo, Y., Negishi, L., &amp; Siomi, H. (2022). TDP-43 safeguards the embryo genome from L1 retrotransposition. Science Advances, 8(47), eabq3806. https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.abq3806</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ling, J. P., Pletnikova, O., Troncoso, J. C., &amp; Wong, P. C. (2015). TDP-43 repression of nonconserved cryptic exons is compromised in ALS-FTD. Science, 349(6248), 650-655. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.aab0983</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma, X. R., Prudencio, M., Koike, Y., Vatsavayai, S. C., Kim, G., Harbinski, F., &amp; Gitler, A. D. (2022). TDP-43 represses cryptic exon inclusion in the FTD-ALS gene UNC13A. Nature, 603(7899), 124-130. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41586-022-04424-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackenzie, I. R., Bigio, E. H., Ince, P. G., Geser, F., Neumann, M., Cairns, N. J., &amp; Trojanowski, J. Q. (2007). Pathological TDP-43 distinguishes sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis from amyotrophic lateral sclerosis with SOD1 mutations. Annals of Neurology, 61(5), 427-434. https://doi.org/10.1002/ana.21147</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehta, P. R., Brown, A. L., Ward, M. E., &amp; Fratta, P. (2023). The era of cryptic exons: Implications for ALS-FTD. Molecular Neurodegeneration, 18(1), 16. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13024-023-00608-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muto, A., Ohkura, M., Abe, G., Nakai, J., &amp; Kawakami, K. (2013). Real-time visualization of neuronal activity during perception. Current Biology, 23(4), 307-311. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cub.2012.12.040</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myers, P. Z., Eisen, J. S., &amp; Westerfield, M. (1986). Development and axonal outgrowth of identified motoneurons in the zebrafish. The Journal of Neuroscience, 6(8), 2278-2289. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.06-08-02278.1986</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neumann, M., Sampathu, D. M., Kwong, L. K., Truax, A. C., Micsenyi, M. C., Chou, T. T., &amp; Lee, V. M. (2006). Ubiquitinated TDP-43 in frontotemporal lobar degeneration and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Science, 314(5796), 130-133. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.1134108</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ou, S. H., Wu, F., Harrich, D., Garcia-Martinez, L. F., &amp; Gaynor, R. B. (1995). Cloning and characterization of a novel cellular protein, TDP-43, that binds to human immunodeficiency virus type 1 TAR DNA sequence motifs. Journal of Virology, 69(6), 3584-3596. https://doi.org/10.1128/JVI.69.6.3584-3596.1995</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petel Legare, V., Harji, Z. A., Rampal, C. J., Allard-Chamard, X., Rodriguez, E. C., &amp; Armstrong, G. A. B. (2019). Augmentation of spinal cord glutamatergic synaptic currents in zebrafish primary motoneurons expressing mutant human TARDBP (TDP-43). Scientific Reports, 9(1), 9122. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-019-45530-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polymenidou, M., Lagier-Tourenne, C., Hutt, K. R., Huelga, S. C., Moran, J., Liang, T. Y., &amp; Cleveland, D. W. (2011). Long pre-mRNA depletion and RNA missplicing contribute to neuronal vulnerability from loss of TDP-43. Nature Neuroscience, 14(4), 459-468. https://doi.org/10.1038/nn.2779</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pujol-Marti, J., Zecca, A., Baudoin, J. P., Faucherre, A., Asakawa, K., Kawakami, K., &amp; Lopez-Schier, H. (2012). Neuronal birth order identifies a dimorphic sensorineural map. The Journal of Neuroscience, 32(9), 2976-2987. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.5157-11.2012</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sagasti, A., Guido, M. R., Raible, D. W., &amp; Schier, A. F. (2005). Repulsive interactions shape the morphologies and functional arrangement of zebrafish peripheral sensory arbors. Current Biology, 15(9), 804-814. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cub.2005.03.048</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saint-Amant, L., &amp; Drapeau, P. (1998). Time course of the development of motor behaviors in the zebrafish embryo. Journal of Neurobiology, 37(4), 622-632. https://doi.org/10.1002/(sici)1097-4695(199812)37:4&lt;622::aid-neu10&gt;3.0.co;2-s</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott, E. K., Mason, L., Arrenberg, A. B., Ziv, L., Gosse, N. J., Xiao, T., &amp; Baier, H. (2007). Targeting neural circuitry in zebrafish using GAL4 enhancer trapping. Nature Methods, 4(4), 323-326. https://doi.org/10.1038/nmeth1033</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sephton, C. F., Cenik, C., Kucukural, A., Dammer, E. B., Cenik, B., Han, Y., &amp; Yu, G. (2011). Identification of neuronal RNA targets of TDP-43-containing ribonucleoprotein complexes. The Journal of Biological Chemistry, 286(2), 1204-1215. https://doi.org/10.1074/jbc.M110.190884</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stoica, R., De Vos, K. J., Paillusson, S., Mueller, S., Sancho, R. M., Lau, K. F., &amp; Miller, C. C. (2014). ER-mitochondria associations are regulated by the VAPB-PTPIP51 interaction and are disrupted by ALS/FTD-associated TDP-43. Nature Communications, 5, 3996. https://doi.org/10.1038/ncomms4996</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suster, M. L., Abe, G., Schouw, A., &amp; Kawakami, K. (2011). Transposon-mediated BAC transgenesis in zebrafish. Nature Protocols, 6(12), 1998-2021. https://doi.org/10.1038/nprot.2011.416</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor, J. P., Brown, R. H., Jr., &amp; Cleveland, D. W. (2016). Decoding ALS: From genes to mechanism. Nature, 539(7628), 197-206. https://doi.org/10.1038/nature20413</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tollervey, J. R., Curk, T., Rogelj, B., Briese, M., Cereda, M., Kayikci, M., &amp; Ule, J. (2011). Characterizing the RNA targets and position-dependent splicing regulation by TDP-43. Nature Neuroscience, 14(4), 452-458. https://doi.org/10.1038/nn.2778</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warming, S., Costantino, N., Court, D. L., Jenkins, N. A., &amp; Copeland, N. G. (2005). Simple and highly efficient BAC recombineering using galK selection. Nucleic Acids Research, 33(4), e36. https://doi.org/10.1093/nar/gni035</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wils, H., Kleinberger, G., Janssens, J., Pereson, S., Joris, G., Cuijt, I., &amp; Kumar-Singh, S. (2010). TDP-43 transgenic mice develop spastic paralysis and neuronal inclusions characteristic of ALS and frontotemporal lobar degeneration. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 107(8), 3858-3863. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.0912417107</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao, S., Sanelli, T., Dib, S., Sheps, D., Findlater, J., Bilbao, J., &amp; Robertson, J. (2011). RNA targets of TDP-43 identified by UV-CLIP are deregulated in ALS. Molecular and Cellular Neurosciences, 47(3), 167-180. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcn.2011.02.013</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, Y. F., Gendron, T. F., Zhang, Y. J., Lin, W. L., D'Alton, S., Sheng, H., &amp; Petrucelli, L. (2010). Wild-type human TDP-43 expression causes TDP-43 phosphorylation, mitochondrial aggregation, motor deficits, and early mortality in transgenic mice. The Journal of Neuroscience, 30(32), 10851-10859. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.1630-10.2010</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>