<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37462337</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>22</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-4598</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>68</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Muscle &amp; nerve</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Muscle Nerve</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>What do people affected by amyotrophic lateral sclerosis want from health communications? Evidence from the ALS Talk Project.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>286</StartPage><EndPage>295</EndPage><MedlinePgn>286-295</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/mus.27935</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION/AIMS">Health communication is central to effective, supportive amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) clinical care. Guidance for ALS communication is limited, focuses on diagnosis disclosure, and frequently relies on expert consensus and/or reviews. Patient-based evidence is needed to guide ALS health communication. We investigated how the experiences of ALS patients and family caregivers can inform effective communication practices from diagnosis to end-of-life.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Data were drawn from the ALS Talk Project, an asynchronous, online focus group study. Seven focus groups and five interviews (105 participants) were conducted. Data were qualitatively analyzed using directed content analysis and the constant-comparative approach.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">We found four primary themes: communication content, communication circumstances, information sufficiency, and communication manner. Data indicate participants relied on clinicians for medical information but also wanted practical information; health communication should attend to the circumstances within which conversations occur; information must be sufficient for individual needs, without overwhelming; and an empathetic, direct, and honest manner facilitated trust. Participants identified communication challenges and strategies to improve communication across major themes, including stepwise approaches and conversations tailored to individuals and their heterogeneous disease experiences.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION">Healthcare professionals should discuss patient/caregiver communication preferences early in the therapeutic relationship, co-develop a communication agreement, and update the agreement in response to changing needs and disease progression. This will foster regular discussion of information needs and promote timely discussions of challenging topics, including advance care, while giving patients and families a sense of control. Findings may have implications for other neuromuscular disease and/or seriously ill populations.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Authors. Muscle &amp; Nerve published by Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Genuis</LastName><ForeName>Shelagh K</ForeName><Initials>SK</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4733-4011</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Neurology, Faculty of Medicine and Dentistry, University of Alberta, Edmonton, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Luth</LastName><ForeName>Westerly</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Neurology, Faculty of Medicine and Dentistry, University of Alberta, Edmonton, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bubela</LastName><ForeName>Tania</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health Sciences, Simon Fraser University, Burnaby, British Columbia, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Johnston</LastName><ForeName>Wendy S</ForeName><Initials>WS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Neurology, Faculty of Medicine and Dentistry, University of Alberta, Edmonton, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Muscle Nerve</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7803146</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0148-639X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058015" MajorTopicYN="Y">Health Communication</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017028" MajorTopicYN="N">Caregivers</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006282" MajorTopicYN="N">Health Personnel</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">family caregivers</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">health communication</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">patients</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physician-patient relations</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>8</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37462337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.27935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Medical Subject Headings-Health Communication. National library of Medicine Web site. https://meshb.nlm.nih.gov/record/ui?name=Health%20Communication. Accessed June 14, 2023</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frankel R, Sherman H. The secret of the care of the patient is in knowing and applying the evidence about effective clinical communication. Oral Dis. 2015;21:919-926.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilligan T, Coyle N, Frankel RM, et al. Patient-clinician communication: American Society of Clinical Oncology consensus guideline. Obstet Gynecol Surv. 2018;73:96-97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grassi L, Caruso R, Costantini A. Communication with patients suffering from serious physical illness. Clin Chall Biopsychosoc Interface. 2015;34:10-23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Connolly S, Galvin M, Hardiman O. End-of-life management in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet Neurol. 2015;14:435-442.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maksymowicz S, Libura M, Malarkiewicz P. Overcoming therapeutic nihilism. Breaking bad news of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-a patient-centred perspective in rare diseases. Neurol Sci. 2022;43:4257-4265.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masrori P, Van Damme P. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a clinical review. Eur J Neurol. 2020;27:1918-1929.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norris SP, Likanje M-FN, Andrews JA. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: update on clinical management. Curr Opin Neurol. 2020;33:641-648.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shoesmith C, Abrahao A, Benstead T, et al. Canadian best practice recommendations for the management of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. CMAJ Can Med Assoc J. 2020;192:E1453-E1468.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aoun SM, Breen LJ, Howting D, et al. Receiving the news of a diagnosis of motor neuron disease: what does it take to make it better? Amyotroph Lateral Scler Front Degener. 2016;17:168-178.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gillespie J, Przybylak-Brouillard A, Watt CL. The palliative care information needs of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and their informal caregivers: a scoping review. J Pain Symptom Manage. 2021;62:848-862.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozanne A, Graneheim UH. Understanding the incomprehensible-patients' and spouses' experiences of comprehensibility before, at and after diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Scand J Caring Sci. 2018;32:663-671.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen PM, Abrahams S, Borasio GD, et al. EFNS guidelines on the clinical Management of Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis (MALS)-revised report of an EFNS task force. Eur J Neurol. 2012;19:360-375.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2; A, Borasio GD. Breaking the news in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord. 2004;5:195-201.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seeber AA, Pols AJ, Hijdra A, Grupstra HF, Willems DL, de Visser M. Experiences and reflections of patients with motor neuron disease on breaking the news in a two-tiered appointment: a qualitative study. BMJ Support Palliat Care. 2019;9:e8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller RG, Brooks BR, Swain-Eng RJ, et al. Quality improvement in neurology: amyotrophic lateral sclerosis quality measures. Neurology. 2013;81:2136-2140.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Eenennaam RM, Kruithof WJ, van Es MA, et al. Discussing personalized prognosis in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: development of a communication guide. BMC Neurol. 2020;20:446.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeo CJJ, Simmons Z. Discussing edaravone with the ALS patient: an ethical framework from a U.S. perspective. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2018;19:167-172.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCluskey L, Casarett D, Siderowf A. Breaking the news: a survey of ALS patients and their caregivers. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord. 2004;5:131-135.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Brien MR, Whitehead B, Jack BA, Mitchell JD. From symptom onset to a diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis/motor neuron disease (ALS/MND): experiences of people with ALS/MND and family carers-a qualitative study. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2011;12:97-104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caron J, Light J. &#x2018;My world has expanded even though I'm stuck at home&#x2019;: experiences of individuals with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis who use augmentative and alternative communication and social media. Am J Speech Lang Pathol. 2015;24:680-695.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook K, Jack S, Siden H, Thabane L, Browne G. Innovations in research with medically fragile populations: using bulletin board focus groups. Qual Rep. 2014;19:1-12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies L, LeClair KL, Bagley P, et al. Face-to-face compared with online collected accounts of health and illness experiences: a scoping review. Qual Health Res. 2020;30:2092-2102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon AR, Calzo JP, Eiduson R, et al. Asynchronous online focus groups for Health Research: case study and lessons learned. Int J Qual Methods. 2021;20. doi:10.1177/1609406921990489.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morgan DL. Basic and Advanced Focus Groups. Sage Publications; 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reisner SL, Randazzo RK, White Hughto JM, et al. Sensitive health topics with underserved patient populations: methodological considerations for online focus group discussions. Qual Health Res. 2018;28:1658-1673.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmad M, Genuis SK, Luth W, Bubela T, Johnston WS. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) health charities are central to ALS care: perspectives of Canadians affected by ALS. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2023;24:246-255.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Genuis SK, Luth W, Bubela T, Johnston WS. Covid-19 threat and coping: application of protection motivation theory to the pandemic experiences of people affected by amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. BMC Neurol. 2022;22:140.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hodgkinson V, Lounsberry J, M'Dahoma S, et al. The Canadian neuromuscular disease registry 2010-2019: a decade of facilitating clinical research Througha Nationwide, pan-NeuromuscularDisease registry. J Neuromuscul Dis. 2021;8:53-61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, Miller RG, Swash M, Munsat TL. El Escorial revisited: revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord. 2000;1:293-299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>itracks. itracks web site. https://www.itracks.com/. Accessed June 14, 2023</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moir M. Communication, Information Gathering and Use among ALS Stakeholders: Diagnosis and Care. University of Alberta, Education &amp; Research Archive; 2019. doi:10.7939/r3-zadf-yh04</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsieh H-F, Shannon SE. Three approaches to qualitative content analysis. Qual Health Res. 2005;15:1277-1288.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glaser BG, Strauss AL. The Discovery of Grounded Theory: Strategies for Qualitative Research. Aldine de Gruyter; 1967.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lombard M, Snyder-Duch J, Bracken CC. Content analysis in mass communication: assessment and reporting of intercoder reliability. Hum Commun Res. 2002;28:587-604.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdulla S, Vielhaber S, Kollewe K, et al. The impact of physical impairment on emotional well-being in ALS. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2014;15:392-397.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hobson EV, Fazal S, Shaw PJ, McDermott CJ. &#x201c;Anything that makes life's journey better.&#x201d; exploring the use of digital technology by people living with motor neurone disease. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2017;18:378-387.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moccia M, Brigo F, Tedeschi G, Bonavita S, Lavorgna L. Neurology and the internet: a review. Neurol Sci. 2018;39:981-987.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh J, Kim JA. Information-seeking behavior and information needs in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: analyzing an online patient community. CIN Comput Inform Nurs. 2017;35:345-351.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chu HS, Oh J. Information needs and preferences of family caregivers of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurosci Nurs. 2020;52:207-213.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Wit J, Schr&#xf6;der CD, Mecky J, Beelen A, van den Berg LH, Visser-Meily JMA. Support needs of caregivers of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a qualitative study. Palliat Support Care. 2019;17:195-201.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh J, Kim JA. Supportive care needs of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis/motor neuron disease and their caregivers: a scoping review. J Clin Nurs. 2017;26:4129-4152.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Groenestijn AC, Kruitwagen-van Reenen ET, Visser-Meily JMA, et al. Associations between psychological factors and health-related quality of life and global quality of life in patients with ALS: a systematic review. Health Qual Life Outcomes. 2016;14:197. doi:10.1186/s12955-016-0507-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cappellato V, Bosco N, Chi&#xf2; A, Calvo A. Curable or treatable? The implications of different definitions of illness when treating patients suffering from amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Front Degener. 2016;17:15-20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cordesse V, Sidorok F, Schimmel P, Holstein J, Meininger V. Coordinated care affects hospitalization and prognosis in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a cohort study. BMC Health Serv Res. 2015;15:134.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paynter C, Mathers S, Gregory H, Vogel AP, Cruice M. Using the concept of health literacy to understand how people living with motor Neurone disease and Carers engage in healthcare: a longitudinal qualitative study. Healthcare. 2022;10:1371.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brizzi K, Paganoni S, Zehm A, de Marchi F, Berry JD. Integration of a palliative care specialist in an amyotrophic lateral sclerosis clinic: observations from one center. Muscle Nerve. 2019;60:137-140.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Creutzfeldt CJ, Robinson MT, Holloway RG. Neurologists as primary palliative care providers: communication and practice approaches. Neurol Clin Pract. 2016;6:40-48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliver DJ, Borasio GD, Caraceni A, et al. A consensus review on the development of palliative care for patients with chronic and progressive neurological disease. Eur J Neurol. 2016;23:30-38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Eenennaam RM, Koppenol LS, Kruithof WJ, et al. Discussing personalized prognosis empowers patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis to regain control over their future: a qualitative study. Brain Sci. 2021;11:1597.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foley G, Timonen V, Hardiman O. Understanding psycho-social processes underpinning engagement with services in motor neurone disease: a qualitative study. Palliat Med. 2014;28:318-325.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pizzimenti A, Gori MC, Onesti E, John B, Inghilleri M. Communication of diagnosis in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: stratification of patients for the estimation of the individual needs. Front Psychol. 2015;6:745. doi:10.3389/fpsyg.2015.00745</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lerum SV, Solbraekke KN, Holm&#xf8;y T, Frich JC. Unstable terminality: negotiating the meaning of chronicity and terminality in motor neurone disease. Sociol Health Illn. 2015;37:81-96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hogden A, Greenfield D, Nugus P, et al. What influences patient decision-making in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis multidisciplinary care? A study of patient perspectives. Patient Prefer Adherence. 2012;6:829-838.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lemoignan J, Ells C. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and assisted ventilation: how patients decide. Palliat Support Care. 2010;8:207-213.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin NH, Lawrence V, Murray J, et al. Decision making about gastrostomy and noninvasive ventilation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Qual Health Res. 2016;26:1366-1381.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munroe CA, Sirdofsky MD, Kuru T, et al. End-of-life decision making in 42 patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Respir Care. 2007;52:996-999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardiman O, Al-Chalabi A, Chio A, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat Rev Dis Primer. 2017;3:17071.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aoun SM, O'Brien MR, Breen LJ, O'Connor M. &#x2018;The shock of diagnosis&#x2019;: qualitative accounts from people with motor Neurone disease reflecting the need for more person-centred care. J Neurol Sci. 2018;387:80-84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cipolletta S, Reggiani M. End-of-life care after the legal introduction of advance directives: a qualitative study involving healthcare professionals and family caregivers of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Palliat Med. 2021;35:209-218.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edwards WF, Malik S, Peters J, Chippendale I, Ravits J. Delivering bad news in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: proposal of specific technique ALS ALLOW. Neurol Clin Pract. 2021;11:521-526.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosengren K, Gustafsson I, Jarnevi E. Every second counts: Women's experience of living with ALS in the end-of-life situations. Home Health Care Manag Pract. 2015;27:76-82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salmon P, Young B. A new paradigm for clinical communication: critical review of literature in cancer care. Med Educ. 2017;51:258-268.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salmon P, Young B. Dependence and caring in clinical communication: the relevance of attachment and other theories. Patient Educ Couns. 2009;74:331-338.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sloan R, Borasio GD. Communication: breaking the news. In: Oliver D, Borasio GD, Johnston W, eds. Palliative Care in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis: from Diagnosis to Bereavement. Oxford University Press; 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Albury C, Hall A, Syed A, et al. Communication practices for delivering health behaviour change conversations in primary care: a systematic review and thematic synthesis. BMC Fam Pract. 2019;20:111.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Land V, Parry R, Pino M, et al. Addressing possible problems with patients' expectations, plans and decisions for the future: one strategy used by experienced clinicians in advance care planning conversations. Patient Educ Couns. 2019;102:670-679.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parry R, Land V, Seymour J. How to communicate with patients about future illness progression and end of life: a systematic review. BMJ Support Palliat Care. 2014;4:331-341.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krawczyk M, Gallagher R. Communicating prognostic uncertainty in potential end-of-life contexts: experiences of family members. BMC Palliat Care. 2016;15:59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Archer W, Latif A, Faull C. Communicating with palliative care patients nearing the end of life, their families and carers. Pharm J. 2017;298. doi:10.1211/PJ.2017.20202154</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hogden A, Greenfield D, Nugus P, Kiernan MC. Engaging in patient decision-making in multidisciplinary care for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: the views of health professionals. Patient Prefer Adherence. 2012;6:691-701.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersson V, Otterstrom-Rydberg E, Karlsson A-K. The importance of written and verbal information on pain treatment for patients undergoing surgical interventions. Pain Manag Nurs. 2015;16:634-641.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson A, Sandford J. Written and verbal information versus verbal information only for patients being discharged from acute hospital settings to home: systematic review. Health Educ Res. 2005;20:423-429.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kynoch K, Ramis M-A, Crowe L, Cabilan CJ, McArdle A. Information needs and information seeking behaviors of patients and families in acute healthcare settings: a scoping review. JBI Evid Synth. 2019;17:1130-1153.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montebugnoli F, Incerti Parenti S, D'Ant&#xf2; V, et al. Effect of verbal and written information on pain perception in patients undergoing fixed orthodontic treatment: a randomized controlled trial. Eur J Orthod. 2020;42:494-499.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peters M, Fitzpatrick R, Doll H, Playford ED, Jenkinson C. Patients' experiences of health and social care in long-term neurological conditions in England: a cross-sectional survey. J Health Serv Res Policy. 2013;18:28-33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munan M, Luth W, Genuis SK, Johnston WSW, MacIntyre E. Transitions in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: patient and caregiver experiences. Can J Neurol Sci J Can Sci Neurol. 2021;48:496-503.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>King SJ, Duke MM, O'Connor BA. Living with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis/motor neurone disease (ALS/MND): decision-making about &#x2018;ongoing change and adaptation&#x2019;. J Clin Nurs. 2009;18:745-754.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zehm A, Hazeltine AM, Greer JA, et al. Neurology clinicians' views on palliative care communication: &#x201c;how do you frame this?&#x201d;. Neurol Clin Pract. 2020;10:527-534.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murray L, Butow PN. Advance care planning in motor neuron disease: a systematic review. Palliat Support Care. 2016;14:411-432.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seeber AA, Pols AJ, Hijdra A, Grupstra HF, Willems DL, de Visser M. Advance care planning in progressive neurological diseases: lessons from ALS. BMC Palliat Care. 2019;18:50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ushikubo M. Comparison between home and hospital as the place of death for individuals with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in the last stages of illness. Am J Hosp Palliat Med. 2015;32:417-426.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Wit J, Beelen A, Drossaert CHC, et al. A blended psychosocial support program for partners of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and progressive muscular atrophy: protocol of a randomized controlled trial. BMC Psychol. 2018;6:20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinto C, Geraghty AWA, Yardley L, Dennison L. Emotional distress and well-being among people with motor neurone disease (MND) and their family caregivers: a qualitative interview study. BMJ Open. 2021;11:e044724.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foley G, Timonen V, Hardiman O. Exerting control and adapting to loss in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Soc Sci Med. 2014;101:113-119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson M, Perrin A. Tech adoption climbs among older adults. Pew Research Centre. May 17, 2017. https://www.pewresearch.org/internet/2017/05/17/tech-adoption-climbs-among-older-adults/. Accessed June 14, 2023</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Internet usage in Canada-statistics &amp; facts. Statista Website. https://www.statista.com/topics/4865/internet-usage-in-canada/. Accessed June 14, 2023</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weeden A, Kelly W. Canada's (dis)connected rural broadband policies: dealing with the digital divide and building &#x2018;digital capitals&#x2019; to address the impacts of COVID-19 In rural Canada. J Rural Community Dev. 2021;16:208-224.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The world by income and region. The World Bank Web site. https://datatopics.worldbank.org/world-development-indicators/the-world-by-income-and-region.html. Accessed June 14, 2023</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anestis E, Eccles F, Fletcher I, French M, Simpson J. Giving and receiving a diagnosis of a progressive neurological condition: a scoping review of doctors' and patients' perspectives. Patient Educ Couns. 2020;103(9):1709-1723.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merlin LR, Horak HA, Milligan TA, Kraakevik JA, Ali II. A competency-based longitudinal core curriculum in medical neuroscience. Neurology. 2014;83:456-462.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Genuis SK, Luth W, Campbell S, Bubela T, Johnston WS. Communication about end of life for patients living with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a scoping review of the empirical evidence. Front Neurol. 2021;12:1332.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palmieri A, Kleinbub JR, Pagnini F, Sorar&#xf9; G, Cipolletta S. Empathy-based supportive treatment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a pragmatic study. Am J Clin Hypn. 2021;63:202-216.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weeks KR, Gould RL, Mcdermott C, et al. Needs and preferences for psychological interventions of people with motor neuron disease. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2019;0:1-11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zarotti N, Mayberry E, Ovaska-Stafford N, Eccles F, Simpson J. Psychological interventions for people with motor neuron disease: a scoping review. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2021;22:1-11.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>