<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37477391</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>22</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-4598</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>68</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Muscle &amp; nerve</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Muscle Nerve</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Combining electromyography and Raman spectroscopy: optical EMG.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>464</StartPage><EndPage>470</EndPage><MedlinePgn>464-470</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/mus.27937</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION/AIMS">Electromyography (EMG) remains a key component of the diagnostic work-up for suspected neuromuscular disease, but it does not provide insight into the molecular composition of muscle which can provide diagnostic information. Raman spectroscopy is an emerging neuromuscular biomarker capable of generating highly specific, molecular fingerprints of tissue. Here, we present "optical EMG," a combination of EMG and Raman spectroscopy, achieved using a single needle.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">An optical EMG needle was created to collect electrophysiological and Raman spectroscopic data during a single insertion. We tested functionality with in vivo recordings in the SOD1<sup>G93A</sup> mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS), using both transgenic (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;10) and non-transgenic (NTg, n&#x2009;=&#x2009;7) mice. Under anesthesia, compound muscle action potentials (CMAPs), spontaneous EMG activity and Raman spectra were recorded from both gastrocnemius muscles with the optical EMG needle. Standard concentric EMG needle recordings were also undertaken. Electrophysiological data were analyzed with standard univariate statistics, Raman data with both univariate and multivariate analyses.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">A significant difference in CMAP amplitude was observed between SOD1<sup>G93A</sup> and NTg mice with optical EMG and standard concentric needles (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;.015 and p&#x2009;=&#x2009;.011, respectively). Spontaneous EMG activity (positive sharp waves) was detected in transgenic SOD1<sup>G93A</sup> mice only. Raman spectra demonstrated peaks associated with key muscle components. Significant differences in molecular composition between SOD1<sup>G93A</sup> and NTg muscle were identified through the Raman spectra.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION">Optical EMG can provide standard electrophysiological data and molecular Raman data during a single needle insertion and represents a potential biomarker for neuromuscular disease.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Authors. Muscle &amp; Nerve published by Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alix</LastName><ForeName>James J P</ForeName><Initials>JJP</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8391-9749</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sheffield Institute for Translational Neuroscience, University of Sheffield, Sheffield, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cross-Faculty Neuroscience Institute, University of Sheffield, Sheffield, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Plesia</LastName><ForeName>Maria</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sheffield Institute for Translational Neuroscience, University of Sheffield, Sheffield, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shaw</LastName><ForeName>Pamela J</ForeName><Initials>PJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8925-2567</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sheffield Institute for Translational Neuroscience, University of Sheffield, Sheffield, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cross-Faculty Neuroscience Institute, University of Sheffield, Sheffield, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mead</LastName><ForeName>Richard J</ForeName><Initials>RJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3207-0068</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sheffield Institute for Translational Neuroscience, University of Sheffield, Sheffield, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cross-Faculty Neuroscience Institute, University of Sheffield, Sheffield, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Day</LastName><ForeName>John C C</ForeName><Initials>JCC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1719-5065</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Interface Analysis Centre, School of Physics, University of Bristol, Bristol, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>MC_PC_15034</GrantID><Acronym>MRC_</Acronym><Agency>Medical Research Council</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>NF-SI-0617-10077</GrantID><Acronym>DH_</Acronym><Agency>Department of Health</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>IS-BRC-1215-20017</GrantID><Acronym>DH_</Acronym><Agency>Department of Health</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Muscle Nerve</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7803146</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0148-639X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 1.15.1.1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000072105">Superoxide Dismutase-1</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 1.15.1.1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D013482">Superoxide Dismutase</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051379" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004576" MajorTopicYN="N">Electromyography</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000072105" MajorTopicYN="N">Superoxide Dismutase-1</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013059" MajorTopicYN="Y">Spectrum Analysis, Raman</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008822" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice, Transgenic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004195" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Models, Animal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013482" MajorTopicYN="N">Superoxide Dismutase</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ALS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">EMG</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Raman spectroscopy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">biomarker</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">optical EMG</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37477391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.27937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Trojaborg W. The concentric versus the monopolar needle electrode. The case for concentric needles. Muscle Nerve. 1998;21(12):1806-1808.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pahlow S, Weber K, Popp J, et al. Application of vibrational spectroscopy and imaging to point-of-care medicine: a review. Appl Spectrosc. 2018;72(1_suppl):52-84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Traynor D, Behl I, O'Dea D, et al. Raman spectral cytopathology for cancer diagnostic applications. Nat Protoc. 2021;16(7):3716-3735.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gautam R, Vanga S, Madan A, Gayathri N, Nongthomba U, Umapathy S. Raman spectroscopic studies on screening of myopathies. Anal Chem. 2015;87(4):2187-2194.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plesia M, Stevens OA, Lloyd GR, et al. In vivo fiber optic Raman spectroscopy of muscle in preclinical models of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and Duchenne muscular dystrophy. ACS Chem Neurosci. 2021;12(10):1768-1776.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paraskevaidi M, Morais CLM, Halliwell DE, et al. Raman spectroscopy to diagnose Alzheimer's disease and Dementia with Lewy bodies in blood. ACS Chem Neurosci. 2018;9(11):2786-2794.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ralbovsky NM, Lednev IK. Towards development of a novel universal medical diagnostic method: Raman spectroscopy and machine learning. Chem Soc Rev. 2020;49(20):7428-7453.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devitt G, Howard K, Mudher A, Mahajan S. Raman spectroscopy: an emerging tool in neurodegenerative disease research and diagnosis. ACS Chem Neurosci. 2018;9(3):404-420.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alix JJP, Plesia M, Hool SA, et al. Fiber optic Raman spectroscopy for the evaluation of disease state in Duchenne muscular dystrophy: an assessment using the mdx model and human muscle. Muscle Nerve. 2022;66(3):362-369.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alix JJP, Plesia M, Lloyd GR, et al. The application of Raman spectroscopy to the diagnosis of mitochondrial muscle disease: a preliminary comparison between fibre optic probe and microscope formats. J Raman Spectrosc. 2022;53(2):172-181.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alix JJP, Plesia M, Lloyd GR, et al. Rapid identification of human muscle disease with fibre optic Raman spectroscopy. Analyst. 2022;147(11):2533-2540.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Day JC, Stone N. A subcutaneous Raman needle probe. Appl Spectrosc. 2013;67(3):349-354.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li R, Verreault D, Payne A, et al. Effects of laser excitation wavelength and optical mode on Raman spectra of human fresh colon, pancreas, and prostate tissues. J Raman Spectrosc. 2014;45(9):773-780.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kilkenny C, Browne WJ, Cuthill IC, Emerson M, Altman DG. Improving bioscience research reporting: the ARRIVE guidelines for reporting animal research. PLoS Biol. 2010;8(6):e1000412.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mead RJ, Bennett EJ, Kennerley AJ, et al. Optimised and rapid pre-clinical screening in the SOD1(G93A) transgenic mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). PLoS One. 2011;6(8):e23244.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ciervo Y, Gatto N, Allen C, et al. Adipose-derived stem cells protect motor neurons and reduce glial activation in both in vitro and in vivo models of ALS. Mol Ther Methods Clin Dev. 2021;21:413-433.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hegedus J, Putman CT, Gordon T. Time course of preferential motor unit loss in the SOD1 G93A mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurobiol Dis. 2007;28(2):154-164.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCampbell A, Cole T, Wegener AJ, et al. Antisense oligonucleotides extend survival and reverse decrement in muscle response in ALS models. J Clin Invest. 2018;128(8):3558-3567.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miana-Mena FJ, Munoz MJ, Yague G, et al. Optimal methods to characterize the G93A mouse model of ALS. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord. 2005;6(1):55-62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dobrowolny G, Aucello M, Rizzuto E, et al. Skeletal muscle is a primary target of SOD1G93A-mediated toxicity. Cell Metab. 2008;8(5):425-436.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bennett EJ, Mead RJ, Azzouz M, Shaw PJ, Grierson AJ. Early detection of motor dysfunction in the SOD1G93A mouse model of Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis (ALS) using home cage running wheels. PLoS One. 2014;9(9):e107918.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo S, Popp J, Bocklitz T. Chemometric analysis in Raman spectroscopy from experimental design to machine learning-based modeling. Nat Protoc. 2021;16(12):5426-5459.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butler HJ, Ashton L, Bird B, et al. Using Raman spectroscopy to characterize biological materials. Nat Protoc. 2016;11(4):664-687.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paraskevaidi M, Morais CLM, Lima KMG, et al. Differential diagnosis of Alzheimer's disease using spectrochemical analysis of blood. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2017;114(38):E7929-E7938.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nandedkar SD, Dumitru D, King JC. Concentric needle electrode duration measurement and uptake area. Muscle Nerve. 1997;20(10):1225-1228.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ambu. Design of the Neuroline Concentric EMG Needle A Multicentre, Post-marketing Study. Ambu; 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mancuso R, Santos-Nogueira E, Osta R, Navarro X. Electrophysiological analysis of a murine model of motoneuron disease. Clin Neurophysiol. 2011;122(8):1660-1670.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carew EB, Asher IM, Stanley HE. Laser raman spectroscopy-new probe of myosin substructure. Science. 1975;188(4191):933-936.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang Z, Teh SK, Zheng W, et al. In vivo detection of epithelial neoplasia in the stomach using image-guided Raman endoscopy. Biosens Bioelectron. 2010;26(2):383-389.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dobrowolny G, Lepore E, Martini M, et al. Metabolic changes associated with muscle expression of SOD1(G93A). Front Physiol. 2018;9:831.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palamiuc L, Schlagowski A, Ngo ST, et al. A metabolic switch toward lipid use in glycolytic muscle is an early pathologic event in a mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. EMBO Mol Med. 2015;7(5):526-546.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lehmann S, Esch E, Hartmann P, et al. Expression profile of pattern recognition receptors in skeletal muscle of SOD1(G93A) amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) mice and sporadic ALS patients. Neuropathol Appl Neurobiol. 2018;44(6):606-627.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harrison JM, Rafuse VF. Muscle fiber-type specific terminal Schwann cell pathology leads to sprouting deficits following partial denervation in SOD1G93A mice. Neurobiol Dis. 2020;145:105052.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dahlbom K, Lindberg C, Oldfors A. Inclusion body myositis: morphological clues to correct diagnosis. Neuromuscul Disord. 2002;12(9):853-857.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai CH, Melli G, Chang YJ, et al. Open muscle biopsy in suspected myopathy: diagnostic yield and clinical utility. Eur J Neurol. 2010;17(1):136-142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prayson RA. Diagnostic yield associated with multiple simultaneous skeletal muscle biopsies. Am J Clin Pathol. 2006;126(6):843-848.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Brien CM, Vargis E, Rudin A, et al. In vivo Raman spectroscopy for biochemical monitoring of the human cervix throughout pregnancy. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 2018;218(5):521-528.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alba-Arbalat S, Andorra M, Sanchez-Dalmau B, et al. In vivo molecular changes in the Retina of patients with multiple sclerosis. Invest Ophthalmol Vis Sci. 2021;62(6):11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wen Y, Truong VX, Li M. Real-time intraoperative surface-enhanced Raman spectroscopy-guided thermosurgical eradication of residual microtumors in orthotopic breast cancer. Nano Lett. 2021;21(7):3066-3074.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horgan CC, Bergholt MS, Thin MZ, et al. Image-guided Raman spectroscopy probe-tracking for tumor margin delineation. J Biomed Opt. 2021;26(3):36002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desroches J, Lemoine E, Pinto M, et al. Development and first in-human use of a Raman spectroscopy guidance system integrated with a brain biopsy needle. J Biophotonics. 2019;12(3):e201800396.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGregor HC, Short MA, McWilliams A, et al. Real-time endoscopic Raman spectroscopy for in vivo early lung cancer detection. J Biophotonics. 2017;10(1):98-110.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>