<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37493444</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>22</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-4598</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>68</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Muscle &amp; nerve</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Muscle Nerve</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Exposure to endogenous and exogenous sex hormones and reproductive history influence prognosis in women with ALS.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>414</StartPage><EndPage>421</EndPage><MedlinePgn>414-421</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/mus.27942</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION/AIMS">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) is a fatal neurodegenerative disease with a higher incidence in men suggesting an influence of sex steroids. Our objective was to investigate past exposure to endogenous and synthetic steroids in female ALS patients and controls.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">We administered a questionnaire to 158 postmenopausal women (75 ALS patients and 83 controls). We calculated reproductive time span (RTS), lifetime endogenous estrogen (LEE) and progesterone exposures (LPE), oral contraceptive pill (OCP) use, and reproductive history.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">ALS patients showed shorter LEE and LPE, a lower proportion of breast cancer, and 11% showed no history of pregnancies vs. 4% of controls. Odds ratios (ORs) showed that &lt;17&#x2009;y of LEE and a delayed menarche (&gt;13&#x2009;y) constitute risk factors for ALS [OR&#x2009;=&#x2009;2.1 (95% confidence interval {CI}, 1.08-4.2); and OR&#x2009;=&#x2009;2.4 (95% CI, 1.1-5.1) respectively]. According to Cox survival analysis, for each year the LEE increased over 17&#x2009;y, it was independently associated with longer survival [hazard ratio (HR)&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.37 (95% CI, 0.16-0.85)] after adjusting for smoking, age and site of onset. Multivariate regression analysis demonstrated that for each month using OCP for longer than 40&#x2009;mo increased the risk of ALS [adjusted OR&#x2009;=&#x2009;4.1 (95% CI, 1.2-13.8)].</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION">Thus, longer exposure to endogenous female sex steroids increased survival and reduced ALS susceptibility. In contrast, longer exposure to synthetic sex steroids showed a negative impact by reducing the production of endogenous female sex steroids or due to crossover with other steroid receptors. Given the neuroprotective effects of sex steroids, we suggest that abnormalities of neuroendocrine components may alter motor function in women with ALS.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gonzalez Deniselle</LastName><ForeName>M Claudia</ForeName><Initials>MC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9121-0019</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Neuroendocrine Biochemistry, Instituto de Biolog&#xed;a y Medicina Experimental-CONICET, Buenos Aires, Buenos Aires, Argentina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiological Sciences, Faculty of Medicine, University of Buenos Aires, Buenos Aires, Argentina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bettini</LastName><ForeName>Mariela</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Hospital Italiano de Buenos Aires, Buenos Aires, Argentina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Garrido</LastName><ForeName>Rosa M</ForeName><Initials>RM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gynecology, Hospital Marie Curie, Buenos Aires, Argentina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Meyer</LastName><ForeName>Maria</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Neuroendocrine Biochemistry, Instituto de Biolog&#xed;a y Medicina Experimental-CONICET, Buenos Aires, Buenos Aires, Argentina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lara</LastName><ForeName>Agustina</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Neuroendocrine Biochemistry, Instituto de Biolog&#xed;a y Medicina Experimental-CONICET, Buenos Aires, Buenos Aires, Argentina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Garay</LastName><ForeName>Laura I</ForeName><Initials>LI</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Neuroendocrine Biochemistry, Instituto de Biolog&#xed;a y Medicina Experimental-CONICET, Buenos Aires, Buenos Aires, Argentina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Human Biochemistry, Faculty of Medicine, University of Buenos Aires, Buenos Aires, Argentina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Casas</LastName><ForeName>Sebastian</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Neuroendocrine Biochemistry, Instituto de Biolog&#xed;a y Medicina Experimental-CONICET, Buenos Aires, Buenos Aires, Argentina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Hospital Militar Central Cirujano Mayor Dr. Cosme Argerich, Buenos Aires, Argentina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fulgenzi</LastName><ForeName>Ernesto</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hospital General de Agudos Dr. Ignacio Pirovano, Buenos Aires, Argentina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nu&#xf1;ez</LastName><ForeName>Myriam</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physics Mathematics, Faculty of Pharmacy and Biochemistry, University of Buenos Aires, Buenos Aires, Argentina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rugiero</LastName><ForeName>Marcelo F</ForeName><Initials>MF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gynecology, Hospital Marie Curie, Buenos Aires, Argentina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>De Nicola</LastName><ForeName>Alejandro F</ForeName><Initials>AF</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3523-9148</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Neuroendocrine Biochemistry, Instituto de Biolog&#xed;a y Medicina Experimental-CONICET, Buenos Aires, Buenos Aires, Argentina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Hospital Italiano de Buenos Aires, Buenos Aires, Argentina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gargiulo-Monachelli</LastName><ForeName>Gisella</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1294-5899</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Neuroendocrine Biochemistry, Instituto de Biolog&#xed;a y Medicina Experimental-CONICET, Buenos Aires, Buenos Aires, Argentina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Hospital General de Agudos Juan A. Fern&#xe1;ndez, Buenos Aires, Argentina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Centro de Educaci&#xf3;n M&#xe9;dica e Investigaciones Cl&#xed;nicas "Norberto Quirno", CEMIC, Buenos Aires, Argentina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Muscle Nerve</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7803146</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0148-639X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D012739">Gonadal Steroid Hormones</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D013256">Steroids</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017584" MajorTopicYN="N">Reproductive History</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019636" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neurodegenerative Diseases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012739" MajorTopicYN="N">Gonadal Steroid Hormones</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011379" MajorTopicYN="N">Prognosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012307" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013256" MajorTopicYN="N">Steroids</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">age of menarche</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sex steroids</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">survival</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">synthetic progestins</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37493444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.27942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Al-Chalabi A, Hardiman O. The epidemiology of ALS: a conspiracy of genes, environment and time. Nat Rev Neurol. 2013;9(11):617-628.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bradley WG, Andrew AS, Traynor BJ, Chio A, Butt TH, Stommel EW. Gene-environment-time interactions in neurodegenerative diseases: hypotheses and research approaches. Ann Neurosci. 2018;25(4):261-267.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gargiulo Monachelli G, Meyer M, Rodriguez GE, et al. Endogenous progesterone is associated to amyotrophic lateral sclerosis prognostic factors. Acta Neurol Scand. 2011;123(1):60-67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huisman MH, de Jong SW, van Doormaal PT, et al. Population based epidemiology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis using capture-recapture methodology. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2011;82(10):1165-1170.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klemann C, Visser JE, Van Den Bosch L, Martens GJM, Poelmans G. Integrated molecular landscape of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis provides insights into disease etiology. Brain Pathol. 2018;28(2):203-211.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Jong S, Huisman M, Sutedja N, et al. Endogenous female reproductive hormones and the risk of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol. 2013;260(2):507-512.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rooney JPK, Visser AE, D'Ovidio F, et al. A case-control study of hormonal exposures as etiologic factors for ALS in women: Euro-MOTOR. Neurology. 2017;89(12):1283-1290.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Nicola AF, Meyer M, Garay L, et al. Progesterone and allopregnanolone neuroprotective effects in the wobbler mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Cell Mol Neurobiol. 2022;42(1):23-40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez Deniselle MC, Carreras MC, Garay L, et al. Progesterone prevents mitochondrial dysfunction in the spinal cord of wobbler mice. J Neurochem. 2012;122(1):185-195.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gargiulo-Monachelli G, Meyer M, Lara A, et al. Comparative effects of progesterone and the synthetic progestin norethindrone on neuroprotection in a model of spontaneous motoneuron degeneration. J Steroid Biochem Mol Biol. 2019;192:105385.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jett S, Malviya N, Schelbaum E, et al. Endogenous and exogenous estrogen exposures: how Women's reproductive health can drive brain aging and inform Alzheimer's prevention. Front Aging Neurosci. 2022;14:831807.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor CM, Pritschet L, Jacobs EG. The scientific body of knowledge - whose body does it serve? A spotlight on oral contraceptives and women's health factors in neuroimaging. Front Neuroendocrinol. 2021;60:100874.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ACOG Committee Opinion No. 755: well-woman visit. Obstet Gynecol. 2018;132(4):e181-e186.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans D, Goldstein S, Loewy A, Altman AD. No. 385-indications for pelvic examination. J Obstetrics Gynaecol Canada: JOGC. 2019;41(8):1221-1234.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, Miller RG, Swash M, Munsat TL, World Federation of Neurology Research Group on Motor Neuron D. El Escorial revisited: revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and other motor neuron disorders: official publication of the world Federation of Neurology. Res Group Motor Neuron Dis. 2000;1(5):293-299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caldwell ASL, Edwards MC, Desai R, et al. Neuroendocrine androgen action is a key extraovarian mediator in the development of polycystic ovary syndrome. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2017;114(16):E3334-E3343.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benrick A, Chanclon B, Micallef P, et al. Adiponectin protects against development of metabolic disturbances in a PCOS mouse model. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2017;114(34):E7187-E7196.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez Paris V, Bertoldo MJ. The mechanism of androgen actions in PCOS etiology. Med Sci. 2019;7(9):89.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dallal CM, Lacey JV Jr, Pfeiffer RM, et al. Estrogen metabolism and risk of postmenopausal endometrial and ovarian cancer: the B approximately FIT cohort. Hormones Cancer. 2016;7(1):49-64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shadyab AH, Macera CA, Shaffer RA, et al. Ages at menarche and menopause and reproductive lifespan as predictors of exceptional longevity in women: the Women's Health Initiative. Menopause. 2017;24(1):35-44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Kleijn MJ, van der Schouw YT, Verbeek AL, Peeters PH, Banga JD, van der Graaf Y. Endogenous estrogen exposure and cardiovascular mortality risk in postmenopausal women. Am J Epidemiol. 2002;155(4):339-345.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Reilly EJ, Wang H, Weisskopf MG, et al. Premorbid body mass index and risk of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Frontotemporal Degener. 2013;14(3):205-211.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paganoni S, Deng J, Jaffa M, Cudkowicz ME, Wills AM. Body mass index, not dyslipidemia, is an independent predictor of survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 2011;44(1):20-24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimizu T, Nagaoka U, Nakayama Y, et al. Reduction rate of body mass index predicts prognosis for survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a multicenter study in Japan. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. 2012;13(4):363-366.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallo V, Wark PA, Jenab M, et al. Prediagnostic body fat and risk of death from amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: the EPIC cohort. Neurology. 2013;80(9):829-838.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaignard P, Liere P, Therond P, Schumacher M, Slama A, Guennoun R. Role of sex hormones on brain mitochondrial function, with special reference to aging and neurodegenerative diseases. Front Aging Neurosci. 2017;9:406.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer M, Garay LI, Kruse MS, et al. Protective effects of the neurosteroid allopregnanolone in a mouse model of spontaneous motoneuron degeneration. J Steroid Biochem Mol Biol. 2017;174:201-216.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vegeto E, Villa A, Della Torre S, et al. The role of sex and sex hormones in neurodegenerative diseases. Endocr Rev. 2020;41(2):273-319.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Irwin RW, Yao J, Ahmed SS, Hamilton RT, Cadenas E, Brinton RD. Medroxyprogesterone acetate antagonizes estrogen up-regulation of brain mitochondrial function. Endocrinology. 2011;152(2):556-567.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gargiulo-Monachelli GM, Sivori M, Meyer M, Sica RE, De Nicola AF, Gonzalez-Deniselle MC. Circulating gonadal and adrenal steroids in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: possible markers of susceptibility and outcome. Hormone Metab Res. 2014;46(6):433-439.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim YJ, Soto M, Branigan GL, Rodgers K, Brinton RD. Association between menopausal hormone therapy and risk of neurodegenerative diseases: implications for precision hormone therapy. Alzheimers Dement. 2021;7(1):e12174.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matyi JM, Rattinger GB, Schwartz S, Buhusi M, Tschanz JT. Lifetime estrogen exposure and cognition in late life: the Cache County study. Menopause. 2019;26(12):1366-1374.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chio A, Meineri P, Tribolo A, Schiffer D. Risk factors in motor neuron disease: a case-control study. Neuroepidemiology. 1991;10(4):174-184.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Popat RA, Van Den Eeden SK, Tanner CM, et al. Effect of reproductive factors and postmenopausal hormone use on the risk of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuroepidemiology. 2006;27(3):117-121.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar N, Koide SS, Tsong Y, Sundaram K. Nestorone: a progestin with a unique pharmacological profile. Steroids. 2000;65(10-11):629-636.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer M, Gonzalez Deniselle MC, Garay L, et al. The progesterone receptor agonist Nestorone holds back proinflammatory mediators and neuropathology in the wobbler mouse model of motoneuron degeneration. Neuroscience. 2015;308:51-63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sitruk-Ware R, Small M, Kumar N, Tsong YY, Sundaram K, Jackanicz T. Nestorone: clinical applications for contraception and HRT. Steroids. 2003;68(10-13):907-913.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Porter KN, Sarkar SN, Dakhlallah DA, Vannoy ME, Quintana DD, Simpkins JW. Medroxyprogesterone acetate impairs amyloid Beta degradation in a matrix Metalloproteinase-9 dependent manner. Front Aging Neurosci. 2020;12:92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chia R, Chio A, Traynor BJ. Novel genes associated with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: diagnostic and clinical implications. Lancet Neurol. 2018;17(1):94-102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu H, Huang Q, Zhang X, Yu Z, Zhong Z. Analysis of genomic copy number variation in miscarriages during early and middle pregnancy. Front Genet. 2021;12:732419.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hicks GG, Singh N, Nashabi A, et al. Fus deficiency in mice results in defective B-lymphocyte development and activation, high levels of chromosomal instability and perinatal death. Nat Genet. 2000;24(2):175-179.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu LS, Cheng WC, Hou SC, Yan YT, Jiang ST, Shen CK. TDP-43, a neuro-pathosignature factor, is essential for early mouse embryogenesis. Genesis. 2010;48(1):56-62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freedman DM, Wu J, Daugherty SE, Kuncl RW, Enewold LR, Pfeiffer RM. The risk of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis after cancer in U.S. elderly adults: a population-based prospective study. Int J Cancer. 2014;135(7):1745-1750.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibson SB, Abbott D, Farnham JM, et al. Population-based risks for cancer in patients with ALS. Neurology. 2016;87(3):289-294.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang F, Al-Chalabi A, Ronnevi LO, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and cancer: a register-based study in Sweden. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Frontotemporal Degener. 2013;14(5-6):362-368.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fois AF, Wotton CJ, Yeates D, Turner MR, Goldacre MJ. Cancer in patients with motor neuron disease, multiple sclerosis and Parkinson's disease: record linkage studies. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2010;81(2):215-221.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roe CM, Fitzpatrick AL, Xiong C, et al. Cancer linked to Alzheimer disease but not vascular dementia. Neurology. 2010;74(2):106-112.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>