<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37525592</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>22</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-4598</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>68</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Muscle &amp; nerve</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Muscle Nerve</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The effects of intervention with intravenous edaravone in Study 19 on hospitalization, tracheostomy, ventilation, and death in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>397</StartPage><EndPage>403</EndPage><MedlinePgn>397-403</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/mus.27946</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION/AIMS">Intravenous (IV) edaravone is a US Food and Drug Administration-approved treatment for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS), shown in clinical trials to slow physical functional decline. In this study we compared the effect of IV edaravone (edaravone-first group) versus placebo followed by IV edaravone (placebo-first group) on survival and additional milestone events.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">This work is a post hoc analysis of Study 19/MCI186-19, which was a randomized, placebo-controlled, phase 3 study investigating IV edaravone versus placebo. Study 19 and its 24-week extension have been described previously (NCT01492686). Edaravone-first versus placebo-first group time to events for specific milestone(s) were analyzed post hoc. Time-to-event composite endpoints were time to death; time to death, tracheostomy, or permanent assisted ventilation (PAV); and time to death, tracheostomy, PAV, or hospitalization.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">The risk for death, tracheostomy, PAV, or hospitalization was 53% lower among patients in the edaravone-first vs placebo-first groups (hazard ratio&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.47 [95% confidence interval 0.25 to 0.88], P&#x2009;=&#x2009;.02). The overall effect of IV edaravone on ALS progression could be seen in the significant separation of time-to-event curves for time to death, tracheostomy, PAV, or hospitalization. ALS survival composite endpoint analyses (ALS/SURV) suggested a treatment benefit (least-squares mean difference) for the edaravone-first versus the placebo-first group at week 24 (0.15&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.05 [95% confidence interval 0.06 to 0.25], P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;.01) and week 48 (0.11&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.05 [95% confidence interval 0.02 to 0.21], P&#x2009;=&#x2009;.02).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION">These analyses illustrate the value of timely and continued IV edaravone treatment, as earlier initiation was associated with a lower risk of death, tracheostomy, PAV, or hospitalization in patients with ALS.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 Mitsubishi Tanabe Pharma America, Inc and The Authors. Muscle &amp; Nerve published by Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brooks</LastName><ForeName>Benjamin Rix</ForeName><Initials>BR</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1914-5061</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Trials Planning LLC, Charlotte, North Carolina, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Atrium Health Neuroscience Institute, Neuromuscular/ALS-MDA Care Center and ALSA Center of Excellence, Department of Neurology, Carolinas Medical Center, University of North Carolina School of Medicine-Charlotte Campus, Charlotte, North Carolina, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pioro</LastName><ForeName>Erik P</ForeName><Initials>EP</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0737-6065</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neuromuscular Division, Davee Department of Neurology, Northwestern University Feinberg School of Medicine, Chicago, Illinois, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sakata</LastName><ForeName>Takeshi</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mitsubishi Tanabe Pharma Corporation, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Takahashi</LastName><ForeName>Fumihiro</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5701-5332</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mitsubishi Tanabe Pharma America, Inc., Jersey City, New Jersey, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hagan</LastName><ForeName>Melissa</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mitsubishi Tanabe Pharma America, Inc., Jersey City, New Jersey, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Apple</LastName><ForeName>Stephen</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3051-3953</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mitsubishi Tanabe Pharma America, Inc., Jersey City, New Jersey, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT01492686</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017428">Clinical Trial, Phase III</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>31</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Muscle Nerve</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7803146</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0148-639X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>S798V6YJRP</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000077553">Edaravone</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000077553" MajorTopicYN="N">Edaravone</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014139" MajorTopicYN="N">Tracheostomy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016016" MajorTopicYN="N">Proportional Hazards Models</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016019" MajorTopicYN="N">Survival Analysis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">intravenous edaravone</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">motor neuron disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">study 19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">survival</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37525592</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.27946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Brown RH, Al-Chalabi A. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. N Engl J Med. 2017;377:162-172. doi:10.1056/NEJMra1603471</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rilutek&#xae; (riluzole). Prescribing information. Covis Pharmaceuticals, Inc.; 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radicava&#xae; (edaravone). Prescribing information. Mitsubishi Tanabe Pharma Corporation. 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller RG, Jackson CE, Kasarskis EJ, et al. Practice parameter update: the care of the patient with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: multidisciplinary care, symptom management, and cognitive/behavioral impairment (an evidence-based review): report of the quality standards subcommittee of the American Academy of Neurology. Neurology. 2009;73:1227-1233.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, Jorgenson JA, Newhouse BJ, Shefner JM, Agnese W. Edaravone in the treatment of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: efficacy and access to therapy-a roundtable discussion. Am J Manag Care. 2018;24(Suppl 9):S175-S186.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Writing Group on Behalf of the Edaravone (MCI-186) ALS 19 Study Group. Safety and efficacy of edaravone in well defined patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Lancet Neurol. 2017;16:505-512. doi:10.1016/S1474-4422(17)30115-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Writing Group on Behalf of the Edaravone ALS 19 Study Group. Open-label 24-week extension study of edaravone (MCI-186) in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2017;18(Suppl 1):55-63. doi:10.1080/21678421.2017.1364269</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takei K, Tsuda K, Takahashi F, Palumbo J. Post-hoc analysis of open-label extension period of study MCI186-19 in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2017;18(Suppl 1):64-70. doi:10.1080/21678421.2017.1365372</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shefner J, Heiman-Patterson T, Pioro EP, et al. Long-term edaravone efficacy in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: post-hoc analyses of study 19 (MCI186-19). Muscle Nerve. 2020;61:218-221. doi:10.1002/mus.26740</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceriana P, Surbone S, Segagni D, Schreiber A, Carlucci A. Decision-making for tracheostomy in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS): a retrospective study. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2017;18:492-497. doi:10.1080/21678421.2017.1317812</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fanaroff AC, Haque G, Thomas B, et al. Methods for safety and endpoint ascertainment: identification of adverse events through scrutiny of negatively adjudicated events. Trials. 2020;21:323. doi:10.1186/s13063-020-04254-w</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goutman SA, Brown MB, Cudkowicz M, Atassi N, Feldman EL. ALS/SURV: a modification of the CAFS statistic. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2019;20:576-583. doi:10.1080/21678421.2019.1643375</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, Berry JD, Ciepielewska M, et al. Intravenous edaravone treatment in ALS and survival: an exploratory, retrospective, administrative claims analysis. eClinicalMedicine. 2022;52:101590. doi:10.1016/j.eclinm.2022.101590</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sugisawa T, Morioka H, Hirayama T, Kano O, Ebihara S. Multidisciplinary clinic contributes to the decreasing trend in the number of emergency hospitalizations for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in Japan. J Clin Neurosci. 2023;107:133-137. doi:10.1016/j.jocn.2022.10.011</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakayama R, Nishiyama A, Matsuda C, Nakayama Y, Hakuta C, Shimada M. Oral health status of hospitalized amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients: a single-centre observational study. Acta Odontol Scand. 2018;76(4):294-298. doi:10.1080/00016357.2017.1420228</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayashi N, Atsuta N, Yokoi D, et al. Prognosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients undergoing tracheostomy invasive ventilation therapy in Japan. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2020;91:285-290. doi:10.1136/jnnp-2019-322213</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurihara M, Bamba S, Yasuhara S, et al. Factors affecting energy metabolism and prognosis in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Nutr Metab. 2021;77:236-243. doi:10.1159/000518908</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takei K, Tsuda K, Takahashi F, Hirai M, Palumbo J. An assessment of treatment guidelines, clinical practices, demographics, and progression of disease among patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in Japan, the United States, and Europe. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2017;18(Suppl 1):88-97. doi:10.1080/21678421.2017.1361445</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakamaru Y, Kinoshita S, Kawaguchi A, Takei K, Palumbo J, Suzuki M. Pharmacokinetic profile of edaravone: a comparison between Japanese and Caucasian populations. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2017;18(Suppl 1):80-87. doi:10.1080/21678421.2017.1353100</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>