<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37540049</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>22</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-4598</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>68</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Muscle &amp; nerve</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Muscle Nerve</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Epidemiology and characteristics of emergency department utilization by patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in Korea from 2016 to 2020: A nationwide study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>451</StartPage><EndPage>459</EndPage><MedlinePgn>451-459</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/mus.27952</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION/AIMS">Patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) inevitably visit the emergency department (ED) due to their increased risk of respiratory failure and mobility limitations. However, nationwide data on ED visits by patients with ALS are limited. This study investigated the characteristics of patients with ALS-related ED visits.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">We conducted a cross-sectional study from 2016 to 2020, utilizing a nationwide ED database. The total number of patients with ALS who visited the ED and their primary reasons for visiting/diagnoses were analyzed.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">In total, 6036 visits to the ED were made by patients with ALS. Of these, 41.8% arrived by ambulance and 27.7% spent &gt;9&#x2009;h in the ED. Following ED treatment, 57.4% were hospitalized, including 19.3% admitted to the intensive care unit (ICU) and 5.4% who died in the hospital. The primary reasons for ALS-related ED visits were dyspnea (35.2%), feeding tube problems (10.1%), fever (7.8%), and mental status changes (3.6%). The most common diagnoses were pneumonia (14.5%), respiratory failure (5.7%), dyspnea (5.5%), aspiration pneumonia (4.3%), and tracheostomy complications (3.4%).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION">Reasons for ED visits for patients with ALS include acute respiratory distress, as well as concerns related to tube feeding and tracheostomy. To reduce the risk of patients with ALS requiring ED visits, it is essential to ensure the provision of timely respiratory support and high-quality home-based medical care teams that can support and address patients before their condition deteriorates.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ko</LastName><ForeName>Jung-In</ForeName><Initials>JI</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5211-6484</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Emergency Medicine, National Medical Center, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Choi</LastName><ForeName>Seok-Jin</ForeName><Initials>SJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6444-977X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Seoul National University Hospital, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yoo</LastName><ForeName>Shin Hye</ForeName><Initials>SH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7473-1082</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Palliative Care and Clinical Ethics, Seoul National University Hospital, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cho</LastName><ForeName>Belong</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9558-689X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Public Healthcare Center, Seoul National University Hospital, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Human Systems Medicine, Seoul National University College of Medicine &amp; Hospital, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute on Aging, Seoul National University College of Medicine, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Min Sun</ForeName><Initials>MS</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5323-9857</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Public Healthcare Center, Seoul National University Hospital, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, Seoul National University College of Medicine &amp; Hospital, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Kyae Hyung</ForeName><Initials>KH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9954-6422</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Public Healthcare Center, Seoul National University Hospital, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Sun Young</ForeName><Initials>SY</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1626-2721</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Public Healthcare Center, Seoul National University Hospital, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Seoul National University College of Medicine, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Muscle Nerve</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7803146</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0148-639X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003430" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Sectional Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004636" MajorTopicYN="N">Emergency Service, Hospital</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012131" MajorTopicYN="Y">Respiratory Insufficiency</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004417" MajorTopicYN="N">Dyspnea</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D056910" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Republic of Korea</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">emergency department</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">healthcare utilization</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">motor neuron disease</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37540049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.27952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Rose L, McKim D, Leasa D, et al. Patterns of healthcare utilisation for respiratory complications of adults with neuromuscular disease: a population study. Eur Respir J. 2018;52:1800754.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lechtzin N, Wiener CM, Clawson L, Chaudhry V, Diette GB. Hospitalization in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: causes, costs, and outcomes. Neurology. 2001;56:753-757.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darb&#xe0; J. Current status and direct medical cost of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in the region of Catalonia: a population-based analysis. PloS One. 2019;14:e0223772.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams AE, Lloyd AC, Watson L, Rabe K. Cost of scheduled and unscheduled asthma management in seven European Union countries. Eur Respir Rev. 2006;15:4-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsieh VC, Hsieh ML, Chiang JH, Chien A, Hsieh MS. Emergency department visits and disease burden attributable to ambulatory care sensitive conditions in elderly adults. Sci Rep. 2019;9(1):3811.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forsg&#xe4;rde E-S, Attebring MF, Elmqvist C. Powerlessness: dissatisfied patients' and relatives' experience of their emergency department visit. Int Emerg Nurs. 2016;25:32-36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang BP, Sumner JA, Haerizadeh M, Carter E, Edmondson D. Perceived clinician-patient communication in the emergency department and subsequent post-traumatic stress symptoms in patients evaluated for acute coronary syndrome. Emerg Med J. 2016;33:626-631.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smulowitz PB, Honigman L, Landon BE. A novel approach to identifying targets for cost reduction in the emergency department. Ann Emerg Med. 2013;61:293-300.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panattoni L, Fedorenko C, Greenwood-Hickman MA, et al. Characterizing potentially preventable cancer- and chronic disease-related emergency department use in the year after treatment initiation: a regional study. J Oncol Pract. 2018;14:e176-e185.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shellikeri S, Karthikeyan V, Martino R, et al. The neuropathological signature of bulbar-onset ALS: a systematic review. Neurosci Biobehav Rev. 2017;75:378-392.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cordesse V, Sidorok F, Schimmel P, Holstein J, Meininger V. Coordinated care affects hospitalization and prognosis in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a cohort study. BMC Health Serv Res. 2015;15:134.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2; A, Bottacchi E, Buffa C, Mutani R, Mora G. Positive effects of tertiary centres for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis on outcome and use of hospital facilities. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2006;77:948-950.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller RG, Jackson CE, Kasarskis EJ, et al. Practice parameter update: the care of the patient with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: multidisciplinary care, symptom management, and cognitive/behavioral impairment (an evidence-based review): report of the quality standards Subcommittee of the American Academy of neurology. Neurology. 2009;73:1227-1233.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>EFNS Task Force on Diagnosis and Management of Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis, Andersen PM, Abrahams S, et al. EFNS guidelines on the clinical management of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (MALS) - revised report of an EFNS task force. Eur J Neurol. 2012;19:360-375.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore A, Young CA, Hughes DA. Health utilities and costs for motor Neurone disease. Value Health. 2019;22:1257-1265.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee SY, Ro YS, Shin SD, Moon S. Epidemiologic trends in cancer-related emergency department utilization in Korea from 2015 to 2019. Sci Rep. 2021;11:21981.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim S, Kwon S. Impact of the policy of expanding benefit coverage for cancer patients on catastrophic health expenditure across different income groups in South Korea. Soc Sci Med. 2015;138:241-247.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pak YS, Ro YS, Kim SH, et al. Effects of emergency care-related health policies during the COVID-19 pandemic in Korea: a quasi-experimental study. J Korean Med Sci. 2021;36:e121.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee SY, Khang YH, Lim HK. Impact of the 2015 Middle East respiratory syndrome outbreak on emergency care utilization and mortality in South Korea. Yonsei Med J. 2019;60:796-803.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim TH, Ro YS, Shin SD, et al. Association of health insurance with post-resuscitation care and neurological outcomes after return of spontaneous circulation in out-of-hospital cardiac arrest patients in Korea. Resuscitation. 2019;135:176-182.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cho SY, Kang JM, Ha YE, et al. MERS-CoV outbreak following a single patient exposure in an emergency room in South Korea: an epidemiological outbreak study. Lancet. 2016;388:994-1001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi SJ, Park CHK, Hong YH, Sung JJ. Previous psychiatric disorders in the multistep hypothesis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a south Korean population study. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2022;23:601-607.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jun KY, Park J, Oh KW, et al. Epidemiology of ALS in Korea using nationwide big data. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2019;90:395-403.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leigh PN, Abrahams S, Al-Chalabi A, et al. The management of motor neurone disease. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2003;74:iv32-iv47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoon SY, Kim HK, Kim MJ, Suh JH, Leigh JH. Factors associated with assisted ventilation use in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a nationwide population-based study in Korea. Sci Rep. 2021;11(1):19682.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayashi N, Atsuta N, Yokoi D, et al. Prognosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients undergoing tracheostomy invasive ventilation therapy in Japan. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2020;91:285-290.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bae JS, Hong YH, Baek W, et al. Current status of the diagnosis and management of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in Korea: a multi-center cross-sectional study. J Clin Neurol. 2012;8:293-300.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>