<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37554051</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1531-8249</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>94</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Annals of neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Ann Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Neutrophils Are Associated with Higher Risk of Incident Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis in a BMI- and Age-Dependent Manner.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>942</StartPage><EndPage>954</EndPage><MedlinePgn>942-954</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/ana.26760</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">Peripheral immune markers have been associated with the progression and prognosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). However, whether dysregulation of peripheral immunity is a risk factor for ALS or a consequence of motor neuron degeneration has not yet been clarified. We aimed to identify longitudinal associations between prediagnostic peripheral immunity and the risk of incident ALS.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">A total of 345,000 individuals from the UK Biobank between 2006 and 2010 were included at the baseline. The counts of peripheral immune markers (neutrophils, lymphocytes, monocytes, platelets, and CRP) and its derived metrics (neutrophil-to-lymphocyte ratio [NLR], platelet-to-lymphocyte ratio [PLR], lymphocyte-to-monocyte ratio [LMR], and systemic immune-inflammation index [SII]) were analyzed in relation to the following incident ALS by Cox proportional hazard models. Subgroup and interaction analyses were performed to explore the covariates of these relationships further.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">After adjusting for all covariates, the multivariate analysis showed that high neutrophil counts and their derived metrics (NLR and SII) were associated with an increased risk of ALS incidence (per SD increment hazard ratio [HR]&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.15, 95% confidence interval [CI]&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.02-1.29 for neutrophils; HR&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.15, 95% CI&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.03-1.28 for NLR; and HR&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.17, 95% CI&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.05-1.30 for SII). Subgroup and interaction analyses revealed that body mass index (BMI) and age had specific effects on this association. In participants with BMI &#x2265;&#x2009;25 or age &lt;&#x2009;65&#x2009;years, higher neutrophil counts, and their metrics increased the risk of incident ALS; however, in participants with BMI &lt;&#x2009;25 or age &#x2265;&#x2009;65&#x2009;years, neutrophils had no effect on incident ALS.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="INTERPRETATION">Our study provides evidence that increased neutrophil levels and neutrophil-derived metrics (NLR and SII) are associated with an increased risk of developing ALS. ANN NEUROL 2023;94:942-954.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 American Neurological Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cao</LastName><ForeName>Wen</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Peking University Third Hospital, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cao</LastName><ForeName>Zhi</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Public Health, Zhejiang University School of Medicine, Hangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Public Health, Hangzhou Normal University, Hangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tian</LastName><ForeName>Yao</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Peking University Third Hospital, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Linjing</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Peking University Third Hospital, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Wenjing</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Peking University Third Hospital, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tang</LastName><ForeName>Lu</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3589-6287</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Peking University Third Hospital, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Beijing Key Laboratory of Biomarker and Translational Research in Neurodegenerative Disorders, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Chenjie</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8997-9299</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Public Health, Hangzhou Normal University, Hangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fan</LastName><ForeName>Dongsheng</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3129-9821</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Peking University Third Hospital, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Beijing Key Laboratory of Biomarker and Translational Research in Neurodegenerative Disorders, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Ann Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7707449</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0364-5134</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D015415">Biomarkers</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009504" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neutrophils</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015992" MajorTopicYN="N">Body Mass Index</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008214" MajorTopicYN="N">Lymphocytes</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011379" MajorTopicYN="N">Prognosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015415" MajorTopicYN="N">Biomarkers</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007249" MajorTopicYN="N">Inflammation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37554051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.26760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Feldman EL, Goutman SA, Petri S, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet 2022;400:1363-1380.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu W, He J, Cai X, et al. Neuroimmune crosstalk between the peripheral and the central immune system in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Front Aging Neurosci 2022;14:890958.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yazdani S, Seitz C, Cui C, et al. T cell responses at diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis predict disease progression. Nat Commun 2022;13:6733.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Figueroa-Romero C, Monteagudo A, Murdock BJ, et al. Tofacitinib suppresses natural killer cells In vitro and In vivo: implications for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Front Immunol 2022;13:773288.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui C, Ingre C, Yin L, et al. Correlation between leukocyte phenotypes and prognosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Elife 2022;11:e74065.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trolese MC, Scarpa C, Melfi V, et al. Boosting the peripheral immune response in the skeletal muscles improved motor function in ALS transgenic mice. Mol Ther 2022;30:2760-2784.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thonhoff JR, Berry JD, Macklin EA, et al. Combined regulatory T-lymphocyte and IL-2 treatment is safe, tolerable, and biologically active for 1 year in persons with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurol Neuroimmunol Neuroinflamm. 2022;9:e200019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polg&#xe1;r TF, Meszl&#xe9;nyi V, N&#xf3;gr&#xe1;di B, et al. Passive transfer of blood sera from ALS patients with identified mutations results in elevated motoneuronal calcium level and loss of motor neurons in the spinal cord of mice. Int J Mol Sci 2021;22:9994.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campisi L, Chizari S, Ho J, et al. Clonally expanded CD8 T cells characterize amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-4. Nature 2022;606:945-952.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang YR, Wang JJ, Chen SF, et al. Peripheral immunity is associated with the risk of incident dementia. Mol Psychiatry 2022;27:1956-1962.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jensen MP, Jacobs BM, Dobson R, et al. Lower lymphocyte count is associated with increased risk of Parkinson's disease. Ann Neurol 2021;89:803-812.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei QQ, Hou YB, Zhang LY, et al. Neutrophil-to-lymphocyte ratio in sporadic amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neural Regen Res 2022;17:875-880.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murdock BJ, Bender DE, Kashlan SR, et al. Increased ratio of circulating neutrophils to monocytes in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurol Neuroimmunol Neuroinflamm 2016;3:e242.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murdock BJ, Famie JP, Piecuch CE, et al. NK cells associate with ALS in a sex- and age-dependent manner. JCI. Insight 2021;6:e147129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murdock BJ, Goutman SA, Boss J, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis survival associates with neutrophils in a sex-specific manner. Neurol Neuroimmunol Neuroinflamm 2021;8:e953.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lackey DE, Olefsky JM. Regulation of metabolism by the innate immune system. Nat Rev Endocrinol 2016;12:15-28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Purdy JC, Shatzel JJ. The hematologic consequences of obesity. Eur J Haematol 2021;106:306-319.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frasca D, Ferracci F, Diaz A, et al. Obesity decreases B cell responses in young and elderly individuals. Obesity (Silver Spring) 2016;24:615-625.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson AR, Milner JJ, Makowski L. The inflammation highway: metabolism accelerates inflammatory traffic in obesity. Immunol Rev 2012;249:218-238.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakken O, Meyer HE, Stigum H, Holm&#xf8;y T. High BMI is associated with low ALS risk: a population-based study. Neurology 2019;93:e424-e432.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudlow C, Gallacher J, Allen N, et al. UK biobank: an open access resource for identifying the causes of a wide range of complex diseases of middle and old age. PLoS Med 2015;12:e1001779.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicoletti A, Baschi R, Cicero CE, et al. Sex and gender differences in Alzheimer's disease, Parkinson's disease, and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a narrative review. Mech Ageing Dev 2023;221:111821.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watts EL, Perez-Cornago A, Kothari J, et al. Hematologic markers and prostate cancer risk: a prospective analysis in UK biobank. Cancer Epidemiol Biomarkers Prev 2020;29:1615-1626.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fry A, Littlejohns TJ, Sudlow C, et al. Comparison of sociodemographic and health-related characteristics of UK biobank participants with those of the general population. Am J Epidemiol 2017;186:1026-1034.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marin B, Fontana A, Arcuti S, et al. Age-specific ALS incidence: a dose-response meta-analysis. Eur J Epidemiol 2018;33:621-634.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehta PR, Iacoangeli A, Opie-Martin S, et al. The impact of age on genetic testing decisions in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain 2022;145:4440-4447.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muscatell KA, Brosso SN, Humphreys KL. Socioeconomic status and inflammation: a meta-analysis. Mol Psychiatry 2020;25:2189-2199.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maurel M, Castagn&#xe9; R, Berger E, et al. Patterning of educational attainment across inflammatory markers: findings from a multi-cohort study. Brain Behav Immun 2020;90:303-310.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>King CC, Piper ME, Gepner AD, et al. Longitudinal impact of smoking and smoking cessation on inflammatory markers of cardiovascular disease risk. Arterioscler Thromb Vasc Biol 2017;37:374-379.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sutedja NA, Veldink JH, Fischer K, et al. Lifetime occupation, education, smoking, and risk of ALS. Neurology 2007;69:1508-1514.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L, Tang L, Xia K, et al. Education, intelligence, and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a mendelian randomization study. Ann Clin Transl Neurol 2020;7:1642-1647.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhan Y, Fang F. Smoking and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a mendelian randomization study. Ann Neurol 2019;85:482-484.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bandres-Ciga S, Noyce AJ, Hemani G, et al. Shared polygenic risk and causal inferences in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann Neurol 2019;85:470-481.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pupillo E, Messina P, Logroscino G, Beghi E. Long-term survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a population-based study. Ann Neurol 2014;75:287-297.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beers DR, Appel SH. Immune dysregulation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: mechanisms and emerging therapies. Lancet Neurol 2019;18:211-220.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murdock BJ, Zhou T, Kashlan SR, et al. Correlation of peripheral immunity with rapid amyotrophic lateral sclerosis progression. JAMA Neurol 2017;74:1446-1454.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zahorec R. Neutrophil-to-lymphocyte ratio, past, present and future perspectives. Bratisl Lek Listy 2021;122:474-488.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie R, Xiao M, Li L, et al. Association between SII and hepatic steatosis and liver fibrosis: a population-based study. Front Immunol 2022;13:925690.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leone MA, Mandrioli J, Russo S, et al. Neutrophils-to-lymphocyte ratio is associated with progression and overall survival in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Biomedicine 2022;10:354.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi SJ, Hong YH, Kim SM, et al. High neutrophil-to-lymphocyte ratio predicts short survival duration in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Sci Rep 2020;10:428.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yazdani S, Mariosa D, Hammar N, et al. Peripheral immune biomarkers and neurodegenerative diseases: a prospective cohort study with 20&#x2009;years of follow-up. Ann Neurol 2019;86:913-926.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrozziello T, Mills AN, Farhan S, et al. Lipocalin-2 is increased in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve 2020;62:272-283.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niebroj-Dobosz I, Janik P, Soko&#x142;owska B, Kwiecinski H. Matrix metalloproteinases and their tissue inhibitors in serum and cerebrospinal fluid of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Eur J Neurol 2010;17:226-231.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butcher SK, Chahal H, Nayak L, et al. Senescence in innate immune responses: reduced neutrophil phagocytic capacity and CD16 expression in elderly humans. J Leukoc Biol 2001;70:881-886.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braga PC, Sala MT, Dal Sasso M, et al. Age-associated differences in neutrophil oxidative burst (chemiluminescence). Exp Gerontol 1998;33:477-484.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vitlic A, Lord JM, Taylor AE, et al. Neutrophil function in young and old caregivers. Br J Health Psychol 2016;21:173-189.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schr&#xf6;der AK, Rink L. Neutrophil immunity of the elderly. Mech Ageing Dev 2003;124:419-425.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nijhuis J, Rensen SS, Slaats Y, et al. Neutrophil activation in morbid obesity, chronic activation of acute inflammation. Obesity (Silver Spring) 2009;17:2014-2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dixon JB, O'Brien PE. Obesity and the white blood cell count: changes with sustained weight loss. Obes Surg 2006;16:251-257.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah TJ, Leik CE, Walsh SW. Neutrophil infiltration and systemic vascular inflammation in obese women. Reprod Sci 2010;17:116-124.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez-Muniesa P, M&#xe1;rtinez-Gonz&#xe1;lez MA, Hu FB, et al. Obesity. Nat Rev Dis Primers 2017;3:17034.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts HM, Grant MM, Hubber N, et al. Impact of bariatric surgical intervention on peripheral blood neutrophil (PBN) function in obesity. Obes Surg 2018;28:1611-1621.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lo T, Haridas RS, Rudge E, et al. Early changes in immune cell count, metabolism, and function following sleeve gastrectomy: a prospective human study. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 2022;107:e619-e630.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Reilly &#xc9;J, Wang H, Weisskopf MG, et al. Premorbid body mass index and risk of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 2013;14:205-211.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson AG, Talbot K, Turner MR. Higher blood high density lipoprotein and apolipoprotein A1 levels are associated with reduced risk of developing amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2022;93:75-81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peter RS, Rosenbohm A, Dupuis L, et al. Life course body mass index and risk and prognosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: results from the ALS registry Swabia. Eur J Epidemiol 2017;32:901-908.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kioumourtzoglou MA, Rotem RS, Seals RM, et al. Diabetes mellitus, obesity, and diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a population-based study. JAMA Neurol 2015;72:905-911.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L, Tang L, Huang T, Fan D. Life course adiposity and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a mendelian randomization study. Ann Neurol 2020;87:434-441.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beers DR, Henkel JS, Zhao W, et al. Endogenous regulatory T lymphocytes ameliorate amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in mice and correlate with disease progression in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain 2011;134:1293-1314.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheean RK, McKay FC, Cretney E, et al. Association of Regulatory T-cell expansion with progression of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a study of humans and a transgenic mouse model. JAMA Neurol 2018;75:681-689.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henkel JS, Beers DR, Wen S, et al. Regulatory T-lymphocytes mediate amyotrophic lateral sclerosis progression and survival. EMBO Mol Med 2013;5:64-79.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garofalo S, Cocozza G, Porzia A, et al. Natural killer cells modulate motor neuron-immune cell cross talk in models of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat Commun 2020;11:1773.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du Y, Zhao W, Thonhoff JR, et al. Increased activation ability of monocytes from ALS patients. Exp Neurol 2020;328:113259.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Black S, Kushner I, Samols D. C-reactive protein. J Biol Chem 2004;279:48487-48490.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kharel S, Ojha R, Preethish-Kumar V, Bhagat R. C-reactive protein levels in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a systematic review. Brain Behav 2022;12:e2532.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lunetta C, Lizio A, Maestri E, et al. Serum C-reactive protein as a prognostic biomarker in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. JAMA Neurol 2017;74:660-667.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu Y, Li M, Zhang J, Huang X. Association between C-reactive protein and risk of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a mendelian randomization study. Front Genet 2022;13:919031.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zenaro E, Pietronigro E, Della Bianca V, et al. Neutrophils promote Alzheimer's disease-like pathology and cognitive decline via LFA-1 integrin. Nat Med 2015;21:880-886.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blanco-Camarillo C, Alem&#xe1;n OR, Rosales C. Low-density neutrophils in healthy individuals display a mature primed phenotype. Front Immunol 2021;12:672520.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Obama T, Itabe H. Neutrophils as a novel target of modified low-density lipoproteins and an accelerator of cardiovascular diseases. Int J Mol Sci 2020;21:8312.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cho Y, Bukong TN, Tornai D, et al. Neutrophil extracellular traps contribute to liver damage and increase defective low-density neutrophils in alcohol-associated hepatitis. J Hepatol 2023;78:28-44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newton R, Priyadharshini B, Turka LA. Immunometabolism of regulatory T cells. Nat Immunol 2016;17:618-625.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun J, Huang T, Debelius JW, Fang F. Gut microbiome and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a systematic review of current evidence. J Intern Med 2021;290:758-788.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>