<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37682161</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>11</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-5964</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>102</Volume><Issue>36</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>08</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Medicine (Baltimore)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Exploring the mechanism of Semen Strychni in treating amyotrophic lateral sclerosis based on network pharmacology.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e35101</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e35101</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e35101</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MD.0000000000035101</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Semen Strychni (SS), known as an agonist of central nervous system, is a traditional herb widely used in treating amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) in small doses to relieve muscle weakness and improve muscle strength. However, the potential mechanisms and the main components of SS in treating ALS remain unclear. To explore the underlying mechanism of SS in treating ALS based on network pharmacology and molecular docking. The active components of SS were obtained using TCMSP, Herb, ETCM, and BATMAN-TCM. The targets of SS were gained from PharmMapper. The targets of ALS were searched on Genecards, Drugbank, DisGeNET, OMIM, TTD and GEO database. After obtaining the coincidence targets, we submitted them to the STRING database to build a protein-protein interaction network. Gene ontology and Kyoto Encyclopedia of Genes and Genomes enrichment analysis were performed subsequently. The active components and targets were further investigated using molecular docking technology. 395 targets of SS and 1925 targets of ALS were obtained with 125 common targets. The protein-protein interaction analysis indicated that SRC, AKT1, MAPK1, EGFR, and HSP90AA1 received the higher degree value and were considered the central genes. The Ras, PI3K-Akt, and MAPK signaling pathway could be involved in the treatment of ALS. Brucine-N-oxide obtained the lowest binding energy in molecular docking. This study explored the mechanism of SS in the treatment of ALS and provides a new perspective for future study. However, further experimental studies are needed to validate the therapeutic effect.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 the Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tang</LastName><ForeName>Xiaohui</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8146-6707</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Second Clinical Medical College, Guangzhou University of Chinese Medicine, Guangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhan</LastName><ForeName>Yingshi</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Second Clinical Medical College, Guangzhou University of Chinese Medicine, Guangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Biying</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Guangdong Provincial Hospital of Chinese Medicine, Guangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Du</LastName><ForeName>Baoxin</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Guangdong Provincial Hospital of Chinese Medicine, Guangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Jingyan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Guangdong Provincial Hospital of Chinese Medicine, Guangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Medicine (Baltimore)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>2985248R</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0025-7974</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 2.7.1.-</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D019869">Phosphatidylinositol 3-Kinases</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012661" MajorTopicYN="Y">Semen</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000091484" MajorTopicYN="N">Network Pharmacology</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D062105" MajorTopicYN="N">Molecular Docking Simulation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019869" MajorTopicYN="N">Phosphatidylinositol 3-Kinases</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors have no conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37682161</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10489316</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000035101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005792-202309080-00039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Hardiman O, Al-Chalabi A, Chio A, et al. . Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat Rev Dis Primers. 2017;3:17071.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28980624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiskinis E, Sandoe J, Williams LA, et al. . Pathways disrupted in human ALS motor neurons identified through genetic correction of mutant SOD1. Cell Stem Cell. 2014;14:781&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4653065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24704492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Chalabi A, Hardiman O. The epidemiology of ALS: a conspiracy of genes, environment and time. Nat Rev Neurol. 2013;9:617&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24126629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor JP, Brown RH, Cleveland DW. Decoding ALS: from genes to mechanism. Nature. 2016;539:197&#x2013;206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5585017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27830784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Limin C, Qingqi Z, Changlin Q. Clinical medication experience of professor QIU Changlin in treating amyotrophic lateral sclerosis by identifying tongue manifestation. China Mod Doctor. 2017;55:4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liping Z, Yu W, Changlin Q. QIU Chang-lin treatment experience of motor neuron disease. Chin Arch Tradit Chin Med. 2011;29:3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang A, Li X, Ren Z, et al. . Clinical efficacy of spleen-invigorating and lung-replenishing therapy for patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. World Chin Med. 2017;12:4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baoxian XIE, Wenzhao T, Xiaojing W. Research progress on chemical constituents and pharmacological effects of Strychnos nux-vomica. J Pharm Res. 2014;33:603&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu W, Tang X, Fan C, et al. . Chemical constituents, pharmacological action, antitumor application, and toxicity of strychnine semen from Strychnons pierriana A.W. Hill.: a review. J Ethnopharmacol. 2023;317:116748.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37348797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saini YI, Wenjiao Z, Liangyuan L, et al. . The inhibition of loganin on microglia activation. Shandong Sci. 2021;34:8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maclean M, Juranek J, Cuddapah S, et al. . Microglia RAGE exacerbates the progression of neurodegeneration within the SOD1(G93A) murine model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in a sex-dependent manner. J Neuroinflamm. 2021;18:139.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8207569</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34130712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossi S, Cozzolino M. Dysfunction of RNA/RNA-binding proteins in ALS astrocytes and microglia. Cells. 2021;10:3005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8616248</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34831228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J, Wang F. Role of Neuroinflammation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: cellular mechanisms and therapeutic implications. Front Immunol. 2017;8:1005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5567007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28871262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z-Y, Wang X, Zhang D-Y, et al. . Traditional Chinese medicine network pharmacology: development in new era under guidance of network pharmacology evaluation method guidance. China J Chin Mater Med. 2022;47:7&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35178906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins AL. Network pharmacology. Nat Biotechnol. 2007;25:1110&#x2013;1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17921993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ru J, Li P, Wang J, et al. . TCMSP: a database of systems pharmacology for drug discovery from herbal medicines. J Cheminf. 2014;6:13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4001360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24735618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang S, Dong L, Liu L, et al. . HERB: a high-throughput experiment- and reference-guided database of traditional Chinese medicine. Nucleic Acids Res. 2021;49:D1197&#x2013;206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7779036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33264402</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu H-Y, Zhang Y-Q, Liu Z-M, et al. . ETCM: an encyclopaedia of traditional Chinese medicine. Nucleic Acids Res. 2019;47:D976&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6323948</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30365030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Z, Guo F, Wang Y, et al. . BATMAN-TCM: a bioinformatics analysis tool for molecular mechANism of traditional Chinese medicine. Sci Rep. 2016;6:21146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4754750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26879404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu X, Zhang W, Huang C, et al. . A novel chemometric method for the prediction of human oral bioavailability. Int J Mol Sci. 2012;13:6964&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3397506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22837674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X, Shen Y, Wang S, et al. . PharmMapper 2017 update: a web server for potential drug target identification with a comprehensive target pharmacophore database. Nucleic Acids Res. 2017;45:W356&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5793840</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28472422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stelzer G, Rosen N, Plaschkes I, et al. . The GeneCards suite: from gene data mining to disease genome sequence analyses. Curr Protoc Bioinformatics. 2016;54:1.30.1&#x2013;1.30.33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27322403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wishart DS, Feunang YD, Guo AC, et al. . DrugBank 5.0: a major update to the DrugBank database for 2018. Nucleic Acids Res. 2017;46:D1074&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5753335</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29126136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pi&#xf1;ero J, Bravo A, Queralt-Rosinach N, et al. . DisGeNET: a comprehensive platform integrating information on human disease-associated genes and variants. Nucleic Acids Res. 2017;45:D833&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5210640</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27924018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amberger JS, Bocchini CA, Schiettecatte F, et al. . OMIM.org: Online Mendelian Inheritance in Man (OMIM&#xae;), an online catalog of human genes and genetic disorders. Nucleic Acids Res. 2015;43:D789&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4383985</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25428349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Y, Zhang Y, Lian X, et al. . Therapeutic target database update 2022: facilitating drug discovery with enriched comparative data of targeted agents. Nucleic Acids Res. 2022;50:D1398&#x2013;407.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8728281</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34718717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clough E, Barrett T. The gene expression omnibus database. Methods Mol Biol. 2016;1418:93&#x2013;110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4944384</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27008011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shannon P, Markiel A, Ozier O, et al. . Cytoscape: a software environment for integrated models of biomolecular interaction networks. Genome Res. 2003;13:2498&#x2013;504.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC403769</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14597658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Missiuro PV, Liu K, Zou L, et al. . Information flow analysis of interactome networks. PLoS Comput Biol. 2009;5:e1000350.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2685719</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19503817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raman K, Damaraju N, Joshi GK. The organisational structure of protein networks: revisiting the centrality-lethality hypothesis. Syst Synth Biol. 2014;8:73&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3933631</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24592293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhuang Z, Lin T, Luo L, et al. . Exploring the mechanism of aidi injection for lung cancer by network pharmacology approach and molecular docking validation. Biosci Rep. 2021;41:BSR20204062.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7881165</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33506873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szklarczyk D, Gable AL, Nastou KC, et al. . The STRING database in 2021: customizable protein-protein networks, and functional characterization of user-uploaded gene/measurement sets. Nucleic Acids Res. 2021;49:D605&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7779004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33237311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szklarczyk D, Gable AL, Lyon D, et al. . STRING v11: protein-protein association networks with increased coverage, supporting functional discovery in genome-wide experimental datasets. Nucleic Acids Res. 2019;47:D607&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6323986</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30476243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song W, Ni S, Fu Y, et al. . Uncovering the mechanism of Maxing Ganshi Decoction on asthma from a systematic perspective: a network pharmacology study. Sci Rep. 2018;8:17362.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6255815</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30478434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bader GD, Hogue CWV. An automated method for finding molecular complexes in large protein interaction networks. BMC Bioinf. 2003;4:2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC149346</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12525261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Y, Zhou B, Pache L, et al. . Metascape provides a biologist-oriented resource for the analysis of systems-level datasets. Nat Commun. 2019;10:1523.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6447622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30944313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang DW, Sherman BT, Lempicki RA. Systematic and integrative analysis of large gene lists using DAVID bioinformatics resources. Nat Protocols. 2009;4:44&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19131956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanehisa M, Furumichi M, Tanabe M, et al. . KEGG: new perspectives on genomes, pathways, diseases and drugs. Nucleic Acids Res. 2017;45:D353&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5210567</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27899662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen G, Seukep AJ, Guo M. Recent advances in molecular docking for the research and discovery of potential marine drugs. Mar Drugs. 2020;18:545.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7692358</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33143025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burley SK, Bhikadiya C, Bi C, et al. . RCSB protein data bank: powerful new tools for exploring 3D structures of biological macromolecules for basic and applied research and education in fundamental biology, biomedicine, biotechnology, bioengineering and energy sciences. Nucleic Acids Res. 2021;49:D437&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7779003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33211854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morris GM, Huey R, Lindstrom W, et al. . AutoDock4 and AutoDockTools4: automated docking with selective receptor flexibility. J Comput Chem. 2009;30:2785&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2760638</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19399780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Q, Li B, Tang J, et al. . Consistent gene signature of schizophrenia identified by a novel feature selection strategy from comprehensive sets of transcriptomic data. Brief Bioinform. 2020;21:1058&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31157371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ridley AJ, Paterson HF, Johnston CL, et al. . The small GTP-binding protein rac regulates growth factor-induced membrane ruffling. Cell. 1992;70:401&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1643658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reijnders M RF, Ansor NM, Kousi M, et al. . RAC1 missense mutations in developmental disorders with diverse phenotypes. Am J Hum Genet. 2017;101:466&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5591022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28886345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mansour HM, Fawzy HM, El-Khatib AS, et al. . Potential repositioning of anti-cancer EGFR inhibitors in Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease: current perspectives and challenging prospects. Neuroscience. 2021;469:191&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34139302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tavassoly O, Sato T, Tavassoly I. Inhibition of brain epidermal growth factor receptor activation: a novel target in neurodegenerative diseases and brain injuries. Mol Pharmacol. 2020;98:13&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32350120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen K, Liu J, Liu S, et al. . Methyltransferase SETD2-mediated methylation of STAT1 is critical for interferon antiviral activity. Cell. 2017;170:492&#x2013;506.e14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28753426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Mao D, Roswit WT, et al. . PARP9-DTX3L ubiquitin ligase targets host histone H2BJ and viral 3C protease to enhance interferon signaling and control viral infection. Nat Immunol. 2015;16:1215&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4653074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26479788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei Y, Huang X, Ma Y, et al. . FOXC1-mediated TRIM22 regulates the excessive proliferation and inflammation of fibroblast-like synoviocytes in rheumatoid arthritis via NF-&#x3ba;B signaling pathway. Mol Med Rep. 2022;26:304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9434987</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35946462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilks A, Black SM, Miller WL, et al. . Expression and characterization of truncated human heme oxygenase (hHO-1) and a fusion protein of hHO-1 with human cytochrome P450 reductase. Biochemistry. 1995;34:4421&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7703255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y, Cao B, Ou R, et al. . Determining the Effect of the HNMT, STK39, and NMD3 polymorphisms on the incidence of Parkinson&#x2019;s disease, amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, and multiple system atrophy in Chinese populations. J Mol Neurosci. 2018;64:574&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29564728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu L, Huang R, Wu Y, et al. . Brucine: a review of phytochemistry, pharmacology, and toxicology. Front Pharmacol. 2020;11:377.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7145893</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32308621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Imamura K, Izumi Y, Watanabe A, et al. . The Src/c-Abl pathway is a potential therapeutic target in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Sci Transl Med. 2017;9:eaaf3962.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28539470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Imamura K, Izumi Y, Banno H, et al. . Induced pluripotent stem cell-based Drug Repurposing for Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis Medicine (iDReAM) study: protocol for a phase I dose escalation study of bosutinib for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. BMJ Open. 2019;9:e033131&#x2013;31-e.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7003406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31796494</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Oliveira G P, Maximino JR, Maschietto M, et al. . Early gene expression changes in skeletal muscle from SOD1(G93A) amyotrophic lateral sclerosis animal model. Cell Mol Neurobiol. 2014;34:451&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24442855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xf6;nnstrand L. Signal transduction via the stem cell factor receptor/c-Kit. Cell Mol Life Sci. 2004;61:2535&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15526160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heron-Milhavet L, Khouya N, Fernandez A, et al. . Akt1 and Akt2: differentiating the aktion. Histol Histopathol. 2011;26:651&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21432781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koh SH, Roh H, Sang ML, et al. . Phosphatidylinositol 3-kinase activator reduces motor neuronal cell death induced by G93A or A4V mutant SOD1 gene. Toxicology. 2005;213:45&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15996807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romano N, Catalani A, Lattante S, et al. . ALS skin fibroblasts reveal oxidative stress and ERK1/2-mediated cytoplasmic localization of TDP-43. Cell Signal. 2020;70:109591.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32126264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hung S-T, Linares GR, Chang W-H, et al. . PIKFYVE inhibition mitigates disease in models of diverse forms of ALS. Cell. 2023;186:786&#x2013;802.e28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10062012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36754049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skaper SD. The neurotrophin family of neurotrophic factors: an overview. Methods Mol Biol. 2012;846:1&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22367796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L, Zhang P, Wang G, et al. . Ras and rap signal bidirectional synaptic plasticity via distinct subcellular microdomains. Neuron. 2018;98:783&#x2013;800.e4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6192044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29706584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaur A, Sharma S. Mammalian target of rapamycin (mTOR) as a potential therapeutic target in various diseases. Inflammopharmacology. 2017;25:293&#x2013;312.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28417246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saxton RA, Sabatini DM. mTOR signaling in growth, metabolism, and disease. Cell. 2017;168:960&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5394987</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28283069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanoue T, Nishida E. Docking interactions in the mitogen-activated protein kinase cascades. Pharmacol Ther. 2002;93:193&#x2013;202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12191611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Z, Yao X, Jiang W, et al. . Advanced oxidation protein products induce microglia-mediated neuroinflammation via MAPKs-NF-&#x3ba;B signaling pathway and pyroptosis after secondary spinal cord injury. J Neuroinflamm. 2020;17:90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7082940</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32192500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J-L, Ren C-H, Feng J, et al. . Oleanolic acid inhibits mouse spinal cord injury through suppressing inflammation and apoptosis via the blockage of p38 and JNK MAPKs. Biomed Pharmacother. 2020;123:109752.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31924596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sahana TG, Zhang K. Mitogen-activated protein kinase pathway in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Biomedicines. 2021;9:969.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8394856</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34440173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhan L, Xie Q, Tibbetts RS. Opposing roles of p38 and JNK in a Drosophila model of TDP-43 proteinopathy reveal oxidative stress and innate immunity as pathogenic components of neurodegeneration. Hum Mol Genet. 2015;24:757&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4291250</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25281658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>