<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37696099</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>18</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2213-1582</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>39</Volume><PubDate><Year>2023</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>NeuroImage. Clinical</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Neuroimage Clin</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Structural and microstructural neuroimaging signature of C9orf72-associated ALS: A multiparametric MRI study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>103505</StartPage><MedlinePgn>103505</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">103505</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.nicl.2023.103505</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S2213-1582(23)00196-1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">ALS patients with hexanucleotide expansion in C9orf72 are characterized by a specific clinical phenotype, including more aggressive disease course and cognitive decline. Computerized multiparametric MRI with gray matter volumetry and diffusion tensor imaging (DTI) to analyze white matter structural connectivity is a potential in vivo biomarker.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">The objective of this study was to develop a multiparametric MRI signature in a large cohort of ALS patients with C9orf72 mutations. The aim was to investigate how morphological features of C9orf72-associated ALS differ in structural MRI and DTI compared to healthy controls and ALS patients without C9orf72 mutations.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Atlas-based volumetry (ABV) and whole brain-based DTI-based analyses were performed in a cohort of n&#xa0;=&#xa0;51 ALS patients with C9orf72 mutations and compared with both n&#xa0;=&#xa0;51 matched healthy controls and n&#xa0;=&#xa0;51 C9orf72 negative ALS patients, respectively. Subsequently, Spearman correlation analysis of C9orf72 ALS patients' data with clinical parameters (age of onset, sex, ALS-FRS-R, progression rate, survival) as well as ECAS and p-NfH in CSF was performed.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">The whole brain voxel-by-voxel comparison of fractional anisotropy (FA) maps between C9orf72 ALS patients and controls showed significant bilateral alterations in axonal structures of the white matter at group level, primarily along the corticospinal tracts and in fibers projecting to the frontal lobes. For the frontal lobes, these alterations were also significant between C9orf72 positive and C9orf72 negative ALS patients. In ABV, patients with C9orf72 mutations showed lower volumes of the frontal, temporal, and parietal lobe, with the lowest values in the gray matter of the superior frontal and the precentral gyrus, but also in hippocampi and amygdala. Compared to C9orf72 negative ALS, the differences were shown to be significant for cerebral gray matter (p&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.04), especially in the frontal (p&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.01) and parietal lobe (p&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.01), and in the thalamus (p&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.004). A correlation analysis between ECAS and averaged regional FA values revealed significant correlations between cognitive performance in ECAS and frontal association fibers. Lower FA values in the frontal lobes were associated with worse performance in all cognitive domains measured (language, verbal fluency, executive functions, memory and spatial perception). In addition, there were significant negative correlations between age of onset and atlas-based volumetry results for gray matter.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">This study demonstrates a distinct pattern of DTI alterations of the white matter and ubiquitous volume reductions of the gray matter early in the disease course of C9orf72-associated ALS. Alterations were closely linked to a more aggressive cognitive phenotype. These results are in line with an expected pTDP43 propagation pattern of cortical affection and thus strengthen the hypothesis that an underlying developmental disorder is present in ALS with C9orf72 expansions. Thus, multiparametric MRI could contribute to the assessment of the disease as an in vivo biomarker even in the early phase of the disease.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 The Authors. Published by Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wiesenfarth</LastName><ForeName>Maximilian</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University Hospital Ulm, Ulm, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huppertz</LastName><ForeName>Hans-J&#xfc;rgen</ForeName><Initials>HJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Swiss Epilepsy Clinic, Klinik Lengg, Z&#xfc;rich, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dorst</LastName><ForeName>Johannes</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University Hospital Ulm, Ulm, Germany; German Centre of Neurodegenerative Diseases (DZNE), Ulm, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lul&#xe9;</LastName><ForeName>Doroth&#xe9;e</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University Hospital Ulm, Ulm, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ludolph</LastName><ForeName>Albert C</ForeName><Initials>AC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University Hospital Ulm, Ulm, Germany; German Centre of Neurodegenerative Diseases (DZNE), Ulm, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>M&#xfc;ller</LastName><ForeName>Hans-Peter</ForeName><Initials>HP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University Hospital Ulm, Ulm, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kassubek</LastName><ForeName>Jan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University Hospital Ulm, Ulm, Germany; German Centre of Neurodegenerative Diseases (DZNE), Ulm, Germany. Electronic address: jan.kassubek@uni-ulm.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Neuroimage Clin</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101597070</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2213-1582</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000073885">C9orf72 Protein</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C568651">C9orf72 protein, human</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000081364" MajorTopicYN="Y">Multiparametric Magnetic Resonance Imaging</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D056324" MajorTopicYN="N">Diffusion Tensor Imaging</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000073885" MajorTopicYN="N">C9orf72 Protein</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D059906" MajorTopicYN="N">Neuroimaging</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Atlas-based volumetry</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">C9orf72 expansion</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Diffusion tensor imaging</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Magnetic resonance imaging</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Motor neuron disease</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of Competing Interest The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37696099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10500452</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nicl.2023.103505</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2213-1582(23)00196-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abrahams S., Newton J., Niven E., Foley J., Bak T.H. Screening for cognition and behaviour changes in ALS. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2014;15(1&#x2013;2):9&#x2013;14. doi: 10.3109/21678421.2013.805784.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/21678421.2013.805784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23781974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agosta F., Ferraro P.M., Riva N., Spinelli E.G., Domi T., Carrera P., Copetti M., Falzone Y., Ferrari M., Lunetta C., Comi G., Falini A., Quattrini A., Filippi M. Structural and functional brain signatures of C9orf72 in motor neuron disease. Neurobiol. Aging. 2017;57:206&#x2013;219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28666709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balendra R., Isaacs A.M. C9orf72-mediated ALS and FTD: multiple pathways to disease. Nat. Rev. Neurol. 2018;14(9):544&#x2013;558. doi: 10.1038/s41582-018-0047-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41582-018-0047-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6417666</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30120348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bede P., Bokde A.L.W., Byrne S., Elamin M., McLaughlin R.L., Kenna K., Fagan A.J., Pender N., Bradley D.G., Hardiman O. Multiparametric MRI study of ALS stratified for the C9orf72 genotype. Neurology. 2013;81(4):361&#x2013;369.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3772833</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23771489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bede P., Omer T., Finegan E., Chipika R.H., Iyer P.M., Doherty M.A., Vajda A., Pender N., McLaughlin R.L., Hutchinson S., Hardiman O. Connectivity-based characterisation of subcortical grey matter pathology in frontotemporal dementia and ALS: a multimodal neuroimaging study. Brain Imaging Behav. 2018;12(6):1696&#x2013;1707.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29423814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bede P., Lul&#xe9; D., M&#xfc;ller H.-P., Tan E.L., Dorst J., Ludolph A.C., Kassubek J. Presymptomatic grey matter alterations in ALS kindreds: a computational neuroimaging study of asymptomatic C9orf72 and SOD1 mutation carriers. J. Neurol. 2023;270(9):4235&#x2013;4247.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10421803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37178170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benatar M., Zhang L., Wang L., Granit V., Statland J., Barohn R., Swenson A., Ravits J., Jackson C., Burns T.M., Trivedi J., Pioro E.P., Caress J., Katz J., McCauley J.L., Rademakers R., Malaspina A., Ostrow L.W., Wuu J. Validation of serum neurofilaments as prognostic and potential pharmacodynamic biomarkers for ALS. Neurology. 2020;95(1):e59&#x2013;e69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7371380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32385188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bertrand A., Wen J., Rinaldi D., Houot M., Sayah S., Camuzat A., Fournier C., Fontanella S., Routier A., Couratier P., Pasquier F., Habert M.-O., Hannequin D., Martinaud O., Caroppo P., Levy R., Dubois B., Brice A., Durrleman S., Colliot O., Le Ber I. Early Cognitive, Structural, and Microstructural Changes in Presymptomatic C9orf72 Carriers Younger Than 40 Years. JAMA Neurol. 2018;75(2):236.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5838615</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29197216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bocchetta M., Gordon E., Cardoso M.J., et al. Thalamic atrophy in frontotemporal dementia - Not just a C9orf72 problem. Neuroimage Clin. 2018;18:675&#x2013;681. doi: 10.1016/j.nicl.2018.02.019. Published 2018 Feb 23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nicl.2018.02.019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5988457</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29876259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braak H., Brettschneider J., Ludolph A.C., Lee V.M., Trojanowski J.Q., Del Tredici K. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis&#x2013;a model of corticofugal axonal spread. Nat. Rev. Neurol. 2013;9(12):708&#x2013;714. doi: 10.1038/nrneurol.2013.221.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrneurol.2013.221</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3943211</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24217521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brenner D., Freischmidt A. Update on genetics of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Curr. Opin. Neurol. 2022;35(5):672&#x2013;677. doi: 10.1097/WCO.0000000000001093.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/WCO.0000000000001093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35942673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brettschneider J., Del Tredici K., Toledo J.B., Robinson J.L., Irwin D.J., Grossman M., Suh EunRan, Van Deerlin V.M., Wood E.M., Baek Y., Kwong L., Lee E.B., Elman L., McCluskey L., Fang L., Feldengut S., Ludolph A.C., Lee V.-Y., Braak H., Trojanowski J.Q. Stages of pTDP-43 pathology in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann. Neurol. 2013;74(1):20&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3785076</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23686809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brettschneider J., Del Tredici K., Lee V.M., Trojanowski J.Q. Spreading of pathology in neurodegenerative diseases: a focus on human studies. Nat. Rev. Neurosci. 2015;16(2):109&#x2013;120. doi: 10.1038/nrn3887.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrn3887</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4312418</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25588378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byrne S., Elamin M., Bede P., Shatunov A., Walsh C., Corr B., Heverin M., Jordan N., Kenna K., Lynch C., McLaughlin R.L., Iyer P.M., O'Brien C., Phukan J., Wynne B., Bokde A.L., Bradley D.G., Pender N., Al-Chalabi A., Hardiman O. Cognitive and clinical characteristics of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis carrying a C9orf72 repeat expansion: a population-based cohort study. Lancet Neurol. 2012;11(3):232&#x2013;240.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3315021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22305801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cedarbaum J.M., Stambler N., Malta E., Fuller C., Hilt D., Thurmond B., Nakanishi A. The ALSFRS-R: a revised ALS functional rating scale that incorporates assessments of respiratory function. BDNF ALS Study Group (Phase III) J. Neurol. Sci. 1999;169(1-2):13&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10540002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chipika R.H., Siah W.F., Shing S.L.H., Finegan E., McKenna M.C., Christidi F., Chang K.M., Karavasilis E., Vajda A., Hengeveld J.C., Doherty M.A., Donaghy C., Hutchinson S., McLaughlin R.L., Hardiman O., Bede P. MRI data confirm the selective involvement of thalamic and amygdalar nuclei in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and primary lateral sclerosis. Data Brief. 2020;32:106246.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7481815</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32944601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cistaro A., Pagani M., Montuschi A., Calvo A., Moglia C., Canosa A., Restagno G., Brunetti M., Traynor B.J., Nobili F., Carrara G., Fania P., Lopiano L., Valentini M.C., Chi&#xf2; A. The metabolic signature of C9orf72-related ALS: FDG PET comparison with nonmutated patients. Eur. J. Nucl. Med. Mol. Imaging. 2014;41(5):844&#x2013;852.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8957062</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24445987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crespi C., Dodich A., Cappa S.F., Canessa N., Iannaccone S., Corbo M., Lunetta C., Falini A., Cerami C. Multimodal MRI quantification of the common neurostructural bases within the FTD-ALS continuum. Neurobiol. Aging. 2018;62:95&#x2013;104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29131982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Vocht J., Van Weehaeghe D., Ombelet F., et al. Differences in Cerebral Glucose Metabolism in ALS Patients with and without C9orf72 and SOD1 Mutations. Cells. 2023;12(6):933. doi: 10.3390/cells12060933.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/cells12060933</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10047407</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36980274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeJesus-Hernandez M., Mackenzie I., Boeve B., Boxer A., Baker M., Rutherford N., Nicholson A., Finch NiColeA., Flynn H., Adamson J., Kouri N., Wojtas A., Sengdy P., Hsiung G.-Y., Karydas A., Seeley W., Josephs K., Coppola G., Geschwind D., Wszolek Z., Feldman H., Knopman D., Petersen R., Miller B., Dickson D., Boylan K., Graff-Radford N., Rademakers R. Expanded GGGGCC hexanucleotide repeat in noncoding region of C9ORF72 causes chromosome 9p-linked FTD and ALS. Neuron. 2011;72(2):245&#x2013;256.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3202986</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21944778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dreger M., Steinbach R., Otto M., Turner M.R., Grosskreutz J. Cerebrospinal fluid biomarkers of disease activity and progression in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J. Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatry. 2022;93(4):422&#x2013;435. doi: 10.1136/jnnp-2021-327503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp-2021-327503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8921583</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35105727</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feldman E.L., Goutman S.A., Petri S., Mazzini L., Savelieff M.G., Shaw P.J., Sobue G. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet. 2022;400(10360):1363&#x2013;1380.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10089700</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36116464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Floeter M.K., Gendron T.F. Biomarkers for Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis and Frontotemporal Dementia Associated With Hexanucleotide Expansion Mutations in C9orf72. Front. Neurol. 2018;9:1063. doi: 10.3389/fneur.2018.01063.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fneur.2018.01063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6289985</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30568632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frings L., Mader I., Landwehrmeyer B.G., Weiller C., H&#xfc;ll M., Huppertz H.J. Quantifying change in individual subjects affected by frontotemporal lobar degeneration using automated longitudinal MRI volumetry. Hum. Brain Mapp. 2012;33(7):1526&#x2013;1535. doi: 10.1002/hbm.21304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hbm.21304</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6869947</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21618662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gagliardi D., Faravelli I., Meneri M., Saccomanno D., Govoni A., Magri F., Ricci G., Siciliano G., Pietro Comi G., Corti S. Diagnostic and prognostic value of CSF neurofilaments in a cohort of patients with motor neuron disease: A cross-sectional study. J. Cell Mol. Med. 2021;25(8):3765&#x2013;3771.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8051694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33609080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gendron T.F., Daughrity L.M., Heckman M.G., Diehl N.N., Wuu J., Miller T.M., Pastor P., Trojanowski J.Q., Grossman M., Berry J.D., Hu W.T., Ratti A., Benatar M., Silani V., Glass J.D., Floeter M.K., Jeromin A., Boylan K.B., Petrucelli L. Phosphorylated neurofilament heavy chain: A biomarker of survival for C9ORF72-associated amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann. Neurol. 2017;82(1):139&#x2013;146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5676468</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28628244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe4;kkinen S., Chu S.A., Lee S.E. Neuroimaging in genetic frontotemporal dementia and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurobiol. Dis. 2020;145 doi: 10.1016/j.nbd.2020.105063.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nbd.2020.105063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7572920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32890771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xf6;glinger G.U., Huppertz H.-J., Wagenpfeil S., Andr&#xe9;s M.V., Belloch V., Le&#xf3;n T., del Ser T. Tideglusib reduces progression of brain atrophy in progressive supranuclear palsy in a randomized trial. Mov. Disord. 2014;29(4):479&#x2013;487.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24488721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xfc;bers A., Marroquin N., Schmoll B., Vielhaber S., Just M., Mayer B., H&#xf6;gel J., Dorst J., Mertens T., Just W., Aulitzky A., Wais V., Ludolph A.C., Kubisch C., Weishaupt J.H., Volk A.E. Polymerase chain reaction and Southern blot-based analysis of the C9orf72 hexanucleotide repeat in different motor neuron diseases. Neurobiol. Aging. 2014;35(5):1214.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24378086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huppertz H.-J., M&#xf6;ller L., S&#xfc;dmeyer M., Hilker R., Hattingen E., Egger K., Amtage F., Respondek G., Stamelou M., Schnitzler A., Pinkhardt E.H., Oertel W.H., Knake S., Kassubek J., H&#xf6;glinger G.U. Differentiation of neurodegenerative parkinsonian syndromes by volumetric magnetic resonance imaging analysis and support vector machine classification. Mov. Disord. 2016;31(10):1506&#x2013;1517.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27452874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalra S., M&#xfc;ller H.-P., Ishaque A., Zinman L., Korngut L., Genge A., Beaulieu C., Frayne R., Graham S.J., Kassubek J. A prospective harmonized multicenter DTI study of cerebral white matter degeneration in ALS. Neurology. 2020;95(8):e943&#x2013;e952.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7668555</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32646955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kassubek J., Pinkhardt E.H., Dietmaier A., Ludolph A.C., Landwehrmeyer G.B., Huppertz H.J. Fully automated atlas-based MR imaging volumetry in Huntington disease, compared with manual volumetry. AJNR Am. J. Neuroradiol. 2011;32(7):1328&#x2013;1332. doi: 10.3174/ajnr.A2514.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3174/ajnr.A2514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7966058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21680653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kassubek J., M&#xfc;ller H.-P., Del Tredici K., Lul&#xe9; D., Gorges M., Braak H., Ludolph A.C. Imaging the pathoanatomy of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in vivo: targeting a propagation-based biological marker. J. Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatry. 2018;89(4):374&#x2013;381.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5869447</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29101254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khalil M., Teunissen C.E., Otto M., Piehl F., Sormani M.P., Gattringer T., Barro C., Kappos L., Comabella M., Fazekas F., Petzold A., Blennow K., Zetterberg H., Kuhle J. Neurofilaments as biomarkers in neurological disorders. Nat. Rev. Neurol. 2018;14(10):577&#x2013;589.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30171200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le Blanc G., Jett&#xe9; Pomerleau V., McCarthy J., et al. Faster Cortical Thinning and Surface Area Loss in Presymptomatic and Symptomatic C9orf72 Repeat Expansion Adult Carriers. Ann. Neurol. 2020;88(1):113&#x2013;122. doi: 10.1002/ana.25748.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.25748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32285980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee SE, Sias AC, Mandelli ML, et al. Network degeneration and dysfunction in presymptomatic&#xa0;C9ORF72&#xa0;expansion carriers.&#xa0;Neuroimage Clin. 2017;14:286-297. Published 2016 Dec 10. 10.1016/j.nicl.2016.12.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5349617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28337409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee E.B., Lee V.-Y., Trojanowski J.Q. Gains or losses: molecular mechanisms of TDP43-mediated neurodegeneration. Nat. Rev. Neurosci. 2011;13(1):38&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3285250</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22127299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Hi Shing S., McKenna M.C., Siah W.F., Chipika R.H., Hardiman O., Bede P. The imaging signature of C9orf72 hexanucleotide repeat expansions: implications for clinical trials and therapy development. Brain Imaging Behav. 2021;15(5):2693&#x2013;2719. doi: 10.1007/s11682-020-00429-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11682-020-00429-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33398779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loose M., Burkhardt C., Aho-&#xd6;zhan H., Keller J., Abdulla S., B&#xf6;hm S., Kollewe K., Uttner I., Abrahams S., Petri S., Weber M., Ludolph A.C., Lul&#xe9; D. Age and education-matched cut-off scores for the revised German/Swiss-German version of ECAS. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2016;17(5-6):374&#x2013;376.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27027323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ludolph A., Drory V., Hardiman O., Nakano I., Ravits J., Robberecht W., Shefner J. A revision of the El Escorial criteria - 2015. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2015;16(5-6):291&#x2013;292.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26121170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lul&#xe9; D., Burkhardt C., Abdulla S., B&#xf6;hm S., Kollewe K., Uttner I., Abrahams S., Bak T.H., Petri S., Weber M., Ludolph A.C. The Edinburgh Cognitive and Behavioural Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Screen: a cross-sectional comparison of established screening tools in a German-Swiss population. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2015;16(1-2):16&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25292386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lul&#xe9; D., B&#xf6;hm S., M&#xfc;ller H.-P., Aho-&#xd6;zhan H., Keller J., Gorges M., Loose M., Weishaupt J.H., Uttner I., Pinkhardt E., Kassubek J., Del Tredici K., Braak H., Abrahams S., Ludolph A.C. Cognitive phenotypes of sequential staging in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Cortex. 2018;101:163&#x2013;171.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29477906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lul&#xe9; D.E., M&#xfc;ller H.P., Finsel J., et al. Deficits in verbal fluency in presymptomatic C9orf72 mutation gene carriers-a developmental disorder. J. Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatry. 2020;91(11):1195&#x2013;1200. doi: 10.1136/jnnp-2020-323671.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp-2020-323671</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7569387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32855285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Machts J., Loewe K., Kaufmann J., Jakubiczka S., Abdulla S., Petri S., Dengler R., Heinze H.-J., Vielhaber S., Schoenfeld M.A., Bede P. Basal ganglia pathology in ALS is associated with neuropsychological deficits. Neurology. 2015;85(15):1301&#x2013;1309.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26385880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandrioli J., Zucchi E., Martinelli I., Van der Most L., Gianferrari G., Moglia C., Manera U., Solero L., Vasta R., Canosa A., Grassano M., Brunetti M., Mazzini L., De Marchi F., Simonini C., Fini N., Tupler R., Vinceti M., Chi&#xf2; A., Calvo A. Factors predicting disease progression in C9ORF72 ALS patients. J. Neurol. 2022;270(2):877&#x2013;890.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36280624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masrori P., Van Damme P. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a clinical review. Eur. J. Neurol. 2020;27(10):1918&#x2013;1929. doi: 10.1111/ene.14393.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ene.14393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7540334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32526057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller T.M., Cudkowicz M.E., Genge A., et al. Trial of Antisense Oligonucleotide Tofersen for SOD1 ALS. New Engl. J. Med. 2022;387(12):1099&#x2013;1110. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa2204705.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2204705</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36129998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller K., Brenner D., Weydt P., Meyer T., Grehl T., Petri S., Grosskreutz J., Schuster J., Volk A.E., Borck G., Kubisch C., Klopstock T., Zeller D., Jablonka S., Sendtner M., Klebe S., Knehr A., G&#xfc;nther K., Weis J., Claeys K.G., Schrank B., Sperfeld A.-D., H&#xfc;bers A., Otto M., Dorst J., Meitinger T., Strom T.M., Andersen P.M., Ludolph A.C., Weishaupt J.H. Comprehensive analysis of the mutation spectrum in 301 German ALS families. J. Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatry. 2018;89(8):817&#x2013;827.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29650794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller H.-P., Del Tredici K., Lul&#xe9; D., M&#xfc;ller K., Weishaupt J.H., Ludolph A.C., Kassubek J. In vivo histopathological staging in C9orf72-associated ALS: A tract of interest DTI study. Neuroimage Clin. 2020;27:102298.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7270604</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32505118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller H.P., Unrath A., Ludolph A.C., Kassubek J. Preservation of diffusion tensor properties during spatial normalization by use of tensor imaging and fibre tracking on a normal brain database. Phys. Med. Biol. 2007;52(6):N99&#x2013;N109. doi: 10.1088/0031-9155/52/6/N01.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/0031-9155/52/6/N01</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17327646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller H.P., Lul&#xe9; D., Roselli F., Behler A., Ludolph A.C., Kassubek J. Segmental involvement of the corpus callosum in C9orf72-associated ALS: a tract of interest-based DTI study. Ther Adv. Chronic Dis. 2021;12 doi: 10.1177/20406223211002969.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/20406223211002969</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7989124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33815737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nigri A., Umberto M., Stanziano M., Ferraro S., Fedeli D., Medina Carrion J.P., Palermo S., Lequio L., Denegri F., Agosta F., Filippi M., Valentini M.C., Canosa A., Calvo A., Chi&#xf2; A., Bruzzone M.G., Moglia C. C9orf72 ALS mutation carriers show extensive cortical and subcortical damage compared to matched wild-type ALS patients. Neuroimage Clin. 2023;38:103400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10130353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37068310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Omer T., Finegan E., Hutchinson S., Doherty M., Vajda A., McLaughlin R.L., Pender N., Hardiman O., Bede P. Neuroimaging patterns along the ALS-FTD spectrum: a multiparametric imaging study. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2017;18(7-8):611&#x2013;623.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28562080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Opfer R., Suppa P., Kepp T., Spies L., Schippling S., Huppertz H.-J. Atlas based brain volumetry: How to distinguish regional volume changes due to biological or physiological effects from inherent noise of the methodology. Magn. Reson. Imaging. 2016;34(4):455&#x2013;461.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26723849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rascovsky K., Hodges J.R., Knopman D., et al. Sensitivity of revised diagnostic criteria for the behavioural variant of frontotemporal dementia. Brain. 2011;134(Pt 9):2456&#x2013;2477. doi: 10.1093/brain/awr179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awr179</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3170532</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21810890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renton A.E., Majounie E., Waite A., et al. A hexanucleotide repeat expansion in C9ORF72 is the cause of chromosome 9p21-linked ALS-FTD. Neuron. 2011;72(2):257&#x2013;268. doi: 10.1016/j.neuron.2011.09.010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuron.2011.09.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3200438</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21944779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sch&#xf6;necker S., Neuhofer C., Otto M., et al. Atrophy in the Thalamus But Not Cerebellum Is Specific for C9orf72 FTD and ALS Patients - An Atlas-Based Volumetric MRI Study. Front. Aging Neurosci. 2018;10:45. doi: 10.3389/fnagi.2018.00045.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnagi.2018.00045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5863593</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29599716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steinacker P, Feneberg E, Weishaupt J, et al. Neurofilaments in the diagnosis of motoneuron diseases: a prospective study on 455 patients.&#xa0;J. Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatry. 2016;87(1):12-20. 10.1136/jnnp-2015-311387.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26296871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Umoh M.E., Fournier C., Li Y., et al. Comparative analysis of C9orf72 and sporadic disease in an ALS clinic population. Neurology. 2016;87(10):1024&#x2013;1030. doi: 10.1212/WNL.0000000000003067.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000003067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5027809</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27488601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Burgh H.K., Westeneng H.-J., Walhout R., van Veenhuijzen K., Tan H.H.G., Meier J.M., Bakker L.A., Hendrikse J., van Es M.A., Veldink J.H., van den Heuvel M.P., van den Berg L.H. Multimodal longitudinal study of structural brain involvement in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology. 2020;94(24):e2592&#x2013;e2604.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7455328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32414878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westeneng H.-J., Walhout R., Straathof M., Schmidt R., Hendrikse J., Veldink J.H., van den Heuvel M.P., van den Berg L.H. Widespread structural brain involvement in ALS is not limited to the C9orf72 repeat expansion. J. Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatry. 2016;87(12):1354&#x2013;1360.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5136726</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27756805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiesenfarth M, G&#xfc;nther K, M&#xfc;ller K, et al. Clinical and genetic features of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients with&#xa0;C9orf72&#xa0;mutations. Brain Commun. Brain Commun. 2023;5(2):fcad087. 10.1093/braincomms/fcad087.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10065188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37006326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeh T.-H., Liu H.-F., Li Y.-W., Lu C.-S., Shih H.-Y., Chiu C.-C., Lin S.-J., Huang Y.-C., Cheng Y.-C. C9orf72 is essential for neurodevelopment and motility mediated by Cyclin G1. Exp. Neurol. 2018;304:114&#x2013;124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29522758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>