<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37803257</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>09</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2288</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>23</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>06</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC medical research methodology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Med Res Methodol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Asynchronous online focus groups for research with people living with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and family caregivers: usefulness, acceptability and lessons learned.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>222</StartPage><MedlinePgn>222</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">222</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12874-023-02051-y</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">People with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) face disability- and travel-related barriers to research participation. We investigate the usefulness and acceptability of asynchronous, online focus groups (AOFGs) for research involving people affected by ALS (patients and family caregivers) and outline lessons learned.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">The ALS Talk Project, consisting of seven AOFGs and 100 participants affected by ALS, provided context for this investigation. Hosted on the secure itracks Board&#x2122; platform, participants interacted in a threaded web forum structure. Moderators posted weekly discussion questions and facilitated discussion. Data pertaining to methodology, participant interaction and experience, and moderator technique were analyzed using itracks and NVivo 12 analytics (quantitative) and conventional content analysis and the constant-comparative approach (qualitative).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">There was active engagement within groups, with post lengths averaging 111.48 words and a complex network of branching interactions between participants. One third of participant responses included individual reflections without further interaction. Participants affirmed their co-group members, offered practical advice, and discussed shared and differing perspectives. Moderators responded to all posts, indicating presence and probing answers. AOFGs facilitated qualitative and quantitative data-gathering and flexible response to unanticipated events. Although total participation fell below 50% after 10-12&#xa0;weeks, participants valued interacting with peers in an inclusive, confidential forum. Participants used a variety of personal devices, browsers, and operating systems when interacting on the online platform.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">This methodological examination of AOFGs for patient-centred investigations involving people affected by ALS demonstrates their usefulness and acceptability, and advances knowledge of online research methodologies. Lessons learned include: early identification of research goals and participant needs is critical to selecting an AOFG platform; although duration longer than 10-12&#xa0;weeks may be burdensome in this population, participants were positive about AOFGs; AOFGs offer real world flexibility enabling response to research challenges and opportunities; and, AOGFs can effectively foster safe spaces for sharing personal perspectives and discussing sensitive topics. With moderators playing an important role in fostering engagement, AOFGs facilitated rich data gathering and promoted reciprocity by fostering the exchange of ideas and interaction between peers. Findings may have implications for research involving other neurologically impaired and/or medically vulnerable populations.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023. BioMed Central Ltd., part of Springer Nature.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Genuis</LastName><ForeName>Shelagh K</ForeName><Initials>SK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Neurology, Department of Medicine, University of Alberta, 7-123 Clinical Sciences Building, Edmonton, AB, T6G 2B7, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Luth</LastName><ForeName>Westerly</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Neurology, Department of Medicine, University of Alberta, 7-123 Clinical Sciences Building, Edmonton, AB, T6G 2B7, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Weber</LastName><ForeName>Garnette</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>itracks, Saskatoon, SK, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bubela</LastName><ForeName>Tania</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health Sciences, Simon Fraser University, Blusson Hall 11328 8888 University Drive, Burnaby, BC, V5A 1S6, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Johnston</LastName><ForeName>Wendy S</ForeName><Initials>WS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Neurology, Department of Medicine, University of Alberta, 7-123 Clinical Sciences Building, Edmonton, AB, T6G 2B7, Canada. wendyj@ualberta.ca.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Med Res Methodol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100968545</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2288</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000690" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017028" MajorTopicYN="N">Caregivers</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017144" MajorTopicYN="N">Focus Groups</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014195" MajorTopicYN="N">Travel</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000076082" MajorTopicYN="N">Travel-Related Illness</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Family caregivers</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Online focus groups</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Patients</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Research design</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Research participation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>SKG, WL, TB, and WSJ declare that they have no competing interests. GW declares a competing financial interest as the CEO of itracks&#x2122;.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37803257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10557269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12874-023-02051-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12874-023-02051-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Davies L, LeClair KL, Bagley P, Blunt H, Hinton L, Ryan S, et al. Face-to-Face compared with online collected accounts of health and illness experiences: a scoping review. Qual. Health Res. 2020;1049732320935835.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32667257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skelton K, Evans R, LaChenaye J, Amsbary J, Wingate M, Talbott L. Utilization of online focus groups to include mothers: a use-case design, reflection, and recommendations. Digit Health. 2018;4:2055207618777675.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5999054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29942638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zwaanswijk M, van Dulmen S. Advantages of asynchronous online focus groups and face-to-face focus groups as perceived by child, adolescent and adult participants: a survey study. BMC Res Notes. 2014;7:756.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4213506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25341440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook K, Jack S, Siden H, Thabane L, Browne G. Innovations in research with medically fragile populations: using bulletin board focus groups. Qual Rep. 2014;19:1&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon AR, Calzo JP, Eiduson R, Sharp K, Silverstein S, Lopez E, et al. Asynchronous online focus groups for health research: case study and lessons learned. Int J Qual Methods. 2021;20:1609406921990489.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8856649</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35185443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tates K, Zwaanswijk M, Otten R, van Dulmen S, Hoogerbrugge PM, Kamps WA, et al. Online focus groups as a tool to collect data in hard-to-include populations: examples from paediatric oncology. BMC Med Res Methodol. 2009;9:15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2653071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19257883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caron J, Light J. &#x201c;My world has expanded even though I&#x2019;m stuck at home&#x201d;: experiences of individuals with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis who use augmentative and alternative communication and social media. Am J Speech Lang Pathol. 2015;24:680&#x2013;695.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26254447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higginbotham J, Fulcher K, Seale J. Time and timing in interactions involving individuals with ALS, their unimpaired partners and their speech generating devices. In: Smith M, Murray J, editors. The Silent Partner? Language, Interaction and Aided Communication. Buildford, Surrey: J&amp;R Press Ltd; 2016. 199&#x2013;227.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paterson HL. The use of social media by adults with acquired conditions who use AAC: current gaps and considerations in research. Augment Altern Commun. 2017;33:23&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28218009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lijadi AA, van Schalkwyk GJ. Online facebook focus group research of hard-to-reach participants. Int J Qual Methods. 2015;14:1609406915621383.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sintjago A, Link A. From synchronous to asynchronous: Researching online focus groups platforms. In: Duin AH, Anklesaria F, Nater EA, editors. Cultivating Change in the Academy: 50+ Stories from the Digital Frontlines at the University of Minnesota in 2012. Minneapolis, Minnesota: University of Minnesota; 2012. 170&#x2013;8. Cited 2019 Apr 2. Available from: 
http://conservancy.umn.edu/handle/11299/125273. 
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Synnot A, Hill S, Summers M, Taylor M. Comparing face-to-face and online qualitative research with people with multiple sclerosis. Qual Health Res. 2014;24:431&#x2013;438.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24572010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abrams K, Gaiser T. Online Focus Groups. In: Fielding N, Lee R, Blank G, editors. The SAGE Handbook of Online Research Methods. London: SAGE Publications, Ltd; 2017. 290&#x2013;306.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reisner SL, Randazzo RK, White Hughto JM, Peitzmeier S, DuBois LZ, Pardee DJ, et al. Sensitive health topics with underserved patient populations: methodological considerations for online focus group discussions. Qual Health Res. 2018;28:1658&#x2013;1673.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5758419</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29298574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gijzen S, L&#x2019;Hoir MP, Boere-Boonekamp MM, Need A. How do parents experience support after the death of their child? BMC Pediatr. 2016;16:204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5142355</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27927172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ybarra ML, Espelage DL, Valido A, Hong JS, Prescott TL. Perceptions of middle school youth about school bullying. J Adolesc. 2019;75:175&#x2013;187.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30413279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horrell B, Stephens C, Breheny M. Online research with informal caregivers: opportunities and challenges. Qual Res Psychol. 2015;12:258&#x2013;271.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pocock T, Smith M, Wiles J. Recommendations for virtual qualitative health research during a pandemic. Qual Health Res. 2021;31:2403&#x2013;2413.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34384307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richard B, Sivo SA, Orlowski M, Ford RC, Murphy J, Boote DN, et al. Qualitative research via focus groups: will going online affect the diversity of your findings? Cornell Hosp Q. 2021;62:32&#x2013;45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mcewan MJ, Espie CA, Metcalfe J, Brodie MJ, Wilson MT. Quality of life and psychosocial development in adolescents with epilepsy: a qualitative investigation using focus group methods. Seizure - Eur J Epilepsy. 2004;13:15&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14741178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morgan DL. Basic and Advanced Focus Groups. Los Angeles: SAGE Publications; 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Traxinger K, Kelly C, Johnson BA, Lyles RH, Glass JD. Prognosis and epidemiology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurol Clin Pract. 2013;3:313&#x2013;320.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3787117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24195020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardiman O, Al-Chalabi A, Chio A, Corr EM, Logroscino G, Robberecht W, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat Rev Dis Primer. 2017;3:17071.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28980624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masrori P, Van Damme P. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a clinical review. Eur J Neurol. 2020;27:1918&#x2013;1929.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7540334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32526057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beukelman D, Fager S, Nordness A. Communication Support for People with ALS. Neurol. Res. Int. 2011. Cited 2019 Aug 29;2011. Available from: 
https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3096454/. 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3096454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21603029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomik B, Professor RJG. Dysarthria in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a review. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2010;11:4&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20184513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boateng B, Nelson MK. Online focus groups with parents and adolescents with heart transplants: challenges and opportunities. Pediatr Nurs. 2016;42:120&#x2013;154.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27468513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atassi N, Yerramilli-Rao P, Szymonifka J, Yu H, Kearney M, Grasso D, et al. Analysis of start-up, retention, and adherence in ALS clinical trials. Neurology. 2013;81:1350&#x2013;1355.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3806927</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24005339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bedlack RS, Wicks P, Heywood J, Kasarskis E. Modifiable barriers to enrollment in American ALS research studies. Amyotroph Lateral Scler. 2010;11:502&#x2013;507.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20446890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Messina P, Beghi E. Modeling drop-outs in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Contemp Clin Trials. 2012;33:218&#x2013;222.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21996525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rutkove SB, Qi K, Shelton K, Liss J, Berisha V, Shefner JM. ALS longitudinal studies with frequent data collection at home: study design and baseline data. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Front Degener. 2019;20:61&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6513689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30486680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Eijk RPA, Westeneng HJ, Nikolakopoulos S, Verhagen IE, van Es MA, Eijkemans MJC, et al. Refining eligibility criteria for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis clinical trials. Neurology. 2019;92:e451&#x2013;e460.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6369899</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30626653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huis in het Veld J, Verkaik R, van Meijel B, Verkade PJ, Werkman W, Hertogh C, et al. Self-management by family caregivers to manage changes in the behavior and mood of their relative with dementia: an online focus group study. BMC Geriatr. 2016;16:95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4855870</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27142664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacLeod H, Jelen B, Prabhakar A, Oehlberg L, Siek K, Connelly K. Asynchronous Remote Communities (ARC) for Researching Distributed Populations [Internet]. In: Proceedings of the 10th EAI International Conference on Pervasive Computing Technologies for Healthcare. ICST, Brussels, Belgium, Belgium: ICST (Institute for Computer Sciences, Social-Informatics and Telecommunications Engineering); 2016. 1&#x2013;8. Cited 2019 Apr 2. Available from: 
http://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?id=3021319.3021320. 
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNaughton D, Light J, Groszyk L. &#x201c;Don&#x2019;t give up&#x201d;: Employment experiences of individuals with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis who use augmentative and alternative communication. Augment Altern Commun AAC Hamilt. 2001;17:179.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morris MA, Dudgeon BJ, Yorkston K. A qualitative study of adult AAC users&#x2019; experiences communicating with medical providers. Disabil Rehabil Assist Technol. 2013;8:472&#x2013;481.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23350909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meaux JB, Green A, Nelson MK, Huett A, Boateng B, Pye S, et al. Transition to Self-Management after Pediatric Heart Transplant. Prog Transplant. 2014;24:226&#x2013;233.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25193722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams S, Clausen MG, Robertson A, Peacock S, McPherson K. Methodological reflections on the use of asynchronous online focus groups in health research. Int J Qual Methods. 2012;11:368&#x2013;383.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Government of Canada CI of HR. Strategy for Patient-Oriented Research. 2018. Cited 2022 May 31;Available from: 
https://cihr-irsc.gc.ca/e/41204.html. 
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Genuis SK, Luth W, Bubela T, Johnston WS. What do people affected by amyotrophic lateral sclerosis want from health communications? Evidence from the ALS Talk Project. Muscle Nerve. 2023;68:286&#x2013;95. 10.1002/mus.27935.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37462337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chu HS, Oh J. Information needs and preferences of family caregivers of patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurosci Nurs. 2020;52:207&#x2013;213.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32868699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wicks P. &#x2018;They embrace you virtually&#x2019;: The internet as a tool for social support for people with ALS. In: Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis: Understanding and Optimizing Quality of Life and Psychological Well-Being. Oxford University Press; 2018. 185&#x2013;97. Cited 2019 Apr 9. Available from: http://oxfordmedicine.com/view/10.1093/med/9780198757726.001.0001/med-9780198757726-chapter-11. 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/med/9780198757726.001.0001/med-9780198757726-chapter-11</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park A, Calderwood L, Wong E. Participant engagement in longitudinal studies: current practice, opportunities and challenges. Soc. Res. Pract. 2019 ;7. Cited 2022 May 27. Available from: 
http://the-sra.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/social-research-practice-journal-issue-07-winter-2019.pdf. 
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmad M, Genuis SK, Luth W, Bubela T, Johnston WS. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) health charities are central to ALS care: perspectives of Canadians affected by ALS. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Front Degener. 2023;24:246&#x2013;255.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36111949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Genuis SK, Luth W, Bubela T, Johnston WS. Covid-19 threat and coping: application of protection motivation theory to the pandemic experiences of people affected by amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. BMC Neurol. 2022;22:140.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9002218</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35413805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, Miller RG, Swash M, Munsat TL, World Federation of Neurology Research Group on Motor Neuron Diseases El Escorial revisited: revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Mot Neuron Disord. 2000;1:293&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11464847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hodgkinson V, Lounsberry J, M&#x2019;Dahoma S, Russell A, Jewett G, Benstead T, et al. The Canadian Neuromuscular Disease Registry 2010&#x2013;2019: a decade of facilitating clinical research through a nationwide. Pan-NeuromuscularDisease Registry J Neuromuscul Dis. 2021;8:53&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7902956</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32925088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>itracks. Itracks. Cited 2021 Oct 19;Available from: 
https://www.itracks.com/. 
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moir M. Communication, information gathering and use among ALS stakeholders: Diagnosis and care. 2019. Cited 2022 Mar 4; Available from: 
https://era.library.ualberta.ca/items/79a20546-8509-44d8-81e5-b32c43074f01. 
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guest G, Namey E, McKenna K. How many focus groups are enough? Building an evidence base for nonprobability sample sizes. Field Methods. 2017;29:3&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogden J, Cornwell D. The role of topic, interviewee and question in predicting rich interview data in the field of health research. Sociol Health Illn. 2010;32:1059&#x2013;1071.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20942822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsieh HF, Shannon SE. Three approaches to qualitative content analysis. Qual Health Res. 2005;15:1277&#x2013;1288.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16204405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glaser BG, Strauss AL. The Discovery of Grounded Theory: Strategies for Qualitative Research. New York: Aldine de Gruyter; 1967.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stahl NA, King JR. Expanding approaches for research: understanding and using trustworthiness in qualitative research. J Dev Educ. 2020;44:26&#x2013;28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lincoln YS, Guba EG. Naturalistic Inquiry. SAGE; 1985.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nowell LS, Norris JM, White DE, Moules NJ. Thematic analysis: striving to meet the trustworthiness criteria. Int J Qual Methods. 2017;16:1609406917733847.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnston W, Genuis SK, Luth W, Bubela T. Patient-centred priorities for participation in longer-term ALS studies: Improving enrollment and retention. In: 31st International Symposium on ALS/MND, theme 09 - Clinical Trials and Trial Design. Virtual 2021: 2020. 11. Available from: 
http://www.symposium.mndassociation.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Theme-09-Clinical-Trials-and-Trial-Design.pdf. 
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rutkove SB, Narayanaswami P, Berisha V, Liss J, Hahn S, Shelton K, et al. Improved ALS clinical trials through frequent at-home self-assessment: a proof of concept study. Ann Clin Transl Neurol. 2020;7:1148&#x2013;1157.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7359124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32515889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnston WS, Luth W. Public Policy of ALS in Canada. In: Blank RH, Kurent JE, Oliver D, editors. Public Policy in ALS/MND Care: An International Perspective. Singapore: Springer Singapore; 2021. 77&#x2013;96. Available from: 10.1007/978-981-15-5840-5_5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Neill A. Urbanization in Canada 2020. Statista2022. Cited 2022 Jun 8; Available from: 
https://www.statista.com/statistics/271208/urbanization-in-canada/. 
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longinetti E, Fang F. Epidemiology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: an update of recent literature. Curr Opin Neurol. 2019;32:771&#x2013;776.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6735526</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31361627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chio A, Canosa A, Gallo S, Cammarosano S, Moglia C, Fuda G, et al. ALS clinical trials: do enrolled patients accurately represent the ALS population? Neurology. 2011;77:1432&#x2013;1437.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21956723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woodyatt CR, Finneran CA, Stephenson R. In-person versus online focus group discussions: a comparative analysis of data quality. Qual Health Res. 2016;26:741&#x2013;749.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26935719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Childerhose JE, Finnila CH, Yu JH, Koenig BA, McEwen J, Berg SL, et al. Participant engagement in translational genomic research: respect for persons&#x2014;and then some. Ethics Hum Res. 2019;41:2&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7199158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31541538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ochieng CA, Minion JT, Turner A, Blell M, Murtagh MJ. What does engagement mean to participants in longitudinal cohort studies? A qualitative study. BMC Med Ethics. 2021;22:77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8223352</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34167521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karl KA, Peluchette JV, Aghakhani N. Virtual work meetings during the COVID-19 pandemic: the good, bad, and ugly. Small Group Res. 2022;53:343&#x2013;365.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson M, Perrin A. Tech adoption climbs among older adults. Pew Research Centre; 2017. Cited 2023 Jan 3. Available from: 
https://www.pewresearch.org/internet/2017/05/17/technology-use-among-seniors/. 
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Auxier B, Anderson M. Social Media Use in 2021. Pew Res. Cent. Internet Sci. Tech2021. Cited 2022 Jan 6;Available from: 
https://www.pewresearch.org/internet/2021/04/07/social-media-use-in-2021/. 
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faverio M. Share of those 65 and older who are tech users has grown in the past decade. Pew Res. Cent.2022. Cited 2022 Jun 22;Available from: 
https://www.pewresearch.org/fact-tank/2022/01/13/share-of-those-65-and-older-who-are-tech-users-has-grown-in-the-past-decade/. 
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beswick E, Glasmacher SA, Dakin R, Newton J, Carson A, Abrahams S, et al. Prospective observational cohort study of factors influencing trial participation in people with motor neuron disease (FIT-participation-MND): a protocol. BMJ Open. 2021;11:e044996.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7993162</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33757953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong C, Stavrou M, Elliott E, Gregory JM, Leigh N, Pinto AA, et al. Clinical trials in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a systematic review and perspective. Brain Commun. 2021;3:fcab242.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8659356</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34901853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrews JA, Berry JD, Baloh RH, Carberry N, Cudkowicz ME, Dedi B, et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis care and research in the United States during the COVID-19 pandemic: challenges and opportunities. Muscle Nerve. 2020;62:182&#x2013;186.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7283687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32445195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aubin D, Hebert M, Eurich D. The importance of measuring the impact of patient-oriented research. CMAJ. 2019;191:E860&#x2013;E864.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6682486</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31387956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zibrowski E, Carr T, McDonald S, Thiessen H, van Dusen R, Goodridge D, et al. A rapid realist review of patient engagement in patient-oriented research and health care system impacts: part one. Res Involv Engagem. 2021;7:72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8504114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34629118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Domecq JP, Prutsky G, Elraiyah T, Wang Z, Nabhan M, Shippee N, et al. Patient engagement in research: a systematic review. BMC Health Serv Res. 2014;14:89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3938901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24568690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warren M, Leamon T, Hall A, Twells L, Street C, Stordy A, et al. The Role of patient advisory councils in health research: lessons from two provincial councils in Canada. J Patient Exp. 2020;7:898&#x2013;905.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7786741</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33457517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Picher-Martel V V, Magnussen C C, Blais Mathieu, Bubela T, Das S, Dionne A, et al. CAPTURE ALS: the comprehensive analysis platform to understand, remedy and eliminate ALS. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Front Degener. 2022;0:1&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35195049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sim J, Waterfield J. Focus group methodology: some ethical challenges. Qual Quant. 2019;53:3003&#x2013;3022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson C. Chapter 5 - Focus Groups. In: Wilson C, editor. Interview Techniques for UX Practitioners. Boston: Morgan Kaufmann; 2014. 83&#x2013;111. Cited 2022 Jun 1. Available from: 
https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/B9780124103931000053. 
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheridan R, Martin-Kerry J, Hudson J, Parker A, Bower P, Knapp P. Why do patients take part in research? An overview of systematic reviews of psychosocial barriers and facilitators. Trials. 2020;21:259.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7069042</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32164790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Internet usage in Canada - statistics &amp; facts. Statista2022. Cited 2023 Jan 3; Available from: 
https://www.statista.com/topics/4865/internet-usage-in-canada/. 
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weeden A, Kelly W. Canada&#x2019;s (Dis)connected Rural Broadband Policies: Dealing with the Digital Divide And Building &#x201c;Digital Capitals&#x201d; To Address the Impacts of COVID-19 In Rural Canada. J Rural Community Dev. 2021;16:208&#x2013;224.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Government of Canada SC. Census Profile, 2016 Census - Canada [Country] and Canada [Country]. Stat. Can. 2017; Cited 2022 Feb 1. Available from: 
https://www12.statcan.gc.ca/census-recensement/2016/dp-pd/prof/details/page.cfm?Lang=E&amp;Geo1=PR&amp;Code1=01&amp;Geo2=PR&amp;Code2=01&amp;SearchText=01&amp;SearchType=Begins&amp;SearchPR=01&amp;B1=All&amp;TABID=3&amp;type=1. 
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinto S, Quintarelli S, Silani V. New technologies and Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis &#x2013; Which step forward rushed by the COVID-19 pandemic? J Neurol Sci. 2020;418:117081.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7403097</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32882437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stegmann GM, Hahn S, Liss J, Shefner J, Rutkove S, Shelton K, et al. Early detection and tracking of bulbar changes in ALS via frequent and remote speech analysis. Npj Digit Med. 2020;3:1&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7555482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33083567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiernan MC, Vucic S, Talbot K, McDermott CJ, Hardiman O, Shefner JM, et al. Improving clinical trial outcomes in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat Rev Neurol. 2021;17:104&#x2013;118.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7747476</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33340024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>