<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">18775514</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2009</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>19</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1471-4892</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>8</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2008</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Current opinion in pharmacology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Curr Opin Pharmacol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy: a motoneuron or muscle disease?</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>752</StartPage><EndPage>758</EndPage><MedlinePgn>752-8</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.coph.2008.08.006</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Kennedy disease (KD, or spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy) is caused by a CAG/polyglutamine expansion in the androgen receptor (AR) gene. Both motoneurons and muscles are affected by KD, but where mutant ARs act to initiate this disease is not clear. We discuss recent insights into this disease with two main themes. (1) KD is androgen-dependent, suggesting that blocking androgen action may be an effective treatment. (2) Androgens may trigger KD by acting in muscles, which indirectly affects the motoneurons, suggesting that blocking AR function in muscles may rescue motoneurons from disease and provide an effective treatment. Future research will provide a better understanding of how androgens trigger KD and the relative contributions of motoneurons versus muscles in this disease.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jordan</LastName><ForeName>Cynthia L</ForeName><Initials>CL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neuroscience Program and Psychology Department, Michigan State University, East Lansing, MI 48824, USA. jordancy@msu.edu</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lieberman</LastName><ForeName>Andrew P</ForeName><Initials>AP</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>NS 055746</GrantID><Acronym>NS</Acronym><Agency>NINDS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01 NS055746-04</GrantID><Acronym>NS</Acronym><Agency>NINDS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01 NS055746</GrantID><Acronym>NS</Acronym><Agency>NINDS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01 NS045195-06</GrantID><Acronym>NS</Acronym><Agency>NINDS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>NS 045195</GrantID><Acronym>NS</Acronym><Agency>NINDS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01 NS045195</GrantID><Acronym>NS</Acronym><Agency>NINDS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2008</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Curr Opin Pharmacol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100966133</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-4892</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D011944">Receptors, Androgen</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055534" MajorTopicYN="N">Bulbo-Spinal Atrophy, X-Linked</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="Y">pathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008954" MajorTopicYN="N">Models, Biological</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016472" MajorTopicYN="N">Motor Neuron Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="Y">pathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009135" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscular Diseases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="Y">pathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009154" MajorTopicYN="N">Mutation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011944" MajorTopicYN="N">Receptors, Androgen</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2008</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2008</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2008</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2009</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2008</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18775514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS80322</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2603477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.coph.2008.08.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S1471-4892(08)00126-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>La Spada AR, Wilson EM, Lubahn DB, Harding AE, Fischbeck KH. Androgen receptor gene mutations in X-linked spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Nature. 1991;352:77&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2062380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orr HT, Zoghbi HY. Trinucleotide Repeat Disorders. Annu Rev Neurosci. 2007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17417937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kennedy WR, Alter M, Sung JH. Progressive proximal spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy of late onset. A sex-linked recessive trait. Neurology. 1968;18:671&#x2013;680.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4233749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>La Spada AR, Roling DB, Harding AE, Warner CL, Spiegel R, Hausmanowa-Petrusewicz I, Yee WC, Fischbeck KH. Meiotic stability and genotype-phenotype correlation of the trinucleotide repeat in X-linked spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Nat Genet. 1992;2:301&#x2013;304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1303283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mariotti C, Castellotti B, Pareyson D, Testa D, Eoli M, Antozzi C, Silani V, Marconi R, Tezzon F, Siciliano G, et al. Phenotypic manifestations associated with CAG-repeat expansion in the androgen receptor gene in male patients and heterozygous females: a clinical and molecular study of 30 families. Neuromuscul Disord. 2000;10:391&#x2013;397.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10899444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt BJ, Greenberg CR, Allingham-Hawkins DJ, Spriggs EL. Expression of X-linked bulbospinal muscular atrophy (Kennedy disease) in two homozygous women. Neurology. 2002;59:770&#x2013;772.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12221177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guidetti D, Vescovini E, Motti L, Ghidoni E, Gemignani F, Marbini A, Patrosso MC, Ferlini A, Solime F. X-linked bulbar and spinal muscular atrophy, or Kennedy disease: clinical, neurophysiological, neuropathological, neuropsychological and molecular study of a large family. J Neurol Sci. 1996;135:140&#x2013;148.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8867070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sobue G, Hashizume Y, Mukai E, Hirayama M, Mitsuma T, Takahashi A. X-linked recessive bulbospinal neuronopathy. A clinicopathological study. Brain. 1989;112(Pt 1):209&#x2013;232.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2917278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagashima T, Seko K, Hirose K, Mannen T, Yoshimura S, Arima R, Nagashima K, Morimatsu Y. Familial bulbo-spinal muscular atrophy associated with testicular atrophy and sensory neuropathy (Kennedy-Alter-Sung syndrome). Autopsy case report of two brothers. J Neurol Sci. 1988;87:141&#x2013;152.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3210030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soraru G, D'Ascenzo C, Polo A, Palmieri A, Baggio L, Vergani L, Gellera C, Moretto G, Pegoraro E, Angelini C. Spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy: skeletal muscle pathology in male patients and heterozygous females. J Neurol Sci. 2008;264:100&#x2013;105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17854832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li M, Miwa S, Kobayashi Y, Merry DE, Yamamoto M, Tanaka F, Doyu M, Hashizume Y, Fischbeck KH, Sobue G. Nuclear inclusions of the androgen receptor protein in spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Ann Neurol. 1998;44:249&#x2013;254.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9708548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adachi H, Katsuno M, Minamiyama M, Waza M, Sang C, Nakagomi Y, Kobayashi Y, Tanaka F, Doyu M, Inukai A, et al. Widespread nuclear and cytoplasmic accumulation of mutant androgen receptor in SBMA patients. Brain. 2005;128:659&#x2013;670.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15659427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chevalier-Larsen ES, O'Brien CJ, Wang H, Jenkins SC, Holder L, Lieberman AP, Merry DE. Castration restores function and neurofilament alterations of aged symptomatic males in a transgenic mouse model of spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. J Neurosci. 2004;24:4778&#x2013;4786.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6729468</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15152038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McManamny P, Chy HS, Finkelstein DI, Craythorn RG, Crack PJ, Kola I, Cheema SS, Horne MK, Wreford NG, O'Bryan MK, et al. A mouse model of spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Hum Mol Genet. 2002;11:2103&#x2013;2111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12189162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sopher BL, Thomas PS, Jr, LaFevre-Bernt MA, Holm IE, Wilke SA, Ware CB, Jin LW, Libby RT, Ellerby LM, La Spada AR. Androgen receptor YAC transgenic mice recapitulate SBMA motor neuronopathy and implicate VEGF164 in the motor neuron degeneration. Neuron. 2004;41:687&#x2013;699.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15003169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kinirons P, Rouleau GA. Administration of testosterone results in reversible deterioration in Kennedy's disease. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2008;79:106&#x2013;107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17056629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shang Y, Brown M. Molecular determinants for the tissue specificity of SERMs. Science. 2002;295:2465&#x2013;2468.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11923541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsiao PW, Lin DL, Nakao R, Chang C. The linkage of Kennedy's neuron disease to ARA24, the first identified androgen receptor polyglutamine region-associated coactivator. J Biol Chem. 1999;274:20229&#x2013;20234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10400640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morfini G, Pigino G, Szebenyi G, You Y, Pollema S, Brady ST. JNK mediates pathogenic effects of polyglutamine-expanded androgen receptor on fast axonal transport. Nat Neurosci. 2006;9:907&#x2013;916.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16751763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szebenyi G, Morfini GA, Babcock A, Gould M, Selkoe K, Stenoien DL, Young M, Faber PW, MacDonald ME, McPhaul MJ, et al. Neuropathogenic forms of huntingtin and androgen receptor inhibit fast axonal transport. Neuron. 2003;40:41&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14527432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jordan CL, Doncarlos L. Androgens in health and disease: an overview. Horm Behav. 2008;53:589&#x2013;595.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2676684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18407273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jessell TM, Sanes JR. Development. The decade of the developing brain. Curr Opin Neurobiol. 2000;10:599&#x2013;611.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11084323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas M, Harrell JM, Morishima Y, Peng HM, Pratt WB, Lieberman AP. Pharmacologic and genetic inhibition of hsp90-dependent trafficking reduces aggregation and promotes degradation of the expanded glutamine androgen receptor without stress protein induction. Hum Mol Genet. 2006;15:1876&#x2013;1883.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16644868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waza M, Adachi H, Katsuno M, Minamiyama M, Sang C, Tanaka F, Inukai A, Doyu M, Sobue G. 17-AAG, an Hsp90 inhibitor, ameliorates polyglutamine-mediated motor neuron degeneration. Nat Med. 2005;11:1088&#x2013;1095.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16155577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adachi H, Katsuno M, Minamiyama M, Sang C, Pagoulatos G, Angelidis C, Kusakabe M, Yoshiki A, Kobayashi Y, Doyu M, et al. Heat shock protein 70 chaperone overexpression ameliorates phenotypes of the spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy transgenic mouse model by reducing nuclear-localized mutant androgen receptor protein. J Neurosci. 2003;23:2203&#x2013;2211.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6742038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12657679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adachi H, Waza M, Tokui K, Katsuno M, Minamiyama M, Tanaka F, Doyu M, Sobue G. CHIP overexpression reduces mutant androgen receptor protein and ameliorates phenotypes of the spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy transgenic mouse model. J Neurosci. 2007;27:5115&#x2013;5126.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6672370</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17494697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Z, Chang YJ, Yu IC, Yeh S, Wu CC, Miyamoto H, Merry DE, Sobue G, Chen LM, Chang SS, et al. ASC-J9 ameliorates spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy phenotype via degradation of androgen receptor. Nat Med. 2007;13:348&#x2013;353.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17334372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pandey UB, Nie Z, Batlevi Y, McCray BA, Ritson GP, Nedelsky NB, Schwartz SL, DiProspero NA, Knight MA, Schuldiner O, et al. HDAC6 rescues neurodegeneration and provides an essential link between autophagy and the UPS. Nature. 2007;447:859&#x2013;863.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17568747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCampbell A, Taye AA, Whitty L, Penney E, Steffan JS, Fischbeck KH. Histone deacetylase inhibitors reduce polyglutamine toxicity. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2001;98:15179&#x2013;15184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC65003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11742087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minamiyama M, Katsuno M, Adachi H, Waza M, Sang C, Kobayashi Y, Tanaka F, Doyu M, Inukai A, Sobue G. Sodium butyrate ameliorates phenotypic expression in a transgenic mouse model of spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Hum Mol Genet. 2004;13:1183&#x2013;1192.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15102712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>