<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">19154005</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2009</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1521-1878</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>31</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2009</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BioEssays : news and reviews in molecular, cellular and developmental biology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Bioessays</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Microsatellite repeat instability and neurological disease.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>71</StartPage><EndPage>83</EndPage><MedlinePgn>71-83</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/bies.080122</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Over 20 unstable microsatellite repeats have been identified as the cause of neurological disease in humans. The repeat nucleotide sequences, their location within the genes, the ranges of normal and disease-causing repeat length and the clinical outcomes differ. Unstable repeats can be located in the coding or the non-coding region of a gene. Different pathogenic mechanisms that are hypothesised to underlie the diseases are discussed. Evidence is given both from studies in simple model systems and from studies on human material and in animal models. Since somatic instability might affect the clinical outcome, this is briefly touched on. Available data and theories on the timing and mechanisms of the repeat instability itself are discussed, along with factors that have been observed to affect instability. Finally, the question of why the often harmful unstable repeats have been maintained throughout evolution is addressed.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brouwer</LastName><ForeName>Judith R</ForeName><Initials>JR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Genetics, ErasmusMC, Rotterdam, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Willemsen</LastName><ForeName>Rob</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oostra</LastName><ForeName>Ben A</ForeName><Initials>BA</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R01 HD038038</GrantID><Acronym>HD</Acronym><Agency>NICHD NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>RL1 NS062411</GrantID><Acronym>NS</Acronym><Agency>NINDS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>NIH ROI HD38038</GrantID><Acronym>HD</Acronym><Agency>NICHD NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>NIH RL1 NS062411-01</GrantID><Acronym>NS</Acronym><Agency>NINDS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Bioessays</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8510851</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0265-9247</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001259" MajorTopicYN="N">Ataxia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055534" MajorTopicYN="N">Bulbo-Spinal Atrophy, X-Linked</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004195" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Models, Animal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005600" MajorTopicYN="N">Fragile X Syndrome</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006816" MajorTopicYN="N">Huntington Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018895" MajorTopicYN="Y">Microsatellite Repeats</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008957" MajorTopicYN="N">Models, Genetic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009223" MajorTopicYN="N">Myotonic Dystrophy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009422" MajorTopicYN="N">Nervous System Diseases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="Y">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020754" MajorTopicYN="N">Spinocerebellar Ataxias</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019680" MajorTopicYN="N">Trinucleotide Repeat Expansion</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2009</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2009</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2009</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19154005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS659540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4321794</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/bies.080122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Fu YH, Kuhl DP, Pizzuti A, Pieretti M, Sutcliffe JS, et al. Variation of the CGG repeat at the fragile X site results in genetic instability: resolution of the Sherman paradox. Cell. 1991;67:1047&#x2013;1058.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1760838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>La Spada AR, Wilson EM, Lubahn DB, Harding AE, Fischbeck KH. Androgen receptor gene mutations in X-linked spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Nature. 1991;352:77&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2062380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richards RI, Sutherland GR. Heritable unstable DNA sequences. Nat Genet. 1992;1:7&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1302002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orr HT, Zoghbi HY. Trinucleotide repeat disorders. Annu Rev Neurosci. 2007;30:575&#x2013;621.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17417937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mirkin SM. Expandable DNA repeats and human disease. Nature. 2007;447:932&#x2013;940.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17581576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willemsen R, Oostra BA, Bassell GJ, Dictenberg J. The fragile X syndrome: from molecular genetics to neurobiology. Ment Retard Dev Disabil Res Rev. 2004;10:60&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14994290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gecz J, Bielby S, Sutherland GR, Mulley JC. Gene structure and subcellular localization of FMR2, a member of a new family of putative transcription activators. Genomics. 1997;44:201&#x2013;213.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9299237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Biase I, Rasmussen A, Bidichandani SI. Evolution and instability of the GAA triplet-repeat sequence in Friedreich&#x2019;s Ataxia. In: Wells RD, Ashizawa T, editors. Genetic instabilities and neurological diseases. Burlington: Academic Press; 2006. pp. 305&#x2013;319.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karthikeyan G, Santos JH, Graziewicz MA, Copeland WC, Isaya G, et al. Reduction in frataxin causes progressive accumulation of mitochondrial damage. Hum Mol Genet. 2003;12:3331&#x2013;3342.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14570713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoon T, Cowan JA. Iron-sulfur cluster biosynthesis. Characterization of frataxin as an iron donor for assembly of [2Fe-2S] clusters in ISU-type proteins. J Am Chem Soc. 2003;125:6078&#x2013;6084.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12785837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cho DH, Tapscott SJ. Myotonic dystrophy: emerging mechanisms for DM1 and DM2. Biochim Biophys Acta. 2007;1772:195&#x2013;204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16876389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashizawa T, Harper P. Myotonic dystrophies: an overview. In: Wells R, Ashizawa T, editors. Genetic instabilities and neurological diseases. Burlington: Academic Press; 2006. pp. 21&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis BM, McCurrach ME, Taneja KL, Singer RH, Housman DE. Expansion of a CUG trinucleotide repeat in the 3&#x2032; untranslated region of myotonic dystrophy protein kinase transcripts results in nuclear retention of transcripts. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 1997;94:7388&#x2013;7393.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC23831</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9207101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Napierala M, Krzyzosiak WJ. CUG repeats present in myotonin kinase RNA form metastable &#x201c;slippery&#x201d; hairpins. J Biol Chem. 1997;272:31079&#x2013;31085.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9388259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fardaei M, Larkin K, Brook JD, Hamshere MG. In vivo co-localisation of MBNL protein with DMPK expanded-repeat transcripts. Nucleic Acids Res. 2001;29:2766&#x2013;2771.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC55763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11433021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller JW, Urbinati CR, Teng-Umnuay P, Stenberg MG, Byrne BJ, et al. Recruitment of human muscleblind proteins to (CUG)(n) expansions associated with myotonic dystrophy. EMBO J. 2000;19:4439&#x2013;4448.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC302046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10970838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Timchenko LT, Miller JW, Timchenko NA, DeVore DR, Datar KV, et al. Identification of a (CUG)n triplet repeat RNA-binding protein and its expression in myotonic dystrophy. Nucleic Acids Res. 1996;24:4407&#x2013;4414.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC146274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8948631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanadia RN, Johnstone KA, Mankodi A, Lungu C, Thornton CA, et al. A muscleblind knockout model for myotonic dystrophy. Science. 2003;302:1978&#x2013;1980.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14671308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pascual M, Vicente M, Monferrer L, Artero R. The Muscleblind family of proteins: an emerging class of regulators of developmentally programmed alternative splicing. Differentiation. 2006;74:65&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16533306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Haro M, Al-Ramahi I, De Gouyon B, Ukani L, Rosa A, et al. MBNL1 and CUGBP1 modify expanded CUG-induced toxicity in a Drosophila model of myotonic dystrophy type 1. Hum Mol Genet. 2006;15:2138&#x2013;2145.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16723374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagerman RJ, Leehey M, Heinrichs W, Tassone F, Wilson R, et al. Intention tremor, parkinsonism, and generalized brain atrophy in male carriers of fragile X. Neurology. 2001;57:127&#x2013;130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11445641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacquemont S, Hagerman RJ, Leehey M, Grigsby J, Zhang L, et al. Fragile X premutation tremor/ataxia syndrome: molecular, clinical, and neuroimaging correlates. Am J Hum Genet. 2003;72:869&#x2013;878.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1180350</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12638084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greco CM, Hagerman RJ, Tassone F, Chudley AE, Del Bigio MR, et al. Neuronal intranuclear inclusions in a new cerebellar tremor/ataxia syndrome among fragile X carriers. Brain. 2002;125:1760&#x2013;1771.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12135967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tassone F, Iwahashi C, Hagerman PJ. FMR1 RNA within the intranuclear inclusions of fragile X-associated tremor/ataxia syndrome (FXTAS) RNA Biol. 2004;1:103&#x2013;105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17179750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagerman PJ, Hagerman RJ. The fragile-X premutation: a maturing perspective. Am J Hum Genet. 2004;74:805&#x2013;816.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1181976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15052536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iwahashi CK, Yasui DH, An HJ, Greco CM, Tassone F, et al. Protein composition of the intranuclear inclusions of FXTAS. Brain. 2006;129:256&#x2013;271.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16246864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arocena DG, Iwahashi CK, Won N, Beilina A, Ludwig AL, et al. Induction of inclusion formation and disruption of lamin A/C structure by premutation CGG-repeat RNA in human cultured neural cells. Hum Mol Genet. 2005;14:3661&#x2013;3671.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16239243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Handa V, Goldwater D, Stiles D, Cam M, Poy G, et al. Long CGG-repeat tracts are toxic to human cells: implications for carriers of Fragile X premutation alleles. FEBS Lett. 2005;579:2702&#x2013;2708.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15862312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin P, Duan R, Qurashi A, Qin Y, Tian D, et al. Pur alpha binds to rCGG repeats and modulates repeat-mediated neurodegeneration in a Drosophila model of fragile X tremor/ataxia syndrome. Neuron. 2007;55:556&#x2013;564.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1994817</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17698009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sofola OA, Jin P, Qin Y, Duan R, Liu H, et al. RNA-binding proteins hnRNP A2/B1 and CUGBP1 suppress fragile X CGG premutation repeat-induced neurodegeneration in a Drosophila model of FXTAS. Neuron. 2007;55:565&#x2013;571.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2215388</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17698010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sherman SL. Premature ovarian failure among fragile X premutation carriers: parent-of-origin effect? Am J Hum Genet. 2000;67:11&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1287068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10848491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oostra BA, Willemsen R. A fragile balance: FMR1 expression levels. Hum Mol Genet. 2003;12:R249&#x2013;R257.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12952862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacquemont S, Leehey MA, Hagerman RJ, Beckett LA, Hagerman PJ. Size bias of fragile X premutation alleles in late-onset movement disorders. J Med Genet. 2006;43:804&#x2013;809.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2563171</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16723388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin P, Zarnescu DC, Zhang F, Pearson CE, Lucchesi JC, et al. RNA-mediated neurodegeneration caused by the fragile X premutation rCGG repeats in drosophila. Neuron. 2003;39:739&#x2013;747.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12948442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ikeda Y, Dick KA, Day JW, Ranum LPW. Molecular genetics of spinocerebellar ataxia type 8. In: Wells RD, Ashizawa T, editors. Genetic instabilities and neurological disease. Burlington: Academic Press; 2006. pp. 417&#x2013;431.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holmes SE, O&#x2019;Hearn E, Cortez-Apreza N, Hwang HS, Ross CA, et al. Spinocerebellar ataxia type 12. In: Wells RD, Ashizawa T, editors. Genetic instabilities and neurological diseases. Burlington: Academic Press; 2006. pp. 461&#x2013;473.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wetzel R. Chemical and physical properties of polyglutamine repeat sequences. In: Wells R, Ashizawa T, editors. Genetic instabilities and neurological disease. Burlington: Academic Press; 2006. pp. 517&#x2013;534.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scherzinger E, Sittler A, Schweiger K, Heiser V, Lurz R, et al. Self-assembly of polyglutamine-containing huntingtin fragments into amyloid-like fibrils: implications for Huntington&#x2019;s disease pathology. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 1999;96:4604&#x2013;4609.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC16379</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10200309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ross CA, Wood JD, Peters MF, Schilling G, Nucifora FC, et al. Polyglutamine pathogenesis, potential role of protein interactions, proteolytic processing and nuclear localization. In: Harper P, Perutz M, editors. Glutamine repeats and neurodegenerative diseases: molecular aspects. New York: Oxford University Press, Inc; 2001. pp. 93&#x2013;112.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen CJ, Fischbeck KH. Clinical features and molecular biology of Kennedy&#x2019;s disease. In: Wells R, Ashizawa T, editors. Genetic instabilities and neurological disease. Burlington: Academic Press; 2006. pp. 211&#x2013;220.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li SH, Li XJ. Huntingtin-protein interactions and the pathogenesis of Huntington&#x2019;s disease. Trends Genet. 2004;20:146&#x2013;154.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15036808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arrasate M, Mitra S, Schweitzer ES, Segal MR, Finkbeiner S. Inclusion body formation reduces levels of mutant huntingtin and the risk of neuronal death. Nature. 2004;431:805&#x2013;810.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15483602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li H, Li SH, Cheng AL, Mangiarini L, Bates GP, et al. Ultrastructural localization and progressive formation of neuropil aggregates in Huntington&#x2019;s disease transgenic mice. Hum Mol Genet. 1999;8:1227&#x2013;1236.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10369868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamamoto A, Lucas JJ, Hen R. Reversal of neuropathology and motor dysfunction in a conditional model of Huntington&#x2019;s disease. Cell. 2000;101:57&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10778856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mirkin SM, Smirnova EV. Positioned to expand. Nat Genet. 2002;31:5&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11984556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brais B, Bouchard JP, Xie YG, Rochefort DL, Chretien N, et al. Short GCG expansions in the PABP2 gene cause oculopharyngeal muscular dystrophy. Nat Genet. 1998;18:164&#x2013;167.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9462747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tome FM, Fardeau M. Nuclear inclusions in oculopharyngeal dystrophy. Acta Neuropathol. 1980;49:85&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6243839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Margolis RL, Holmes SE, Rudnicki D, O&#x2019;Hearn E, Ross CA, et al. Huntington&#x2019;s disease-like 2. In: Wells R, Ashizawa T, editors. Genetic instabilities and neurological diseases. Burlington: Academic Press; 2006. pp. 261&#x2013;273.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reyniers E, Vits L, De Boulle K, Van Roy B, Van Velzen D, et al. The full mutation in the FMR-1 gene of male fragile X patients is absent in their sperm. Nat Genet. 1993;4:143&#x2013;146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8348152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malter HE, Iber JC, Willemsen R, De Graaff E, Tarleton JC, et al. Characterization of the full fragile X syndrome mutation in fetal gametes. Nat Genet. 1997;15:165&#x2013;169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9020841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hansen RS, Canfield TK, Lamb MM, Gartler SM, Laird CD. Association of fragile X syndrome with delayed replication of the FMR1 gene. Cell. 1993;73:1403&#x2013;1409.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8324827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>W&#xf6;hrle D, Hennig I, Vogel W, Steinbach P. Mitotic stability of fragile X mutations in differentiated cells indicates early post-conceptional trinucleotide repeat expansion. Nat Genet. 1993;4:140&#x2013;142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8348151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moutou C, Vincent MC, Biancalana V, Mandel JL. Transition from premutation to full mutation in fragile X syndrome is likely to be prezygotic. Hum Mol Genet. 1997;6:971&#x2013;979.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9215664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bontekoe CJ, Bakker CE, Nieuwenhuizen IM, van Der Linde H, Lans H, et al. Instability of a (CGG)(98) repeat in the Fmr1 promoter. Hum Mol Genet. 2001;10:1693&#x2013;1699.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11487573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Entezam A, Biacsi R, Orrison B, Saha T, Hoffman GE, et al. Regional FMRP deficits and large repeat expansions into the full mutation range in a new Fragile X premutation mouse model. Gene. 2007;395:125&#x2013;134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1950257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17442505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brouwer JR, Mientjes EJ, Bakker CE, Nieuwenhuizen IM, Severijnen LA, et al. Elevated Fmr1 mRNA levels and reduced protein expression in a mouse model with an unmethylated fragile X full mutation. Exp Cell Res. 2007;313:244&#x2013;253.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1852528</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17150213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jansen G, Willems P, Coerwinkel M, Nillesen W, Smeets H, et al. Gonosomal mosaicism in myotonic dystrophy patients: involvement of mitotic events in (CTG)n repeat variation and selection against extreme expansion in sperm. Am J Hum Genet. 1993;54:575&#x2013;585.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1918095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8128954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dean NL, Tan SL, Ao A. Instability in the transmission of the myotonic dystrophy CTG repeat in human oocytes and preimplantation embryos. Fertil Steril. 2006;86:98&#x2013;105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16716318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaytor MD, Burright EN, Duvick LA, Zoghbi HY, Orr HT. Increased trinucleotide repeat instability with advanced maternal age. Hum Mol Genet. 1997;6:2135&#x2013;2139.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9328478</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Savouret C, Garcia-Cordier C, Megret J, te Riele H, Junien C, et al. MSH2-dependent germinal CTG repeat expansions are produced continuously in spermatogonia from DM1 transgenic mice. Mol Cell Biol. 2004;24:629&#x2013;637.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC343816</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14701736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leeflang EP, Tavare S, Marjoram P, Neal CO, Srinidhi J, et al. Analysis of germline mutation spectra at the Huntington&#x2019;s disease locus supports a mitotic mutation mechanism. Hum Mol Genet. 1999;8:173&#x2013;183.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9931325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kovtun IV, McMurray CT. Trinucleotide expansion in haploid germ cells by gap repair. Nat Genet. 2001;27:407&#x2013;411.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11279522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoon SR, Dubeau L, de Young M, Wexler NS, Arnheim N. Huntington disease expansion mutations in humans can occur before meiosis is completed. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2003;100:8834&#x2013;8838.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC166399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12857955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nichol Edamura K, Pearson CE. DNA methylation and replication: implications for the &#x201c;deletion hotspot&#x201d; region of FMR1. Hum Genet. 2005;118:301&#x2013;304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16133176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>W&#xf6;hrle D, Kennerknecht I, Wolf M, Enders H, Schwemmle S, et al. Heterogeneity of DM kinase repeat expansion in different fetal tissues and further expansion during cell proliferation in vitro: evidence for a causal involvement of methyl-directed DNA mismatch repair in triplet repeat stability. Hum Mol Genet. 1995;4:1147&#x2013;1153.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8528201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashizawa T, Dubel JR, Harati Y. Somatic instability of CTG repeat in myotonic dystrophy. Neurology. 1993;43:2674&#x2013;2678.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8255475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monckton DG, Wong LJ, Ashizawa T, Caskey CT. Somatic mosaicism, germline expansions, germline reversions and intergenerational reductions in myotonic dystrophy males: small pool PCR analyses. Hum Mol Genet. 1995;4:1&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7711720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong LJC, Ashizawa T, Monckton DG, Caskey CT, Richards CS. Somatic heterogeneity of the CTG repeat in myotonic dystrophy is age and size dependent. Am J Hum Genet. 1995;56:114&#x2013;122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1801291</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7825566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Broek WJ, Wansink DG, Wieringa B. Somatic CTG*CAG repeat instability in a mouse model for myotonic dystrophy type 1 is associated with changes in cell nuclearity and DNA ploidy. BMC Mol Biol. 2007;8:61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1940261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17645799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kennedy L, Shelbourne PF. Dramatic mutation instability in HD mouse striatum: does polyglutamine load contribute to cell-specific vulnerability in Huntington&#x2019;s disease? Hum Mol Genet. 2000;9:2539&#x2013;2544.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11030759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kennedy L, Evans E, Chen CM, Craven L, Detloff PJ, et al. Dramatic tissue-specific mutation length increases are an early molecular event in Huntington disease pathogenesis. Hum Mol Genet. 2003;12:3359&#x2013;3367.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14570710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gomes-Pereira M, Foiry L, Gourdon G. Transgenic mouse models of unstable trinucleotide repeats: toward an understanding of disease-associated repeat size mutation. In: Wells R, Ashizawa T, editors. Genetic instabilities and neurological diseases. Burlington: Academic Press; 2006. pp. 563&#x2013;583.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kunkel TA. Nucleotide repeats. Slippery DNA and diseases. Nature. 1993;365:207&#x2013;208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8371775</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pearson CE, Tam M, Wang YH, Montgomery SE, Dar AC, et al. Slipped-strand DNAs formed by long (CAG)*(CTG) repeats: slipped-out repeats and slip-out junctions. Nucleic Acids Res. 2002;30:4534&#x2013;4547.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC137136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12384601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mirkin SM. DNA structures, repeat expansions and human hereditary disorders. Curr Opin Struct Biol. 2006;16:351&#x2013;358.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16713248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eichler EE, Holden J, Popovich BW, Reiss AL, Snow K, et al. Length of uninterrupted CGG repeats determines instability in the FMR1 gene. Nat Genet. 1994;8:88&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7987398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kunst CB, Warren ST. Cryptic and polar variation of the fragile X repeat could result in predisposing normal alleles. Cell. 1994;77:853&#x2013;861.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7911740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung MY, Ranum LPW, Duvick LA, Servadio A, Zoghbi HY. Evidence for a mechanism predisposing to intergenerational CAG repeat instability in spinocerebellar ataxia type I. Nat Genet. 1993;5:254&#x2013;258.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8275090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miret JJ, Pessoa-Brandao L, Lahue RS. Orientation-dependent and sequence-specific expansions of CTG/CAG trinucleotide repeats in Saccharomyces cerevisiae. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 1998;95:12438&#x2013;12443.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC22849</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9770504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bontekoe CJM, de Graaff E, Nieuwenhuizen IM, Willemsen R, Oostra BA. FMR1 premutation allele is stable in mice. Eur J Hum Genet. 1997;5:293&#x2013;298.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9412786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gourdon G, Dessen P, Lia AS, Junien C, Hofmann-fRadvanyi H. Intriguing association between disease associated unstable trinucleotide repeat and CpG island. Ann Genet. 1997;40:73&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9259953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brock GJ, Anderson NH, Monckton DG. Cis-acting modifiers of expanded CAG/CTG triplet repeat expandability: associations with flanking GC content and proximity to CpG islands. Hum Mol Genet. 1999;8:1061&#x2013;1067.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10332038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sutherland GR. Fragile sites on human chromosomes: demonstration of their dependence on the type of tissue culture medium. Science. 1977;197:265&#x2013;266.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">877551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gourdon G, Radvanyi F, Lia AS, Duros C, Blanche M, et al. Moderate intergenerational and somatic instability of a 55-CTG repeat in transgenic mice. Nat Genet. 1997;15:190&#x2013;192.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9020847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seznec H, Lia-Baldini AS, Duros C, Fouquet C, Lacroix C, et al. Transgenic mice carrying large human genomic sequences with expanded CTG repeat mimic closely the CM CTG repeat intergenerational and somatic instability. Hum Mol Genet. 2000;9:1185&#x2013;1194.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10767343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peier A, Nelson D. Instability of a premutation-sized CGG repeat in FMR1 YAC transgenic mice. Genomics. 2002;80:423&#x2013;432.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12376097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monckton DG, Coolbaugh MI, Ashizawa KT, Siciliano MJ, Caskey CT. Hypermutable myotonic dystrophy CTG repeats in transgenic mice. Nat Genet. 1997;15:193&#x2013;196.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9020848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang S, Jaworski A, Ohshima K, Wells RD. Expansion and deletion of CTG repeats from human disease genes are determined by the direction of replication in E. coli. Nat Genet. 1995;10:213&#x2013;218.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7663518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gray SJ, Gerhardt J, Doerfler W, Small LE, Fanning E. An origin of DNA replication in the promoter region of the human fragile X mental retardation (FMR1) gene. Mol Cell Biol. 2007;27:426437.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1800797</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17101793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cleary JD, Pearson CE. The contribution of cis-elements to disease-associated repeat instability: clinical and experimental evidence. Cytogenet Genome Res. 2003;100:25&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14526163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pearson CE. Slipping while sleeping? Trinucleotide repeat expansions in germ cells. Trends Mol Med. 2003;9:490&#x2013;495.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14604827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Monckton DG, Siciliano MJ, Connor TH, Meistrich ML. Age and insertion site dependence of repeat number instability of a human DM1 transgene in individual mouse sperm. Hum Mol Genet. 2002;11:791&#x2013;798.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11929851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thornton CA, Griggs RC, Moxley R. Myotonic dystrophy with no trinucleotide repeat expansion. Ann Neurol. 1994;35:269&#x2013;272.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8122879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Z, Lau R, Marcadier JL, Chitayat D, Pearson CE. Replication inhibitors modulate instability of an expanded trinucleotide repeat at the myotonic dystrophy type 1 disease locus in human cells. Am J Hum Genet. 2003;73:1092&#x2013;1105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1180489</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14574643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spiro C, McMurray CT. Nuclease-deficient FEN-1 blocks Rad51/ BRCA1-mediated repair and causes trinucleotide repeat instability. Mol Cell Biol. 2003;23:6063&#x2013;6074.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC180932</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12917330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonitel R, Moffitt H, Sathasivam K, Woodman B, Detloff PJ, et al. DNA instability in postmitotic neurons. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2008;105:3467&#x2013;3472.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2265187</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18299573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Savouret C, Brisson E, Essers J, Kanaar R, Pastink A, et al. CTG repeat instability and size variation timing in DNA repair-deficient mice. EMBO J. 2003;22:2264&#x2013;2273.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC156074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12727892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wheeler VC, Lebel LA, Vrbanac V, Teed A, te Riele H, et al. Mismatch repair gene Msh2 modifies the timing of early disease in Hdh(Q111) striatum. Hum Mol Genet. 2003;12:273&#x2013;281.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12554681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foiry L, Dong L, Savouret C, Hubert L, te Riele H, et al. Msh3 is a limiting factor in the formation of intergenerational CTG expansions in DM1 transgenic mice. Hum Genet. 2006;119:520&#x2013;526.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16552576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Entezam A, Usdin K. ATR protects the genome against CGG*CGG-repeat expansion in Fragile X premutation mice. Nucleic Acids Res. 2007;36:1050&#x2013;1056.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2241920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18160412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Razidlo DF, Lahue RS. Mrc1, Tof1 and Csm3 inhibit CAG. CTG repeat instability by at least two mechanisms. DNA Repair (Amst) 2008;7:633&#x2013;640.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2396238</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18321795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kovtun IV, McMurray CT. Features of trinucleotide repeat instability in vivo. Cell Res. 2008;18:198&#x2013;213.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18166978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jung J, Bonini N. CREB-binding protein modulates repeat instability in a Drosophila model for polyQ disease. Science. 2007;315:1857&#x2013;1859.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17332375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin Y, Wilson JH. Transcription-induced CAG repeat contraction in human cells is mediated in part by transcription-coupled nucleotide excision repair. Mol Cell Biol. 2007;27:6209&#x2013;6217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1952160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17591697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dion V, Lin Y, Hubert L, Jr, Waterland RA, Wilson JH. Dnmt1 deficiency promotes CAG repeat expansion in the mouse germ-line. Hum Mol Genet. 2008;17:1306&#x2013;1317.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3686304</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18252747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baskaran S, Datta S, Mandal A, Gulati N, Totey S, et al. Instability of CGG repeats in transgenic mice. Genomics. 2002;80:151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12160728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang YH, Griffith J. Methylation of expanded CCG triplet repeat DNA from fragile X syndrome patients enhances nucleosome exclusion. J Biol Chem. 1996;271:22937&#x2013;22940.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8798475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jasinska A, Michlewski G, de Mezer M, Sobczak K, Kozlowski P, et al. Structures of trinucleotide repeats in human transcripts and their functional implications. Nucleic Acids Res. 2003;31:5463&#x2013;5468.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC206467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14500808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Godde JS, Kass SU, Hirst MC, Wolffe AP. Nucleosome assembly on methylated CGG triplet repeats in the Fragile X Mental Retardation gene 1 promoter. J Biol Chem. 1996;271:24325&#x2013;24328.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8798682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang YH, Amirhaeri S, Kang S, Wells RD, Griffith JD. Preferential nucleosome assembly at DNA triplet repeats from the myotonic dystrophy gene. Science. 1994;265:669&#x2013;671.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8036515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>