<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">20886071</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2011</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>18</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1932-6203</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>5</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2010</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>23</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PloS one</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PLoS One</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Microarray analysis of gene expression by skeletal muscle of three mouse models of Kennedy disease/spinal bulbar muscular atrophy.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e12922</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e12922</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e12922</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1371/journal.pone.0012922</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Emerging evidence implicates altered gene expression within skeletal muscle in the pathogenesis of Kennedy disease/spinal bulbar muscular atrophy (KD/SBMA). We therefore broadly characterized gene expression in skeletal muscle of three independently generated mouse models of this disease. The mouse models included a polyglutamine expanded (polyQ) AR knock-in model (AR113Q), a polyQ AR transgenic model (AR97Q), and a transgenic mouse that overexpresses wild type AR solely in skeletal muscle (HSA-AR). HSA-AR mice were included because they substantially reproduce the KD/SBMA phenotype despite the absence of polyQ AR.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODOLOGY/PRINCIPAL FINDINGS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">We performed microarray analysis of lower hindlimb muscles taken from these three models relative to wild type controls using high density oligonucleotide arrays. All microarray comparisons were made with at least 3 animals in each condition, and only those genes having at least 2-fold difference and whose coefficient of variance was less than 100% were considered to be differentially expressed. When considered globally, there was a similar overlap in gene changes between the 3 models: 19% between HSA-AR and AR97Q, 21% between AR97Q and AR113Q, and 17% between HSA-AR and AR113Q, with 8% shared by all models. Several patterns of gene expression relevant to the disease process were observed. Notably, patterns of gene expression typical of loss of AR function were observed in all three models, as were alterations in genes involved in cell adhesion, energy balance, muscle atrophy and myogenesis. We additionally measured changes similar to those observed in skeletal muscle of a mouse model of Huntington's Disease, and to those common to muscle atrophy from diverse causes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS/SIGNIFICANCE" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">By comparing patterns of gene expression in three independent models of KD/SBMA, we have been able to identify candidate genes that might mediate the core myogenic features of KD/SBMA.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mo</LastName><ForeName>Kaiguo</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, University of Toronto at Mississauga, Mississauga, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Razak</LastName><ForeName>Zak</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rao</LastName><ForeName>Pengcheng</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yu</LastName><ForeName>Zhigang</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Adachi</LastName><ForeName>Hiroaki</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Katsuno</LastName><ForeName>Masahisa</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sobue</LastName><ForeName>Gen</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lieberman</LastName><ForeName>Andrew P</ForeName><Initials>AP</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Westwood</LastName><ForeName>J Timothy</ForeName><Initials>JT</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Monks</LastName><ForeName>D Ashley</ForeName><Initials>DA</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R01-NS51257</GrantID><Acronym>NS</Acronym><Agency>NINDS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01 NS055746</GrantID><Acronym>NS</Acronym><Agency>NINDS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01-NS055746</GrantID><Acronym>NS</Acronym><Agency>NINDS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01 NS055746-04</GrantID><Acronym>NS</Acronym><Agency>NINDS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01 NS051257</GrantID><Acronym>NS</Acronym><Agency>NINDS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2010</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PLoS One</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101285081</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1932-6203</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055534" MajorTopicYN="N">Bulbo-Spinal Atrophy, X-Linked</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="Y">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004195" MajorTopicYN="Y">Disease Models, Animal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051379" MajorTopicYN="Y">Mice</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008810" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice, Inbred C57BL</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018345" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice, Knockout</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008822" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice, Transgenic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009134" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscular Atrophy, Spinal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="Y">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020411" MajorTopicYN="N">Oligonucleotide Array Sequence Analysis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement><b>Competing Interests: </b>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2010</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2010</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2010</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2010</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2011</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20886071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2944863</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0012922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">e12922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Kennedy WR, Alter M, Sung JH. Progressive proximal spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy of late onset. A sex-linked recessive trait. Neurology. 1968;18:671&#x2013;680.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4233749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atsuta N, Watanabe H, Ito M, Banno H, Suzuki K, et al. Natural history of spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy (SBMA): a study of 223 Japanese patients. Brain. 2006;129:1446&#x2013;1455.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16621916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>La Spada AR, Wilson EM, Lubahn DB, Harding AE, Fischbeck KH. Androgen receptor gene mutations in X-linked spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Nature. 1991;352:77&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2062380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zoghbi HY, Orr HT. Glutamine repeats and neurodegeneration. Annu Rev Neurosci. 2000;23:217&#x2013;247.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10845064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monks DA, Rao P, Mo K, Johansen JA, Lewis G, et al. Androgen receptor and Kennedy disease/spinal bulbar muscular atrophy. Horm Behav. 2008;53:729&#x2013;740.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2883265</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18321505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu Z, Dadgar N, Albertelli M, Gruis K, Jordan C, et al. Androgen-dependent pathology demonstrates myopathic contribution to the Kennedy disease phenotype in a mouse knock-in model. J Clin Invest. 2006;116:2663&#x2013;2672.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1564432</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16981011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monks DA, Johansen JA, Mo K, Rao P, Eagleson B, et al. Overexpression of wild-type androgen receptor in muscle recapitulates polyglutamine expansion. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2007;104:18259&#x2013;18264.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2084330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17984063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katsuno M, Adachi H, Waza M, Banno H, Suzuki K, et al. Pathogenesis, animal models and therapeutics in spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy (SBMA). Exp Neurol. 2006;200:8&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16513111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sopher BL, Thomas PS, Jr, LaFevre-Bernt MA, Holm IE, Wilke SA, et al. Androgen Receptor YAC Transgenic Mice Recapitulate SBMA Motor Neuronopathy and Implicate VEGF164 in the Motor Neuron Degeneration. Neuron. 2004;41:687&#x2013;699.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15003169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katsuno M, Adachi H, Sobue G. Spinal and Bulbar Muscular Atrophy: Clinical Features and Pathogenesis. ACNR. 2003;3:8&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adachi H, Waza M, Katsuno M, Tanaka F, Doyu M, et al. Pathogenesis and molecular targeted therapy of spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Neuropathol Appl Neurobiol. 2007;33:135&#x2013;151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17359355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas PS, Jr, Fraley GS, Damian V, Woodke LB, Zapata F, et al. Loss of endogenous androgen receptor protein accelerates motor neuron degeneration and accentuates androgen insensitivity in a mouse model of X-linked spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Hum Mol Genet. 2006;15:2225&#x2013;2238.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16772330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCampbell A, Taylor JP, Taye AA, Robitschek J, Li M, et al. CREB-binding protein sequestration by expanded polyglutamine. Hum Mol Genet. 2000;9:2197&#x2013;2202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10958659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lieberman AP, Harmison G, Strand AD, Olson JM, Fischbeck KH. Altered transcriptional regulation in cells expressing the expanded polyglutamine androgen receptor. Hum Mol Genet. 2002;11:1967&#x2013;1976.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12165558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sacheck JM, Hyatt JP, Raffaello A, Jagoe RT, Roy RR, et al. Rapid disuse and denervation atrophy involve transcriptional changes similar to those of muscle wasting during systemic diseases. FASEB J. 2007;21:140&#x2013;155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17116744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minamiyama M, Katsuno M, Adachi H, Waza M, Sang C, et al. Sodium butyrate ameliorates phenotypic expression in a transgenic mouse model of spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Hum Mol Genet 2004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15102712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stenoien DL, Cummings CJ, Adams HP, Mancini MG, Patel K, et al. Polyglutamine-expanded androgen receptors form aggregates that sequester heat shock proteins, proteasome components and SRC-1, and are suppressed by the HDJ-2 chaperone. Hum Mol Genet. 1999;8:731&#x2013;741.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10196362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walcott JL, Merry DE. Ligand promotes intranuclear inclusions in a novel cell model of spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. J Biol Chem. 2002;277:50855&#x2013;50859.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12388541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kobayashi Y, Kume A, Li M, Doyu M, Hata M, et al. Chaperones Hsp70 and Hsp40 suppress aggregate formation and apoptosis in cultured neuronal cells expressing truncated androgen receptor protein with expanded polyglutamine tract. J Biol Chem. 2000;275:8772&#x2013;8778.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10722721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bailey CK, Andriola IF, Kampinga HH, Merry DE. Molecular chaperones enhance the degradation of expanded polyglutamine repeat androgen receptor in a cellular model of spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Hum Mol Genet. 2002;11:515&#x2013;523.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11875046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishihara K, Yamagishi N, Saito Y, Adachi H, Kobayashi Y, et al. Hsp105alpha suppresses the aggregation of truncated androgen receptor with expanded CAG repeats and cell toxicity. J Biol Chem. 2003;278:25143&#x2013;25150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12714591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas M, Harrell JM, Morishima Y, Peng HM, Pratt WB, et al. Pharmacologic and genetic inhibition of hsp90-dependent trafficking reduces aggregation and promotes degradation of the expanded glutamine androgen receptor without stress protein induction. Hum Mol Genet. 2006;15:1876&#x2013;1883.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16644868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katsuno M, Sang C, Adachi H, Minamiyama M, Waza M, et al. Pharmacological induction of heat-shock proteins alleviates polyglutamine-mediated motor neuron disease. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2005;102:16801&#x2013;16806.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1275598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16260738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waza M, Adachi H, Katsuno M, Minamiyama M, Sang C, et al. 17-AAG, an Hsp90 inhibitor, ameliorates polyglutamine-mediated motor neuron degeneration. Nat Med. 2005;11:1088&#x2013;1095.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16155577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ranganathan S, Harmison GG, Meyertholen K, Pennuto M, Burnett BG, et al. Mitochondrial abnormalities in spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Hum Mol Genet. 2009;18:27&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2644643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18824496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacLean HE, Chiu WS, Notini AJ, Axell AM, Davey RA, et al. Impaired skeletal muscle development and function in male, but not female, genomic androgen receptor knockout mice. FASEB J. 2008;22:2676&#x2013;2689.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18390925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshioka M, Boivin A, Bolduc C, St-Amand J. Gender difference of androgen actions on skeletal muscle transcriptome. J Mol Endocrinol. 2007;39:119&#x2013;133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17693611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshioka M, Boivin A, Ye P, Labrie F, St-Amand J. Effects of dihydrotestosterone on skeletal muscle transcriptome in mice measured by serial analysis of gene expression. J Mol Endocrinol. 2006;36:247&#x2013;259.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16595697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strand AD, Aragaki AK, Shaw D, Bird T, Holton J, et al. Gene expression in Huntington's disease skeletal muscle: a potential biomarker. Hum Mol Genet. 2005;14:1863&#x2013;1876.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15888475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lecker SH, Jagoe RT, Gilbert A, Gomes M, Baracos V, et al. Multiple types of skeletal muscle atrophy involve a common program of changes in gene expression. Faseb J. 2004;18:39&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14718385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyazaki M, Esser KA. REDD2 is enriched in skeletal muscle and inhibits mTOR signaling in response to leucine and stretch. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol. 2009;296:C583&#x2013;592.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2660267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19129461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pisani DF, Leclerc L, Jarretou G, Marini JF, Dechesne CA. SMHS1 is involved in oxidative/glycolytic-energy metabolism balance of muscle fibers. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 2005;326:788&#x2013;793.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15607738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eigenthaler M, Engelhardt S, Schinke B, Kobsar A, Schmitteckert E, et al. Disruption of cardiac Ena-VASP protein localization in intercalated disks causes dilated cardiomyopathy. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol. 2003;285:H2471&#x2013;2481.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12933343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J, Rao H, Burkin D, Kaufman SJ, Wu C. The muscle integrin binding protein (MIBP) interacts with alpha7beta1 integrin and regulates cell adhesion and laminin matrix deposition. Dev Biol. 2003;261:209&#x2013;219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12941630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J, Mayne R, Wu C. A novel muscle-specific beta 1 integrin binding protein (MIBP) that modulates myogenic differentiation. J Cell Biol. 1999;147:1391&#x2013;1398.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2174245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10613898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wootton PT, Flavell DM, Montgomery HE, World M, Humphries SE, et al. Lipoprotein-associated phospholipase A2 A379V variant is associated with body composition changes in response to exercise training. Nutr Metab Cardiovasc Dis. 2007;17:24&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17174223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernando SM, Rao P, Niel L, Chatterjee D, Stagljar M, et al. Myocyte androgen receptors increase metabolic rate and improve body composition by reducing fat mass. Endocrinology. 2010;151:3125&#x2013;3132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2903941</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20427479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orngreen MC, Schelhaas HJ, Jeppesen TD, Akman HO, Wevers RA, et al. Is muscle glycogenolysis impaired in X-linked phosphorylase b kinase deficiency? Neurology. 2008;70:1876&#x2013;1882.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18401027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wuyts W, Reyniers E, Ceuterick C, Storm K, de Barsy T, et al. Myopathy and phosphorylase kinase deficiency caused by a mutation in the PHKA1 gene. Am J Med Genet A. 2005;133A:82&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15637709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palazzolo I, Burnett BG, Young JE, Brenne PL, La Spada AR, et al. Akt blocks ligand binding and protects against expanded polyglutamine androgen receptor toxicity. Hum Mol Genet. 2007;16:1593&#x2013;1603.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17470458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monks DA, Johansen JA, Mo K, Rao P, Eagleson B, et al. Overexpression of wild-type androgen receptor in muscle recapitulates polyglutamine disease. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2007;104:18259&#x2013;18264.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2084330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17984063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chuang JZ, Zhou H, Zhu M, Li SH, Li XJ, et al. Characterization of a brain-enriched chaperone, MRJ, that inhibits Huntingtin aggregation and toxicity independently. J Biol Chem. 2002;277:19831&#x2013;19838.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11896048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fayazi Z, Ghosh S, Marion S, Bao X, Shero M, et al. A Drosophila ortholog of the human MRJ modulates polyglutamine toxicity and aggregation. Neurobiol Dis. 2006;24:226&#x2013;244.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16934481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katsuno M, Adachi H, Minamiyama M, Waza M, Doi H, et al. Disrupted transforming growth factor-beta signaling in spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. J Neurosci. 30:5702&#x2013;5712.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6632356</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20410122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribchester RR, Thomson D, Wood NI, Hinks T, Gillingwater TH, et al. Progressive abnormalities in skeletal muscle and neuromuscular junctions of transgenic mice expressing the Huntington's disease mutation. Eur J Neurosci. 2004;20:3092&#x2013;3114.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15579164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boirie Y, Short KR, Ahlman B, Charlton M, Nair KS. Tissue-specific regulation of mitochondrial and cytoplasmic protein synthesis rates by insulin. Diabetes. 2001;50:2652&#x2013;2658.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11723046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stump CS, Short KR, Bigelow ML, Schimke JM, Nair KS. Effect of insulin on human skeletal muscle mitochondrial ATP production, protein synthesis, and mRNA transcripts. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2003;100:7996&#x2013;8001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC164701</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12808136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tong JF, Yan X, Zhu MJ, Du M. AMP-activated protein kinase enhances the expression of muscle-specific ubiquitin ligases despite its activation of IGF-1/Akt signaling in C2C12 myotubes. J Cell Biochem. 2009;108:458&#x2013;468.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19639604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pires-Oliveira M, Maragno AL, Parreiras-e-Silva LT, Chiavegatti T, Gomes MD, et al. Testosterone represses ubiquitin ligases atrogin-1 and Murf-1 expression in an androgen-sensitive rat skeletal muscle in vivo. J Appl Physiol. 108:266&#x2013;273.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19926828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas M, Yu Z, Dadgar N, Varambally S, Yu J, et al. The unfolded protein response modulates toxicity of the expanded glutamine androgen receptor. J Biol Chem. 2005;280:21264&#x2013;21271.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15799970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merry DE, Kobayashi Y, Bailey CK, Taye AA, Fischbeck KH. Cleavage, aggregation and toxicity of the expanded androgen receptor in spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Hum Mol Genet. 1998;7:693&#x2013;701.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9499423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li M, Chevalier-Larsen ES, Merry DE, Diamond MI. Soluble androgen receptor oligomers underlie pathology in a mouse model of spinobulbar muscular atrophy. J Biol Chem. 2007;282:3157&#x2013;3164.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17121819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandrusiak LM, Beitel LK, Wang X, Scanlon TC, Chevalier-Larsen E, et al. Transglutaminase potentiates ligand-dependent proteasome dysfunction induced by polyglutamine-expanded androgen receptor. Hum Mol Genet. 2003;12:1497&#x2013;1506.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12812978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adachi H, Katsuno M, Minamiyama M, Sang C, Pagoulatos G, et al. Heat shock protein 70 chaperone overexpression ameliorates phenotypes of the spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy transgenic mouse model by reducing nuclear-localized mutant androgen receptor protein. J Neurosci. 2003;23:2203&#x2013;2211.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6742038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12657679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wyttenbach A, Carmichael J, Swartz J, Furlong RA, Narain Y, et al. Effects of heat shock, heat shock protein 40 (HDJ-2), and proteasome inhibition on protein aggregation in cellular models of Huntington's disease. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2000;97:2898&#x2013;2903.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC16027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10717003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adachi H, Waza M, Tokui K, Katsuno M, Minamiyama M, et al. CHIP overexpression reduces mutant androgen receptor protein and ameliorates phenotypes of the spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy transgenic mouse model. J Neurosci. 2007;27:5115&#x2013;5126.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6672370</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17494697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johansen JA, Yu Z, Mo K, Monks DA, Lieberman AP, et al. Recovery of function in a myogenic mouse model of spinal bulbar muscular atrophy. Neurobiol Dis 2008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4209964</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19211034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu Z, Dadgar N, Albertelli M, Scheller A, Albin RL, et al. Abnormalities of germ cell maturation and sertoli cell cytoskeleton in androgen receptor 113 CAG knock-in mice reveal toxic effects of the mutant protein. Am J Pathol. 2006;168:195&#x2013;204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1592669</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16400023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katsuno M, Adachi H, Kume A, Li M, Nakagomi Y, et al. Testosterone reduction prevents phenotypic expression in a transgenic mouse model of spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Neuron. 2002;35:843&#x2013;854.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12372280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eisen MB, Spellman PT, Brown PO, Botstein D. Cluster analysis and display of genome-wide expression patterns. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 1998;95:14863&#x2013;14868.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC24541</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9843981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramakers C, Ruijter JM, Deprez RH, Moorman AF. Assumption-free analysis of quantitative real-time polymerase chain reaction (PCR) data. Neurosci Lett. 2003;339:62&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12618301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rozen S, Skaletsky H. Primer3 on the WWW for general users and for biologist programmers. Methods Mol Biol. 2000;132:365&#x2013;386.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10547847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>