<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">21954065</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2012</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>01</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1754-8411</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>5</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2012</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Disease models &amp; mechanisms</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Dis Model Mech</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Testosterone treatment fails to accelerate disease in a transgenic mouse model of spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>141</StartPage><EndPage>145</EndPage><MedlinePgn>141-5</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1242/dmm.007849</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Evidence from multiple animal models demonstrates that testosterone plays a crucial role in the progression of symptoms in spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy (SBMA), a condition that results in neurodegeneration and muscle atrophy in affected men. Mice bearing a transgene encoding a human androgen receptor (AR) that contains a stretch of 112 glutamines (expanded polyglutamine tract; AR112Q mice) reproduce several aspects of the human disease. We treated transgenic male AR112Q mice with testosterone for 6 months. Surprisingly, testosterone treatment of AR112Q males did not exacerbate the disease. Although transgenic AR112Q males exhibited functional deficits when compared with non-transgenics, long-term testosterone treatment had no effect on motor function. Testosterone treatment also failed to affect cellular markers of disease, including inclusion formation (the accumulation of large nuclear aggregates of mutant AR protein) and levels of unphosphorylated neurofilament heavy chain. These data suggest that the mechanism of disease in SBMA saturates at close to endogenous hormone levels and that individuals with SBMA who take, or have taken, testosterone for its putative therapeutic properties are unlikely to suffer adverse effects.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chevalier-Larsen</LastName><ForeName>Erica S</ForeName><Initials>ES</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biochemistry and Molecular Biology, Thomas Jefferson University, Philadelphia, PA 19107, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Merry</LastName><ForeName>Diane E</ForeName><Initials>DE</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R01 NS032214</GrantID><Acronym>NS</Acronym><Agency>NINDS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01 NS32214</GrantID><Acronym>NS</Acronym><Agency>NINDS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2011</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Dis Model Mech</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101483332</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1754-8403</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D015415">Biomarkers</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>3XMK78S47O</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D013739">Testosterone</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015415" MajorTopicYN="N">Biomarkers</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055534" MajorTopicYN="N">Bulbo-Spinal Atrophy, X-Linked</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="Y">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="Y">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004195" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Models, Animal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018450" MajorTopicYN="Y">Disease Progression</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051379" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008822" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice, Transgenic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010641" MajorTopicYN="N">Phenotype</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013739" MajorTopicYN="N">Testosterone</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017211" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Failure</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2011</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2011</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2012</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21954065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3255552</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1242/dmm.007849</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">dmm.007849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Chevalier-Larsen E. S., O&#x2019;Brien C. J., Wang H., Jenkins S. C., Holder L., Lieberman A. P., Merry D. E. (2004). Castration restores function and neurofilament alterations of aged symptomatic males in a transgenic mouse model of spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. J. Neurosci. 24, 4778&#x2013;4786</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6729468</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15152038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferlini A., Patrosso M. C., Guidetti D., Merlini L., Uncini A., Ragno M., Plasmati R., Fini S., Repetto M., Vezzoni P., et al. (1995). Androgen receptor gene (CAG)n repeat analysis in the differential diagnosis between Kennedy Disease and other motoneuron disorders. Am. J. Med. Genet. 55, 105&#x2013;111</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7702080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandez-Rhodes L. E., Kokkinis A. D., White M. J., Watts C. A., Auh S., Jeffries N. O., Shrader J. A., Lehky T. J., Li L., Ryder J. E., et al. (2011). Efficacy and safety of dutasteride in patients with spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy: a randomised placebo-controlled trial. Lancet Neurol. 10, 140&#x2013;147</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3056353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21216197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldenberg J. N., Bradley W. G. (1996). Testosterone therapy and the pathogenesis of Kennedy&#x2019;s disease (X-linked bulbospinal muscular atrophy). J. Neurol. Sci. 135, 158&#x2013;161</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8867072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griffin L. D., Mellon S. H. (1999). Selective serotonin reuptake inhibitors directly alter activity of neurosteroidogenic enzymes. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA 96, 13512&#x2013;13517</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC23979</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10557352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katsuno M., Adachi H., Kume A., Li M., Nakagomi Y., Niwa H., Sang C., Kobayashi Y., Doyu M., Sobue G. (2002). Testosterone reduction prevents phenotypic expression in a transgenic mouse model of spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Neuron 35, 843&#x2013;854</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12372280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katsuno M., Adachi H., Doyu M., Minamiyama M., Sang C., Kobayashi Y., Inukai A., Sobue G. (2003). Leuprorelin rescues polyglutamine-dependent phenotypes in a transgenic mouse model of spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Nat. Med. 9, 768&#x2013;773</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12754502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kennedy W. R., Alter M., Sung J. H. (1968). Progressive proximal spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy of late onset: a sex-linked recessive trait. Neurology 18, 671&#x2013;680</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4233749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kinirons P., Rouleau G. A. (2008). Administration of testosterone results in reversible deterioration in Kennedy&#x2019;s disease. J. Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatry 79, 106&#x2013;107</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17056629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>La Spada A. R., Wilson E. M., Lubahn D. B., Harding A. E., Fischbeck K. H. (1991). Androgen receptor gene mutations in X-linked spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Nature 353, 77&#x2013;79</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2062380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li M., Miwa S., Kobayashi Y., Merry de Yamamoto M., Tanaka F., Doyu M., Hashizume Y., Fischbeck K. H., Sobue G. (1998). Nuclear inclusions of the androgen receptor protein in spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Ann. Neurol. 44, 249&#x2013;254</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9708548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li M., Chevalier-Larsen E. S., Merry de Diamond M. I. (2007). Soluble androgen receptor oligomers underlie pathology in a mouse model of SBMA. J. Biol. Chem. 5, 3157&#x2013;3164</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17121819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monks D. A., Johansen J. A., Mo K., Rao P., Eagleson B., Yu Z., Lieberman A. P., Breedlove S. M., Jordan C. L. (2007). Overexpression of wild-type androgen receptor in muscle recapitulates polyglutamine disease. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA 104, 18259&#x2013;18264</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2084330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17984063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montie H. L., Cho M. S., Holder L., Liu Y., Tsvetkov A. S., Finkbeiner S., Merry D. E. (2009). Cytoplasmic retention of polyglutamine-expanded androgen receptor ameliorates disease via autophagy in a mouse model of spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Hum. Mol. Genet. 18, 1937&#x2013;1950</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2678926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19279159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nedelsky N. B., Pennuto M., Smith R. B., Palazzolo I., Moore J., Nie Z., Neale G., Taylor J. P. (2010). Native functions of the androgen receptor are essential to pathogenesis in a Drosophila model of spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Neuron 67, 936&#x2013;952</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3514079</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20869592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neuschmid-Kaspar F., Gast A., Peterziel H., Schneikert J., Muigg A., Ransmayr G., Klocker H., Bartsch G., Cato A. C. B. (1996). CAG-repeat expansion in androgen receptor in Kennedy&#x2019;s disease is not a loss of function mutation. Mol. Cell. Endocrinol. 177, 149&#x2013;156</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8737374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orr C. R., Montie H. L., Liu Y., Bolzoni E., Jenkins S. C., Wilson E. M., Joseph J. D., McDonnell D. P., Merry D. E. (2010). An interdomain interaction of the androgen receptor is required for its aggregation and toxicity in spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. J. Biol. Chem. 285, 35567&#x2013;35577</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2975181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20826791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pozzi P., Bendotti C., Simeoni S., Piccioni F., Guerini V., Marron T. U., Martini L., Poletti A. (2003). Androgen 5-alpha-reductase type 2 is highly expressed and active in rat spinal cord motor neurones. J. Neuroendocrinol. 15, 882&#x2013;887</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12899683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt B. J., Greenberg C. R., Allingham-Hawkins D. J., Spriggs E. L. (2002). Expression of X-linked bulbospinal muscular atrophy (Kennedy disease) in two homozygous women. Neurology 59, 770&#x2013;772</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12221177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheffield-Moore M. (2000). Androgens and the control of skeletal muscle protein synthesis. Ann. Med. 32, 181&#x2013;186</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10821325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stenoien D. L., Cummings C. J., Adams H. P., Mancini M. G., Patel K., DeMartino G. N., Marcelli M., Weigel N. L., Mancini M. A. (1999). Polyglutamine-expanded androgen receptors form aggregates that sequester heat shock proteins, proteasome components and SRC-1, and are suppressed by the HDJ-2 chaperone. Hum. Mol. Genet. 8, 731&#x2013;741</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10196362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takeyama K., Ito S., Yamamoto A., Tanimoto H., Furutani T., Kanuka H., Miura M., Tabata T., Kato S. (2002). Androgen-dependent neurodegeneration by polyglutamine-expanded human androgen receptor in Drosophila. Neuron 35, 855&#x2013;864</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12372281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vismara G., Simonini F., Onesto E., Bignamini M., Miceli V., Martini L., Poletti A. (2009). Androgens inhibit androgen receptor promoter activation in motor neurons. Neurobiol. Dis. 33, 395&#x2013;404</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19100835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walcott J. L., Merry D. E. (2002). Ligand promotes intranuclear inclusions in a novel cell model of spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. J. Biol. Chem. 277, 50855&#x2013;50859</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12388541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu Z., Dadgar N., Albertelli M., Gruis K., Jordan D., Robins D. M., Lieberman A. P. (2006). Androgen-dependent pathology demonstrates myopathic contribution to the Kennedy disease phenotyope in a mouse knock-in model. J. Clin. Invest. 116, 2663&#x2013;2672</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1564432</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16981011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>