<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">22720173</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2013</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>03</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1687-5443</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>2012</Volume><PubDate><Year>2012</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Neural plasticity</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Neural Plast</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Current status of treatment of spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>369284</StartPage><MedlinePgn>369284</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">369284</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1155/2012/369284</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy (SBMA) is the first member identified among polyglutamine diseases characterized by slowly progressive muscle weakness and atrophy of the bulbar, facial, and limb muscles pathologically associated with motor neuron loss in the spinal cord and brainstem. Androgen receptor (AR), a disease-causing protein of SBMA, is a well-characterized ligand-activated transcription factor, and androgen binding induces nuclear translocation, conformational change and recruitment of coregulators for transactivation of AR target genes. Some therapeutic strategies for SBMA are based on these native functions of AR. Since ligand-induced nuclear translocation of mutant AR has been shown to be a critical step in motor neuron degeneration in SBMA, androgen deprivation therapies using leuprorelin and dutasteride have been developed and translated into clinical trials. Although the results of these trials are inconclusive, renewed clinical trials with more sophisticated design might prove the effectiveness of hormonal intervention in the near future. Furthermore, based on the normal function of AR, therapies targeted for conformational changes of AR including amino-terminal (N) and carboxy-terminal (C) (N/C) interaction and transcriptional coregulators might be promising. Other treatments targeted for mitochondrial function, ubiquitin-proteasome system (UPS), and autophagy could be applicable for all types of polyglutamine diseases.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tanaka</LastName><ForeName>Fumiaki</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Nagoya University Graduate School of Medicine, 65 Tsurumai-cho, Showa-ku, Nagoya 466-8550, Japan. ftanaka@med.nagoya-u.ac.jp</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Katsuno</LastName><ForeName>Masahisa</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Banno</LastName><ForeName>Haruhiko</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Suzuki</LastName><ForeName>Keisuke</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Adachi</LastName><ForeName>Hiroaki</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sobue</LastName><ForeName>Gen</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2012</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Neural Plast</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100883417</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1687-5443</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000726">Androgen Antagonists</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D006727">Hormone Antagonists</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D008024">Ligands</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D011944">Receptors, Androgen</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000726" MajorTopicYN="N">Androgen Antagonists</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055534" MajorTopicYN="N">Bulbo-Spinal Atrophy, X-Linked</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="Y">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015316" MajorTopicYN="N">Genetic Therapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000639" MajorTopicYN="Y">trends</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006727" MajorTopicYN="N">Hormone Antagonists</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008024" MajorTopicYN="N">Ligands</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011944" MajorTopicYN="N">Receptors, Androgen</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2012</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2012</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2012</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2012</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2013</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22720173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3376774</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2012/369284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Kawahara H. A family of progressive bulbar palsy. Aichi Medical Journal. 1897;16:3&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kennedy WR, Alter M, Sung JH. Progressive proximal spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy of late onset. A sex-linked recessive trait. Neurology. 1968;18(7):671&#x2013;680.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4233749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parodi S, Pennuto M. Neurotoxic effects of androgens in spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Frontiers in Neuroendocrinology. 2011;32(4):416&#x2013;425.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21745497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katsuno M, Adachi H, Waza M, et al. Pathogenesis, animal models and therapeutics in Spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy (SBMA) Experimental Neurology. 2006;200(1):8&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16513111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>La Spada AR, Wilson EM, Lubahn DB, Harding AE, Fischbeck KH. Androgen receptor gene mutations in X-linked spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Nature. 1991;352(6330):77&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2062380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanaka F, Doyu M, Ito Y, et al. Founder effect in spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy (SBMA) Human Molecular Genetics. 1996;5(9):1253&#x2013;1257.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8872464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li M, Miwa S, Kobayashi Y, et al. Nuclear inclusions of the androgen receptor protein in spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Annals of Neurology. 1998;44(2):249&#x2013;254.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9708548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finsterer J. Perspectives of Kennedy&#x2019;s disease. Journal of the Neurological Sciences. 2010;298(1-2):1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20846673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zoghbi HY, Orr HT. Glutamine repeats and neurodegeneration. Annual Review of Neuroscience. 2000;23:217&#x2013;247.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10845064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orr HT, Zoghbi HY. Trinucleotide repeat disorders. Annual Review of Neuroscience. 2007;30:575&#x2013;621.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17417937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanaka F, Sobue G, Doyu M, et al. Differential pattern in tissue-specific somatic mosaicism of expanded CAG trinucleotide repeat in dentatorubral-pallidoluysian atrophy, Machado-Joseph disease, and X-linked recessive spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Journal of the Neurological Sciences. 1996;135(1):43&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8926495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanaka F, Reeves MF, Ito Y, et al. Tissue-specific somatic mosaicism in spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy is dependent on CAG-repeat length and androgen receptor&#x2013;gene expression level. American Journal of Human Genetics. 1999;65(4):966&#x2013;973.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1288267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10486315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamada M, Sato T, Tsuji S, Takahashi H. CAG repeat disorder models and human neuropathology: similarities and differences. Acta Neuropathologica. 2008;115(1):71&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17786457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perutz MF, Johnson T, Suzuki M, Finch JT. Glutamine repeats as polar zippers: their possible role in inherited neurodegenerative diseases. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America. 1994;91(12):5355&#x2013;5358.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC43993</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8202492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor JP, Tanaka F, Robitschek J, et al. Aggresomes protect cells by enhancing the degradation of toxic polyglutamine-containing protein. Human Molecular Genetics. 2003;12(7):749&#x2013;757.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12651870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arrasate M, Mitra S, Schweitzer ES, Segal MR, Finkbeiner S. Inclusion body formation reduces levels of mutant huntingtin and the risk of neuronal death. Nature. 2004;431(7010):805&#x2013;810.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15483602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palazzolo I, Nedelsky NB, Askew CE, et al. B2 attenuates polyglutamine-expanded androgen receptor toxicity in cell and fly models of spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Journal of Neuroscience Research. 2010;88(10):2207&#x2013;2216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3881232</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20336775</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adachi H, Katsuno M, Minamiyama M, et al. Widespread nuclear and cytoplasmic accumulation of mutant androgen receptor in SBMA patients. Brain. 2005;128(3):659&#x2013;670.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15659427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adachi H, Waza M, Tokui K, et al. CHIP overexpression reduces mutant androgen receptor protein and ameliorates phenotypes of the spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy transgenic mouse model. Journal of Neuroscience. 2007;27(19):5115&#x2013;5126.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6672370</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17494697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nedelsky NB, Pennuto M, Smith RB, et al. Native functions of the androgen receptor are essential to pathogenesis in a drosophila model of spinobulbar muscular atrophy. Neuron. 2010;67(6):936&#x2013;952.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3514079</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20869592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monks DA, Johansen JA, Mo K, et al. Overexpression of wild-type androgen receptor in muscle recapitulates polyglutamine disease. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America. 2007;104(46):18259&#x2013;18264.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2084330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17984063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katsuno M, Banno H, Suzuki K, Adachi H, Tanaka F, Sobue G. Molecular pathophysiology and disease-modifying therapies for spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Archives of Neurology. 2012;69(4):436&#x2013;440.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22158719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rusmini P, Bolzoni E, Crippa V, et al. Proteasomal and autophagic degradative activities in spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Neurobiology of Disease. 2010;40(2):361&#x2013;369.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20621188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orr CR, Montie HL, Liu Y, et al. An interdomain interaction of the androgen receptor is required for its aggregation and toxicity in spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Journal of Biological Chemistry. 2010;285(46):35567&#x2013;35577.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2975181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20826791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mhatre AN, Trifiro MA, Kaufman M, et al. Reduced transcriptional regulatory competence of the androgen receptor in X-linked spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Nature Genetics. 1993;5(2):184&#x2013;188.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8252045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kazemi-Esfarjani P, Trifiro MA, Pinsky L. Evidence for a repressive function of the long polyglutamine tract in the human androgen receptor: possible pathogenetic relevance for the (CAG) n-expanded neuronopathies. Human Molecular Genetics. 1995;4(4):523&#x2013;527.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7633399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dejager S, Bry-Gauillard H, Bruckert E, et al. A comprehensive endocrine description of Kennedy&#x2019;s disease revealing androgen insensitivity linked to CAG repeat length. Journal of Clinical Endocrinology and Metabolism. 2002;87(8):3893&#x2013;3901.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12161529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brinkmann AO. Molecular basis of androgen insensitivity. Molecular and Cellular Endocrinology. 2001;179(1-2):105&#x2013;109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11420135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sato T, Matsumoto T, Yamada T, Watanabe T, Kawano H, Kato S. Late onset of obesity in male androgen receptor-deficient (AR KO) mice. Biochemical and Biophysical Research Communications. 2003;300(1):167&#x2013;171.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12480537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katsuno M, Adachi H, Kume A, et al. Testosterone reduction prevents phenotypic expression in a transgenic mouse model of spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Neuron. 2002;35(5):843&#x2013;854.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12372280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takeyama KI, Ito S, Yamamoto A, et al. Androgen-dependent neurodegeneration by polyglutamine-expanded human androgen receptor in Drosophila. Neuron. 2002;35(5):855&#x2013;864.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12372281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chevalier-Larsen ES, O&#x2019;Brien CJ, Wang H, et al. Castration restores function and neurofilament alterations of aged symptomatic males in a transgenic mouse model of spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Journal of Neuroscience. 2004;24(20):4778&#x2013;4786.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6729468</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15152038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu Z, Dadgar N, Albertelli M, et al. Androgen-dependent pathology demonstrates myopathic contribution to the Kennedy disease phenotype in a mouse knock-in model. Journal of Clinical Investigation. 2006;116(10):2663&#x2013;2672.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1564432</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16981011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montie HI, Cho MS, Holder L, et al. Cytoplasmic retention of polyglutamine-expanded androgen receptor ameliorates disease via autophagy in a mouse model of spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Human Molecular Genetics. 2009;18(11):1937&#x2013;1950.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2678926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19279159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katsuno M, Adachi H, Doyu M, et al. Leuprorelin rescues polyglutamine-dependent phenotypes in a transgenic mouse model of spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Nature Medicine. 2003;9(6):768&#x2013;773.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12754502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banno H, Katsurio M, Suzuki K, et al. Phase 2 trial of leuprorelin in patients with spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Annals of Neurology. 2009;65(2):140&#x2013;150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19259967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katsuno M, Banno H, Suzuki K, et al. Efficacy and safety of leuprorelin in patients with spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy (JASMITT study): a multicentre, randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. The Lancet Neurology. 2010;9(9):875&#x2013;884.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20691641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-Rhodes LE, Kokkinis AD, White MJ, et al. Efficacy and safety of dutasteride in patients with spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy: a randomised placebo-controlled trial. The Lancet Neurology. 2011;10(2):140&#x2013;147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3056353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21216197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimohata T, Kimura T, Nishizawa M, Onodera O, Tsuji S. Five year follow up of a patient with spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy treated with leuprorelin. Journal of Neurology, Neurosurgery and Psychiatry. 2004;75(8):1206&#x2013;1207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1739181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15258239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palazzolo I, Burnett BG, Young JE, et al. Akt blocks ligand binding and protects against expanded polyglutamine androgen receptor toxicity. Human Molecular Genetics. 2007;16(13):1593&#x2013;1603.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17470458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palazzolo I, Stack C, Kong L, et al. Overexpression of IGF-1 in muscle attenuates disease in a mouse model of spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Neuron. 2009;63(3):316&#x2013;328.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2735765</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19679072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He B, Kemppainen JA, Voegel JJ, Gronemeyer H, Wilson EM. Activation function 2 in the human androgen receptor ligand binding domain mediates interdomain communication with the NH2-terminal domain. Journal of Biological Chemistry. 1999;274(52):37219&#x2013;37225.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10601285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schaufele F, Carbonell X, Guerbadot M, et al. The structural basis of androgen receptor activation: intramolecular and intermolecular amino-carboxy interactions. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America. 2005;102(28):9802&#x2013;9807.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1168953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15994236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He B, Gampe RT, Kole AJ, et al. Structural basis for androgen receptor interdomain and coactivator interactions suggests a transition in nuclear receptor activation function dominance. Molecular Cell. 2004;16(3):425&#x2013;438.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15525515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orr CR, Montie HL, Liu Y, et al. An interdomain interaction of the androgen receptor is required for its aggregation and toxicity in spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Journal of Biological Chemistry. 2010;285(46):35567&#x2013;35577.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2975181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20826791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jochum T, Ritz ME, Schuster C, et al. Toxic and non-toxic aggregates from the SBMA and normal forms of androgen receptor have distinct oligomeric structures. Biochimica et Biophysica Acta. 2012;1822(6):1070&#x2013;1078.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22366762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heinlein CA, Chang C. Androgen receptor (AR) coregulators: an overview. Endocrine Reviews. 2002;23(2):175&#x2013;200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11943742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Royen ME, Cunha SM, Brink MC, et al. Compartmentalization of androgen receptor protein-protein interactions in living cells. Journal of Cell Biology. 2007;177(1):63&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2064112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17420290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCampbell A, Fischbeck KH. Polyglutamine and CBP: fatal attraction? Nature Medicine. 2001;7(5):528&#x2013;530.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11329046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCampbell A, Taylor JP, Taye AA, et al. CREB-binding protein sequestration by expanded polyglutamine. Human Molecular Genetics. 2000;9(14):2197&#x2013;2202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10958659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Z, Chang YJ, Yu IC, et al. ASC-J9 ameliorates spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy phenotype via degradation of androgen receptor. Nature Medicine. 2007;13(3):348&#x2013;353.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17334372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor JP, Taye AA, Campbell C, Kazemi-Esfarjani P, Fischbeck KH, Min KT. Aberrant histone acetylation, altered transcription, and retinal degeneration in a Drosophila model of polyglutamine disease are rescued by CREB-binding protein. Genes and Development. 2003;17(12):1463&#x2013;1468.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC196076</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12815067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minamiyama M, Katsuno M, Adachi H, et al. Sodium butyrate ameliorates phenotypic expression in a transgenic mouse model of spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Human Molecular Genetics. 2004;13(11):1183&#x2013;1192.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15102712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sopher BL, Thomas PS, Lafevre-Bernt MA, et al. Androgen receptor YAC transgenic mice recapitulate SBMA motor neuronopathy and implicate VEGF164 in the motor neuron degeneration. Neuron. 2004;41(5):687&#x2013;699.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15003169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katsuno M, Sobue G. Polyglutamine diminishes VEGF: passage to motor neuron death? Neuron. 2004;41(5):677&#x2013;679.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15003165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katsuno M, Adachi H, Minamiyama M, et al. Reversible disruption of dynactin 1-mediated retrograde axonal transport in polyglutamine-induced motor neuron degeneration. Journal of Neuroscience. 2006;26(47):12106&#x2013;12117.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6675422</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17122035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katsuno M, Adachi H, Minamiyama M, et al. Disrupted transforming growth factor-&#x3b2; signaling in spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Journal of Neuroscience. 2010;30(16):5702&#x2013;5712.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6632356</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20410122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oosthuyse B, Moons L, Storkebaum E, et al. Deletion of the hypoxia-response element in the vascular endothelial growth factor promoter causes motor neuron degeneration. Nature Genetics. 2001;28(2):131&#x2013;138.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11381259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gill SR, Schroer TA, Szilak I, Steuer ER, Sheetz MP, Cleveland DW. Dynactin, a conserved, ubiquitously expressed component of an activator of vesicle motility mediated by cytoplasmic dynein. Journal of Cell Biology. 1991;115(6):1639&#x2013;1650.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2289205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1836789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirokawa N, Niwa S, Tanaka Y. Molecular motors in neurons: transport mechanisms and roles in brain function, development, and disease. Neuron. 2010;68(4):610&#x2013;638.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21092854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puls I, Jonnakuty C, LaMonte BH, et al. Mutant dynactin in motor neuron disease. Nature Genetics. 2003;33(4):455&#x2013;456.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12627231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flanders KC, Ren RF, Lippa CF. Transforming growth factor-&#x3b2;S in neurodegenerative disease. Progress in Neurobiology. 1998;54(1):71&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9460794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kobayashi Y, Kume A, Li M, et al. Chaperones Hsp70 and Hsp40 suppress aggregate formation and apoptosis in cultured neuronal cells expressing truncated androgen receptor protein with expanded polyglutamine tract. Journal of Biological Chemistry. 2000;275(12):8772&#x2013;8778.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10722721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bailey CK, Andriola IFM, Kampinga HH, Merry DE. Molecular chaperones enhance the degradation of expanded polyglutamine repeat androgen receptor in a cellular model of spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Human Molecular Genetics. 2002;11(5):515&#x2013;523.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11875046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adachi H, Katsuno M, Minamiyama M, et al. Heat shock protein 70 chaperone overexpression ameliorates phenotypes of the spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy transgenic mouse model by reducing nuclear-localized mutant androgen receptor protein. Journal of Neuroscience. 2003;23(6):2203&#x2013;2211.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6742038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12657679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morishima Y, Wang AM, Yu Z, Pratt WB, Osawa Y, Lieberman AP. CHIP deletion reveals functional redundancy of E3 ligases in promoting degradation of both signaling proteins and expanded glutamine proteins. Human Molecular Genetics. 2008;17(24):3942&#x2013;3952.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2605787</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18784277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katsuno M, Sang C, Adachi H, et al. Pharmacological induction of heat-shock proteins alleviates polyglutamine-mediated motor neuron disease. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America. 2005;102(46):16801&#x2013;16806.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1275598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16260738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waza M, Adachi H, Katsuno M, et al. 17-AAG, an Hsp90 inhibitor, ameliorates polyglutamine-mediated motor neuron degeneration. Nature Medicine. 2005;11(10):1088&#x2013;1095.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16155577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waza M, Adachi H, Katsuno M, et al. Modulation of Hsp90 function in neurodegenerative disorders: a molecular-targeted therapy against disease-causing protein. Journal of Molecular Medicine. 2006;84(8):635&#x2013;646.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16741751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tokui K, Adachi H, Waza M, et al. 17-DMAG ameliorates polyglutamine-mediated motor neuron degeneration through well-preserved proteasome function in an SBMA model mouse. Human Molecular Genetics. 2009;18(5):898&#x2013;910.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19066230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goetz MP, Toft DO, Ames MM, Erlichman C. The Hsp90 chaperone complex as a novel target for cancer therapy. Annals of Oncology. 2003;14(8):1169&#x2013;1176.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12881371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rusmini P, Simonini F, Crippa V, et al. 17-AAG increases autophagic removal of mutant androgen receptor in spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Neurobiology of Disease. 2011;41(1):83&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20816782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pandey UB, Nie Z, Batlevi Y, et al. HDAC6 rescues neurodegeneration and provides an essential link between autophagy and the UPS. Nature. 2007;447(7146):859&#x2013;863.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17568747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montie HL, Merry DE. Autophagy and access: understanding the role of androgen receptor subcellular localization in SBMA. Autophagy. 2009;5(8):1194&#x2013;1197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19770590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu Z, Wang AM, Adachi H, et al. Macroautophagy is regulated by the UPR-mediator CHOP and accentuates the phenotype of SBMA mice. PLoS Genetics. 2011;7(10) Article ID e1002321.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3192827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22022281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Prospero NA, Fischbeck KH. Therapeutics development for triplet repeat expansion diseases. Nature Reviews Genetics. 2005;6(10):756&#x2013;765.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16205715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trushina E, McMurray CT. Oxidative stress and mitochondrial dysfunction in neurodegenerative diseases. Neuroscience. 2007;145(4):1233&#x2013;1248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17303344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ranganathan S, Harmison GG, Meyertholen K, Pennuto M, Burnett BG, Fischbeck KH. Mitochondrial abnormalities in spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Human Molecular Genetics. 2009;18(1):27&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2644643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18824496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banno H, Katsuno M, Suzuki K, Sobue G. Dutasteride for spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. The Lancet Neurology. 2011;10(2):113&#x2013;115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21216198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hashizume A, Katsuno M, Banno H, et al. Difference in chronological changes of outcome measures between untreated and placebo-treated patients of spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Journal of Neurology. 2012;259(4):712&#x2013;719.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21952871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>