<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">32306402</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1469-7793</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>598</Volume><Issue>13</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Journal of physiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Physiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Muscle BDNF improves synaptic and contractile muscle strength in Kennedy's disease mice in a muscle-type specific manner.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2719</StartPage><EndPage>2739</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2719-2739</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1113/JP279208</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="KEY POINTS">Muscle-derived neurotrophic factors may offer therapeutic promise for treating neuromuscular diseases. We report that a muscle-derived neurotrophic factor, BDNF, rescues synaptic and muscle function in a muscle-type specific manner in mice modelling Kennedy's disease (KD). We also find that BDNF rescues select molecular mechanisms in slow and fast muscle that may underlie the improved cellular function. We also report for the first time that expression of BDNF, but not other members of the neurotrophin family, is perturbed in muscle from patients with KD. Given that muscle BDNF had divergent therapeutic effects that depended on muscle type, a combination of neurotrophic factors may optimally rescue neuromuscular function via effects on both pre- and postsynaptic function, in the face of disease.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="ABSTRACT">Deficits in muscle brain-derived neurotrophic factor (BDNF) correlate with neuromuscular deficits in mouse models of Kennedy's disease (KD), suggesting that restoring muscle BDNF might restore function. To test this possibility, transgenic mice expressing human BDNF in skeletal muscle were crossed with '97Q' KD mice. We found that muscle BDNF slowed disease, doubling the time between symptom onset and endstage. BDNF also improved expression of genes in muscle known to play key roles in neuromuscular function, including counteracting the expression of neonatal isoforms induced by disease. Intriguingly, BDNF's ameliorative effects differed between muscle types: synaptic strength was rescued only in slow-twitch muscle, while contractile strength was improved only in fast-twitch muscle. In sum, muscle BDNF slows disease progression, rescuing select cellular and molecular mechanisms that depend on fibre type. Muscle BDNF expression was also affected in KD patients, reinforcing its translational and therapeutic potential for treating this disorder.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020 The Authors. The Journal of Physiology &#xa9; 2020 The Physiological Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Halievski</LastName><ForeName>Katherine</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neuroscience Program, Michigan State University, 108 Giltner Hall, East Lansing, MI, 48824-1115, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Program in Neurosciences and Mental Health, The Hospital for Sick Children, 686 Bay St, Toronto, ON, M5G 0A4, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Youfen</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neuroscience Program, Michigan State University, 108 Giltner Hall, East Lansing, MI, 48824-1115, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Haddad</LastName><ForeName>Yazeed W</ForeName><Initials>YW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neuroscience Program, Michigan State University, 108 Giltner Hall, East Lansing, MI, 48824-1115, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tang</LastName><ForeName>Yu Ping</ForeName><Initials>YP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neuroscience Program, Michigan State University, 108 Giltner Hall, East Lansing, MI, 48824-1115, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yamada</LastName><ForeName>Shinichiro</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Nagoya University Graduate School of Medicine, 65 Tsurumai-cho, Showa-ku, Nagoya, 466-8550, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Katsuno</LastName><ForeName>Masahisa</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Nagoya University Graduate School of Medicine, 65 Tsurumai-cho, Showa-ku, Nagoya, 466-8550, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Adachi</LastName><ForeName>Hiroaki</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9302-4663</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of Occupational and Environment Health School of Medicine, 1-1 Iseigaoka, Yahatanishi-ku, Kitakyushu, Fukuoka, 807-8555, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sobue</LastName><ForeName>Gen</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Nagoya University Graduate School of Medicine, 65 Tsurumai-cho, Showa-ku, Nagoya, 466-8550, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Breedlove</LastName><ForeName>S Marc</ForeName><Initials>SM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neuroscience Program, Michigan State University, 108 Giltner Hall, East Lansing, MI, 48824-1115, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jordan</LastName><ForeName>Cynthia L</ForeName><Initials>CL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neuroscience Program, Michigan State University, 108 Giltner Hall, East Lansing, MI, 48824-1115, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physiology Department, Michigan State University, 108 Giltner Hall, East Lansing, MI, 48824-1115, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>17H04195</GrantID><Agency>Grant-in-Aid (KAKENHI) from MEXT, Japan</Agency><Country>International</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>NS045195</GrantID><Acronym>NH</Acronym><Agency>NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>NS045195</GrantID><Acronym>NH</Acronym><Agency>NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Physiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0266262</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0022-3751</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D019208">Brain-Derived Neurotrophic Factor</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="CommentIn"><RefSource>J Physiol. 2020 Jul;598(13):2543-2544</RefSource><PMID Version="1">32390166</PMID></CommentsCorrections><CommentsCorrections RefType="CommentIn"><RefSource>J Physiol. 2020 Sep;598(17):3547-3548</RefSource><PMID Version="1">32506451</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019208" MajorTopicYN="N">Brain-Derived Neurotrophic Factor</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055534" MajorTopicYN="Y">Bulbo-Spinal Atrophy, X-Linked</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051379" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008822" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice, Transgenic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009119" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Contraction</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle-derived neurotrophic factors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neuromuscular disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neurotrophin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">polyglutamine disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">spinal bulbar muscular atrophy</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32306402</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/JP279208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>ALS CNTF Treatment Study Group (1996). A double-blind placebo-controlled clinical trial of subcutaneous recombinant human ciliary neurotrophic factor (rHCNTF) in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. ALS CNTF Treatment Study Group. Neurology 46, 1244-1249.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang Q, Khare G, Dani V, Nelson S &amp; Jaenisch R (2006). The disease progression of Mecp2 mutant mice is affected by the level of BDNF expression. Neuron 49, 341-348.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chevalier-Larsen ES, O'Brien CJ, Wang H, Jenkins SC, Holder L, Lieberman AP &amp; Merry DE (2004). Castration restores function and neurofilament alterations of aged symptomatic males in a transgenic mouse model of spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. J Neurosci 24, 4778-4786.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clow C &amp; Jasmin BJ (2010). Brain-derived neurotrophic factor regulates satellite cell differentiation and skeltal muscle regeneration. Mol Biol Cell 21, 2182-2190.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cortes CJ, Ling SC, Guo LT, Hung G, Tsunemi T, Ly L, Tokunaga S, Lopez E, Sopher BL, Bennett CF, Shelton GD, Cleveland DW &amp; La Spada AR (2014). Muscle expression of mutant androgen receptor accounts for systemic and motor neuron disease phenotypes in spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Neuron 82, 295-307.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>dePins B, Cifuentes-Diaz C, Farah AT, Lopez-Molina L, Montalban E, Sancho-Balsells A, Lopez A, Gines S, Delgado-Garcia JM, Alberch J, Gruart A, Girault J-A &amp; Giralt A (2019). Conditional BDNF delivery from astrocytes rescues memory deficits, spine density, and synaptic properties in the 5xFAD mouse model of Alzheimer disease. J Neurosci 39, 2441-2458.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deinhardt K &amp; Chao MV (2014). Trk receptors. Handb Exp Pharmacol 220, 103-119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding Y, Adachi H, Katsuno M, Huang Z, Jiang YM, Kondo N, Iida M, Tohnai G, Nakatsuji H, Funakoshi H, Nakamura T &amp; Sobue G (2015). Overexpression of hepatocyte growth factor in SBMA model mice has an additive effect on combination therapy with castration. Biochem Biophys Res Commun 468, 677-683.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dorsey SG, Lovering RM, Renn CL, Leitch CC, Liu X, Tallon LJ, Sadzewicz LD, Pratap A, Ott S, Sengamalay N, Jones KM, Barrick C, Fulgenzi G, Becker J, Voelker K, Talmadge R, Harvey BK, Wyatt RM, Vernon-Pitts E, Zhang C, Shokat K, Fraser-Liggett C, Balice-Gordon RJ, Tessarollo L &amp; Ward CW (2012). Genetic deletion of trkB.T1 increases neuromuscular function. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol 302, C141-C153.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans S, Goldman D, Heinemann S &amp; Patrick J (1987). Muscle acetylcholine receptor biosynthesis. Regulation by transcript availability. J Biol Chem 262, 4911-4916.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faria MC, Goncalves GS, Rocha NP, Moraes EN, Bicalho MA, Gualberto Cintra MT, Jardim de Paula J, Jose Ravic de Miranda LF, Clayton de Souza Ferreira A, Teixeira AL, Gomes KB, Carvalho MD &amp; Sousa LP (2014). Increased plasma levels of BDNF and inflammatory markers in Alzheimer's disease. J Psychiatr Res 53, 166-172.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia N, Tomas M, Santafe MM, Besalduch N, Lanuza MA &amp; Tomas J (2010). The interaction between tropomyosin-related kinase B receptors and presynaptic muscarinic receptors modulates transmitter release in adult rodent motor nerve terminals. J Neurosci 30, 16514-16522.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia N, Tomas M, Santafe MM, Lanuza MA, Besalduch N &amp; Tomas J (2010). Localization of brain-derived neurotrophic factor, neurotrophin-4, tropomyosin-related kinase b receptor, and p75 NTR receptor by high-resolution immunohistochemistry on the adult mouse neuromuscular junction. J Peripher Nerv Syst 15, 40-49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halievski K, Henley CL, Domino L, Poort JE, Fu M, Katsuno M, Adachi H, Sobue G, Breedlove SM &amp; Jordan CL (2015). Androgen-dependent loss of muscle BDNF mRNA in two mouse models of SBMA. Exp Neurol 269, 224-232.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harding AE, Thomas PK, Baraitser M, Bradbury PG, Morgan-Hughes JA &amp; Ponsford JR (1982). X-linked recessive bulbospinal neuronopathy: a report of ten cases. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 45, 1012-1019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jerkovic R, Argentini C, Serrano-Sanchez A, Cordonnier C &amp; Schiaffino S (1997). Early myosin switching induced by nerve activity in regenerating slow skeletal muscle. Cell Struct Funct 22, 147-153.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johansen JA, Troxell-Smith SM, Yu Z, Mo K, Monks DA, Lieberman AP, Breedlove SM &amp; Jordan CL (2011). Prenatal flutamide enhances survival in a myogenic mouse model of spinal bulbar muscular atrophy. Neurodegener Dis 8,25-34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johansen JA, Yu Z, Mo K, Monks DA, Lieberman AP, Breedlove SM &amp; Jordan CL (2009). Recovery of function in a myogenic mouse model of spinal bulbar muscular atrophy. Neurobiol Dis 34, 113-120.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jokela M, Huovinen S, Raheem O, Lindfors M, Palmio J, Penttila S &amp; Udd B (2016). Distinct muscle biopsy findings in genetically defined adult-onset motor neuron disorders. PLoS One 11, e0151376.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katsuno M, Adachi H, Kume A, Li M, Nakagomi Y, Niwa H, Sang C, Kobayashi Y, Doyu M &amp; Sobue G (2002). Testosterone reduction prevents phenotypic expression in a transgenic mouse model of spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Neuron 35, 843-854.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katsuno M, Tanaka F, Adachi H, Banno H, Suzuki K, Watanabe H &amp; Sobue G (2012). Pathogenesis and therapy of spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy (SBMA). Prog Neurobiol 99, 246-256.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kazim SF, Blanchard J, Dai CL, Tung YC, LaFerla FM, Iqbal IG &amp; Iqbal K (2014). Disease modifying effect of chronic oral treatment with a neurotrophic peptidergic compound in a triple transgenic mouse model of Alzheimer's disease. Neurobiol Dis 71, 110-130.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kemp MQ, Poort JL, Baqri RM, Lieberman AP, Breedlove SM, Miller KE &amp; Jordan CL (2011). Impaired motoneuronal retrograde transport in two models of SBMA implicates two sites of androgen action. Hum Mol Genet 20, 4475-4490.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kennedy WR, Alter M &amp; Sung JH (1968). Progressive proximal spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy of late onset. A sex-linked recessive trait. Neurology 18, 671-680.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer BR, Yoon SO &amp; Carter BD (2014). The biological functions and signaling mechanisms of the p75 neurotrophin receptor. Handb Exp Pharmacol 220, 121-164.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krakora D, Mulcrone P, Meyer M, Lewis C, Bernau K, Gowing G, Zimprich C, Aebischer P, Svendsen CN &amp; Suzuki M (2013). Synergistic effects of GDNF and VEGF on lifespan and disease progression in a familial ALS rat model. Mol Ther 21, 1602-1610.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laske C, Stransky E, Leyhe T, Eschweiler GW, Wittorf A, Richartz E, Bartels M, Buchkremer G &amp; Schott K (2006). Stage-dependent BDNF serum concentrations in Alzheimer's disease. J Neural Transm (Vienna) 113, 1217-1224.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lieberman AP (2018). Spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Handb Clin Neurol 148, 625-632.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lieberman AP, Yu Z, Murray S, Peralta R, Low A, Guo S, Yu XX, Cortes CJ, Bennett CF, Monia BP, La Spada AR &amp; Hung G (2014). Peripheral androgen receptor gene suppression rescues disease in mouse models of spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Cell Rep 7, 774-784.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lohof AM, Ip NY &amp; Poo MM (1993). Potentiation of developing neuromuscular synapses by the neurotrophins NT-3 and BDNF. Nature 363, 350-353.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mantilla CB, Zhan WZ &amp; Sieck GC (2004). Neurotrophins improve neuromuscular transmission in the adult rat diaphragm. Muscle Nerve 29, 381-386.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matthews VB, Astrom MB, Chan MH, Bruce CR, Krabbe KS, Prelovsek O, Akerstrom T, Yfanti C, Broholm C, Mortensen OH, Penkowa M, Hojman P, Zankari A, Watt MJ, Bruunsgaard H, Pedersen BK &amp; Febbraio MA (2009). Brain-derived neurotrophic factor is produced by skeletal muscle cells in response to contraction and enhances fat oxidation via activation of AMP-activated protein kinase. Diabetologia 52, 1409-1418.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGurk JS, Shim S, Kim JY, Wen Z, Song H &amp; Ming GL (2011). Postsynaptic TRPC1 function contributes to BDNF-induced synaptic potentiation at the developing neuromuscular junction. J Neurosci 31, 14754-14762.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Missias AC, Chu GC, Klocke BJ, Sanes JR &amp; Merlie JP (1996). Maturation of the acetylcholine receptor in skeletal muscle: regulation of the AChR gamma-to-epsilon switch. Dev Biol 179, 223-238.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitsumoto H, Ikeda K, Klinkosz B, Cedarbaum JM, Wong V &amp; Lindsay RM (1994). Arrest of motor neuron disease in wobbler mice cotreated with CNTF and BDNF. Science 265, 1107-1110.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miura P, Amirouche A, Clow C, Belanger G &amp; Jasmin BJ (2012). Brain-derived neurotrophic factor expression is repressed during myogenic differentiation by miR-206.J Neurochem 120, 230-238.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyazaki Y, Adachi H, Katsuno M, Minamiyama M, Jiang YM, Huang Z, Doi H, Matsumoto S, Kondo N, Iida M, Tohnai G, Tanaka F, Muramatsu S-i &amp; Sobue G (2012). Viral delivery of miR-196a ameliorates the SBMA phenotype via the silencing of CELF2. Nat Med 18, 1136-1141.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monks DA, Johansen JA, Mo K, Rao P, Eagleson B, Yu Z, Lieberman AP, Breedlove SM &amp; Jordan CL (2007). Overexpression of wild-type androgen receptor in muscle recapitulates polyglutamine disease. Proc Natl Acad Sci, 104, 18259-18264.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mousavi K, Parry DJ &amp; Jasmin BJ (2004). BDNF rescues myosin heavy chain IIB muscle fibers after neonatal nerve injury. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol 287, C22-C29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oki K, Halievski K, Vicente L, Xu Y, Zeolla D, Poort J, Katsuno M, Adachi H, Sobue G, Wiseman RW, Breedlove SM &amp; Jordan CL (2015). Contractile dysfunction in muscle may underlie androgen-dependent motor dysfunction in spinal bulbar muscular atrophy. J Appl Physiol (1985) 118,941-952.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oki K, Wiseman RW, Breedlove SM &amp; Jordan CL (2013). Androgen receptors in muscle fibers induce rapid loss of force but not mass: implications for spinal bulbar muscular atrophy. Muscle Nerve 47, 823-834.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pagala MK, Venkatachari SA, Nandakumar NV, Ravindran K, Kerstein J, Namba T &amp; Grob D (1991). Peripheral mechanisms of fatigue in muscles of normal and dystrophic mice. Neuromuscul Disord 1, 287-298.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palazzolo I, Stack C, Kong L, Musaro A, Adachi H, Katsuno M, Sobue G, Taylor JP, Sumner CJ, Fischbeck KH &amp; Pennuto M (2009). Overexpression of IGF-1 in muscle attenuates disease in a mouse model of spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Neuron 63, 316-328.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedersen BK (2013). Muscle as a secretory organ. Compr Physiol 3, 1337-1362.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrou P, Gothelf Y, Argov Z, Gotkine M, Levy YS, Kassis I, Vaknin-Dembinsky A, Ben-Hur T, Offen D &amp; Abramsky O, Melamed E &amp; Karussis D (2016). Safety and clinical effects of mesenchymal stem cells secreting neurotrophic factor transplantation in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: results of phase 1/2 and 2a clinical trials. JAMA Neurol 73, 337-344.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pfaffl MW, Horgan GW and Dempfle L (2002). Relative expression software tool (REST) for group-wise comparison and statistical analysis of relative expression results in real-time PCR. Nucleic Acids Res 30, e36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rao P &amp; Monks DA (2009). A tetracycline-inducible and skeletal muscle-specific Cre recombinase transgenic mouse. Dev Neurobiol 69, 401-406.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rocchi A, Milioto C, Parodi S, Armirotti A, Borgia D, Pellegrini M, Urciuolo A, Molon S, Morbidoni V, Marabita M, Romanello V, Gatto P, Blaauw B, Bonaldo P, Sambataro F, Robins DM, Lieberman AP, Sorar&#xf9; G, Vergani L, Sandri M &amp; Pennuto M (2016). Glycolytic-to-oxidative fiber-type switch and mTOR signaling activation are early-onset features of SBMA muscle modified by high-fat diet. Acta Neuropathol (Berl) 132, 127-144.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sorenson EJ, Windbank AJ, Mandrekar JN, Bamlet WR, Appel SH, Armon C, Barkhaus PE, Bosch P, Boylan K, David WS, Feldman E, Glass J, Gutmann L, Katz J, King W, Luciano CA, McCluskey LF, Nash S, Newman DS, Pascuzzi RM, Pioro E, Sams LJ, Scelsa S, Simpson EP, Subramony SH, Tiryaki E &amp; Thornton CA (2008). Subcutaneous IGF-1 is not beneficial in 2-year ALS trial. Neurology 71, 1770-1775.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stoop R &amp; Poo MM (1996). Synaptic modulation by neurotrophic factors: differential and synergistic effects of brain-derived neurotrophic factor and ciliary neurotrophic factor. J Neurosci 16, 3256-3264.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The BDNF Study Group (1999). A controlled trial of recombinant methionyl human BDNF in ALS: The BDNF Study Group (Phase III). Neurology 52, 1427-1433.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tyler WJ, Zhang XL, Hartman K, Winterer J, Muller W, Stanton PK &amp; Pozzo-Miller L (2006). BDNF increases release probability and the size of a rapidly recycling vesicle pool within rat hippocampal excitatory synapses. J Physiol 574, 787-803.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vejsada R, Tseng JL, Lindsay RM, Acheson A, Aebischer P &amp; Kato AC (1998). Synergistic but transient rescue effects of BDNF and GDNF on axotomized neonatal motoneurons. Neuroscience 84, 129-139.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu Y, Halievski K, Henley C, Atchison WD, Katsuno M, Adachi H, Sobue G, Breedlove SM &amp; Jordan CL (2016). Defects in neuromuscular transmission may underlie motor dysfunction in spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy.J Neurosci 36, 5094-5106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamada S, Hashizume A, Hijikata Y, Inagaki T, Suzuki K, Kondo N, Kawai K, Noda S, Nakanishi H, Banno H, Hirakawa A, Koike H, Halievski K, Jordan CL, Katsuno M &amp; Sobue G (2016). Decreased peak expiratory flow associated with muscle fiber-type switching in spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. PLoS One 11, e0168846.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamamoto M, Mitsuma N, Inukai A, Ito Y, Li M, Mitsuma T &amp; Sobue G (1999). Expression of GDNF and GDNFR-alpha mRNAs in muscles of patients with motor neuron diseases. Neurochem Res 24, 785-790.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu Z, Dadgar N, Albertelli M, Gruis K, Jordan C, Robins DM &amp; Lieberman AP (2006). Androgen-dependent pathology demonstrates myopathic contribution to the Kennedy disease phenotype in a mouse knock-in model. J Clin Invest 116, 2663-2672.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>