<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">32839928</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>31</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2240-2993</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>120</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Acta neurologica Belgica</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Acta Neurol Belg</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Kennedy's disease: an under-recognized motor neuron disorder.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1289</StartPage><EndPage>1295</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1289-1295</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s13760-020-01472-6</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Kennedy's disease or spinal bulbar muscular atrophy is a rare, inherited and slowly progressive multisystem disease mostly manifesting with a motor neuron disease phenotype leading to disability. The slow progression, partial androgen insensitivity, electrophysiological evidence of sensory neuronopathy, and relatively spared central nervous system pathways help differentiate it from amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. To date, there is no treatment or cure with clinical care mainly focused on accurate diagnosis, symptom management, patient education, and genetic counselling.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Malek</LastName><ForeName>Elia G</ForeName><Initials>EG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurology Department, American University of Beirut Medical Center, Riad El-Solh, P.O.Box 11-0236, Beirut, 1107 2020, Lebanon.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Salameh</LastName><ForeName>Johnny S</ForeName><Initials>JS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurology Department, American University of Beirut Medical Center, Riad El-Solh, P.O.Box 11-0236, Beirut, 1107 2020, Lebanon.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Makki</LastName><ForeName>Achraf</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurology Department, American University of Beirut Medical Center, Riad El-Solh, P.O.Box 11-0236, Beirut, 1107 2020, Lebanon. am132@aub.edu.lb.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Italy</Country><MedlineTA>Acta Neurol Belg</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0247035</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0300-9009</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055534" MajorTopicYN="Y">Bulbo-Spinal Atrophy, X-Linked</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Kennedy&#x2019;s disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Motor neuron disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Spinal bulbar muscular atrophy</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32839928</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13760-020-01472-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s13760-020-01472-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Kennedy WR, Alter M, Sung JH (1968) Progressive proximal spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy of late onset. A sex-linked recessive trait. Neurology 18(7):671&#x2013;680</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parboosingh JS, Figlewicz DA, Krizus A, Meininger V, Azad NA, Newman DS et al (1997) Spinobulbar muscular atrophy can mimic ALS: the importance of genetic testing in male patients with atypical ALS. Neurology 49(2):568&#x2013;572</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jokela ME, Udd B (2016) Diagnostic clinical, electrodiagnostic and muscle pathology features of spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. J Mol Neurosci 58(3):330&#x2013;334</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>La Spada AR, Wilson EM, Lubahn DB, Harding AE, Fischbeck KH (1991) Androgen receptor gene mutations in X-linked spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Nature 352(6330):77&#x2013;79</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poletti A (2004) The polyglutamine tract of androgen receptor: from functions to dysfunctions in motor neurons. Front Neuroendocrinol 25(1):1&#x2013;26</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandez-Guasti A, Kruijver FP, Fodor M, Swaab DF (2000) Sex differences in the distribution of androgen receptors in the human hypothalamus. J Comp Neurol 425(3):422&#x2013;435</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li M, Sobue G, Doyu M, Mukai E, Hashizume Y, Mitsuma T (1995) Primary sensory neurons in X-linked recessive bulbospinal neuropathy: histopathology and androgen receptor gene expression. Muscle Nerve 18(3):301&#x2013;308</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sengelaub DR, Forger NG (2008) The spinal nucleus of the bulbocavernosus: firsts in androgen-dependent neural sex differences. Horm Behav 53(5):596&#x2013;612</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brinkmann A, Jenster G, Ris-Stalpers C, van der Korput H, Bruggenwirth H, Boehmer A et al (1996) Molecular basis of androgen insensitivity. Steroids 61(4):172&#x2013;175</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neuschmid-Kaspar F, Gast A, Peterziel H, Schneikert J, Muigg A, Ransmayr G et al (1996) CAG-repeat expansion in androgen receptor in Kennedy&#x2019;s disease is not a loss of function mutation. Mol Cell Endocrinol 117(2):149&#x2013;156</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piccioni F, Simeoni S, Andriola I, Armatura E, Bassanini S, Pozzi P et al (2001) Polyglutamine tract expansion of the androgen receptor in a motoneuronal model of spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Brain Res Bull 56(3&#x2013;4):215&#x2013;220</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adegbuyiro A, Sedighi F, Pilkington AW, Groover S, Legleiter J (2017) Proteins containing expanded polyglutamine tracts and neurodegenerative disease. Biochemistry 56(9):1199&#x2013;1217</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5727916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soraru G, D'Ascenzo C, Polo A, Palmieri A, Baggio L, Vergani L et al (2008) Spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy: skeletal muscle pathology in male patients and heterozygous females. J Neurol Sci 264(1&#x2013;2):100&#x2013;105</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borgia D, Malena A, Spinazzi M, Desbats MA, Salviati L, Russell AP et al (2017) Increased mitophagy in the skeletal muscle of spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy patients. Hum Mol Genet 26(6):1087&#x2013;1103</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5409076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guidetti D, Vescovini E, Motti L, Ghidoni E, Gemignani F, Marbini A et al (1996) X-linked bulbar and spinal muscular atrophy, or Kennedy disease: clinical, neurophysiological, neuropathological, neuropsychological and molecular study of a large family. J Neurol Sci 135(2):140&#x2013;148</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Querin G, Bertolin C, Da Re E, Volpe M, Zara G, Pegoraro E et al (2016) Non-neural phenotype of spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy: results from a large cohort of Italian patients. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 87(8):810&#x2013;816</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Udd B, Juvonen V, Hakamies L, Nieminen A, Wallgren-Pettersson C, Cederquist K et al (1998) High prevalence of Kennedy&#x2019;s disease in Western Finland&#x2014;is the syndrome underdiagnosed? Acta Neurol Scand 98(2):128&#x2013;133</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bertolin C, Querin G, Martinelli I, Pennuto M, Pegoraro E, Soraru G (2019) Insights into the genetic epidemiology of spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy: prevalence estimation and multiple founder haplotypes in the Veneto Italian region. Eur J Neurol 26(3):519&#x2013;524</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scialo C, Novi G, di Bandettini PM, Canosa A, Sormani MP, Mandich P et al (2016) Clinical epidemiology of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in Liguria, Italy: an update of LIGALS register. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener 17(7&#x2013;8):535&#x2013;542</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fratta P, Nirmalananthan N, Masset L, Skorupinska I, Collins T, Cortese A et al (2014) Correlation of clinical and molecular features in spinal bulbar muscular atrophy. Neurology 82(23):2077&#x2013;2084</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4075620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hashizume A, Banno H, Katsuno M, Hijikata Y, Yamada S, Inagaki T et al (2017) Quantitative assessment of swallowing dysfunction in patients with spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Intern Med 56(23):3159&#x2013;3165</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5742386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhodes LE, Freeman BK, Auh S, Kokkinis AD, La Pean A, Chen C et al (2009) Clinical features of spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Brain 132(Pt 12):3242&#x2013;3251</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2792370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atsuta N, Watanabe H, Ito M, Banno H, Suzuki K, Katsuno M et al (2006) Natural history of spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy (SBMA): a study of 223 Japanese patients. Brain 129(Pt 6):1446&#x2013;1455</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu SC, Kuo HC, Chu CC, Wu YR, Ro LS, Liu CS et al (2013) Long-term follow-up of spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy in Taiwan. J Formos Med Assoc 112(6):326&#x2013;331</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rohani M, Miri S (2015) Teaching video NeuroImages: hand tremor, tongue and perioral fasciculation in a patient with Kennedy disease. Neurology 84(10):e76</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sperfeld AD, Karitzky J, Brummer D, Schreiber H, Haussler J, Ludolph AC et al (2002) X-linked bulbospinal neuronopathy: Kennedy disease. Arch Neurol 59(12):1921&#x2013;1926</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warnecke T, Oelenberg S, Teismann I, Suntrup S, Hamacher C, Young P et al (2009) Dysphagia in X-linked bulbospinal muscular atrophy (Kennedy disease). Neuromuscul Disord 19(10):704&#x2013;708</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soukup GR, Sperfeld AD, Uttner I, Karitzky J, Ludolph AC, Kassubek J et al (2009) Frontotemporal cognitive function in X-linked spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy (SBMA): a controlled neuropsychological study of 20 patients. J Neurol 256(11):1869&#x2013;1875</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romigi A, Liguori C, Placidi F, Albanese M, Izzi F, Uasone E et al (2014) Sleep disorders in spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy (Kennedy&#x2019;s disease): a controlled polysomnographic and self-reported questionnaires study. J Neurol 261(5):889&#x2013;893</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manganelli F, Iodice V, Provitera V, Pisciotta C, Nolano M, Perretti A et al (2007) Small-fiber involvement in spinobulbar muscular atrophy (Kennedy&#x2019;s disease). Muscle Nerve 36(6):816&#x2013;820</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anannontsak A, Massakulpan P, Aksaranugraha S, Phanthumchinda K (1999) Somatosensory evoked potentials in X-linked recessive bulbospinal neuronopathy: a case demonstration. Electromyogr Clin Neurophysiol 39(7):393&#x2013;396</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kachi T, Sobue G, Sobue I (1992) Central motor and sensory conduction in X-linked recessive bulbospinal neuronopathy. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 55(5):394&#x2013;397</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">489083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anagnostou E, Zachou A, Breza M, Kladi A, Karadima G, Koutsis G (2019) Disentangling balance impairments in spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Neurosci Lett 705:94&#x2013;98</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rocchi C, Greco V, Urbani A, Di Giorgio A, Priori M, Massa R et al (2011) Subclinical autonomic dysfunction in spinobulbar muscular atrophy (Kennedy disease). Muscle Nerve 44(5):737&#x2013;740</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dejager S, Bry-Gauillard H, Bruckert E, Eymard B, Salachas F, LeGuern E et al (2002) A comprehensive endocrine description of Kennedy&#x2019;s disease revealing androgen insensitivity linked to CAG repeat length. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 87(8):3893&#x2013;3901</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Querin G, Melacini P, D'Ascenzo C, Morandi L, Mazzini L, Silani V et al (2013) No evidence of cardiomyopathy in spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Acta Neurol Scand 128(6):e30&#x2013;e32</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Araki A, Katsuno M, Suzuki K, Banno H, Suga N, Hashizume A et al (2014) Brugada syndrome in spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Neurology 82(20):1813&#x2013;1821</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrante MA, Wilbourn AJ (1997) The characteristic electrodiagnostic features of Kennedy&#x2019;s disease. Muscle Nerve 20(3):323&#x2013;329</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suzuki K, Katsuno M, Banno H, Takeuchi Y, Atsuta N, Ito M et al (2008) CAG repeat size correlates to electrophysiological motor and sensory phenotypes in SBMA. Brain 131(Pt 1):229&#x2013;239</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polo A, Teatini F, D'Anna S, Manganotti P, Salviati A, Dallapiccola B et al (1996) Sensory involvement in X-linked spino-bulbar muscular atrophy (Kennedy&#x2019;s syndrome): an electrophysiological study. J Neurol 243(5):388&#x2013;392</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chahin N, Sorenson EJ (2009) Serum creatine kinase levels in spinobulbar muscular atrophy and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve 40(1):126&#x2013;129</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hijikata Y, Katsuno M, Suzuki K, Hashizume A, Araki A, Yamada S et al (2016) Impaired muscle uptake of creatine in spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Ann Clin Transl Neurol 3(7):537&#x2013;546</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4931718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hijikata Y, Hashizume A, Yamada S, Inagaki T, Ito D, Hirakawa A et al (2018) Biomarker-based analysis of preclinical progression in spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Neurology 90(17):e1501&#x2013;e1509</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kassubek J, Juengling FD, Sperfeld AD (2007) Widespread white matter changes in Kennedy disease: a voxel based morphometry study. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 78(11):1209&#x2013;1212</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2117581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pieper CC, Konrad C, Sommer J, Teismann I, Schiffbauer H (2013) Structural changes of central white matter tracts in Kennedy&#x2019;s disease&#x2014;a diffusion tensor imaging and voxel-based morphometry study. Acta Neurol Scand 127(5):323&#x2013;328</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lombardi V, Querin G, Ziff OJ, Zampedri L, Martinelli I, Heller C et al (2019) Muscle and not neuronal biomarkers correlate with severity in spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Neurology 92(11):e1205&#x2013;e1211</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6511101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dahlqvist JR, Oestergaard ST, Poulsen NS, Thomsen C, Vissing J (2019) Refining the spinobulbar muscular atrophy phenotype by quantitative MRI and clinical assessments. Neurology 92(6):e548&#x2013;e559</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klickovic U, Zampedri L, Sinclair CDJ, Wastling SJ, Trimmel K, Howard RS et al (2019) Skeletal muscle MRI differentiates SBMA and ALS and correlates with disease severity. Neurology 93:e895&#x2013;e907</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6745729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hashizume A, Katsuno M, Suzuki K, Banno H, Suga N, Mano T et al (2015) A functional scale for spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy: cross-sectional and longitudinal study. Neuromuscul Disord 25(7):554&#x2013;562</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5608513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu M, Guo H, Fan D (2017) Kennedy&#x2019;s disease 1234 scale: preliminary design and test. J Clin Neurosci 40:185&#x2013;189</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banno H, Katsuno M, Suzuki K, Takeuchi Y, Kawashima M, Suga N et al (2009) Phase 2 trial of leuprorelin in patients with spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Ann Neurol 65(2):140&#x2013;150</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katsuno M, Banno H, Suzuki K, Takeuchi Y, Kawashima M, Yabe I et al (2010) Efficacy and safety of leuprorelin in patients with spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy (JASMITT study): a multicentre, randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Lancet Neurol 9(9):875&#x2013;884</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandez-Rhodes LE, Kokkinis AD, White MJ, Watts CA, Auh S, Jeffries NO et al (2011) Efficacy and safety of dutasteride in patients with spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy: a randomised placebo-controlled trial. Lancet Neurol 10(2):140&#x2013;147</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3056353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hashizume A, Katsuno M, Suzuki K, Hirakawa A, Hijikata Y, Yamada S et al (2017) Long-term treatment with leuprorelin for spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy: natural history-controlled study. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 88(12):1026&#x2013;1032</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grunseich C, Miller R, Swan T, Glass DJ, El Mouelhi M, Fornaro M et al (2018) Safety, tolerability, and preliminary efficacy of an IGF-1 mimetic in patients with spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy: a randomised, placebo-controlled trial. Lancet Neurol 17(12):1043&#x2013;1052</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6415539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Querin G, D'Ascenzo C, Peterle E, Ermani M, Bello L, Melacini P et al (2013) Pilot trial of clenbuterol in spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Neurology 80(23):2095&#x2013;2098</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hijikata Y, Katsuno M, Suzuki K, Hashizume A, Araki A, Yamada S et al (2018) Treatment with creatine monohydrate in spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy: protocol for a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. JMIR Res Protoc 7(3):e69</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5859194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Preisler N, Andersen G, Thogersen F, Crone C, Jeppesen TD, Wibrand F et al (2009) Effect of aerobic training in patients with spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy (Kennedy disease). Neurology 72(4):317&#x2013;323</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shrader JA, Kats I, Kokkinis A, Zampieri C, Levy E, Joe GO et al (2015) A randomized controlled trial of exercise in spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Ann Clin Transl Neurol 2(7):739&#x2013;747</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4531056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>