<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35092036</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>21</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-4598</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>65</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>May</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Muscle &amp; nerve</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Muscle Nerve</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Nerve ultrasound detects abnormally small nerves in patients with spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>599</StartPage><EndPage>602</EndPage><MedlinePgn>599-602</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/mus.27509</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION/AIMS">Sensory impairment secondary to dorsal root ganglion neuronopathy is common, although often subclinical, in X-linked spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy (SBMA). We investigated the hypothesis that nerves of SBMA patients show the same morphological changes on ultrasound as other inherited sensory neuronopathies and that these changes are distinct from those in axonal neuropathy.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">We compared the ultrasound cross-sectional areas (CSAs) of median, ulnar, sural, and tibial nerves of prospectively recruited SBMA patients with those of patients with acquired axonal neuropathy and healthy controls. We also compared the individual nerve CSAs of SBMA and neuropathy patients with our laboratory reference values.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">There were 7 SBMA patients, 18 neuropathy patients, and 42 healthy controls. The nerve CSAs of the SBMA patients were significantly smaller than those of patients in the other two groups. The changes were most prominent in the upper limbs (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;.001), with the nerves of the SBMA patients being on average approximately half the size of the controls and a third the size of the neuropathy patients. On individual analysis, the ultrasound abnormality was sufficiently characteristic to be detected in all but one SBMA patient.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION">These ultrasound changes are similar to those reported in other inherited sensory neuronopathies and clearly different from the ultrasound findings in axonal neuropathy. Smaller nerves are possibly a distinctive finding in SBMA that may distinguish it from other motor neuron syndromes. Further studies are warranted to confirm this and determine the optimal sonographic protocol.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pelosi</LastName><ForeName>Luciana</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6443-6952</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departments of Neurology and Neurophysiology, Bay Of Plenty District Health Board, Tauranga Hospital, Tauranga, New Zealand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ghosh</LastName><ForeName>Avroneel</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Auckland District Health Board, Auckland, New Zealand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Leadbetter</LastName><ForeName>Ruth</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Wellington Hospital, Wellington, New Zealand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lance</LastName><ForeName>Sean</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Wellington Hospital, Wellington, New Zealand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rodrigues</LastName><ForeName>Miriam</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Auckland District Health Board, Auckland, New Zealand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Roxburgh</LastName><ForeName>Richard</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Auckland District Health Board, Auckland, New Zealand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre of Brain Research Neurogenetics Research Clinic, University of Auckland, Auckland, New Zealand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Muscle Nerve</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7803146</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0148-639X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055534" MajorTopicYN="Y">Bulbo-Spinal Atrophy, X-Linked</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005727" MajorTopicYN="N">Ganglia, Spinal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009046" MajorTopicYN="N">Motor Neurons</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009134" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscular Atrophy, Spinal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010523" MajorTopicYN="Y">Peripheral Nervous System Diseases</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014463" MajorTopicYN="N">Ultrasonography</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">axonal neuropathy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">motor neuron syndromes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nerve ultrasound</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sensory neuronopathy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35092036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.27509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Breza M, Koutsis G. Kennedy's disease (spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy): a clinically oriented review of a rare disease. J Neurol. 2019;266(3):565-573.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>La Spada AR, Wilson EM, Lubahn DB, Harding AE, Fischbeck KH. Androgen receptor gene mutations in X-linked spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy. Nature. 1991;352:77-79.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hashizume A, Fischbeck KH, Pennuto M, Fratta P, Katsuno M. Disease mechanism, biomarker and therapeutics for spinal and bulbar muscular atrophy (SBMA). J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2020;91(10):1085-1091.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manzano R, Sorar&#xfa; G, Grunseich C, et al. Beyond motor neurons: expanding the clinical spectrum in Kennedy's disease. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2018;89:808-812.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li M, Sobue G, Doyu M, Mukai E, Hashizume Y, Mitsuma T. Primary sensory neurons in X-linked recessive bulbospinal neuropathy: histopathology and androgen receptor gene expression. Muscle Nerve. 1995;18:301-308.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Camdessanch&#xe9; JP, Jousserand G, Ferraud K, et al. The pattern and diagnostic criteria of sensory neuronopathy: a case-control study. Brain. 2009;132:1723-1733.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parboosingh JS, Figlewicz DA, Krizus A, et al. Spinobulbar muscular atrophy can mimic ALS: the importance of genetic testing in male patients with atypical ALS. Neurology. 1997;49:568-572.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pelosi L, Mulroy E, Leadbetter R, et al. Peripheral nerves are pathologically small in cerebellar ataxia neuropathy vestibular areflexia syndrome: a controlled ultrasound study. Eur J Neurol. 2018;25(4):659-665.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pelosi L, Mulroy E, Rodrigues MJ, Roxburgh RH. Neuronopathy and neuropathy in autosomal dominant spino-cerebellar ataxia (SCA): a preliminary peripheral nerve ultrasound study. Clin Neurophysiol. 2017;128(12):2436-2437.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pelosi L, Iodice R, Antenora A, et al. Spinocerebellar ataxia type 2-neuronopathy or neuropathy? Muscle Nerve. 2019;60(3):271-278.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leadbetter R, Weatherall M, Pelosi L. Nerve ultrasound as a diagnostic tool for sensory neuronopathy in spinocerebellar ataxia syndrome. Clin Neurophysiol. 2019;130(4):568-572.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cartwright MS, Walker FO, Griffin LP, Caress JB. Peripheral nerve and muscle ultrasound in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle Nerve. 2011;44:346-351.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schreiber S, Vielhaber S, Schreiber F, Cartwright MS. Peripheral nerve imaging in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Clin Neurophysiol. 2020;131(9):2315-2326.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodrigues M, Hammond-Tooke G, Kidd A, et al. The New Zealand neuromuscular registry. J Clin Neurosci. 2012;19(12):1749-1750.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fuglsang-Frederiksen A, Pugdahl K. Current status on electrodiagnostic standards and guidelines in neuromuscular disorders. Clin Neurophysiol. 2011;122:440-455.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gesslbauer B, Hruby L, Roche AD, Farina D, Blumer R, Aszmann OC. Axonal components of nerves innervating the human arm. Ann Neurol. 2017;82:396-408.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nodera H, Takamatsu N, Shimatoni Y, et al. Thinning of cervical nerve roots and peripheral nerves in ALS as measured by sonography. Clin Neurophysiol. 2014;125:1906-1911.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonini G, Gragnani F, Romaniello A, et al. Sensory involvement in spinal-bulbar muscular atrophy (Kennedy's disease). Muscle Nerve. 2000;23:252-258.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>